[Music]
my first call is lead paramedic
yeah it was pretty bad so my partner and
i we got paged out for
an altered mental status just outside of
golden colorado
pull up to this mobile home and the
patient's neighbor met us down the
bottom she called us in
because she'd gone in to check on her
neighbor and found her kind of
semi-conscious sitting in her kitchen
walk in and i can i can still picture
the patient sitting in a chair
it was on a formica floor in a very
well-kept kitchen
some of those 70s style tables that's
got the metal rooms around the edges
and from a distance it looked like it
was probably going to be
a diabetic emergency so this is pretty
straightforward for us to go ahead and
take care of
first thing i would do is check the
patient's glucose and if her blood
sugar's super low we give her what's
called an amp of d50
it's 25 grams of dextrose high octane
sugar that's so concentrated when you
put it in through the iv
if you actually mess up and miss you'll
kill all the surrounding tissue
well sure enough her blood glucose was
low and everything's going fine at this
point
then i really messed up
and everything went wrong i got it into
my head
that to treat the patient i wanted to
start the iv
and give her the d50 in the back of my
ambulance now there's reasons for this
that sugar is so pure it's very fast
acting but it also wears off really
quickly
so if the patient doesn't manage their
sugar for the longer term
they can end up right back where they
started and you really should be checked
out at the hospital
and the patient's not really with it so
she can't tell me we have what's known
as implied consent
that she doesn't want to go to the
hospital but if you've ever had low
blood sugar
you know how angry you get and so i told
my partner let's get her out let's get
her in the back of the ambulance i'll
take care of her
and she started fighting and the
neighbor is wondering why we're dragging
this poor woman out of her house
bringing her into the back of the
ambulance and it was ugly and i still
remember us just kind of pulling her
down the stairs
and my partner looking at me like i was
crazy because i was
because maybe i could have given her the
d50 in the house
her neighbor is right there and made her
a sandwich or given her a bowl of cereal
and kept an eye on her instead i made
that decision for the patient
put her in the back of my ambulance
started the iv
she wakes up and she is even angrier
albeit fighting us a little bit less the
reality is is i did not manage that call
well
that partner never wanted to work for me
again and i had actually caused me
problems in that job in the longer term
it took me about a year or two before i
think i became a competent paramedic i
went out to the east coast i worked some
high volume places like the jersey city
medical center
before coming back to colorado doing a
little more work and then eventually
going back to college
and when i went back to college i
dropped down after my paramedic expired
to emt
so and got a part-time job as a pc
technician because it was just
really too hard to work as a paramedic
while going to school at the same time
but over those years i stayed active in
emergency services i did about five
years of
volunteer firefighting uh 12 years with
rocky mountain rescue group five years
on the copper mountain ski patrol
now 20 years as a federal disaster
responder
and for a couple of years i've been a
member of team rubicon and actually
deployed with them recently up to the
navajo nation
also got my paramedic back about two
years ago
so over this time period i built up my
it career
as well eventually starting securosis
and
the cloud security company disrupt ops
and i realize as i've lived these
parallel lives
one foot in emergency services one foot
in cyber security
that the lessons i was learning from
each profession
were helping me in the other profession
and to be honest
i think i got more out of emergency
services than i've gotten out of the
security industry improving my job as a
paramedic
and it's because there's a lot of
similarities between the two
i mean first of all they're both very
young professions
but when i first started getting
interested in emergency services i was
just a little kid and i was watching
this show emergency with johnny and roy
and it turns out that that was kind of
the start of paramedics in the u.s
back in the early 1970s that tv show was
actually about an experimental program
in los angeles
and that wasn't even covering the entire
city and if you tried to call 9-1-1
after watching that show
the odds were nobody's going to answer
even after the show went off the air in
1979.
so i became a paramedic about 20 years
after the profession started
when i started in security around the
year 2000
we were still in our infancy as a
profession as well
and we had really only been around for
10 15 maybe 20 years if you count some
of the government
aspects of it but that's just the start
of these parallels not only are both
industries
relatively new in security newer than
emergency medicine
we both have our roots in the government
and military ambulances start over in
the military in the battlefield where a
lot of what we have taken from i.t
security
actually started with government and
government computing systems because
they're the first ones that had the
money for computers
both professions also have their feet in
two different worlds
as a paramedic i split the difference
between the
fire and rescue world and the continuity
of care
and the medical world of in hospitals
and they're very very different
and that's really similar to how in
security we have the requirements to be
able to talk to and work with the
business
but we also the very technical aspects
of our job particularly those of us that
are dealing with
things like on the incident response
side and both jobs
are highly technical be it the years it
takes many months to years to learn how
to read an ekg
it's very similar to looking at packet
captures or writing code
and across both professions we deal with
incidents as well as longer term issues
although to be honest as paramedic i
deal more with the short-term incidents
but again in both there's the how do i
solve this problem today
to what are the larger issues that i
have to look i
look at to protect my organization or as
a medic to protect my community
but there's downsides to these
similarities the biggest being around
mental health
and burnout we have huge problems in
both fields
with burnout and with mental health and
i think it's worse than emergency
services
but we have a growing recognition of
burnout issues
in information security i think
the reason these two fields are so
similar is we share one really core
aspect the job is never done
we are always pushing the rock uphill
we're always treating the next patient
or solving the next incident
or securing the next technology and we
don't get that
same sense of satisfaction you might get
if you deploy a new application
or you release some new kind of business
product
and whatever our plans are in either
field
we never know when the meteorites are
going to come in and blow them apart we
don't really have full control over our
environment we're dealing with
a certain level of chaos and that takes
a certain kind of a personality
and so as i've lived both of these lives
and learned the lessons across both of
these communities
i think not only can we learn from each
other but i do think emergency services
is a little further ahead
uh the profession's just been around for
about 15
20 years longer than cyber security has
been around
and i think we can learn the lessons
from emergency services
emergency medical services and apply
those to what we do in cyber security
to improve how we do our jobs but also
to
help us in the long term to help us with
our mental health
and in the development of our careers
i've realized that there's
four phases to our career in these
professions
and not everybody makes it through all
of these some of us stall out at these
different steps
and i recognize these earlier in ems
but i think they apply to security as
well
and the first one of those is enthusiasm
because when you first start the very
first time i sat on
as a paramedic in that right hand seat i
can't tell you how exhilarating
it was and yeah my first call didn't go
very well but eventually my calls did go
out
by the way it's really important to my
kids that i tell all of you
that that's our cat his name is goose
he's very cute and yes he does wear a
harness
when you first start we're really
enthusiastic because
we had to do incredible things as
in ems and particularly after i got my
paramedic i got to fly around in
helicopters and
drive around with lights and sirens and
sit in the back of that fire truck for
the first time with the air pack and the
bunker gear on
i mean this is every kid's little dream
or many kids dreams
when we first get into cyber security we
have a real similar
issue we are we we have real similar
advantages
we're dealing with aspects of technology
that others don't get to see or play
with
be it hacking tools and packet captures
and seeing everything that's going on in
our organizations
so we're really enthusiastic we're very
eager to learn and we really want to use
these new skills
i mean when i got out of paramedic
school i couldn't wait to innovate and
start ivs and when we come out of
security training you can't wait to use
those latest tools
and to run a penetration test against
your organization
we're also really flexible in this phase
our minds aren't really locked into any
particular way of doing things we're
still looking for role models we're
still figuring out
you know how the profession works and
and how the job works
which means we tend to be inexperienced
because we're new
very task focused very skills focused
so what are some of the challenges that
we face during this time and one of the
biggest ones is the skills without
context
it's the i want to use the new toys i
want to use the new skills
i want to innovate a patient while i'm
wearing full hazmat gear
and that's great i've never done that on
a real patient in my career
although some of those skills are
actually helping now during the covet
era
but it's the understanding when to use
these tools we don't really yet and we
tend to over
treat and we tend to overuse our tools
and tend to over rely
on our technologies versus seeing that
larger context
another really dangerous problem is
picking the wrong role models
people who are burnt out and cynical
they have a particular magnetism to them
they come across as the old crusty seen
it all
done it all they are the han solo
characters that we try to emulate
but the problem is is they're not going
to be good role models
they tend to think rigidly they have
kind of turned their brains up to
learning they're in this survival
mindset
and so we have to be very cautious who
we pick for those role models
and so to get through these challenges i
think there's some things we can do
that will not only help us through this
enthusiasm phase to move on with our
careers
but actually you're building the
foundation for
the rest of our time in the profession
one of the first is
you just got to know the job as a
paramedic i have to know my protocols i
have to know my drug doses
i can't be messing around with those in
the slightest i may not always know the
context i may go down the wrong protocol
i may mess up an assessment
but if i fundamentally don't know those
it's a problem and in security
particularly for those of us on the
incident response side
it's really important know our playbooks
nor run books know our standards know
our technologies
you just have to know those that's level
one for being able to move forward as
professional
now one thing that's becoming more
recognized in the medical community is
the use of checklist
particularly for complex and harder
procedures i know i've actually started
building a lot of these
when i do security work particularly
hands-on so that i don't miss steps and
i don't make mistakes
because no matter how much experience
you have you might still make a mistake
this is a checklist built by a physician
who's
one of the probably the best in the
country at managing airways as for rapid
sequence innovation it's where we sedate
and then we paralyze a patient something
paramedics do it's something physicians
do and think about it they can't breathe
anymore so if i don't have every piece
of equipment i need
and through two or three layers of
backup equipment that i might need
if i screw up i can easily kill that
patient and
checklists are the kind of thing you
don't just use in the beginning of your
career
you can use them throughout your career
just go ask the nest pilot
next time you get on an airplane if we
ever get on airplanes again
now there's another skill that you want
to try to start developing at this phase
which is harder
that's the idea of zooming out is can i
take a step back and look at the bigger
picture
it's what i didn't do when i dragged
that poor woman out of her house
i was on a mountain rescue call once it
was a
kind of a sketchy on edge weather sort
of day and the call came in the
afternoon
for some people shouting for help
somewhere up in the mountains i mean
deep in the mountains just west of
boulder colorado
and nobody saw anybody her they just
heard the shouts for help
so a bunch of us went out and me and
another gentleman were partnered up and
we went out we were one of the
we're the second and third people out
the door with some medical equipment and
clothes
we're thinking we're out for a nice hike
you get these calls all the time there's
no one there
well somebody ahead of us called out on
the radio they found two patients
we got there pretty quickly and i had to
do the medical assessment
my first patient had an injured ankle
second patient two injured ankles and it
smashed his chest these guys were
trying to slide down a permanent snow
field lost control and smashed into the
rocks at the bottom
and the second patient he was pretty
banged up and he was having trouble
breathing
i looked up at the sky and there's bad
weather coming in
and we're losing light so i went over to
the guy with the injured ankle
i didn't take his boot off i didn't
assess his ankle i just made sure there
was no blood
no bone sticking out look how i go can
you walk he goes yeah go good
go with this guy and hike down the
mountain stop if you need help and call
for it on the radio
i zoomed out because at that point in
time the best thing for that patient
wasn't following my protocol and
treating that ankle which it turns out
was broken
it was getting him out of there as
quickly as possible before we had a very
complicated
complicated evacuation and the rescue
for his partner ended up being overnight
and almost resulted in a helicopter
crash
from the mental health side we also want
to start building our skills early
mental health skills need to be built
just as much as your technical skills
some of the things that can help find
positive mentors and make sure you
understand those procedures and
processes start learning why
you have those protocols the way they
are don't just know what the steps are
know why you have those steps
and start really learning continuously
don't assume because you got out of
school or you passed a few tests
that you actually know what's going on
medicine changes technology changes
there's always
opportunities to learn new things this
is also really important time to create
biased defenses
now this is huge in all public safety
emergency services as we've seen in the
news lately
when you're dealing with certain user
populations socioeconomic and even
racial classes
you can get a very biased view of them
because of the nature of only seeing
people at their worst
in security we face the same issue how
we look at our developers how we look at
different business units how we look at
auditors others in the business
i know we have a lot of biases i know we
like to victim blame
and the earlier you recognize this and
you don't get into that habit
the better and it's something you have
to fight all the time and then we want
to embrace this concept of
anti-fragility
if i'm resilient i can keep taking hits
and i don't change
it's like that simpsons episode where
homer simpson is fighting
the fake mike tyson and the only reason
he's in the ring is because he's the
only one that wouldn't
go three rounds without dying but if he
went to round four he'd die and
moe threw in the white towel and rescued
him with well they flew
out of the anyway it's the simpsons but
resiliency is you are inflexible and you
can take the hits
anti-fragility is all about thriving in
chaos and uncertainty
it's where you look for that uncertainty
and when something happens
you take the hit and you learn from it
and you adapt from it
and you move forward and it really is a
mindset that
mindset that i absolutely prefer
now the next phase is ego
as a paramedic this is where you're
going to get your first clean kill
this is where i'm going to make a
mistake because i'm burned out
what we found when i first started as a
paramedic i was told
average burnout per paramedic is around
seven years
nobody had done a study on that that was
just this person's experience
so if you think about it it takes you
one two three to five years to become
pretty good at the job
and then around five to seven years you
start burning out
and that's going to happen if you don't
actively manage
and try to prevent that burnout why is
that
well you've seen a lot and
a lot of things that are hard to handle
and so you you kind of stop
listening you jump to conclusions
because you're seeing this constant
repetition of the same things over and
over
your sleep can be affected there's
exhaustion maybe it's because
of the psychological aspects of the job
or maybe it's just because you're
rotating shifts so you've got too many
pager calls in the middle of the night
this is also where having a beer after
work
may become more of a crux and a
dependency because you're now
abusing substances as a way to escape
from the burnout and your
dissatisfaction
with what's going on and you're just
caught in this endless cycle
seeing the same things over responding
the same ways over in a very unhealthy
cycle
we can measure this something known as
the mask burnout inventory i actually
learned about this from
a couple of people in the cyber security
industry jack daniel and josh corman who
both took time out to give me some
results of a survey that they did
around information security and
uh josh actually did a great
presentation in 2019
with dr maslock who created the burnout
inventory
what we found or what they found is that
in security
we hit all three criteria we're red in
exhaustion
we're red in cynicism to the point of
where jack daniels says
cynicism is our core competence and
we're
low on perceived self-efficiency are we
feeling like we are making a change
that's actually split there are many
people in the security committee that
feel like they're
making a change those more in the
incident response side feel like
less like they're making a change and
burnout's something we have to battle
all the time
so how do we get through this ego phase
well it's a combination of
mindset and process on the mental health
side this is where we really have to
focus on the fundamentals
there's no surprises here people have
talked about this over and over again
you need to eat healthy you need to
exercise you need to sleep
you need to rely on more peer support
one of the great things that
we can do in some of the places i work
ems is for example
when i got back from my deployment to
puerto rico they
actually in the federal there was a
database someplace
where i got a call a month or two later
just to make sure i was okay with team
rubicon that's absolutely essential
there's like monthly buddy checks
to make sure people are okay and
mentally okay and picking the right
peers
can be a very large part of this if you
hang out with that cynical burnt out
crowd you're going to be cynical and
burnt out
think about it when you're enthusiastic
you're trying to impress those above you
but when you've been around for a while
you're trying to impress those below you
and that can actually
get into this vicious negative cycle
and then having workplace support really
helps i think we're actually better
on this believe it or not in security
than in ems particularly some ems
companies do a really poor job people
don't get time off they're low paid
they don't get a lot of benefits and we
do we just have more money in security
than people in ems have which helps but
both industries also have toxic
environments and we need to recognize
that and try to avoid those if we can
because you know ego burnout these are
rivers that are constantly eating away
at our mental health
foundations and we need to constantly be
rebuilding and refreshing those
foundations for our career
and this is why i say start with that
mental toolkit early recognize these
issues early
be aware of them because it's going to
be a better chance to protect yourself
from them as you move forward
now that feeds into some of the process
issues because some of the problems you
make and the reason as a medic i might
get a clean kill
at this phase is i stop paying attention
and i stop the fundamentals i start
jumping around a little bit
because i now have the experience to do
that this is where what i call second
level pathways or protocols make sense
these are the kinds of things that
physicians are often very good at
that we as paramedics need to spend a
little more time with
this one's from advanced medical life
support and it's a patient assessment
pathway
to make sure we're both we're constantly
assessing and reassessing patients
and we're not missing anything it really
comes down to you know making sure that
we introduce the right kind of processes
and we stick with those
even when we start being very very good
at our job
information security we don't have a lot
of these we have some stuff
in incident response we have some
written technical processes
but i think it's a real big place where
we can grow as a profession
to start really operationalizing what we
do
in both generic ways and in the
individual incident with the individual
technologies as well
and now at this ego phaso we are
competent at our jobs so this is the
time where we can really build some of
these advanced skills
uh i talked about zooming out keeping a
flexible mind continuous learning
uh doing drills and exercises this was a
great one we did
with federal government it was a top off
they called it where we did a simulated
weapon to mass destruction it actually
involved an attack in multiple states
throughout the u.s
so i got flown up to seattle and you can
see that i'm in the
decontamination tent and our full hazmat
gear taking a picture of the bus that
they fake exploded and threw onto its
side
as we're treating hundreds of fake
patients those are the kinds of things
that really make a difference just
drilling in and challenging us mentally
to keep us on our toes so we have the
flexibility to adapt to new situations
and the decisiveness to make a decision
and actually act we had an exercise once
where the person running it
got mentally locked up things didn't go
the way she expected
she didn't have that mental flexibility
as a result she didn't act
and that whole exercise fell apart
thankfully it was an exercise and not a
real situation
but i think we all know that it happens
in real life as well
the ego phase some people skip it and
some people never leave it
this is that really tough area and it's
the most
i think personally challenging
challenging phase to go into because
your ego gets pretty strong because you
know what you're doing
but you are also fighting those burn out
those mental health issues
and it can really be a bad combination
and it really comes down to your choice
do you want to move forward
or do you want to stay locked into that
negative cycle
because the next phase has its own
challenges and that's empathy
this is where you start seeing people as
human beings again
not as patients with vital signs one of
the first times this really hit me
was when i responded hurricane katrina
and we actually ended up in houston
where we
started off by triaging 900 patients in
three hours and they were helping
provide medical
care in the stadium where all these
evacuees who'd come out of
new orleans had gone to and when i'm
dealing with 900 patients
in a matter of hours i have to do
assessment after assessment after
assessment
it's important to remember that for
almost every one of them that was
possibly the worst
day of their lives that they were
experiencing absolutely horrible things
and really i'm not going to be providing
much medical care
most of them didn't need any medical
care but what i could bring in is
empathy and kindness
make them feel like human beings as
they're being shuttled around and
treated like meat
on these buses making just that small
difference in someone's day
when you start earlier in your career
you don't feel personally rewarded
by making those kinds of small
differences but i really think that
that's what
separates the true experts in our field
from people who are kind of younger and
earlier in their career
but it's tough because you have to learn
how to empathize without
sympathizing too much what's the
difference well
when i deployed down to puerto rico
things had been torn apart
and we ended up in a series of our
disaster response tents in the parking
lot of a hospital we were functioning as
an icu
we had a patient come in with diabetic
ketoacidosis
uh dka which is high blood sugar versus
the patient i talked about earlier with
low blood sugar
and this woman she was actually from
florida she lived now in puerto rico but
she was originally from florida
of course florida we'll get there no
offense to our watchers from florida
but she came in with the high glucose
and she knew she was in a hospital and
she quickly became drug seeking
and she wasn't very kind to us as the
staff even though we were trying to
treat her dignity and respect because
however horrible it is in her drug
conditions and everything else
she still had probably lost her home
like most of the other people they were
dealing with and there was certainly no
electricity or clean water around
well at one point the
flight nurse and i who are treating her
talk to the physician assistant who was
responsible for her overall care
and he said just give her the meds or
like she's drug seeking you don't give a
drug seeking patient
uh opioids and he goes look guys
we're not changing her life today we're
not going to change her life decisions
today
we need to treat her get her out of
our room open up that bed for somebody
else and us withholding that drug isn't
going to make that situation any better
and so we did and i learned
that day to be able to empathize and
treat her like a human being
without once justifying her poor
decisions
and this was hard because i was starting
to suffer from compassion fatigue
compassion fatigue is really different
than burnout think about it is we have a
gas tank for empathy we have a gas tank
for compassion
at a certain point you're going to run
out of fuel and the more you get into
this empathy phase
the more that you're going to be
challenged with compassion fatigue
because you can't just close yourself
off like you do when you're burnt out
and compassion fatigue is very well
recognized
within the medical industry there's
something in the compassion fatigue
project
i've got some links actually that that
will go out with this presentation
and a lot of it comes down to the
regular same mental health fund
fundamentals now with compassion fatigue
it can be very short term
i did not get compassion fatigue when i
was treating those
hundreds of patients from hurricane
katrina i did get compassion fatigue
from this one patient who was just
sucking my life out of me as i was
trying to deal with her and as she was
trying to get what she wanted
out of the system and so it's really
important to recognize that and i'll be
honest we're
really bad at that in security we
like to blame victims we like to blame
business units
when the reality is is in many cases
maybe they are making the wrong
decisions
but maybe if we listen and try and
understand why they're making those
decisions
we can better manage the situations and
be better professionals
at this phase our skills actually do
really have the potential to start
ramping up so if we can get through
these mental health and the empathy and
the sympathy
we know our fundamentals cold we
hopefully are still learning we have
those flexible minds we've kind of
graduated from making those ego-based
decisions
and one of the things that we can start
doing more is moving from pattern
matching
to reasoning this is something i'm still
really working on as a paramedic
i think i'm better at it in security
these are those medics
when i look at them and if they hear
hoof beats they can tell the difference
between a horse and a zebra
from across the room because they're
actually able to think through
the situations instead of just looking
at the blood values and assuming
they are what they are they actually
think through the problem and understand
the physiology behind it
that really just does take a lot of
experience a lot of time a lot of
continuous learning
so this is something that we can strive
towards and we can do this in security
as well
i think it's one of the things that's
helped me a lot in my world when i'm
dealing with
cloud security issues is i know the
fundamentals of my platform so well
and i can kind of reason through why
things are working or not working the
way they are
and as a result i am able to better
assess risk and be able better able to
manage risk
now the last phase is enlightenment
no not cosmic enlightenment but
at this point we are hopefully
anti-fragile
because you can't get through everything
that i've just talked about
unless you have learned really strong
coping skills
because either you become anti-fragile
or you burn out
and trust me just because you burnt out
doesn't mean you stop working
but you're not going to be a positive
influence on your coworkers
your patients your organization and
we're have kind of a balance as well as
a better
perspective because of all those years
of experience and working through these
issues
now at this point we have a lot of
baggage
i see some pretty horrible things as a
paramedic plenty of dead bodies
dead kids maggots smells
rotting flesh like i don't want to go
into it you don't care domestic violence
is probably the one that really gets me
the most or one of the ones that gets me
the most
it's pretty bad but i'm okay and i'm
okay because
for me what i've managed to do is
compartmentalize
and everybody has different techniques
to do this i use context shifting
i try and keep work at work and then i
have
my home life and my non-medical career
and my hobbies on the outside and you
really got to break those apart
if all you do and we we call them
sometimes the rescue randy's in the uh
in the emergency services community
where they work all day and then they
volunteer and they take pages all night
for another agency
that's not sustainable you have to have
the ability to turn it off and go do
other
things and compartmentalize that
particularly if you're working in busier
areas
when you do that in security as well we
need to shut the laptop and spend time
with our families
those are things that really help us in
the longer term mental health and the
people who really
are in this for the long haul and who
are basically well balanced
you can see that and how they work we
also
start focusing a bit more on outcomes as
opposed to just
inputs and protocols and numbers in
medicine we call
science-based medicine this is a a
combination of you know what if a new
study comes out and and
you know with all the new covid stuff
coming out this is what i look for
is there a plausible scientific basis is
there evidence to support it the actual
numbers and
are there good outcomes because you can
actually have a plausible scientific
basis
and evidence but then turns out the
outcomes are really bad
i think we're actually terrible at this
in security we don't do randomized
control trials
rely on vendor numbers of of uh
vulnerability counts or
surveys or malware variants that have
been detected we don't do a good job of
correlating
uh we don't have controls we don't have
p-values randomized controlled trials
and it's hard to do that but it's not
impossible to do that clearly if we can
do it on human beings and do it
ethically
we can probably do it in security
without placing our organizations at
greater risk
a great example of this came out
recently it's something called the
paramedic ii trial
where they actually looked at thousands
of patients who got epinephrine
pre-hospital in the ambulance when they
were in cardiac arrest
and it turns out we as paramedics are
very very very good at getting
heartbeats back
if i catch you in the field probably
within 10 minutes of you going down i
can almost always guarantee you're going
to have some kind of a heartbeat when i
drop you off at the hospital
but are you going to walk out of the
hospital it turns out the answer is no
there's actually
no difference between placebos and
epinephrine in patients who
survived with an intact neurological
outcome we were getting heartbeats back
and creating very expensive icu patients
without necessarily actually improving
that overall patient's life
and this one study is not going to
change medicine we're still going to
give epinephrine because now
we need to move forward to the next
level and figure out what are the
different circumstances
what are the different mechanisms of
action why does this work why doesn't
it not work and is there still a role
for epinephrine and it's going to
probably take us a decade
to answer those questions but that's the
difference between science or pure
evidence based which
is if you want to know the difference if
you look at those studies for food
supplements that you can go buy at some
of those
you know at some of the nutrition stores
they have a lot of evidence and studies
but they're like
us letting the vendors tell us if we
need to worry about malware
an example of this is we force
people to reset their passwords every 90
days even if they have multi-factor
authentication enabled
i just did work for a client i think it
was every oh it was every 90 days
does that improve security well if they
have mfa turned on
probably not and it is adding
complexity into a situation without
necessarily improving the outcome
and if we're really good we've moved up
at this point into management and we've
looked at these issues and we have a
better understanding of our profession
and we're mentally healthy and one of
the things that
we can really use do to improve is look
at just culture
just culture is about creating
anti-fragile workplaces so with just
culture the idea is it's the opposite of
blame culture
if we find that there's an error that
somebody made a mistake
do we blame them for that mistake or do
we take the anti-fragile approach
and find out why that mistake was made
the classic example of medicine
is medication errors paramedic i work at
three in the morning
in bad light i'm now 49 years old so i
don't see as well at night as i used to
some of my medications depending on
where i'm working they come in vials
that have the same colored tops
in the same shape vial and the same
fonts on the labels
it's very easy for me to potentially
make a mistake and if i did make a
mistake
in a blame culture environment i'd get
yelled at for not checking the
medication for not
making sure that i was giving the right
patient the right medication at the
right time
in just culture they're going to find a
different vial
they're going to put a different color
on the top or maybe we'll put a piece of
tape around it
so that we know the difference so that
i'm not making that mistake it's about
improving the system
it's not about necessarily finding
somebody to blame
again an area we have a lot of room for
improvement in cyber security
if you use the word shadow i.t you don't
have a just
culture you're blaming users for using
technologies that they think they need
to get their job done
why are they going around in some cases
it could still be recklessness it could
still be negligence
but in other cases maybe we're just not
giving them the right tools or not
understanding their needs
enthusiasm ego empathy and enlightenment
we don't all go through these phases and
we don't all go through them in the same
timeframe it's just a way of thinking
about it
myself i don't think i'm in
enlightenment in emergency medicine yet
i think that moving to a part-time
paramedic has
inhibited my ability there's things i
still don't have fully internalized that
i would like to in terms of my practice
but i think i've nailed the empathy
recently i was up in the navajo nation
helping with the covet response i was
out there with team rubicon which is an
amazing organization
and we had one patient that came in
every night alcoholic
the police were dropping him off because
they were just finding him on the street
wanting to get him out of the way
or he'd wander in because he wanted a
place to sleep this guy's brain was
fried
but he was a nice person and
we i would not have treated him as a
human being earlier in my career
i didn't have the right role models for
it i didn't even think about it it was
just another drunk getting in my way
but i tried my best to treat him with
empathy and compassion
and so did the rest of that emergency
department to the point where people
brought in clothes
and then one night myself at and the emt
that i was working with
we actually stripped them down and we
cleaned them off with wipes
this is not in any paramedic or nurses
protocols
unless somebody's in the hospital for
days or weeks we cleaned the guy down
i even trimmed his fungus ridden
toenails because the thing is is
we weren't going to make him not an
alcoholic we were
not going to be able to change his
long-term life decisions
i was not going to justify any of those
decisions but
he was a human being who was having a
really bad time
and the best part of that was i got to
do it with this emt
and maybe hopefully i was serving a bit
as mentor
because if you make it this far into
your career
i think we have an obligation to be that
positive role model
to help others throughout their careers
mentoring is one of the best ways to do
that
thank you for your time that's all i
have but i do want to close on one last
note
we are in the midst of for me what i was
trained in
as the worst possible case scenario and
things are pretty bad out there so i'm
just going to ask
pay attention think of others and please
wear your mask
protect yourself protect your families
and protect those of us who have to come
out and help you
thank you
hey everyone so thanks for watching the
session this was uh
um it was a big one it was an emotional
one for me to do this after
a few years so i'm gonna blab away until
we have any chat questions
uh for me i think for infosec
professionals
i try to cover a bit about like the
lessons i learned about incident
response and
and kind of some of those skills i think
those have absolutely helped me in
security
but i think particularly for those who
are high level managers the
just culture concepts uh that that come
in at the end
is probably where we need to focus um
you know i think that that's where we
can really start to make
systemic differences uh into
our environments and and actually you
know again if you're in a managerial
position like i get to be
uh these days that you're actually able
to go through and and make changes and
induce that kind of a positive
environment
uh you know they
all the other bits i mean um the mental
health the burnout
i think also with covet and what's going
on are
definitely it's definitely hitting all
of us i mean the the repetition of being
home all the time
is you know this is some of the same
things that we see when you're running
on calls and everything else
um by the way i appreciate all the
comments in here um
you know ask questions we got a couple
of minutes left if you have
anything else that you want to hear
about uh you know kind of
uh what went into putting this one
together and everything else but i had a
blast i mean i was
i spent like two three years planning
this um i think like you're saying who's
watching this and a few other people
uh you know many uh conversations
usually at black hat and defcon and
frequently
uh let's just say well alcohol abuse is
bad a little bit at
your conferences and stuff uh isn't
always bad if uh
if you're okay with them you know kind
of over those late night drinks talking
about a bunch of these concepts and
and trying to put it into that framework
of those four phases those were all like
things i really tried to do
to kind of bring it in and i i honestly
until i started seeing the feedback you
guys are standing here i didn't know if
anyone care about this stuff
uh you know it's not the same i'm used
to giving technical talks and
you know and defensive technical talks
so i think am i out of time guys um i
did put the link in the chat room if you
want to go ahead and
carry on a conversation but otherwise
enjoy the rest of black hat and
maybe we'll get the chance to meet each
other they meet up again next year
hopefully we'll be having this stuff
dealt with by next year
with the crispy role models yeah if you
identify you're the crispy role model
it's time to get mental health
actually uh that's a um
you have to take a step back separate
yourself and i had that i got in trouble
at
the stuff at securosa's my partners had
to talk to me because i was going down a
bad path unfortunately they did and i
instead of fighting back i recognized it
and i recognized my own issues
uh took some time and was able to come
back uh
so with uh
i got 10 seconds left so i'm gonna have
to answer the other questions over in
the zoom
i'll pop it over again but um yeah there
were a couple of other questions
uh yeah and thanks for the uh eric for
the the extra camera thing was a
bit of a risk but i think that played
out all right thanks everyone
and i'll see you maybe over in the zoom