[Music]
hi
everyone my name is from the city of
life i'm glad to have this opportunity
to share this topic with you
and we know because of the exist of many
mitigations in android nowadays it's
very difficult to
the most needed android devices but
today
i'll show you how i importantly use the
toughest android device
the pixel 4 at the beginning of this
talk
i want to introduce our team shortening
i am the team leader of 360 of lab
our main research fields are android
assistant security and
chrome broader security we have found
more than 300 vulnerabilities in android
system
we won the highest
reward in the history of asr program in
2017 because of the
express chain introduced in this talk
we have won the highest reward in the
history
of all google vrp programs in 2019
we have also had different targets in
different
porn contests
a brief look at today's agenda i'll
first
explain why google pixel phone is a
tough target
from two aspects the price paid by
vulnerability blocks and the
results of mobile. in last three years
next i'll introduce remote telescopes of
android devices
then i'll share my experience of
recording android device
six times in different competitions
next we will overview the exploit chain
name the tv zoom this can remotely use
a wide range of qualcomm based android
devices
include pixel devices after that
i'll detail the three vulnerabilities in
the chain
and how i change these three
vulnerabilities
for exploitation without any rp
at the end of this presentation i'll
demonstrate
how to get a reverse share with good
permission
or a piece of form by accessing a
malicious
link in android
which is the most secure smartphone
it's an open question and i think there
is no standard answer
android and ios are the two most popular
mobile operating system in the world and
there are too many arguments
about which one is more secure
there are different answers from
different perspectives
if we ask the questions from the
perspective of their price paid by
vulnerability blocks is since now
android is
more secure than always
the audience pays up to 0.5
million dollars for android fcp there
are click
express chain which is higher than
rs fcp zero click export
chain
if we assume android is more secure
than ios the remaining question is
which is the most secure phones among
android phones is easier to answer
than the previous one google pixel phone
often have more updates also versions
security patches and vulnerability
mitigations
than other android phones which makes it
more difficult to be attracted
as shown in table
the pizza phone is the only device
that will not pond him welcome to all
competitions in another three years
while iphone will pronounce seven tasks
in total
all other android android devices
include the sensor galaxy huawei
mate p-series xiaomi mi
devices were found several times
in the contest too many exploits
demonstrated in the contest target
android
devices existed in australia
os component or unsecured
customized code so we can conclude that
pixel device is a
tough target
before i talk about my exploit chain
i want to give you a telesurface
analysis
of remotely compromising smartphones
as shown in the picture the most attack
of smart remote attacks of smartphones
can be divided into two categories by
a target victor it hurts through
internet and attacks
through adjacent network
normally speaking attacks that
vulnerabilities in brothers arms
and emails can be launched through
internet more more evenly
it has that exploits availabilities in
nfc
bluetooth wi-fi and the baseband
are mostly launched through adjacent
network
attacks from internet is more
destructive than it has from
hs network but the former often
needs some instructions such as clicking
a url opening an email or instance
message
is relative easier to launch i tag from
adjacent network without interaction
than from the internet product home and
blue bone are amazing
adjacent network attacks it's hard to
say which attack is more harmful
between zero click adjacent
adjacent network attack and one click
internet deployable attack
the exploit chain are used to remotely
use the piece of phone is a
one-click internet deployable attaching
this table summarize some remote
working support chains from the by me
started android
in recent years in mobile control
2015 upcoming lesson 6 with a single
variability
a force to get rce in chrome render
process
then attend this rc into a uss
vulnerability
so any javascript could be injected to
google play websites
any apps any gap could be installed
right
in front of rama 2016
upon enjoy the phone with a single
express chain
the express chain also started from a vs
bug
combined with a chrome ipc weakness
the webview in android had no standpoint
at that time
by exploiting the v8 bug again in a
review
chrome samples could be bypassed
easily this thunderbolts escaping method
that doesn't work
anymore because webview is sandbox now
is it also unboxed now
in front of us 2016
i found a pixel xl
with a single vulnerability once more
the method is
similar to point on
2050 house confessed
2016 google
output updated their
remote apps installation features to
prompt their user to enter their
password
which makes this form of attack
difficult but
it took more than a year for them to
mitigate this kind of attack
and of chrome 77 such
as nation has been enabled on android
devices
it's nearly impossible to navigate the
rce2
uss method in mobile.
2017 i found a galaxy s8 with two parts
an oob ass bar in sensor internet
browser and a
use of a map variability in sensor
essentials gr lock module
and can create a reverse share with
system user permission
through this exploit chair in 2018
i found a piece of phone with two parts
fbs engine bug is used to get rc
in sun post render process above
in android devices
module is used to escape from
chrome's sandbox together this
express chain can be used to inject
archery code into system server by
accessing a malicious url in
chrome in 2
3 and 19 upon the first three
with three bars and then this explode
chain
t window
so what is t window tv zone is from a
very famous
chinese kung fu story and these come for
all people
to move upward swiftly and
effortlessly as if clouds are the stairs
the explorer chain includes three bars
which are just not the cloud styles of
tv
zone
the exploit chain is composed of three
bars
two chromebooks and one qualcomm kg sl
java bar
the attack vector is malicious links
once victim access a
weblink conjured by attack it
has they target can get a reward share
with the permission of the
intellect form this video
shows how to emotionally get those
permission
with the use production first
orb aspart in v8 is
exploited to achieve remote code
execution in
a chrome vendor process random process
runs in the
sc seniors domain as needed app and a
harness and post
for example if it can't access the gpu
java territory
cbe 2019
10567 is about in core contribute java
but it can be tweaked
directly from isolated
isolated app domain in order to
trigger this problem we need to escape
from isolated
abdomen with the help of
cve 2019 5s70
firstly it is a use of free
vulnerability
in the media component a
compromise the render process can
trigger this vulnerability
through module call by exploiting
this bug archicad can be
executed in chrome privileged process
this process runs in the synx domain
on just the app it can access gpu driver
i'm going to detail how to exploit
these three bugs separately
first let me introduce the rce
vulnerability
this bug exists in the tokyo of chrome
vs javascript engine
we add the code stop assembler
provide no newer primitive
as a thin abstract abstraction over
assembly
we as a tokyo is a we as
a specifier a specific domain
specific language that is translated
many javascript appears in functions and
the objects are
implemented by vlog
talk this figure shows the build process
of
talking code if there is any bug in
toggle code it will be
propagated to generate the css
csa code and then to the generated
structural
file in the end the snapshot file
is embedded into chrome to speed up
the initialization of all built-in
functionality in v8 heap
before we talk about the rc bug we have
to know
the js function memory layout first
this function in columbia is the
internal representation of function in
javascript
the sound of these objects in vs is not
fixed
it may contain the field the product
type orientation map or not
the field prototype or initial map is
the last field of
js function if it has
this is the field information of the
function
how prototype slots
means the area function has a field
prototype or initial map so it starts in
the 64 parts this is the field
information of the function
pass in it has no prototypes node
so itself is 56
but in most situation
if a function is a constructor
it has prototypes not
if a function is not a construct it has
no prototypes node
but there is an exception
the function proxy is a constructor
but it has no prototypes node
so the bucket here the token macro
credit derived map didn't check
whether the argument's a new target
contains a prototype or initial map
and the analysis is directed so it's out
of boundary access
it's easy to trigger the bug you can
only
need one layer of javascript with the
code
as shown on screen you can create an
untapped array with the refresh dot
construct
to trigger the bug refresh dot construct
we are called a token function create
type
array this function we are called a
variable
macro credit derived map
because the new target argument is set
to the proxy function
so the obsess will be triggered
but if the above javascript is wrong in
chrome symphony nothing special will
happen
although the obsess has already occurred
it is because that
after loading proper prototype prototype
or initial map
the value will will be treated
as a map is construct
constructor is loaded and compared
with a target
and in most situation this value is an
illegal map
but its constructor is not the same as a
target
so execution flow your bare altitudes no
pass
everything is normal if revenue isn't a
map
execution flow your bare other tools no
past two well it's fair to
to be cast today to a map because of
because there is no path we are will
make all the assets use needs
to exploit this bug
the execution flow must return a map in
fast pass
so here is the exploit strategy of this
park
first we have to free the objects below
the
proxy function then we
occupy the free space with an object
with map
whose maps the construct is unit at ua
we need this map for x
and then drop all reference to map x
so the graphics connect will mark the
map else and capture and we also sweep
it
in schedule the sweep task
then we trigger the obs part before map
x gets
swept by gc so the developer
creative map
after sweep task finished we
occupy the free space of
map x with a map whose construct is
you enter 32
l.a so because a smartphone tablet array
is marked if you enter
32 anyway but there's no odds especially
if the element hand
is you enter at a later it's easy to
implement optional read and write with
this smartphone
object with the ability of
archery reader loads we can enable
module
js binding and exploit the following
module variability to escape from chrome
samples
next i'm going to introduce the eop bug
chrome use a multi-processed
architecture it also needs
render process from other privileged
process
and the pictures show the main process
that runs the ui and manages types is
called the broadcast
process the gpu process is a process
used when chrome is displaying
tpu gpu accelerated content
likewise the type of specific
processes are called render processes
normally render process has the noise
the privilege
the gpu process and the broader process
have high probabilities random processes
are highly standardized and main and
many interaction between then and the
system are processed by all the
privileged process
in android render process run the unit
only associated app
the gpu process and the broad process
run in the domain
on trusted app the rc park
according to a random process while the
eop
occurred in the gpu process the
communication between processes
the vrpc there are two rpc systems in
chrome network cmc and the module fc
module is chrome's new ibc system
the eop plug can be triggered by a
module confirm render process
is a url vulnerability in chrome's
media component it is related with the
interface of content decryption
module this module and our chrome to
play drm protected html file
video and audio the idl format of the
content decryption module is shown on
the screen
the function in night ring is
responsible
for initiating the ctm
if it is narration succeed
cdm ide will be no zero
and we are later he used to locate
the cm at the remote side
the initial function is implemented in c
plus plus if initialization succeeds the
function on cdm created
will be called this functional code
the cost of the variability is that
there is no restriction to
the number of the cause of the function
initial
if this function is called twice by
through module call in debug version
this detector will be triggered
and all cdm created
will would it be called a twice two
which without the same
module stem service would be reduced
to us in a function or cdn create
created
in the function we twisted the end two
cdm
ids will be mapped to the same
module module stem service in nav4
when module stem service was distributed
only
one cdm id was unregistered
and removed from the map
cdn services the other steam id was
mapped
to a dangling point
after that if the function kills dm
contest level code with
a formation that's dmrd
the uf would equally null 6. modus dm
services
can be configured to be run in different
process
it can be configured to run in the
broader process
the gpu process it also can be
configured to run in utility process
desk desktop chrome
is a desktop chrome config
configure um ctm service
run in utility process
utility process is a highly sandboxed
just
a render process so it can't be
exploited to escape both in desktop
chrome
but anakin mojo stem source is
configured to be run in the gpu process
by defaulting android
so we can exploit this part this bug to
access the gpu drive directly
the usf object is a module cm service
itself is small it has only
48 parts
there is a lot of noise in the heap in
this cell range
so it's hard to be occupied through the
modulus stem service objects will
control the
data now a member pointer
point to a large object this type is a
meteor drm bridge the cell is
[Music]
bytes in debug version and
160 but in relation
her release version we can
we occupy the memory of the free the
media diamond bridge
you'll use the control data
so we can control its water table
alright it is a water table
with this snack we can use rp to finish
the
exploit because there is another problem
we can't we can't allocate memories with
no
address in gpu process
so we don't know where the water table
coins
can can be modified 2.2
we need another information disclosure
bug
to fake a volume table with no edges
then we can finish the exploiter group
however it's not a good choice there is
a
simple simple solution as we know
random process and the gpu process
have the same memory layout in android
they are focused from the same process
so we know the best address of most
shared library in gpu process the shield
library
new llvm geo next
use as system function
so there will be a system function point
in
in this child library after it's
loaded now if we modify
what your projectile pointer to point to
near system function point
when you have a clause the system
function is called
the argument is a controllable tool
we can use this simple method
we can use a simple method that we tend
to leave
c to execute any share command
in gpu process so we
escape from the chrome sandbox
next i'm going to introduce the root
vulnerability
the google plus phone has an adreno gpu
it's
used ktsl driver developed by
qualcomm the picture
shows the architecture of kgsl driver
apps can create adrenal context with
different
priorities normally there are four
content context priorities
0 1 2 and 3 0 denotes
the highest priority and 3 denotes the
noise the priority
each adrenal context is bonded to a ring
buffer
depending on its priority because
adrenal context have
four priorities there are four ring
buffers
relatively there are rb0 rb2 of
3 and r4 similar
as cpu has different
pre-regional gpu current in different
mode
adreno gpu can run in two more two modes
primitive mode and unpredicted mode some
pages and
register can only be accessed
or modified in privileged mode
after an app creates an
arduino context the app can send the gpu
command
to the context by our control
each context has a command q
they receive the gpu command are killed
the dispatcher is the core
module in ktsl
it stands in a
separate separate kernel thread
the google pixel phone has an adreno gpu
it's used the ktsl driver developed by
qualcomm the picture shows the
architecture of ktsl java
apps create apps can create adrenal
content context with different
priorities
all right
the pix
the google pixel phone has a adrenal gpu
it uses the ktsl driver developed by
qualcomm the picture shows the
architecture of
the kgs driver apps can create
adrenal contacts with different
priorities normally there are four
properties 0 1 2 and 3 0 denotes the
highest priority and
read loads the noise priority each
adrenal context is bonded
it bonded to a ring buffer
depending on its priority
because adrenal contacts have four
priorities
there are four ring buffer win buffers
relatively 0 rb1
r2 and rb3 similar and cpu has different
priority level gpu can
run in different mode
arduino gpu can run in two modes
the mode and unprivileged mode some
pages and
registers can only be accessed and
modified in privileged mode after a map
created create an
arduino context the app can send the gpu
command to the
context by our control each context has
a
mod queue the received gpu command are
queued the dispatch is the core model in
ktsl it runs in a separate
cloud thread and keeps reading commands
from the queue and
submit sub submitting them to win
bubbles
after commands are submitting to a rim
buffer the
red point of the ring buffer is updated
now the gpu executes some
commands the reader point is updated by
gpu every context
use different page tables but some pages
are mapped globally to all contexts
contest
this list shows all globally mapped
pages in pizza form note that
scratch in that file is a globally
mapped page and
we will exploit it later some pages in
this list
are not only mapped by gpu but also
can be modified by cpu scratches above
this kind of page
the scratch memory is a it is one page
data that is mapped into the gpu
this can offer some shared data between
gpu and
cpu for example it will be used by the
gpu to
right update the read point for each
member
the format of the scratch is showing
this table the fourth six
sixteen parts are the middle point of
the
four ring buffers
and therefore information the real point
of rim buffers are stored in scratch
scratch memory the scratch memory is
mapped in gpu space and
cpu space reader pointer
since read point of sensitive
data for ktsl driver the
travel read reads read points
when allocate buffer from ring bubbles
but this scratch memory is running set
to drag table
by normal gpu command processor
instructions
in this function
in this noun the function ktsl allocator
globe
allocate a global memory without read
only
and privilege the flag
so rptr's can be modified by gpu command
processor
by gpu command processor instructions
in on privilege mode
in a function in a functioning arduino
invert for a local space the variable
iptr is
the variable rptr in nav5
is a reader from their scratch memory an
rptr can be modified to any value
the function can be conjured to return a
wrong
ring buffer point
as with that we can override the eagle
these command process
instructions and inject initial command
processing
instructions into ring upper to execute
so how to exploit this file there are
few public documents about the internal
architecture of
arduino gpu you can only speculate some
internal behaviors of the gpu
rpts in the scratch memory are updated
by the gpu
but in the sense that there are there
are just
shadows of read point used by the gpu to
fetch instructions modifying the
rptr in the scratching memory don't
affect the effects of the execution flow
of the gpu
knocking it affects the canal allocation
space for rim buffers
rptr points to the next instruction
which will be executed by
the gpu and the wp2
red point and the other point point to
the
start of a free space of a
bubble there are two scenarios
of the positioning of reader peter and
the red media
with a picture less than
less than or equal radication or reader
picture
not than not peter
when real point is less than or equal
to red point if there is enough step
enough space from right point to the end
of the
ring bubble allocating is simple we just
need to advance red point and retain the
original
blood point if there isn't enough space
towards the end of the ring buffer you
have to look
for space from the beginning of the
ring buffer up to the read point
if there is enough space advance a
red point from the beginning of
it advance the red point from the
beginning of the
window otherwise the allocation will
fail when windpoint is not on
red point if there is enough space from
red point
to midpoint we just need to advance the
red point and return the original red
point
otherwise their allocation will fail
midpoints in scratch alpha can be set to
any value
by normal gpu installation because of
the
bug so we can follow the allocation
function as shown on screen
assume that after gpu executing some
instructions rptr is less than
less than wptr a request of
locating a knowledge space will be
is issued because of the space at the
beginning
and the end is small the request
will fail if we modify rtr in scratch
memory
for example advanced is near
wptr
then some space will only mark as free
as this moment if another request of
allocating energy space from rim buffer
is issued
it's real succeed but some existing
command processor
instructions will be overwritten
the the adrenal gpu will execute the
instructions still from the
the original rptr without reducing the
without him executing on another
instructions
it means executing from the middle of
uh instrumentation choose some
data of the instructions or code
so it's possible to inject arbitrary
command process
instructions into rainbow for a week
large optical data to ring buffer
when gpu instructions are dispatched to
rim buffer
cp indirect buffer prefetcher
instructions
are inserted into ring buffer by ktsa
driver
gpu instructions provided in euler mode
are in into the bubbles
they are not copied into green buffer
directory
the execution flow will jump to
integrate buffer when
cp indirect buffer prefetching
instruction is executed
it's difficult to write arbitrary code
into rimba
narcany we found another party in user
profiling command
user profiling command is used to read
the gpu tickets at the
ancestor and the end of gpu command
the gpu address of the profiling buffer
is accountable by user mode and
can be set to any manual gpu address is
a
8 parts it's enough to write a
cp knob or cv cell protection mode and
charge into it
as shown in the picture it's
it's a cp instruction sequence of
executing
our control ktso tpu command
cp introduced buffer professional
instructions
instructions are loved by other
instruction
instructions such as instructions to
enable and disable
protected mode instructions to start and
end
user profiling if protest mode is
disabled
gpu runs in privileged mode
many privileged registers
can be modified protected module
can only be disabled by cp instructions
which is runs in rim buffer cp
instructions
executed in each directory buffer have
low permission to
disable protection mode
as mentioned before we can execute a cp
instruction from its middle
so we can exploit the bug as shown in
the picture
before we trigger the bug the layout of
a ring buffer is shown on the left
the first the cp indirect buffer
prefetcher
will jump to uh into the buffer
in this buckle there is a cp with
regular
is junction which will wait until the
venue in a specific
gpu address to become a specific
value at this moment i assume the
condition is not satisfied
so read the pointer the reader point of
view
point to the next
cp induced buffer prefecture instruction
then we trigger the power in
about in the highest priority contact
context
so we can preempt
the weight instruction to
modify feeder pointer
near to to near wptr
which distills the gpu kernel
gpu cannot drive into think
the space before with the pointer
is all free then we
execute our control kt seo gpu command
two times to override the ring buffer
as shown in the middle the gpu address
of
the second and the fourth user profiling
command
are carefully designed as a cp
nope instruction and a cp protected
model is charging if the weight
condition is satisfied
at this moment after execute executing
some refreshed instructions
cpu knob instruction will be executed as
shown on the right
cpu no instruction will unlock all the
instructions until the cp says protected
mode
the cpu says the protection instruction
via disable protective mode
so the cpu induced buffer professional
instruction will jump to
it deals a buffer with protect will
protest off
with protector off
now we can change ttpr
to any value by instructions in
individual buffer is a powerful
primitive
we can exploit to read a lot of
arbitrary
physical memory including core segments
in kernel
is easy to improve
together archery cannot call the
execution
at the end of my presentation let me
show you a demo of the
huawei blood chain
first we launch a web server in the
attack's
computer then the victim form
accesses the monitor's link because in
a reverse shield will be
established please wait for a moment
okay we get a reward still
then the target can execute
the downloaded binary file to exploit
the
total variability to get a load share
we run the root exploit
you can see we have loot commission
and the uh this is disabled
i show the conclusion in this
presentation i
first explained why google pixel phone
is one of the most
secure smartphones then i
introduced the remote telesource of
android
phone and the sixth android express
chain
funded by me over three years after that
we overviewed the express chain which
can
importantly do to the modern android
devices include google plus phones
as not detailed three vulnerabilities
in the chain and how i exploit them
okay that's all for my talk thanks for
your listening
any questions
okay hello
okay thank you everyone for your
listening for my
talk if you have any questions you can
contact
contact me online
and i will be very
happy to answer that