because uh
uh as as an employer
i don't i don't want to see deputies
going to fake calls
at 100 plus miles an hour to get
somewhere when somebody says i'm just
checking your response time
that doesn't that doesn't work well
because if one of your family members
was t-boned by a deputy
you'd be mad especially when you found
out it was a fake call or something like
that they needed to be rested
you're going to try to break in period
lock them up i don't care you know
we didn't do it we didn't charge these
two gentlemen for
because we wanted to or we were trying
to make a statement there's nothing
political or
all these things these comments that are
being made none of that stuff came into
if you look out there i've never made a
single statement period
never done a single press release never
done anything
you know this is a confusing case
hopefully it'll wash out at the end
[Music]
this belongs to the corporate county
this don't belong to the state mm-hmm
the world's a dumpster fire and
everybody's mind is gone and if they
hadn't said
something these guys would have just
been
forgotten no other than without the
public pressure maybe
their their case would have gone a
different way i don't know
um
nowadays lawyers still want to squash
people and say never talk
but if you don't talk everyone else is
talking for you
and it gets worse and worse
hello everyone i'm justin and i'm gary
and we are senior security consultants
with coal fire systems
we are here today to talk to you about
the chronicles of iowa
and the events that unfolded there
hopefully we're going to dispel
a lot of the misinformation and myths
that may have come up and coming to the
media's light during that while we were
legally gagged so without further ado
we'd like to walk you through the
process
well not being gay all right to set the
stage let's go through some of the
engagement details so this is a scoping
and charter process that takes place
before we're ever brought onto an
engagement when the client contracts
with coal fire
they fill out some forms that details
overall what they're looking for
in this particular engagement it was a
red team engagement which covers all
attack services but the one that we're
most
concerned about today is the physical
engagement this is where the client
wanted us to come on site test security
of the courthouse's judicial buildings
things of that nature
and from that process see if you can
plant a drone on the internal network
and then do the internal network
penetration test down the road
so when we're discussing the physical
engagement details the client was
specifically requesting please focus on
after hours testing we want to see what
can be done
in a real life scenario like that and
some of the confusion that happened in
here
was the hours in the daytime the daytime
testing versus the evening testing
what was released in the medium
partially from the client's perspective
was
well we didn't want nighttime testing
and we didn't want after-hours testing
was only supposed to be during the day
hence
the day in the evening the reality of
that story was when they first came to
us
they only wanted physical pin testing at
night after hours
the actuality of what changed was they
said
after speaking to us in the charter
calls you know what we really do want
social engineering during the day
we want to test some of our employees we
want to do it during the day so can we
add day
and evening to that testing to make sure
that we encompass the social engineering
so the truth of that story is originally
it was night
we changed it and amended that to day
and evening to encompass the daytime
portion
of the social engineering and to
cooperate our story was actually five
people on the phone it wasn't just
us and the client there was two out of
the three clients came
um came to the charter call along with
myself
justin another pintester who actually
didn't make it due to family issues
our project manager and the director all
of them ended up giving out testimony
all corroborating our stories saying
this is exactly what happened just as we
said it was
from uh from at least five different
viewpoints from us
yep all aligned in that in that idea um
so another point of contention that
kind of crept up again related to the
hours when judicial branch accused us of
being out of scope or testing when they
weren't expecting it
was the default boilerplate template
that we have in there says we're only
going to conduct network penetration
testing between 6am and 6pm
when we're on the calls with the client
of course it's understood and we
communicated with them
when we're doing a physical engagement
this is likely to occur over 24 hours of
the day
as long as that's amenable to you and so
we kind of clear that up and that's
where we put that field that can be
during day and evening
in relation to the physical penetration
testing where all the virtual stuff
we've done before that
was within business hours um another
point to that as well
is the social engineer or the letter of
authorization rather
uh scoped us to begin testing on sunday
so
if we're coming on site to iowa to
assess government buildings
nothing's going to be open on sunday but
that's when we're slated to begin again
because the client wanted us to test
outside of business that's important
that comes up later
all right so these are the target
locations client had outlined five
locations that they wanted us to assess
we did walk through these individually
we asked questions like who's going to
be there after hours if we encounter
anybody are there armed guards what's
the maintenance crew look like what is
it what is the cleaning crew schedule
look like
um and we have specific uh limitations
on some of these locations so some of
those did arise like the criminal
justice center
client told us we only own a server rack
inside this building we do not have
authorization to perform a physical
penetration test
but what you can do is a social
engineering exercise go in
ask them flash them a fake business card
see if you can gain access to the server
closet
other than that the restrictions were
placed around the judicial branch
building don't access floors three or
four or maybe open a door and take a
proof of concept that you guys could
access that
but don't actually go in as far as
anything else it was full scope
access reach facility and try to gain
access to the internal network
and show us what other vulnerabilities
you find while you're on site and this
in this
conversation that we're having with the
client isn't isn't a
quick conversation this is line by line
building by building address by address
what exactly do you want us to perform
in this building what are the hours you
want us to do it what's in scope what's
out of scope
per building so if there would have been
a miscommunication which there wasn't at
the time
it would have been fleshed out in this
call because we went building by
building
exactly what was in scope what wasn't in
scope per building
now what makes it into the actual
contract is a little more generalized
which is why we have the scoping call
let's learn from this record your calls
yeah very important all right so we have
a number of parties involved of course
there's coal fire the company that we
work for there's gary and myself who had
charges pressed individually against us
that makes an important legal
distinction that we'll see there's a
difference between the company that
you're working for and when charges were
pressed against us as individuals
you have dallas county which was
primarily comprised of sheriff chad
leonard and the county attorney chuck
cenar
we also have the iowa judicial branch so
our three points of contact that we were
working for mark hedley
john hoover and andrew shirley and
there's also going to be a special guest
appearance from somebody that we'll see
later in the presentation
all right so now what we're going to do
is we're going to run you through kind
of a real
quick uh story of events on sunday
monday and then
a little bit of tuesday before we
actually went to new dallas county
to the fabled courthouse sunday we hit
the ground running uh we were there
again like we had said before
our third teammate had some uh some
family health issues with one of his
relatives
so he couldn't actually come and the bad
part about that is is he had
the drone that we were gonna use so we
were still waiting on the drone to come
in the mail on i think it was
supposed to be there monday or tuesday
which is why we ended up going back to
the polk county courthouse later
was to set the drone in the server room
so sunday we hit we hit the ground
running
we we go after the polk county historic
courthouse
we get in we get in through uh bypassing
it bypassing a door
and then we hit all flags we're probably
there until one or two in the morning
something like that
um all the value that the customer was
looking for and then some
uh we were able to get in that single
night so for the most part outside of
coming back there and placing the drone
that was done and then
monday justin will go into all right so
we wake up the following day
um that's our first full day while we're
on site so we decided to drive by all
the locations make sure the addresses
match up to what we're seeing online and
talking with the client about
and we just verify everything's there
during public hours we are able to
access the judicial branch
and the dallas county courthouse during
business hours we're able to walk
through see some of the stuff
in judicial branch we're escorted by an
armed guard who didn't let us leave
inside and then for the dallas county
courthouse it's open public access so we
were able to see some of the floors
and the purpose of that is to walk
through get an idea of what we're
working with so when we come back later
that night
we know how to approach it and what to
be looking out for so the real me of
tuesday is we enter and we breach the
judicial branch um
actually we arrive on site we're outside
working on a door for about 10 or 15
minutes
when a state trooper arrives so this is
kind of expected behavior
um the client had informed us there are
patrols after hours from 5 pm to 6 a.m
at this location
you may run into state trooper so he
arrives says hey gentlemen how's it
going as we have tools inside a door
we look back and say hey officer how are
you he's like great uh just
checking what you guys are up to is the
security testing we say yep we're hired
by coal fire um and hired by the
state judicial branch to test security
of some facilities here he says great no
problem that's pretty routine we
actually do this testing regularly
sometimes they give us a heads up before
this
this time they didn't but do you have a
business card is there some way you can
verify yourselves
so give him a business card he's
satisfied and that's the end of the
encounter
um afterwards we end up making access we
make uh entry
into that building um we go through and
again we start
elevating privileges checking off
findings indoors like we're looking for
clean desk policies
uh seeing what a malicious actor could
do while we're actually inside and
telling the client how to remediate
those vulnerabilities
so throughout this process we end up
getting into the iet offices
where we find our point of contact's
desk uh leave a business card there for
him
next morning first thing in the morning
when he walks in he sees the card and he
shoots me an email he says
well i guess i owe you congratulations
i'll be curious to see how easy this was
um well we didn't find out until later
right at that same time
uh he actually pulled the guys together
all our points of contact they reviewed
the footage they saw how we got in
what tools we were using what we
performed while we were on site and most
importantly
the hours and nature of testing so
offensive in nature after hours
and they didn't raise any flags they
didn't decide to call us and say hey
stop testing this isn't what we were
expecting
because we were performing the contract
exactly how they requested yeah and you
couple that with
our our get out of jail free card
started on sunday
and so you couple that with we're there
on sunday already outside of business
hours we're already
we're already doing that now we're in
this other building outside of business
hours we're testing they saw us there
they gave it a congratulatory emails and
we're really looking forward to the
engagement
so now we've already have these all
these green flags as far as
we're concerned that everything is going
well and everything is great up to and
including
the state trooper that showed up on time
they gave us the time he was supposed to
be there we were expecting him knowing
that he could come around the corner
any minute and lo and behold just when
our client told us that this trooper
would be there
the trooper ends up showing up and so as
of right now to this point in the
engagement
everything is going along perfectly
exactly how it was said in the chart
right so we wrap things up on monday
night end up with the judicial branch
the next day tuesday we come back we
breach a few more facilities so at that
point
we have reached three facilities no
alarms have gone off that have prompted
a law enforcement response it's just
kind of happenstance that we ran into
the state trooper earlier but we're
becoming very concerned okay we're
assessing government facilities
no alarms are going off whatsoever and
we did notice there is an alarm panel
from our walkthrough during the daily
hours at the dallas county courthouse
they do have an alarm system in place
when we go up later tonight
we're hoping that alarm goes off and we
actually see a police response
misguided hope yes yep 2020
learn some lessons all right so now to
the meat of the story what everybody
really wants to hear is what happened to
dallas county
we got there at about 11 30 on tuesday
night 11 30 on tuesday night which would
have been september 10th
um we walked around we did we did just a
a a brief walk around
the building just to make sure that
there was nothing wonky going on we come
up to the front door which by the way if
you turn if you're looking at the
building like this you turn around
the sheriff's department is literally at
our back as we're looking at the
courthouse so
it wasn't any surprise that the
sheriff's department was right behind us
uh we go and justin grabs the door and
the door is actually open and we're
like oh my goodness look at this but of
course we're not there to
to walk through open doors we're there
to make sure that the the building
once in a secure state is actually
really secure so justin closes the door
we're able to bypass the door we get in
and we hear the initial alarm go off
which is that 30 seconds or so that you
have
when you open the door the alarm
triggers and then you've got that 30
seconds to actually punch in the code we
tried all the default codes that we knew
offhand none of them worked and so
eventually the alarm goes off
in which case we said well how would you
like to proceed let's just hang out wait
and see
if there was response because again
there hadn't been any response up to
this point
we make it to the third floor we bypass
a couple doors we're in a courtroom
and at which point we look out and there
is a city police officer that has
already spawned
wick responds time too probably the
fastest response time
and give credit where credit is due the
fastest response time we have ever seen
like literally literally three minutes
um so
we talk about a little bit about what
we're going to do what we don't want to
do is we don't want to surprise
any police officers or get surprised by
police officers
for everyone right it's not what the the
scenario you want to be in so we walk
out we walk to the stairwell we shout
down a couple times
are there any officers in the building
we're here performing a security
assessment and we hear nothing this
probably goes on for about
five to seven minutes at which point
we're sitting down we're waiting we're
listening for doors to open nothing ever
happens
we make our way downstairs and what
you're going to see in this clip right
after that
right after this is that initial initial
contact with the deputy sheriff that's
on the south side
um of the building which is the opposite
door of actually what we came in
what you don't see in the clip or
actually here in the clip is when we
come down down you'll see our hands go
up like this the sheriff
the deputy sheriff looks at us and i say
would you like us to come out or do you
want to come in
and he actually waves us out which is
why we come to the door open the door
and then we begin talking all right
let's take a look at that footage
i've got them here in the south side
how's it going good we just came to find
where security we work with
coal fire and the court system had us
they're having us test all the buildings
they're what having us
i saw the car out there so we thought
we'd come find you yeah to come out and
go through all the
you know yeah is this a little bit yeah
30. well yeah there's nobody here at 12
30 while we come here at three o'clock
when there's a bunch of people here
okay you guys got your id's with you yes
sir
[Music]
yeah they're good to go i heard he was
in routes
i think dispatch well yeah they call
checks
where's all that information it goes
sounds like you guys are good thank you
all right so what you just saw there
just in case you missed it right
is they let us go the deputy asked the
other w they are good are we waiting for
the sheriff he says no we're not waiting
for a sheriff they're good to go
he walks up to us and says you guys are
good everything checks out we've talked
to your contact you guys are great
the reason that we stuck around is we
were actually having a really good
interaction with law enforcement
they were asking us a ton of questions
they were asking us how we did things
how we bypassed stuff
craziest stories switching area trading
war stories between law enforcement
officers and us
it was actually a lot of fun which is
why we were still sticking around there
was probably
nine law enforcement officers on the
steps of the courthouse it was
it ever it was really jovial we were all
smoking a joke and having a good time
um and then that mood suddenly switches
and it gets
much different real quick uh as soon as
you see the sheriff arrive body cameras
start going off
the mood dramatically changes and we
start losing a lot of profession
so let's take a look at debbie and
that's what you're going to see right
now
is some body cam or black drug
so their job is to walk around in a
professional burger
this ought to be good
maybe i'd better shut my videotape off
all right so the sheriff has arrived on
site and this is when he decides to
wrongfully arrest us so his um
rationale behind this is that this is
the county courthouse the state doesn't
have the authority
to provide us with the authorization to
assess this facility
and because of that we were going to go
to jail for burglary now if you know
anything about law
you can't have burglary without intent
and whether or not the judicial branch
did have the authority to authorize us
to perform this testing
we they they assured us that we did and
we had no intent of committing a crime
we had intent of
executing on our engagement and facili
fulfilling the contract
according to the judicial branch's
wishes now what's also interesting about
this
is that despite all the lectures that
were given that night about this being
county property and not the state
there was actually an independent review
by a law firm performed at the request
the judicial branch
that took a look at the standing
statutes and history of case law in iowa
and what they concluded was that it is
actually likely the state
that has the sole burden of providing
security for this courthouse
so what we're going to do now is we're
going to kind of set up the slide that's
going to follow which
is actually the slide the slide of our
arrest
what you're going to see is you're going
to see the sheriff talking to a couple
of his deputies
his deputies repeatedly tell him that
we've been extraordinarily cooperative
and you can see he's very flustered he's
he's throwing a lot
out a lot of bad language saying that
they don't have authorization that these
guys really aren't professionals
and the reason that we want to point
this out is up until the point where the
sheriff arrives
we are treated with the utmost respect
we are seen as professionals we're seen
as doing our job
we're questioned about our job asking us
advice on how to do things
the sheriff shows up and now all of a
sudden like we said before that
mentality shifts it comes to more of a
group think
and everybody starts following the
sheriff's lead like well these guys
really aren't professionals because they
used a very simple tool to get in
and that obviously isn't what a
professional would do so that
that starts to change a little bit and
then of course you're going to see in
the slide you're going to see us get
arrested we're going to go through
uh the the entire process very quickly i
might add
to the very point where the sheriff kind
of makes fun of me outside
in a hallway and again for somebody who
said this wasn't personal and it wasn't
political
it looks very different when you see
when you see the actual right
let him know
[Music]
they've been pretty cooperative so we
can just walk them over
okay
[Music]
it's all you never saw been in trouble
with the law since the day they was born
[Music]
oh yeah i'll go ahead and i'll let me go
grab my pbt and i'll take him out the
hallway and all running through
so there i am sitting in a holding cell
looking at seven years of prison time
and i the sheriff comes out right after
the the clip that you saw where he's
making fun of me in the hallway and he
starts questioning me on whether or not
i was a marine asking me
uh who my ceo was where i was stationed
at some point during that conversation i
say hey sir are you going to actually
charge us or can you just hold us
overnight until we get this figured out
he says no no you guys are absolutely
100 getting charged and then he
realizes i believe that i actually was a
marine and says
i hate putting a good marine in jail
this is his comment
to me so that that annoyed me a little
bit but from that point on we're able to
actually make phone calls so i make a
phone call and i get a hold of mark
headley
and what we're going to do is we're
going to play a clip for you right now
and i want you guys to make your own
decisions here your own judgment on
whether or not this really sounds like
somebody who was not expecting us to do
any after hours
testing whatsoever so without further
ado
all phone calls are recorded and are
subject to monitoring
hello is this mark higley yes it is
hey it's how you doing this is gary and
carol from coal fire yes
yeah we're in jail yeah i know i got a
call from uh
andrew and he told me about that
i okay doing anything i can't get ahold
of anybody from my company and this is
the first time i've been able to talk to
any of you guys
yeah well i got it i talked to andrew
and i had him and he's supposed to call
the sheriff back and talk to him but he
had a conversation with the sheriff from
the sheriff said that
they weren't budging because it was a
county building and
so there's not much i can do right now
until in the morning when i can get
somebody
to talk with the sheriff to have them
try and understand what's going on
okay so the sheriff incorrect in his
assumption or is he correct and if he is
so then why were we sent here
no he it is a county building yes he is
correct but
um the thing is is that
i figured that the sheriff would be a
little more understanding in regards to
it
okay so gary's made his phone calls he
gets through to people um
sets the wheels in motion and we spend
the rest of the night in jail so
following morning around 9 00 a.m
we're arraigned which the process as it
follows was we're handcuffed to our to
our wrists the chain goes underneath
through a belt in your waist
and then down to your your ankle cuffs
so chained up all the way and then we're
strung together and we are paraded
across the street in downtown adl
to the courthouse that we've just broken
into early that morning
uh gary's first up on the docket so when
he goes in front of the judge
i start explaining immediately she says
uh
first first they ask you know what's
your name where do you work how much
money do you make and
basically to see if you qualify for um a
public defender when you realize that we
didn't
qualify for a public defender she looks
down at her docket and sees what i did
and she is instantly enraged you broke
into this courthouse
into my courtroom and just starts
berating me right there
when i finally do have a chance to speak
i explained to her i said man this is
just a big misunderstanding
i work for a cyber security company
called coal fire we were actually
contracted by the state to come in here
and do
a physical security assessment of this
building and she
halts me immediately says you must think
i fell off the turnip truck i must be
the dumbest person alive etc etc etc
i'm just telling you how wrong i was and
if any testing
of of the sort was going to be done like
that they would have let her now
out of the 5 000 judges in the state
they would have called her specifically
and said
hey miss judge they're going to come to
your courthouse and they're going to do
this while you're not there after hours
you have nothing to do with security of
the building but that's the way that
that is so
i get berated by the judge and the whole
time
i am thinking this is insane i can't
believe that the judge
would would not at least listen to what
i'm saying
at some point she lets me talk again and
i look over and i say man because
if you're the judge the sheriff is
sitting right here in a bench with a
gentleman next
and i say ma'am the sheriff verified
that we were
sent by the state last night his
deputies had let us go and they had
verified that we were working under
contract from the state
and i look over at the sheriff expecting
him to say something and he's just
sitting back like this with a big grin
on his face and doesn't say a word which
infuriated me like you would not
understand so again she says you must
think i'm dumb you need to change your
story etc etc
and so at which point the gentleman next
to the sheriff stands up and i'm
thinking
because we had never actually met our
contacts in person
this must be the gentleman from the
state he's going to set all of this
straight
gentleman comes in sits down or stands
next to me
and looks at the judge and says man
these people are a flight risk i want
you to increase their bail
uh they shouldn't be allowed to leave
and so now my heart just sinks because i
thought for sure this was going to be
our client coming here explaining the
fact
that this is a big misunderstanding the
judge apparently completely agrees with
him and changes our bail from seven
thousand dollars each
to fifty thousand dollars so to give you
a kind of an
idea of what a big jump that is in case
you don't know
recently in the news there was a
shooting in seattle
in the middle of the street two of the
two of the people that
got trouble for the shooting actually
fled to vegas were captured in vegas
and their bail was said can you guess
that's right fifty thousand dollars for
murder
fair i don't know you decide um so after
that point
i i see what gary's gone through i'm
next online and once i go up
i kind of spell the same story and say
same result and outcome
uh bail has increased to fifty thousand
dollars so up from our original seven
thousand now collectively we're facing a
hundred thousand dollars and
bond um at which point we're walked back
to the to the jail um
up until that point coal fired been
trying to work with the state trying to
get them to go down and represent us or
at least
vouch for us which had not happened at
this point we found out they had
lawyered up
um so same deal early that morning one
one of the guys one of our point of
contacts had
uploaded a signed contract to the portal
it's something we don't normally sign
but they wanted our signature on that as
well
and that's the document they were going
to provide to the county sheriff to say
look guys this is all a huge
misunderstanding these guys are working
for the state
at which point i think they realize they
were facing
backlash from the county so it's very
clear that the county wanted to attack
the state
over the altercation that had occurred
and they subsequently removed that
document from our
portal which we call coal fire one have
all those time stamps um so at that
point we're back in the jail cells
um and now coal fire is working on
actually paying for for our bail and
posting bail for us so we can get out as
it's very clear that the sheriff isn't
going to let us go
and judicial branch is coming to the
rescue so we're in jail for
another 12 hours after that point for a
total of about 20 hours
we end up getting let go late that night
around 9 00 pm
um after coal fire was able to postpone
okay
so throughout this entire process we're
also having to remain cognizant of polk
county we were inside that courthouse if
we were arrested inside the dallas
county courthouse
it stands to reason that those sheriffs
that that county could have also pressed
charges against
us fortunately for us um they were a
little bit more cautious about things
they decided to feel it out get all the
facts of the case first before they
decided to press charges
um throughout part of that process they
they did want to
um give us immunity if they decided to
go against the state they they asked us
hey we'll give you a plea deal if you
guys want full immunity
testify against the state and we said
guys we're not guilty whatsoever we have
no problems
with any of this we have all the
contracts and documentation in the world
to back us up whereas
some other poor folks at the um
discretion of the state might be
run through the legal system and not
have all the resources that we have
but we know we're innocent and we have
all the documentation in the world to
prove it so we said
no we don't want any plea deals we don't
want immunity from you
if anyone wants us to come in and
testify and give the facts of the story
we are absolutely willing to do so but
it's not going to be to save our own
skins because we did
absolutely nothing wrong so at this
point the da is involved
and the da is basically saying
somebody's head is going to roll
i don't care who it is but somebody
needs to be held responsible for this
so this all kind of goes away he kind of
pushes it towards the lead prosecutor
for the county of for polk county
who actually is a pretty good guy he
looks at
all the evidence he looks at the uh the
detectives that are doing all the
investigation and says
justin gary are not guilty they didn't
do anything wrong he says there's no way
they are they they were burglarizing
anything
and even trespassing would be an
absolute hail mary
that i don't think we would absolutely
or we would we would win
in any court um so good on him for
taking the time and actually saying that
and he actually comes to a point
later on down the road where he tells
the d.a he says look if you want to
charge these guys you're going to have
to find somebody else
because i ethically and in good
conscience cannot charge them because i
don't think they are guilty of anything
so
huge thumbs up to the polk county uh the
polk county attorney thank you so much
for
at least having the wherewithal and the
common sense to
do your due diligence and investigate
everything before you made
um made your decisions so a couple other
things that happened during this process
is we had some threats from the sheriff
of polk county too because
our ceo tom had released a couple of
statements that you might be familiar
with that
weren't didn't paint the sheriff of
dallas county in the best light
um that made the other sheriffs angry
and uh he threatened us and said if we
release any more or if coal fire
releases any more statements like that
or says anything negative about any
other sheriff's especially the dallas
county sheriff
that they were going to come at us they
were going to take the gloves off and
they were going to come and punch it
uh we had that that happened as well um
later on through this and again we're
truncating something that took over six
months all down to this like
little like two minute little spiel that
we can go into um
at some point um supreme justice
katie comes in our chief justice katie
comes in
[Music]
non-felonious misconduct while in office
against against
the people who hired us for the state
are actual contacts that we're working
with for the state
something gets delayed that's actually
supposed to happen on the friday after
we gave
our um after we gave our testimony it
was supposed to happen on that friday
something happens the paper
paperwork gets delayed to the next week
and in between the time that we give our
testimony and the time that that's
actually supposed to happen
chief justice katie dies like straight
out of a movie the gentleman dies before
anything can happen
and right at the cusp of us being
completely vindicated through this
entire scenario
chief justice katie dies
and everything dies with you just
all right so at the end of this lengthy
legal process we have some personal
repercussions
uh at this point now we have permanent
felony arrest records anytime we're
picked up on the job assessing a
facility if police show up and respond
to our presence there
we provide credentials and our letter of
authorization they may totally buy our
story and be in agreement with us until
they
run our credentials which comes back
spelling arrest records
i'm going to be severely detrimental for
us to ever try to perform these types of
engagements
future there's a lot of stuff we need to
undergo for um
certain departments within the united
states or we're trying to pass a
security clearance
very unlikely we'll be able to do so now
with felony arrest records
uh we have our personal gear which we
bring on on site we supply all that
ourselves
that was held by dallas county for
approximately six months which had other
repercussions we were unable to perform
other engagements
we're advised not to leave the country
we had to give up on speaking
engagements in belgium and new york city
and mexico as a result of all of this
we are also stripped of our second
amendment rights so even for
months after after felony charges has
been dropped went to misdemeanors and we
shouldn't be able to acquire firearms
we still got status pending by the atf
we're
unable to exercise our second amendment
rights even after charges were dropped
entirely still had to wait some months
until those background checks were clear
and the people as much as we would like
to cry about ourselves
right who for us the people are actually
getting screwed here are the citizens of
iowa
you have you have a law firm
and politicians now that have made law
and passed policies within the state
that are more concerned with liability
and zero concern on actual security and
as much as we would like to share all of
the things that we found it would be
irresponsible not
unethical for us to do so but needless
to say
there is a plethora of things within
iowa state
that need to be fixed and they affect
each
person there significantly and that's
not going to happen now because
basically all
offensive security whatsoever has been
axed
in the state of iowa and that is the
real the real
crux of this issue and what what really
kind of chaps our high to security
professionals right
every one of us are kind of like you
know the good guy riding in by the horse
to save the day
like i think all of us kind of see
ourselves as that is trying to help
other people right we're
we're as as much as we like to do the
you know the whole the whole hacker idea
in our mind is
i think everybody in the cyber security
is very altruistic like we want to help
people
we want to make things better and we
want to protect them and that is
the exact opposite of what happened in
this entire scenario
and that and that's the real loser in
this whole thing is the citizens of iowa
so um the last thing that we want to
bring up is
is us actually having all charges
dropped
we had one final shot across our bow
right before our charges were dropped
and that was sheriff leonard coming to
us
and saying if i don't get to talk to the
ceo of coal fire
i'm not dropping charges i'm going to
press charges with this and we're going
to go forward
through your through your hearing as far
as as seeing if there was enough
if there was enough information or
whatever it is that they look for
right to make sure that we can actually
take him to trial
he holds us hostage and says i'm not
dropping any charges until i get to talk
to your ceo luckily our ceo tom is a
great guy and he says
dude that's not a problem whatever
whatever helps you guys out
but you have the same sheriff that set
up an awareness con
saying that it's not up to me i'm not
the one that makes these decisions
i'm not the one that's going to do all
of this this is all probably vegan
misunderstanding
i hope all of this fleshes out in the
end and when it came time
as as deviant's so eloquently put it
took time for him to either take action
or tweet and take a choice between which
one of those it was
he chose to hold us hostage and say i
refuse to drop charges
unless i get my way we have a video next
that's actually the final day before
they could actually drop
charges uh if they waited any longer our
emotion dismissed would have gone
through we would appear in court and
hopefully have things dropped
however the last final moment we
actually have on video which we're about
to share
i just got an email during the interview
that um
[Music]
thank you i've been sweating at the last
24 hours thanks patrick
[Music]
security workers charged with breaking
into the dallas county courthouse back
in september
are vindicated tonight kcci's laura
terrell joins us now to tell us why
all of the criminal charges against them
were dropped yes dallas county attorney
chuck cenard says after talking with
everyone involved it's clear that the
coal fire workers were doing what they
were hired to do
and that's test the security
[Music]
last but definitely not least we owe a
massive thank you to
our entire infosec family and community
we got to witness it firsthand there is
a family here
that we all are a part of and everyone
came to our rescue and for everyone that
did they were encouraging positive
discussion online
reaching out to us reaching out to the
lawmakers sincere
thank you for everyone involved right we
as soon as we got into jail
we walked we walked to our we walked to
our car
we charged our phones and as soon as our
phones were charged
we had literally hundreds of text
messages
voicemails emails like you name it it
came through from
people that we worked with the people
that we used to work with
to people that we trained with like
deviant who was like hey do you guys
need anything
we're here to help two people that we
have never met before reaching out to us
on linkedin and twitter saying
you guys need anything we're here for
you the community is behind you it was
absolutely amazing so thank you very
much
the last thing we want to bring up is
we're actually looking for some help
here we want to get a good samaritan law
passed so this doesn't happen to anybody
else
we have seen firsthand what happens when
a client decides to go rogue
and completely disavow somebody most
importantly we never want this to happen
again
so if you have any ideas if some of you
out there are lawyers or you know
exactly what we need to do to get this
this enacted please hit us up we're
including a link here on our slide
uh that coal fires so graciously allowed
us to have hit us up there
talk to us on twitter or linkedin or
however you want to get a hold of us
please
we're more than welcome or we're more
than happy to talk to anybody about
anything
uh concerning this uh more than anything
thank you so very much
and anything you want to say justin from
yeah guys just thank you so much for
attending this talk if you have anything
you want to add if you want to continue
the discussion
please get in contact with us we'd love
to hear from you but other than that
thank you so much for your time