[Music]
we'll see was too early for then this
was Thursday so is too early
take whatever work he needed with his
management we uh startling thanks for
checking this is this is great all the
power plugs the chairs have no no
[Laughter]
JavaScript
[Music]
so they might be showing up the blue
sheets making their way around yes very
good very good
good morning it's a Tuesday morning at
9:30 you are in cat port hopefully you
wanted to be in cat port I think dkg has
volunteered to be our diver scribe
Martin is taking minutes mm let's see
anything to deal with before we begin
virgin sings okay welcome to cat port
this is the note well as usual is this
the latest note well I never know
doesn't matter oh is that people
understand that it exists and that they
have responsibilities so it has been in
the past translated into Arabic without
people actually objecting so go to the
web page understand your obligations for
already any any agenda bashing I think
actually the the said that not on the
agenda explicitly is 7710 this but
there's the slide after this is about
that so the chairs section may expand
from administrivia to administrivia plus
7710 bists and take more than five
minutes any other agenda bashing
carrying forward okey doke so after way
too long a delay I finally got a - zero
7710 Biss uploaded it's missing a
handful of citations I need to find one
for content negotiation but it clarifies
that the URI that we're talking about in
77 this is the API endpoint says capture
portals may do content negotiation
depending on the accepts header in there
if they don't see cat port or whatever
the tell me you'll have to remind me
what the what the type is application
can't port JSON something captive - um
and we remove the recommendation that
you should use IP address literals and
we in fact invert it you should not use
IP address literals and I tried to
suggest that we use this u RN IETF
params kept port unrestricted as a URI
thing to to say district to let clients
know that they can just not bother with
Internet connectivity checks and just
proceed straight to getting on I don't
know if this is useful but it seemed
like a way to short-circuit or to
indicate that you could short-circuit
they kept a portal connectivity checks
there was the question of where
additionally this might be made
available in discussions with one
captive portal vendor last week it
seemed that the DHCP on link
infrastructure was not always under
their control in a substantial portion
of deployments furthermore in the ones
they did control changing DHCP
parameters might be seen as
exceptionally risky and so they asked
whether the capture portal API could be
made blue sheets anybody you know thank
you so they asked whether the capture
portal API could be available via some
means other than DHCP or Ras given that
they wouldn't be able to I asked if they
could deploy 7710 URL options in new
deployments and they said yeah yeah sure
sure okay um but it's not gonna deal
with the existing deployment base so
most likely most of it so could we do
something else and one idea that came up
was in the redirect HTTP redirect of the
sacrificial clear text could there be an
HTTP header that said not only location
: redirect destination
something about where to find the
captive API portal ed point I don't know
what people think about this this is not
in 7710 this but I do think we should
talk about it I can and fully intend to
send something to the mailing list about
this I don't know if you want to talk
about it now what people think about
this idea and I don't know what's
required for actually sort of requesting
an official HTTP header or X - the
strict upper cable love's no X - so so I
think we have a slide in the API URL
specifically talked about this the last
slide which is well I can I can give it
a rewrite say right now is like it was
just using the link header with a link
thing but it does all read a suggestion
in there I will see that in the HTML
content or in the header in the header
NH to be hitter okay yeah that's
actually it's it's great think is it it
tells you if the 302 originates from a
captive portal or if it's just a three
or two yeah definitely take this to the
list it sounds like there's some value
in this and I think - - X point there's
probably some way to to use this in the
API potentially as well and this should
be if if approved where should this go
in 7710 miss or should we leave them for
the API document for the API document
okay fair enough
thank you all right on to the next
presentation I suppose there we go tell
me your door sir
Gionta
now it is alright morning everyone
so I'll be talking about the captive API
stuff I'm Tommy Pauly halfway through I
think we're gonna switch with Tariq
because he has some thoughts out on what
you just mentioned about how we do kind
of the URI redirecting how we handle the
URL problem but before that I'll give a
summary of the latest updates to the API
document so there are a couple of
different changes that we've made in the
- l1 so one is that we have put in all
of the necessary I Ana registration
forms to get our captive JSON type so
application slash captive JSON is the
one that we chose by a coup and so if
anyone has complaints speak now so the
text says that the clients should
include this media type in their accept
header and a get request to say I'm
trying to access the captive portal API
and that the servers must mark this as
their content type in responses when
they are serving up the captive API JSON
so I think this solves the problem of
knowing what we're talking about we also
added a section on how we deal with
server authentication and the point of
the authentication here is to validate
that the certificate on the connect TLS
connection for the captive portal API
does indeed match the hostname that we
have and so this does assume to some
degree that what we are validating is at
some point presented to the user in the
UI as if it is some type of browser or
something about the network you're
joining
the overall recommendation is that you
should be using OCSP stapling here
because the other forms of OCSP that
require actually connecting back to some
other service or crl or that those often
conflict with the captive portal nature
of being captive you can do it if you
want but that is left as an exercise to
the implementer to deal with if they
want to go down that road and they
should just use stapling and we
discourage certificates that require a
ia and we also more clearly specify that
if there's any certificate validation
failure that the ue should reject and
ignore any of the information that it
gets on this connection and essentially
treat the network as if there is no
captive portal api present that does not
mean that captive portals will not work
you essentially fall back to the current
stance in which you may get redirected
and bad stuff may happen but it that it
is going to be a lesser user experience
than it would be otherwise and we can
live with that and hopefully people will
go forward and correctly deploy their
captive portals I have someone pitching
what should be the behavior of the Yui
if yours name is not presented to the
user circle I assume that all name is
presented to you is admonitory to put on
the earth name no I mean I think we
should still be doing the validation of
a certificate either way like that's a
good thing to do um the my assumption
here is I don't think this actually
stated quite like that in the document
my assumption is that the value of
validating this is that the user at some
point can recognize that oh this captive
portal at least is claiming to be
provided by Google or Starbucks or
whatever I don't know if we're just
valid like if if what we're validating
that indeed the captive portal is owned
by evil evil there's not a huge amount
of benefit to that
like actually what is the behavior of
the Yui if the hostname is not in the
certificate or Daisy they have no host
name for the server I mean essentially
we're just treating this like any other
certificate validation for like a
website thank you right just follow the
same project the hostname being
validated is the one in the cap for URI
correct yeah Lorenza clearly that that
URL it's just you know an a parent
communications endpoint and you know do
really need to present it to user I mean
what's it you know what does the user
gonna events from it there's no
information there that that's
potentially visible to give it the user
can understand and I mean we want
certificate validation for
confidentiality really but I don't see a
lot of value in presenting it to the
user
to be clear the document does not say
that we're doing this this is my comment
on the slide yes so Martin Thompson I'm
making notes and try to make comments at
the same time the the text in the
document and your text here I think mrs.
um mrs. the the key point look a little
bit the the important thing here is that
we have a long sequence of interactions
and hmm yeah the first one is with the
network and we kind of know that it's
with the network because it's DHCP or an
RA or something along those lines of
beyond that point where we're exposed to
all sorts of attacks and and whatnot and
then we're limiting the attacks from
that point onwards so that this
validation is essentially is tying the
thread between the different so for
instance
so when when you do certificate
validation in in TLS you do that for for
basically particularly I should yes you
did have one reason which is so that you
can say that your expectations with
regard to the identity of the thing that
you're communicating with Ahmet and so
we established those expectations when
we get the RA
the 7710 URI and from that point onwards
we want to make sure that no one can
violate those expectations and so that
is what has been provided here but in
the fact that we're following all the
standard best practices for doing HTTPS
and we like the confidentiality and
we've enacted it's using all the same
tools all those things are great but
fundamentally the the security property
that we're looking for here is that that
that continuity of expectations and
actually meeting them great very good
fun
this is dkg so I appreciate the view
from the network
you know like reasoning about the chain
of network events but the reason that
we're validating the the name is because
when you connect to a given network and
you think you're connecting to the
Metropolitan Transit Wi-Fi you want to
see that it's the user needs to see that
it is the network that is the
Metropolitan Transit Wi-Fi we do not the
point I was getting to here that that is
a way to go or to say like if I join the
Starbucks captive network that something
to indicate that oh yes this portal is
brought to you by the thing you're
expecting and it's useful and if we do
that via showing them a web interface
where you can put the Starbucks logo
like well sorry but I can put the
Starbucks logo on my home network and so
the so I absolutely agree that which if
the document doesn't say as you put that
as it should for the user agent if the
user is interacting with it the user
needs to know the name of the network
that it's connecting to you if the user
is not it is not doing any interaction
whatsoever then you don't show the user
anything but they have to be not
interacting with it on the basis of
something that they have maybe
interacted with in the past like if this
is with the dot Starbucks dot biz then
I'm ok
right but that but there needs to be
some linkage between the users mind and
what they're doing so that they know
what networks that connecting to right
right that's kind of the direction I was
going down here I do think that we do
need to clarify what point that Martin
made of the linkage because that's kind
of the fundamental thing for the API
linking with the rest of the
architecture but right presenting
something to the user is a good way to
make sure that
if they join something just because the
SSID looked to be like the thing that
they wanted that they have some some
level of confirmation that maybe there
is someone with authority behind this
one now Warren was before me or not I'm
gonna go after work okay yes so Warren
quarry I'm still a little confused when
I go to the Sheraton and get on the SSID
that's called Sheraton guest what
actually connects me is something called
room links like they've outsourced that
to room links so I don't really know
what I'm supposed to be expecting here
right like Sheraton room links who's
these people yeah what am I supposed to
do with this information now forensic ly
I mean this this URL just comes from
like an entirely untrusted source right
I mean we can say oh yeah like from the
point on where we get this URL which is
basically anyone on link can can send it
to us then yeah we're gonna validate
that I mean sure but I don't think you
know maybe maybe you could say I don't
think you can even say well let's check
that it was the last that what the one
we got last time because this stuff is
that as Lauren says it's out sourced all
over the place you know there's there's
things you know there's this SSID that I
connect to and it's got you know it's
it's cold Hills Wi-Fi and depending on
the venue it's provided by a different
operator with different captive portal
policies it's sort of kind of luck of
the draw really there's an interesting
deployment question because this is not
the same as the pager redirected to
right so you could even have the pager
redirected to being a different entity
than the one that's providing the API
maybe the one that's providing the API
is closer to what you would expect and
they outsource the redirect page or it
could be completely all the way around
stratum to the same host thing so that
because the user will see that one if
they log in to the network they will see
in their user interaction page they will
see a host name right you present it yes
I believe we do right but either way I
mean you could also present like you
mean
if we're adding the API support we can
also present that in that same portal
but we're in the UI you present to your
I don't know that's not so my job but
you know that the people whose job it is
are gonna be very hard to convince to
present to you our eyes right so I mean
what do we lose if we make it we make
them be the same hostname potential
flexibility of deployment Jeffrey Stehr
I think the point is not whether you
want to present the hostname to the user
or not the thing is what was said before
that I would disagree with you Lorenzo
that when you connect to the network you
sort of trust the configuration
information that you get from you from
your network so the HTTP arrays or PVD
you somehow get that URI that tells you
that there is a CAPTCHA photo API you
have to connect with it and when you
connect with it it is a good thing that
you can use TLS to validate that the
thing you're connected to is actually
the one that your network told you to
connect to the one right though the one
who is screwing with you by making you
captive and giving you this captive
information one is the same one who sent
you they are the dates be like they
they're in collusion you're proving that
they are indeed inclusion yes so I think
I'm gonna address I think the point that
you made like if you make the API host
the host and the same as that one we
lose probably a lot of actual practical
deployment scenarios I think because the
thing is it is very possible that the
captive portal API URL may be hosted by
some other entity compared to the one
that's providing the user page and not
the same house they may not be the same
host and second point is even if let's
say the host name may not be apparent to
the user so if the user connects to
share it on things at all it's from some
on link some something else that's fine
at least you have showed it to the user
right and then let the user ask the
question or decide decide if they still
want to continue or not we should at
least put a recommendation of saying
they should show it to the user so not
in function I think this is difficult
problem and even in the case where you
think that you're connected to Starbucks
and it looks like Starbucks it might not
be
as we we have this problem on the web
where the thing that is presented to you
doesn't always match expectations and
the the reason that's less of a problem
on the web is because you establish
expectations in how you type things in
how you get to them we don't have that
property here because essentially the
network can send you anything and it's
very very easy to use confusable x' and
all those sorts of other things too to
basically fish in this way and that's
not necessarily a problem in this case
as long as the primary properties that
we're looking for maintained
however there is there is still some
value in having this continuity and till
I saw the way because you have the
ability to do things like well okay so
I've got a password that I use with
Starbucks and now I'm under attack looks
like Starbucks but now your password
manager will recognize that this is a
different origin and not feed that
password in and if people are using
those sorts of tools as they should then
you you avoid some attacks the problem
with with taking TLS out of a link at
any point in this process is that you
open the door to all sorts of
interesting problems I don't think we
need to go there right and that's an
interesting point you bring up because
if we eventually do evolve the captive
API into something that doesn't just
require user interaction on a repo web
page and then we can do some more
automatic rejoining of things then yes
certainly the fact that we're validating
this will help us reuse whatever
credentials we had from previous
sessions I don't think anyone has
suggested not using TLS I mean the hotel
said that well I think bkg said is TLS
is worthless unless the user sees the
name and and part of me agrees with that
part of me doesn't but if we want to do
that I would really challenge people to
say okay so what deployment scenario do
we have where the the party operating
the captive portal login page is not the
same party
would be operating the API server
because I can see how the venue page is
not going to be the same page but the
the entity that is making you captive or
not surely should be the same entity
that's using the that's powering the API
no yeah tell me tell me more
you've seen all of David Byrd's
presentations on this stuff is it really
complicated yes I agree it's complicated
but those yeah okay so for those people
who haven't seen those presentations and
it was probably a few meetings ago he
showed some of the ways in which these
network architectures are built up
behind the scenes so you just see a
Wi-Fi access point and something happens
and what what it shows is that you have
you could probably find that one in its
IT f99
oh it's in the chest lights you want to
switch to that so he's the concern there
I think is that people who build the
overly complicated hotspots if they see
any impediment to doing these api's then
they're not going to deploy this thing
and we're not going to get any benefit
from having defined these things in
those networks and we're already at the
point where this is not this is a big
ask for these guys to deploy and you see
the picture here the portal and the and
the website sometimes different yeah I'm
not talking about the partner web site
at all
that has nothing to do with it that was
exactly my point my how much one is the
one that's being shown to be which one
are we getting redirected to today
that's being normally shown to the user
my understanding limited understanding
is that the the page that we redirect to
when we have to login is the thing
labeled captive portals it's the my
understanding now my or my limited
understanding and is if you clear that
captive portal you end up on partner
website generally speaking and so I
using require the colocation of the API
service
with that portal yeah I mean that like
we should yes exactly
we should check whether that's actually
and on and on you know cruel and unusual
burden right that that's that's the
point it may be that it's not because I
definitely see this perforation between
partnerweb side in captive portal but
can I can ask what do you think you're
gaining by having this restriction well
I'm trying to address the kgs point
about the user actually because the user
will see that login page when you log
into the captive portal they will see
that otherwise there's no portal right
because if they doesn't see right like
by definition if it's a captive portal
you it means that the user sees the
login page right but doesn't that
doesn't that simply mean that the the
operator of the network needs to ensure
that the page that the user ultimately
ends up seeing is one that they will
trust I I don't understand a question so
you could imagine I think let's say that
my API hostname is different from my
portal hostname and my API tells you
where to go for your portal and maybe it
sends you to something that looks good
but it itself as the API server is some
hostname you would not expect and so we
potentially redirecting you so as a
concrete example I go to the Starbucks
the you know mechanical details of all
of this has been offloaded to some other
provider and so that provider manages
all of the plumbing but they send you to
a portal page that redirects and
redirects and redirects and ultimately
lands you want a page that has the
Starbucks origin and shows all of the
nice things that you might expect to see
underneath the covers the thing that's
being presented to the ap2 over 70/7 10
or over the api could be anything and
sort of saying here that there's a bunch
of websites involved in this process I
see so you're saying basically you're
saying that captive portal could love
the the initial redirect it we couldn't
even if we enforce that the initial the
first 302 got sent to the same URI it's
the same hostname as the captive as the
api the initials leader you you might
just bounce off that not
something else and it would just be in
an undisturbed use it wouldn't even ever
see that anyway
right right right so this is dkj let me
just clarify why I think it matters what
this is if we are envisioning that this
is something that's going to provide
smoother more seamless access for future
connections then the the user the user
may actually never see the captive
portal page on a sub script connections
and so that captive portal page may
never end up showing up which means that
whatever your client is doing to decide
to navigate you through this without you
having to face the captive portal is
going to be keyed to something and what
it's going to be keyed to is this
invisible thing in the middle that we're
talking about validating and if that's
actually invisible than what you're
saying is the you know evil dot evil can
ultimately point you to Starbucks dot
with E and then you go into Starbucks
out with and you think you're going into
Starbucks but whatever registration set
up actually happens there it gets tied
by your at your end point to evil dot
evil so the next time you go to evil dot
evil you end up connecting there even
though you thought you were
authenticating to Starbucks that with E
right and so whatever the user is going
to see needs to be visible now I agree
with Lorenzo that these things should be
the same thing because showing the user
two different names is on top of the
SSID is confusing and users will not get
it so if the goal here is to communicate
something to the user these things
should be tied together well you could
imagine that if they are not then you
the UI highlights that in some way
another place where this could be
represented to the user not to go too
far off track for example in the list of
what Wi-Fi you're associated to because
this is actually potentially a longer
lived thing or something that's
happening automatically so essentially
your captive portal SSID could be
annotated with you know captive provided
by this with even potentially like a way
to like drill down into that and see
here's the properties the
were aware of on this network that look
like captive portal properties Chi
LaRue's just one quick thing I don't
want to make sure we don't lose sight of
this but we're not solving captive
portals only for Wi-Fi networks we're
solving it for wired networks or
cellular networks it's very not being
you explicitly connect to that's fair if
we have a button if we have an
affordance in the UI of any sort to to
let the user connect to the login page
after the fact then you know maybe
there's gonna have to be some space or
to see how much time they have left or
whatever oh the time yeah can I oh is
that in scope for this presentation no
we can let's probably jump back to the
normal slides and just clear out the
presentation that dark talk all right
this is very interesting I think we
should probably have more discussion on
the list as well great so these are just
a couple questions or comments that have
come up from the list when we got some
reviews of the document so far one of
the things that I think needs to be
further emphasized in the document as it
stands is that the list of keys and
information currently provided by the
JSON API is not exhaustive some of the
comments were like oh this is you know a
fairly naive approach of saying oh yeah
you have a UI portal you have the
potentially remaining time potentially
the remaining bytes I think we fully
recognize that at this point this list
especially the optional values to have
the remaining time or the rating bytes
is a bit of a strawman and it does need
some more nuance there and potentially
extensibility we can see that just being
something that we discuss in this group
as we are working on the document to
clarify that but we probably also want
some mechanism by which people can
extend the keys that they are putting in
this JSON format so I don't know if we
have thoughts about the appropriate way
to do that
have you enjoyed let me just define new
keys of yeah proprietor these people can
put whatever they want in here right
essentially is there a process at which
Oh someone like do we have extension
documents in which people just define
new keys I don't know JSON bits with
blobs of HTML to also please display on
that page oh yes right like does this
need to eventually become a registry is
a question that came up from this you're
basically saying do we need a registry
and if so should the procedures for
adding that registry be standards action
or or expert review or like email Tommy
oh yeah right there's potentially
direction that this takes us down and so
as a working group we will need to think
about that if that's something we want
to do yeah yeah well I mean we know be
like I don't think we'll survive iesg
review if there's no extension process
right exactly
yes something that will need to be a fix
that comes in a other version of this
document great the other thing that came
up I think based on David Byrd's
comments were you know what are some of
the edge cases what are the failure
cases here so just to review I think how
the document and the API stands today if
everything is working and centrally you
are advertising a captive API on a
network that is truly captive then
everything is hunky-dory we have a
pretty good user experience we are we
know where the portal is we don't have
to deal with redirects we can make sure
we present it to you and then the two
failure cases are the cases in which
maybe someone's advertising and captive
API on what would otherwise not be
considered a captive Network this is an
interesting question that was brought up
you could imagine this potentially being
a good thing in which oh yeah this
network has given you extra portal
information without blocking you just
too
give you some user experience but it's
also you know an invasion of the user
experience without potentially adding
too much benefit we've decided is this a
harmful thing do we need to worry about
this and then the other edge case is
that someone is not advertising the API
correctly on this captive Network and
that's essentially what we have today
it's also equivalent to having an
invalid certificate on your captive
portal API and we just could fall back
to existing behavior or there's an extra
edge case which I don't think is
captured by the bottom one where it's an
incorrect captive API listed and I don't
quite know what happens there
it's like so this time a server
authentication works out but it has
nothing to do with the thing that's
actually blocking you or it just doesn't
answer like it's listed but the captive
portal API server is down do you type oh
you sure do right I mean if it times out
I think then we essentially fall back to
existing behavior well so what you we
imagine is that this thing is governing
the behavior of like what we consider to
be like the captive interaction like the
sheet that pops up if someone goes into
a browser and just tries to load a page
they may still get redirected or get the
other behavior this is talking about
what is governing system behavior so
maybe it does to lay the system
automatic behavior Kyle arose regarding
a second one yes I could see in a
nuisance portal that just you go to
login as it no do bad no no no and then
what what does the user equipment do
does it just give up or does it fall
back on all behavior right well
especially if you aren't actually being
denied access to your traffic this is I
I think the the thing that comes out of
this is we maybe shouldn't you know
disallow you from joining that network
like we should make sure that your your
browser traffic can still go through if
it can right that we don't prevent that
or do we want to wait I mean do we with
maybe a timeout because we don't want to
just let it go through immediately
because then it was redirected if there
is it kind of cradle
um I think there's that and I mean non
captive Network could also be a network
the captive network that's currently
logged into right correct so I would say
number two is not really a configuration
error I mean I think that's my father as
well like it's just they're giving
information it could be a nuisance in
which case well I suppose if you do 77
10 and yeah then you could like if
you're just trying to essentially pop up
a random URL into the users face that
can be a nuisance if you can't I mean if
you get it from if you get it from the
302 than that you stand that nuisance is
basically Cher's fate with the nuisance
that you pop up the login page anyway
exactly right in some cases I think this
is potentially somewhat useful because
there are some services and let's say
like on airplanes in which I want that
that landing page cuz I want to know how
far my flight is along and all this
other cute little information but maybe
I am already allowed to use the network
and so how do I get back to that page
etc etc so this solves that say it also
provides perhaps an incentive to the
operators by providing a UI affordance
to learn more about the network or visit
the venues page exactly so I know it
seems seems reasonable I think yep all
right
this does also feel a fair bit like it
might be abused that every time I join
the network from now on somebody's gonna
pop up a shiny website for me offering I
mean I guess that that currently is kind
of a thing that kept the photos do
anyway but it feels like this might make
it easier to pop up I did you know that
we now dual Aragon say the fact that we
have a captive portal API and that we
joined the network does not necessarily
mean that we have to pop up the page but
because if we are aware that we're
already logged in hopefully we do
nothing so the question is if they lie
about being logged in what do we do
right that's true everything and what I
would say is basically the same thing as
Lorenzo said you ate well - anyway the
refer back to this case
but displaying an URL could also be a
frame of one picture by one pixel all
sorts of your viewport containing of
style JavaScript or whatever but this is
simply gets 302 right anyway no you need
to do seven seven ten if you want to
support number at case number two there
right right I mean there is value to
having knowledge about the state of your
captive portal without relying on
redirects like part of also this allows
us to not do program because the
redirect relies on something that can be
successfully redirected precisely so um
mountaintops exist in response to Eric's
point there the fundamental premise of
the web is that you can do that safely I
mean if we fail with that as we often do
that's on us as those people who provide
the browser's but there's nothing much
we can do about and then yeah we've
already established the fact that they
can do this anyways okay great
with that I'm going to turn it over to
director so we can talk about how we can
avoid using seven seven ten so I should
check or give elapsed so I actually had
some text also that was supposed to
publish for this but I wrote the text I
didn't like it so I didn't publish the
text but I think I want what I want to
try to do was just kind of throw it out
for discussion and see what people think
about it and then we'll see if that
makes sense so we sort of had a
discussion about this at the last idea
of I think Tommy brought it up in terms
of what should 77 10.2 right and so what
we are suggesting here is it can be like
let the network operator choose what
they want to publish in 77 10 or any
other equivalent mechanism right it's
their choice what we provide here is if
they are already advertising a captive
portal URI in 77 10 then we already have
the user
URL key that will point to the user
portal and the user can and you you can
actually find that if they want to
advertise the user portal then we
register in the API document are maybe
in the architecture somewhere we
registered a link header weight whatever
some link relation we can figure that
out and that one captive API whatever
right and that one points to the captive
portal so if the user actually gets to
if the you HOV just goes and receives an
actual you Hotel URL page it can still
look at a link header it can still find
out there is an captive API URL there
so you actually have kind of connection
both ways and then we don't have benefit
is we don't have to decide if you want
what we want to do with 7710 we may
still want to fix 7710 for other reasons
and that's fine but at least with this
we like we just give a suggestion and
let the deployer or the network operator
choose clarification that this would
this would also work with the 302
redirect yes the sacrificial one you
would use that you could use that in the
same context okay and you would get the
same information in the same way yeah
because one one of I guess the question
would be if the user ends up on a page
after a long sequence of redirects which
one of those redirects have the link
relation yeah and so I guess the answer
would be well any of them yeah exactly
yeah that may be a problem we can
discuss that yes that's a good point so
so Warren Kumari um let's say that I
join a normal network there's no captive
portal and I connect to the Internet's
and a browser arm for a while and then
eventually I stumble across evil example
calm and it includes one of these links
saying please go along and use this
capture photo API and come back every 30
seconds in order to make sure that you
still have you know time remaining and
now for the next you know three weeks
everywhere I go I'm happily checking in
and telling them where
this is this is part of like the current
you ease when you try to when you get
redirect to a captive portal knowing
that you are behind a captive portal
this is for those URLs to advertise it
to that not so right now so right now in
the uu right how do you actually
whatever mechanism we are using to load
up your special you know you're doing
your probing and whatever mechanism
using to find a special page is where
that is the idea that supposed to
provide this the URL back so I so I
would I would suggest the answer to
Martin's question is which of those
three or twos I would suggest the answer
is only the first one and the first one
is essentially the the same tofu model
at the the DHB URL has if someone is
able to manipulate your on link traffic
then they get to choose what you do yeah
so Warren kumari I think it's also but
it would have to be also not just the
first 302 that you see but you can only
do this for the first few seconds as
well because right you might connect
anoxia 302 for a long time yeah I don't
like I really don't hate the sacrificial
probe I really don't care about it it we
do it anyway we're going to do it till
the end of time pretty much I mean the
know from an implementation perspective
as well I mean the sacrificial probes
already there and in our implementation
it happens to be an entirely different
component from the one that actually
displays the login page which we don't
display unless the user actually
interacts and so there is a there's a
difference in terms of trust model there
as well so Eric Kinnear so just a point
on the captive probe if you're on a
portal that then later becomes captive
because your time expired or something
like that I don't think we can guarantee
that you always have a probe that's
going that is gonna come back so you may
hit a redirect sometime later for some
totally legitimate traffic
if you have it no that's not my name is
optional and even this one is kind of an
optional it's a shoot or option
available to the network operator so oh
speaking of which so option C choice
choice is good but it it increases
testing burden and it provides
opportunities for miss configuration
which agreed it you know B seems
restrictive in the sense that I tried to
argue for that about twenty minutes ago
I was like no that's too hard so let's
so that I think that leaves us with a
right I don't know well something
question it would be something me
destroy it and then it's up to we will
still have to provide some deployment or
some security guidance around when the
UE should actually look at it right so I
think the the trust model for the the
HTTP redirect is different from from
DHCP and R is a smart tofu because many
many hops off link might enter interact
with whatnot we would have to have some
guidance for this link relation saying
that browsers were not really supposed
to do anything with it except pass it
off to an operating system component for
subsequent evaluation yeah is that that
kind of thing that happens you enter I'm
saying yeah yeah I understand what he's
saying I think what Lorenz I was saying
was something different which is that
you make a request with an expectation
to be receptive to receiving one of
these things and when you when you are
receptive to one of these things then it
has meaning yeah in every other context
so here houses in particular would just
look at this and go huh link relation
like they do with all of them just about
and that's fine
I think that's actually a property we
would like it out of this which is that
unless you're specifically looking for
this information you're not going to do
anything about it I think that's really
going dead here I think that's them yeah
but what about the idea of having a
possible mechanism at the operating
system level or browsers could say I
observed a captive portal API link thing
you might want to decide if that means
I'm captive again yeah so does that make
any sense so we have a mechanism in
android
basically that apps can report you know
I don't have any working network
connection please please check it out
for me yeah and we redo the capture
portal stuff and sometimes the capture
portal is back and sometimes their
server is gone okay but but what we
handle it yeah Tommy just the the
conversation about having a very like
the specific probe that this is a
connection in which I'm trying to detect
a captive portal and I only want that
response if I'm I only want to use that
response if I'm doing this it makes me
concerned that you know if we add the
definition of the link relation and
someone just sees the definition and
they see come back and they don't read
that part of the document that yeah they
could end up doing the browser not at
the system level yeah but does this mean
that if we're doing our captive probe
should we add in like the accept header
for cap the captive API JSON like
essentially like do a probe for the API
as a next step thing - like when the
other side detects that are like oh this
is apparently what you want to get
redirected to it's this I think why not
yeah so you get your if you're doing the
program you get your program and if the
probe responds if you're getting a three
or dual right you can prop you can
choose to interpret that and go to that
URI and find out if there's anything you
want to use from the right I find that
like a captive probe has this format and
is trying to accept this thing so Warren
Kumari I mean maybe but the thing is a
lot at the moment a lot of
we'll spend a lot of time trying to
figure out what the captive portal
probes are and do special handling for
them with whitelists and blacklists and
things if you now include a thing being
like hey this is a captive portal probe
then they've got less work to do this
may be a feature or about the point
earlier about some only using the link
relation if we think that we may have
lost a captive portal is interesting
because it means that you know we use
the link relation it comes back from a
probe and then any other time we only
use it if we had previously seen one
from a probe we could make that kind of
the logic so yeah the OS is aware that
we're in a captive portal from it having
to previously it kind of breaks down
when you look at cases where maybe the
big kind of portal starts being forced
later on or it's being used for some
other purpose or something like that but
so I think that was one of the reasons
why I probably didn't even put the push
because as I started writing it I mean
this actually literally apart from just
I guess registering the link relation we
will probably have to have a huge
section about deployment guidance or you
know security consideration some things
somewhere is that in the architecture or
in the API document I don't know where
the right place is if we do decide to
even consider this wherever this
mentions yeah the only people need to be
considered in the security section
section yeah so all right all right
thank you thank you our 10 minute API
update discussion in here for an hour it
was okay so we have tons of time for
this meeting but I I'm hoping we don't
use it but Kyle no pressure
hi I'm Kyle arose from aggelakas and I'm
going to present just updates to the
captive portal architecture between now
and the O 2 and O one version alright so
first I'm going to summarize changes I'm
going to talk a little bit about the
signaling protocol we've introduced
and then just finish off discussing some
open issues and questions that come up
let's store in the github repo so what
am i changed well so we added a
requirement so nicely provided by
Lorenzo for the signaling protocol we
sort of stripped it ICMP or we did a
said and replace you know icpo signa
protocol for the most part and there was
a bunch of typos and spelling mistakes
because I was dumb didn't run it through
a spell checker I fix those all right so
the second protocol as I hinted it's
very similar to the old ICMP workflow is
just we've replaced it with a abstract
concept called signalling protocol to
find some requirements for it
so that when we go to actually implement
one well we all know what to do just
stepping back a second for context the
last ITF there's a bunch of debate about
using ICMP to signal that your captive
and I correct me if I'm wrong but we
decided that rather than try to solve
that problem in the architecture
document we would sort of just describe
at a higher level we want that protocol
to do and then move make it optional so
that we could actually deploy captive
corals without if we need to and then
finally move any specification of it
into a separate document so moving
forward so the requirements before the
document are essentially that it's not
easy a spoof so you can't just have it
coming from randomly on the internet
that you can send it before the portal
closes to inform the user that there's a
pending expiry that and those are sort
of the two main ones another one is that
there was I hope I didn't misinterpret
you Lorenzo there was minimal
information in the message that means
that really keep it simple just give
enough information to the user equipment
to make the decision it needs to go
whether or not is captive whether this
stuff's going to expire etc I added some
requirements
around being able to identify the source
of a signal in order to validate it
later it's debatable whether that's
actually necessary and I think I'm going
to discuss that a bit at the end of the
presentation I mean finally I added a
requirement about it not needing to be
reliable um and I wanted people who
implement the protocol to be aware that
it's not TCP signal necessarily it could
be something like ICMP or it could be
something like a uep packet and that
they should be aware that I just get
lost and you know if the user you're
cooking keeps on trying to connect keep
trying to send a message if just yeah be
smart about it
so from after having talked to friendly
camper portal operators I I'm sort of
grown to be worried about the ability to
send this before portal closure
particularly if such signal might result
in you ease presenting the uses some
plead for attention some plea for
attention
you know I was really I was actually
wanting to make a comment about your
draft where the the expiry time and my
fear is that we can't have nice things
in the sense that if if there's a if
there's a an opportunity for a captive
portal operator to say you had your time
left on the clock is three minutes and
20 seconds
and so we would dutifully if we
dutifully present to the user
notification you know one minute and
thirty seconds in and show hey click on
this page to keep - stay logged into the
network they would do that as often as
they are able and so my fear was that we
would be forced to tie the expiration
date the time left on the clock at to
actual expiration in the sense that we'd
have to run a probe and determine that
we were actually locked in again before
we would have honored that so I don't
know if this fear is justified or well
could we do something to mitigate it
like you know the UI experts put a
snooze button on it and say you know
what I hate the same you can go away for
a while okay
she said Tommy Polly Apple so for the
expiry bites or time in the API my
thought was not that one should prompt
at all but for example like if you had a
page that was like oh here's your
network settings you can have
essentially say the network said you
have this much time left here is a link
to the portal if you want to of your own
volition
click on it and if you say oh yeah that
30 seconds is bogus then you won't do it
but essentially it's I paid for an hour
it's a way for the system to handle the
clock for me so cuz I got countdown
going or something so they even just
like keep a clock so I can have this
window open like like what you they
actually do this on a lot of captive
portals like on an airplane they'll have
the countdown timer if you leave that
window open the point of this is that
could be a system-level window that says
they reported this time a countdown
timer here it is if you want to see it
so I'm more okay with that than I am
with having the signalling protocol be
able to do this because it could
continually change its mind and it can
essentially pester you with this a
little bit more you could represent it
in the same way but if we have an API
I'm not sure what the value of a
signalling on the wire is before a
portal code because like how long before
a portal closure should that come and so
even if it's not necessary pestering the
user are we encouraging people via this
mechanism to pester the radio on the
device and just send packets to wake up
the devices hey hey hey hey hey hey you
may be about to close and the user
doesn't care and there's no point to
send that traffic on the water a few
things to stay in response to that so um
the holes gonna say first crap so
regarding a portal pestering the user I
mean they could do that right now why
don't they right they could just keep
sending redirects every three minutes
guess the differences it actually okay
and I guess it's a little more impactful
when it's actually interrupting the
connection as well so um so so I think
the idea with the Signum protocol is
that it's potentially more reliable and
that is coming from the thing that's
actually making this decision I want to
wanted one of the big points is that if
you keep if you make all the decisions
centrally it's a lot harder to make
misconfigure a lot harder to mess up so
I mean that maybe that's part of the
reason behind it uh regarding the the is
a little blurb in the giraffe talking
about why we have that and it's to make
the make a more seamless so you don't
lose connectivity first so maybe rather
than you know I you can I guess it'll be
up to the UI to decide okay well the API
or maybe I said we have 10 minutes to
expiry let's maybe do something in 9
minutes it's so yeah I guess I was gonna
make something similar captive portals
can currently do this and some of them
do um but it seems that having an
ability to at least signal you should
come back and look at the API piece
would be useful because I mean some
captive portals you sign up for an hour
and the timer starts now and continues
running for sixty minutes and then stops
otherwise you sign up for an hour and
then if you decide to leave the hotel
and go to Starbucks and get some coffee
and come back the timer stops and when
you reconnect having a you know you
should come have a look you thought you
only had 15 minutes left you now
actually have 45 we could also agree
that the user will only be annoyed if
the timer you know with the you should
probably log in again if the timer says
that it's less than five minutes or
maybe something that the user says so
you know they could keep saying they
come look the API come look the API but
if we don't do anything with that
information they've got no incentive to
send it I so I don't think there's an
incentive for the captive portal
operator necessarily to ask the user to
go to the API and they the only thing
that the only thing that you know
appears to me to be an incentive for the
us operators is to show the user stuff
everything else is caught
and so I think if we if we get prompted
to go to the API even if it results in
us you know burning packets I don't see
a lot of harm in it most will update our
idea of what the JSON values are
including perhaps time left on the clock
and if those don't actually result in
you know please for attention to the
user then maybe that's fine right you
know it - Tommy's point we just update
our clock with our new idea of what the
clock is so but you know that was one of
the thing one of the points I think we'd
made and Chicago I think was it where
are we or maybe London where we said
look the this should be a hint to go to
the API it should never be a hint to do
something else it should always be hey
something has changed go look at the API
I think that removes a lot of the intent
of the negative or the the wrong
incentives here so it so I'd appreciate
if someone reads my the the text in the
draft is to make sure that I've captured
that correctly I think I did that but
you know if there's any wiggle room in
there we should try and lock it down
this is dkg so I just wanted to ask that
we think clearly about the sort of power
structures that we're putting in place
here and I tend to agree that providing
the signaling protocol to happen after
the fact puts a lot more power in the
hands of the network operator and if we
say that you only get this during
connection then the network operator
basically has to state something and
then stick to it right it negotiates
something during that during the
registration phase I might be using the
wrong term there but right during that
during the phase where the user
interacts with the captive portal and
it's committing to something that the
user and the user agent is going to keep
track of and we'll do the right thing
appropriately now if you want to do
during the negotiation phase tell the
user I'm gonna register you but only for
two and a half minutes you'll come back
and look at an ad in two and a half
minutes then the user can say I'm this
network is not functional for me and be
done if instead it says sure sure go
ahead I'm registering you for an hour
and then it comes back two and a half
minutes later and says Bo you got to
check it out something
then I think that's a problem and so I
think we can this is something that will
be more useful for the users it's a
negotiation if the if the network
operator knows that they have to stick
to the negotiation that they've made
with the user at the registration time
what if when we you know in the API we
are a little more strict about changing
time' right if it's also is it is weird
discontinuity in the in the remaining
time when you go and visit indicate
something's wrong but I mean you know
you go and Eve it what's that what's the
damage of going to visiting the API
again
aside from cell power API is different
from the web portal so that was
Lorenzo's point is that we need to make
sure this is this is a signal for the
headless portion of the program wise has
a limited set of resources right whether
it's my brain or whether it's my
smartphone or whatever that's battery
that's radio that what all of that right
when when the network comes back to me
and says hey I need you to do this thing
you're burning my resources and if I'd
negotiated with you to not you're not
gonna burn my resources for the next you
know X amount of time I'm choosing to do
it I want you to stick to that so yep
you sir so given that we have an API we
are designing an API portal that it runs
on HTTP that it's trusted so this looks
a bit unsecure to me to rely too much on
such a signalling protocol so for me it
would really be useful in case there is
some synchronization issue between the
API portal and the network for some
reason you know load balancing in your
network some device went down and up
again and so that can happen so for in
my opinion that shouldn't be more than
just a nice CMP error message I don't
see why it would need to be to happen
before portal closer like the network
shouldn't have to keep track of who's
connected and that's up to the API
portal so yeah when you send a packet
that packet has to be dropped by the
enforcement point yeah it seems fair
that it would send you an ICMP message
telling you oh you're captive and
probably go to the API portal that you
already should know the URI for like URI
should not be in the ICMP message
otherwise it's an attack vector and and
I would be fine with you you know that
would be an information if you actually
get such an ICMP message and your
connection is running fine why would you
do anything so if you don't want to
visit the API portal just don't if your
network is evil or somehow wants to
block your connection you don't really
have a choice you have to go to the API
bottle and if you'd want if the network
wants to exhaust your resources based on
that it just can so Warren Kumari I
think that there is some incentive for
people to play any games here so unless
and I don't quite know where this goes
maybe architecture doctor when I come
along and I join the Fairmont Network
and it pops up a captive model and then
it says you have access for 47 years you
should come back every 30 seconds in
check or they use this to signal come
back and check now I go to the Hilton
and various other hotels and Starbucks
and wander around and the whole time I'm
checking in for the next 47 years to
tell them exactly where I am
so we need to make sure that the captive
portal information stays scoped to the
network that you actually join and
doesn't and that's not actually I don't
think that that's actually written in a
document
it seems common sense yeah thanks I
think we have to we have to accept the
sad reality that there is no enforcement
of anything that is in the API at all
right because the user doesn't see it
and therefore they can't keep anyone
honest right the only thing that you
know so so to my point about you know to
the earlier point about we should only
do this on on initial signaling there's
nothing in initial signaling which makes
this remotely trust work at all
the API is just there for you know
information and you can't trust any of
it because the user is not in a position
to to it to enforce any of it or to keep
anyone on this so I don't I don't see
there's a lot of ways that networks can
use your battery they can send you
packets and they cause you to drop them
and something will on your device will
wake up when you do that even if it's
just the chipset it still does wake up
and so they can find you with packets
they can do all sorts of stuff and I
think if we don't give them incentive to
do that it's just gonna be more trouble
than it's worth for them to attempt it
so I don't see yeah so if all if all
that happens when we do this ICMP is we
hit their URL and ask for Jason then
we're just like they're just imposing
costs on themselves to do X or SSL
handshakes for no benefit because yeah
we update our idea over the timer that's
left on the clock we don't do anything
else particularly if we don't show
anything to the user they don't care
so Tommy Paulie
two points here one just to what Lorenzo
was saying you could imagine that if
there is information in the API like
expiry time or something else simply the
moment you get through the portal and
we're like hey we're good now the system
could give a summary of like hey you've
joined this network it says you have
this much time left and that is the
opportunity at which user says but I
paid for an hour and you say I only have
this so like it's potentially a way to
confirm is that useful is that spoof
able sure the other point kind of basic
info is what peer was saying earlier I'm
not totally sure about all the
deployment models and someone like David
burger would be able to help with this
better but when we're looking at the
indication before portal closure that
assumes that the thing that is giving
the signaling like ICMP is aware of the
kind of the long-term state of these and
when it's going to close I could imagine
an architecture in which the thing that
is sending the ICMP are the redirects
simply just has a white list in a black
list or just a white list of these are
the addresses that are allowed to get
through or the MAC addresses or whatever
to say okay on or off and it is some
other entity that actually is doing the
countdown of the time and just
essentially updating a rule list
somewhere else
so it may be difficult
for the same entity that is giving you
the signaling of you're blocked you're
blocked to also have the nuanced notion
of and 30 seconds or two minutes before
this person is about to be blocked then
go give them some other update so I mean
I think that I put it in the documents
that it's a should not a must send a
signal and that's a good it's a good
reason to have it as it should not a
must
why would we even send before portal
closure right you know if we we are
absolutely 100% Craven and sent it like
if we if we if we if we're gonna present
that to the user in terms of a captive
portal login page it's gonna be a
disaster right because you know because
you know they're just gonna do that
every 20 seconds I think the idea was to
what was to try to allow networks to
signal issues back
maybe that's what destination
unreachable is for right know what issue
I mean like trying to consider like the
there are some people in here a while
back talking about the telecom use cases
where something you know you're
inspected with a virus and they want to
tell you that you're infected with a
virus right now they're just sending you
a 302 redirect to a random like HTTP
access well that you now qualify for
Comcast business access if you only sign
up here for so I mean I I don't know if
we want to explicitly D scope that sort
of use case but right now as far as I'm
aware it's still on the table okay so
let me summarize a conversation that we
had with a apparently quite competent
captive portal operator right the only
thing that their customers wanted the
only reason why they were providing free
Wi-Fi at all was that they got to show
the user a page at the end of the
captive portal signing work sign-in okay
and they hate our guts because we closed
that page as soon as they unlock the
portal right they and so right so they
were basically saying that makes it like
entirely useless to us from that I did
use that really the only thing that's
that basically we get free why
five four user attention and I think we
need to keep those incentives very well
in mind before we allow you know the
network to signal user attention it's
basically you know and I think literally
the yes capital portals can lock on you
today but what they do is they cause
themselves collateral damage because you
know you E's can switch away from their
network and it also provides irritating
stuff to irritation to the user when
they're browsing and they get
interrupted and it's a disincentive for
them if we just give them a free
incentive then they're gonna use it so
Warren Kumari I mean I think that's
exactly my point is that users don't
like it when their captive portal
suddenly stops like the destination
unreachable as being a good signal I
don't like that idea cuz I'm on a
FaceTime call or you know Google
Hangouts call with my wife and suddenly
it stops and dies in the middle of an
argument and she figures I hung up on
her I would I would network signals this
is gonna timeout in an hour and that
system just ignores that it's gonna
timeout in 10 minutes and the system and
ignores it but I've said please let me
know
two minutes beforehand right so we could
always have the device decide that it's
going to ignore all of the please pop up
a message until you know thirty seconds
before or a minute before then Noah
might as well just set the captive
portal timeout to 30 min three minutes
as well right it's the same amount of
like if they go if they're willing to
pop up and make themselves be annoying
they're willing to pop up and we'll just
make the timeout that much if I may were
in more in at certain myself and the
queue there um it might be that you can
get your time remaining warning from the
system because it got it out of the
captive portal API and not from
destination and reachable zand one thing
one very hypothetical thing I would put
to the room for consideration is what if
we just stick with the existing ICMP
destination and reachable as the
enforcement thing when they want to shut
connections down we remove signalling
protocol altogether and replace it with
a recommendation that operating systems
provide a mechanism
our applications to request reevaluation
of network access basically are
basically operating systems provide
should provide a report bad network or a
please check the network for me call
that applications can use when they
think something is gone amiss possibly a
captured portal but but then it still is
gonna break my video call or something
all right
it's gonna you're gonna have to break it
before the app notice only if the
capture portal is lying about how much
api is lying about how much time you
have left or it forgot yeah
bear in mind right it's entirely
possible that you know a captive portal
enforcement point might have might
reboot completely lost state and then
really your yes toast again I mean so
the earlier thing if they can just keep
popping things up the reason that
captive portals don't currently said a
one-minute time out is because users
will get annoyed and wander off all I
was suggesting is the signaling thing we
could ignore it until we think that
there's only a small amount of time left
although that breaks yeah when you lose
state okay so I have it at all they're
basically just repeating what has been
said already sorry it was just before it
looks like a cmp destination unreachable
is the thing that we are looking for i
we could add a new type like you are
captive type to give a little bit more
information about the reason why the
packet was dropped not Monday did I mean
if if and all the router wants to use
the destination or reachable for some
other types might make sense and it
Lauren so it looks like what you are
looking for is that in the in the
architecture there is a requirement that
says that based on the time that is
available on the API the the user
equipment should never have to never be
mandated to do to connect to the API
before that time so so when you log in
when you log into the portal you you pay
for something for some time and and that
time should be the one that's even by
the API and you shouldn't have to
connect again and again and again every
time you get an ICMP message that's what
you're looking for I think that's what
you that's what you asked for
to make sure that the hose doesn't need
to do more connections that what the API
asked for and if the API says oh you're
only allowed for 30 seconds what do you
want to do yes sure you will have to
connect to the API every 30 seconds
because that's what that's what CAPTCHA
pothole lets you do or you want to
mandate that with that shouldn't be less
than whatever personally I don't care
about like I can hit the API every five
seconds no one's gonna make me do that
no one's gonna care unless there's an
incentive in the form of like annoying
the user with an ADD and in that case I
promise you they're gonna do that and
that that's the thing I'm trying to I'm
trying to ensure here I don't care you
know if we if we get a signal hit the
API sure we'll update our counter
because our clocks might have drifted I
don't know who cares no one's gonna ask
us to do this unless hitting the API is
actually gonna result in us annoying the
user and like I said my fear is that
we're not gonna have we can't have nice
things
there but just like you said before the
if the API just gives 30-second leases
it's going to annoy the user enough that
it's going to age the captive on service
it's going to wander off and my point to
that is like I said we can't have nice
things and so even if it says 30 seconds
we're just gonna ignore it right I mean
I I mean like the only the only way I
see around this is Tommy's suggestion
says like the summary says you're an
hour logged in for an hour and then the
user might get pissed off if if it locks
before that and you know it mean which
case right you know if we if we get told
to hit it again after 12 seconds and
says like yeah you're actually now
logged in for two minutes what do we do
right and my point is I think we have to
design this with an adversarial mindset
right and so like I said I don't care if
we hit the API every time every twenty
seconds because no one's gonna make us
do that because it's just like it
couldn't increase the load on their
server and they're not gonna do that
right so there's no point there's
there's no attack vector there the
attack vector there is the attack
vectors in terms of user attention
so I think I'm maybe I'm missing it but
I think I just wanted to point out that
when we talk about the you know is that
a captive you are either logged in or
not I don't think logging in is actually
always a binary stay you may be like
when you connect your captive portal you
miss is like okay you chose the free low
speed connection right and if you try to
connect on Netflix it's gonna block you
right it's like you're not allowed to
stream blocked Netflix you know with the
current settings that you're selected so
how do you do I mean I just want to make
sure that we that is a reality right is
like how do you account for that I'd
encourage people to take that one to the
list the the discussion about selective
blocking of services is an interesting
one and perhaps not something that we
can we don't know Mia Jim can we get rid
of that topic forever here's my
suggestion okay we start a thread on it
there's a massive argument we declare
that there will never be consensus and
then we drop this topic please I didn't
I can write like passionate emails I
could like rail at people risk being
banned from the list like you can do it
as well and you could do it as well and
then we have this great argument say
okay there's no hope of ever reaching
consensus on this let's declare it out
of scope forever
so my understanding my understanding was
that we wouldn't we wouldn't engage on
this topic for that reason if if people
think that I'm wrong come and talk to me
private come talk with me privately but
my understanding was that when we when
we built this yeah the expectation was
that any such information of that nature
will be left to communication between
the the network operator and the users
using the captive portal pages or what
have what have you and we wouldn't
provide any specific mechanisms in
support of those sorts of things I think
the problem comes when we have a
mechanism that seems to offer some
benefits but also has some downsides but
then one of the possible benefits that
is really strong for it is the is this
use
and I guess we just need to strike that
benefit from consideration if we're
going to I wasn't a suggest you I wasn't
a suggesting that we need to do anything
about you all I'm saying is we just
history to account for the fact that
that's a reality right and whatever we
say recommend in here has to occur at
least say something that something like
that could happen and you do blah right
we don't deal with it but you at least
have to mention it I know I know if
you're not gonna get any consensus on it
okay so so you're suggesting that we
need to at least address the issue even
if the way that we address it is to say
that when I'm not going to address it
okay so we're enquiry I can't tell if
this as part of that third rail subject
or not I get on a United plane and I
connect to the network and it gives me
automatically the pretty thing that
tells me how far the plane is and
streaming from their internal you know
thing of movies versus connect to the
internet is that a differentiation of
surface or no because one sort of thing
behind the capture pole and one isn't
right like I get internet but the
Internet's is very limited to just the
stuff on this plane I mean you may be
older argue that you know you draw some
boundaries that you think about it like
literally it's on the plane with the
captive portal versus not on the plane I
mean I think okay so too much to the
earlier point this is this is you know
this is the reality of things you know
it also it's also a reality that we
can't write anything unless you get
rough consensus on it and certain topics
they're just like no point in discussing
them because we know they're not they're
not going to result in consensus because
we've had those discussions recently and
frequently and we just end up with the
same conclusion we can't write anything
unless we agree on it is the point right
do you think we can agree I think we can
agree that's my point
yeah so so my feeling is that we are
forced to force that we will only be
able to agree on a model which has
essentially a binary captive state and
stuff that's inside the portal and
that's it's available regardless of
whether the portal is unlocked or not
and the intern
right and I think you know we can
probably on that I don't know I don't
think we can't ruin anything else so we
might as well say look it is out of
scope and we're because I don't I don't
know if we can say there's no consensus
or we could say look you know it raises
count isn't there are some IAB document
that we can point you or something
that's already written down that says
we're not gonna engage in this topic
because black 40 84 Tommy Polly I agree
that we should not engage in the raging
debate that red proposes although it
would be really fun I appreciate that I
think the one thing this brings up to me
is that while we should be designing for
the internet internet or not use case
there are captive portals that do
partial blockage today so I think we
should have as a requirement to
ourselves that any solution that we come
up with which is less bad for Internet
or not captive portals is also less bad
for the other ones so doing something in
our architecture or in a protocol that
actually limits or harms those use cases
in ways that we don't need to make those
use cases much much better but we need
to make sure that we don't make them
worse what I'm concerned about with the
signaling let's say if we did have this
not what you're proposing but like an
ICMP error that every time I get an ICMP
your captive or unreachable or something
that then I actually pop up the portal
web page to the user something that is
something that will not work for a
walled garden or a partial scenario
because that inherently assumes is one
or the other because I may have done
everything I can possibly do or want to
do with the portal and I'm still blocked
on Netflix and so the fact that Netflix
gives me an ICMP or some signal should
not cause me to do anything more because
that is potentially this good steady
state so that's my concern with the
signaling protocol is that if
we're assuming that some signal that
your your being blocked by a captive
portal implies that you need to go and
do something more is I think an
incorrect assumption the reason I like
the API more than the signaling and more
than even today's redirect model is that
it truly separates them outright says
there is a path and the API is not about
employment as we are going on with David
bird on the list API has nothing to do
with enforcement it is only a bootstrap
for user experience and I think that's
actually what we're trying to solve the
enforcement model is not something
actually I think we're trying to change
here in this group we're trying to
change the way that we interact with the
portal to allow the user to get to what
they need to do which is the network's
problem but I mean this signalling
protocol is an interaction that hints it
is a hint but the question is what do we
do in reaction to it and we could get to
the place where in reaction to being
blocked we do exactly what you would do
on a non captive network and you got a
destination reachable like we don't have
to do anything different I just wanna
make sure I understand your point so
regarding Netflix and instance a state
so the idea is the user leaves they've
connected the portal they've chosen
their plan and that's it and you know
they know that Netflix isn't gonna work
but for some reason they have a window
open and is just trying to connect
Netflix in the background and they just
don't care um so why would you pop
something up just gonna annoy them yeah
if I may
okay I learned that if Netflix doesn't
work it's an outage right if they if the
user expects that outage then that's
fine I mean I agree I agree with Tommy I
think and also I don't think we can I
don't think there's anything we can do
about these partial connectivity use
cases we can I we certainly can't make
them worse because they're just gonna be
the operators just gonna make you know
continue to do whatever they need to do
in order to enforce their business
models right we can try to make other
stuff better we can't try to make this
stuff better because we can't agree on
it so
and you can't make it worse we can't
make it better I think in the case where
the user paid for you know the non video
streaming service right they there's no
there isn't there's I don't understand
what will be gained from a protocol to
tell them you're going to Netflix and
you could pay more if you wanted to we
have the API for the URL for the user
interaction if they wanted to go back
there should be a path in the operating
system to say I need to go back to that
interaction page because I decided I
want to upgrade we have that because the
API gave it to us
I guess the one nice thing would be if
the failure was a little more explicit
like just no I mean just more like
rather than just hanging and waiting and
waiting and waiting or mine sh t I could
fail randomly it just just fails and
then that's where maybe what Eric was
saying earlier it was anyways Eric who
said it that the ability of an
application to request the OS to
validate the network and I said I kind
of like that just but but for if it
weren't the Netflix app they would you
would get the answer yeah no
everything's fine you're just not gonna
work but so Warren Kumari maybe this is
already covered or maybe it's too much
UI but what's often happened to me as
I've gone along to a hotel and I connect
to the capture portal and it says for
free you can get internet access at one
Meg for $9.99 you can get it at 10 Meg
like I had I want to pay 10 Meg when you
nine a night so I get the free one and
then I discovered that was not a good
option because there one Meg is not
actually one wreck and then I can never
actually find the captive portal thing
again so it would be really nice is I
guess that this is a UI thing or
something where I can then click on a
button and be like what was that URL
again cuz I'd like to upgrade now please
and we should please provide you yeah I
also I really don't see the issue that
we are right now like if the user tries
to connect to netflix and that's not
provided by a service there is an ICMP
return message it doesn't egg out the
connection is just closed
because there is the ICMP error you can
display it in the browser or whatever in
whatever way you want
if the ICMP message actually is you are
captive then you can display you are
captive and then the user is supposed to
click somewhere in his system that tells
okay actually I want to upgrade or and
reach back to the the do aisle I don't
think it should that there shouldn't be
anything automatic and I think we all
agree on that lines are clearly not
instead of well mostly related we so we
we encountered a captive portal where
the user signed into the messaging plan
which included I don't know what and and
we know that it included Google comm
because the Google Search app was
telling us quite regularly that they had
connectivity and then there were the
other apps that were telling us and we
do have such an API to report internet
continue there are other apps that we're
telling us we we really don't have
connectivity and unfortunately the probe
that we do for Internet connectivity
includes a random element and some of
those were 302 and some of them were not
and so he ended up
we ended up and the bug that was
followed was I keep getting prompted for
access but I already signed into
everything I signed into I wanted the
messaging plan get on my way I don't
know how to fix that but yeah so and I
don't think this would help to be honest
right so I think we've run that one to
ground and there seems to be pretty
pretty strong consensus about this one I
think the conclusion there was that
we're not making things worse
and I've put in I put an issue in on the
on the architecture draft to simply
state explicitly what we're doing and
what we're not doing with respect to
this sort of news case and I think
that'll be relatively straightforward to
do one paragraph should be enough for
that sort of thing but it'll mean that
we can close this issue in the sense
we actually have an artifact that says
what a what we agreed and so if you if
you if anyone was to produce that one
paragraph I welcome that but otherwise
they son you sir it's the notes are not
that good so I moderately confuse this
want to make sure did we agree that
there should be no signaling protocol at
all or did we agree that there should be
not on that question we we got
sidetracked onto this other more
interesting question I thought we agreed
that it was gonna be a hint yeah okay at
most it's a hint which is I think
consistent with what's what's in the
draft okay so should we can results
should result in reef etching the API
could may okay so I probably probably
need to rephrase I'm with me okay fine
yeah I'm getting the impression that
people will make their own decisions
about whether or not they want to go and
get the API yeah okay all right moving
on okay so some open issues and
questions that aren't the ones we've
been talking about so there was a issue
open saying hey we need a way to
indicate that there is no captive portal
so we can just go on Eric has that in
the draft I think you actually answered
my question on github today and I think
I noticed in the API no the in the PVD
document there is also a note about it
you're always right slice yeah so I
think probably can just close that issue
there was also something we had some
language in the draft talking about PVD
and now that pierre has nicely provided
one i'm assuming it gets adopted I think
I can probably clean that text up and
get rid of the issue there is a section
talking about the backwards
compatibility of signals in particular
it's talking about how you know a portal
might choose to continue to do redirects
as well as do signals I think I don't
know what we want
I'm not even clear that that text makes
sense anymore in the discussion we just
had so maybe I'll just
I can strip out that whole thing or I
can try and clarify it a bit more I
[Music]
think I do think about that one a bit
more it's not it's not clear what the
answer for that is maybe I'll take it to
the list a bit
what is the section give us except an
opportunity for disagreement I mean I
don't disagree with it but you know I
don't think it also provides a lot of
information it's like yeah you could do
this sure of course you could mmm and
also saying you should implement this
RFC in the RFC itself is like a you must
read it you must implement it if there's
the hint of disagreement on the side
strike all right there was some
discussion at 101 about the accept field
and backwards compatibility there's
language in the architecture right now
about that I'm not sure it really should
be in the architecture so I'm thinking
of just removing it and delegating that
to the API slash DHCP offense right this
is my fault
or yeah hey you know it's the draft the
are the authors at fault we said there's
in a work flow there's a section about
verifying the plausibility of a signal
or ICMP message and I'm not sure
plausibility really makes sense I mean
pretty plausible so I know I suggested
on the mailing list that we renamed it
to authenticity not sure if that makes
sense
but it raised a point that I didn't
really capture very well in the draft
regarding the requirements on the
signaling protocol we didn't really talk
well about having the security of it
like having me the user equipment trust
that the signal is a real signal there
is a
requirements saying that is hard to
spoof do we also need a requirement
saying that it is real whatever that
means so before Tommy speaks we've
talked about the nature of the signal
and I think we've established that this
is not necessarily a requirement here
and so saying saying something
particularly with assured is problematic
in the sense that you're now
contradicting yourself so and what I was
going to suggest actually is that any
any protocol that provides a signal like
this will have certain properties with
respect to authenticity um being on the
path this may be not the property that
we're looking for but that's something
that ICMP provides some information on
we don't have a lot else and so we could
do the whole HVAC thing that we talked
about before and whatnot but that's what
I was trying to capture here
the question is yeah I I would not put
any specific requirement on this one so
you think it may be a little too
restrictive let's just keep keep the
option open if you want to but just move
right so that let's leave that problem
for someone else right you're making
table this problem basically
so Tommy right at the point I was came
up here to make was that the
requirements around authenticity of
signaling are intimately tied with what
we are using the signaling for and so if
if we do what we were discussing here of
it's a hint that you may use to tell you
that something went wrong which is I I
find to be exactly the same as a normal
ICMP unreachable today it doesn't really
seem to require any more authenticity
because it's exactly equivalent to the
unauthenticated signal we have today and
we should try to do nothing like my
concern is if you had try to add a
signaling method with authenticity that
implies now that I have more of
should that I should be using this to
validate something I should be trusting
this and doing something with the user
and that it gets into the whole can of
worms again so until we actually have
benefit from the signal that's gonna be
a strong signal that carries more than
just a hint
we shouldn't add authenticity to give
the impression that it does make sense
copy stuff so if we if we keep calling
it a signaling protocol and not ICMP and
retrieval and try to speak in general
terms it seems important to me that
there is some text about the properties
of the spoofing possibilities like okay
if you imagine that signaling protocol
that can come out of the blue from
anywhere anybody that knows your source
address even though it's a hint that's
going to be an issue that anyone can
send you that all your captives signal
from anywhere if it's nicely mPHA below
that and that you need to make sure that
it comes from the path and that it's
related to an actual connection that you
are having it's a little bit better just
possibility would be you know in the API
there was the H Mak possibility that can
be done we can also imagine putting a
list of valid source addresses in the
API that you know not strong security
but still better than accepting eyes
such messages from anywhere on the
network Lorenza I in the weed
how how likely is it that we could get
rough consensus on this document if we
removed in if we removed all of the
signaling text there's somebody can
somebody not live with that yeah I mean
at you in this room and do we believe
that somebody could not live with that
on the mailing list such that we would
not get rough consensus or rather enough
people would would not live with it that
we couldn't help you sir I think there
will be cases where there will you know
bugs going on between the API and the
network and as
as I said before I don't want the page
to just hang forever waiting for
something to happen it's good to have
some message from the network saying I'm
the network there is something wrong
please you know reach the API or as the
user to do something or I mean at least
inform the device that there was
something going wrong and it's because
of you kept you kept a bottle yeah I
think so I I think I can't
Warren Kumari I think removing
everything about signaling might be a
bad thing but saying signaling is out of
scope for now we're planning on writing
a document in the future to deal with
that would be perfectly fine with me or
you know there may be somebody may one
day write a protocol that does this but
like at least showing that we thought
about it so where would be the
appropriate spot to place that note
would that be interesting like
introduction something so just as a
suggestion there that that suggests that
maybe you could lighten the requirements
in the sense that they could be a little
bit more abstract and a little bit more
sure a little bit shorter and not go
into these sorts of details in too much
at too much length but but still say you
know this is what it the role that would
would play in the architecture but we're
not really describing a concrete
manifestation of it the following things
are probably important like the spoofing
thing but we don't need to get into the
details and the nuts and bolts of it
because that that's very hard for us to
do right now because we don't know what
this thing concretely looks like yeah
especially if it's like these things are
probably important not the signaling
protocol must have the following brick
you know requirement sort of things goes
yeah I think I think we need to at least
have some statement and I think probably
it is some some level of character it
doesn't have to be requirements or it
can just be characteristics like it
should ideally have these you know these
characteristics and that that might be
okay but laceration one so we're going
down his path of considering shrinking
the scope with a signal more does
right now there's there's a fair amount
of text describing how the signal
actually works in the work flow if it
were there with that also involved just
removing all of that removed from the
diagrams and just have a brief blurb
saying hey we would kind of use it to
talk between me for some point these are
equipment kind of look like this it's
probably not the right room to be having
that discussion without actually having
the text in front of us in the time so
my suggestion would be that you and
those who are interested go back and
have a look at the document and what
you've got at the moment and make some
suggestions on what what might be done
okay
can I make a suggestion that that's what
I was planning to do would anybody
disagree with this so we just say that
the the network the enforcement point
should or you know maybe must when it
drops the packets send the destination
unreachable ICMP message so just like we
make sure that something happens another
packet is silently dropped
that's a question really but that's a
separate question but please we should
we should talk about that but right now
this is about the that the trigger for
going and fetching the API and the
requirements we have around that that's
a separate separate thing that maybe we
should talk about I'd like to get to the
answer on this one are you happy taking
an action to to look at the signaling
stuff and seeing what you can do to
reduce the the level of detail perhaps
and maybe come up with the repose 'el
yep okay or suitable or not
ICMP destination rule is that's the
question I think we can now make is it
actually used to be can we can we just
close this one before I move on to that
one please Tommy you know you wanted to
run it close I want to talk to that as
it is is anyone
does anyone have any objection to that
to that plan cause gonna go and have a
look at the draft and look at the
signaling that stuff and and remove the
landmines of this nature and try to get
it down to the essential parts
and I think you're close but you've got
a lot of detail in there and we'd
probably just lighten that bit yeah all
right Tommy so should not solving this
problem but more to go and what Dara was
saying one thing we could say and you
can take this down of the notes that I
think could be helpful is just silent
dropping is considered harmful
and that's it right like if you have
some mechanism that will produce an
error and cause the connection to be
closed or redirected or whatever that
isn't preferred to black holing traffic
and then we can just stop there so the
suggestion from Lorenzo and in case
anyone missed that one for the record is
yeah you should you should generate
invalid assets that's a great should
must in preference to dropping the
packet okay one final thing I don't have
on the slides but there was a question
raised on the list or our point made by
a couple of people that they felt the
architecture needed a bit more detail in
terms of the role of the enforcement
device I'm not sure I mean I thought
there was enough but if people feel that
we need to call it a more detailed a bit
more prescriptive in terms of
functionality I'd like to hear that like
there any suggestions about what I
should say that I'm not right now feel
free to ignore me because I'm gonna say
something not very helpful but and I
think my feeling is the value that we
can provide in this group is in terms of
a protocol to try to help clarify some
sort of contract between two different
devices it's really not I think that
useful in this group to tell captive
portal operators how to build what
they've already built so you know if we
already have text and we agree with that
sure but if not I think that's not the
value necessarily here so you know it's
possible I'm a citizen
oh the enforcement point shooter should
not do this in pursuit of a signal that
we don't even agree how it's supposed to
work I don't see a lot of so war inquiry
and I think that this is property on
this topic so enforcement stuff um a
while back I was wandering around with
an Ubuntu laptop and I really wanted to
reach google.com for some reason so I
opened up my laptop and I connected to
the captive portal and I didn't have any
internets and i taked in google calm and
sure enough it sent me a destination
unreachable which my machine decided was
met destination unreachable and then I
paid for the CAPTCHA for I could reach
everything other than google.com so very
careful with making sure that you know
what signal we send back or what is
suggested and what one actually does
with that yeah turns out clearing Oh
like this nation reachable that the
kernels learnt is kind of tricky and
rebooting is the right way that is not
good user experience okay so so tiller
ends this point if we talk we should
probably be the case that if we talk
about the be more descriptive than
prescriptive when it could term when it
comes to the enforcement point we're
just give descriptions of how we think
it's working
in order to illustrate the main things
we're doing which is the protocol right
all right I think that's it any closing
thoughts thank you yes
yo here's our time up if we continue
with this right we're gonna run out of
time so
so hello everyone I'm Shep Reiser as you
probably noticed and I'm going to talk
about thank you I'm looking going to
talk about this new draft which is about
discovering the CAPTCHA bottle API with
using provisioning domains and so it's
caught hers cause our twist Tommy wrote
quite about everything in the documents
but I'm presenting it Thank You Tommy so
this is not something totally new the
concept of provisioning domains it was
defined by the myth working group and we
discussed it quite a lot in this working
group but now is the opportunity to have
a deeper loop a deeper look at it since
there is a there is an actual document
to look at so it's defined in the
architecture document RFC 3550 six as a
consistent set of information basically
this is the set of things that you
receive from the network that lets you
access the network now we have an
additional draft the provisional domain
in the interior working group which
intends which is like two main
objectives the first objective is to
identify the provisioning domain and for
that purpose we use fully fully
qualified domain name which means that
if you're connected on one interface to
one Wi-Fi you would receive some
notification telling you the name of the
PVD so it's a fully qualified domain
name and on another interface another
provisioning domain you might have
multiple different provisioning domains
on the same interface by the mean of you
know different router advertisements
meaning that they would have different
fully qualified domain names or you
could even have the same provisioning
domains on two different interfaces if
they ultimately connect you to the same
upstream networks like for instance in a
hotel room you get Wi-Fi and wire but in
the end the upstream connectivity is the
same it's the same service that is
provided with the same characteristics
so there is the idea would be to let
host know that it's actually the same
service that is provided and now the the
second objective of the provisioning
domain work is to provide additional
information about the fundamental
properties of the upstream link you're
connected to the way you access the
Internet
so that can be you know the the service
provider the name of the upstream
connectivity it can be for instance we
are going to talk about it whether or
not there is a capture photo it could be
the the throughput so we are not right
now currently defining all that in the
in the draft in the free stream of that
domain draft but the idea is to provide
something that is generic by no mean of
JSON objects that is provided to you by
the network and that lists the different
properties of the network for the folder
host so the idea in this raft with this
additional object is to do something
that would be generic and that would
serve multiple purposes so for instance
the one of the captive portal working
group in all the cases where the host
would know a little bit more about the
network but it might be considered
slightly you know annoying to to define
a new array or the HTTP option for every
use case so not saying that that working
group shouldn't do that but we have lots
of cases where you would like the host
to know more about the network and that
you don't want to have to define a new
ipv6 ICMP option to do that so for the
phase one the way it works is that the
fully qualified domain name is put in
the router advertisements packet that
you received from your router so in the
first in this example you have two
interfaces with two different routers
but as I mentioned you may have a single
router with multiple pvd's and so this
is the option that has been defined you
see so there is on the middle of it
there is activity ID so that's the fully
qualified domain name we have a set of
bits that are set or not so the H bit is
the one that is pretty important because
it's it stands for HTTP
it's because it means that based on the
fully qualified domain name the host is
allowed to create an HTTP requests to
retrieve the JSON objects which you can
see on the other part on the bottom of
the side so that's an example of a JSON
object that you can get the other bits
are the L beat which is for a legacy
which means that the provisioning domain
ID is applicable to the ipv4 connection
as well so it's compatible with ipv4
although it requires an router
attachments so you can say that the PVD
works for the ipv4 link and then we have
other fields like whether or not there
is a specific router advertisement
options that are included in the PPID so
you can play with the options that you
want the PVD aware host to be able to
parse and those that you don't but
that's not really the topic for today
there also is a delay field that lets
you avoid thundering herd problem when
you want to update the DVD now for the
JSON object the the the keys that we
have today are the name so you can
display a fancy name to the user there
is a localized name so you can display a
fancy name in the language of the user
we have a time of expiry such that from
time to time you can update the JSON
objects know that time shouldn't be
really often right because it's really
about the characteristics of the link
and those are not intended to change all
the time
so the JSON object can be seen as
something that is pretty stable over
time we put a prefix in order to
validate that the JSON object that you
receive from a server that I didn't
mention it yet but we use HTTP so we
validate the fact that the server is
actually owning the name that is inside
the PVD but then that wouldn't prevent
an attacker for from advertising a PVD
ID that is not that it doesn't her own
so there is as well the prefix there to
make sure that the PVD is used on a
network which
uses the same source addresses and
configured addresses and then we just
have an additional key for saying if
there is internet access or no but
that's not what that's not what we are
going to use for CAPTCHA photo it's a
bit different because this internet
equals true or false is really a fixed
property so in the case of a captive
portal use case it would be actually
false like there you would have internet
access but there is a CAPTCHA photo so
in that case in the captive portal case
the key would be a kind of absent yeah
so implementation status it's been
implemented for quite a while now we
have a daemon that helps the user space
application to get information about the
object there is a patch for the Linux
kernel but right now it's not abstruse
having the our RFC published will help
with up streaming the the kernel
modifications we have IP route change
Wireshark dissector are a DVD for an OD
HPD for open wrt so just one slide to
talk about happily hotel no it's really
simple we are just proposing to add an
additional key in the JSON object that
you get from your network that
additional key is called captive api it
gives you the URI of the API such that
when it is present the host would know
that it is captive and that it can
connect to the API to login to the
CAPTCHA but also really really simple
basically not anything more to say about
the actual proposal for the capture
portal working group and just to mention
that it's that simple that we actually
implemented it twice in two different
Agathon so that was HF 101 I got on we
implemented it and demonstrated it and
then it was HF 99 Bacchus on yeah that
so final slide for discussion today four
main topics I would guess whether we
should add an additional key that's kind
of short
the API to go to the UI faster so that's
one possibility should we define a way
to stage that there is no CAPTCHA photo
so that would be as simple as particular
an empty an empty string instead of the
your API then we can discuss the pros
and cons of using pvd's should we use
these only or should we use DHCP and RA
only or should we use both and finally I
mean just tell us if you think this is
useful if we have to keep working this
direction or if you think that the
option with the RA option and DHCP
options are sufficient to the workgroup
another thing actually another question
was which we I don't know if we've
considered that in the in the API doc is
what if this URL changes because the PVD
can actually PPD has a big mechanism so
what what should happen if the captive
API URL changes during the lifetime of
the network that's another question to
ask as for whether we should use the RA
or DHCP option well I mean pvd's or v6
only right so so for before no I was
about to say this if you don't mind
jumping in the queue indeed it requires
@p v6 but what defines an ipv6 networks
are and oast not network as long as
android iOS are there and listen for
ipv6 array it works the URL can be fetch
over HTTP over ipv4 the DNS requests or
CSP can be done over TV for so let me
sorry let me amend my definition of v6
Network it requires that the network
operator send our ace all right so it
won't all work on a v4 only network mmm
okay so I can we can we just assume that
by the time this is specified the
routers that are in the wild are able to
send arrays
yeah all right so okay so okay so
all right so okay that's for my my
initial was my initial advice would be
to say well let's use that's used 7710
for before we could consider using this
instead of adding 7710 to b6 if we
wanted to
given that like in real captive portals
v sixes or in most of them B sixes you
know one of those yeah we have no plans
for it right now so you could be an
incentive really okay that was yeah so
maybe we can just say okay we'll use
7710 for before and this for b6 I don't
know that because otherwise we have two
ways of doing it in b6 but I just
answered your first question about the
API URI that could change right yes so
there is an update mechanism in the JSON
in the PD specification not going in the
details right but it's a it's push based
just like the RA so you can just push
the updates to the hosts
Tommy poly so as partly as co-author but
also speaking just from my being a
working group my answers to these
questions and other people please agree
or shoot them down for the first one
should we have a direct essentially a
shortcut of the API I would say no extra
methods are kind of extraneous and it
kind of ossifies on one current
deployment model that's why we left it
out for now the second one based on the
7710 bists document that we have now
seen which we did not have earlier I
would argue that they should be the same
string for marking that there is no
captive portal because that already
defines one so we should just copy that
that seems natural as far as the
coexistence with 72 seven ten bits the
feeling I have
today is that they can live in harmony
that there really doesn't need to be an
either-or here because 7710 business has
a great property of being very simple
for the simple deployments and it seems
like a slightly lower barrier to entry
for those things and if that can help
captive portals that's great and I think
the updates 277 canvas are taking in the
direction that we want to go and they
solved the problems with the original
RFC there are benefits to having a PVD
so first of all if you have a PVD this
feels like this should be a property of
your provisioning domain it's a natural
thing to extend so like I think this is
good work for this group to do in order
to extend that set of available
information and that should be specified
here
it adds value because if we're seeing
the world in which you actually have
multiple up links this provides ways of
getting more nuanced deployments of
captive portal so like this could
actually be the way that we solved the
partial captivity problem because like
what long term right like if I have a
one PVD for my streaming work one PVD
for this and I actually using different
v6 prefixes they have different captive
state etc etc maybe they all point to
the same API they have different API is
but they can point to the same user
portal for actually buying the things
but then we actually have multiple PVD
States associated with different captive
portal API is to maintain the lifetimes
of the different services that you've
bought so I think this is useful work to
keep doing I don't think it's going to
be the most common simple deployment
that we're gonna see in round one but I
think we should have them coexist and
like yeah let's adopt both documents and
they're different use cases you can't
both solve the Multi multi payment
scenario and use 7710 bits at the same
time because you those two things will
stomp on each other and they'll race
correct right this these would be
separate deployment models but a
I get Android our iOS host would
understand either and if you want to use
the one that lets you give different sub
networks great if you want to just have
the one that's just the boom here's your
are a DHCP option that works too which
ones who proceeds if they defer that's
very different I think that would be up
to the PVD documented sort of like a PVD
aware host prefers the people the
nuanced PVD one I don't know like that's
something that we would need to discuss
if we were to take on the book one one
option as well is that if there is an
array option that is that is defined for
discovering the API you can put it in
the array with the PVD and if you have
multiple services different services you
can put you know send multiple pvd's
multiple arrays and each related to one
of the services that you provide with
different captive portal api's okay by
everything I was about just you said
yeah that we can get multiple dvds for
this covering multiple captivate on the
same network
now the captive API I will not say the
very detail cosmetic empty string good
no yeah so what was your proposal to me
you said there was a key that already
exists in the API document and there is
a long string and we should use the same
instead of an empty string or Neil this
is Daniel can't go more so as I'm
thinking about this I'm imagining
connecting to a network where I get
dhcpv6 with cat porn info I get a route
advertisement with a cat for the
information it also has a PVD
information I get the PVD and the PVD
gives me additional portable information
and I get another PV another RA and I
get another DVD and some of those things
point to the same things and some of
them point to different things and I am
really glad that I am NOT responsible
for implementing this in a way that the
user can understand
III think we are we are building
ourselves a swamp that will have failure
modes that are completely impenetrable
and that worries me is this a problem
that we already have with 7710 this with
the G HP v6 option key pond again as
someone who is responsible for building
implementation I can't if I kind of with
you I mean I think we're here already
instead of talking about already talking
about you know 7710 and then well but
like 7710 is hard so let's do the
location header and I you know that
that's actually I almost feel that we
should just maybe just only do that
first and publishing a document doesn't
automatically create a swamp but it also
if it doesn't do anything then there's
no point in publishing it so I mean we
could either publish it and then you
know people will implement it or not or
wait until let's say the PVD work
actually gathers a lot of steam and when
that is actually sort of mainstream and
fully supported we would just put it in
there I I would almost say let's delay
this until the PVD work actually goes in
and becomes a standard and sort of
weight on it and yes of course you can
do this another thing that of course the
PVD option does is God it may or may not
depending on we have where where this
lands have this containerized IRA option
in which case you can containerize the
the 7710 URL anyway so yeah we've got
like this combinatorial explosion of
ways simply captive portals I would wait
on this one to be other dkg again um so
let me let me just ask a question that
perhaps okay so maybe this is already
specified and I apologize if I haven't
understood it properly if I receive
two different captive portal
informations from one link whether it's
via pvd's or dhcp announcements or our
Ras directly or whatever and they're the
same thing and I go to that captive
portal API to register what is my
expectation as an endpoint have I
registered to both of those things or
have I registered to one of them right
so with the with the the PVD is defined
well the PVD provides the tool to bind
ipv4 connectivity and ipv6 connectivity
together so when you register to the the
one that is provided by the PVD I would
assume that you would have connectivity
with both ipv4 and ipv6 I got to pvd's
ranks in the network I got to pvd's they
both gave me the same captive API so I
go to that captive API to register did I
just register with both of them which
one did I register with the one you used
for your source address that needs to be
documented yeah sure Tommy so yeah I
really liked ekgs point there so yeah
this is not specified the multi-tenancy
yet one thing I'd be tempted to do is
say like that they shoot like they
should not be the same and maybe they
can point to the same user portal but be
different API eyes so one thing that
this brings up and if Barton you can
take this in the notes that we need to
specify in the API document separately
is once you have interacted with the
user portal and you think you are done
we do need to check in again with the
API to see what the updated values are I
don't think it actually ever says that
anywhere because it's kind of important
so one thing you could imagine doing
like if they pointed to the same portal
user interaction and on that user
interaction I bought two out of three
services then ideally I should be able
to check in with the API is for those
services or those pvd's and figure out
which one's of those did the user just
open up so it's gonna be some model like
that if we go down that route
but even for the simple model we do need
to specify that we need to check in
again to actually know what the user did
so generally speaking PVD is a sort of
separate networks right so if it's not
just a source address it's you know the
DNS lookup yeah let's say that I have a
PVD host name of like I'd okay so it has
to pass and this is else art so it's
gotta be a valid host name but it could
be like you well login dot you know
whatever captive portal dot login or
whatever I mean yeah probably not it's
gonna be you know or login Boingo comm
right but they could be entirely
separate you know networks and yeah
login for one wouldn't assume login for
the other you'd have to do a DNS lookup
on both those pvd's and like it an ssl
connection on both of them if you wanted
to login to both of them how you present
this to the user of courses is basically
tear your hair up because it's really
like yeah i don't know i will say one
thing that is interesting about having
the captive portal API available via
BVDs is that if the network is extended
saved by tethering it might be easier to
discover that there's a capture portal
there rather than having to have all the
things that do the tethering and the
tethering and the tethering and the
preview delegation remember that they
need to also pass along 7710 this urls
know on the on your EO point about
having j GP v for HPV 6 erase what's the
what's the current definition define
behavior with you know you have dual
stack network you get a an array with an
option with the API and then DHCP with
an API are you supposed to log in to
both or do you assume that the ipv4 and
ipv6 are bound together you just need to
connect one I mean my point is to really
defend PPP is that in the PD spec II it
is defined what it means to be bound was
an ipv4 and ipv6 how to bind them
together so if I understand the kind of
questions you guys I think what we
should do
if we are going to use the PVD right so
I guess that's a good question is
between if you also receive a DHCP
option and a PVD now the DHCP option is
going to be ipv4 only well maybe v6 but
before let's say now we have to give
some player I don't have an answer we
have to give a clarification on which
one is which one wins right especially
if they are different captive or EPA if
they're different end points maybe I
think the answer is this fits in
implicit PVD then they're all in the
same PVD and it doesn't matter if you
use before ov6
that they're assumed to be the same that
one and actually just thinking about it
I wonder what's the point of having a
DHCP auction overall even for 7710 miss
why can't we just use an array so maybe
what we want is if you use this we want
to say that if this is used and this
wins out that it should discourage 7710
being use sent is that what you're
saying sorry no I didn't get it Lauren
the world is laughing too long too hard
are you suggesting that if PVD is being
used and PVD wins over DHCP option being
sent is that what you're suggesting yeah
if you use
I mean PVD solution would work as just
by itself you wouldn't you would need a
judge before or v6 option if it is sent
right if the operator if they have
already deployed 7710 and they forgot to
turn it off right now they'll deploy DVD
and now the you he gets both the DHCP
you know option and then the PVD we have
to give some if we use this we have to
give some you know tiebreaker right yep
you need to define so I get that we
should wait for the PVD work to progress
or is everyone comfortable with that or
as in the the proposal would be they
would continue to work on the
and make the improvements we discussed
but we would leave it as an individual
draft until such time as we are more
certain that pvd's good get deployed or
what have you is so this raises a
question for the architecture draft
which does explicitly mention PPD's in
it right now does that mean I should
probably just strike them from it until
so do you do need that no I don't know I
mean it's more given as an example of a
way of discovering the API so I could
probably remove it see Tommy says just
to avoid not holding up your document
being published I would not down
reference this document what you could
do is just bring up in the architecture
that when you're supporting multiple
networks that this is not Wi-Fi specific
you can just have a reference just to
the npvd architecture saying that there
may be leads in the future to specify
captive portals also for discovered
provisioning domains which there may be
multiple of on a network and just
essentially say that is a use case that
says that this architecture could be
useful for and then this document
whenever it evolves would just reference
and we are filling that role my
impression is that this is this is Adam
Roach my impression is is an
informational reference right now down
drafts don't apply to information I only
know of normative yeah you're like yeah
that's true III think I think what Polly
says very I think I think what he says
makes sense and I'll do that I just
wanted to remind the authors of the cat
port API doc that we should decide what
it means for the captive portal API URL
to change and okay good yeah thank you
all
see some greatness