should be good folks welcome this is the
distributed mobility management group I
was wakened early and our area director
Suresh as a family emergency he is not
able to be here but I believe Terri will
be here at some point and he will be
monitoring this meeting so today's
agenda before getting started okay this
is the neutral statement this meeting is
governed under Center in IETF policies
and code of conduct please be aware of
those rules
these are framed in member of Phi T of
documents please read them up and
there's also a ETF for IPR policy please
be aware of that so before the meeting I
think we need some note takers please
any volunteers we need to note takers
you can look up here any volunteers
absolute silence okay so who did not
send the slides in time I think say
yesterday 6:00 p.m. was the deadline and
at least I know as far as we know sort
of the song gets on us so ha the subtle
son would you be able to take the
meeting minutes please
okay thank you and we need one more
anybody else okay all right I think we
Carlos she's okay I think this is your
first meeting right it will be a good
experience for you if you take some
notes yeah okay thank you so much
all right so this is the let's review
the status of each sha IETF documents or
first one is the on-demand mobility
management document so this completed
last call recent to iesg and there was
some feedback and authors have not yet
resolved those issues yet but today you
know there's going to be a presentation
and I think Brian Haberman has is one of
the reviewers he's going to be here as
well he's going to give his feedback
so let's wait for that that is one
document the second one is the DMM
deployment model so I think you know I
think the question is you know you're
wondering whether you know we should
continue with this or you know is it
truly needed you know I think that is
one thing but let's let's hold on to
this I think you know for now but we
should at some point you need to make a
call whether we should you know
value in this document or we should you
know take this up and in fold into other
documents is one of the key question
that you know we are struggling with the
other thing SRA six mobile user plain I
think this is on a good track or all
there have been some good discussions
but after my idea one of the haven't
seen you know we haven't seen many
discussions but overall this on a good
track you know I think the others are
making putting a lot of efforts and I
think we are quite you know happy with
the progress and there's another
document which is the the the pv6 the
DMM document that is Carlos as the first
version was posted zero zero version was
posted in the last meeting right after
the last meeting and I think today
there's going to be a presentation let's
review the status of that and the FPC
document this is one document that went
through significant amount of
contributions from the authors lots of
work went in I think it's time to wrap
this up and again I think you know one
thing you are struggling with this is we
need to get some you know feedback from
the you know from the working group we
need more discussions more comments I
think that others have put in a lot of
efforts but I think we need some good
reviews all right and moving on I think
this another the distributed mobility
anchoring I think this is I think we or
the last you know few meetings I think
in like we said essentially you were not
happy with the quality of this document
and so we had a point they editor for
this and Carlos kindly you know two core
and he did a complete rewrite at the
document what was 80 pages came down to
literally like you know order 20 pages
so here you know overall it's a quality
document at this point but at the same
time it also reset so everything in the
sense that we again need a new set of
radius because it's we're almost at a
0-0 version but because you know I think
it's a rewrite of the document but
technically the document is stable right
I think but we need some reviewers I
think you know I think
any anywhere any volunteers anybody can
review this document it provides some
you know feedback I think that's you
know maybe after Carlos presentation
let's you know identify some reviews and
I think the one more
the ammon ID document is under the
maintenance category this finally is
going to be published as RFC 83-71
congratulations to Charlie Perkins and
others I think I did from what I
remember this document was it's been
there for a while I believe it was
published if I remember if I can now my
daughter was born and now she's a
teenager so it's as old as that so so a
license statement I think there were few
LS treatments I think one is there is a
3-2 BLS request from City for working
group mainly essentially it's an update
on the work that they're doing with
respect to mobile use a plain
optimization and they wanted you know
some feedback from IETF and like an
update from idea for what we are doing
and like how it you know how we can you
know help those efforts right I read
drafted a response and the response was
sent to the working group and we got
some comments and I think you know we
have a finally discussion slot just to
make sure that the working group is on
on the same page with the with respect
to the response response that we are
sending right and I think let's discuss
that and finally I think these are the
new set of you know essentially new set
of documents that were published after
idea 101 right a few or mainly the
survey six based you know pocs I think
you know some again mostly around user
plain optimization I think because there
is a burning topic in 3gpp and I think
you know that's that's the key point of
discussion right and I think let's you
know some of these documents are
allotted time slot and you know we will
be you know discussing those documents
and I think with that let's start our
first you know presentation
it will be lying on the FPC work just
just one second actually I think our
blue sheets please everybody please sign
the blue sheets I think they should so
just remind your right so this is about
control your separation many to many
clients amo so we have the concept of
all NC and essentially nothing's changed
right the last several revisions so our
job in this document is kind of a
semantic selection basically notes that
are actually providing reporting
services as well as Jeff's basically
implementing your desire for policies
and contractions so from 101 so from 101
right what we're really doing is we had
a few actually so we've had constant
service influence if we eliminated those
that was actually discussed in one we
actually put that out the mail is third
one its
okay employees and groups and then by
looking at our primary use it is which
is Triple D s that we're really
emulating are able to successfully
eliminate the influence in structures or
sown in show compliance or things like
triple yes and selection we were also
able to demonstrate that it quiet view
the selection and equality agencies of
the information model is better and
appears to be sufficient with what we
currently do a production what some
people are constantly don't mean to so
we had review the yank memorandum be a
compliance really the end result there
was basically explaining really weird in
MB aid and some of the concept applies
if you read the document at the unit of
the facts so the compliance information
as well as advanced attractiveness so we
did change a few configure statements
row for catching that so as we submitted
so that's actually why there didn't
follow up Kaminsky version 11 so right
we did add more examples we only had a
few in the beginning part of this was as
we went from nine to ten it was a major
rewrite and so we want to make sure we
had an example for each of the major
data structures as well as a life cycle
as we talked about in 101 policy base
we're a template based design and so we
wanted to make sure that we were
completely backed up in terms of having
examples in the document so it's a
little bit bigger but what we did was we
basically reduced it using editing and
then added more back from the examples
so it's a lightweight update to the spec
so if you've read version 10 it's very
consistent with that the biggest change
as we talked about on the mailing list
with service groups and I'll just kind
of blast through these really quick in
the interest of time but what we're
trying to do here is really enable the
selection so once again we're interested
in making sure there's
information available for this to be
done but we're not worried since we're
not specifying a protocol in terms of
who's actually doing the selection the
clients are agents so in several
examples that we did in terms of
bouncing its 3gpp as well as IETF
applications in production it seems to
hold up quite well as we talked about
before we're template based so we talked
about this in 101 but we do have a
lightweight language infrastructure and
this is actually then used for the base
information model to keep the front
section short in the information model
and then if you really want a verbose
dissertation the yang will be more than
sufficient we then broke out the entity
and config data policy really hasn't
changed so thank you so policy really
hasn't changed what's actually happened
here is by adding the examples right
we're able to talk a bit more about how
the usage applies down in here we're
able to show more of the lifecycle so
once again look to those examples those
are going to help you out quite a bit
but we were able to demonstrate full
lifecycle models in the document data
planes once again haven't changed we do
right with the policy configuration this
was something we did not have time to
talk about in 101 just as a reminder the
biggest change that we did from version
to version 10 was we put the policy
templates underneath the data plane and
eliminated some of the old concepts of
those errors so basically the system's
really simple you specify your policy
templates to install them on the data
plane node you set up a DPM policy
configuration and then that's your pre
install for so for those of us who have
ever been wondering how pre-installed
rules work this would be kind of your
answer so you can actually pre install
and then when it comes to the mobility
context you can then reference those
pre-installed rules that are here on the
data point node you can also have
policies on the data play node that just
apply to all traffic so this is just a
general policy application you don't
have to think about it in terms of a
mobility context the context as the
structure implies right is there
and we see with respect to kind of our
overall design you'll see we can pull in
mobile node specific policies the DPN
specific policies if our domain specific
policies or templates if you actually
use a domain to actually select this
this is for those of us that worried
about roaming you have the specifically
assigned policy that's available that
came from the DPN so we're looking for
and this gives you your traceability
make sure it was actually installed and
then within a specific service data flow
you can actually have a service data
flow policy and those are typically
dynamic rules that are built on the fly
most prevalent application is halti but
you'll see that it's all basically there
so that's it's with the exception of
monitors those haven't changed in a long
time watch what you want how you want it
this now shows you the operations so
this is kind of that overall I'll leave
this once again for your reference the
overall lifecycle of installing probing
the one thing to note right is even in
the Pro you know the basis semantics of
the protocol everything comes back by a
notification so you actually use a probe
stimulate a response you don't get the
data back in a response on monitors
configure results and result
notifications have not changed in
several revisions and then probably the
big thing that we talked about in
version 10 was how operations been
modified so we do follow yang patch
style operations at the FPC semantic
level and this allows us to actually do
some interesting things probably the the
one that's the most interesting is the
move so the idea of moving policies
between data plane nodes in a single
command as opposed to kind of picking
them up telling one guy he's
uninstalling it's only the other guy
that he's installing so we're able to
actually run a lot of this in the design
the inserts and the merges are also
interesting so it allows us to kind of
set up a situation with the operations
work and minimize the over the wire
communication as it's eventually
realized in a protocol next steps as
we've talked about
we're done guys so we're not intending
to add anymore we've made our editing
passes we've closed all of our action
items so at this point what we really
need as was said was we need reviewers
and to get a good couple set of reviews
so we can go ahead and get this thing to
last call
okay thank you light so like can you
comment on the so as far as you're
concerned all the issues have been
addressed right there is one thing
now can you you've been you know working
on the open source efforts can you yeah
so we we still have out the two existing
implementations and and they're
primarily version 4 based because a lot
of activity happened from about version
7 to version 10 and then as we said
really version 11 and then when we made
the area with 12 11 and 12 a really
error correction 10 so the codebase has
been out for it's been open source like
the open daylight one I think for now a
year and a half and we've got different
people using it at various stages so
we've even learned that there's some
operators who have actually done a trial
where they inserted it tested it out and
pulled it back so it's it's fairly
mature sure but that's a new thing to
the conclusion yeah absolutely because
right now just to let you know on the
open daylight and it's actually a it's
it's more of a job at issue and and
right we this is the first time we're
talking call processing with yang right
so that's kind of a new concept so right
now we're doing about a thousand TPS
with a triple redundant you know Sdn
cluster right because we were worried
about five 9s as an operator all right
and that's requiring about 12 CPU cores
we'd like to see that shrink and the
shrinkage is going to come from the fact
that the code base we're using is using
TCP and other items so we want to do the
updates because the protocol also has
many optimizations like the merge and
the replace so we know we're going to
get some efficiencies there and it's an
opportunity to have greater protocols
yeah all right so I think we need to we
need some reviews maybe you know let's
identify some of us
we can now send it to issue last call
thank you thank you Lyle okay next one
is extensions for demon Carlos you're
ten minutes okay I plan to use less than
10 minutes so should be fast there's not
a line with this one okay so basically
briefly to remind the status of the
draft and the history where we started
with this and where we are now
then again I will very quickly summarize
the operation of the document for you
for those that are not aware and then I
will basically ask for previews which is
the main point of actually this
presentation today so so in terms of the
story of the graph these drug wars are
adopted as working with document after
longer meeting although has been there
for quite a while since actually since
the beginning of the DMM working group
we started working on this solution and
we even had a couple of kind of demo
events in collocated with ITF meetings
so we have implementation available on
this document and the solution is
basically a Pima base stations for DMS
so very simple we basically push a
mobility to the edge and allowed to have
more than one core working
simultaneously for a given mobile node
by the mobile node having multiple
prefixes allocated so basically every
time I'm aware now that attaches to a
network it gets an ipv6 prefix anchored
that at that access router and it
continues using the former prefixes that
were allocated in previews or by
previous access routers so basically
it's the that that simple way of
ensuring which ability of the prefixes
and then by the time the device stopped
using those prefixes continues in the
end the new ones that are allocated so
the solution is partially
rooted in the sense that we have
distributed at a plane so the anchors
are at they at the edge and then we have
a kind of centralized control plane an
entity that takes care of keeping all
the windings of the mobility bindings
and ensuring that the if an access
router get the proper information to
establish the tunneling and every
direction of the packets so here is a
bit of terminology so we have a couple
of I mean the uncor the router we call
it mobility and called an access router
but it's basically the regular router
that is concentrating the access router
LMA and functionalities depending on the
prefix and the and the mobile node and
then we have this entity that is a
centralized controller entity but we
cause it relies mobility database and
basically as I mentioned keeping the
dependence from the mobility of the VIP
my notes so here maybe you can write
okay just a picture maybe not okay so
basically this is a simple picture
summarizing the what happens when the
device attaches to the network attached
it to a access router and then the
signal is sent to this CMD to
decentralize control plane entity which
is the one that creates divining and
replies with the pba to the to Virata so
basically this kind of as the CND is the
LMA and the Mar at this point in time is
actually not even a mark is basically
the encoding the preface that is locally
allocated from from data Explorer then
if we move it device move maybe you can
also put a picture on so in that case if
the device attaches to a different exit
router it will also signal that will be
detected that will be seen added to the
to the scene into a centralized
mobility database and that guy will be
the one signaling to the different
anchors that are available or are active
at a time in this case the pivot one and
any one the new one will knock it
locally and corporate fix and the neck
the the other one will set up a panel
with a new point of attachment in this
case the divine we have two addresses
one on call at mark two there is no need
for any tunnel anything is a circular
route
for that prefix and one ankle at marwan
the traffic will be related to the
current location which is be a mark 2 so
basically is standing be meep to support
multiple angles and next one which is
should be the last one so this in this
division we seems the adoption we
address all the comments we got actually
quite a few revisions from during the
option call from different guys so we
have results reviews in the current
version so the document although has
been presently adopted is point mature
in the sense that we had a lot of
revisions when it was individual so we
really need some reviews to move it
forward so that's what I would like to
do a sixer see they can ask for reviews
I come on appeal myself for example for
the previous one to review with somebody
from the team and do you this one this
kind of things I guess no I think we
need definitely need more reviews folks
anyone ideas Thanks force you need more
contribution I think in a few we cannot
move this work without your contractions
please you know you whether you like it
or not we need to review that often and
post comments please any any any other
volunteers okay very good so we have
Danny and like alright okay okay very
good thank you
ok ok so that so thanks Carlos and I
think that's about it right yeah very
good
so this is a asana v6 for mobile user
plane it will be Pablo yeah I think it
just wants yeah yeah I can take this
okay yeah there's an update on the
working group document yeah let's go so
good morning this is pooja from Cisco
this is an update on drop by tfGM I'm
sorry six mobile airplane it would be
quite fast so the summary of updates
from version one to version two it was
in essence just to clarify some of the
questions that we had on the mailing
list so first one of them was to clarify
the type of PD you system supported so
in essence this IP v4 v6 we only seek
serenade on a structure and in the in
the drop you actually have which is
obvious expansions in supporting which
kind of PD uses anti the second
modification that we introduced in a
draft will we added an appendix where we
added an to current implementations so
we have an open source p4 code that is
implementing the sorry six functions
that are introduced in this document is
specific to mobility and we also have
two ongoing talks for M Court and open
air interface which we documented in a
separate draft
we are just referencing to it we also
added some references to the what
technologies are used for networking
slicing so this is referring to other
crafts and we are added some control
plan considerations there was also
another we fix some typos as well and
there was additionally there is one more
change in the draft which is just a
clarification and how the interworking
mechanism works so the end so d end at M
that could be six that t function and
how does it work based on our question
that there wasn't a draft
so as nexus tips what the authors what
we are working on is on how to to
support a different gtp you messages and
extension headers so for example if
ideas container we are still analyzing
how to do this we believe that
maybe we do not need to modify the gtp
you extensional Heather but this is a
still being discussed if you have any
input please or any feedback test please
come to us and then there was also
another question on how we support
different types of EPF so for example
uplink classifier idea for branching
point and we need to add an illustration
on the draft and on this topic that we
will add and we are working on that's it
for the update any feedback is welcome
so Pablo with respect to the various PEC
to the document like how much work is
left and so I don't think there is that
much work left on the draft we just say
the most important topic is just which
was then the function coverage we also
received some comments on the motivation
of this work and for this reason the
authors have worked in a separate raft
which we just posted last Sunday we are
not presenting that is explaining the
use cases for every six and mobility and
that's only deployment of the open
source you mention implementation yes so
the open source implementation RC under
development it is not fully finalized
open they are work in progress the first
phase is completed by the see there are
several phases and this is the community
that will be discussed later okay so has
there been any feedback from 3gpp on
this document any reviews anybody else
any feedback any reviews from 3gpp folks
please
satoru mastema Softbank um specifically
this document does not leave you by CPP
folks but certain for some of the field
work really hard line discussion but uh
later on this agenda at the feet of upon
the Year Honor Society
so then those will be as kind of the SL
physics we take into account by them
thank you so we need to keep this for
some we need more reviews okay
please I'm also working in fact Istanbul
in CPP I said um I have you these people
before for I don't know three division
maybe in what I think most a lot of
constant revision based on the forty TDP
you function and the faculty there's a
lot of a new function have been
introduced by the faculty for example we
forget serious now asking that the paper
had not aware of document is in your
function don't need any consideration
how to set boundaries and do excuse me
can you please repeat your question I
said there's some new fifty introduced
some new function for the user plan
function for example like a vanity press
indication and qfo I first follow
identity this add new identity have been
introduced for the new William Ltd you
but I say because a city for had not
defined anyway you but we need to
include this new function and identity
in the end you use a plan protocol but
based on I checked
Boyan this new function has not been
discussed in your paper
thank you for your feedback so this is
part of the work that we are analyzing
as part of next steps so as part of
analyzing how the GDP you messages an
extension headers will
analyzing how to eat and go directly at
five relational for compliments
yeah thank you okay thank you
so I think Duchenne can you comment
posted your comment on qfi to the
working group maybe you can post a
comment so that's about it right now
publish okay thank you thank you think
next is to be good or distributed
mobility occurring revised yeah okay
hello
this campus again so I'm really update
on the issue that Molly the anchor draft
so just the status as we mentioned at
the beginning we have a significant
update for London so we went from more
than forty pages to around 50 so trying
to improve their ability at the document
and also improve the chances of people
willing to take a look at it so that was
the main goal at when we did that so we
try to simplify the complexity
simplified that Rowan's try to have a
less maybe less ambitious scope but more
useful and since then we we had a review
from Marco that was very very useful and
we have a couple of revisions in since
then trying to address the comments from
from Marco so we try to improve the
focus at the documents or less PP simple
that was a principle that we we try to
do or with we have in mind basically we
we believe that another document is much
easier to read and it's more concrete
I don't know Marco if you have the
chance to take a look at the revision
that will be helpful did you in the
future in you can we can discuss offline
about that and also the drop is
available me happening based somebody
wants to contribute we can do it
directly there so this is the
the table of contents of the version 0-8
so the one that we beat for London and
this is the table of content of the
version that we have in version 10 there
isn't something that is less because
there is a type own version 10 something
that shouldn't be there but I will
remove that after the meeting but
basically what we try to do is to
identify the kind of three on Korean
cases that we we have which are the what
we call in America case the Mobility
case in which we use traffic radiation
and the mobility case in which we have
fun quarter location this basically came
up from the review that Marco did the
suggestion that he he proposed to keep
data structure or to use data structure
so these are the three cases that we
consider so they know many cases there
is no need of an arrest continuity they
are the mobility is either even either
sorry not require or sandal by on
another layer layer four application
layer whatever so basically there is no
mobility at all they know every time it
moves its changes addresses that simple
and then we have the mobility cases and
in that case in that we have two sub
cases one s where we have traffic
federation so when the move one node
moves to another point of attachment the
traffic for the preface that why not
values in is redirected to the current
point of attachment so this basically
the case of the drafted a president
before and then the retailer case in
which the anchor is actually relegated
so that's more complex that require some
support in the network in order to
actually move the anchor of the demo I
notice you see so those are the three
cases that we described in the in the
document so as before again next steps
we believe that argument is now stable
in the sense that we reduce the
complexity we got a initial to you from
Marco basically saying if I understood
probably otherwise correct me if I is at
your point that we were on the right
track in terms of simplifying the
document now we fully address the
revision of Marco with in more reviews
because as we mentioned this
really had a lot of changes since before
London so now it's something that is not
simpler to read a much shorter so I
would like to really as you guys could
take a look at the data point because
otherwise we cannot do anything else I
mean from my stylist so thank you Carla
so other than the rewrite of the
document you know what are the technical
changes did you make any changes
basically I summarized those in in
London good reviews I mean we remove all
the stuff related to your icon mobility
and Korean things with Nemo part we also
simplify so basically you focus on very
simple things like those are the three
cases those are the things that you need
to do those are the entities referring
to this that I mean early that is in the
deployment model I think document so we
try to use the actual terminology that
is kind of adapted in the working group
and it's really simple so I mean we just
remove all the fat kind of thing focus
on the three main cases that are those
three ones and then we provide some
pictures and like okay in this case this
is the entity this identity this is the
scenery that will require a play maybe I
have one proposal since this document
how it should be you know aligned with
other solution document so me as
proposed that FPC government
Hauser's and also the skin routing token
answers have to reveal that to make sure
that is aligned so any any other any
questions comments okay thank you think
so the next one we have on the agenda is
Danny is going to present an update Oh
so we also have brand thank you Brian
for coming yeah so then you think you're
going to give an update on you know if I
use the comments
yes I'll provide a short presentation
because earlier this week I met with
yeah yeah roughly like getting your okay
timewise I think you're roughly it okay
I hope I won't mean ten minutes anyway
we had a discussion early this morning I
just to remind the group the document
went through a preview by Brian and he
had five comments will listed the
comments on the list and the initial
response and since then we had some
email exchange trying to resolve these
issues and can we go through the next
slide okay so I would like to present
two issues in which we have action items
change in the text I guess the rest if
people are interested in the rest they
can read the presentation so the first
one and I think the most the one that
was initially acknowledged is that the
draft uses the term IP session
continuity and IP session is really well
defined and the comment was either
define what IP session is or better yet
use a different term and initially we
provided various alternatives and I
think that we came to an agreement that
we will use the term session continuity
rather than IP session continuity and in
addition to that there were some text
changes as a result and I pointed out
here
crucial one and that is rather than
having the text the ability to maintain
an ongoing IP session since we are
changing IP session we change the text
to the ability to maintain an ongoing
transport interaction now Brian and I
agree on these changes but we felt that
we need to present that to the working
group receive approval from the working
group on these changes so hopefully we
can do that and the next issue is I
think issue number 386 no not this one
no okay this one so the feeling was that
okay we describe the extensions for the
socket interface but the feeling was
that the description of the whole
picture meaning okay an application
requires something from using the socket
interface how is the interaction with
the network or does the network - what
does it reply and things like that could
be better described in the draft so we
agree - and initially I wasn't sure I
wanted to do that because we didn't want
to impose a specific solution for this
would be done there could be different
alternatives but eventually we agreed
that maybe better explanation could help
so we are going to add an example of
some message flow indicating that this
is an example it's not the only message
flow which is correct but hopefully that
will improve the reader help people
understand
the draft better so these are really the
two action items that the writers have
and and that was the agreement in our
Monday morning session and my next step
is to update the draft openly as early
as next week and I'm not sure about the
process do we have to go through work
last fall again it depends on the
changes okay so I will post the changes
and if anyone has comments on yes
mascots HT consulting I lived through
the OSI Wars I'm a Stax person and going
back to come about IP session to you
just say safe session you can't really
say transport unless you can assure you
do not disrupt the transport port
assignments which is an OS concept so
only thing you can say I believe is
session continuity IP continuity only
applies if because of whatever you
actually maintain the IP addressing
which you actually don't so being a
survivor ragazza
I would say that you should just say
session continuity and leave it at that
can you move back to the first issue you
were referring to the first issue right
[Music]
for those of us who survive gossip so
what what is your comment you dissing
continuity just session continuity
that's does it don't not transfer
continuity because that's an OS concept
you can't make any statement about
transport continuity and you are
definitely not IP content right so so
first of all we don't have transfer
continuity in the new we mentioned that
in your talking oh I'm sorry you may
have misspoken I'm sorry I'm sorry okay
so I agree to be very accurate you're
right but there is
one mode in which the IP source address
is maintained and that's part of the
service that the network does provide
very clearly state it is IP session
continuity in that case if you are
really maintaining that IP address in
that move and you're not disrupting it
then you can make that set course of
what is an IP session exactly this is
what we're trying to avoid yeah so again
those of us who survived the OSI wars
okay and really lived all those those
debates yeah it's okay okay thank you
but I am your feedback yeah Brian Berman
and I definitely did not have yellow dot
but I will say that since this document
is an ad evaluation before the working
group actually goes and does anything
they should wait for feedback from the
ad because he may have additional
comments and he wants you guys to
address so I told Danny this the other
day I am NOT the gating factor I just
make the reviews it's up to the ad who
actually asked with reviews to decide
which ones are important which ones
aren't
and what comments they want address
before they actually move it to is via
or two into IETF last call okay so bring
but with the changes that be a great
opponent and if those changes are made
are you okay
moving this document forward so my my
basically issues two three and four or
driven by the fact that there is not
enough descriptions in the document for
someone to actually look at it from from
the outside and say okay I understand
how this concept is supposed to work if
Danny goes in and does he put any puts
of changes to kind of give that
conceptual example then that should help
with that clarity because you know it's
hard enough for for somebody who to
review it who's not involved in the
working group but they're involved in
the idea if you ask somebody who's
actually in the interior if you ask
somebody to review this from say the
transport area or the security area they
need that context
right and so you I would much rather see
you guys fix this clarity problem here
sooner rather than later so that you
don't get you know three discusses from
three different areas and then have to
try and go back and retrofit everything
yeah yeah very good thanks fun I think
that helps I think Danny I think
definitely there is work for this I
think you know discuss it's rich but Tom
so 3d movie is currently reviewing
referencing this document right not this
document it's referencing there are
other extension extension which
reference yeah should but the the basis
yes yeah okay okay so but so you know I
think is to update draft yeah I will
post it and yeah for sure okay thank you
alright thank you
oh I think next one should be more
correct we have the mobility of a
floating anchor so this is a brief
update on the floating anchors draft and
since we have ten minutes so if you need
details please have a look to the draft
and or to series presentation from last
idea at the moment so for today we just
want to highlight a little bit the basic
principles of that approach and how it
fits into the overall picture of the
data plane discussion so the draft with
the basic principles and operation has
been published before last ITF and has
been discussed in the meanwhile we
received some very wearable comments
which cost some discussion on the
mailing list some of the comments went a
little bit ahead of the basic principles
but very important to see how that
concept fits when being deployed with a
cellular architecture so in the next
revision we plan to publish soon
would like to address most of these
items at some level alright so there are
the main the main objectives in general
is to meet the requirement of future
connectivity services which will
comprise huge diversity in device types
different traffic makes mobility
communication parents etc also Network
slicing for customized provisioning of
network should be in the account just a
reference to current study and 3gpp
about our reliability and low latency
communication which really discusses
also the dilemma city in the network by
moving and devices but also changing
data on network so that peering seems to
be important in particular for edge
computation and services so that's our
main objectives in general we look at
annexes independent data plane we would
like to leverage the currently being
discussed on different data plane
protocols in the and the programmatic
tools in the view of a customized data
plane so by the architecture we propose
we enable optimized routes and between
the mobile node and one or multiple
correspondence services yeah moving from
centralized or fixed anchor to
decentralize data plane that's the
original requirement an objective of the
DMM working group which is on stage
since a while and last but not least in
the draft we address and would like to
strengthen the discussion on how that
approach can be deployed and integrated
tightly or loosely where the mobile
cellular architecture so as that we want
to move from a single mobility gateway
to programmable access whereas the edges
are on the one inside the mobile H which
is here sorry for the small picture we
have a bigger one on the next slide and
on the other hand side the correspondent
that shows which is
one or multiple correspondent notes or
services in a data center so by applying
default routes in between one or
multiple correspondent edges on the
mobile knowledge we have a low number of
data plane nodes which are impacted so
in case the mobile moves and gets a new
mobile edge being assigned we apply
house States at the correspondent edges
and enable optimized roaring in between
the multiple services and the mobile
node we have an example on the next
slide here so to enable this traffic
steering the approach is compatible with
any of the currently being discussed
data plane protocols so the draft
currently focuses on segment routing
because here we have the flexibility in
choosing intermediate hops between the
corresponding edge and the mobile edge
but other proposals like locator
rewriting or any ID lock separation kind
of approach I can apply it here these
states that the correspondent edge are
of or can be of transient nature so
whenever the mobile node gives up its IP
address and IP address continually is
not required anymore
the correspondent edge states can be
diminished as what not least by the
programmatic flexibility we can go
beyond the actual traffic steering and
additional states and policies for
metering who is monitoring reporting
gating whatever also paging support can
be taking into account and enforce in
any of these edges either mobile or
correspondent a brief example here very
similar to what's represented last idea
so the control plane let's not focus too
much on that here but we have the
control plane leveraging topology
awareness and location awareness on the
data plane let's assume the mobile node
attaches to a nexus gateway to purchase
its IP address anchor so here in the
example there with the green IP address
with prefix 2 from gateway 2 is the one
that's to be maintained so IP address
continuty
has to be supported when the mobile node
gets a new access gateway being assigned
in addition the mobile node may receive
a local prefix which is route over but
valid only as long as the mobile node is
attached to access gateway to so in that
example the mobile node has
communication with two correspondent
nodes one you can see here and the other
one here so since the IP address is from
X's gateway to whose network default
routes apply in between correspondent
nodes and the mobile node so what
happens if the mobile moves and gets
assigned a new access gateway so further
requirement on the local prefix the
yellow one is deprecated and the mobile
node gets a new one but the green IP
address has to be maintained so we call
that IP address continuity somehow
related to a previous discussion with
Danny's drafts or maybe in terms of
terminology we have to line it here
important point is that the control
plane can leverage the programmability
of the correspondent edges by enforcing
additional policies for traffic steering
so what we do is basically enforcing
States at the correspondent edges
enabling segment routing ideally located
separation approaches tunneling whatever
you want to steer the traffic to the
Mobile's current access gateway so by
that we can enable optimized routing the
feedback we received was very valuable
so since the graph focuses on segment
routing there was a request to the visa
section about how that works with other
data plane protocols like iolaus then
there was a request to add more
information about additional functional
or non-functional aspects like device
dormancy and paging
so that's very important if you
integrate that approach with a cellular
network or the mobile may enter
this continuous reception mode and the
exact location of the mobile node is not
available in all the day looking nodes
so that's something we consider very
high importance and we will add a
section on that here so the big question
on the mailing list was how the
correspondent edges get information from
the control plane for traffic steering
so the current route focuses on a
reactive approach which is work working
but improvements can be made here so we
are currently discussing the evaluating
different proactive approaches just to
avoid factory ordering and that kind of
things have been addressed in the
feedback we received so that's very well
ability to update the draft there was a
question of so if we move the exes edge
to the very much extreme so two base
station or something that axis edge
maybe axis specific but we could clarify
that if we have a loose coupling between
the programmable data plane node at the
edge and the actual radio technology or
fixed on technology so there is no no
tight binding between that approach that
we present in the draft and the actual
access technology here same the
interfaces so how do the correspondent
edges receive the policies for traffic
steering and additional ones for
metering whatever from the control plan
so in the view of cellular integration
cellular technologies and architects are
very particular but we have some ideas
which we would like to discuss with you
folks how that picture could fit into a
3gpp next-gen architecture as an example
and this is also pretty much related to
some proposals that are currently being
discussed in 3gpp where the data network
plays a role in influencing the traffic
steering policies last but not least so
correspondent edges have States when do
we actually delete the states is that
something in force
by the control plane is it soft state so
there are a few things that should still
be thought about and actually captured
in the draft so more comments are of
course appreciated and hope during this
week and then online we can have more
discussion about these ok thank you a
macro if there are any comments for this
draft any questions ok so I'd like to
ask how many people are resist raft
please raise your hands
okay sir of you so maybe I think for the
next step the answers may keep update on
the menu lists and triggers on this
constraint here
that's next step yes I think I'm author
on this doctrine I think any reviews
okay thank you macro next one is the the
laser and statement from 3gpp on city
for I think you know we had some
discussions on the mailer but I think it
will be very good subtle sound do you
want to just you know talk about it I
know then you know it's you know we have
yeah thank you don't have slides on this
yeah yeah yeah subtle massima series PP
hot on the good can show the book funny
fortunately you know we did not make us
like this
yeah yeah this is what I presently in
the society meeting in London on what we
asked to IFD mmm is to provide any
information regarding the user Prime
protocol so then you can see the mini
activity on this so I really appreciate
all the effort on the ITF side so that
the discussion and out comedy thought
about discussing videos so if you can
show the draft autism in statement or
the setp I at least I think the content
yes the good good river to like show the
the current state of a creative side so
this was a response I think the response
that we drafted and what was discussed
in the mailer was this I think they were
one or two minor comments but overall we
have so other as we equated to ITF had
to provide any information and with the
some additional information we will work
on the to this figure out the criteria
to compare the candidate solution and
then need to be stopped the award of the
candidate from the ITF side so I think a
dirty Gary probably techies under
content are including the the document
are only pointing to the data I internet
dwarf would be a suspicion suitable for
Dia and he is about to die the CPP for
us thank
so any any other comments on this a less
response you know this is what is going
out I think you know there were a few
comments
anybody who commented on the mailers do
you want to say anything or Dave yeah I
did Alan Erickson do you really want to
be pointing them but individual
submissions or do you want to hold this
to stuff that at least the working group
has agreed to work on because I mean
they're looking this is an issue of
managing expectations and if you're
giving them stuff that has no status is
not on track to have any status then
you're not sending on the right message
I think fair point are do I think this
is what you know I think last time what
we discussed we are not pointing to any
solution documents if you look at these
two individual documents that we
referenced I think you're differencing
three documents one is a working group
document which is on track to become a
standard I think that yeah because
that's that setting a right level
absolutely so the next two documents are
a requirement analysis yeah and you know
comparison of various approaches so
these are neutral to any one specific
approach so I think given that these
documents are neutral and we are stating
that you know IDF is not a couple of
points we are stating that idea which is
not going to pick any one document as
the document for this we are going to
standardize potentially maybe more than
one solution more than one protocol
right but the analysis the requirement
analysis that we are referencing that
because that may be useful work and we
are neutral to you know the solution
that means that is the thought process
so there folks are asked to reference
individual documents but we refuse to
list them out here yeah just to me I
don't know how a document can be a
completely neutral analysis except you
know if it hasn't been through the
process it is probably incomplete and
hasn't been fully commented on because
it wasn't adopted by the working group
so that for me is a bit of a red flag
and like I said you're setting the wrong
level of expectation as to how this
stuff is going to progress in the ietf
you know I 3 GPP you know they're trying
to work the schedules they've got a lot
to do on 5g they're doing a lot of
polling of the industry to see what is
there that they can consume and
something to me that is not working good
status just by definition isn't
consumable so yeah thank you thank you
do for the treatment yeah hi see this is
Uma from Bobby
so this response is good very good
actually but the only comment is please
say that this is initial response there
are various proposals that need to be
thoroughly discussed some of the
proposals recently published and some of
the some of the proposals are published
like you know last five ETF but not
significant discussion happened so it
say that this is initial response as we
we can send an updated response based on
the progress of the some of the work
example an apocryphal is there's a dino
presented last time so there's some some
more work need to be done on that so so
more we posted the text to the working
loop for you know for any changes right
I think so we are not editing this at
this point right I think you know if
there were any comments we gave a
deadline of last Friday right to make
any suggestions comes so we are just
going by you know what was discussed in
the manor so if you comment notes maybe
I I don't know if they say you need to
extend that you know we can probably
extend it for another few days for
additional comments but you know if you
have specific comments on the text
whatever that is please post it to the
manor no no I said the text is fine
please say that this is an initial
response
they'll been updated responds up maybe
after one month or two months I don't
know but even that has to be in the text
from Huawei two points the you planed
analysis basically is neutral in the
sense that we are basically trying to
pick up the 3gpp requirements and
conduct a study on what gtp does and
what the extensions to gtp will will
level provide to do it is not favoring
any particular solution is basically
completely studying that the 3G
requirements and that's why it's usual
as well as far as the optimization
optimized mobile user plan is concerned
there are different solutions that
you're considering in that in that in
that draft however we are not
particularly advocating a particular
solution because the the the final
decision actually is based on the
analysis that we TPP will will conduct
on its own and as a result all we are
doing in there we are trying to compare
different protocols with existing gtp
scope and and and behavior that's why
even in the in the optimum is mobile
user plain we stood away from doing any
any or prove providing any any final
decision in which one of these things we
are favored in terms of 3gpp study items
so they will pick up what what needs to
be done they will conduct this study we
are made merely providing information in
there okay thank you yeah thank you my
name is key of Maya I am the 3gpp
liaison person to ITF and I just wanted
to say that the discussions that are
going on in CT for they are focusing on
this and whether you have here a draft
with just a name in front of it or a
working group agree draft or adopted
draft or whatever I think that at the
moment secondary we you need to go on
with your work and you need to stay in
exchange with CT for if I guess you're
serious with this work and we need to
find out the stability of the work that
you are doing here and how it can be
adopted in CT for at the moment I agree
we have very tough timelines in suite
EPP but nevertheless we started to study
now and if you take longer then maybe
it's not really sixteen where this will
be adopted but really seventeen if if
there's an agreement to adopt anything
from
EMM Group outcome but I wouldn't go into
a discussion where practically our
timelines to switch BP timelines push
you too hard to complete your work make
sure that your work is stable and most
of all makes sure that the informal and
formal communication between this group
and ct4 is well in the life
thank you okay thank you for sharing
that yep this is Danny so just to add a
little bit to what Derek said and to
answer Dave 3gpp is well aware of the
statuses of the different drafts in ITF
so they understand the difference
between an individual draft and a
working group draft so they won't be
confused by whatever we provide them and
I also agree that we need to continue
the work especially as it's of interest
for ct4 and I think Gehrig is being a
middle polite or over polite
the reason issue of working ITF tends to
be in a much slower pace than what is
done in 3gpp and we should do this work
as fast as possible so that it could be
seriously addressed in cd44 released 16
or maybe release M&T okay Dave again
just one other thing I remember we had
the discussion of what class of
information we would Lee A's in London
and what it was is we would not provide
analysis we would simply provide raw
information and let's see t4 do the
analysis so we seem to have be going
backwards on that that is not true Dave
I think if you read the response that
you know that what you're seeing on the
screen we are clearly stating that you
know we are going to standardize now
potentially more than
solution or approach we are not going to
say you're only going to characterize
the solution approach but you're not
going to say that this is a ticket you
know all you are going to say is do
something you like you know approach one
approach to and characterize it in a
very neutral you know but but that's but
it's up against business based on the
system architecture the which one big ok
so I just want to go on record of having
expressed the concern and that and only
understanding was that was the agreement
so I hope whatever we do is consistent
with them absolutely thank you just give
my again I just want to say yes I'm a
polite person maybe too polite for ITF
I'm sorry for that one issue is of
course how fast you want this work to
conclude and to possibly be adopted in
in 3gpp that is up to you how fast you
can do the work and I don't want to
influence anything on that I think
you're progressing at the moment at a
very high speed and you have to be
careful that your work still stay stable
right the other thing is that the the
study we are conducting now in CT 4
relies on that you have a certain amount
of stability in your work and clarity
also in your work so you need to
progress it in a way that ct4 can
evaluate the outcome of your group and
see if it's really valuable or possible
to adopt it in in the city in 3gpp the
final decision whether we will go on
with Swiss GDP or with one of your
solutions that will be taken by CT 4 or
maybe not only CT 4 but also other
groups in 3gpp so from that perspective
I fully agree with what you said that
you can only provide us a set of
different solutions and we will evaluate
them in 3gpp but sort of the evaluation
of these solutions is not part of DMM to
my understanding Thanks yeah fair point
next time you can pick up the gloves
boxing gloves from the registration desk
I think people have a purpose um to
issue one use that as VP we have very
quickly working down then ITF other
assay this 11 says that this celebrity
TPU for diabetes 16 in understanding
even for the Whistling the faulty
Santa's is not a stable enough in a
settled over 20 study I think is kinda
studied in the assay to there's a lot of
new feature was introduced in a with 16
for example data that Travis there
impotent even accessed an alley between
50 40 and the Wi-Fi access and there's
also actually will have additional less
in communication in that way they were
introduced a to apparel kit video
connection for 1ue to improve the
reliability so in there's a lot of a new
feature and function point is cancer and
studying in CVP so I think it's very
hard for our our the amendment to follow
the steps or the purpose in in sweetie
pee even we working in ITF wrong heinous
sweetest and a fan is very powerful for
the progress of the standard I would
stand us so our previous authority that
we provided our text as as a current
tourism and that we continue you would
identify the real requirement upon the
poverty decision then we focus our our
our solution in current 5 DVD's beauty
isn't or enough to support 50
requirement okay thank you
so any final thoughts sorry to come
again yeah I just want to avoid that we
have a 3gpp discussion in this room
so what essay 2 is currently doing is
studying an enormous amount of new feet
just and nobody knows what will be the
outcome of that right and it's not your
job to evaluate it at this moment and
you can look at that you can draw some
conclusions from that that's fine but
from my understanding
let's take CT for as the single entry
point for the communication between the
MST mm on this topic and let CT force
evaluate what the real requirements in
release 16 will be this will change over
the time as other groups in 3gpp will
progress but let's keep that discussion
out of this room please no I understand
I think that's absolutely fair point
yeah you know this is you know if this
working group is going to interface with
3gpp I think we need to go a lot faster
and if we can go faster and impress 3gpp
hopefully they will return a response
just as fast okay thanks you know think
oh yeah she's next one I think with that
I think we are going to extend the you
know four so I think whatever you guys
have posted if there any objections to
the ls response please you know send it
to the mailer and I think but we will
extend the deadline by another few days
but that LS response will go out this
car this week just one second oops so
this is a new document I think this
analysis document roughly like 15
minutes buddy I'm just a homo from MGP
Laboratories in this presentation I will
talk about to use a pen photo per
architectural I suppose you see PP 4G
systems and we put the feedback for a
CPP first area I introduced background
on the overview
this arises work so we mainly have too
much patience on this process work first
is if showing a showing understanding
level or ITF side force with these
specifications it will be helped to make
three TPP folks recognize the ITF
proposal was concerning and it will be
helped to understand Assaf occasion for
IT folks and second we are clarifying
problem spaces and improve our points
it's very important for proposing new
portables to switch BP and we build at
this document should be part of recently
right so in this work we undereyes the
gtp you specification from TS two to
nine to eight months and 5g
architectural equipment from TF twenty
three five one five thirty two absolute
suite at cetera
in addition we extracted some evaluation
aspects for studying the use of plant
protocol flaunt
analyzed 5g architecture requirements
from the this work we provided a certain
gtp you the patient's six oxygen
requirements for user plane and seven
operational aspects in addition we could
find some potential gaps between the gtp
you as a current user plane protocol and
5g architecture the comments so in the
following few strides either explained
context of a nice draft so in these
tools right shows the gtp of its
operations for example gtp you is
basically point-to-point toneri product
and sometimes supports a point-to-point
tunneling and in the 5g architecture qfy
us qfy is used for identifying feeding
session and DDP you can convey GFI with
extensional header but the order of
extension headers note is not strict to
really define in the specification
document this is this this is a example
of gtp forward so it will be helped to
understand what did you a pocket in
these two right shows article
requirement 5g architecture so for
example in 5 g 5g architecture defines
PT session or four types of gtp bit of
station ipv4 IP received internet and a
structure so use a plane protocol passed
combat this PT session or 5g
architecture arose to how to repay you
thin flexible you be abstractions or
putting multiple ups in the data path so
this may cause increase of number of
data path or toners and 5g architecture
uses allows to create multiple qs4 all
indicated that way it's qf I into a PDF
session so here's a plane protocol must
compare ok qfi information
so this table shows average effects
abrogation aspects extracted from of
teacher government's so as I mentioned
in the previous right use the plane
protocol must convey every must cover
every decision time and earth nature of
the past use the plane protocol will be
required to support much point-to-point
protocol toneri to reduce a money load
of management of apostate also in the 5g
era various types of network access
network including other operating
operators network we connected to the 5g
core and so user plane will be liquid to
support dynamic use dynamic MTU
discovery and adjustment us controller
is still a very important point and
emulation so the first rising will be we
will have a we assume that the trans
pricing we may have big challenges for
example the processing leader which can
network and some slices share the same
physical resources such as ups and
sister beam and in some cases some
several Metro slices has different forum
forces so use a plane protocol may be
liquid to conveys such a reporting a
defiant swatting policy for each vices
so in the following slides are finally
put feedback from see TPP City for
meeting so there was a city for meeting
last week and we obtained some feedback
from city for folks
so these to thrive describes detail
details of the feedback and you can find
original document from bottom link in
this presentation I will introduce is a
2-2 characteristic feedback first is
things about QF the place of QA fly so
in the Alice's work we couldn't find the
description about the order of Q
extension header but in the recent
specification document describes are
noted for its recommends recommends that
qfi information should be contained in
the first extension header now secondly
is implementation of GTP you in the
sweetie PP so TF - 9 - 8 1 defines gtp
you it's p2p ternary protocol but 3gpp
allows to use a gtp like much point to
portable so like this video several UPF
may use same TV ID for the PD session so
from T's feedback now we could confirm
they're our query gaps between gtp you
and 5g architecture and we believe that
this mark is in the right direction so
lastly I've talked about next steps or
this document so for improving this
context so we need a more feedback
and review or feedback from both ITF and
3gpp side and we beat that this it
should be a part of later deploy and
also if this document is you think this
document input are very important or
useful so we would write to request the
this document the working look document
that's all thank you very much and you
can find the image examples of image
various aspects in the appendix thank
you very much ok thank you thank you son
so any comments that came from wall
again so everybody in this group to
actually read these analysis and we're
trying actually to use these analysis as
a base for or our own work in terms of
you know conducting competitor like
competitive analysis between different
different different approaches that
you're talking about the other dress so
this will basically put a ground work
together so that we can have a common
ground analyzing all those different
protocols against against the same thing
you know basically gives us an apple to
Apple comparison so any any any solution
that comes to the picture basically will
be will be looked at from from this
document perspective and see first but
ere we can satisfied all the all the
analysis and and the comparison that
you're we're trying to make based on
this before going forward two to three T
V P we set up these are the set of
basically protocols that we want to take
to you guys to look at the first to our
own work to make sure that you know
everything actually is in order before
we go to 3gpp with the list of protocols
to to for them to consider
that's basically the work that you're
trying to do you thank you thank you I
should do okay Dave again my
understanding of what we discussed at
the last meeting was we would not try
and do their thinking for them and I get
the import has just been described to me
is doing their thinking for them so
I have an issue with this harassment
here again from what we know I don't
think we are trying to actually do their
thinking for them we are basically
taking their their requirements and we
are trying to do our homework in terms
of putting a groundwork for our own
protocols that you're proposing let's
say you have five protocols that we are
suggesting as a to be evaluated by 3 GPP
this work is basically there to make
sure that these protocols and approaches
basically can do what ecology
requirements ask any other approaches to
actually do gtp can do it the least
those protocols can do is basically be
at par with gtp forget about like you
know being better but these are the
basically gives us the the the the first
pass tests in terms of in terms of the
other approaches are being proposed in
the Indian you're not trying to actually
tell to 3gpp that this is what you have
to do or whatever no you're taking their
specifications and we are trying to
basically create a bar for ourselves so
that when the new protocol or an
approach comes into for evaluation
provide us we basically have a bar to
consider those protocols yes right so
that that's the purpose of this work ok
all right
any so how many people have read this
document ok thank you
I think that's fair number of people I
think we need some discussions on the
mailing list you know based on law
they're good this amount of discussions
we'll be able to see on adoption at some
point yeah thank you next is it
optimized mobile user plain by Irish
myth Kalyani
this is Geoff Kalyani right ok
this is yes okay so you have 15 minutes
hi everyone my name is the ration that
I've aim from Huawei along with my
colleagues we have been putting together
a draft that talks about different
protocols and approaches to address some
of the 5g requirements as a as Shunsuke
mentioned in the in the previous one
what was that that piece basically is
what was missing in this piece the
requirements that we need to conduct or
work with this traffic basically is
considering - to compare different
protocols from the 3gpp requirements so
background I guess you guys are already
know about this treaty has issued the
ct4 has issued a new study welcome to us
there are references in there that you
can take a look the new revision of this
graph has gone through many many reviews
and we have done a lot of work in the in
the conference calls and receive
comments we receive also comments from
101 and this new revision basically is a
reflection of all those comments and and
we are trying to to address all the
issues that came up during those reviews
several protocols are basically being
considered here from SR v6 all the way
to Hardwick hybrid ICN which is a
relatively new one to d2 the document
the talk the document has been prepared
there as a submission for consideration
of different protocols by 3gpp and
that's what how we are positioning this
again you're not trying to actually tell
3gpp what to do we are just presenting
the facts and we're trying to actually
say these are the these are from our
perspective these are the contenders
that you might want to consider in your
evaluation the evaluation is not even
ours you're not trying to actually do
with the evaluation ourselves we do
however come back consider evaluating
these protocols against the the previous
strap that Suki and others are putting
together so what are the focuses of this
new object it basically focuses on 5g
architecture from the mobility
management
dr. Roman architecture now has been
added to the draft you're considering
the roaming architecture as well and how
these protocols basically behave in
terms of roaming support for different
mobility protocols within the operator
networks and then slicing for example
that's another consideration we have
made in the new division again the data
player architecture model for m9 because
the study all right and this is a very
important they study item that cc4
issued is is only applicable to the n9
interface the interface between the UPF
so n 3 & 6 & 3 or 4 & 2 they are all out
of the out of the out of the scope we
are only concentrating on the n9 to
place for now that's what is in scope
and we have the last one is the last
portion is a bit controversial because
we made it we made those classifications
with of the protocols that debate is
still ongoing and we might have to
revise it at the idea at the end of this
reviewed approaches so generally
speaking that the first two the first
two actually are the are the problem in
the models that you're following there
are two basic models that we considered
one of them is interworking and the
other one is the integrated model in the
interworking model the the idea is to
leave the 3gpp control plane intact and
for basically will remain the same and
three remains the same and and and and
four and six and will remain the same
and the only the only thing that we are
changing is the n9 from the upx
perspective the idea is to make sure
that they are still under the impression
that they are doing gtp they are
connecting to each other with gtp and
your we are dropping basically some sort
of gateways in in the middle to to allow
the operation to continue as it is today
the the one of the one of the biggest
objective is probably migration from
existing network to to the next and this
interworking model is aimed to to
actually address that how you actually
go from the existing gtp based model
to anything in the future basically
that's the bird the second one is the
integrated model which basically talks
about how ups will get integrated with
the new protocols and basically they we
start going toward the next generation
of n9 in mobile network the draft also
as I mentioned it has gone through some
sort of classifications in terms of you
know these protocols some of them are
locator based on them on lock ID and
some of them are ID based again this is
under debate whether we want to actually
classify these protocols as such there
are many different classifications and
and this might change as we go into the
future because again they're something
like SR v6 and lists can actually get
get classified as differently into the
into the model and that's why the debate
is sort of continues last but not least
there is a there is a there's another
draft that my colleagues will talk about
which takes advantage of 3gpp own
release 15 feature which is called an
uplink classifier again this is this is
another important aspect that we
considered in this new draft which
basically allows us to to fit the model
into interworking essentially even the
new new slices in body start appearing
we can use the uplink classifier as a
filter at the at the G note B to add the
two to separate the traffic in this
manner if we have a blank canvas slice
we can basically set the n9 to a
different approach or a different
protocol only for that particular slice
based on the filter that we put place in
the in the you SEL so this is this is
this is again another approach toward
the the migration basically which is in
any network we find that it's the most
important part you you cannot turn on
the switch and convert the old network
to the new one just like that another
good example is the use of ulc help
which basically allows us to to apply
any protocols in a smooth manner and
migrate the network out so and now a
little bit about one of the the rest of
the document basically goes through
through different approaches that we
have considered one of the approaches is
is an SR basics which we are positioning
as a as a possible protocol or approach
or for the annoying interface the
approach basically said okay so if I
have a GTP tunnel here the first
approach basically is addressing the
integrate into working model which we
allow us to drop the SRB state within
them in the middle and use some of the
existing drafts that are being worked
out but very voice a Toro and other
people here to to carry a tu IDs around
and and basically having a smooth
migration toward the new data plane once
we do that given that s our v6 gateways
now become can be viewed as network
functions these network functions can be
actually pushed into the into the UPF s
and therefore will provide us with the
integrated model if you want to go that
way
I have a question my name is Uma I'm
with this document from the day one last
year December with Kalyani but I am NOT
a co-author I'm not a contributor in
this document but I'm everywhere of all
the progression of this document I mean
aware of is to be in the offline calls
so my question is the service X is good
very good choice but only one comment I
like a survey six because people if a
give a comment people are thinking that
it's not like that it's good but the
problem with the drop in gtp drop in
replacement the problem with that
approach is you are mixing underlay with
overlay because you are putting PID
ripping off the TA ID from the gtp you
header and encoding as ipv6 eight the
problem with that approach is you are
forcing all under layers to be a service
six and ipv6 which is not which is not
you intended SR MPLS this will radiate a
plane which is assault he used Assessor
so let's not dictate operators what they
want to use I talked a couple of
operators in Europe from Xcor Kimbrough
point of view so there are lot of a lot
of existing deployments using other than
v6 ok so we need to be cognizant
that only that aspect otherwise the
document is great Lisa this like this
this need to be corrected I'll send a
mail to mailing list yesterday make this
comment to spring so I'll send an email
okay so so this is a comparison document
but this is not about one approach so
your comment is on one of the approach I
think please post a comment and I think
you know you guys should try to reflect
that point absolutely so we are we
actually this is this is something I've
taught off with with the Duomo as well
and we will short consider this in our
order some some work that is going on on
the sidelines to actually have enjoyed
working situation between SR v6 and MPLS
and other networks as well so they are
coming down the price I'll be going to
be as they come and you will basically
put put these things and we hope the
document accordingly okay so I think one
important thing is I think for every
solution you know because we are saying
you're characterizing it the feedback
has to be incorporated because otherwise
if you send this to 3gpp they say it's a
bad view because these analysis
documents I want to be absolutely
neutral absolutely yeah so again the
essence is not basically to to to favor
one one or one approach with the other
because we are just presenting facts and
what can be done using different
approaches it's the 3gpp that will pick
up these these draft and we'll take a
look at it and basically they can come
back and say okay probably you need to
actually give me some more information
I'm interested in this one please give
you more information about about this
approach so that that's how you're
looking at this whole thing as I said
like once we actually integrate the the
the SR v6 into the UPS then we can
actually start using other options like
te and introduce entropy and and for
example function chaining into the place
you got to remember the function
chaining is something that we see in the
IETF i something important 3 GPP might
don't actually look at it from from the
specifications allow for multiple
UPF in the india standards however we
might not go beyond the current svw and
PGW in the in the network any Turnstone
so again some of these things might be a
bit futuristic
of course the support for slicing will
will come up we will support the
splicing using these services and then
the next thing is toward fixed mobile
convergence with with ideologue the idea
is basically to support our gallant
readers or v6 which again has two models
at the interval team model and the
integrated model that can be done either
way I'm fleeing from a Nokia this was
support m9 interface yes
service chaining is on which interface
n9 no m6 no n9 because you can actually
pick up ups and put it me in between and
from once you actually have multiple ups
then you are actually talking about
service chaining so because we're there
you will have GTP's going from one UPF
to not of UPF to another ups we are rate
not reading the same concentrate well
you're talking about service chaining
I'm talking about chaining in general
whenever you actually drop more than one
view PF cinder in the data plane you
will have to continue consider another
gtp in the middle so this is supposed to
actually address that issue
John just point to the previous comment
the current specification say that
chaining will be on n6 and not online it
may change later but the current will be
specifically tolerant so I let me give
you another comment so today bi have we
have a whole bunch of functions are
actually being done within the FCW and
PG double if you want to actually
separate those functions and put them in
their own ups then you have to actually
steer traffic to those duties right so
that's where you need more channels and
that's where service chaining aspect of
S or v6 come to the picture not saying
that this is not the right product or it
should not be followed or anything but
just to say that that's the status in so
I think yeah quick response chaining is
an n6 interface you cannot characterize
and nine interfaces are you sending
because it can carry encapsulation
happens at the LCL yup that is a brand
for intuitive
that's not service change so where is
the on the Geo interface or where is the
I think I think part of the problem is
the terminology it I think we are
distinguishing if you serve is shining
and function chaining so service rating
you're absolutely right and six
but we at least myself I'm considering
function chaining as a form of service
training as well so that's why I think
they know we can actually put that app
to apply that concept into the in mind
as well just a quick note here service
chaining in a service if context is more
like cellulous programming and it is
broader concept for network
virtualization and other things so when
you drop cook here is a broader context
in terms of service programming where
you can do network virtualization at
wall which would be part of this thank
you
very quick very quick comment so I was
in some carts at the very beginning of
this work and I understand very well why
you focus on in nine and nine and six
we're out at six so now you bring in
service training on an nine which I also
think it's an in six issue so I was
wondering and at the beginning I asked
Kalani why not in including n6 into that
work because if you so so you still
assume the the PDI session anchor which
is one end point of nine is a central
anchor so if you move that anchor more
and more to the edge you mitigate the
impact of nine but you move the problems
to in six between which is in the
context of the MFI draft so it's related
problems and now if you introduced
service chaining it applies to both in
nine and at six
so if you don't introduce it to the
draft let's at least consider it in the
discussion what happens if you move the
PDS session anchor to the edge and how
to solve the problems yam in six so that
is exactly what I call in this slide if
you can see I didn't call it service
chaining at all I call it chaining right
so to us it is to me it's the is the
function chaining that you can today if
you look at the s gwgw the fact that
these guys are actually tied up together
it's basically create a chain of
functions right so you can actually
separate those functions and put them in
different different different boxes and
basically now you have a traffic
steering problem in your hand that you
have to actually take the traffic from
one point to the other point to the
other point to the other point all the
way to B to D to the PGW final function
that's what that's what we consider
chaining so it's not a service chaining
that n6 is
is trying to dress it's basically the
the multitude of functions that are
being available in PGW and sgw and there
is a way to actually separate those
those those functions constraining
what's the UPF and uplink less whereas
today to distribute between multiple
notes and you service chaining that's
right yeah so now you you bill you will
have to face the fact that now you have
to basically steer traffic between these
points of these function points that's
it okay I think we should so this habit
Rodya from Cisco I'm gonna go through
the LOC idea split approaches and the
rest of the document first list locate
the reservation protocol I would like to
clarify something here because we were
still hearing some misunderstanding on
this so the least working group was each
other a couple of years ago and one of
the main topics of the returning was to
separate the least control plane from
the least they deplane that work is
complete now the documents are about to
become standards so the the recipes that
are mentioned and they under the Queen
at about become a standards today when
someone says that these you see lives
that doesn't necessarily mean that there
isn't the least data plane so I said on
the on the first one and they on the
slide today you can use the least
concern plane to support many different
data planes and actually there are a few
documents that have innocently parties
that go in the deliver that so one thing
to notice here is that the instrument of
rank has been around for over 10 years
now and it's pretty mature and it's
reducing quite large deployments
operational experience with with this
protocol and it tackles mobility aspects
deeply in the in the in the protocol
there are several documents that go in
detail over different axis of a mobility
with list there is one in particular on
list for mobile networks and then on the
list data plane that has something you
can use with the list control plane but
is not the only option
basically discipline
do have hyssop in IP encapsulation with
a fix 16 byte here in in the middle
using UTM calculation are not the
critical stuff so two recent documents
that relevance for this work and for
these working group the least control
plane for for i'll a highly we'll talk a
bit toward and the least canto brief for
a services that we have recently
published so the last one is controlling
for SL v6 we are going to present it on
the least working group on Thursday so
you guys are free to common commander
and then on the on the right side of
this slide you can see the the models
that Alice was talking about the
integrity and inter working models run
an ID log perspective so you can have
the ideal of functionality integrated
into the UPS directly or you can have
them escape ways in the in the neck I
think we should practice on yeah so ila
another protocol it does others right
instead of encapsulation there are no
documents done by her but I'm sure that
he will be more than happy to discuss it
with you a highly ICN and you're gonna
Luca will present later today Here I am
for mobility this is slice is really
nice or invite you to take a look in
details on the runtime you can use
different slices to have all these
approaches persisting if you wish to do
some and finally we hope in to get
feedback from you guys okay thank you
Alberto you know just one quick
clarification for the 3gpp people in the
world in the room and the world I guess
the list mobile networks
spec is specking the N 3 + 6 + n9
interface and the most important feature
is to get shortest paths between G note
B's so to you ease have the lowest
latency that's what the focus is not so
when we did the comparison among and
focused on n9 we just want to make it
clear that the list proposals showing
all those interfaces
thank you you know I think our next is
there's already no coexistence yeah
q so this is the coexistence of five
years with a lock separation our
pictures shouldn't say kiss on ten
minutes yeah okay so I'll be wrong again
so in this presentation I will introduce
an approach to introduce ideal
expression architecture into OMG system
mostly uh I'm going to use the
background and purpose of this document
is approach
so as we you already know the ID locks
and separation protocols is expected to
enhance mobility in mobile network and
we we are proceeding to introduce such
protocols to the CP on the other
meanwhile specification of five the
width is 15 is already fixed and 60p B
may decide to change any interfaces so
this in internet draft it provides an
approach to introduce ideal expression
architecture without any impact to the
Falchi specs so this slide shows
overview and summary of this document so
this approach I use is you are in
crossfire which is a fundamental
fundamental function of EF and provide
enable to introduce I do capture we know
a low impact to the FRG as
specifications and each this will we
provide will be able to provide a
vibration a good vibration path to the
UPF support ID look
mekinese Netley so this is the objection
model which this approach has as a
assumption so in this network model
several UPS distributed geographically
for mac we use cases such as connecticut
car and the most of traffic conveyed
with GTP you this offering to slicer
shows challenges on the such network
so in this network central UPF will be a
anchor for the traffic falling so in the
UE to ue communication every traffic is
forward to the central UPF and forward
to the destination UPF so this may cause
additional delay this figure shows
challenges in the UE to distributed to
data network communication so in if you
e moved to the another site during any
session so you the traffic afforded to
the little function deployed in the data
network be a central UPF it's also made
cause I shall today
so this proposal provides solution to
use such additional delay so this
surprise shows a key concept of this
approach so this approach uses the open
crossfire and open crossfire type out
just 12 traffic which needs to be
afforded with
Coris path to the ideal domain as
external network so this is over B or
with this architecture so idyllic node
is deployed between distributed UPF and
data network and you LCL monitors the
traffic and diapered required
traffic and idyllic not receive the
packet and for that to the appropriate
destination and a yoke node so this
enables to provide uncle s foreign this
troilus shows user player control plane
features of this approach this approach
allows to use every user praying
protocols such as SLP six and even GTP
you or on the plane in the control plane
some interaction will be required
interaction between open system and SMS
OB liquid because for indicating has a
you location of ue to the rocket system
so SMF should indicate such information
to the idea of mapping system John John
I have a question on the previous slide
yeah this is showing the uplink
classifier being used to forward to the
destination how would the programming
make sure that it takes same path on the
downlink for example so up in crossfire
look up the destination address and if
the destination otherwise is one of Ida
space of its own okay but on the reverse
part on the way back it will go back to
wherever the IP address is incorrect or
which is the default gateway the bus
traffic
on the downlink downlink yeah
the downlink the packet is going to take
the path to the the Gateway where the IP
address is so the question is where is
the IP address anchored I think John's
question is in which yeah that's so from
the downlink traffic from internet were
centered determine if it's come for a
tour with gtp you so existing budget
system I mean I think that what I see in
2501 at least they put a couple of notes
note zero in this context is saying use
NAT and maybe that's not such a good
idea for ipv6 and then there's a note 4
which says it's our scope so how think
there's some problem and I was wondering
if you thought that maybe maybe John why
don't you put in good comment yeah why
don't you post it enough email it please
sorry did I just understand your answer
correctly this only applies to the
uplink it doesn't apply to the downlink
the downlink just follows what it was
happening without us did I get that
right yeah I think they want I mean from
a three we said you want a the same path
you don't want the uplink to go in one
way and don't like to go another way
yeah this approach focuses on just gonna
be uplink yes a couple of things so yes
you're absolutely right we have to
actually used to work on this and make
sure you know we have a symmetrical path
between the opting and down like the
other thing is that is alluded to to
yank or less mobility I would say that
you know for a man called less mobility
therefore more work to be done which
they today the path probably is that is
that is the least you know problematic
with anchor less mobility if you have to
consider a whole bunch of different
functions that are bitching actually
being being applied and at the at the
service KP in the packet gateway and as
long as we haven't solved those issues
we did the pathway on Karla's mobility
is very
difficult to actually achieve so and but
but I agree that we have to actually
work on this approach and see how we can
actually come up with the solution to to
to make the both paths symmetrical
because know for exactly if you were
going for you are LLC for example that's
pretty much way you have to go lightly
quick comment just just a question it'll
take the answer offline the comment was
made at 3gpp wanted a symmetrical path
my question is you know is that a hard
requirement and if so where can we get
that information because that would
really guide a lot of us looking at
solutions to make sure we're not
entertaining anything that does not meet
that base requirement good point yeah I
think your lines question was is there a
hard requirement the GPB state this
requirement that was this question
this shows a conclusion of you take this
approach so this approach uses up a
cross fire and provide so provide a way
to introduce our u-local without any
impact for large areas and this will be
a preferable migration path until now I
just need to be a support like looks the
other are you done I don't want to
interrupt you I just want to make a
comment on the symmetric comment
previously with the mapping system you
can get symmetric or asymmetric
depending on what set of locators you
register the mapping system so no matter
what the requirement is I think with a
mapping system based solution we could
support either one yep thank you
irrational again I don't build up on
what Dean what you just said so we might
have to actually just clarify this in
the in the new version of the draft and
basically show how mapping system can
actually solve solve this problem the
new new version of the draft thank you
the next steps yes so we need a more
leave you
it work and we did that this is an
option to introduce our v ID lock
separation protocol into 5g system so
Korean is draft already includes this
approach as an option so and if possible
I would like to make this be a bomb all
right from the Indian market good Thank
You ojiisan
you got a lot of good comments I think
how many people have read this document
okay so few people I think not I think
we want few more discussions and all of
that before even issued an option called
but I think two key points or I think
you know you got a lot of feedback
there's one thing already right second
thing I think regarding the LS reply we
will not be able to intervene you know
refer to this document at this point
because it's not a working document it's
a specific solution yeah so but I think
you should get some feedback from the
reviewers and then continue to update
the document and maybe hopefully next
idea we can write an option cause you
know I have a general question for the
chairs in the working group does the
working group think that there's too
many proposals that are being put
forward to ct4 should we have more
should we have less it would be nice to
hear opinions yeah I think I think from
all point of view I think you know I
think we talked in the past as well we
are not we are going to I think pick up
individual solutions or approaches and
we are going to standardize them right
again as we discussed before we are not
saying you know less or more you know
whatever like in ipv6 transitioning is a
great example vit have ended up with a
bunch of approaches right so if somebody
can justify the work and if they support
for the work and if this is within the
Charter will absolutely standardize it I
wanted to ask the question of 3gpp maybe
there's a
thank you so I I think you have two
types of documents the one is where you
evaluate our stuff from 3gpp there you
just can't expect too much reply from
the 3gpp we cannot correct your papers
right you trying to do your papers here
in a consolidated manner and we cannot
just come down and say this is wrong
what it should be written in a different
way or so on and and I think it's also
not beneficial for you that we spending
in 3gpp too much time on reviewing your
analysis of our documents that would be
not leading to any goal so don't expect
too much from us on that part on
alternative solutions to to Chi TPU that
you have we have a study item now of
course if we are overloaded study items
will always take second priority so we
will have a lot of load in in release 16
nevertheless I think this is now
understood that this is important that
that many companies are pushing for that
so yes bring us proposals and bring us
different proposals we will evaluate
them and we will most likely come back
with questions but one thing in general
and that is really now set as sort of a
private person here if you want to get
your proposal to get more attention in
3gpp please consider to come to ct4 and
work there with us this is a crucial
time now if you think your solution is
the right one to go then please bring
your input not only here but also come
to CT for and explain the background of
your ideas there thank you great
feedback thank you yeah I think very I
think last presentation is years so
you're running into your quick quick
quick quick
comment on what Dino was saying so maybe
we can actually use the analysis strap
as a way to actually chin down the chin
down the list
maybe so first we evaluate it against
what we did in terms of analysis and
then we saying okay which one of these
protocols they stand their own our
basically sticks and then we can
probably trim there the number of
protocols that way ok very click on this
Kenley I'm actually I mean I was a big
commenter earlier I just want to skip it
which is that this solves the easier
problem of the ankle list but I wasn't
sure if anybody's addressing all the
other key requirements are which is
really what the anchor model provides
the services of a quas charging quote a
whole bunch of stuff that's happening
only you move that out of the way who is
actually addressing that and I think
even we solved this problem it's not you
know that use abilities that become the
key factor so until somebody brings that
in or in address it in some ways I think
that will then address some of these
issues right so I again I was in more of
a comment at this point I guess the
implications for control plan needs to
be studied yeah great okay thank you so
much okay the next one is I think Amon
transport network of air mobility for
Phi G yeah unfortunately five minutes
okay my name is Zuma I'm just because a
five minutes I'll quickly run through it
I will let you read my draft this is put
forth by me and couple of folks so I'm
not going to talk about the background
we talked about you know multiple drafts
like the analysis draft gtp analysis
staff and you know beta sub proposals so
we are talking about a nine interface
here so the background is for the nine
and n 3 and then six whatever or
whatever it is so the thing is what I'm
talking about here is so various SS
piece like 3gpp has defined service
slice types as indicated here
there are various traffic types for
various video sessions which are machine
critical or real-time today is only EMV
b4 fixed wireless requirements initially
for Fiji but in future if you go to the
different video sessions where low
latency and mission-critical
applications are there today for
transport network is considered not not
considered in the middle either
returning and 3 or n9 there will be
significant problem that all the gains
made in an RFID Inara the watch realized
code will be evaporated quickly and the
second the second part of it is sorry
can you make this issue okay the the
second part of it is how how various
transport technologies IETF developed
over a period of 20 years how these can
be leveraged effectively to integrate
this some of the PDO sessions can be
leveraged to integrate with the Phi G
radio access network on the network so
the objective is create a reference
model in the service based interface and
how IETF technologies can be integrated
in this and if you have there also it
also talks about clear market mapping
between PD of sessions 3gpp PD sessions
and various IETF transport technologies
also specifically talks about preferred
path routing which builds on SR and it
helps the goal of here of optimize the
transport and I will talk quickly about
that and also other technologies like SR
v6s our MPLS or RSVP T how this can be
integrated into the fire architecture
this approach doesn't replace gtp you it
works with gtp U 1 in 3 interface and it
works with any encapsulation approach
you choose on n line interface including
gtp you so this is the service based
architecture various cups architecture
basically is control plane is separated
and data plane is separated so which is
all good so because of the coverage area
P gateways to be thousand kilometers
moved to hundred kilometers range
because of EPF this interface a new
problem so this new concept of UPF
mobility has come in so that there are
two things that being solved there I
will talk about SSA mode 1 mode 2 mode 3
later so but thing is the most important
point here is how do you integrate the
transport network in between between
anything
face online interface there are two ways
that can be done one is discrete
approach where underlying transport
network is you know just it's it's
independent of you know fiber and axis
which is deployed way for for chase like
4G slices basically we have only two
barrels they're only default in
voiceover voice better so it's easy
there so there's not the hard political
requirements in the discrete approach
you were transport network complete
links and node information it fed into
the central place and it's continuously
monitored and path selection happens
based on the beauty piece or sport these
GT PhD once gtp a packet is encapsulated
with gtp you source code base of
selection of the transport will happen
this is being deployed in current
current a couple of deployments
including in US and UK UK in couple of
places actually so what I'm proposing is
an integrated approach where this is not
required for all the PD sessions where
this mission critical and
mission-critical real-time sensor
sensitive applications the approach is
you put the PMF transport network
function into the service based
interface and create two interfaces here
they I should say cell site router which
is apart from G note B which is front
hall it can be in some places so a cell
set router can be part of the G note P
so this not Bowl interface from the UPF
you'll see a loop here for a branch
point appear for the anchor PF the
sorbonne interface to the cell set
router so this completely enough the
advantage of putting into the spi is
when the mobility happens resources on
the transport network can be factored
for some of the PDA sessions so what are
the TNF functionalities I'm looking here
so the NSS I what they 20 purified zero
one defined can get that 80 transport
network information while making the
dish including mobility and X and
mobility or enter mobility and for
wherever it is required for some of the
slices some of the Phi Q eyes this can
be this information can be used to
making the mobility decisions and for
the regular non mobility cases for a
service request I I don't have to actual
to ideal case also whether you have
transport network resource that they are
not there you can be verified and I
think we're out of time just a few final
thoughts okay
next slide I was talking about just give
me one okay
I was talking about various technologies
various transport technologies including
rsvp-te including SR MPLS including SR
v6 including the optimizations PPR can
bring in have been discussed in the
summary this proposal leverages the
existing IETF technologies to get the
benefits to the fising some of the pedia
sessions
it works with any model like you know
any or less IP v4 v6 v spree for v6 a
three-time structure to the any backhoe
transporter this is important because to
protect the existing investments of some
of the operators Thank You MA I think
it's a new document it was possible you
one day back so we are not going to ask
who read it right but so if there's more
discussions next time we'll so we are
not doing any questions we are out of
time sorry so thank you can I just make
one comment yeah while we discuss in LS
our working group yesterday a lot of
look it's like the CV R is really an
honest murder it needs to be discussed
outside this working group with spring
and LS are more there was some comment
posted as well
I presented the PPR technology base
technology in LSR how it can enable
optimization for SR MPLS and SR v6 and
there are some questions going on in a
spring water pipe
snoring so in the meantime why don't you
start your presentation yeah
Sheldon og from Cisco and in this
presentation I wanted to give you an
overview of what we proposed to manage
uncle s mobility for the use of hybrid
AZN so I badarian has been introduced by
a Schmidt in his to his presentation and
it belongs to a class of approaches
which is ID based which means that this
come in contrast thank you so this come
in contrast with the typical use of IP
addresses which are interpreted as
locators by typical IP networks and
mobility is then built on top through
the use of genell's and anchoring of
communication through specific nodes so
following that we have seen approaches
based on locate the separation which
been proven to be interesting in the ups
of mobility management but they have one
common characteristics that they use a
mapping system to bind the IDs and the
locators and this has been shown
sometimes to be challenging to operate
because it introduced some latency for
resolution or some bindings to
coordinate the caches at very high
frequency in this proposal we tried to
move the ideas behind locate a
separation one step further and propose
to remove the mapping and forward the
request directly on identifiers so this
is done to new ID and it has been
already introduced in the draft I refer
in the slides and it's a concept of
native ID oriented except that in this
draft there was no real implementation
and was only a wished feature so the
interest of this ID base the
architecture is that you don't have the
need for that opinion corner for comfort
when and how we propose to do it is by
applying ICN principles and we're
interested especially in the
hybridization proposal which is an
implementation of ICN within IP and Luca
give a presentation yesterday in Korea
about this technology so I said when I
pee
it's basically an integration of all
ASEAN features inside regular IP
protocols with the only compromise that
when code names inside ipv6 addresses so
this transplant integration is very
interesting in the sense that we don't
need all nodes to be haz and enable and
we have only a subset of nodes which I
Jason enabled and the rest of their
network can be plane ID and interoperate
nicely with I chase yen in terms of
mobility what is interesting is that I
would ACN is a request to apply
communication pattern and you have a
consumer requesting some data and this
data is not fried by his name isn't fire
and this request is propagated in a hop
by hop fashion by the Reuters using the
feebs and it leaves some state every
time it's forwarded by rotor and this
state is used to forward the response
back to the originator and at the same
time it leaves some temporary cache in
the network route as it encounters so
thank you this request reply pattern
mobility of the consumers is native
because it's simply a matter of
rationing pending interest or next
request for data so as to continue the
communication without an interruption or
the need to renegotiate society or to
transfer contexts producer mobility is
not supported natively and the draft
tries to describe the mechanisms we use
to support it so very shortly what we do
is to use distributed forwarding updates
to manage mobility and this has been
previously proposed in madney protocol
for the ASEAN context in is energy and
the key idea is to use to repair the
pass to reach the producer through data
plan mechanism and again this concept is
not new and actually borrowed the title
of the slide from a paper at NS di a few
years ago that proposed to use data plan
mechanisms to ensure connectivity and
they proposed this to low the latency to
contact the control plane and to be more
efficient in restaurant connectivity
they propose it for link failures we
proposed it for mobility and our scheme
is doing lightweight but very process
what is important in our scheme is that
both forward and mobility operations
actually based on ideas or names in the
case of hybridization we have no
interaction with the control plane no
mapping to contact or date
and no new note to deploy a provision to
manage mobility so it should remove most
of the challenges in operating mobility
so I won't describe much more but the
key aspects to remember is that this
scheme is fully on Karla's and that
mobility is under layer 3 which makes it
very convenient for hydrologic network
supports in the draft you will find
pointers to some documents supporting
the performance of the scheme for
scaling or for performance plus some
optimization we do for latency sensitive
traffic in the rest of the presentation
I will illustrate some of the benefits
in the context of deployments which is
the object of the second draft we
proposed and we focused mainly on the
3gpp architecture so I won't go into
detail for free DDP but just illustrate
how we benefit from regulation in this
context so so Jordan me it should be
wrapping it up a little bit short sorry
so the first benefits they originate
from the use of Oracle's to play pattern
and it's simply the matter of ratio in
interest and at the same time it's
sufficient for you to load balance you
request on many accesses to benefit from
a native multihoming ability passed the
second benefits are originating from the
use of intermediate caches in pass from
the rooters and this allows low latency
and native mythical sting of the request
because ruto is able to answer on behalf
of a consumer the second types of
benefits originate from the native
vocalist
properties of the skin and we obtained
this when we use for example in 3gpp
haan on in place of the gtp tunnels and
this allows on Karla's mobility and
offloading of each communication at the
edge of the network so I want to tell
that so of course both benefits from HIC
NM for the use of ID base the mobility
can be combined what we propose we have
discussion in the draft about partial
insertion so it is where we can have ID
even a subset of nodes or use as a v6 in
between each ACN to extend the reach of
the proposal will require chastening
endpoints but we try to make the
insertion really minimal through easy to
use implementation and non HSN traffic
can also benefit from the mobility
pattern based on IDs so to complete I
would say that we have proposed a new
paradigm based the purely on identifier
we bid on Abaddon
it brings us native consumer mobility
and we have made a proposal for
lightweight producer mobility based on
that brain updates so we analyzed
several deployment raiders and the
different benefits we gained and as a
computer I would say it's a
general-purpose architecture with nice
on Collison netsupport abilities and it
offers the possibility to insert the
choice en and benefit ready for this new
transport features Thank You Q so how
many people have read this document ok
thank you I think we need a few more
discussions yeah thank you I think next
ESO every six Forks
I think hi I'm mark bales probably the
last one it's a v6 like a plane oh ok
the title this is this is a follow up on
Pablo's document for the 36 mobile parks
this is specifically around the M core
project that will go back to testing
there the the M chord project that he
mentioned in his previous presentation
today was an import project called c-3po
which is an LTE 4G open-source core
essentially
trying to do in this POC is to establish
the inner working of an SR v6 underlay
for and I and involve the PC core in the
3gpp standards essentially we built a we
built an underlay for it and then went
through the process of interworking ipv4
gtp across 10 SR v6 network just to
prove that we have a transition path so
back to the traffic environment we did
generate we use 25 users and 10,000
packets per second to prove out our
prove out the functionality the c3po
provide the the import project c3po
provided the EPC core and used the VPP
software to create three nodes to
provide the interworking underlay so we
ran two scenarios through the EPC core
one was policy based encapsulation of
the ipv4 gtp traffic ran into jumbo
frame problems as you would expect and
then we did the interworking with ipv4
gtp tunnels with the tid stored in the
IP at the SR v6 pile of headers to get
the interworking so we didn't rebuild
the header at the other end and both of
those were successful we haven't got to
the point where we've been able to test
this at Ryan lime rate but the software
we're using from the EM cord as well as
the VPP software aren't quite ready for
production and aren't released to the
general public just yet but they will be
shortly the software is available here
that's the generic software this is
where we would expect these to be after
they get generally released if you wish
to go in and try this yourself
like I said they both both scenarios
were successful in testing be aware that
the jumbo frames will cause you problems
if you're just trying to do straight
encapsulation
but the ipv4 gtp policy-based
interworking was successful as well
c-3po code release
we're expecting one here in the next
couple days actually it's not 718 that's
yeah the 718 sorry our next step sort of
go back and and redo the baseline
testing and try to push this towards
line rate just to see how the software
performs and the contributors to the
solution are listed there if you need
any information or detailed help feel
free to reach out to us okay thank you a
mock I think there's one last related
presentation is sorry six-month that
we're going to see we talked about it is
another demo that you're putting
together with using the OIE
open source software so that one will be
complimentary to what Mark was talking
about and their plans to actually
integrate the two to two demos together
and live even in the planning stage of
that so the the objective is again for
the Oei model to for the Oei open source
to actually be used as a base for for
demoing SR v6 gateways as showed in the
in the previous presentation the the
problem is that the Oei basically right
now only supports the combined s gwgw so
there's not really an annoying interface
to actually do the work so we're
basically focusing our effort to showing
it on the n3 and then we see whether we
can actually separate the sgw from the
PGW inside your way i and and that then
we'll follow the fo our v6 mobility for
you you plane mobility to basically get
the data te ID from the gtp tunnels and
transfer them over set across the
network between the the in ot and the
and the the SGP
SSC wmtw so if you need more information
come talk to me I can elaborate some
more okay Thank You Ashley thank you
Mark
Thanks so with dark I think I think this
is good work in general anything about
implementation deployments we want that
feedback
I think this great stuff but that will
conclude this meeting thanks everyone
yeah I think blue sheet saturation is
one more Brosius who has a place
so thanks books
[Music]