all right good afternoon good afternoon
everyone we're gonna get started I hope
you're here for dots you may want to
step out just for last-minute get your
coffee or your cookie we have somewhat
full agenda to talk through some things
my name is roaming to Nadeau and you
know Frank shall but he is now up on the
stage here with us as as a co-chair
Tobias will be stepping down after this
meeting so we're thrilled to have
Franklin on the team here pushing our
working group through some progress it's
late in the week will you've seen this
note well it references a number of
policies related to code of conduct
copyright patents and privacy policy
like things if you do have any questions
please don't hesitate to ask from one
group chair or the a did administrative
Lea we have the blue sheets getting
passed around cristinaw Co is going to
be our jabber jabber scribe and taking
notes is Jessica and Daniel thank you so
much for doing that for us the agenda we
have here for you today is slightly
tuned from what what was sent on the
mailing list we we had some
late-breaking ads to talk about
implementation experience and then some
commentary about some possible mods to
the signal Channel
we're gonna have both in-person and
remote participants which has
historically worked really well for us
so before we get into some of the
details we have a lot of documents and
different different kind of status and
we've been talking about what next steps
were Frank and I wanted to summarize
that for the working group and have a
conversation about whether this seems
right and whether or whether this is the
next the best way to proceed so we've
gone through a working group last call
and closed issues related to the
requirements document and at this point
we have a Shepherd write-up prepared and
we're going to be advancing that
document thank you Frank for for doing
kind of that write-up so Ben we're going
to be sending that to you with the
architecture draft we're a little late
and that's on on the chairs and we're
gonna start a working group last call
starting on Monday as we had planned in
previous discussions then as we talked
about use case signal and data channel
we have time for each one of those
drafts on the on the agenda but to kind
of lay it out we think from the chairs
perspective from at least early
conversations with the editor team that
the use case is almost ready to for its
Shepherd kind of write up it's going to
likely take one more version to process
last call then with the signal draft
it's been many months of processing
feedback there's still a little bit more
on the mailing list we feel that's gonna
take another working group last fall and
we can talk about that and then the data
channel is closed there's one identified
issue and we believe that can likely go
to work group last call in September so
I was going to ask for reactions Fleming
thank you yeah Fleming interesting so
the architecture dev we have a couple of
pending changes there actually so we
might want to just hold off a little bit
on the working group last call all right
I get those updates in you know okay
fair enough so what do you think it oh
okay on timewise what are we thinking
so frankly staggering dates Andrew
Mortensen sorry uh yeah we just need to
cover a little bit more on the neck
considerations what's there right now is
a little bit shallow okay and we've been
going back and forth privately but we
should have something soon August okay
so you prefer to have that as the basis
of the working group last call yes okay
we can wait again that actually works
for a benefit there's a lot of documents
and I don't think we have the bandwidth
to to go through last call so we can
talk as we as we cover the use case the
signal draft and the data channel we can
cover you know we can cover the
specifics of what makes most sense we
didn't have an explicit slot for
requirements and architecture so thank
you for bringing that up to date so let
me flash the agenda kind of back up you
know would anyone like to bash what we
have planned here now that we have some
logistics stuff sorted out are we
comfortable with what's planned here
okay I'm taking that as you know okay so
we'll proceed
so first up as is our tradition let's
talk about the running code we have for
all the drafts we're going to be talking
about so first stuff we're gonna be
talking about our hackathons so Konami
thanks so much turning you over to you
can I give you the quicker please okay I
thank you for its reduction I'm Konami
she's come from NTT communications I
make a presentation about the repo of
the internal testing which was done on
the hackathon this time so hey the
hackathon
so actually we studied the hackathon
from IETF 99 and we are positing it
constructively
so the first hackathon we did only the
implementation of implementation
implementation of an oasis which is
fraud entity then are eating 100 we did
first
interoperability testing with IDT and in
which she group Patrick Farrell
far away but it is only limited to this
you know each other about this time in
ie8 mano to hackathon we did the first
data channel intro so I can take both
signal channel today each other are
covered also checked with the real
implementation and also I'd like to
mention that actually entity and
leadership group the two internal
Interop as a preparation for the IETF
102 hackathon so here the diagram of
interrupts testing so um on the website
the other it coded from entity which is
always implementation running on AWS
server then on the other end in the
sushi group's implementation which is in
London running on proprietary production
mitigation box then we communicated each
other both signal channel on the data
channel then I'll start cryin Godspeed
education request and sister
configuration of a Sunnah channel and
also used data each other for the
registration of client areas is issues
and also data capability discovering
then those mushishi groups
implementation work as the thought
solder them eat eat toady dose
mitigation actions also vice versa we
did tests within she she groups dot
quiet co dot dot servers and we tested
the same things in other direction
so hey the summary of the internal
testing then ok I will dig into the
details in the latest life but you may
see that
the green cells represent tested
elements in the eye thick bundle and
blue cells represent tested element in
this ETA 102 so you may see that the
test coverage was enhanced significantly
so first I'll move on to the data
channel result so on the data channel
here the evaluated features so for the
iteration of triads ideas and filtering
rules we need a test of these missiles
like our post to get theories of these
elements and also we did victories of
the capabilities we'd get method then
here the result then all of the test is
checked as green so I checked with this
check mat so actually our the result was
good then several issues found so those
are already reported to the body group
so with the summary so actually our
message exchange over risk of over TLS
is very stable so I can say that there
are no problem with such transport but
we fixed several thoughts about message
format itself on each side so among them
for issues with the data draft child a
data channel draft were a race to the
party group during the hackathon and all
of issues on the repository of get heart
of met Dana
okay I was also occupied and only minor
issues are found except for fragment
bits in Asia so I explained the four
issues
okay family a very tiny issue just a
clarification of ambiguity about a text
in the 6.1 create aliases so in that
take is the ban of these attributes like
target prefix target fqdn I'll get you a
light must be present input request but
it post progressed but it must be exist
existing in post and also put so just
updated Atticus and second one second
one is about painting lifetime in the
response if you are credit you are a
query is aliases content config so
pending lifetime is defined as a config
false so if we wanted coffee
it should not be included in the
response of gap but so the text was
included those life pending lifetime so
text was updated to use config all in
thought in order to shoot on so that all
the variants should be included
okay so that's the fix of the text and
so the next one is about so what get we
get returns for the context non coffee
so in our SG 80 40 which is the rest of
our she stated if content parameter is
set to non config mode that
configuration ancestor at least key leaf
are also retard so name of a share areas
should be also with ru because it is
leaf keys so that is already written in
RFC 80 40 so there's no need to update
data data channel drop into service but
I need to ensure that as an invitation
guide right
we need to see and read our exeat Cody
carefully okay then the issue number two
fragment bits representation he the most
important one
then for ipv4 fragmentation the current
roster it should be represented as a
beach type so it includes the name of
Pete like a la morra
in the flux leaf then a pizza names
should be in the one string with space
superlative form 1040 v6 the type is a
peaceful it's 2d representation of this
but this is not active if six case is
not difficult but for ipv4 there is a
problem like this so the current draw
stage of K okay that's all then our
decision for the last fragment rats is
kind of new shrinks but can it be used
for the representation of the last vlog
mix so that that yeah intuitively that
is not only the more beat is zero but
also it says that other bit like
reserved the beat don't fragment beat
the be zero because I defined the beat
in check if there is a defined beat it
should be repeated as zero if in our C
seven nine seven nine five round so that
is difficult to represent the fragment
in this form so
question is how best to represent
irrelevant futile rules with net misako
or each enhancement so for me bgp
prospect like representation for her
fragment fit for my feelings but we
should discuss about this but discussion
will be should be in the little the made
presentation or not here or whatever
Aleutians okay the then the locator
let's move on to the next so we we
discussed about these fragmented see
presentation but this is important so I
need to make emphasis on this issue so
first you know each other we evaluated
these features so the category the
category of features is myself so if you
have some objection to the
categorization please let me know but in
this category categorization we can say
that I can say that these specifications
like session configuration which mission
request code pink observe of mutation
session config Akashi update and the
request confliction hungry and
confliction not fault is a constitution
because without them we can't do not we
can not execute DDoS mitigation of god
clients do not stop but further these
features like that month trigger it wave
function with erection and happy
eyeballs we can do the minimum
mitigation request without those
features so I they all say that those
additional specifications so among be
call 800 specifications we tested the
six
specifications in this in
testing so this is the summary of the
testing of she knows charlie drop so
there are several bugs so several dogs
are found on both site but those bugs
are already fixed during the hackathon
even after the hackathon
so this summary readout shows some of
cells are marked with triangle but this
trial robot represents that foggy status
authy Pakistan but actually it is now
fixed so we tested us we know each other
with live based on the latest
specification then two issues are raised
but these issues are already fixed so
the first one is about the missing
mandatory lifetime in example figure
seven eight so this is just a editorial
need so like time is actually mandatory
attribute it but it will even not it did
not exist in the mediation request
figure so it was already added so it
already fixed then the second one is
about Sri know each other four point
five point three configuration freshness
and notification so I explained I
explained this shortly the adult server
needs to be able to update you know
channel configuration parameters so to
toad server and postcard need to agree
on the funeral channel configuration so
it needs to be it need to be able to
update it and then dot triad can do the
food to refresh the configuration so it
overwrite the server's configuration as
you know channel configuration so then
that client needed to get to reach the
agreed configuration within the max age
type so dot signal china draft did
mention about these features so the
trust is not updated so again this
issues issue is already fixed so this is
a wrap up of the presentation so as
takeaway I can say successful
interrupted continuing then Co efficient
of dot is now major enough not only for
our channel but also the each other then
several issues are fund during the
hackathon but they are not so
significant so they've been sorted out
on the fixed then we have two
implementations one is OSS the reports
tree is here at github from ninety T
entity named co dot and one proper
proprietary from initiative groups which
will be the production level then we
need my limitation so we say my
limitations are welcome then we'd like
to do the the kind of exhaustive
internal testing name in the next IETF
or a Scylla okay we see the report of
our hackathons read that Thank You
late-night questions for the hackathon
team so on behalf of the chairs we want
to thank the hackathon team for for
doing for do it for doing everything
they did this past kind of weekend I
know there's been a lot of focus in
previous events on the signal channel
giraffe
we know has improved the quality of a
document now that you the fact that you
focused on the Daito channel helped
tremendously we hadn't previously done
that and you've clearly found issues so
to the editor team of the signal and
data channel document thanks again for
revving again in preparation for this
meeting so all of your work on go dots
and I think John you're listening with
NCC Group with your implementation
you're really advancing these drafts and
letting us get your closure so thank you
again for all your hard work and if you
want no questions thank you thank you
thank you very much just wait a minute I
have a question through the signature
now dead to Anna also I have seen that
you have very very recent the latest of
this to document right in this week yeah
yeah so if this updated incorporated
enemies ensues yeah exactly who's
affected to the latest document that
Konami raised we discussed them and we
we fixed the document we update them so
that there is no confusion about the
some because most of the of the issues
are not that that majors only about
clarification and and some of them could
be just to leave the technologies but as
an editor I preferred to to modify it so
that there is no someone else can not
misinterpret the text and so on so they
and so I really appreciate the work
which is done by D Beckenham Ian and the
team because it's helped us to assess
that what we are putting on the
committee's really can be implemented
and the its ability so thank you all for
for this work not only I are also a job
did much work 15 odd I had generate
issues based on the drop we results yes
so yeah I have only one confession
question one question about the behavior
of the implementation given that I have
seen one question from Andrew about the
mitigation or loss yeah so just to make
sure there is no confusion about about
about that one how the implementation is
behaving right
now when you activate the year you have
the parameter which is trigger on loss
which is enabled how do you accept the
mitigation coming from the DES client or
you you discard them sorry I I think MIT
is referring to the issue around the
dead man's trigger which I'm not sure
you guys have actually tested is that
correct yeah because it Monster Eagle is
okay uh okay for me we need to ask about
John but I I'm thinking about which
mitigation should be activated of based
on the to be thought of that no only an
hour or so for the meeting which I
wasn't fair so I see John as junk in the
queue so John yeah can you hear me we
can yep okay so you know I have the dead
my interpretation was that the dead man
trigger was there if there was a loss of
signal heartbeats between the server and
the client and then the server could
then initiate whatever he needed to
initiate to start mitigation as a
consequence of the dead man's trigger
but following Andrews email that came
out about an hour ago I realized that we
don't actually have anything in place
for what should happen to start the
mitigation dude you just take overall
does it have some predefined kind of
environmental words it's nothing as
clear as to what actually should happen
when the dead man's trigger kicks in so
we're missing a part on that but
certainly it's not that if that is not
set in the signal channel mitigations
are held until it is set true in the
signal channel it's that was not my
interpretation of the original text yes
because what we have done in this signal
change that we in avoid to in order to
avoid having redundant specification of
what we do at authoritative text for us
is as we just pointed to this section in
the architecture
so I don't know I didn't read the latest
version of the architecture that we have
to make sure that whether to import all
the text and put it on the signal
channel or to leave the text as right
now so we can you can see at the point
we could I ask a clarifying question
because I clearly did not track that
change in the signal channel so we are
gonna point from the from the standard
track back to you and informational for
a normative thing I misunderstood what
we have what we have say we have the
parameter there and what we said the
full description of the behavior
see section theta then on the detector
for me that's that is fine that sounds
fine sorry my question is that if we
think that we will avoid confusion
perhaps this is an open question we just
need to copy the most point from the
architecture and put it into the the
signal channel even if this is my
favorite but it's - I transfer to your
to your to your issued it's after you to
let us know
sure yeah that's that's really it so for
me it's okay the current the current the
current Texas is okay because I am
pointing to to to the architecture but
if you think that this is not the way to
where to go and if you prefer that we do
add few sentences there that this is
something that can be done sorry inter
Mortensen I think the issue for me
really is that we don't have it defined
what mitigation is the scope of the
mitigation actually is on the dead man's
trigger we can say that it takes place
on loss of signal in the architecture
graph but them there's no way to tell
the server currently based on the
specification in the signal Channel what
that scope should be good
Thank You Canali okay so next up we were
gonna transition from the implementation
work at the hackathon to other
implementation work that's happening so
first up youhave Romain Kiki was gonna
talk about the particular intradomain
orchestration use case with with go dots
so you hey we're pulling up your sides
can you hey are you ready we ah there we
go
ah okay Hayashi wrong entity
thank you for choose to give me
presentation throat today I want to make
a presentation about the POC report of
inter-domain so castration use case and
I want to discuss what those should be
for a journey took providers first of
all I will explain brief summary of this
presentation annex please
at first I willing to reduce our
motivation on demonstration well then I
will explain our requirement about dose
signal at next right I will explain our
motivation next please
in the future we want to automate a DDoS
mitigation in inter domain network with
Orchestrator the orchestrator automates
like collecting information from full of
lectures on DDoS mitigation systems and
designing what to do and ordering
polluters our DDoS mutation systems to
mitigate DDoS attack we also want to use
a standardized interface between the
orchestrator and the security products
in IETF 100 so I went to Singapore and
investigated a security automation
working group and I got to know about
adults working group so we want to try
adults as a standardized interface
between the orchestrator and throw
cricketers or adidas mutation systems
from next rice I want to explain about
the POC
next piece this figure shows a POC
overview our left one is our pockets
case and light one is adidas
orchestration use-case are written in
the draft in
our pokey use case we assumed that the
dots has adult cry and functions a so
that it sends dog signal two dots our us
overall decreased after that at the
orchestrator order to be ruta to carry
out a black hole routing next piece this
figure issues our environment at the
Polk inter-domain network consists of
two types of networks a core network on
scrubbing center core network consists
of two peer artists the scrubbing center
consists overflow corrector Orchestrator
a DDoS mitigation system on GRE and
point water in this environment we
assumed that the flow corrector and the
DDoS mitigation systems was a dots
client about dot server a we deployed to
the Saba VM with goats Abba on the
orchestrator on the other hand about
touch grant there were no commercial
products which implemented to describe
function so we deployed dots grant BM
for the flow corrector and tedious
mutation systems on the orchestrator
each dose cry and vm has some functions
a friendiy is a pasta fiji transforms
sister all of the protractor or DDoS
musician system into imp top go Dawgs
grant controller the goats current
controller controls goats client and the
goats crayons
st. dot Sigrid suffer from next rise a
week's
pray about how it works next please
first of all a pirata seems net flow to
the flock Richter next please
when the protractor detects the polymer
dark-eyed sends his dog to the dog
client vm other dogs mitigation request
after that in dose grinder BM our friend
de extracts target IP others from the
Cicero
makes a JSON file are the input of the
gods grant control then the god of grant
contour is invoked so that the chords
gray and sends the signal to the world
server next please
the goddess Sabra invokes a go BGP and
attack traffic is directed at adidas
magician system b.a.p Ruta next please
after that event DDoS magician system
detects attack in detail
it sends syslog to descry and
vm has overall request then these
systems are act same as before
next please finally the goal of server
inbox go BGP on a peer outer abroad
attack traffic by abraca whole routine
that's all of action our POC a home next
race we will explain our requirement so
far in our pork we use bracha horrid
thing gossipy ruta fiber I in the future
we want to use BGP prospect 2 Broke
attack traffic @p Lotus more correctly
so we want to just grants to send
attacker information like top talker for
IDF 103 I I think I want to write draft
about expansion of toad signal a that's
all all my questions
next please I have a to question first
is does our poker use case attract to
you second one is if it does what do you
think about our requirement I won't
discuss it oh thank you for your
attention
any question
I have not invite folks to the mic
I enjoy dancin so is the question
whether you can send the information
that the top talkers are over the signal
Channel or over the data channel uh I
think Steve Carrell okay so the the
ackles in the data channel are not
sufficient or you're concerned about
bandwidth so far
I don't think ah not a data channel but
as you know channel okay maybe this is a
conversation we can take to the man
listen - yeah I think this is a valid
question this is a question wishes we
received several times to add more
information into the signal channel and
what we have decided so far is to
maintain the signature I would say the
monetary information to be included
there so once the signal shown is is
frozen and sent then we can open the
discussion about the new information to
be included new section but this will be
really extension that optional to have
and not as what we have in in the
current signal channel imma take know
the use case is interesting and this
alludes to what I was kind of like
thinking earlier when I was reading
through the signal channel in the fact
that we kind of mentioned vendor
extensions twice and then we just gloss
over where we see anything else so I
think from rather than how it is vendor
extensions we might want to change it to
extensions of some description or
optional extensions or non you know not
specify vendor but they might give us
the option to them like stuff in here
whoever we want to do but at the same
time we need to be able to stuff it in
without breaking anything else or or or
anything like that but then again I
think it does say in the single channel
know if you should be ignored but I
think it's it's interesting in that nuts
I would agree with method of who frees
and signal channel to a certain point
and then you build it into other drafts
or other functionality within that we've
already built the extensibility in there
and it's just a case of defining what
you want to do and bring that into new
documents but I think it's really cool
Ian Frank's ah how I sense that you're
here you bring this your your poke and
the yard comment - here yes
I think that's real that this you come
and make sense and maybe in future we
can do some extension to counter
protocol to so it so my individual and
yet from my my individual comments is
that if you want to bring this new work
to this working group please write a
draft to describe your use case and the
requirements so that we can check we can
have more discussion more maybe we can
be transfer in the next stage but
currently stager I think our most
important the walking's is the RAB are
our current protocol and the provider
are stable and the basic protocol but
anyway in the future yeah that's totally
impossible oh sorry
possible sorry ah thank you very much
hi Nick Teague again now I just wanted
to say that um I don't think you should
it's there's nothing stopping you from
putting this into a draft now though as
far as everything goes if you want to do
it it's it we might consider it to be
the next consideration or something but
while we're getting everything else
sorted out but at the same time would be
nice to have stuff sitting there waiting
to work on so if you wanted to start
rolling it out now as far as getting
documents out and done drafts you know
why not so I wanted to hold a working
group on this thread as Frank could of
alluded to this conversation has come up
before about wanting to do extensions
and you know at the my god I heard
something that I guess is a little too
vague for me you know we've talked about
let's get the core thing done and then
we can kind of have extensions but what
does that practically mean to folks to
folks kind of here in the room I mean is
there are we talking about we want to
embed an extension hook into the current
protocol and then we're gonna have more
drafts that tell us you know how to hook
that in or are we gonna release a
one-one what's the feeling in the room
here um hey Nick Teague well I think
when we when we first started this we
always kind of had extensibility is part
of the one of the reasons we were doing
it or one of the one I'm sorry one of
the attributes and I think from every
kind of like very variation that we've
put together of
protocol standard you know critical
candidates always had some kind of
extensibility in there now the one with
you have has a bunch of stuff already
there we're just hand waving over it as
being there but we've made room for it
so I don't think it's so much a case of
one one I think it's a case of like
we're just defining how you could use
those use the stuff that's there it's
just we don't really call it out much of
the minute you read you did you want to
say something I'm sorry Chris were you
singing what I said
danyoung me Gary Erickson so I think we
well the protocol needs to have some
extensions but we should really think
about which extension we're going to go
through you can if you see what makes a
product all successful is that it's been
extendable but when you see why a
protocol is dying is that when you have
a bunch of uncontrolled extensions so I
think that's where the discussion has to
take place which extension where you're
going through and find the right one
that is hitting all the use cases we
want to address enter Mortenson again I
will say that more implementations would
make me feel more comfortable about the
possibility of extensions and so I'll
drop this drop us rolling we see in the
queue let me finish I mean one of the
things that we may want to you a did you
want to respond hey hear me yes we can
hear you so I want to write that
expansion over those signature nails
and I will send working group to Mary so
well I want to give me I won't take some
comments from you sits at all
okay makes sense thank you you know what
are we doing this Oh Roland you you're
up Roland if you're speaking we can't
hear you
Roland I may have just booted you out oh
never mind got it okay we'll close the
the conversation here but I mean we are
having a recurring conversation about
extensions and I'll put something again
on the mailings to discuss but I think
you've us to have some text somewhere or
some guidance that we can point you that
would govern how we want to handle this
in the future but I think we need to
flush this out a little more so what
we'll take it to to the male voice okay
yoohoo thank you for your presentation
we have a little bit of time left
just for open mic if folks with
implementations that already exist want
to talk about progress they've made or
if someone here in the room or in media
Co would like to surface the existence
of another implementation that we
haven't previously learned about so
hoping my time if you want to talk about
running code you have hi we've made some
progress internally with the coop based
version and we're also now experimenting
with additional languages with the
intention of bringing some a variety to
the foundations and frameworks that are
being used currently I believe it's all
the coop based yes Kaname is nodding
so we we're hoping to at least bring
some of that forward as open source and
are also potentially looking for some
Interop opportunities in other venues in
the future so I would be eager to hear
of additional implementers aside from
John okay so you heard it here that was
farmer networks anyone else we're going
to talk about an implementation they
have they're planning or is in flight
okay with that move on injurer gender so
next up we are going to talk about the
signal channel so med the floor is yours
okay so this would be a quick update of
the signal specification so as you know
last so it was in and of naturalism I
woke you up last fall that was issues
for this for is the document yeah it was
very happy for about the outcome that
that's working on glass Scott was this
only shown that we have only manner
memory issues and all the qualifications
to be to be added to a document this so
I this is a signal for us that that we
are close to to travel version of the of
the document so this is only the listen
there the some of the main point at
Brazil at that time so it is only
clarifications there to about the do
arise to to be used this is something
which is and we had explicit sentences
to document to make it sure that people
we understand that we are using this
your items because we are just in the
beginning we are just pointing to the
RFC's in which is defined we enhance the
develop behavior in the document
so again when there is a loop which has
it taken somewhere by the Gateway what
now the behavior is that we are asking
each gateway to insert its own
information and then it will prepend it
to add weather
gateway so that this will simplify and
is a diagnostic if there is any any
troubleshooting to to to be done another
modification was about the direct signal
in there so we the beginning we assume
that the the server is know that what it
is it is doing that means that if there
is an a request to a client or direct to
another server we are assuming that
there is an some configurations which is
done at the server but we figured out
that in case there are some misconfigure
there we introduce this a guard in order
to avoid us relation between multiple
servers for instance if you ever see a
signal from a given server to you that
you have to go direct to another server
and then right after you receive another
signal for that server as you go back to
the other one so this will be something
which is bubi so that's why we we
introduced this guard about the five
minutes that we forbid that you can go
back to to the previous server
unless this lifetimes expired we also
clarify the way we are using detail
there we have four direction so where
direction can be can can last forever
or can be limited in time so this is
something that we are conveniently
parameter and also we have introduced
that there are some sentences to say -
yeah we are
dis recommending against returning short
TTL for our direction because it will
impact the stability of the service this
is happening the outcome for discussion
we had with about the phone that
economists about the D behavior when
there's a conflict before in the in the
previous version that we only returned a
conflict there but the Konami R is a
valid point is that you cannot send back
an update of this situation if you don't
create the resource so that's why we we
updated the behavior - again it is
stable policy based but it's up to the
server to decide whether it has to
return the decrypted code or the
deconflict code this is a the last
change that we we have implemented eg
and the latest version as an outcome of
the of the interrupt meeting this is
mainly minor modifications there it's
about the example that we have fixed and
also the one word change that we we
added in a draft so this is for the
chairs yeah so I take full
responsibility for this in the handoff
with Tobias I was a bubble on this
at this point honestly the early
registration this is is less germane
given that we are about to submit this
document but I will nevertheless check
the action yeah it's fine they're too
closely actually to make sure that we
make some progress on that one so what
next so this slice when I prepare the
slides this is before Andrew raise the
point about the mitigation or loss so
yeah so it's on draw it sucks you - yeah
really so that's whether we yeah we
proceed with with the plan that we we
agree so together that means that next
week there will be another last fall of
the of the document it will one week
we're gonna do cachi weeks one of the
things that the core working group has
asked is hey you're using coop that's
that's great actually after this meeting
I'm gonna go remind everyone and I'm
gonna make the work route - in a state
you know put eyes on it and I'm hopeful
that I'm not necessarily expecting to
find anything but if nothing else I'm
hoping this will grease the grease the
process through through iesg
given that we've had more eyes to look
on it so my hope if that's okay setting
the date we could start the we can start
the working group last call starting on
Monday and kind of run into kind of a
customary to get or two weeks and that
way we can you know start from we think
we fixed absolutely everything we have a
clean document does anyone have any
comment last kind of comments on this
and then we can move forward okay
feedback from Ed on the signal draft all
right that's good news okay because yeah
I don't know if you you have a
discussion with the core cheers yeah
okay so yeah because we have you have
written and in errata because we
contacted them multiple times the
authors or the the the coop RFC and also
for the civil we clarify some of the
point with the Carson but there's one a
errata which we opened there and they
didn't heard any feedback from then it's
about the token for the observe case and
so on but but anyway it's
to them to manage the errata that's it's
left to ya to let them know that we
already in touch with them for some of
the points so you should not be
surprised to see this the specification
indicates surprise they actually
indicated that they wanted to help and
they invited us just to come to the
working group meeting and just remind
everyone then there is a couette another
couette protocol that's in another
working group and offer to put some eyes
on it so what I'm just gonna do a little
advertising at the next session so thank
you for okay one question welcome Adam
could you return the one-page the fun as
well you was a three I mean she's got
from NTT communications so about a
faster rate okay
I know why these changes and also I know
that was read discussed about this issue
but I just feel that this updated text
is not friendly to the new readers of
this draft so I hear some of explanation
of the context which was disgusted up
eating with us should be included in why
the food is replaced with Kate why it is
Kate okay so you think that the how it
takes the D point yes so for me the top
of refresh is not quite clear for maybe
for ya reader yeah in document we don't
remember where in which part that might
be explain what we mean by refresh
surfaces you updates and something and
then so you receive the configuration
you have the the max-age option which
indicate the lifetime for this
configuration and the you have to take
contact the server before the expiry of
that max option to add to refresh it
refresh it does mean that you are
sending the
you see in a sign of life that's in it
that you are there and you will receive
your new configuration from the server
so it's if you think that this is not
clear in the in the new text yeah so
just let me know which okay wait X part
and then we can we can work that as part
of the develop last call that we can you
can help to provide some
texture because actually for this for
this change I am personally fine with
the previous text that we have but I
decided to change it because a for the
implementation I received from John that
he has some confusion when i read the
text i don't see the the origin of the
confusion but even for that with that i
decided to modify the text to avoid this
capital so if you think that this is
still not better if there are a room for
enhancement please feel free to propose
texts and proposals for that yeah thank
you thank you okay thank you
so next on the agenda is beau yang from
China Mobile is going to be talking
about an extension to the signal draft
so if you could step into the mic while
we switch slides here okay so if you
want to step in the queue okay the floor
is yours
if you're speaking we can't hear you
though okay the work is very low do you
increase one of my men
well that's still very quiet we can't
hear you
hello oh that is much better thank you
okay okay I must go very near to the mic
in my my book okay so this is a very
very short discussion about the
intention oh oh this this presentation
is not not just introduces some trouble
to the group but because we know that we
we are almost in the time over the last
call over there or the signal but
because this is a the this is a
requirement from us we want to have a we
are going to have a Kuip for that for
the toast so that way we can make some
changes to that we can make some better
performance to the meaty mediations over
and there's a arrangement of the
resource so this is a what what we
intentioned actually can you please Fred
can you please display the slides thank
you so wrong a second slide no way can I
see this I'm okay
now we are in the second is our second
page in your agenda page so please
continue
I cannot see you cannot see this right
[Laughter]
give me one minute let me come out that
serve oh I mean we can see the slides in
the room here and other media
participants are saying they can see it
so if you just can have a local copy of
the slides and you sent us the slide so
you have the same thing we have and we
slide three that reads background right
now yes for the background is that him
that way
in our in our in our work we do find
that if we have some we have some type t
finally it will be very paid her for you
know for that for the resource
arrangement but actually it's not very
easy to give them to a very worried
because that there are many those types
it's not very easy to give all the types
defined and now
because we were how's a new type of
doubts oh oh das excuse me I do not have
a slight copy I must have a one minute
to get dead if you still is some time to
prepare your local copy maybe we can
switch the order later okay we go to
other topics now and you are the next or
next what okay okay okay thank you
if you prepare the way you can yeah let
me know okay okay thank you thank you
for the SWAT man yeah excuse me this is
a bit of the channel so the there will
be a bit about the the progress status
and the dependent issues and then the
the next steps so this is just as a
reminder of the delusive issue that we
have discussed last time in London and
also in the mailing list I want to go
and to all of them so it's only two to
report that the outcome of the
discussion about the resolution that we
have for each of these issues have been
implemented in the in the 14 version of
the of the document yes no no I was just
gonna jump in so if you're seeing mad
you could have come up with numbers to
things that's because we have explicitly
asked in the case of the various
documents just to help us track all the
issues and kind of number them so we
know when we got closure so we thank you
very much for doing that so then the
where is the the versions there so the
memory finish need that in the in the
diversity that we in the discussion I
had with Jeremy figured out that in the
Danette mode working group access list
specification do you have the some
slides there for the AP before I before
hand with the fragments but for ipv6
this is not something which is really
really clear so we released with the a
lot but working up and also the outward
of the net word specification to make
sure about our interpretation of the
order specification so yeah and the
outcome of that discussion is that they
don't handle a physics fragment in D in
the current net mode eco egg model so
the the as an outcome of that we there
is no modification that we we include it
into a channel specification but we we
added an example in an appendix to show
to the Raiders how you can use the D our
data channel for the the first reign of
the ipv6 fragments for the ipv4 we
completely relied on the on the net mode
specifications so that basically on the
flags but later on we figure we found
another issue with that that I will
explain later
and then we where is not another another
update of draft mainly it's about
clarifications and to fix to fix some of
the of the of the issue that was
reported as an by the the implementers
mainly adjourned for at version and the
the latest version is about the it's
about to fix some of the the point that
was raised by Konami as an output of the
the interrupt and the hackathon so as
you see this is basically some only few
very few changes there that are yeah
that that are were to be to be to be to
be implemented and we have done in the
in the 17 version we have one pending
issue there's again it's about ipv4
fragmentation
actually with the example we have in the
draft we are just fine - with the with
the current use of the the net mode
model but the problem is that if you if
you want for instance to have a
filtering rule in which you want only to
apply some of the Yi on the filter and
only based for instance on the last
fragment you cannot do that with the
current net mod specification because it
is not a bit a bit mess but it is a set
of flags there and for instance if you
have if you want that only the last
fragments will be dropped and then if
you if you set the DD flags to null for
instance this will drop also the de
packet are not not fragmented this is
also the same issue as you have if you
have for instance a packet in which
which is the dot fragment is set and you
in your rule you are just checking that
the more bit is set or unset the the
packet with the don't fragment will go
through while this is this this is
should not be the the operate behavior
so this is this is why we are proposing
to to update the data channel
specification to have this kind of bit
bit bit must be kept a bit rather than
the the current flag based behavior that
they have in the net mode working group
actually this applies not only for the
fragment but also for the TCP flags but
I am NOT putting it here because we have
to decide whether we have to generalize
this for the TCP flags and also for the
different the ipv4 flags there and the
there is a point that was raised to the
widow wish that we need to go back to
the net mode working group so that they
can fix their module there but the issue
is that the they are already sent and
their document to a to the SG and the
discussion I have we with manage that
did not want to have this kind of
features in their module so I prefer
that we fix that in our document rather
than just going back to them to have
this dependency so that's that's the
plan for the the proposal for the
fragmentation and if he where yeah we
would like to hear from the working
group with oh you are you agree with
that or not so just to make sure
everyone understands this is one of the
blockers to finish this document so if
you have a
the authors would very much benefit from
it yeah I entered Mortensen I support
this proposal if we do ever have this
corrected in that mod we can just rather
the version of the protocol yeah no I'm
not sure the team will accept but I like
the representation in the flow of HP
from 1855 extreme high because I as a
dot server I will convert the dot
message into the acrostic message we
know that to stop that eatos attack so
the digital spec itself has a
representation of the fragment of flags
with masks so maybe about a hospital
okay so that's yeah that's that's the
plan that we are proposing for this
graph is that we took to prepare an
abyss version in which we will fix this
fragmentation and for the TCP flanks I
don't know if you want us to cover it in
the next version so that we have the
same behavior for build TCP flags and
also the IP flags or if you want us only
to to focus on the ipv4 flags only
because this will require two
modifications for TCP one is not we
don't have use case for right now but
it's the same problem so I don't know
what if yeah anyone who proposed this
kind of to comment no for for what a
filtering drawer or maybe if the earth
is not now maybe we can raise some
question you can read some question on
the main leads them to solicit other
people's opinion if we needed their here
or not
[Music]
ok so we have some folks in the meet
echo queue hello sir
oh you're up yes is killing me for that
because I do not take my hello can you
hear me
okay yeah we can hear you now you were
breaking up there okay excuse me for
that because I did not take my my laptop
to my my home
so I'd not how all the things is it's
really a mistake for me so so let me
have a quick introduction about them
with insulation actually the those
attacks can be generated in different
ways different mechanisms
right now we are we are discussing the
data China document and you are the next
issue or ego yeah any comments you can
you can you can you can talk if not all
okay okay John okay so just picking up
the TCP flag situation we can specify
something like the sin and the fin flag
in their mosques and we want to drop
that type of attack but again the issue
is if the attacker then adds in any
other bit using the current bits
implementation of memo ACL that will
bypass that particular ACL and go on to
the next ACL so I think I would also
like to see the ability to have the bits
and the mask capability of the TCP flags
okay okay thank you for the feedback
okay so kind of rolling things up thank
you for for the briefing and I kind of
med we have a little bit of an issue
still to resolve we're gonna clear that
in - 18 when we have - 18 we're going to
go order last call on this document
that's the plan okay very good
thank you okay so let's loop back though
we're gonna bring your talk back up here
if you could re-enter the queue bow we
have you on slide three where we left
off on your presentation
perfect so you coming in excuse me okay
we we have okay actually from from out
we can tell area now if the pitch three
hello
yes we are on slide three Bell so we -
things that those attacks can be formed
in different ways different mechanisms
is required to use a different mutation
measured actually from our our
information we we do have three types
and the definition is that the network
layer we have ICMP I for transport alive
with having TCP UDP and soul application
like we have so many candles different
winners have different viewpoint and
clarification dos which lead to some in
talking issues especially when we want
to have a cloud our our resource poor
it's not very easy to do some into
working or to to some you know resource
a Richmond so this is the issue we want
to have a the type either you know in
the toast signal channel so next slide
please
okay so we have what definition
according to the some many vendors
feedback and our our practice from this
we have the three three subsets but the
Foster is the about the layer which
layer it's a network transport of
application for protocol we were used as
a as a seconder information and it's the
third we have attack types and then we
have other attacked subtypes this is
what we used in our network we we try it
we try to how all the vendors to me
ranges here the ghost type uses this
table next slide please
I think we are you in page 3 page 6 way
to sing some benefits for those type in
in you dos foster is for the toast
client it's very easy to get those type
from the attack to tiger target because
it's a it's very easy to because it how
being suffered from the DOS
it's it aware how very very very
detailed information about what kinda
with detect protector its suffered and
it helps make the decision right which
store to send the medications
requirement because we have the one
client to earn store connections and for
the dots gateway it will help to
aggregation over the same time attacked
so more efficiency communication and it
will help the thought did we to have the
information come to the native speakers
and help to analyze this
things and a photo store it will help of
two intruders their medication Santa -
although it's for the communication
between the dose so under the mitigator
is the outer scope but actually it will
help for doing that so with the toast
type included in single movie share the
information between client and the
getaway and the store each node should
have more information about the attacks
the opposite this model can even be set
up easily nice slide please
actually this is my current
consideration about that how can we work
with that the signal is that we
introduce a post type know the Inza
in your model and a nice slide please as
I mentioned that because is a that we
are used for the single truck that we
are almost as elastic on stage we got
distracted discuss and if we come alone
without this discuss and it refines a
current a toast type before it is
included into the draft if we note with
the knockout comes load movie she that
can be included in tonight's the world
that's almost thank you
hello know we're here thank thanks bro
comments from from the floor ok I see
Roland in the queue I'm gonna go I'm
gonna drop you sir Roland can speak
Roland please
if you're speaking we can't hear you
rolling Chris could you put it if it is
if roll ends on Jabbar can you could you
proxy rolling since we can't hear you
could you drop your comment on Jabbar
and well proxy into the room
okay so let me just while we're waiting
for Roland's conduct come up I mean
again to summarize with this draft
there's an introduction of an optional
an optional field that does
classification of a particular das the
denial service type and there's a desire
to drop that into the signal draft now
Rowan's common is dots is not intended
to be a full interventive control
channel there are in infinitude of
possible DDoS attack types different
vendors used up different vendors use
different paradigms we should stick to
signaling for now okay thanks Roland
Kaname one last thing is let's take this
up as a possible extension tsunami yeah
convenient easy communication maybe are
the same common law Alice's but yep so
how to keep young model and simple
mapping latest with imagine these are
taxis difficult question in my feeling
it is nature to be included in the you
know each other and also to each other
is that kind of get those types yeah
okay other comments I'll intermittent
also lend my support for the previous
comments from condom and Rowand and also
point out that there is a document
defining different das types already in
the ayat the IETF RFC 4732 okay over the
line right now is empty okay did you
want to respond hello thanks for the for
the feedback III gotta study for missus
data will to have that the foundation
for the house of typing is a IETF so I
will go back to check that I just want
to fit back to the low latticed suggests
the question that why they need that how
you hear that okay yes wrong to comment
at that RFC 4732 obsolete shouldn't be
used
yeah okay Andrew right that he's correct
but that is the the most standardized
version of the document that we that we
have inside to work on so the other
thing is that we we have discussed
something like this in the past one of
the reasons we didn't do it if I'm
recalling correctly
is that the signal or the dots client
may not actually have the full scope of
the attack it's hard to trust the dots
client to actually be reporting accurate
information in certain cases certainly
even one of the attack types he's got if
there's a care gem an amplification
that's pretty easily represented in a
source port in an Akal UDP 19 so there
are other ways to get some of this
information across okay
actually I just give both back about
that yes maybe that client do not have
the whole information or even ADA to the
information is not fully trusted but it
but as we suggested it's a optional
field it can be used as a reference at
least the inside the inside a wine
domain as it were important
hey Mortensen again yes I agree
I'm also supporting the the idea of
moving this beyond the current signaling
draft thank you
okay there thanks boo
other comments okay
so thank you for that I mean what we're
hearing with the multiple kind of
presentations we had is we're gonna have
to figure out what to do with extensions
and how to talk about them in parallel
to advancing the signal draft so that
that's a marker for something we need to
resolve as a working group okay so next
up on the agenda is the use case
conversation so Daniel hi everyone so
the use case so actually I in the front
page there is 15 version 15 but I think
at the time I was writing the
presentation testers while I was writing
the presentation another version came up
yeah 16 so in in the ITF 101 in London
we had a commitment from the co-author
to put a version then it's gonna be
wrecking your black hole into a month
and I think that's what we which hit our
goal so so that's fine um we had very
few comments from version 12 to the
working of last hole but since the
version of Lascaux that means started
Trey's a lot of questions a lot of
comments and reviews so the latest we
had was version 16 just published today
I think we are really in this state
where we are polishing two drafts now so
well I believe from version 10 to 11 we
had a major refactoring nothing
controversial we most of the tech-savvy
net just for youth and this place of
different places so the main changes
that we're reduces the number of few
spaces from the initial number to three
use cases so that's also I think now
it's almost ready to to be shipped to
the IHG or to be sent to the ad and
thank you for all the reviews okay so
Daniel thank you for all the rapid
revisions there we so Frank and I need
to kind of take a look at given yet many
of these revisions were made this week
we have not had a chance to kind of
review the things certainly in the last
two days it looks like many of the
issues kind of are closed it's likely
our feeling that we will not need
another worker blast call this is really
a matter of kind of closing those issues
and we believe it will likely be ready
to submit for for shepherding we just
want to take one more kind of luck
before that yeah yeah but from your
perspective there will be you are done
there are no more edits to kind of
process you believe all feedback has
been covered yeah that's my feeling but
if you disagree raised that's on the
milling is okay and so let's just gonna
do a final check everyone feels like
there were comments have been addressed
anyone descending anyone else have any
other comments to add into the use case
document there's been robust discussions
yeah okay very good thank you for all
data duration and thank you for the
mailing list for responding back with
all of all of that okay thank you Daniel
thanks for preparing that all right so
let's do we have a little we had
actually quite a lot of time for open
mic so if there are things folks would
like to raise by all means come come on
up while we prepare the wrap-up
you know okay then we pull up the
wrap-up slides here I do have to leave
fullscreen
okay so we did a bunch of discussion
about where to take the giraffe so I
have updated the the table so on
requirements we have the Shepherd right
up that's going to be going to our ad
with the architecture draft there's one
more revision to do ready about
mid-august and we're gonna start a
working group last call than likely kind
of late August
I see head nodding from the architecture
team so that's good with use cases that
text is actually incorrect the - 15 is
the last version it believes we believe
that that covers everything that needs
to get done the chairs are going to make
sure that it looks like everything is
closed and if it is we're gonna go to
kind of you the Shepherd review if
not we may force another Rev we talked
about the signal draft there's going to
be one more revision to 22 and then
we're gonna go working a second group a
second working group last call or did I
not write that down right then do we go
work the second working group last call
with - 21 yes okay so we go second
working group last call with - 21 thank
you for that clarification and then with
the data channel we we at least know
about the fragmentation issues so that's
going to take a revision to - 18 and
that's going to get us to working group
last call in this September timeframe
and that is our whole stack of documents
and then we noted that we need to
further a conversation relative to kind
of extensions and make sure it's clearly
known how to how to proceed there and
we're gonna take that to the mailing
list okay so anything wrong with that
voiceover in terms of kind of dates we
have some time I see Konami approaching
please yeah from NTT communications so
I'd like to hear from the room about
meetings about the thoughts second step
though
maybe those vacuum items are of stable
and then coming IETF we we do the
Hakkasan or internal testing with more
implementations then
if it not time for thinking about a
husband of the kind of dogs stipple and
daddy switch biting teeth those men are
then you can proceed to the step - I
think so
how about what do we think about that
okay now it's a tiring further making
you talk about new make new working
group I can drop further yeah yes II
think that's it's time that we think
about the at the next estate in Italy
charter to see that we we have something
which is official in term of the the
item of interest the working group we in
the past we have presented the the dots
discovery discussions with a home in and
so on
I would like that we revive all this
discussion so that he can be considered
this is only examples but I think that's
there is a room for reform or
enhancement and more work for the if the
discussion can happen it would be really
great remembering of course that some of
this may take reach are during and
that's a conversation can with the eg
and the community writ large with that
caveat
it's been was giving me that look yeah
hi enter Mortensen yeah one of the
things that is to mention in the use
cases but it's not necessarily been
treated here is is the case where the I
think could be ITP is actually signaling
downstream to the the enterprise to say
you're the source of an attack you need
to block closer to it and we haven't
seen any of that treated other thoughts
on what next-gen dots would look like
that we want to talk about here going
once going twice
good oh I see Roland coming into the
queue rolling the floor is yours Oh
Roland if you're speaking we don't hear
you I assume you are jabbering and
jabber scribe will hopefully bring that
up for us we appreciate that and on the
screen I just flashed up the edits folks
made in our conversation about next
steps with the current draft so this one
should be correct now if it is not
please correct me this is what we're
gonna enter into the minutes and
milestones the Roland's common is more
of the extension stuff that's what I'd
really like to see more of the things we
talked about as possible extensions then
Caidic just noting since you asked for
Corrections the - 16 of the use cases
document was published earlier today
thank you okay
going once going twice thank you for for
coming we'll see you around the man
lists continue the conversations and I
thank everyone for their hard work to
getting us disclose to a lot of work
group last calls
[Music]