I caught your name or your question
accurately so please go to the ether pad
we can all contribute here's the blue
sheet being passed down so hopefully
people can start filling them out agenda
here's the the milestone okay we have
adopted quite a few working group drafts
and our working group the primary goal
is to define the data models to network
security functions and we have achieved
quite a lot there are quite a few
there's some left over work and ad
wanted us to finish them as quickly as
possible by next April
no next February we should all finish
the data model and send to the iesg for
review and after that we can either
close the working group or if there are
new work we can reach other and continue
okay so today's that's today's agenda is
quite tight so next one I will pass it
to the Hakkasan update okay
little bit technical issues I think this
is the we implemented I trained as a
frame-up using open source software this
work involves seven graduate students in
some human University and two graduate
students in students in university three
professors and three which others are
leading our project this is the poster
or I to Anna's and as a framework
project in this eckerton we implemented
the registration interface security
policy translation and automated police
provisioning first registration
interface I Tennessee Futurecast and as
their capabilities to scourge controller
security controller
the high-level policy into low-level
policy if his security controller cannot
find the proper NSA security controller
cast the instantiation of NSA to
developers management system and then
develop developers management system
registered an sf2 switch controller and
this is the young data model of a
registration interface and this is the
stable security policy translation first
extract the data from high-level policy
using the extractor determines define it
automata and convert the data into NSA
record required data and then make
low-level policy using the context-free
grammar the top of tree is the NSA
record data and matching the
capabilities using context-free grammar
so let live to let the blue boxes though
the left blue boxes though is the
example of making the low-level c4
firewall and right blue boxes though
example making low-level policy for web
filter this is the hexagon topology and
this is this is the environment team in
Paris I
this is implementing environment we
unloaded our source code and you get hop
and you can see the demo and YouTube
in this in this 100 second hackathon we
implemented the registration interface
to create a police translator and
automatically see provisioning using the
CompTIA Chekov sir kata opendaylight and
mini name thank you thank you thank you
very much for doing that hackathon and
so um I'll move on to the next one so
this next one is armor STM controlled
IPSec configurations so the presenter
will be talking remotely afterwards
since there's another model in this
particular model that defined two cases
like where's the controller only sending
down the configuration another one is
element network service function doesn't
security function doesn't support a key
and actually there's a sir model so
after this presentation or like Carol to
to talk about the sir model and then see
how that could be made me integrate it
together okay so okay yeah okay thank
you good afternoon they're basically
following integers advice with this
presentation trying to come up tomorrow
what we have done the idea we are now
arriving and some treacherous tricks so
what makes life sorry so we think we are
we are trying to define as an
architecture for the management of IPSec
security Association using an SDM model
so
we have a centralized controller
providing the information are to
establish dynamically all these IPSec
security Association we define two cases
in the first case the assumption is the
network security function will have a
night person to implementation so the
controller will need to configure that
I'm implementing on other pieces of
different databases and relating with
IPSec and then the case to where the
assumption is the nerd more security
fashion Anderson has any version of
implementation so the only thing we have
is the kernel to board for Ivy set so
the goal behind the draft is to define
the interface interfaces required to
manage and monitor all the Ivy sex again
the Association in the NSF taking into
account these two gates is case one and
case two for case one we will need a
jump model for Ike version two SPD d ad
and models that allows to collect state
data for aggression to and the sa ID for
the IPSec security associations of
course in the case - we don't have Ike
we don't need PA D the only thing we
need to be fine there is this in the NS
ad and actually our dev already passed
the jump model for all these cases and
all these are required information so
next one so here just a summary you can
find the explanation in the internet
draft case 100 as you can see in the
safe I can type e6 support so they
controlling will need to provide that
information based on the jumbo that we
have defined the case - there's no key
management protocol in an NSF so in the
staff is simpler huh so this security
controller following the typical Sdn
controller has everything so you need to
create all the state and create a VIP
security associations because actually
the NSF doesn't have our IQ
implementation migration to implications
next
so as I mentioned we have all 25 of your
model
the model is based on our radio or the
standard our experience and the RFC 4301
of the AG version 2 RFC and we have also
included sound information observe in
implementation out there particular are
XF our API in Linux system as I said
depending on the case you will need to
configure part of them for case one of
your diagram to information feeding
information SPD for the IPSec policies
and actually related with that I just
execute the Association the only thing
you need is to get a black plastic data
because after all like version 2 will
create that is actually with the
association for you based on the
information on this ID and the rest of
the information in case - there's no I
person - so the only thing we need to
deal with his SPD to include I detect
policies and collects on the state data
and then to create to configure to the
latest data about the basic security
associations that they are controlling
has created based on the information are
provided by the administrator you seen
typically the northbound API also this
so from the last version we provide a
nice idea we didn't have any
presentation because it was a minor
modification that right now and I have
an update in Section 803
in the discussion about case one on
parcel case 2 where we describe a little
bit the recurring process and now in
more details we have several step there
like an algorithms
explaining how to do it in case in case
- or what happened with the NSF
crashes and then it doesn't have any
state about IPSec or what having the
naturally so behavior
we have also on the state to young model
for example to collect current IPSec say
lifetime or foreign-policy lifetime or
what are the numbers of our toilet days
that they I get i person's
implementation Haas building it has held
waiting so basically that and then that
is pretty new in this new version
version 0 block next one so here a few
slides about is their natural muscle
burn so it's this is update let's not
run okay so the configuration in case
one basically is fairly easy because the
only thing you need to I mean I Gresham
to is in the NSF and has a mechanism to
detect McRoberts also little
configuration there in case to it
relates on the assumption that the
security controller knows it comes on so
you can know this where the network
devices based on that the controller you
to starving for accessible ESP over UDP
or ESP over TCP etc and we have that
information in there in the young model
next one about the regime again case one
of course is one we have ignition to
make version two already handles there
we keep the ringing part like this we
don't have that and everything is saved
to the security control we need some
kind of procedure to do the Ricky
actually what we have designed is
something simple in the sense what we do
in summary is security control
we'll create the amount security
Association in both NSF's mall and that
McGee will start when we receive
notification from the NSF one of the NSF
may be both saying some particular at
this executive session is going to
spires firing and then we grade the
amount security Association first when
we have confirmation the inbound
security Association out there and then
we install the outbound security
associations and then in that part after
that we can remove the old IPSec
security Association of course we can
think about another approaches maybe
more optimized but this one could be
reasonable in the sense everything is
fixed in the in terms of the installing
inbound and then outbound and then when
everything is set set up and it's it's
okay and then we can remove the day on
work in case for example one of the NSS
crashes a lost state actually the
algorithm for the case two is fairly
similar accepting the step three where
obviously for example in one of them a
service B is if B crashes then there is
no need to remove their own IPSec
security associations but we need to
remove the other peer at least they all
appeared security associations next one
so regarding the implementation we have
actually we have a NSF implementation
for case one we have the Ike version two
based on Strongsville and regarding to
the net confront yelling fermentation
we're using metal beer this is a
linux-based implementation for case two
we are just using another beer no need
for a version two implementation and we
have been able to go very basic
configuration about the stablishing this
IPSec security Association but just
using a not compliant using the terminal
from another another machine so what do
we needs to work in the security
controller side we have explored only
end of in daylight and on earth we have
the aim we have be able to configure in
a self in a very basic mode using both
controllers we have all the Eleanor no
but I can assure you we still need a lot
of work there as you know this piece of
solar are complex so we are fighting
with them at this point our goal
actually we would like to have a
complete proof of concept at least an
autonomous way to receiving notification
what happened with one NSF is crap is
crushing or during the wreak a period so
we are working on that so that is part
or it related with the next slide please
next so to be done of course what we
need is review the jump model in the
current stage we have detected some
minor correction that we will update in
the next revision but we receive pole
pounders review some time ago but of
course we ever say that but we require
more reviews for an expert of course and
a little imitation level it's clear we
need to continue the work in the
controller side we would like to have a
complete or not autonomous is scenario
list even if it's small list to see how
everything evolves based on all the
notification we have designed out all
the information we have the jam hall of
the sitter and we would really
appreciate collaboration in this side
because I'm pretty sure there are more
expert in the road and out there that
are working with implementation we have
sit down in the hackathon and we would
need some help on this part so that is
my presentation I have been I have tried
to be short just to promote some
discussion if you have any question yes
let me know thank you thank you
any questions comments
Frank Safari hello firstly I want to say
that I think that that that is a good
draft because 80s are proposed to our
radical solution for the industry right
now for example for the Espeon
management and provision mean it is kind
of automatic IPSec VPN Turner
Construction solution so this document
is a very good input for second a second
a second comment is I think during our
previous discussion whether it's my main
list or by some of language scholarship
I think the biggest question or biggest
concern of current draft is mainly on
the case to on the you know on the
hardwood directory configure or manager
the session key and the related
accession configure special continue
chattering attributes directory to the
CP to the pier so I yeah actually I I
think your crystal solution is one way
but there are still other way based on
the STM control decentralized the way to
for example where we can where we can
calculated the key and the hallway
distributed and so but I I kind of think
this these have some trade-off between
the security and the provision
efficiency or the scalability so I would
like to hear more discussion and
comments on this part should shoot away
supplanter
people ways to probation them and how to
say aye
I think I think I found my personal view
I think her the crystal solution has has
its own value and its own scenarios but
we master have a good assumption that
the controller and the manager link
between the controller and the peer has
we're protected met madmen so to protect
her to protect her the information is
changes then so that I still think that
to the case to men's are they is
variable it makes sense so that's not
you that's my cousin idea but I think we
do have care to the consensus about it
so I like to hear more comments about
this point I have a the main thank you
think about that the main part there is
one of the key question there was
obviously the SDN controller the
security controller needs to create all
the IPSec security Association in the
NSS that's clear and one of the
parameter of course the key you will you
will have to use and that's the the
particular are common there so the
concern might be okay the security
controller is seeing in some point at
some point anything the keys that will
be installed in the NSS the question is
obviously following this the Empire in
the controller is it should be a trusted
entity obviously you have security
associations between the NSF and the
security controller based for example
you're using that counts you'll have TLS
or SSH so the distribution itself is not
is it's not a problem the problem or the
the comments we have received is the
security controller will need to create
a random key that we finally be
installed it will be
finally installed in the NSF that's the
key point
so solutions there are a recent draft as
well that written by Dave Carroll well
they want to or to avoid that for
example using some kind of difficult
saying okay
the controller doesn't see the key so
the key is generated by the NSF itself
so they let the security controller
cannot get those keys from anywhere
right
it creates maybe some problem but that's
another discussion the thing is the key
point in case two is what happened is in
somehow the security controller is not
trusted for some reason it's attacked
and then what happened you're speaking
now I'm going to do anything here like
this
hi so thanks for bringing this and got
two questions well the first is well I
still don't see the value in your case
too because any NSF is running on some
platform could be usually Linux could be
Mac OS the windows even phones every one
of them has an IP to demon I think you
demons are ubiquitous there is
ubiquitous is TLS implementations so
they're everywhere we don't really have
this tour and a stuff that doesn't have
an IQ to implementation and the other
thing is that well it's a matter of key
hiding we know these saying that three
people can keep a secret if one of
them's dead so it's far better for the
traffic he at least to be common just to
the two peers and not be able to and not
have the less the SDN controller being
able to
leak it and well one final thing that's
for Linda we really need the job scribe
is anybody can do
jabbers Craig so right now we don't have
anybody come and do it my computer
cannot allow that so right yeah good
question a quick comment to the
presenters equine wise Francisco
I think the contribution of the yang
models is it's very valuable and case
one is a very valuable as well just to
put what maybe you all have said in a
different light or what some people have
been saying when we think of caen
distributing configuration through a
yang model that's reasonably safe
because a third party that would see the
configuration can't do a tremendous
amount with it but when we treat keys as
configuration that's where the threat
model becomes very difficult to deal
with and I think that's what the another
way to say what's kind of the issues
with that case - thank you the thing can
I say something okay now the thing is in
our view in our experience for example
when when the SDM parenting started for
example the the routing protocols are
not that in the routing device so are
moved to the head to the Sdn and
basically their routing device is young
merely switch our processing flows so
that's the basic idea in case - right if
you are doing that you are moving part
of the control to the partner of
everything and just leaving in the
device the flow based part which is
their basic kernel for example where
they have seen regarding your or your
command your job I don't understand why
NSF should be there is there any
requirement for NIH and NSF should be
this one or this one or
this requirements in terms of CPU memory
or everything I don't know here we have
seen some comments also and they
manually say maybe your who we can have
for example thousands of nodes creating
and then if you're saving some memory or
some CPU could be variable so what I see
is obviously if you have a constraint
device there is a malleable thing there
when are we saying this word is not
valid in general I mean in this working
group to or you know to provide that
kind of models to more constrained
devices to save memory save CPU I cannot
tell I'm working also with IOT stuff and
then the Sun of this idea are coming
from there maybe maybe you're not using
IPSec maybe you're using DTLS or DTLS
but you know I don't know what are the
NSF requirements terms of capacity or
[Music]
capabilities that NSF should be should
be should have in that case I remember
during our interim meeting on this
subject we agreed that this document
should clearly writing down the security
risks associated with model to write so
that for like IOT device with very
constraining resource they can utilize
that with acknowledge the risk they are
taking that's I thought that was the
agreement right in fact the ID has a
security section explaining precisely
that in the sense ok of course you have
a trusted entity which is acting a key
distribution center obviously that
trusted entity is not trusted anymore
for some reason Tatian that's clear but
I think it's as you mentioned it's a
trade-off somebody I think Frank
mentioned that it's a trade-off
obviously then I say be simple
even in terms of implementation you need
to deal with just with the SPD jump part
the immoral part and this is ID we are
sending that information and it's
simpler you need to deal with the kernel
part and just that then in case one the
ninja need to add the information for
the BA D there Ike version two
information the SPD of course and I said
he just a collecting data but you know
what we see what we see is there is
value even in the case to of course
there is a risk is there explained and
somehow people understand that case and
you are trying to you know fixing that
problem where or that issue where maybe
the controller may see some kids okay
that's good that's good yeah well I
understand that it's just that I
personally don't see much see the case
for IOT devices that's do IPSec there
well they might do for themselves but
not a functioning as an network security
function at any rate I think this debate
is going to continue at the IPSec me
working group later this days yeah we'll
see you there
okay so just to continue discussion that
there's actually 1.5 case like we turn
case one and a taste to so I'll let Dave
Carol to exploit a little bit so that
see if that kind of thing can be
incorporating to those data models okay
I'll try to do this really quickly
so we've I work in a SD Wang company
they're actually acquired by someone
bigger so I've been working on this
problem for a while and we have a real
case where we actually do want something
case to like we don't want to implement
an IKE v2 in our end nodes but we need
the security you know as Brian said as
your offset there's key hygiene and we
don't want the Anna
or we I'm sorry we don't want the
central controller knowing these keys so
we put together this controller IP and
whether it's a case - or a case three I
don't know it doesn't really matter
there may be a Rafa was saying that
maybe a point were you wanting really a
small IOT device that doesn't do any key
management so what we put together is
really a simple idea can we pop the
first slide so what is this controller I
it's a key exchange method and that's
really all it is we're not trying to
create a protocol that manages the NSF
this is something that would be suitable
for embedding in Rafah the submission or
something else the concept is really
simple we're doing diffie-hellman so
each each peer creates their own
diffie-hellman pair they're going to
send their public values up to the
controller the controller will
distribute out an entire list of
everybody's public keys and now every
node can create a shared secret with
every other node in the network it's
it's pretty simple there's no
peer-to-peer messaging needed and you
know speaking to yobs comments this is
part of where the value is
we don't want peer-to-peer messages
because we have topologies whether it's
possibly only one-way communication we
have topology is where we don't want the
latency of doing an Ike setup and you
know I think people have talked on the
list about how many how many RSA is can
you do in a second there's a little more
to it than that so anyways if you look
at it that's all we did
now we've got our keying up it sounds
like that was really easy and now we're
done but the problem is synchronized so
we have to rekey all these devices
fairly often right keys gets stale we
don't want to use these keys forever
so what happens when one purely keys
they're going to send a new key up to
the controller the controller now has to
distribute that to the other peers
they're all going to get it at a
different period of time and so
keeping this all synchronized is an
issue that's something you have to worry
about when you've got a network of
10,000 nodes you can assume that a lot
of them are wreaking at the same time so
now you have to handle how did all that
happen
and we don't want to drop packets we can
we explode
so synchronization is where it comes
down to I'm going to speak a little more
to this and I'd be sick of me so I'll be
really quick in the draft we've got four
rules that you have to you have to
follow we spent a lot of time kind of
proving this out and reducing it down to
four simple rules if we follow those we
have state machines that now can support
all of the synchronization we can very
large networks even with you know in our
cases tens of thousands of nodes and it
all works everything can be done
simultaneously if it needs to but that
synchronization is very loose so one one
person can rekey at one point in time
another peer can receive those keys at a
later point in time in fact they can
receive those keys and decide I don't
have the time to deal with it right now
and I'll react to it later it's loose if
all works everything comes out security
needs the big thing in this only the
peers you know session keys that are
being used and that was pretty much the
five of the other impetus for this and
that's all I'd say read the draft and
find out more come to IQ second I mean I
don't have a one question for the
messaging between the nose to the
controller what carry the message is it
like it so we don't define a protocol we
had methods so we've we've indicated
what needs to be in that message message
well you know what are the fundamental
units but I'm assuming that a night to
an ACEF protocol or somebody else's
protocol is what's in preparing this
okay and there are requirements on there
you need to have a trusted authenticated
connection to your controller you don't
trust your connect
your controller all bets are off this
would be pointless thank you I have I
have a question yes basically the thing
is assuming we are using V V helm and of
course if the SDN controller is attacked
then we may have a mug in the middle
possibly mine the middle but obviously
this is better because in the end you
don't see their kids the final kiss but
I thinking that for example looking at
the case two we have where we send all
the IPSec security Association
information instead of sending the key
you could stand for example or the
public key the diffie-hellman public key
right correct that's right in the end in
the end what we're it's it's we're
keeping the same there may be a little
something we need to change but what I
see is if I send that information this
is the IPSec security Association you i
won
we want you to configure but instead of
sending you the key that I again already
I meaning security controller I'm
sending you the public key of the other
side correct
so yes the SI information that's pretty
much all of it would still be coming
from your protocol but not the keys we
want to get something that only the
peers ago so so that that's that's fine
because in the end there's still to me
to me I think your presentation is
saying that and I and I agree this case
too is I don't I I don't say case three
or what I see is case two but with a
modification that instead of sending the
the wrong public key sorry there are all
session key you're sending the public
key so the NSF is generating the year
correct and we need to add a mechanism
for the peer to send its public key up
to the
but you get there there there are ways
to do that I would assume that it would
be part of this of your draft or a note
but yes it needs to be provided for how
that's done
so at you sorry this kentley um i chide
someone break the tie here i think
there's a distinction what's being
mentioned right so I think the way
Rafael's merchants are similar to the
scheme that you guys proposed but that
in the sense this controller is the man
in middle ask that right so I think I
think that's a wrap I was saying that
and that it is using your Duffy helmet
but then is generated by the controller
versus having one side generating and
passing it through the controller that's
my understanding the difference right
that's why I seem to hear are you
talking about the controller generating
the public keys okay two questions first
one through your way through your mentor
though you achieve what you achieve the
user you you calculate either the
pairwise session key among among each
each pair of the pier right like that
classical I okay he was in - right
correct okay and okay this is a rank one
question for credit kitchen secondly in
addition to the session key how about
SAE
tributes other si attributes to use
share the same attributes among other
communication peers or still the
pairwise specifically a part of our
method our method is really focused on
just getting the keys across so I I
would assume it's still up to
Rafa's protocol to push down the si
attributes and tell the NSF okay how
it's supposed to be communicating okay
in our in our method we added some
ability for you could almost call it
negotiation
when you have cases typically an SDN
Network you've just told everyone you're
running a SGC m256 period and nobody has
to negotiate anything but there are
times where you'll be doing migrations
you may be moving too you know from
aes-128 KS 256 and you can't you don't
want a red-letter day where traffic's
gonna stop you're gonna want to tell
people to migrate and so how do you then
have people figure out when there is no
like between them that hey I can only do
this but I can I can only do a but
I can do 256 mm-hmm so so we try to put
in some provisions for that but it's
potentially not necessary okay so for
the finalists and you're correctly so
you're clear you adjusted to the key you
ago she ate you but other actually this
may be the not a negotiation right
it's a centralized away and everywhere
the the the the same essay attributes
something maybe we can talk offline all
right okay Brian Weiss so I think Rafael
what you're saying is the the state
machine by which you today in case to
when you push down keys could be the
same state machine is used for pushing
tentatively humming Keys as opposed to
our draft kind of implies a broadcast
model by the controller is that right
yeah that the thing is because you're
sending the public key in a broadcast
way you mission right well but it
doesn't anything I guess a peer sends
its public key to the controller oh all
right then the controller sends it out
to all the other peers how it sends it
whether it's in an individual message to
each other peer by the way when you want
to talk today if here's his key or
whether it broadcasts it out as one big
ears day's key that's protocol dependent
so we're not my hug a my my my comment
my previous comment was of course in
some point the controller needs to say
an IPSec security an IPSec security
Association inbound outbound to the
different two different NSS
right for example for every gig correct
you're sending the information what we
are doing right now in case two we send
all the information including the key
for the inbound and the key for the
outbound okay so so what we see is okay
let's not send that session key just
sent some key material diffie-hellman
key material so the NSF just need to
create the session key so the session
key is not seen by the security
controller but the security controller
still has all the information about the
IPSec security Association as Sept the
key material that will be used in the
inbound and outbound correct so so a
slight difference sir to your state
machine you were talking about doing
synchronization sending out the inbound
si is first in the outbound si is later
that would not be needed with this
method you could simply send out the si
information with the public keys and the
convenient NSF's can then complete they
can handle the synchronization of
knowing how to install the inbound and
waiting for the appropriate time to
install the app app that you know when
we thought about the that algorithm we
have in our ID was you know to be pretty
sure that we have the inbound first and
then the outbound so when the unbound is
installed in the kernel everything goes
there I mean the flow will go using the
the new outbound so the inbound in the
other side will really but we also
thought about saying okay here you have
outbound are inbound to one and a set
obviously you will optimize the number
of messages between the the security
controller and the NSS because you're
sending all the information they are
violent bow but we our approach we
consider that approach a little bit
safer in the say okay we have the
inbound there so nothing happened the
old one is still used and then we
install the outbound in the kernel and
then
everything is really multi but I mean
Donnell garden can be a yes we also as I
mention we also thought about installing
outbound and inbound at the same time in
parallel in both NSF so consider that
just like installing the inbound and
outbound is going to break network
communications at least temporarily you
can't you can't blindly install both you
need to keep things synchronized your
method I believe will have scaling
issues if you try to scale it up to say
10,000 nodes but the biggest thing is
your what you're negotiating is unique
got security associations yeah it's a if
unicast which means you need a secure
station between this point and this
point even if we have a thousand nodes
right but those are if this node has
security association with different
nodes those are unique up security
Association
so it's one-to-one so if something
happened for example you receive expired
notification from the NSF from the
kernel actually we're transforming that
in a drift occasion using that
conferring Jam model the security
controller will need to react will need
to install maybe the policies has
changed for some reason and apply
another different way in that particular
moment and then it needs to send a basic
security Association the difference here
is whether we send the session key from
the security controller meaning the
security no dollar generates a random
value which is the session key so the
significance unless sees that key or we
send a public key diffie-hellman public
key we send that and then the the NSF
will create that the session key by the
zone which is fine terminal security
because the security control doesn't see
that key but their procedure all the
information about the IPSec security
Association all the policies all
information is in the security
controller the security controller has
the picture of the different nodes in
the Indian
work so to me trying to move that I I'm
talking about the case to so creating
the students NSF creates understate
about the inbound outbound I in our
comes to the NSF in case two is even
with simpler everything is coming all
the configuration IPSec configuration is
coming from the security controller
internal office scalability as the
imperative is designed to support that
kind of scalability it can control many
devices routing information now security
so I don't see I don't see a problem
there what I see all the discussion here
was we may have a security problem the
security controller may see those keys
and somehow this part feels people
uncomfortable and I understand that we
have that in Security section part your
idea is fine because solve that
particular fact but not sure about what
is the scalability problem because in
the end the security controller needs to
take actions based on events coming from
the NSF for anything okay well I mean at
this point maybe we should continue some
of this offline oh sure but I I'm
hearing what you're saying and you know
I I think I have some comments to it but
I'd rather sort of beat it around so I
think that's have a good discussion
thank you thank you very much let's
continue offline on the mailing list so
the next one thank you we're running a
little bit late so next one is the
applicability document and that's the
one we actually it's very close to
working group last call
so Paul
okay we have don't have enough time I
just particularly reporter status and
the domaine in content please take a
look
so a probability I to NSF to network
security and services this document
updated okay added to ourselves our
sections the first one is I to NSF or
with except she architecture the second
one is I to Ana's that will weigh the an
apple we reference architecture
so the a separate cases we implemented
the hackathon project we are ruled on
concept secondly a Nepali that runs
architecture case my university skq and
then our colleague university summer
university we are working for
improvement I to NSF on top of an apple
we using acoustic so this coming
November meeting
we try to probe concept using hackathon
project so I mentioned so mainly the a
probability case how to apply I to NSF
to do network system so you can see the
three earlier our address that the first
one is a Sdn with iTunes app other case
SPC enough of me okay so next please
slide so let me show you so this is the
structure for now I Taurus apple with a
surface ship framework so in order to
power we enforce
get the policy into the truck we have to
configure classifier or the established
families on polder with traffic flow
information and security policy together
so that kind information can be
configured to using NSF OPC interface
okay so this is a detailed let me skip
it the last one is I to NSF are with an
employee so currently we're thinking
security controller can be implemented
using en element management and also
develop a minimal system can be also
implemented as element management and
then the life of cycling case we just
take advantage of existing and after we
interface at 3e and whenever manager
interface okay shot for yet yeah
thanks Paul on the previous slide with
SF see are you going to use nsh at all
all here yeah okay so basically we also
using MSH so we try to for example we
consider what scenario is a chain of I
were a dpi or a technician case
especially power is at the first NSF if
there is a something some messages
should be delivered to dpi we can using
ns8 metadata filter and then the next
tip here MSF can take advantage over
that so we can surely use yeah
okay that that's good I think you should
maybe add an explanation in your draft
okay and then on the next slide in a in
a NFV system especially a man''ôs system
you've called out one interface
just ensure that it's obvious that
that's a man oh interface and I think
there's some others that might be
involved so please take a look at the
latest mono drafts I'm sure Diego can
help you if you need some help there and
make sure that because I think that we
mono is established so it's important
that we are compatible with the mono
reference points that doesn't mean that
we don't need our own of course we do
but compatibility I think will be a big
thing
thank you okay thank you so Diego Lopez
also going up with all sorts so he or
lady I gave us some information open
source or mono so we definitely take a
look ok thank you so we want to last
poll we believe almost there so I
welcome your feedback ok that's it thank
you very much
and any questions actually we are
running out of time so how about if you
please read the document and provide
feedback we probably will call the last
call after this meeting so next one is
the capability information modeling that
Linda just one thing and this is the
arrow phone again now when it comes to
the last call I Paul and I am talking
about reshaping a little bit the flow of
the document to make it a little bit
more consistent and check to tell a
consistent story so before we go for
less call okay let me okay
absolutely absolutely okay thank you
thank you so much
[Music]
you want to use this too okay
sure why not I like lightsabers yeah it
works so hello my name is John Strauss
snare and I will talk about the current
status of the capability model this
seems like it's yeah thank you
so who always read the draft yeah that's
this is kind of an important draft if
we're going to do models please read it
basically a capability is a function or
a set of functions that are advertised
by an NSF they can be vendor independent
they could possibly be vendor dependent
as well and with that the security
controller can realize the security
functions desired for a given domain by
putting together different capabilities
from one or more NSS there in
normatively we say that n every NSF
should be described with the set of its
capabilities capabilities are not the
same as access control but capabilities
may be affected by access Patrol so this
draft defines an information model for
representing capabilities in a
vendor-neutral way one data model
implementation of that could be yang
there's many others as well there is the
notion of a capability algebra now what
that algebra is is a template to provide
a mathematically formal definition of
which capabilities are actually active
so if I if I'm the security controller
and I have sets of capabilities from
different NSF's then using set
theoretics i can construct a algebraic
definition a template if you will of the
final set of capabilities that are
applicable for that NSF that's very
important because otherwise not only do
you not know what features are being
used but you have no idea if the policy
rules conflict with each other so this
is a key part of the draft so thank you
Linda
right now the draft is received is
restricted to imperative policies so
basically when an event fires if the
condition of the policy is true then you
may execute actions otherwise you do
nothing I say may because there's both
metadata as well as other restrictions
that control for example the execution
order of policies remember this is an
imperative system so order is important
right you can also control side effects
so what happens if a policy fails do you
continue executing other policies do you
stop do you rollback etc all of that is
defined in the draft there's a set of
key abstractions so the capabilities are
independent of vendor independent of
physical or virtual implementation you
can if you want use metadata to add
English light descriptions when does a
big fan of English come for describing
what this complex security mechanism is
so for example this NSF can filter
packets based upon source and
destination address bla bla bla
I know you're behind schedule so I'm
going fast
okay so X so basically scroll up just a
little bit more okay so this draft was
built to be compatible with as many
external projects as possible so it does
not define an information model from top
to bottom rather it defines a fragment
specifically two fragments one for
representing capabilities which are a
type of security and the second for
representing policy rules and if the
external information model doesn't have
it then a third fragment can define NSS
so the way to read this is that starting
with an external information model you
build a an NSF object or set of aljex
this funny little symbol is UML for an
aggregation so that means that the NSF
may aggregate zero or more security
capabilities which are inherited from
metadata this funny little symbol means
an association class so that means that
I have the power of a class attributes
methods other relationships etc to
realize the semantics of this
association so simple example I have
employers and employees and let's assume
that zero or more employees can work for
an employer and an employer can have
zero more employees where do you put the
salary attribute by put it in the
employee at class then every employer
pays every employee that salary that's
bad if I put it in them the employer
class that's worse
if I put it in a Association class then
the salary becomes an attribute of the
relationship between employer and
employee and notice that this is now
powerful I can use that relationship to
figure out raises bonuses etc same thing
here with security and well we'll talk
about gaming in a minute so this is an
example of a fairly complex industry
standard this is from the meth MCM
stands for the meth core model and I've
used these little highlights to show
points where NSF could attach so for
example in the meth we have not just
imperative rules we have declarative
roles we have intent rules we have
utility functions they have lots of
things so this class says I am a policy
this sub class here says I am an EC any
policy rule simple and arrogance any
class can contain elements that are
aggregated by it so for an ECA class you
have events conditions and actions so
under policy structure component you
have a decorator which I'll talk about
in a minute that decorator contains
events conditions and actions a
decorator is a software concept it was
defined in 1995 it's used in pretty much
every windowing toolkit I've ever come
across it's used in Java and what it
does is it allows you to use delegation
to assemble a new object by putting all
our parts of existing objects together
so think of it this
if I want to extend functionality of a
model and I create a new subclass that
subclass is not known to anything else
so I have to recompile redeploy do all
the horrible things that operators hate
if instead of using the decorator model
I've already defined all my objects
right data is code code is data and so
then all I have to do is to say to make
this new function I want one of a two of
B this part of C add them together and
boom I've got my new objects it always
loved these general explanations but I
need to be tactical for a moment John is
it okay if I ask tactical question or
should I wait till later yeah far away
the tactical question is probably to ask
you to provide your summation where
you're heading for just a moment so I
can get my mind into the right concept
we have the information model we have
the data model
I met real peace maybe you aren't and
that may be your summation with having
the information show all model for these
capabilities show these really cool
ideas and the data model over here have
substantively less because we can't
really do all these cool things and yang
yet they're making progress toward it
but they're not there yet is that why
you're going to this explanation you're
telling us all the cool things and then
you're going to say something about it
and then I I'm just trying to make sure
and it's in in essence of time so I am
you know the answer is yes and no so I
would absolutely agree that any
self-respecting data model what at least
should not and possibly must not contain
everything that
parent information model has that's like
shipping a relational database in third
normal form or higher you have zero
performance that way in speaking
generally right and you have a whole
bunch of things that your implementation
might not use that is not my quarrel
what my what I worry about is how we're
constructing our yang you're absolutely
right that yang is not the best
implementation language for policy one
reason that we're using Association
classes is to get around some of the
limitations in semantics for game and
that's also why we're using the
decorator pattern to enable a more
flexible construction of objects to get
around these yang problems so the
punchline is coming in the next couple
of slides okay where I'm going to give
you some concrete recommendations of
recipe on how I would build the game to
make it less fragile okay then I should
probably have that debate with you once
I see your recommendations well nmda is
is adopting it so we can debate it the
nmda yep of course I'm off you you
missed the channel where I'm really in
an MDA proponents so we'll wait till you
finish I don't know I fixated on debate
so I'm like okay I'll go back and wait I
just I just was missing the punch line
now I know it is o8 thank you you're
welcome
so any questions on this so in summary
just in case people got confused if I
was building I to NSF in the MCM which I
happen to be then for the event
condition and action classes defined in
our information model they would
subclass
here under gonna see on policy event
policy condition and policy action if I
was defining metadata to better explain
policy or other objects they would
subclass metadata isn't shown on this
one but it's probably about right there
they would subclass from the MCM
metadata class are I to NSF security
rule is a subclass from MCM EC a policy
rule so just as I said an answer to this
question do I have to use all of the
structure no but it's but if I want to I
can that's the advantage of building a
modular object ran it info model okay so
now the game so for me as an
object-oriented guy there's three
important things that an object oriented
model
must provide one is the concept of class
two is the concept of inheritance or
subclass and if you will and three are
relationships now yang cannot really
differentiate between an association and
aggregation and a composition and that's
fine
but we can still build relationships in
yang and we can get around that problem
by implementing every relationship as an
association class so in our model that's
exactly what we've done if we have a
relationship it is always implemented as
an association class that makes coding
and implementation for all students much
easier now when we build a class and
these this is a summary from the work
that we did in supa so what we do is we
use an identity and a group why well how
else can you tell whose parent
this current gang letha's right so every
class has a grouping every grouping has
one leaf that has a unique system-wide
identifier that identifies this instance
and then the second leaf is just an
identity rep and what that allows you to
do is a very simple form of reflection
now in and translated for those of you
that aren't software implementers that
means that I can always determine the
type of object that is on each end of
the Association if you don't do this I
do not understand how you can guarantee
that either end of the Association is
what you think it is so I think this is
something that the data models haven't
done so far and I would strongly
encourage you to do this and if for
those of you that are implementing if
you don't understand this then let's
discuss offline subclassing is uses a
similar approach and we did this
specifically to simplify coding and so
now we've got identity and a grouping
and it's the important thing here is
that reusing inheritance of the identity
itself to emulate the sub classing that
we do in the mall because remember yang
is a flat model right yang you cannot
represent hierarchies of hierarchies
unless you do special things this is one
of those special things the third point
is associations these are a little more
complex but and again if you want to
talk to me on making myself available
but what we do is basically combine the
first two steps so we define a new
that represents the association class we
use instance identifier for each end of
the Association and the Association
class and then we have instance
identifier is that basically point from
the source to the Association class and
from the Association class to the
destination it's very simple to
implement as a software pattern and it
will make your life easier I can skip
the rest of this since we're out of time
and this is just an example of what
something like this would look like
following these rules when you see PTR
that's just an instance identifier that
is implementing one end of an
association between an object and the
Association class suit so good
explanation for everyone I did mention
it to the other co-authors we needed to
get the nmda compliant because won't get
through the yang doctors without it some
of these are really good suggestions
thank you John for presenting you're
welcome and if I can help you guys in
implementation
I'm an email away that's it any
questions questions from a co-author is
usually bad no no no don't scare the
question anything anything no no you
know I have come to the idea that we
should try to find a way in which we
could create some kind of actionable
mapping between this and the other data
models that are around so we can allow
them to it to refers to capabilities
inside and this is the only thing that's
just - we have had no time to talk about
this because it it has been complicated
this is something sir for therefore the
basically for our chair to know that we
are doing at this thank you thank you so
much
and we definitely to align the two maybe
afterwards we should have our offline
maybe conference call - oh yeah that
does not be entering another we are
running out of time and so I'm so sorry
for getting too much time on to that
IPSec thing because that's really
important for many of the sd1 deployment
so now we only have time to do the data
model so the data model actually is a
very important the deliverable from this
working group and so okay this is a poor
attempt from skq Korea so certainly I
cannot deport my group tried to address
the John and the prank information a
model to our a young model so almost yes
stop I believe or neglected but we tried
to more our young model looked like
object oriented using identity John
mentioned
so my team tried to finalize so let me
shortly just because we don't have a
time I scroll down so you can see there
are a model our working group case
capability this is a Sue's the page
based our young model based on that we
make the consuming pacing and as a
facing and iteration also monitoring
also the Frank is working for
information model so this is very
important to monitor NSF okay so so we
implement all of the during hackers on
projects or be proconsi we try to make
final right so currently the legislation
and the monitor model are are also
trying to work in your adoption code
okay this time so Lester slide I believe
just update so you can take a look and
if you have question please
the snow by the email okay back to a
question oh come on no okay okay so yeah
in wisdom Linda this is where I want to
put the other slide I said yes I I
instead of just having a right common
illness I realized this in the middle of
reviewing this with the co-author so I
sent a slide I tried to be effective
okay
and and you notice it's not in the form
of a drafts you know it's just a to-do
it's a discussion point you can go to
the next slide Linda okay look when we
were looking at it we started to talk
where's the operational state for the
data model we've talked about really
cool capabilities but you've not talked
about where the operational state where
the NSF address and the transport it's
not really applicable to put it in the
registration I think Diego made that
point that's what you get from vendors
it probably needs to be in some place
toward the NSF nodes it's probably not
just straight a capability but it's an
operational issue you need you need to
know here I am a controller I need to
know what the NSF dresses I need to know
how to transport Paul has put this and
his wonderful hackathon team has put
that in their actual implementation so
it works it's just a-- to do it needs to
be stored someplace and i didn't want us
to forget it because it's operationally
needed so that's my short okay so why
can't i we will address this one
solution is the legislation took place
maybe can okay so those data you're
saying to be put into the registration
day tomorrow
okay okay so we have time probably do
one more the information model okay
hi this is single wave from skk you and
today I explained update shorty how to
information of the object I trained a
say so for the conservation interface we
added the robustus access control
section in order to synchronize the
requirement of consequence interface I
am and the description of condition
condition crafts is consisting the
condition object is added and we also
added to attack diagrams presenting the
high level abstraction of convincing
interface condition cross august access
control and the other object consists in
the eye game and for the next steps we
because we really curse the walking
robot adoption call and we will expand
the object in depth to cover some
popular security service such as fire
warrior filter and diversity mitigation
or so we are really apply the semantics
used in a condition close to the event
and actions or motive so registration
interface first we divide the section
fall to discuss about updating on
existing NSF instance fire the
registration interface according to the
changes the figures two three and four
have been updated we also curl clarify
the the Appendix A to discuss the use of
the registration interface related to
the lifecycle management so for the next
steps we will request the walking or
adoption course for the registration
interface to and we will implement
instantiation is the instantiation
and updating functions to the
registration interface in the OpenStack
and the OpenStack mano open-source mano
environment this is something a half is
probably I pay every pity days since we
first saw these information models I
believe that we should not have separate
information models documents with the
exception of the capability model and
basically because the capability model
implies complex algebra for generating
policies in the translation I think that
to meet make sense to have this as an
introductory discussion in the
corresponding dates and model documents
well I have seen this I have said this
several times and I will repeat myself
as many times as necessary I'm sorry
you're saying those should be included
in well my point is that I don't see the
need for having separate information
model documents okay with the section of
a capability model because that defines
a complex or complex up a little bit
more complicated algebra for for
capability matching and other like so I
believe these documents should be part
an introduction introductory part of the
corresponding data models I see thank
you so this is a port from
skq so I have a different opinion on the
current consumer PC interface
information model and laceration case
address aspect or a consumer painting
and the restoration so current
capability information is a very cool
good
but specifically different the interface
case I still believe that the separate
information model also Palio or so so we
tried to parallel working the working
document will be I have
well they're immortal okay got it
so in the interest of time we are
running out of time and there's a remote
anticipation presentation so maybe you
can just spend five minutes to discuss
that so there go I remember when we
discussed this last meeting and
Katherine said they're gonna create a
new initiative in idea to do that okay
yeah first of all let me assist replying
to Paul and not same to build a single
information model document well then
saying is to bring the different
information models today as
justification of the data models when
saying is that is to take the text of
the registration interface information
over to the registration interface data
model but merging IMS and DMS okay well
it comes to the trivia station does just
to the document we have added it to the
document we have idea that some sections
on topology at the station which is
important thing and please have a look
at it because there's something that is
connected with some ideas we are going
to discuss in SFC which is about pilot
should go the other way in control so
what just to go very very fast with news
precisely this is about having topology
verification mechanisms topology at the
station mechanisms including including a
proof of transits using an assessee
brief I'll have a look at it have a look
at the the proof of transit document in
the SFC group and the important thing
here is that take into account we're not
talking about Katherine was mentioning
this this is not a general a document or
attestation this particular one is very
much oriented to h1 SF is very much
connected to the a of having the
security controller as the points
collecting the measurements of all the
interval
all the components delivering it to the
to the client for further purification
so it is it is a particular it's a
particular ization of any of a general
the station flow for the case of the
Jonases environments so we believe it
belongs here before whatever the reason
the group doesn't think that it's here
what we will stop working on this and
we'll concentrate in the general flow
and maybe the future we will put as part
of another document in the case as I do
in a third level and this is why well
it's a call for adoption or or let's
forget about this okay
and finally just if you allow me
tomorrow at 7:00
sort of serving I'll share with you the
the announcements again we will have
above a bar both informal side meeting
whatever you call it to discuss
precisely about the possibility of
certain some activity regarding general
at the station so this is more about
monitoring the security environment of
the NSF is that what you say this is
about it is this about the ideas that it
relies on the architecture that we have
with the security controls and the NSF's
so it performs or it proposes mechanisms
for performing at the station based on
the fact that you have a controller that
is centralizing everything okay thank
you comment Darryl I agree that this is
very closely to the item a safe
architecture based on that architecture
to tourism what attestation so maybe we
can do this in either a safe working
group but I think we should be clear for
that we will have another initial work
other place right in the other work so
how to a client your work with with
those work because in the family maybe
we will show a way a share the same
protocol the same process so we don't do
hope that there are some confliction
between here under there so Frank I'm
not saying that we'll go for less coal
or whatever what I'm saying is that
weather is to check whether the group is
interested
continuing this maybe this will even
happen that we closed the group and it's
not finished because it's not aligned
yeah but if you be and asking whether
the group believes that there is a value
in that we continue working for so these
here if not well we can make a
particular case or what simply that's
know for sure is there is not what I'm
not asking to go on publish this yet
because I I think it should be here so I
so I say that maybe later we need to be
alive come on okay thank you very very
much
I'm sorry for two more drafts we didn't
change yeah where's the blue sheet can
people pass around and if you haven't
signed your name please do in the back
table so please go signing that thank
you very much and I think we have two
more drafts didn't finish so we can
continue the discussion your draft
probably is more part of the data model
right so please working with the data
model authors see if you can incorporate
that into their drafts so we can finish
our I to NASA untied thank you very much
okay let me just a one second so we
implement the security our translator
please the lead and they keep me
commented thank you thank you thank you
thank you very much