okay I love it when a plan comes
together at the very last minute so
Jared are you gonna lock the doors so
that we're all locked in here together
thank you all right we are here for IDR
we have an hour to get this done and
then we reconvene tomorrow so we're
going to start a start now one two three
go hopefully there are blue sheets
circulating please do the right thing
I'm supposed to push this button here
there we go we're getting toward the end
of the week so you've noted that note
well many times but nonetheless please
note it I can't actually believe how
many times I shouldn't even confess this
on an open mic button how many times I
saw this before I actually went and read
the RFC and you know what goes worth
reading the RFC okay so here's our
agenda for today this has been a
eventful week for the chairs anyway
and that is being reflected in today's
agenda and tomorrow's that have somewhat
gotten rewritten on the fly so just a
couple things to set up talks that are
coming later in the in the session one
is that you know we have been presented
to several times now about route leek
solutions from two major groups of
authors I think last time we talked we
talked about a it would be awesome to
take you guys who are almost converged
but not quite and try to get you
converged and we're still almost but not
quite there is you know as in everything
else in this game there are there's
semantics and there's syntax right and
we love to
talk about syntax we'd love to dive down
into packet diagrams but we're really
trying to push to come to conclusion on
what the semantics of the solution are
going to be it would be our our belief
it the chairs belief is we're just about
there and then after that there is an
interesting discussion they have about
syntax so reruns talk I'm hoping we'll
focus primarily on the questions of
semantics and I'm hoping the working
group will engage either now at the mic
or later on the mailing list to help us
settle any remaining open questions and
then we can build this intact stuff
later the syntax stuff is potentially a
very attractive bike shed I would prefer
that we not paint it in this meeting
today but just you know in the interest
of full disclosure the chairs and the
author's had a meeting was it just
yesterday and I don't remember who was
responsible for throwing this idea out
it might have been me or might not maybe
it was Alex I Oh like you know we talked
in the past about doing this with the
community instead of the path attribute
and maybe we can really do this with the
community and a bunch of configuration
and make it into a BCP and send the
whole darn thing over to grow so maybe
that will maybe that that maybe that
will come back to haunt us but it's a
bike shed I would prefer not to paint
right now but Kher wants to tell us what
color it will be I know I'm just waiting
for you to get done because I have a
question on the slide before this okay
yes
kate patel arcus not meaning to be rude
but this is a question for chairs I
think the presentation number four there
was a mail out of the mailing list that
this is not going to be adopted do we
still need to present this
thank you for leading into my next slide
I didn't put him up to it I promise
so another interesting thing that has
happened over the last well a couple
weeks during the working group adoption
call but also in the hallways and
meeting rooms here is you know we have
had it fully bludgeoned into our heads
that number one multiple working groups
are interested in topics that you can
generally lump under the heading of
auto-discovery different people want to
autodiscover different things but
there's a whole lot of overlap between
it some people have very maximal
proposals some people have very minimal
proposals with interesting names so it
was also clear to us as we said on the
list that we don't have consensus to
move forward with a particular proposal
and not only that we don't have
consensus on you know I hate
requirements documents but we don't have
consensus on what our requirements are
so in a perfect world we would have
realized that a few weeks ago solicited
or prepared a talk on requirements
comparing and contrasting all of the
proposals with a multicolored grid but
it's an imperfect world and what we have
is a prepared presentation on the
proposal that this group has been
discussing for a while and also we
invited Randi to give Randy Bush to give
the a talk that he gave previously at
LSB R which is which is oriented towards
LS PR but I think it it sets up a fair
number of the requirements points pretty
well and you know so that that should
get be enough to get us started and then
we can move forward to you know
potentially hash things out that are at
an interim does that answer your
question care I know actually so if I
can make a suggestion this is just
pretend speaking for myself if we don't
spend time on the solutions that are
already decided by working group that we
don't want to progress that would be
super
your suggestion is noted but we're not
taking it off the agenda but we will
move through it as quickly as possible
and I think that you know will respect
the fact that it's not an adopted
proposal well so do you want to speak to
this okay so now we've come down to
another thing the chairs want to confess
is that we're looking at the BGP data
model it looks like it's it's been nmd
aid network management data store
architecture it replaces the old model
in case any of you know there was a
model proposed by another set of authors
but they haven't gone forward with it
when they found they wanted to have it
they must have it MDMA we're going to go
to working group last call at the end of
the meeting so when you take a look at
this draft please it'll be a short
presentation but beware we are going to
go to the working group last call with
that I think we start our presentations
just Jeff you probably notice that we
are also working on policy model that is
not open country it's ITF and it has to
work together with BGP and there are
some inconsistencies in between would be
really good to meet insulting ru is our
TWG finished with their routing policy
model there are 60% 50% 162 maybe it
since we started maybe it would be time
to put that on a hot burner okay so
shall we start with route leaks do we
know
it's as good as it gets okay Shriram
would you like the clicker so good
evening so we we met the two sets of
author teams mez met in London we had a
good meeting then we discussed continue
to discuss these things through email we
made some progress but as John said
there is agreement to a merger solution
but not quite a complete agreement so
what I'm going to do today is so we have
the draft and the changes will happen
still it is because of the
considerations of attribute versus
community and and other issues we had we
had so we have the draft and also a
design discussion document please take a
look at both of those and offer some
feedback so quickly like what's going to
happen in this talk is that I should
mention to you that Alex and I had the
opportunity to meet face to face several
times this week to go over the
subtleties and the details and so it's
been a very good conversation between us
and lot of things clarified and we have
the kind of two team leads from the two
drafts so I should mention that there
are some things there where we have
reached better understanding how to do
things between the two of us and because
of that some of the things in the slides
may not be quite accurate or we don't
quite have agreement on those and point
those out so we have design a design B
and also the EO T C so I want to mention
those three things the the code that the
current a or T C proposal as it was the
originally OTC so between
what we are trying to do here is that
each AAS in the path inserts what we
call our LP information so it could be
in the form of InDesign a the a s number
and an RL p-value to indicate whether
the update is being sent up to a
provider or to a customer or a peer so
depending on that it will set a zero bit
or a one bit and InDesign being it's
simplified a smaller it occupies less
space less memory in in this nothing is
set when the update is being propagated
up and s number of the sending a s is
inserted when the update is being sent
to a customer or a peer and originally
your TC design is similar to design B
except that it has room for only one a s
number so the first very first areas
that set a bit indicating it's going to
a customer or PL that that stays so
that's the difference in so accordingly
as you go from left to right design a to
design v2 the originally or TC the
amount of memory the amount of
processing potentially decreases and the
complexity decreases but as but with
design a and design B there is more
information that that's being propagated
in the our LP and because of that the in
terms of being able to detect multiple
leaks etcetera there is better
functionality and then there is a
trade-off also like I mentioned before
with respect to the memory so in this
slide I I don't want to speak too much
to it because it's kind of a busy slide
but the basic idea is that on the left
some things are happening that that
could happen in practice and if you look
at a s4 it can receive an update which
has a route leak indication already set
but yes but for whatever reasons s4
doesn't have an alternative and Desai
and because it's coming from a customer
on a customer interface it for life in
order not to cause unreachable ax t is
for decides to accept
and propagate it as well then it goes to
a s5 and at a s7 there are two routes
being received one from a peer and
another one is that leaked it goes down
into the customer towards a customer and
then leaks so with more information in
like with with design a or design B you
can tell more as to what happened both
at leaks but but one is more egregious
than the other that kind of a thing in
this is important so Alexander brought
up this example where if you didn't have
route leaks you just have the
traditional BGP in this topology you
could have persistent oscillations if
you if if the the providers p2 for
example prefers P threes route over its
customers and and p4 prefers P ones P
ones in that case if you if you do go by
something like local pref and that
happens then you would have persistent
oscillations and the same thing once you
bring in doubt leaks and you just go
with a local proof without looking at
the path length for example then again
you could have persistent oscillations
so there are a couple of ways to solve
this problem you you would prefer p2 to
you you would like three to to prefer
the customer route over the provider
route in order to not have the
persistent oscillations in case both are
leaks and for that p2 has to be able to
know that the route from p3 is a leak
and out from p0 is a leak and it has to
prioritize the customer out over the
provider route there are a couple of
ways to do it one would be for example
to check whether p0 is is in the path of
the provider route also and if you know
that then then that then you know that
it is a detour of the customer route
that is coming back through p3 and if
you know that and both are leaks then
then you would prefer the route through
the customer but Alexander has thought
about it quite a bit and there is a
proof purple possibly a better solution
where you would have
addition to the our LP values you would
have another attribute or value that is
carried in the update which indicates
for example p0 will say that I saw a
leak but I don't have a choice I don't
have an alternative route so I selected
it and I sent it to the two providers
but at the same time it has this
additional attribute or or information
in it adds to the update to indicate
that I it was a leak but I still am
still propagating it and with that
information p2 can now set the local
craft to zero on both of these routes
and then it will go with the longest
path and it will make the right right
decision right selection and and we can
avoid the oscillation so like with that
I can skip the next light because I
already covered that so so that's pretty
much it in in brief so main thing we
want to focus today is if you have some
feedback on design a or B well great but
that may change because we are
considering very likely moving to large
community so we would like you to focus
more on the I mean on today if we can
get some comments from you suggestions
about attributes versus large community
perhaps we can focus the discussion on
that
thank you that be exactly the opposite
of what I was hoping for but that's okay
go ahead oh yeah I take apart some Cisco
Systems about a year ago I put in a
draft for another solution to this which
it sends a large community that says
these are my up streams and it sends it
to the neighbor only so that way if that
neighbor gets one from somewhere else it
can check whether that upstream is there
or not
so did you see that I mean I was going
to present it but I didn't have enough
time to update it
[Music]
link's Alexander can possibly commit he
has an ASP a new chart I wonder if there
is an overlap between maybe not you but
guys I'm gonna I'm gonna call it here
the the chairs really need a specific
feedback that sure arms got and that's a
a great discussion with sure um but not
on the question topic the chairs want to
see do you see if that was if that was
if that was what you're trying to say in
a different way please say it we just
want to know is there utility for the
additional information we're talking
about what's there if that was part of
your comment I don't want to halt it I
just want you to be specific for the
chairs Alexandra is in for one of the
authors so I just want to highlight now
why we are going to move from attribute
to the community the idea behind it so
attribute is better but it will take
years before the software will be
shipped and stars configured and so on
so on and so on now we have ASB which is
much more powerful that anything that we
can get with our shield community or
whatever it is because it's also capable
to detect not only mistakes but also
malicious activity and that's why we
decided that we need
sattell in place as soon as possible and
just before before we will have a phase
if we will have an attribute or
community attribute at the same time HP
will be delivered it will make no sense
so at the same time we know the limit
zone of the communities so it may be
stripped there will be some issues for
sure so please comment it's a so it's
it's not a choice for the draft some
kind of strategic choice for the whole
prop
so please that device really Bruges
arcus and I AJ luckily communities are
very strongly authenticated and
integrity checked so so that was a joke
go ahead please
job Snyder's MTT less snarky it's no
difference for attributes like these and
we don't expect the ROP style attribute
to propagate very far it's more of if it
happens to pass for you you can benefit
would you say attribute propagates a
longer distance and community yeah but
the point for for this pathology to be
effective is that it doesn't need to
propagate very far so I probably gates
in the limits at radius there's already
benefits I would like to close this
conversation right now I'd like to
encourage people to take advantage of
the in-person time we have left to have
hallway conversation or you know over
dinner or whatever and I would like to
encourage people to review the draft
specifically with an eye toward the
semantics and not the encoding there are
two different you know design a design
beyond that bullet there you can very
usefully provide feedback about you know
if you feel like the additional overhead
of the one versus the other is warranted
there will likely be changes in the
encoding this coming down the coming
down the road fairly shortly thank you
thank you thank you sure I'm sure um I
hate to ask you to put that yeah area
Church er
[Music]
cool good afternoon folks my name is
Caleb Patel and I'm gonna talk about the
yang model update if you have a new
draft for BCP yang models which is now
an NDMA compatible we have removed in
this draft particularly all the
dependencies that were there on the open
config models brief introduction if
folks are looking at what NDMA is so RFC
83 42 is the state machine should be
fairly clear and most of the extensions
that were there in base are already
covered in the current draft whatever is
defined in BGP extension drafts need to
be taken care of which is the next set
of changes we will be doing again in a
separate document that also includes the
support for VP LSE VPN and a to VPN l3
VPN address family changes in model
right yeah and I believe that's all I
have
it's pretty straightforward the AC
Linden this is a quick one we talked
about offline where you are going to
change it to augment IETF routing
protocol basically instead of being at
the top okay thanks
and all I was gonna tell you was that
the model compiles thankfully so we like
to take it to last call if possible
after that change though yeah for sure
then in the region Cisco same comment as
AC about it needs to be linked under
routing model under control 10 protocols
and second question is do you plan to
define BGP rib data the pyramid
structure yeah we can extend it in this
one or next no it has to be in the main
one in the base on Y so I think that is
completely not there right now so
hopefully I think before but what last
call and the third is the our PCs are
not defined
PCs are pcs the clear actions yeah I
think the clear should be taken it off
on a separate track because the base
model is only there to cover the base
functionality if you will with the
configurations okay thank you and the
last question is the policy extensions
for services you mentioned that a number
of extension models yeah so I assume
that if they require any policy
extensions for example bgp evpn or VPLS
this base BGP model has a BGP policy
module so looks like the extensions for
policy also will need to be thought
about so the base model has just base
policy modules in here right and for
those we have taken care of for all the
extension extended policies would like
to take it over into the extension
struct and progress the work accordingly
that way at least be a base set of
functionality moving forward
sure so looks like if I get it right all
the extensions will define the bgp
extensions plus the policy extensions
together in the extension module yeah
all right okay
so thank you and we'll be looking
towards you to help us out as well
preferably since you ask all the
questions sure we can discuss here just
to summarize what was the one addition
you felt had to go into the base model
be really quick Himanshu from Siena we
questioned on what kind of extensions
you are including for bgp evpn and l2
VPN Saffy Saffy support and any bgp
parameters that are there esoteric - EVP
ends ok dude does the bgp evpn model has
- because there is a separate yang model
for I mean we will work with the
separate yang model if there is one to
see that it's routing compatible and
fits into the overall BGP framework so
we are happy to let that drop progress
separately if need be ok but it needs to
be done somewhere then there will be no
overlapping no
we don't I don't think we expect any
overlap oh and if the works done
somewhere happy to just document it and
be done with it right now looking for
extra work to be done here okay
let's coordinate on that yeah thanks so
much
hey data pipes from Cisco are presenting
extra in the communities okay
extended why extended we're making the
extended community longer and the reason
for this is that we're going to be able
to write the code very quickly because
it's just extending the extended
communities it's just taking the
extended community code and just adding
little bits and pieces to cut and paste
it and change the size by 24 bits 24
updates and why is it fixed length well
again because we're gonna roll out the
code quickly we do not want to make a
variable length because we've seen what
happened to me wanted to variable enter
takes 16 years to get something variable
thence through the ITF and it's still
not through why bigger aha we we have a
and when you what I'll derive to order
derive identifies you want to take
existing identifies and sticking
together to make water Matic identifies
and to be able to fit those into
anything you need more space so that's
why that is and it's a specific case we
needed that was in a VPN target to put
an ESI and an Ethernet tag ID and
a is number to give up all in one spot
in the current extended community
there's not our space so they have to be
compressed or find new identifies which
is not good for what I confit
okay now I added added a couple more
things right so we have transit of a
non-transitive extended communities
there's been some issues with that
there's been in several cases where we
have wanted to have community
communities and extended communities go
a few hops perhaps but not throughout
the whole internet right so leaking a
community throughout the whole in in
there accidentally is a big deal so I
thought let's take let's use two bits
for transitivity and so we can have four
different transitivity so now the first
one is administration transitive that
means it's transitive within a set of
guesses that are perhaps owned by a
single administration now to make that
happen we we configure we add a
configuration to the neighbor ship that
is in the same administration but they
fault there's always a different
administration okay the other one would
be a one-time transitive that means you
can send in a community to your neighbor
a s but it will not go to the next
neighbor is so it's just one time I klo
which er sale that was an example of of
the case where it could not be made
transitive over more than one hop in
because it was not able to be done BTP
persistence
has not been specified for ipv4 address
family just because we couldn't contain
a community properly so one time
transitive would have fixed that the RT
constraint because if we have a nuke
extended community with new rap targets
in it right we need an ERT constraint so
there were several possible ways to
handling this so this is not nailed down
but I preferred and some other people
here seem to prefer to have a new RT
constraint address family and so then so
it'll be nearly exactly the same as the
current RT constraint will just filter
the extra extended communities where the
regular RT constraint filters the
regular extended communities but now
since we had a new address family I
thought oh we have some other problems
with our key constraint and something
that's been there for quite some time it
hasn't been solved is what happens if
you put an RT into regular unicast ipv4
or ipv6 update because RT constraint
wasn't specified for that address family
it was only specified for VPNs so if you
have it in a non VPN aiders family what
do you do so there's no clear answer for
that so in this one I just put an Fe
selfie into it to say for the specified
Fe Safi we are specifying this RT
constraint also there's no reason why
the route target value actually has to
be a route target it couldn't be any
extended community and it would just
work just fine so I remove the need for
it to be an actual named real target
okay are you close to the end because
we're close to out of time oh yeah okay
um this is detail are just the types we
have a a species of people see for ipv6
specific evpn specific a a specific
doesn't need to be troubadour for bike
this is enough bytes in there
here are the a VPN subtypes you can go
and read them in read them in the draft
and I need to mix questions Patel arcus
what happens if the working group thinks
we need 30 bike community six months
later we will define a new officer fee
for another RTC yes okay so if that's
the thought process my suggestion would
be we I know why what was that wide or a
flexible communities container and it's
a working group document I suggest we
leverage this over that therefore their
way we only have one Safi in future to
worry about other things the code
changes now that you explained earlier
in in the presentation that the whites
being too complicated to implement
suddenly becomes very simpler okay Jeff
as I think you know what half my
comments are gonna be sure we can take
the bit of the white communities the
container we already did the refactoring
initially if we're looking at large we
could do that that'd be one way to look
for it let's stick to your presentation
though what I would like to be changed
out of your minimally for this to move
Ford I'd love that you did transitivity
yay let's do that you're doing fixed
bytes I don't like that the fact that
you happen to have some union in your
data structures that makes you wonder
have the specific size that's your
implementation I don't have that my
implementation let's not do that if you
put just that
field at the beginning of it so that we
can variable-sized them and say that
this type must be this size and you can
know do your parsing that way that's
great I'm happy with that done do those
two things should be just FYI line is
closed after job na na variable-length
it takes too long to write the code it
takes too long to specify I did the
large community okay so hey guys no you
know food fight about this on the floor
your your various unreasonable positions
have been Nokia I'm very confused about
your statement here they were on the
slide you're saying that the the new
router targets are to be used in
addition and not as a replacement is
they intend I mean this statement I
guess is valid until all your EVP MPs
support is community karina at that
point you can only use the the extended
community I mean the XX in the community
and not the other one so when you you
end the migration of all the EVP MPs you
can actually get rid of the external
community only if only there extracts
than the community otherwise there is no
gain right yeah you can only use the new
ones if all of the EVP MPs understand
the new ones and only those yeah well
basically there will be no conversion
between the old and the new I mean you
could say let's if there's one that
doesn't understand it will convert back
to an old one but I wouldn't do that so
I would only only put these in if all of
the peers that need to know need to
understand them to understand them right
okay thanks
I mean you could you could but it makes
it complicated yeah but I guess there's
no I'd like to have people if you want
to make a comment make it into the mic
and by the way
mic line is closed if you're gonna hey
wait
if you send both on all the peers there
is no gaining because then the main
advantages stay out - derivation if you
still need to configure manually the
other target yeah so everybody needs to
understand all of the nodes in the
network need to understand then you have
your gain job Snider's NTT I wanted to
comment on the transit ii aspect because
i think you're highlighting on a broader
issue IDR and grower faced over the
years I know that caterer and and Jeff
has and others have put out drafts in
about rancifer T specifically I would
like to remind the working group that
the reason the large community ended up
not being contained within what was -
back then called the common header or
the common container is that we could
end up with a situation where it would
be a legal construct that a large
community may or not may be transitive
and from an operator perspective when we
went to market saying this is just like
all the communities but it's bigger that
also meant that we wanted exactly the
same transiti so I'm not clear on what
the technical solution is like you do
here so the outcome of what you define
here is entirely reasonable
I would love these features be really
nice if we have pieces of encoding that
would either stay within the ASN or just
one hub but how we solve this as a
working group will be a challenge
because if you put it on the attributes
itself it may be too broad and it will
cover everything contained within the
attributes but if you do it per
community or per color or kerfing
that may also not be ideal but we have
to keep in mind what users expect and
when we talk about for instance extract
standard communities or large
communities people associate transiti
with that and that we need to think
ahead of pushing this to market on how
we think the audience will perceive this
yeah I understand is there's many
possible ways of handling attributes
code thing okay you know what this one
is my I'm gonna have to cut it and ask
you guys to yeah thank you so we're
running about ten minutes late and I
would like to ask Catan if you can catch
us up okay
so I'll go really fast
I think problem statement is known I'm
going to skip this some so I just focus
on spend a bit on this slide which is
really the requirement that we had in
mind on this working on this draft we're
looking for a neighbor discovery
mechanism for BGP and which runs on top
of ipv4 and ipv6 so you know it can work
on any of this make any I could be for
v6 or dual stack and you know supported
authentication mechanism for security
focused on BGP requirements because we
have lldp and BFD for lioness and other
discovery so we just look for the BFD
part of sorry BGP part of it but we
wanted to make this extensible for
signaling of BGP information the queue
requirement was for auto discovery of
neighbors and bootstrapping for BGP TCP
sessions between directly connected
nodes based on feedback and even
requirements we wanted a separation of
discovery and liveness for BGP neighbors
so there is a discovery part of it and
maintenance of the adjacency and then
based on feedback the liveness
an ism is optional and can continue to
leverage bgp keep alive BFD fast
external failover features and there's
minimal changes for integration with the
bgp PR FSM and no changes in the bgp
protocol operations so I think many of
you I hope would have already seen this
so I'm going to skip through this really
fast to catch up there is UDP hello
message is sent on a per link basis and
we exchanged this so this is a hello
message which is used useful UDP port
179 and it's sent to link local
addresses so it can be used over both
ipv4 and v6 there are the key TL ways
that are used here one is the peering
address so that the directly connected
neighbors can learn the address to which
set up the BGP TCP session then there is
a link attributes which indicates the IP
v4 and v6 addresses and identifiers so
that the link can be described
accurately in you know BGP LS but also
we can do some other checking like
subnet matching and any other policies
that we may want to keep there is a
neighbor TLV which actually includes the
discovered neighbors and their status
this is to ensure a two-way you know
acceptance before bringing up the BGP
peering over it because the session
neighbor may be rejected for some policy
reason there are certain optional tlvs T
one is the local prefix TLV this is
really the prefix route that needs to be
programmed via this neighbor discovery
mechanism to ensure that there is reach
ability between the loopback addresses
when doing the peering you know over
them it's
required when the pairing is done with
interface addresses this is an adjacency
state machine just a quick overview of
that it's very similar to some of the
you know link protocols like OSPF for
example key thing is that there is a
verification ensure to waste a kitten's
let's skip the state machine and so I
think yeah I think mainly what we were
hoping for was he captured in your first
few slides which I think summarized
requirements as you see them and that
was very helpful and the details of the
proposal are needed thank you yeah it's
Comic Sans time
you know um link discovering liveness
what do we really need we're here and
we're trying to discover our neighbors
okay hi IJ is building a second medium
scale data center with 6,000 racks how
can we route in something of this scale
OSPF is okay to 500 nodes is maybe a
thousand they're limited because they
repeatedly flood everything this is your
cloths on OSPF or is is thank you
Miyazaki BGP is great as updates are
infrequent it only signals change okay
it scales because of that it so
therefore this is probably the major
reason it's become common in large-scale
data centers but ecmp can be wider than
heck okay so discovery and topology
become critical
the problem is discovering it okay so a
little religion first if anybody can
help me attribute this by the way I
would really appreciate it there's the
Union standards the accumulation of all
the features everybody wanted and
intersection standards only those things
everybody absolutely had to have I'm a
fan of the latter when Russ Housley was
talking to the ITU for the ITF he said
let me understand it you add features
until the nose stop and they said well
we don't like to think of it that way
but that's in fact what happens so let's
not do that
what are the must-haves we want to
discover the nodes and the links between
them we want to discover the link
encapsulations on those interfaces and
only on those interfaces we're not
trying to do routing we want to maintain
layer 2 liveness and Su and I have a
confusion here and what I really mean is
the layer 2 is up not layer 3
you've got being BFD and other things
for that but if layer 2 changes it needs
to be signaled very quickly and then a
northbound API this whole thing was done
for BGP SPF there are other paths
security I've been told data center ops
don't think of security at this layer I
don't think that's reasonable and some
have finally spoken up um certainly we
need authentication is my neighbor the
person that the note that I think it is
is it authentic
kated to talk to me over this interface
do we need an integrity that I question
but this is one of the things that may
drive the PD use over 1500 bytes why do
I care about that wait a minute non
features routing data BGP does that up
the next layer up access to I GP
databases this is discovering liveness
not routing I contend you don't even
need an IDP you just want the length not
transport you want discovery in liveness
to push up to BGP SPF it's got to be
usable in massively scalable networks it
may be used
for other applications and it should be
simple it should be extensible so that
we can add authentication maybe link
costs etc etc John I've been discussing
adding what's the flavor of my labor my
neighbor is it a spine is it a leaf etc
so I think of that as colors and we
might have two of them the other fonts
so I can have magenta Comic Sans um it
should be simple it should not have IPR
and I didn't have enough room on the
slide to include simple again why simple
is because we're here to produce
implementable understood and securable
standards not build our resumes and I
feel really nastily strongly about this
and Rob Pike one of the fathers of
playing nine and other Dell lab stuff
had this to say just two weeks ago that
the high goal of software engineering is
removing the need for features so one of
the candidates we have in front of us
today we have lldp we have something
like is is link discovery Alvaro tossed
edge control protocol over the fence at
me and I think he regrets it because
I've been teasing him about it ever
since
bgp neighbor under discovery you've just
heard that song and something that I've
been working on with care link stayed
over ether LD pre is an I Triple E
protocol and now the magic number 1500
appears he could want a big PD you and
you hit IPR okay it's a bit complex it
in some circumstances it won't go
through a switch in others it will what
do you really want here
are the nodes switches in which case you
really don't want it to go through a
switch it does beaconing but not keep
allies it's viable okay is is discovery
at least it's a an ITF protocol it's
complex enough the BGP LS was invented
so people who are allergic to link state
databases can see it in a different form
I only read BGP D so please translate
the is is and OSPF LSD B's to me this is
pretty silly is is not common is is is
not commonly implemented right on mstc
devices RFC 1812 I think it is host
requirements didn't include is is it was
OSPF edge control protocol it's a
transport control by eiope Triple E it's
really a transport it's layer to
transport it does flow control
reliability non reorder neither its
reinventing PCP thanks Alvaro at least I
got to read something BGP neighbor
auto-discovery is introduced in ITF very
new needs the peering address to get the
peering address it's a s base can't use
other identifiers not really discovery
at all it's configuration and then it
doesn't maintain like this link state
over ether was custom made for the LSD
our job let's be specific very
bare-bones brutally simple only this
does discovery in liveness it's new
that's those bgp SPF and NOAA
measurement and monitoring tools and
that line kind of applies to too many
things here so this is kind of what it
looks like and let's discuss it
I think the only thing I mentioned in
the LSB ARP was the ESI is protocol and
by the way since you said l2 liveliness
I would throw my other time limits
coming he'll either make it or you won't
with the life I mean that's it layer 2
we gonna go home early you that hungry
so we do have a few minutes for
conversation yeah I I guess really what
I said at the beginning we we have I
mean sure we don't normally hum in this
room but let's home
how many hum if you think the general
topic as presented in the last two
presentations and others that have come
to us of discovering in the BGP context
is one that this group should work on
and hum if you think that we should not
work on the topic it's very quiet ok ok
I heard a little humming but very little
so that I mean that was our impression I
guess the other thing that I would like
some some honey ratification on is it is
the chairs impression that we are at the
beginning rather than the end of
defining what we think our ID ours
requirements are for discovering we
don't think that we have a solid set of
requirements yet so I just like to get a
home if you pretty much agree with that
statement that we do not yet know what
our requirements are ok I heard some
humming hum if you do think we have firm
enough requirements to start writing a
spec
okay that's interesting that's you know
pretty close pretty close so yeah
actually it was a trick question because
in either case that means that you would
like to participate in a interim to nail
down what those requirements are half of
you have got some requirements to bring
to the table and half of you have got a
interest in evaluating the requirements
of the first half and now I would like
to open the mic Jeff has two points in
reverse order so Randy's motive Randy's
motivation for presentation is partially
due to LS VR that has a liveness
requirement we do not have that piece
that may bias the solution if we're
trying to be general second comment is I
think that the majority of the solutions
they've been offered in this space have
significant overlap so I don't think
we're really that far in terms of the
actual requirements I do think that we
have a few details like the yellow TP
draft for examples out there because we
thought we had a specific limitation
that we needed to know for data center
type equipment that the general bgp
solution doesn't I don't see that as an
obstacle I did you see that is you know
one of the things that needs to be
answered
i ka patel arcus I agree to what Jeff
says the only thing I would add is if we
are going to take this work we probably
want to think of this work with an
understanding that this has an
applicability to M I miss DC's but can
be generally applied and could be
applied even beyond BGP in certain cases
Allah think bfv like mechanism materia
which is more generically applied so
have a surgical insertion point from a
network perspective in mind but make it
a generic sure and I'll just cut in to
point out that of course LS VR has their
own requirements and the ad has I think
very sensibly asked you know the chairs
of the two groups to get together and
basically said you know can't you people
figure out how to bring forward one
instead of two things so we we have had
some requests not not a hard requirement
but a request to try to come up with
unified proposal instead of two
different proposals that does do almost
the same thing yeah Rajeev oh sorry
[Music]
definitely this at least surrenders
analysis very useful um one thing that
hit me was thinking about it that most
of the large-scale data centers that
they are being built or going to be
built a predominantly gonna be around I
P basic so hope that's the case Randy
said that I mean if you make that
assumption I don't make that assumption
would be useful to leverage something
that we have in ipv6 and they were
discovery does it check does it pass all
the marks not sure would be useful to
have at least that we added to the
analysis AC Linda there are specific
there's the requirements have a lot more
than that that's already been being done
there are implementations that use the
ipv6
router advertisements to peer on the
link local address and then use RFC
55:49 to do both ipv4 and ipv6 yeah okay
so so what my question suggestion was to
perhaps expand this list and add ipv6 as
well ipv6 NDP to be more specific okay
and I actually also want to you know
take privilege to respond a little bit
and just say you know although this this
grid you know is what it is and it's a
useful grid we should keep in mind that
you can have a set of requirements that
are then met by a set of technologies
they don't have to be met necessarily by
just one technology one protocol yeah
AC Linda I just like to point out to
this group that Randy's like liable eNOS
requirement is not bgp session
liveliness so don't confuse that we're
not trying to we're
not solving that with this it's
liveliness of ipv4 ipv6 and possibly
other end caps on on the link it's ok
liveness of the link for very selfish
reasons I would rather the IP ID are not
take this up because L SVR has a nice
constrained problem and I like working
on it this group can expand to the
interplanetary universe and drive me
crazy for years we love you too a lease
agency Cisco with respect to the lldp
option I'm wondering whether jumbo frame
size have been considered for lldp
honest we think that we're gonna go over
8 9 K in size so I believe Brandi had a
bullet to that about IPR and greater
than 1500 bytes and blah blah blah I
thought that IP is with respect to the
segmentation segmenting it to the
multiple pieces not using a single jumbo
frame ok well I guess I will defer that
to people who know more about it than I
do
um so here will take your comment but I
I want to point out that we're out of
time
so yours will be the last comment sure
I'm just gonna reply really put to our
list comment up
jumbo frames is good to have but not
necessarily D way of doing it and then
as Randy said there are other issues
with lldp where you know it goes to a
switch you may not want to you may not
want this information to go beyond 1/2
so putting extra constraints seems like
adding more complexity here so ok and
and with that we will close the meeting
we probably I'm almost certain we will
try to schedule an interim to talk about
this topic thanks everybody and we'll
see you tomorrow