this Chester check right did we get some
decent written responses I'm truly where
we have a few buttons was just
confirmation of the concept so yeah you
can just use some later on the phone
[Laughter]
the
Hasini stuff you can do it well when you
did the same amount of work that ran and
Selena threat they get all the material
press you want me to do everything and
you if the NGT wants one give me enough
material so I can it's Sunday actually I
may have a problem in Bank there's a
separate issue get into Bank on Sunday
is going to be fun because I have
supposed to be in Los Angeles
Thursday and Friday before that and it
turns out that I wanna use United flying
United from LA to Bangkok you either
connect on a morning flight through
Narita or nighttime you can fly through
San Francisco to Singapore to Bangkok I
don't get there until I leave Friday
night Sunday afternoon it's just
scheduling will be in Bangkok but I
watch you open I will get
okay should we start few minutes okay so
welcome to the least working group okay
you see the note well which means
basically that whatever we we say and do
in the next two hours is a contribution
to their ETF um blue sheets are one is
yeah just came back yeah the usual
pointers to the Java room out of three
immutable and the agenda slides okay so
to a brief update on the states of the
documents so since London we we have a
non newbies document which is the 68th
for this yeah it's about map versioning
okay we need to push this forward as
we're under under standard track okay
because all the sick 38:33 beasts they
refer to this one as well okay it's kind
of blurry but didn't find the right set
up in
so then we have the usual intro and SEC
documents that instant by different
stage we have the vendor al-kahf
actually that was in working group last
call in the last two weeks this was just
our consensus check because we this
document was presented in London it was
asked for working two plus call the room
said okay there was consensus then but
there were few changes that I asked
editorial so they came in few weeks ago
and we so we open the official working
group last call we had a few emails
confirming the the support the saw I
think when we are done with this
document later on I will send our formal
email on the mailing list and and the
usual process chef holding etc etc now
as you can see on this slide there are
few other points which is so we have
three documents the best documents plus
GB that are gone really done okay even
though the right app is ready but I
don't have IP our disclosure from all of
the others fabulou you included so
actually you are on the GPL document
yeah there are small editorial changes
that I need to be confirmed and that an
IPR disclosure remember this IPR
disclosure is not just Cisco hot this is
to you know of IPR because presumably
you know all the things you should know
of so it's not this isn't do a
disclosure this is do you know of
something that isn't disclosed if so
then you have
and do it but tell us so we know to wait
for that if not tell us so we can get
this done this is not an onerous thing
no no no there are others yeah yeah I
will continue pink the other out was on
the these documents of we will get a
reply otherwise we will write down in
the write-up that we don't have I PR
disclosure from all of the others we
will send anyway for forward the
document okay to the is G the problem
will kind of come back when we will have
the 48 hour out of confirmation that
that where we really need confirmation
from the others I mean and we'll see how
to deal with it hopefully in the
meantime we will get in touch with all
of the others okay
well as there is still concerning IPR
actually I forgot already last time to
point out that we have two IPR
disclosure about Lisp AI D anonymity and
lease predictive are locks so both are
from war way you can check on the data
trackers I assume do you can have more
information about this IPR disclosure
and one last point coming back to the
B's documents so there is no idea of
disclosure there directly but if you go
back in and check out the original heart
of C so 68 30 and 60 833 they are
alcoholics kosher again from Y way so
which means that basically in the Indian
right up we will state that because the
B's documents are based on the original
documents for which there is an idea so
it may apply then it's not up to you to
check this but just point out these
things may be done do not I don't know
okay
and that's it as an update so coming to
the agenda today we have an update on
the young model is the only official
document we will discuss Rashad can Kali
come here and then we have a bunch of
non-working departments mainly Dean will
talk about the console plain
authentication authorization data
Plymouth telemetry Fred should stop
Polly and talk about gambe still lists
for aeronautical telecommunication
network later on Alberto it will explain
us how to use the list control plane for
segment routing v6 ok
to conclude they will be calling giving
an update on the list a set mapping
system ok and there are some spare time
so don't hesitate to ask questions and
discuss ok
any comment we can yes we can move
forward and we go up from this
[Music]
hmm I don't know why you showed up in
this way that simply and is too small
yep look much better with PDF - nice -
yes we can switch here so you start
so this is just okay thank you okay so
if decap swing next year's participate
in this telemetry feature more
performance data is available and we can
make better informed decisions like you
know what you transmitted on ITR what
you encapsulate but you don't know
what's being received on the other side
so you can measure different things like
packet loss and bandwidth and jitter so
this was first a list was put together
with the first 0-0 draft is doing is
just identifying what sort of parameters
we want and how to encode them and then
what later drafts will do is to find how
its measured on the ETR so after we do
some implementation we could say how we
measure these things but things like
packet count by count rate packet rate
bitrate bandwidth those are all things
that can be retrieved right now in the
ITR but packet loss package it or
pack account forward one-way latency
reverse TTL from the et are coming back
and reverse time stamping these are
things that would be reportable by the
EGR so like I said the early version is
just showing that we send these things
in our load probes we oughta look probe
ascent and the EGR has been measuring
and collecting all this data and it
returns back in an hour look Pro reply
an extra hour look record that's the
JSON elk f-type that encodes all this
stuff and we want to use JSON because if
we want to add parameters later we can
do it in a compatible way without
changing the protocol and arguably
without changing the implementations as
well so that's it for now stay tuned for
next next revision questions comments
and as I looked at the stuff I realized
that oh we should probably consider this
colouring thing that people are doing an
IP PM right there's this way one way of
measuring loss is you send n packets
colored red and then n packets colored
blue and then the receiver knows that
okay it only received 98 there were
colored red and there's some even some
techniques to do this to get some
latency measurement so you either need
one or two bits somewhere but I find a
place for those bits okay so good
suggestion great I had two questions one
is so reading the draft the only xtr
that asked about the limit C data is the
one pocket to you so anyway and I can
ask chemically the data about mappings
like why not order I mean if you are a
next year why somebody else cannot ask
you telemetry data about one mapping now
then you have to have a policy that says
can Victor knows about the the telemetry
of which is mapping on Ondina or not but
why not
kids so what you'll see in my next
presentation is that we probably don't
want to give telemetry data to anybody
who just requests it so we want to
actually sign map requests and validate
them so when you return the information
you know it's to an authenticated source
so that's one thing and the other thing
is is if if there's a source that wants
to make its decisions unilaterally
without having a management plane we can
make it self-contained in Lisp in the
control plane so if there's an
application that's possibly co-located
with the ITR side and wants this
information rather than running a
separate management plane to retrieve
the data and have all these separate
api's it just has to ask about the
forward and reverse data in one place ok
ok like to give an update on the third
revision of ecbs authentication erics in
the room so he could comment or answer
any questions so we initially wrote the
draft in July of 2017
and we presented it at that IETF did one
update - two updates and we have another
one planned for the summer and at that
time I we want to keep it as an
individual submission and what's the
working group thinks it's good to make
it a working group document but I'll
talk about that next so just a brief
over you know what the draft is
basically you can authenticate and
authorize XT hours using the mapping
system and then in the way it does it
describes how to sign map register
messages and how to sign me up request
messages and the map server actually
verifies the signatures by looking up
public keys in the mapping system so we
use or introducing this concept of
crypto a IDs where part of the
ipv6 Eid is a hash of the public key
that's used when when a message is
signed that crypto Eid hash is used as a
lookup to the mapping system so the map
server itself can retrieve the public
key and then verify the signature if the
signature fails the map register map
requests is dropped if it's succeeds
then the next levels of authentication
for a map register the shared key
authentication to see are you authorized
to register this particular Eid in this
instance ID is then checked do you know
if I may ask a question sure how would
that look up of the hash fit with
something like PvP where it's supposed
to be the tree is based on delegation
just arbitrarily map it onto the tree or
yeah so the way we expected out was the
hash that you look up is appended to an
ASCII string called hash - so it's
actually a distinguished name as the Eid
in the Eid record and DDT can build
hierarchy on any ascii character in any
string so we've played with this before
so you know here's the delegation for
Joel and here's Joel Halpern - a helper
in Prime and it's all subordinate to
that so you can you can break the hey a
hierarchy up not on bit boundaries of
course but on character boundaries right
okay okay so well what we also did is we
recently introduced signature e IDs the
signature Eid is a crypto Eid even
though it's not one that you're using
for doing ipv6 communication it could
still be used to authenticate other
things that you want to send to our
register the mapping system or request
from the mapping system so some family
fits we're using you know the latest in
digital signatures lift a curve that's
why the draft is called the ECDSA and
what the benefit is is that you can
actually
you
yeah I was that now he went today still
working group and then it goes back
alright so least for 436 yes so as you
guys know very well and now that is
contraband except right that we have
taken the chance to to see how we can
apply the least control into to
definitive edge the last time which is
10 days for LA now that I know these 4s
every six the the tag working progress
really applies to to this one because as
we speak we are discussing changes on on
the diaphragm and the underwear so for
the next iteration it would change and I
will have to refine as we go but the
basic idea that we have here is that we
would like to use the least control
plane offer their services English notes
information about where they have to
send the traffic so as we put in at
least least four forward to go so
basically we map the ladies the point
being is heading to the egress a survey
six node and the VPNs are met on that
degrees
not where the traffic has to go then the
rest of his stuff when a service is
about traffic engineering far out it's
still done by bias a v6 so least forward
to go as a basis for how to vote so in
this in the person person of the draft
in the zero zero we cover like kind of
the foot picture right where you have an
overlay with mobility and defecate you
needn't be in every six but becomes
already about that we should be clear on
that
that's not necessary and I would plant
to clarify that first and you don't need
traffic engineer so if you are
interested in sending traffic from the
English to the egress and - so you need
to to go further for the whole thing but
for now we have covered you know the
difficult use case now we will narrow
down to more simple cases so these are
the basic ideas later on I have some
slides with examples that will help a
lot to clarify how things work but this
is the basic idea of the draft so you
rely on the IGAs a services knows to
register the end points into the maps
solution and then we use a new aircraft
to register the services needed
information so the ingress Asano's and
talked on our way through this
information can use it to first see
where they have to go so where we have
two significant and also computer and
they are prepared traffic a name and
politician and whatnot
thus the two points are covered on the
at the bottom of the slide and and then
how do you resolve the end points so
basically we present two models in the
in the draft one where the English note
request then put information to
knowledge system it gets the exit
pipian seeds so like the the final
service expansion that the traffic has
to go to and also that little
information that we saw in the previous
slide like the they the Eagers know the
traffic is still intact and Alda so with
that information the ingress a service
each node can go to the to the PC this
is common as a Vista and go to the PC
retrieve the SR policy to reach to that
egress SR know then we also have another
model where the English services note
requests again the mapping system and is
the map consistent the one that take
care at the scale of talking if needed
with the PC to compute the path to the
SLE underlay and then the Marshall
directly returns the list of SR hops
through the underlay so the Angus I said
no doesn't need to to talk with the PC
to compute that so let's go through
examples to clarify all these so first
first what I call him a slice this
general solution so going to the map
server and then going to the PC right so
this is the basic a scenario that we
consider you can see their doors a and C
are the English and aggressive notes and
on the left you can see the information
in the English note a as well as the
information they on the map server and
you'll see how the information gets gets
populated as we go you can see that the
endpoints that are attached to the to
the si English notes and and how you
look at the if you look here at the
table you can see how for instance a has
two important right and it has two
recognition functions that point to the
two graphs that that guy is in parenting
so when you want to send traffic to to
this valve you will use this one and so
on and you can imagine a similar table
for for C all right so this is happy to
start a mob register so
they just send information about the
local endpoints the localities to the
server as usual and what the history is
the the information about if you want to
go to this guy that is an instance 91
this is the ingress Sr function that you
need to capture the traffic towers and
this is the traffic is didn't act the
color that you actually with that
particular Empire so you can use that
later on to communicate the PC to
compute the appropriate path through
there to the under map so now let's see
let's say that you have traffic going
from from V to X as you can see this or
destination source added another's
payload so what happens is commonly
stuff my request my reply so you get the
this line from the from the map request
molecular change where the Ino knows
that to go to X it has to encapsulate
traffic towards C column D 33 and that
it can use the direct product to to find
the appropriate not in the under day
that is what he is doing in this step is
talking with the PCs and I want to go to
to this egress as a node and I know that
the traffic has to be a city with this
with this color with this particular SLA
or traffic is the entire or whatever you
want to put it
so tell me the the path so that's what's
happening here and you can see the the
lesser policies are populated here so
they ain't know now know that to go to
the egress see when the traffic is type
color red it has to go through through B
so that is what is happening here
yeah I know they're not going to the
details of how they sell encapsulation
go straight case that you guys can take
a look at that on the spring go through
the plenty of presentations around on
this basically captures a traffic
through the services underlay to until
be the capsule eight
in Si and deliver as usual
so now mobility which is what we covered
in the drive right so let's assume that
X moves to a new egress point e so this
is regularly spaced off your cinema
blister and this my register well I've
put both options in in there so I
consider the mobility and the ATF this
pops up some of you may argue the only
one is needed and I can I could agree
with that so after us how you want to
deal with mobility so you can use one
the other are both so they are all as
you know interval so I put them both
therefore for reference so basically you
update the Coconino to come to the Mike
on this value offer it now this you know
just one quick question we'll need to do
pub/sub or SMRs
even if the our loop doesn't change but
the srt the source route segment route
that's associated with our luck changes
it looks like a mobility change and has
to be signaled to that yeah yeah we it's
not enough that's specified in space
that's in the next model so in this
model we assume that the SR part is like
computed by the one the computer it's
really from the PC directly from the
English so it's like this joint from the
front dailies retrieval of the final
decapsulation point but in the model
where we call okay these two options
that is certainly the case so if the SL
passengers in definitely fine so in the
EIT mobility draft we never this is AB
new setting a precedent which is ok it
the ID mobilities draft said whenever
the our log changes or has a new binding
and we trigger map registers we do SMRs
we do pub/sub we do data trigger SM ours
whatever the case for all those mobility
cases but I don't remember if the text
says if the our load if the contents of
the our local record changes versus the
are locating well be careful do you know
because what they put in the or lock
address is not the segment route
it's the label for the policy for the
segment route to go ask the PCE so I
didn't want to bring that up because
that's another issue I have with
two-stage lookups so so not at the point
is the way they're doing it in this
version this part they're the mobility
that the policy didn't change you don't
change anything in the read in the
database that's why I say that
so the Seco model this is not a
criticism by any means on segment
routing but let's think of this let's
look at just a ID mobility earning over
an MPLS cloud and let's say the label
switches for the underlay that's the
same case here where the our look
doesn't change just the label changes
because you have a new te path I don't
know if we have language that talks
about the characteristics of the
underlay have changed the how-to part
not the wear part science are not there
on that trigger the comment you made
just made it more complicated because of
level of indirection I mean then you get
into you'd have to trigger something to
indicate that you need to require the
PCE wait there's nothing to change in
the mapping system so I don't know how
you would do it
listen let's maybe go through this
second model because I think your
question applies more to the second
mother than to this one so let's just
finish with this once the English has
been notified of the new attachment
point for the endpoint it will find if
needed and us our policy to go through
the through the underlay
traffic goes there okay so now the
second model is I think what universe as
never in this model the map server is
the one that interacts with the PC to
find the paths to the underlay so things
are like in a previous one
let's see if that everything has been
released already and whatnot so traffic
appears on the ingress map request is
trick what happens here is that the MSM
arrow goes to the PC or maybe firstborn
previously on has something for the
store there so the map server goes to
the to the
see and okay I want to know which is the
SL policy to go to the study series
because they have someone that is that
is asking about an endpoint attached to
that aggressor I understand the whole
path to to that guy
so the luxury gets up and sends back a
map reply with the with the complete
path right so in this case the note a
will have a Marcus entry that says that
okay I want to send traffic to X so I
have to use that s a b6 path that goes
through B and then C using the
decapsulation function the the traffic
course like in the other example
mobility is the same and in this case
it's worth the the mobility event
triggers also the depart for the SL
which seeks English now to reach the ETS
not say this as well and this is I think
that the case that we know was
mentioning so let's assume that yes the
SR policy changes so yeah in this second
model the map Shara will notify like
okay i i've sent this information to you
in the past and others in Fircrest
change so here's the new information
this is D know what if the SR policy
doesn't change but the reach ability of
the segment route changes English hands
like that you are not every tool that
you have a segue route ABC and there's a
reach ability problem between B and C is
there any proactive I think of that like
go through a b-prime c-prime or
something that's not necessary for na
yeah yeah no yeah maybe Darren Duke
Cisco Systems and yes the PC with
noticed by MSL are when that when that
changes the PCE would compute a new path
and notify msmr of the new path which
would then it gets tributed down to the
ITR well all i tiaras are all i care is
interested i don't know
yeah okay so that's it for the example
so we have an ongoing discussion on how
we want to encode this part and I think
that denoxin opinion on these two I just
wanted you to comment on the issue we
had in the side meeting about how to
avoid the two-stage lookup right so in
the driver and now we have these two
models one with the two estates look up
another with a single stage so for now
we prefer to consider these two as
separate options that images to attend
one or the other as we move on through
the person's refund in the era was if so
in the first model the SR is directly in
the our lot in the alcove in the airlock
record in the first model the
information needed to compute the SR
path in the underlay is in the ELCA and
then right this is really working
progress so things may change quite a
bit for for personal one and at some
point while this is more stable we went
over to to Experian Camp list and there
and we also plan to have this listed
limitation on on the open source router
so we can play a bit with it so that's
all I have so Victor Cisco question on
on the second model where you have two
single look up once you get the update
from the PC is the thought to actually
push that update to the ITRs or are you
gonna send them up notified to the ETRS
involved and then let the SMR mechanisms
take place or are we restrict are we
thinking about restricting this to pops
up as saneras only yeah so if
if we follow it the universe end before
right so once this had changed on the
policy PC will notify the map server yes
the map server will see a change from
the airlock information and it will
candy pop server it can do pawns half we
can do also in mobility let's say that's
observe so it sends Marvin notifies to
whoever has request that information in
the past right or has been subscribed to
that information okay it's clear for the
pops up you know not so much for the SMR
based mechanism or how we do well
technically for decimal base you will
send to the et reviews yeah previous
information and then if traffic reaches
that point
SMI will trigger map request and you
will get back there they updated
information okay so I don't know if we
add text to the EAD mobility draft or if
we handle that in this draft right now
let's look at the ID mobility draft to
see what the text looks like to seem it
generically covers this case without
being specific mm-hmm okay so I just
want to make a reference to Luigi's
question and listen to telemetry talk
about why should the ETR give the
information back to the ITR this is a
good example here where an ITR may have
to our low chrec ERDs to either the same
our local different ones but the point
is as if there's different say it's for
the same one because it's kind of
interesting but there's different
segment routes so you may want to our
load probe twice because you're going on
a different path and then when you get
the information back you want the ETR to
tell the idea and it knows with path
that is since these segments routes are
source based or relative to the ITR you
need to you have this directionality
problem so we thought that you know
would be more general for that slid over
MPLS okay I have two quick questions
actually so you don't use that all the
least pick up selection I'm instead by
but you don't say anything
document in principle you could you
could if you wish to use the any
functionality that there comes with the
on sped up solution yeah technically you
could yes I mean I think would be
clearer he is in the document you are
text they say no we don't want or you
could I can respond on that officer side
of that anyway you can I think it was at
the front of this document where you'd
mentioned over to where you know we went
for kind of the whole enchilada right
off the bat we need to break it down
into into what happens if we are not
doing te I think your question of doing
lisping cap and doing s our traffic
engineering as well maybe one that needs
to be looked at in there as well we
could we could expand on that because I
think you're right this is with an SR v6
in cap but what about some other end cap
with the same SR traffic engineering
yeah it quickly put a second question
unless is related to this my new one
okay so can you go back to the ABC
slider so I'm glad that Luigi brought
this up because it begs another question
why can't a B and C be our TRS and you
encapsulate at each point and re
encapsulate and if you do that you get
our look probing between each components
of this source route this is exactly
what list te is doing with LPS right
they can see and so one argues when I
use the question why do you need segment
routing v6 because if you put that our
TR topology in there those links the the
link between or the underlay between a
and B and B and C could be a combination
of ipv6 and ipv4 now I know the answer
to the question but I just want I'm glad
he brought it off because I didn't want
to
[Laughter]
so so you mentioned an interesting
scenario where you're trying to
basically break things down and show
that you could actually have SR v6 with
Lisp and no traffic engineering and in
that case what are your thoughts on
basically subsuming the pc functionality
into the msmr would you need a PC at
that point okay and and then I guess the
other point is even if you have traffic
engineering it could could be
consolidate actually my name is second
question kind of related I mean why PC
let me finish so you you have a two
models integrated and and it's pretty
fine why you need to specify PC because
you can just describe the two models in
an abstract way and say yeah I need the
traffic engineering information I either
the mapping system does it for me all I
do it and then PC would be one a great
example how you do it because you can
have all the control plane for the SLV
six so I mean if you want to put PC into
this document fine but if you split
other sets so you let it opening in case
you want to use a different absolutely
that's that's what I was referring to
that we are paying to go more after for
the next edition of the lab so
definitely find what you said so okay
that could help answer the to look of
concern okay thank you
okay good I'll just total mic so this is
a talk that I've been giving this talk
to the last couple lists working groups
was also given the writing research
rowdy working group this this meeting a
simple BGP based mobile routing system
for the aeronautical telecommunications
network so some background the
International Civil Aviation
Organization is building an IP based
networking system for worldwide air
traffic management and for those that
don't know ICAO is walking distance from
this building their headquarters were
just down the road from here so they're
developing what's called the
aeronautical telecommunications network
with Internet Protocol services or
etienne IPs
it's a new development in the ICAO
working group I which is like the IETF
versatile aviation it's an ipv6 based
and mobility capable and it's going to
accommodate aircraft with multiple data
links so an aircraft might have some
satellite links all Dax is a cellular
link that's being developed currently
VHF links and Inmarsat iridium you name
it aircraft have many links when they're
traveling so we're looking at a BGP
based internet working design where the
BGP overlay network will be separate
from the global public internet BGP
routing system it's based on a hub and
spokes arrangement with regionally
distributed stub ASPRS and centrally
located core ASPRS
the stub autonomous system boy routers
advertising withdraw mobile network
prefixes that belong to planes and the
core autonomous system border routers
form a hub autonomous system between two
four packets between the stub autonomous
system where routers proxies or X TRS
connect datalink sub networks to the
overlay and clients that are aircraft
that may connect multiple sub networks
then route optimization removes the
autonomous system where routers from the
path so what it looks like here is that
it's think of it in terms of concentric
circles
in the center circle you have those
purple routers that are core autonomous
system border routers that are within
the same autonomous system and they talk
use an eye bgp to keep full topology
information and the next outer circle
you have those green routers those are
the stub autonomous system border
routers and they connect to aircraft
mobile network prefixes into the core
and then out in the next circle you see
what I've label there there's proxies
but that's where the XT are it's it in
the list model and then finally further
out you've got the the client airplanes
and as you can see some is there a light
on this or all right I didn't want to do
that
okay so you have some airplanes can
connect to multiple data links for
example if it has that comm link through
the first sub Network and in L - link
through a second sub Network and again
your calf may have many data links that
they they activate they're in different
phases of flight so the details on the
BGP arrangement here is that each the
Hanauma system border router is a stub
autonomous system unto itself all core
autonomous system border routers make
our members of the same core autonomous
system the stub it advertised their
associative mobile network prefixes
that's the prefix is owned by the
airplanes so the core using the ebgp
and the core autonomous system border
routers at originate default but they
did not advertise any mobile network
prefixes to the stub autonomous system
or routers by the court system south
tunnel system border routers discover
all mobile network prefixes in the
system using ibgp
and they can connect the overlay to the
global public Internet in which case
they would advertise only a short
aggregate like a 2001 DBA : font size 32
instead of dumping all the airplane
mobile network prefix is into the BGP
routing system we've seen in past
experiments that that doesn't scale this
is kind of reiterating what I've already
said about the hub and spokes model and
this is the diagram that comes from the
draft so
changes since last version we removed
the discussion of route optimization and
mobility in multi-link because these are
covered under other drafts we have the
draft that that's that's the Lisp
ground-based Lisp that talks about one
proposal there and I've got another
draft on arrow that talks about a second
proposal but this draft is now generic
it doesn't apply to either lisper arrow
directly and either one can be fit in
we've had some discussions how the
multiple systems can come into play in
different partitions of the network and
the document focuses on the BGP topology
and route interactions and it emphasizes
that in earth autonomous system mobility
events and quality of service updates
are not propagated into the BGP routing
system so that's that's pretty much it
it's it's a it's again it's think of it
in terms of the concentric reigns where
you have your mobility and your multi
only can happen in the outermost ring so
that the core doesn't get affected by
that you know a quick question
you said the plains are multi home do
they use both links at the same time
they can and what is the what's the
addressing when they're using both at
the same time they they use the same Eid
over both links and so the ID perfect so
I should say okay so you might have
differentiated service code points point
to link a for some traffic points like B
for other traffic I see okay I think
that's it let me just check oh okay
here's the draft again it's been
presented I can working group by
mobility subgroup and it's and reactive
consideration there and it has been
presented in the routing working group
that ITF 99 101 and also one or two is
just presented on Monday and also
presented at the list working group at
IES 101 101 and also now now this one at
102 so I think that's all I have any any
further questions have you considered
using both Lisp and BGP at the same time
like just use Lisp on the proxies does
that make sense that's what we're
thinking about all that yeah that's what
we're thinking about doing okay thank
you just curiosity one will I kow
additionally they considering the
solution right so what is the time ICAO
is really kind of pushing forward to get
a solution decided on soon but whether
that solution would be a pure list or a
pure arrow or a pure mobile ipv6 or some
kind of hybrid of those that's what kind
of in the press is trying to decide
right now and figure out hi Brian with
Nexus um actually just was wondering if
you were considering using the planes is
sort of a mesh network so they could
relay each other's packets that's a very
interesting idea so air-to-air links are
you thinking about that yes yeah yeah we
think about that when we talk about
drones we talk about unmanned aircraft
the small drones you know we haven't
been thinking so much about the civil
aviation airplanes but that's certainly
something for us to consider okay thank
you thanks Pat so the last presenter of
today is calling
well nobody it's my first presentation
so well hope it goes well make sure that
should questions get comments let me
know anything uh I may not be seeing
correctly on this but this is uh this is
essentially something that you know what
I've been working on kind of speculate
on for a while a little background I
work on peer-to-peer networks
cryptographic distributed ledger so as
we've kind of had some interesting
interactions figuring out how we can
come integrate some network level on
components to distribute ledger so
that's kind of where the berthing place
is the decentralized mapping system came
in essentially if you have a period of
your network valued in hundreds of
billions of dollars let's say Bitcoin
for an example and it's running over
Lisp you need to basically mitigate
central points of failure which mapping
servers can't potentially be which could
essentially bring down the entire
network and cause significant damages
monetarily so what if lists STRs did
rely on pre-configured map servers and
what if map servers could also allocate
to their own shards when they came
online now what if the abstraction
layers on top of the OSI could actually
improve key management and authorization
in map servers and what if we could
mitigate map server DDoS attacks the
partial free image collisions of zero
bits so what this basically means is we
can distribute the X TRS and the map
servers and make them auto allocating as
the type of distributed consensus
mechanism so that they can allocate
specific shards within one another and
then from that they can create a higher
level of reliability now this is gonna
mitigate DDoS attacks I'll get to that
about the partial pre image collisions
that's essentially finding a number of
zero bits that are partial pre-minced
collision on any type of hash with Iran
and once the little sensor would be a
proof-of-work that would create an
asymmetric type situation which means
that the requester would require to
fulfill thousands more hashes than the
actual verify or the map server which
will may be required to fulfill one so
you could draw packets and I'll get to
that later so I'm going on a tangent
so starting a map server so what if each
sex er was a map server allocated to a
DHT sharra to a distributed hash table
and what if eat sexy our could actually
map register to each X Y are based on
deterministic modulus so essentially
what you could do is every time a new
map server came online they could
replicate one another and then they
would be acting through a shared type of
address registry that will get to that
with the DNS which essentially would be
able to create an Alok eight new shards
so it would in a sense share some of the
cache and new notes coming on that are
aware of new map servers would
essentially be able to start asking or
talking to these in charge within caches
and then the map servers would
eventually cache and timeout since some
of the records would go and so it would
automatically be able to locate and
create shard 4506 as needed so this
would be something that would be
determined by the map servers it would
probably require a little OSHA machinery
but it would allow them to essentially
Auto synchronize and Auto manage
themselves so the DDoS protection we
always have the needle in a haystack
problem with the us attacks what do we
do if a central map server goes down
under it it is attacked me does this
cripple the network now what if the
server low determines the location on
the DHT charge or map servers and also
access to require requesting party to
compute a proof-of-work
by iterating and wants to find a value
that meets a member of zero bits making
require work for the requester if the
server happens to be under heavy low so
if you have some sort of minimum
threshold that the map servers are
located near shards at let's say 30
percent over a moving average window
you'll be able to reasonably determine
if the server load goes above 50 or 60
percent that you're under some form of
DDoS attack which you can throttle
requests from all parties by requiring
let's say 100 milliseconds or 500
milliseconds of actual proof of work
which would be easy to verify on the map
server side it would slow down request
the requesters side and it would allow
the map server to resolve that load and
reduce it which would improve the actual
accessibility for the end user
now the downside for the user is they
would require computing cycles if the
server did get under heavier load but if
you're on
ddos attack and the service completely
down that's completely service outage
this would just be a slow the service
which would require you to essentially
pay your dues to get access to the
system so how to start the mapping
system so as Joel brought up last time
we went over the lifts decentralized
draft there was a bootstrapping problem
so the DNS record would simply be
something that is pre-configured they
would talk to a DNS type of map server
that would just be keeping a running
record of all of the actual distributed
map servers so this would be the way
that you get through the bootstrap you
can figure that in and then the DNS
server is essentially what you get the a
record for which then you talk to it
over a predefined message set and ask it
directly back for the list of money map
servers or shards and then you'll know
exactly ones now if a shard is in
bootstrapping phase which could be a
24-hour phase creating let's say shard 4
then you would be essentially talking to
modulus 3 in modulus for in order to
bootstrap and help that map cache fill
up to eventually get through that
bootstrapping period to where the new
char can allocate so the exit er's that
are part of the mapping system resolved
the first DNS records to obtain the
initial DNS see the send resolves return
a list of known map-servers map
registers are sent to the correct shark
allocated by the terminus assignment of
modules so an example would essentially
be we have three and then the new
location there would essentially be
getting map register request that would
still be having the cash let's say if it
was in mod two and the original starts
it would be getting new registers and
not for an MOT two but eventually the
more of them that started become aware
of this in char would eventually cause
all of the mah twos to timeout and then
they eventually ignore it so that they
can automatically synchronize into new
shards so the DDoS request throttling
one of the map servers can essentially
use the AED as a part of the throttling
mechanism to do the individual now when
we have a DDoS attack we have a problem
where somebody could be essentially
manipulating the source the destination
and completely spoofing all the IPS the
problem that we can have there's the
needle in the haystack problem so we
resolve that through the CPU collective
usage and use that to essentially say
well if you're making me work more I'm
going to
you work a little bit more and then
that's the global to do the DDoS now if
it's just a DOS attack then you could
easily throttle that by saying if you're
making too many requests per second then
we're gonna slowly increase the amount
of zero bits that you're required to do
which is going to increase the
computational requirements for you to
send a message so all you have to do is
verify one hash and then drop a packet
if it doesn't meet approval work
requirements - there seem to be mixed -
did at least two different sets of
requests in this which come from
different parties and I'm a little
confused about that
there's map registers which come from
other etrs while waiting the ETR is one
of your DHT elements so it wouldn't be
sending map registers so there probably
are no map registers and their map
requests which come from ITRs to map
requesters not map servers okay and now
who's going to prove work because the
request has to go across the the DHT to
the guy who has the authoritative thing
he's going to ask somebody to prove work
but it looks like he's asking the
trusted party to end up doing work
because the trusted party is getting
besieged with requests which he has no
way to ask for proof of work it would be
agnostic to the message and oh you could
also theoretically scale it based on the
actual let's say computation
requirements of each message so that's
still something that's being thought out
but this is kind of the theory being put
in place and that doesn't answer the
question at all my point is map requests
come from ITRs yes to the edge of the
mapping system those don't you you
haven't talked about those entries
entities a missed slide at all so
obviously apparently those aren't asking
for proof of work so the proof of work
is coming from the guy who has the
authoritative information well by the
time you've gotten it to him asking him
asking somebody else to prove work a
seems to be the wrong question and B
he's asking the wrong party he's
actually asking a trusted member of the
mapping system to prove work not the
ITRs unless you're also changing things
to assume that ITRs are members
the mapping system and a decentralized
system the word trust is something that
is generally disregarded because anybody
could be a malicious actor so this would
be something to mitigate that in a
certain sense in case even a map server
could be malicious so you're saying what
you're trying to deal with is a very
different DDoS than everybody else
worries me there's a lot of different
factors yes and I'm not saying that I
have the answers for all of them this is
just a preliminary architecture in order
to maybe facilitate the idea of a
potential use case in this as far as
mitigating potential risk of dose or
DDoS on whatever layers the network okay
well I I'm speaking about in a general
sense so I apologize if I'm not so
explicit but anyhow so so separate all
the xprm Appling system from das
attacking the mapping system because we
could toss protect a mapping system when
it's not decentralized okay so think of
the mapping system as you know it today
and it's being das attack I thought how
could we use proof-of-work
to slow down attackers that is a major
change not to the mapping system but to
the interface which we have defined as
stable now we can evolve it but it's
that's what I was trying to get out is
the difference between mapping system
operation we've structured this so that
putting in a new mapping system is
transparent to the external interfaces
yes and changes to those external
interfaces it looks like this takes
changes to those external interfaces
right that's not out of the question
right but we just want to make it clear
if you're gonna present it here yes
about that distinction and from what I
understand you wouldn't need to modulate
too much at the package structure you
would be able to use the nos that
already exist within it and then just
check the zero bits as far as it checks
out we need some extra messaging to say
a little have to meet this constraint
yes that's new message on the map reply
message that would be exactly where he
could send we were talking about using a
few high order bits or something with
the next since there is 64 bits number
space you said you know correct so the
idea would be Joel that the ETR would
do the proof of work and the hash would
be the hash doesn't have to be sent in
the map register only the nonce does
that nonce we already sent today now
what is said on the other side is that
the guy takes the nonce hashes the
packet and then he he gets the hash
needles if he's good or bad
now as you want to change the level of
difficulty we know we have a map notify
that's an acknowledgement for the map
register the map notify that you send
back could have a difficulty value so as
the dosa tech it increases level of
difficulty for proof of work increases
I'm all I'm saying was you have to put
something doing the messages so that you
know what the difficulty level you gotta
meet is yep and I mean I'm not saying
that it's gonna be perfect but I think
that the potential risk that could be
mitigated especially getting lisp in a
decentralized environment could be a so
it sounds to me like you've got to two
things here the decentralization of the
mapping system and this in its own right
as its own ideas you need two separate
documents that's probably more
appropriate yes okay so I apologize for
I'll do better next time
but um okay so anyhow so then we
essentially what you can do is you can
have certain types of attacks let's say
EC they said verify unless crypto that
would be done through a CPU exhaustion
attacks so by being able to throttle and
create the asymmetric proof or work you
would be able to essentially require the
end party that means doing the requests
or any sort to basically require to do a
proof of work which would throttle them
now the benefits are the XE ours only
depend on each other and today already
if they want to talk to each other now
no third-party trust or dependency
exists master Cup locos has low latency
and map servers have McDonough C and
scalability those are important
components to get into a completely
centralized environment to utilize lisp
with something such as a distributed
ledger so the distributed ledger is an
abstraction layer on top of lisp or on
top of the LSI reference stack can
actually handle the removal of need of
third parties such as key management
authorization access control schemes
since the distributed ledger is actually
a very secure data layer that is built
through a consensus mechanisms globally
there's a lot of things that you can
actually be implementing on
list so the prerequisites defined in
this document are for their
prerequisites of line to make the
decentralized mapping system function in
a case that would eventually allow a
distributed ledger to sit on top of it
which also allows you to create
reputation systems mathematically
verified on Eid so that you know exactly
who you're talking to and then you can
have certain let's say selection bias
from the list selamat read data on the
distributed ledger and vice versa if a
map server can verify a IDs or arlok's
that are mentioned in to the distributed
ledger and verify their actual trust and
reputation
there can be implications in that as
well it sounds like there's a real
assumption here that's very important
and valid for some of the use cases
you're describing but I want to make
sure I'm understanding you your
assumption seems to be that this is an
environment in which not only are the
xtr highly distributed but any X T it is
perfectly okay for any X TR to claim to
be serving any ID as long as nobody else
is claiming that Eid or Eid prefix know
when you have to distribute a ledger on
top of that we actually create a
reputation system the series of events
so that somebody's claim is not just a
claim out in the open abyss you actually
have a masterful verifiable trail of
somebody's trustworthiness so that you
can have a distributed trustless system
by mathematical verification that's
going to be okay
nothing you're gonna need if you want to
claim this applies to a lot more you're
going to need to provide a lot more
details on how that's related because
frankly it is I would take way too long
for me to unpack what you just said
you're absolutely right and this this
presentation is kind of a mix of three
different components that do us modeling
the list decentralization with the
automaticall occasion of the Maps and
then the distributed ledger technology I
could go in I've been developing the
sugar Letters for about four years now
so I have a sense of experience in that
I've been running a live one for about
three and a half so I could get into a
lot of details and I'll probably author
a draft on the DDoS and then the
distributed ledger technology on top of
the OSI I just be continually wanna
treat that as separate then you're gonna
create a dependency
between the two drafts and the DDoS
thing it looks like it's really
separable okay I'd like to be able to
evaluate that separately because I think
it's potentially interesting but very
separate cool the relationship about who
is allowed to register what and how that
is achieved is central to the notion of
what the mapping system does okay
there's a whole lot of work in the
register messages in these authorization
models we've done and that doesn't mean
we have to stick with them maybe we want
to offer alternative ones as well but
it's very important to address yes yes
and I think that can be addressed with
the distributed ledger so in our next
revision of this draft we will continue
forward on explaining in a strap letting
on the implications of that it's victory
so Joel if you if you keep them as one
document right all those users of the
distributed ledger etc would only be
applicable to the decentralized model of
the mapping system but they may be
applicable to a centralized model that
yeahthere's operations yes they can be
separate but you need to be careful
about how they're related okay yet the
deal T is is a secure data layer that's
formed through a global consensus which
makes it very difficult to forge any
data on it because instead of having
let's say conventional Byzantine fault
tolerance of 30% three o plus one you
end up having multiple layers of
validation that become incredibly costly
to forge and create which allows you to
create a track record of cryptographic
identities and keys that we can then use
through authorization systems in
centralized or decentralized mapping
systems so regarding the last bullet
Albert's been doing a lot of work with
his team on how blockchain technology in
general could help less and there's
there's ideas on how to enhance the
mapping system how to do prefix openness
and allocation and stuff like that so
yeah thank you yeah there's a lot of
implications on it and I mean I believe
that the OSI as we have it works to a
point but the need for so many third
parties is kind of showing that there
needs to be more layers under that stack
and I think the distributed ledger is
one of the layers that could sit
possibly even in the applications
presentation of the OSI and then so on
and so forth create kind of the auto
executing environments and tie financial
instruments into it um I noticed that
there was a need for DNS to begin with
right yes No if they're following their
intent try that the intent is to get
away from the relying on the third-party
elements as much as possible but then
you still have to rely on us for the
seeding processes I guess right so does
that somewhat reduce the efficacy of the
world solution mean here the way we
wanted to be centralize it but we are
going back to the third party if not
necessarily if you were passed an IP
address of your friend that was already
connected to the network and they said
you can use my IP address you can hard
code that directly inter put in your
configuration file and it would function
the same way all it's doing is
functioning to give you the gateway and
the network once you get in the network
address discovery happens automatically
so the DNS is kind of a convenient user
way in order to get access to the
network but if you want to read not rely
on it that's perfectly possible to do
you just need to know the IP address of
a game right to get the initial address
seats okay man orkap dns gives me the
response that I didn't I shouldn't have
had all right so yeah that's fine
generally you're not gonna want to rely
on one domain name so and Nexus what we
do right now is we have a set of twenty
or thirty different DNS records that act
is the first nodes that a node ever
talks to is then gets the seeds of all
the other nodes that are accessible and
then it goes and it starts connecting so
you do that through redundancy by having
multiple DNS records if one of them
results won't interact address then that
poor it's not gonna be open and you're
not gonna be able to make that
connection and you're just gonna discard
it well the fit is open and it's
malicious on the other side
that's the possibility on think it's
possibility this malicious and that's
the beautiful thing about distributed
consensus is you don't have to just talk
to one node you generally talk to
multiple ones so if they do give you a
list of malicious addresses that's why
you do the full validation of the ledger
on your local node and verify all the
cryptography so even if they try to send
you malicious data you're gonna be able
to detect it and it's gonna be about
assuming that they don't have the
consensus they don't have the majority
if yes and that that majority would come
generally in your contacts saying that
would be called the civil attack but in
this sense it requires an incredible
computing power through proof-of-work
and also other mechanisms to proof of
stake validation processes to actually
make those cryptographic blocks so you
wouldn't it wouldn't matter if you talk
to an invalid land they could give you a
bad blotching or a bad set of blocks and
you're gonna be able to verify with your
neighbor the correct thank you Thanks
yep to address your comment so I asked
III look I mean many people have asked
this question before what's the
decentralized internet and I like to
think of it of a way is if you use DNS
are you depending on a third party well
you may be depending on a third party
but you could still be decentralized
because it depends where the third party
is and who's managing it so I like to
think of it this way if we use something
like list decent and every xtr is a
mapping system or a map server of the
same mapping system I like to think of
it as a neighborhood of devices that
have local connectivity that's an IP
packets each other they want to be
self-sufficient they want to run
themselves they have no connections to
the Internet but maybe if you don't have
multicast which is if you have multicast
locally then you can do everything
dynamically just like we see how a
bonjour works in our house with Macs and
stuff like that but if you don't have
that multi guess for some reason you can
still depend on dns but the DNS is all
local and trusted among that trust group
in the in the in that neighborhood so
even though you're depending on this
protocol that looks centralized it's
being deployed in a decentralized
trusted environment and mitigate my far
as I know none of the arguments for our
deployments we describe for a lisp match
what you just described email agree they
tend to be scattered around the internet
not locally connected or they tend to be
under if they're serving a single data
center which is the opposite case where
they are clustered they're under a
single administrative control and so you
don't have a distributed trust problem
right so be very careful about
describing the problem because I I've
run into this a lot with people applying
to saying we could use black chains for
food well yeah but
actually match any of the properties of
food black jeans have interesting
properties I get its supply chain
management and auditability and
immutability of the data so that's where
you create trust where it's mathematics
it becomes the verify of truth so in a
sense you could call it blockchain or
distributed ledger a truth layer of the
Internet which is something that we
don't really have now the truth is
determined by global consensus and the
more people you have validating and that
consensus the more you could consider
that truth so it essentially gives you
just layers of abstraction that help
give an improved frame of reference I
would never speak in absolutes about it
but there is a significant improvement
that can be done ok so this is pretty
much almost over anything so why do
centralized well it's important the
Internet the IETF was designed to be to
decentralize the internet was designed
to be decentralized it makes it more
robust and it removes it from central
points of failure and also four central
points of control so peer-to-peer
networks are we seen their star forces
and they've proven high levels of
robustness you have 100% uptime and you
don't have to have let's say any any
point essential failure no you always
have fall backs if a map server gets put
under a DDoS attack if you have the
distributed mapping system now as Jill
said there is certain trust issues that
need to be associated with that and
that's where the DLT hopefully can help
now distributed ledger technology relies
on the robust nature a peer to peer and
sort of run less reliable on such a
network would require this distributed
topology which makes it very interesting
where you can punch through the Nats and
get through the our Tiaras which is a
big problem of getting the full mesh
topology and what we exist now is just
something that list is actually bridging
for Nexus very significantly and also
the decoupling of your routing locators
to your endpoint identifiers and being
able to tie that to a cryptographic
identity so that you can actually be
reached and I can know somebody is
somebody and they can prove who they are
by signing from the specific key I'm a
signature chain and I can look up not
just from that Eid I can look up their
whole track record if they validate it
if they've had any spends if they've
created this a pet loans a bad escrow
contracts that failed and so on and so
forth so it just gives you a better
auditable trail of events that you can
use to create better selection bias
whether from yeti user map servers or
anything so my questions actions I just
want to add it to your last point yes so
the idea here is that crypto e IDs give
you identity at the network layer and
cryptocurrency wallets give you this
identity that can that is very
changeable because you have different
set of parameters when you want to
change it at the application layer the
question is is can the security of this
application layer help the network being
more secure and vice versa
yeah and Lisp security help the
application be more secure that's an
idea with the layers of abstraction so
if you add let's say a ledger layer on
the OSI and then that ledger layer could
have an API that's accessible from the
list layer or layer 3 which then be able
to ask the ledger about certain things
or certainly IDs or certain map servers
and be able to get actual data from
there so that the network layer can be
less spoof able and vice versa when the
letter can actually recognize a IDs
through that and have trust and they're
gonna know that nobody can spoof an ID
you can spoof an Arlo you can use VPN
whatever but I know I'm always talking
the same Eid and I see the cryptographic
proof that this person is who they are
based on the distributed ledger any
other questions comments cool thank you
guys so we we don't have any anymore
presentation on the agenda so we have a
few minutes I'd like 10 minutes if
someone like Dina wants to bring
something up to the mic yeah I I just
want to know where we are on the
decision on the OAM document and is that
holding up the best documents do we have
an OEM document if we don't have an OEM
document are we losing the text that we
pulled out so they are not unlocking the
best documents because there is no
reference to the document which is not
existing I sent an email to you to you I
bet about where we are with this dog
meat so it's up to you to answer the
question so you
you personally said I don't want a
variety because I I don't think it's the
right solution so I don't care
basically yeah oh I don't care
yeah so since I don't believe in it I
don't want to write the document and I'm
not going to speak for it to be honestly
there's nothing to me to be roped I mean
you just take the text do you put it in
in annex mail format technically we're
not questioning the effort of building a
separate document it's it's the
principle of having it in a third place
that's not helpful we are however to get
to the rest of your question trying to
get everything else unstuck so we
already broke ground the Shepherd right
up for the 66-34 bits we're trying to
get everything else out the door you
take him longer than we like we want it
done we understand we're at a stalemate
that's not blocking you that's what he
said we're gonna be moving that on
without regard to the other we're not
waiting for it right and my greatest
fear came true we're losing text it can
be recovered by somebody you are
somebody else putting it in a separate
document but it doesn't block our
getting the stuff to PS which we really
want oh yeah miss part of the chapter or
it is not part of the Charter sorry om
is part of the chapter or not it's I
believe it's a chartered work item but
it's not doesn't have to be part of
getting to PS we want it that's not the
question we didn't think it will fit
well where it was and so that's not
where it is and frankly if nobody cares
to put in the work to put it back
together
that says something about the work
groups actual interest in that work
that's a problem but it's a different
problem
it's not a questions of interest in the
work people have implemented that text
fine and it's going to be lost in the
only way to recover it will not be long
right
we will point to the experimental
artists II know who somebody will write
the dang RFC we want four standards
track that says what we want to do okay
let me try - let's try let me try to
have a different perspective
okay I think at that text we seem the
right context
hot value and the right context was the
the rest of the text the rest of their
absolute now what you're telling us is
you can take that debt and put it
somewhere else but I think that when you
do that it loses the value so it's not
that no one cares about that text it is
not true that seems no one is willing to
do that this means that the text has no
value I think that when you do that is
when you lose the value of the text well
the working this wasn't just the chair
is going well we arbitrarily decided we
targeted the working group it's not that
we just said well we don't like it I try
to stay off my high horse I like riding
I do it very very rarely and badly but I
kind of stay off that but we asked folks
agreed that it was better to remove it
so that's why we're advancing it without
it