to pad you can find the easiest way to
get there is through the tools page so
if you go tools that ITF org slash WG /
net mod and click on minutes you'll find
etherpad for 102 and we'd really
appreciate everyone in the room helping
to contribute to those notes in real
time I think that work has started the
session welcome to our second net mod
session this is the last session for us
obviously if the IPF there's one more
session after this but who won't be
there thank you for sticking with us we
have about a half full agenda and I know
there was one additional discussion
topic that we were expecting in AV to
talk about and I think he stepped out so
he'll come back in and we'll have that
conversation when she's ready so I'm Lou
burgers can Watson George a green and we
have Michael taking notes here as well
as our secretary given that this is the
last day of the of the meeting I think
everyone should be familiar with the
note well if for some reason you're not
please take a look at the URL on the
bottom and just be aware anything you
say here is part of our permanent record
we are sending and recording video we do
have people remote it's very important
that if you speak of the mic to say your
name and I apologize if I forget to do
that we have blue sheets circulating
sign knows and we already talked about
ether pad and our agenda is online and
unmodified this is the second session
you're here we don't remind you that
it's there so
we
[Music]
[Applause]
so these two pieces will be allowed in
right
yeah so basically this here does not
include the timing aspects over here the
expectation that you compared was
missing the they have no words compared
to both you can over why this using this
flag just a full comparison which
include also which visual them actually
include all data nodes which are related
to scheme and France which are nothing
both trees time option there's no state
aspect if you will so basically this is
basically the experience that compares
the RPC is performed when when it is
when it is requested so what here
suggests this I just want to compare
because the ways
we're not convinced actually is so when
you are actually you know do this NPA
compare actually maybe some sugar maybe
several mean sent us on notification we
don't just as many as discussed them for
applied intent when my antennae gotta
startle em and and completer
so waiting me this year is an RPC so
behind this is pretty
so this comparison is an automatic
trigger is not within the scope of this
draft okay but what's in Cisco and so I
like to think about such things - okay
trans con I think it makes sense to
maybe clarify when the schema differs
between two dates stores what that means
so I don't have the draft already says
that means the data we were talking yeah
excluded from the comparison if there is
potentially one node in one scheme and
once again around so clarify this a
little bit because
what you mean by that because he's kind
of the explanation it's different it
does indicate the original metadata
which might be an explanation about this
word is just on the data instances and
use comparing whether the values are
there in the to date stores just not
given to me that if for example what
racial state this or does not implement
some of those is daeviated remove then
you want to always flag was being diffs
so I think you need to just consider
that sort of case and maybe have another
option to say whether or not that's
reported or not I could talk to you
offline and then one other Connie can
get back to your original slide you had
your metadata included in comparison
which i think is good and again I would
potentially have an option to choose
whether or not to include that in the
different the origin metadata because
you may think that you may want to
compare know if they already but may not
carry different I think it's really
useful work and I support obtaining a
test I can one use case actually could
be in connection with my draft on West
Conway transactions just as an eight
forth emerging the staging repository
into into running or something like this
so I really would like to see this
adopted by Ericsson maybe some beginner
questions in the yank touch as I
understand there is many ways to
describe the same I think you mean
specify gets that same so is a creator
always an original fraction or I hike
get to be just one way because that has
to solve the equivalent problem and
obviously with the impacts you don't
apply this to two configuration files
data but this to the core you added one
who created the new leaf one way to
detect when you get this notification
result if you have multiple options what
I'm thinking is that the fiber from the
CRI
[Music]
should actually the causation of watch
how the difference came into being that
I'm actually not sure if we can do this
here because we
you can only see oh I have those through
data source obviously there's a
discrepancy of difference but why that
occurred it's enough to indicate the
difference I don't know I'm not so much
interested in one origin request was a
merger system unit another just a fun
question I don't know if you want me to
be hand
theoretically I think it's possible to
have different features activated in
different data stores will you say
something about that is that the same
would be a strange situation okay maybe
this one will be surely I should put for
the data source schema knows right
because obviously if you're having in
feature differences that would explain
that because there is a new history
maybe that's a question to the to the
chairs maybe you can because you know
location
- yeah it sort of makes sense that if he
here so I agree with the dead cough
chair okay there are comments how many
people think that this is a worthwhile
function for the working group to work
on first and rise I would say that's a
really good number
the document also a really good number
how many people think that this should
be the story and by the way compared to
the number that I can't mentioned
earlier fine does anyone object to
adopting this none so that seems like
pretty strong consensus of the room
we'll take the list
this is the information integrate his
management systems with a new yen so he
has to work
[Music]
gives you again these things document
that what should be perpetually use it
for pre
as well there are two document data sets
are supplied which means that some of
the yang constraints like the elements
or mandatory might be violated here it
might be that coating different groups
apply Parsifal
so which is the last time there was a
draft first one is that earlier the
draft said that you should a document
server instance data files kind of like
a recommendation best practice and come
back to this at this point in the draft
it was just a primary use case of the
most important use case next one was to
remove mr. yang data extension so the
whole
[Music]
we'll go into the into the document or
anything else but this this data can be
modified later on either by the system
itself already through management
operations that should the current
situation not what we thought will be
true there will be
Nations should we recommend that should
be documented in this one is that just a
use case some people said that server
capabilities is too uncertain some other
people said that yes let's say just an
idea about that I think this is a very
important principle and I would like to
keep it there but some people objected
comments Bob Wilson Cisco so I prefer
there is not not in this document so I'm
not debating whether or not and
documenting the capabilities useful
actually do things useful thing to do
but I have keep this this draft more
abstract in terms of this is just how
you do this data and you use the
capabilities as an example effectively
in this draft that's fine I want to have
a separate draft the talks about device
capabilities and it's probably more
stuff to say about them and says that
the way to do is use instance data
documents and many of you in your
previous line you said about comparing
like old data and the current one again
that's that's used to be thing to do
with capabilities if you think about the
access control in case which is used
widely I think very often that people
would go in and modify but then I'll
describe this you're saying this is just
providing a snapshot of data at one
point in time but I mean it's of course
a document is this written to a file
can't obviously update and it's the
context of how it's used defines which
one is the right one to use I don't
think this draft should say that it's
inter strange thing to say this is just
about how you represent long instance
data
other people requested this explicit way
to put this statement here okay it's a
snapshot I feel that's just a different
wording of the same statement
Katzenjammer network says contributor
sir I think they showed us a good idea
we could have a standard around how they
would publish their instance documents
[Applause]
this should be the standard that says
that if you have a yeah this is the five
[Music]
things that we should be in some method
that doesn't move the live documentation
yeah joy I think we need the method
right otherwise the shirt is kind of
empty right I don't necessarily think
that needs to be done in this draft
about like you know a normative
reference to the pointer where it
actually is followed by this being in
this ref and how that gets would be one
way to describe that but like yeah I'm
having having saying you should solve
this problem in a particular way and not
being able to do it is a bit of an
implementation gap so so so you say that
we should take this out of the draft for
an hour I think the shirt is okay but
it's there
would you expect implementation still no
some guidance merge nothing really needs
me in another draft necessary
implementations your I mean
implementation advice is actually
sometimes like especially if it is
necessary for interoperability in order
to like have two implementations do the
same thing right this is from Jurgen
so I'm channeling it's not my comment
I'm with Rob the shorted issue one is
misplaced a file format specification in
a file format specification so he
doesn't like it joke like Cisco so as
part of the work in the main catalog for
the in catalog every Cisco has been
trying to do even before this existed
publish some of the device capability in
fact probably the hello message is in
github I'm not saying that this that's
how they should that's how the how
should be implemented I'm just saying
that when you presented this I thought
this is the format we could use I think
well I don't think we would have to
figure out how admin yang data works but
today a party if the should stays in
that could be another half in terms of
publishing to the catalog I also think
that this should not be in this document
because this data format is quite
generic and Confused for any number of
other proposes so I wouldn't mind if
documenting server capabilities is
mentioned as one use case but I support
open organ said it should be a separate
document if it's necessary to to
standardize some best practice or
something
Tim karaoke I'm trying to connect some
dots here right I there's some other
drafts that talk about factory factory
defaults or the default factory store
how is this how is this any really
different than in a factory store
because now the draft said that you want
to restore the that it didn't tell you
how to document it really this is a more
about getting information before you
actually have the network notes
available okay so the the fact that the
factory store exists just connecting
dots so the the instance data is what
you would expect from you you're
manufacturing element right yes okay and
it's it's provided outside the context
of a deployed element right yes into
some location that you can obtain that
contains a config data right website so
it would be in my did I get so if I had
both of those together if I did it get
on the factory store it would probably
come with the same data that you had
posted right yes I'm just trying to
connect all of us together so robots in
Cisco I'm not sure really the answer I
overthought was in the factory store is
just the default configuration where the
device comes up so if you just power on
for the very first time
that's the configuration you get that
gets written to start off or running
where as surely the capabilities data is
just about what functionality the device
can do protocol enabler features you can
have different
[Music]
I don't know username and password is
right for the config server I was burned
in at the at the manufacturing plant
that's the factory data store yeah right
but this doesn't state that you have to
document the full factory before setting
the default config in this format this
gives you a way to do that but it
doesn't prescribe you this is this
really is way to document things not the
prescription what the document okay a
clarifying question where's this factory
store published difference is that's
from the box that's from the device well
this isn't what he's talking about is
not this can't get in separate
documentation or through yankov catalog
or some other place and it's your place
I understand that now is just trying to
figure out that what the contents of
what that file would look like this
doesn't prescribe the contents in any
way even the shreds removed not so well
but since Cisco so I just have one on
the common that the capabilities
inflation itself I don't think you get
interoperability if you just say you
need to publish this data needs to find
one level of what that looks like that
you otherwise just saying everyone
should do this I'm not sure how that
helps the world alone I think as an
example if I would get a set of
supported or modules for every network
build I'm getting that would help me yes
yes generally is a bit loose term I
agree so I think it needs definition of
these definition of needs to be yeah
model defines what this capabilities
data looks like what does it contain
how do vendors extend it because
otherwise it's just I get some random
beta you should provide some random beta
that in some format I'm not sure that
that helps friend them because you can
immediately check which modules there
are and
if you find you the one you need them
you might enjoy them
you might return modules you need them
we might return something else unless
you define it I would chairs now or
later on the mailing list the second
question would you support some kind of
trials defining what's the capabilities
means and ITF young libraries the first
thing that comes to mind so from what
from a church standpoint it is okay to
have a shirt that says that you
implement a ssin should do a behavior
like report some information but not the
in many places and that could be a
reference so you could do that I think
this is both chair house contributor and
contributor if if you follow what our
rob saying is Rob sighs if you never
sure you have to find what that instance
data is so if you know I think if you
want to try to keep this you're gonna
have to define what the format is that
you want to publish you don't
necessarily have to format and publish I
include the transport in this document
you can have that elsewhere but you
least have to say what the information
is that you're publishing such a
separate draft about this that we see
what other comments are and ancillary
iodine's Kent from Jim for networks is
following up on ten carries question I
think there's quite a difference between
this and the factory data store effort
the factory data search and capture the
configuration that we're going to start
up we said well idea this is primarily
capturing well with being library and
young library is purely an up
my data store so it's not actually even
wouldn't be found inside the factory but
it's more for example we already use
this for defining a predefined access
control rose Angeles which is quite a
big work to do and it's good to help and
that's configuration you could also use
this for documenting that that's factory
default comes up with one internet
interface configure to whatever so it's
really free of use but yes you're right
that much of this will be about state
data read-only data so it's more a
superset and yes Adrian Farrell at the
moment this seems a little bit of an
apple-pie draft so it's telling people
to do stuff that yeah good idea to do
sensible to do that I'm still waiting
for the meat yeah I met but what I
actually wanted to ask you is do you
aware of the observer work on mud okay
so at the moment there's no overlap but
I see the trajectories overlap in some
time in the future so mud is talking
about advertising what what a device is
and what its network requirements are
whether a sentence that says and in the
future we will add a description of more
things that the device or the server
what other can do and I see this as
possibly intersecting somewhere two
years in the future or three years so
take a look at that and talk to those
guys so that we will end up with only
one way of doing things
yeah we've never ever had in this
organization I think it's a good
proposal and I'll try to follow up on
the other hand this is something that's
already happening
so that's it the mud working group
before I'm gonna wear it synopsis AWG
manufacturer uses description that's
just a separate document and that was a
mess already
I don't remember the form of these shoes
but I will have a look at it so as to
whether we asked question this is an
individual draft so it's okay so you
should feel free to ask questions in the
regular off hands providing data for
which version of that but at this point
because using rotations is far too
strict like and here it would be
problematic if the versioning we should
reuse that but I don't see using
radiation Bates as a viable solution
because most of the times instance data
doesn't change when you make a small
addition to your module that's
potentially what I see is maybe a list
of modules and revisions that that is
usable with this instance data set
okay know by your favorite question
chair sense maybe that document what is
the use case and the proposed use case
for yang they taxed any data that is not
part of the yang data store or some
small set yes anyway that was not part
of a data store on the event without
yang data
extension it just defined some schema so
if an offer of a server for whatever
reason decides to implement it I don't
see anything wrong so right so it's and
the practical consequences of doing so
of course are true first you cannot use
tools for processing this yeah and what
yoga do for this extension and I suspect
this is why you didn't include Eska tree
of this module in your document because
you can you cannot print it with pay
angle whatever and second consequence is
is that you have to have a normative
reference to this yang beta extension in
this draft so this may of course delay
its obligation I suspect probably it'll
be enough to reference the rest I would
really suggest to do it right without I
don't see any problem with that
if it's not implemented it's not
implemented but the skin is particular
from that you can process it in any way
you want and I just don't see any reason
for doing it here don't true I don't
really care I just want consensus on
this for him you can ask the good
[Music]
they thinks it's a good idea
can you repeat that question
didn't you want describe to use yang
data to to capture structure it was
against using yang extensions in this
draft so you should report your using
Yang was a good result is too few number
you know somewhere there on the first
one and one or very few on the second
then they honest things and they'll try
to just keep in mind this is a
individual draft so you
do whatever you want independent of the
working group and the working group you
try meandering adoption yes Joe Clark
Cisco at the risk of upsetting lotta the
young gate extension so you cannot
define or the metadata that one might
want to your instance data so some
solution to augmenting to be able to say
I want to add or define this metadata I
think we need for something for that so
that would be a use case for the other
the first session that shall we have a
data store parameter following an MVA
that which data store is this is the
beta instance data defined here relevant
for but I didn't seem to understand the
use case for it because yes if it's good
the data is perfect for us then it will
always belong to the operational if it's
conflict true then it belongs to either
also the low draft doesn't really wants
to say anything about how this file is
used so some servers might use it to
preload the data command or something
like that some might use it just what
documentation
some might populate it from software
internally so generally we don't want to
say any anything prescriptive about how
this is used so I would not put in this
parameter about datastore robots in
Cisco and so I think if the dates
approach was included it'd be an
optional thing so you could include it
was useful even have to populate where
it is I think it was to be defined so I
remember guys when it's mandatory it
might be places where as useful
outside I'm not sure the estate below in
terms of it being confiscated once
operatio and convict true bronze mine
calculate is that is that can actually
work isn't this just data coming out of
a datastore so you have a schema node
that's being this conflict really it's
the data commander a chanel you don't
want to interpret half that data's being
configuration half of being racial
states the whole Lots company's
operational states so I think you least
need a flag to say is this configuration
data or is this state data I think the
said stated already in their target data
modules and I really don't want to say
more about it because this one I wrote
here about running candidate and
operation I would say that that's a big
to use case might use it differently
okay so give a concrete example say you
had a list of interfaces that's the data
you're returning in nmda those nodes are
config true so you're saying that by
definition those list of interfaces have
to be configuration because the scheme
Association is title true
whereas they might be in spaces that
just instantiate in the system haven't
been configured so I I think you need
some more indication as to what the data
is the point is that there are so many
ways to use this operation because I
don't prescribe that this is use loaded
into configuration either today I don't
prescribe that it's not loaded so what
does it mean if I put their operation
it's just providing context to allow
some who's interpreting the data to
understand what it means I mean does
this mean configuring you're saying
automatically that will mean
configuration because it's because those
nodes are defined in the scheme was
conflict true but but a half the data in
operations could be defined as conflict
true and you're now saying actually all
that data is not state data that's all
configuration data because it's
convict reunites doesn't make sense to
me interfaces up in nmda says they are
both configuration and state data and
that's true of old conflict rune oh yes
in MEA all have this duality that they
wrote they represent both configuration
and their operational state value so
good you could write the short
description what does it mean what is
the difference to anyone if I ride this
sis as I need to face this operation
he's suggesting that it's good context
if you don't use it ok I can put it
there but please help you with the
description statement a few times it
seems like we're mixing some concepts
which are really the data representation
focused on build a representation and
then other concepts items that are
focused on how we are moving that
representation or restoring that
representation and just like we have the
separation between that mod and Netcom
for people to keep that separation in
this work so information related or
description related to how you're
representing the data I think it's good
to have a draft and how you are moving
it around or storing I would say this is
about our discussion there seems to be
police saying just keep it in mind when
again it's an individual document so you
control the content anyway so there was
another question that do the current
draft says that you have one instance
data set in bonds five
being one year module in once fired
practically every time should we allow
multiple instance data sets in single
file
I think it's not important that it's
makes the world a bit more complicated
yeah it could be done the next one was
do we need to create tags like we have
code begins and code ends today for
hearing modules and for other things
should we if we would use such X
examples for instance data begins and
instance data ends in a draft or an RFC
I would save no because this would be
typically used for examples in drafts
and even for the end modules we don't
use the code begin and code and tags and
we are pulling the examples we might not
need the record about the instance data
set its name its revision and contact
information so proposal is not to have
them okay there was a question of the
instance data itself there is because I
[Music]
say also collecting this 12 so first 24
can specify well file with the other
confirmations and he repeated only one
job so I thought you told people whole
data store everything
you can different factory default file
you can I have one more comment draft
draft also says that if this data is
stored in the file then the file name
should encode the version I think this
is a really bad practice probably these
files will often be stored in some kind
of version management system I get and
for such systems this file name scheme
is next to unusable because a relevation
you have to do something so we can just
committed a cities and given that this
data are stored as metadata inside the
file it shouldn't be needed to use the
file name for encoding and information
so I would suggest maybe two if this
prescription completely just the ferric
for nine can be and I think it's not so
important in my view of course I think
your problem is real and we faced it as
well that and 95% of the cases we don't
use their graduation date in language
modules either in some cases it is good
and if in some case it is good that the
tools will allow it
I thought following the yank breakfast
maybe we were and adding comments about
version control would be good but is
that ok materials right ok then I read
know that usually avoid because of
Russian control problems so how I see it
[Music]
now wait until the address is so few how
many would like to see an update based
on the discussion today and then
proceeding less that's definitely less
well notice that was actually a trick
question
how many would object to adopting this
this work so that's consistent with the
poll from the last meeting of people are
interested in this world like the
supersede it sounds right the general
sense of the room which is in sets of
those who responded which isn't a huge
number they like to see now so what I
find the chairs and go from there
[Music]
we use is consolidated job that's a
basis to ensure that it's cutting the
strands apart and the change we made
actually compared with the previous
vision actually we define the 14
structures such as rather structure only
structure and why not with them include
the photo structure yeah there'll be a
shoe everybody's container and we also
have sculptor actually put on
appendix and we have the additional
cancer and remove the top pastor based
on the Menenius that it's cause she and
we somehow it's constant on the lister
we won't you will pop back to of the
issue actually we have to obey issue
that first alliance of altering
invasions apartment the second one is
the extraction supporter for the first
open usual we have discussed stories or
in the second issue we already have
discussed on the list issue right on the
current dropping nine fourteen or
wrapping and so for this ovation the
code is actually we add the in the
vision support than in the true unity
and right now these indentations fisher
can apply to such as jason expels spirit
we use the toolspace upset so just like
Aziz example before the forty might have
you know so there's no mystery here now
after floating they actually we can
reduce speeds are the Nona in two to
nine independent second in line with two
space from the left so the benefit to
take this powder is this because we use
Bacchus last year to speed on mine so
this kind of backslash placement can be
the fixed or verbal and so this actually
has been discussed on the list and we
sing the
so to to do this actually annotation is
this kind of protein is northern
conditions and also an online can be for
any remarkable times next the first the
first ball actually we actually just a
supporter the writing division PI
similar to the natural indentation the
benefit is same as a conventional also
we
[Music]
Lantry a part where the foldings
tree because i think that some other
proposals here aimed making those
readable and close to have people would
naturally probably writing dint of apt
that belief or something
this is so strict approach to how it's
been done sir but may be more useful
examples here I think what you've got
then it's failed to do the others a gun
it's understand things classically
actually got up when you said the word
examples so I'm co-author of this and
I've been a little bit of sleep at the
Lord for the last few words but in my
opening my editor I've got a pile and
examples that I want to drop into the
draft I'm not sure that those examples
help resolve that question that Chuy's
are asking about the different options
but my concern is not just Auto full
fold in which I think was where Kent was
coming from as I write my drafts in XML
and handcrafted XML work my father's
father did and when I do that I sort of
automatically insert the indentation
spacing that I like to see although I
want to create in the output text file
and therefore the only floater has to
suppose that and I think that but
whichever option we choose for the auto
for whatever we've got a support the
manual profiting so um because in terms
of these examples you hear backs
proposal three that's the one I put
forward so the suggestion here I
definitely fear this example what's been
shown but the idea is having mark on
both lines at the end of the first line
and we're on the second line and then
you just rip everything between those
two to even example its right to the
left and it doesn't make any difference
from so proposal zero we also have
option here of right indent in that
second line wherever you like and you
know you can strip all that space in
between whereas if you have one of the
cases where and you're not using fixed
amount what happens when you to a
splitter or whitespace point then then
how do you do that so I think one that's
floating doesn't work unless you're some
way of denoting where it finishes
we discussed this draft in the transport
on be our design team where we are
developing a lot of JSON code and we
found it's very useful and the one
comment I got from the members of one
team is that they will have to prefer to
see the folding being done at the end of
the world rather than in the middle of
the word for readability it will be much
more readable if you fold again when you
have a space rather than just in the
middle of the line if that is possible
will be a good announcement and thank
you extraction so based on the many
discounting we actually proposed a 44
name actually so we know that means we
need to extend a scope for this document
Thank You Ethel I think if you can about
destruction will be much better for a
game for a user perspective because you
can't act the document there you can get
the document is a good idea so some of
the here what especially the artwork it
has in it is right applicable thank you
it is rather workable then just within
this working group and then maybe moving
into the ops area working group would be
a better place to do it then in just
hearing the worker group because it's a
smaller audience countess
I was having coffee yesterday with hello
friend in our CEO and I mentioned bust
draft and she mailed the recommendation
to reach out to see because ideally the
would be for the intimate tool for
thinking being that only text-based
presentation format needs to be in
photos if the presentation format is
HTML or something else and world would
not want to for it to be folded and and
similarly for extraction purposes if
it's for instance the XML format you
don't need to have any tags for do an
extraction they've already already
inside tags so perhaps it's a
dimensional speak it's an another issue
or something think about the let's maybe
reach out to connect in the tools team
and see how we could what we can do to
facilitate teacher integration of his
work speaking with with definite
contributor but another hat not sure
which had I think we should decide what
we want to be done and then asked
willing to do it I don't think we should
be constrained by what the tooling is
today the tools are generally changeable
let's figure out what the right answer
is and then also figure out where we
documented whether it be a standalone
document or this document or somewhere
else but I would strongly encourage not
talking to the tools team until we know
what we want to do the hydrent so sedan
was just mentioned in artwork and I
think there's a bit of a confused
history because when we used to document
sort of fragments of young as examples
we tended to put them inside the artwork
to know pragmas to stop them getting
reformatted
so our work was in our head but this
document actually recommends against
using rappin on conventional artwork in
their pictures of networks and things I
think we should go more strongly again
do not use this for if you didn't ask
the art and you can't fit it in in the
168 columns then reckon it is just going
to make it worse
so you're saying interpret that as
rapping long lines in the egg models or
sure go for it
rapping long lines in artwork fix your
artwork yeah and then goes to the
question where should this what happen
if we collapse back to just the amend
examples then that lives here in my
opinion if we were to put artwork here
man it probably comes out it's not even
up so it's just it's global right so
that's an I would be an RFC editor
discussion then or RFC format discussion
excuse me not editors yeah just to
follow up on that the draft says in
Section four point one it is not
recommended to use this solution for
graphical our work and give me you think
[Music]
they want to at that point or continue
as individual
[Music]
okay but at the time so to put the son
of the stripes together
[Music]
so away
Cantus sure I'd like to get the working
groups opinion interest level in this
work if you interested please raise your
hand it's a reason remember and if
you're not interested in this work
please raise your hand
[Music]
because from Andy Berman says support
the problem not at all the solution
[Music]
[Laughter]
because I thought we talked about this
last time we get I think it's I go with
Andy and in the sense we know we have
the problem but I think between here and
there was a finite state there was a
couple of ways of doing this that that
we were still trying to figure out and
then there was some direction from 101
that said hey you guys get together and
see if we can come in with with a decent
solution or not I don't know if that
happened I yeah we actually had to get
there and ask that exact question so
I'll be interested in hearing me
author's responses you know did you take
can you talk to the author of the next
draft FSM draft yeah so is just take a
look at the FSM draft and see if well so
at high level 20
[Music]
Jabar yeah you go ahead okay thanks
so from from jabber you're gonna ask the
question is does the working group have
the resources to work on things other
things we take on say that what's a I
think a chair question as chair my views
or contribution driven so if people
bring things to the working group and
the working group is interested in
expending energy there that's that's
what we take on and of course I've
cooked
yeah Joey not speaking as a chair
I think election would and I think they
were a little weird for us to progress
this one and the one that comes behind
it like they sort of seem related to
each other sufficiently that like
mmm-hmm it looks like a working group
where the working group participants are
exploring the problem and solution space
and like there's probably a synthesis of
all the work that's being done around
this that comes out of that great I'm
not sure that that's a particular
document the idea of working in this
space seems appropriate
but I'm not sure either this document or
the subsequent one are necessarily like
the place that we should be when we get
to adopting something mmm and I say that
as a contributor and or as a idiot and
the working group and not as someone
with a great deal of experience or with
respect to channeling the chairs opinion
I'll basically say plus one with chair
hat on unless we understand there's two
problems here
we shouldn't be progressing to got to
two documents that seem to cover that's
the same solution space my reading of it
is personal as chaired personal is that
this one seems a little more generic but
it's still a little hard to figure out
whether that's it the right read so I
think you know I think your comment if
there's more discretion and feedback is
just right you really gotta spend some
more time with this other document
figuring out where there's overlap or
there's not and if you think there's not
overlap it would be good to clearly
identify what probable miss document is
solving that and the next author who
needs to figure out what problem
different problem we're addressing but I
don't see two documents going forward
right now it's those anguish with
whatever hat he was saying and Kent is
co-chair plus one Tibet as well we
should look to see how and also
regarding question I understand that
what contribution driven I'm suppose
there's interest the contribution that's
Anna Freud but also dozen sometimes
there's no notion of prioritization you
know holistically like many different
things independently but holistically
then there's something from others I
mean it's not really unique to this
working group but I think every working
group so perhaps others with more
experience or 80s could how do other
work in groups address this problem I'm
not sure we want to have a working group
philosophy discussions
right here I mean I've been in other
working groups where basically it's you
know as more contributions come in and
you actually can do more work because
there's now more people able to work in
parallel so manure --xx out okay and
that and the workload can dramatically
increase that doesn't always work so we
have to figure out what's right for this
group but you know generally our
processes is being driven by
contributions not chair not we're sort
of well thought them up and top down so
of course the ad can chime in if they if
you'd like it was known as that you
asked so these two documents seem to be
focusing more on the actual problem
space of usability than on the paradigms
themselves and for someone original
reversing opps awgn came here because
the feeling that was that it is generic
enough to be used as a generic mechanism
for modeling the state machines I don't
have a strong feeling whether this
should be done here or in some other
working group but one question that I
would like to have an answer is whether
this is an experiment to do something or
whatever actually uses for both of these
documents - the second one I think the
author just said that there's an
implementation we have other
applications there's a slight difference
between having an implementation and
having he use for that great when you do
have an implementation I bet we'll have
a state machine
so like I think that's part of the
reason I see like synthesis as a
potential route forward with this
because that's something that happens as
you get closer to having that
[Music]
progressing and very interested in any
conversations you have the next
presenter so we're going to try to our
note presentation here hi can you can
you hear me we did we hear you yeah good
good hi good morning so yes this tough
present
a young model for a defeated state for a
finished state machine please the the
next slide so the objective of this
draft is to increase the programmability
of network elements so for frame we
denta fide some use cases one is brain
struct data play advices of an optical
network for example does optical
transponders two about configuration
settings in case of physical layer
changes so for example in case of
physical layer
definitions the objective to install
this phoenix state machine in the agent
of the transponder to that something
happens
the transponder the agent already
knows what to do and it can apply the
reconfiguration settings so based on the
physical conditions though the proper
washing formats the coding and so on
another useful is related network
telemetry and another one with that we
identified is related to to the
monitoring of of packet loss so
regarding a quest question related to
the previous to the previous talk about
the implementation we implement ich
finished and tested in lab and also in a
field trial at Telecom Italia for what
concerns the first use case so there a
configuration of the of the of the
transponders in in an optical network so
the v trial was successful and the
transponder was able to automatically
reconfigure without acquiring or asking
something through the to the Sdn
controller because it was a prayer
instantly so we next next slide please
so this slide describes the first use
case so while the connection is is
active and Sdn controller can instruct
by installing the the finished state
machine into the agent of the data plane
devices so if something happened changes
at the physical layer the data plane
already knows what to do and the
reaction can be can be faster the second
case next slide please
the second use case if work at telemetry
here the the objective is to reduce
telemetry bandwidth on demand data
collection so in this case we we can see
network probes as as a phoenix state can
be described that word probes as a
phoenix state machine so based on the
state we we send data stream Telemachus
team to to the network telemetry
applications so we can optimize the
bandwidth drop of the telemetry state
the third use case next slide please
is related to I think performance
measurements so here we the the scenario
is that is an SDN controller application
for performance measurement the idea is
that we can calibrate a deep go through
the monitoring data so we we consider
here across the clustering approach so
the network can be divided in clusters
in regions so more or less deep into to
the network and we can retrieve
monitoring performance measurement
related to each cluster here the
finished state machine can be it can be
can be used and particles can be
associated to a specific class their
division next item
so here we go to the young model
the young model is a list of states so
for example regarding the transponder
the keys of the transponder each state
can correspond to two specific settings
of setting of the transmission parameter
of a transponder and to each state a
list of transmission is associated to
each state and we can go from a state to
another state when something that change
so for example in the case of the
optical network one deteriorate increase
we can see some attitude for example a
filter attribute can be used to to to
describe more more deeply the transition
for example to put threshold enough in
the bit error rate increase then each
transition is associated to a list of
actions that for the case of the
transponder could could be the change of
the modulation format and the change of
the code rate and and so on so this list
of action we have not execute that when
whether that actually implement
implements change the actual and then we
can go to a next action and finally to a
next state so this this young model has
been described more into the detail in
key details in C kampfgruppe for the use
case of of the transponder so more
details can be found in in in another
draft of the C camp
next slide please well in summary we
describe the finished state machine with
respect previous previous version of the
draft which was presented in London we
clarified here in this new version some
we put some clarifications about the use
cases well and then and that's it we
would like to to ask for for the
adoption definitely thanks
so I think we will action points got off
for until simple February is the last
draft we will go to hear the discussion
that went on I'm sorry did you hear the
discussion what took closed well over to
the previous draft yeah yeah I had the
discussion about well I have two two
impressions my face is my first
impression is that this draft is more is
more generic than than the than the
other one and then I have another
impression but I'm not sure about this I
have to better understand the other
draft maybe we can have an offline
discussion with the other authors but my
impression is that their draft is more
associated to to central control while
here the objective is to give a sort of
intelligence to to the a to the agent
- okay we could you okay fine fine - so
that's great thank you thank you so much
[Music]
so can't we clearly yes we do your stars
are still coming out okay hear me
clearly
yes go ahead
please proceed so I can do this work is
because if we reviews our health system
young module page now it again covers
some basic function those are as users
as notation but it's a lick of feature
of some punctures to support as a user
authorization accounting and also the
current system young model not a
supported caucus process server so we
propose this young motor to address
these issues and also I know a lot of
window has employment attacks passed in
their device
so and they also we have say average
under the module so I think it may be an
issue should be discuss it may be issued
a defined some standard module to
support it as an artist past so we
propose this document between introduced
and took us long model and
all the presents so solution we augment
eyes have sister modulation Takas
Archbold and here is an Tucker's
template system has been used to
configure as such of trance over New
South Wales out the phantom in an HTML
meta file in change our user list in the
Indus in user domain if Toscana received
a pass from user and as a Turkish
template can be slighted to at least on
the Dumon so is a can carry the recent
murders and I also talked us so well me
straight
attribution from email list and a lot of
wearable Commons and we also discussed
with him maybe a way to like to prepares
another version to address this issue
but always seems it needs just world is
in ordained you to do because it already
have a lot of wind you have implement as
I talk across and so standard and yon
document a super user writable work
Joyce I didn't make it to UPS AWG right
is there an attempt to discuss that
there since the tac-x work is also being
done to the yes we add some new security
functions to sort and remove some
obsolescent features of tac-x so sort of
the notion of what a drafts the
historical implementation of taxes and
maybe some drafts that but i see the ad
who's also responsible for that working
group actually standing behind me so I'm
gonna let him speak jokes are playing
I'd say WG co-chair had so yes as was
brought up we mentioned it
in say WG we didn't have an agenda slack
for it I agree that drove everything you
said essentially we are trying to
document how tax is implemented today in
the industry and get vendors who've
implemented clients and servers to
feedback into that we are not looking to
add more to that draft but it seems that
this work might fit in that working
group and certainly as you said Joe as
additional drafts come out to change or
to add features specifically around
security to tax if there is to be a
model to configure it that that work
would have to fold into this donors to
give a perspective of the tax work the
current work is to document what is
there not to work on the additional
features and other things well this
needs to be finalized at tactics is
widely deployed and that's how commodity
service so from a perspective of that it
is used yes certainly a model for that
seems to be needed one concern that I
will have is that it's not only the
tactics it's also the radius which is
frequently used for similar things and
if we look from a system perspective
those two protocols can be selected by
the choice of the deployment of a basic
would buy it by the user so maybe it
would be a good idea to try to work a
little bit on the overall external
authentication authorization system
framework and then have tactics and
radius put into that it's not a hard
suggestion but that's from a from a
practical usability perspective that
might seem a reasonable thing to do as
of where the work could happen as the
protocol work is happening in ops AWG
logical that the model work might be a
good home for that why we
applauds they start opening to the
molding because we think it see arts and
some function awesome attribute should
be in she should she because I was I'd
have sister motive way since it can
argument I'm extensions a sister might
have sister module and to cover some
attribute or some feature not currently
not covers just why we want you avoid
white why way synthesis drafted to
current what improvements so also i
certain that this is a strong argument
certainly the protocol models cannot
mend some of elements if they need the
chairs agree with the comment baby's
coming okay thank you
also I think that they you're talking
about is that the common framework makes
a lot of sense
would you think that the common
framework still belongs over there but
I'm happy with either answer actually I
probably think that the common framework
might be better tied to the actual
protocols so what's your recommendation
you guys can have questions because if
we are looking at the practical system
how that user's authentication sources
it's not only tactics and radios the
mind the local store there might be
something else and if we look this way
it quite quickly gets into the napkin
keystore topics it gets into other key
store topics I don't have an answer for
that right now but if we look from the
user perspective suddenly flooding
different mechanisms for using similar
functionality is not the right thing
maybe some thinking it needs to happen
around with the office and and both from
another key store side though from a
tactic side probably involved IPSec
model office and see whether this
commonality that Joey way as a chair at
this point like if there were extensions
to tax that were to come in the other
model I would think that would possibly
be inappropriate and dangerous at this
point since we're still working on
documenting tac-x itself
on but like those extensions would
definitely be this is the sort of thing
that ops AWG would be looking at in
light of the fact that they actually
sort of owned the progressing of of
tackett's itself so I wouldn't want to I
wouldn't want to see those come in
through the model without having
treatment somewhere else also if you
could spend a left a little time
[Music]
phobar big mass is referring to and come
back with a proposal that would be very
useful and then from where we can figure
out which working group of Iran's own
but clearly the tax specific work does
not belong here okay so maybe as as
there is no system authentication maybe
there needs to be more global loans for
system authorization and system
accounting and from those ties to the
protocol specific amounts I'm not
suggesting with this I'm just asking a
question okay okay thank you thank you
very much thank you I think we've
managed to fill up the whole time so the
session we finished the session thank
you for staying here to the last day and
we will see you in Bangkok and if you
ever sign a blue sheet please start
coming up here I have one and there
should be another one somewhere
you