[Music]
no no we can't even discuss tonight I
mean and it's not that I am I am a
strong advocate for that
[Music]
sorry
well first of all my my apologies first
a team late I was taking it easy because
I was sure we had to start at 3:00 3:30
no 3:30 so I was just living time pass
so well this is this is an effigy just
welcome note well adapted to the iot of
conditions right these are the usual
call for document review and about the
site the list the group etc things we
have we have Pedro taking notes a second
note-taker that connects to the etherpad
will be really really really appreciated
so we have and we have evangelist
somewhere they are acting as a
JavaScript
well the usual research related events
whenever do you know about anything just
tell run key or myself
happy to help and if you come and soon
that the gaps draft the one that was
went through last call inside the group
is the under I've RTF cherish revision
and she
according to she has notes she will be
the dang ready to to be sent to 22 the
IAS G for conflict review there was an
interim meeting on model driven
optimization dissipation remote
participation but just in case you have
the report and the presentations in that
link
and well there is a proposal that will
discuss to specifically consider natural
slicing among the group work items I
know that comes discounts were after
some bhavam or neutral slicing pieces it
was which with the results that were so
how not very much welcomed by parts of
the communities so well let's see what
happen after the presentations today
many of them two-thirds of them with
their net worth nothing and well
something that we should have to address
later on in the day but on the list that
sat there is about they concrete meat
matters is something whether a
particular aspects be is beliefs that
belongs to the discussions on the
discussion of the any fear G group and
the other the other point is about
whether metal slicing in general should
we have a specific item for any future
well no more this is the the agenda we
start with these reflections and making
one of the proposed drafts on intent and
how this connects with the negotiation
frameworks then we were talking about
discovery mechanisms and then the rest
is there other for presentations that
will be I hope brief enough just to
cover less than one hour on metal
slicing as charged you're really looking
for more trafficking in the list
especially for the model driven
optimization it was a lot of interest in
discussions the interim meeting but
you're hoping there are more discussions
of the list but it quieten down so we're
really allowed to see more you know
discussions yeah
okay so let's add better adored the next
one I hope everything will go well so hi
good morning this a an update on the
work I've been doing on recursive energy
definition it works so since the last
idea but what I did was corrected minor
typos thanks for the thanks for the
pointers and it was requested I added a
section on operational experience which
I'm going to be elaborating a bit of
right now in this talk
so there's a based on real-life
experience we have a project called
mommy there you see the log of that
project in the upper corner and on that
we have we are doing NFB stuff as a way
of experimenting on middleboxes
and it's in that environment that I've
been doing quite a lot of stuff so the
network service I base this thing upon
is a bunch of enemies of energy seas
that help us characterizing VIP
performance of 5g enabled networks
what have I touched okay so we have two
V two components that are based on topic
which is a traffic generator and we're
just actually wrapping on on top of our
three then I have a daughter base to
feed data from the measurements and
that's based on it looks DB and then I
have a traffic sniffer that is based on
aunty shark so in the nice thing about
this environment is that depending on
what you want to do if you have the
Midianites the traffic leontief's what
you're going to have is add whatever you
need for you
particular environment so we start with
something like this you have a client
and a server and the network you're
testing there and then it can go to well
of course better if you also have the
database to collect your measurements
because afterwards really the data from
the influx TV match very well into
anything any kind of reboot you want
today can be even better you can also
mix in a t-shirt a Wireshark a traffic
safer and you can instead of getting the
results from the measurements or you get
from traffic you can also go and go
directly into the packets and analyze
the packets to see your things and to
make things complete you can also have
everything you have for possible
network services which are if you look
at them they are incremental based on
the on the network service you have
there at yet at the top right from your
site so main problem is a i/o these
things if you go in your system and you
want to do it using the using the the
mono stock you have will be normally
written in yellow however the experience
I'm showing here is that's much better
to have everything written in with Nemo
it's like this question of yeah and in
the 80s of the last century it was still
part of the cool stuff to write
assembler but it's a this you started to
have other wonderful high level programs
to do real programming so in this
version of the draft one of the things
I'm showing is how to use Nemo to build
things incrementally incremental Yama is
sort of complex because you have to put
many different little lines in very
specific parts of your network service
the scripture while on Yahoo if you do
it incrementally with Nemo and take what
you already have and put things on top
of that I should hey there's a small
there are a couple of examples of this
in the draft and since it is what you
have is not touched and what you put new
comes incremental into it and it's a
high level language that you can really
read and you don't have to worry about
having the right indentation less things
can go wrong so another goodie while
working on this we had another goodie
and Mo for those who recall Priya where
previous versions of the raft have two
things one is the node models and the
other things the link models where the
node models are used to express the
virtual network function components and
with the link models you can express
things like the the network service
graph so you have something like this
you know in this case that is the
universe sniffing when you put the
sniffer and we've been starting to see
that non infrastructure support things
like are starting to support things like
tabs as a service for example in
OpenStack so you can you could actually
extend even the link model we currently
we have point-to-point and for some pay
and Elon or villain you can go and add a
third link model that implements this
tapas of service in order to do this
instead of having to write lots of
things and putting in a hopper outside
the network to do the sniffing so this
is something that is already available
in OpenStack so one of the things that's
currently being part of the
work is once the mono we are using which
is OSM has a notion of this at opposite
service plug-in in in OpenStack we are
going to be having the link below the
specific link model that implements
sniffing so conclusion it's a sixth
round of the draft we have included all
the corrections from previous critical
readings and I want to thank again here
all the people that took the time read
the previous versions of the draft and
sent comments included the operational
experience as requested in London so
just a question and request I think we
should move this forward and have it
part of adoption aisle so I would ask
for research group adoption of this prop
as it is now and that's it thank you so
that's time for questions and comments
this is very interesting especially the
modeling aspect so one thing you may
want to take a look there is some work
happening around networks of East Nash
you know it's trying to abstract sort of
the reference different physical I mean
basically hardware representations for
example you have InfiniBand or you could
you know different types of transport
right so rather than right now the
approaches the exposed ethical
interference network functions and you
exactly they're all synonymous to the
hardware implementation
instead network service nash is looking
to abstract those so here in a more
developer-friendly way it's something
perhaps we can take a look into anything
of course the only thing is that this
link right now if you go it only has
point-to-point and lan which is everyone
with everyone so it's already
abstracting whether that is a via clan
or
or an OVS or whatever so I think this is
already there the only thing is when it
really makes sense to have a new link
modulus for things like this sniffing
which where you actually have a tap as a
service which is neither early an eland
nor a point to a point or we are doing
this from the very high level already so
I think it's it's already there maybe we
should synchronize the word this and the
other okay yes yeah thanks okay thanks
okay Somalia on the eruption move on the
list okay thank you so Carlos yeah
let me try to see how I so now like
these no okay
thank you my name is Karla Bernardo from
uc3m and I'm gonna present some insights
about discovery mechanisms in the HC and
every manner stack so they are here to
basically present in the problem and
then I will basically also present a one
example of solution that we have been
working on but this just for the sake of
presenting an example MN ABS to present
a problem and see whether there is
interest in the room for this for
working in this kind of of issues so
this is the outline of my presentation
so first very brief motivation of why we
need discovery mechanisms and why what
we are why what I understand by
discovery mechanisms in the HC energy
mono stack then we will basically try to
identify in the monastic where we need
this discovery mechanisms there are like
three four reference points there that
are identified by HC that require is
kind of despair American instance and
then I am just publishing one of them
there VI were exact in the one that is
relevant for economists and I thought we
are a duty three and particularly
working on and I will present an example
of solution based on ipv6 but this yes
an example as I mentioned before
understand conclusions next steps so
motivation I always like to try to use a
deal worse trip for this kind of
motivation I think this is clear it's in
a V or NFV it's no longer something that
will happen in the future network
function but it is something that is
happening today already but it's also
true that today is something that is
mostly limited to data center
environment so on by data center
environments in the scope of four day in
this talk Bay
before I highlight the characteristics
there is a semi static environment where
all the entities that are there are
pre-configured and all the entities that
are involved already know the other
entities that they will interact with
but this is not the only scenario that
we we can consider one before I go into
other scenarios this is an example of
what I mean by data center environments
this is a figure taken from one by paper
and is basically showing the unique
architecture a unique addition which is
from telefónica but this would apply to
many other companies where basically in
the vision that they have in how to you
know function bit recession in the
end-to-end services you have data
centers that may be centralized in local
sorry in regional data centers or closer
to the users in local point of presence
but at the end of the day they are data
centers that are very very static they
are there you have your infrastructure
basically we are talking about drugs and
infrastructure of servers put there but
this again is not the only potential
deployment environment for network
function virtualization another one is
what we call this edge for dynamic
environment basically is where we put or
we push the utilization closer to the
users in a microliter center that are in
the premises of the user or even at
mobile devices we may think of a car or
we may even think of a mobile phone as a
device that may host visualization
resources and even and it's ENFP kind of
manual stack on that and in what we
refer to the phone and then we have this
continuum from the folk at the very edge
of the network even at the end-user
devices to the centralized cloud the
typical glad that we are more familiar
with so this is scenario we have these
resources on the end devices these
devices may move may appear and
disappear so it's volatile dynamic in
those cases we really need to have
mechanisms to discover or to advertise
what are the resources that are
available so they involve entities can
know that they are there that
they can interact that they can engage
into a relationship and what are the
resources that they offer what others
was it a dark behind those entities so
there is something that has been already
identified by Etsy for some point in in
some of the specs on a knife at when in
effort on it for example for
multi-domain marine i-55 they also
discover that for example between an MPO
an Orchestrator an and a beam on the
resources these ratios it is now assumed
to be pretty known pre-established but
there may be environments where do we
need to have discovery mechanisms photos
so this is one example that we will talk
about more later trying to basically
show in the straight in a picture where
a man before buying this distribution of
for use of availability of resources at
the at the edge basically here we have a
picture where we have the data centers
and relize data centers we may have with
politician staff at the transport of
amyloid core environment so really close
to the mean closer not close closer to
the end users but we may have also
devices here that are mobile appear and
disappear where we may have big
collocation resources where we may be
running BNF and those things may host
bns may host part of the monastic and as
I mentioned mate it can appear disappear
so this is why we really need to have
discovery mechanisms because in these
environments we cannot assume that
everything knows everything in advance
and everything is pre-configured because
there are things that may appear
disappear denim so that's kind of the
motivation with a particular example
which is kind of dynamic distributed
environments the fog this is not the
only one and we'll talk a bit more later
about multi-domain which is another
environment or scenario that means this
need for discovery functions but then
let's take a look at the Etsy NFB frame
or architecture for an MV this well no
one is not the only one that we can
think of but anyway what I am gonna
present here will apply to other a
potential architecture so where do we
need discovery functions in this
architecture basically those are the
main four points where we may need
so one is between an Orchestrator and
the beam so we turn our castrator and
you know the day the resources that the
orchestrator made with my may control
these resources may not be always there
where the AVO is for example because of
this mobility stuff
this one is one point where we may need
this dysphoria mechanisms and other
ponies between orchestrators if we think
of multi domain environments like the
ones address in haifa 28 we may have
different orchestrators in both and we
may need to discovered those and not
only that they have the ability or the
presence of those orchestrators but more
importantly what is available behind
those orchestrators so what are they
function the resources that those of
pace raters manage so this is another
point will women need discovery
functions another one is between the vnf
managers and their beams so you may have
a via net manager needs to interact in
operating in what is called Eric mode
two would be friendly with different
beams so we may need to discover what
are the beams that are available and
similarly to the or bi to the interface
between the orchestrator and the beams
there is also in the context of life a
to Nate in the context was multi-domain
the interface between different beams
and then maybe also the need for for
discovering what are the beams that are
available so those are the main four
points that we consider as potential
targets for these qualifications so I
mentioned before that then a misty fog
environment is not the only use case for
having this kind of need for the scoring
mechanisms another one is multi domain
but the main is basically the idea that
we may have multiple initiative domains
where we may make them collaborate in
order to instantiate deploy and into an
service in order to do so you need to
have interaction between the
orchestrators this aura or
our interface or between beams or a
combination of both in these scenarios
let's see or identify that there are two
potential options either you have
everything pre-configured in advance
which may fit in several scenarios but
certainly nothing in all of them or you
may need to have some Alto discovery
functions to discovery what are these
orchestrators what are these functions
that are available and what are the
resources that are behind those so this
is basically what we will also focus in
in the context of this talk so we have
identified four different kind of points
where we need discovery functions not
all of them have the same requirements
because not all of them require the same
amount of information or the same type
of information or assume the same three
requirements so here we list the full of
them so basically for example the you
are who are between orchestrators theses
basically something between different
domains so here is important not only
discovering those but mainly once you
have those discovery discover so they
know that there is an Orchestrator there
are 50 total
what are the resources and the functions
that are behind those orchestrators are
controlled by those Orchestrator so if
i'ma and mr. dip domain and I want to
deploy something that I cannot deploy my
own infrastructure because for example I
don't have the graphic a footprint that
is required for that service I need to
understand if another Orchestrator is
capable of providing me that
geographical footprint that I need so I
need to have the knowledge that the
visitor is there first and then the
knowledge of worries that that
appreciator can provide me in terms of
functions that I can instantiate like
kind of a vnf as a service thing or
resources kind of na VI na VI as a
service that I can use to instantiate a
service as part of a service a time list
and with resources in my
infrastructure and in other
infrastructure so this one one one kind
of requirements in the V VI be nfm the
requirements are a bit different because
in this case these are being ephemeral
this is basically intradomain so I don't
need to have the the discovery of other
entities that are belong to different
and different domains but we need to
discover what are the beams that are
available because I may need to contact
them in order to scale
philippic allow instantiate whatever
functions on the resources managed by
those bits
the RBI we will spend more time later
but this is basically the need for this
is mainly but not only because of this
dynamic environment as I mentioned I'm a
fan Orchestrator I may have several
resources but some point in time
additional resources may appear or
disappear so I need to be able to
discover that that happen and also if
new resources appear I may need to
remain want to know what are those
resources that appear and in in case I'm
interested in inducing them in
registering with them to do so so I mean
it's not only about the scoring that
they are there but also discovering what
is available with is provided by those
bibs we will see a bit more in the next
slides and then the Vav is similar to
the RBI and basically the needs for that
is in the context of multi-domain when
you have been implementing what is
called the single logical point of
contact basically you have been
interacting with multiple babies and
traded a single interface to be to
whatever is above the nav you do you
need that beam to be able to discover
the other beams so basically similar to
the RBI kind of requirements but in the
context of between different bibs
so this basically generally where we
where do we need discovery functions and
why do we need those is Cori functions
so now let's focus on one particular
thing this is the RBI and but a sample
of solution ok again is just an example
so the generic case scenario potential
example of the scenario that we have in
mind so we have on any big platform
basically like a kind of data center
that is available there is what we have
we are used to and in the risks kind of
a static and then we have a resource
that is mobile or a device that is
mobile
maybe a car maybe something that that
since its mobile it may appear disappear
in the same network where we have the
cysteine data centers cysteine and every
platform and this device here may have
available resources for other to use and
how do we make that happen today we we
cannot do this with the system standards
because this interface is something is
pre-configure the this reference point
is used to attach
it's used to query what is available but
before doing that you need to have that
relationship in place so in order to
extend this for a more dynamic scenario
we need mechanisms that allow this an
AVL to know that this beam is available
here that there are some resources that
it can provide and how these nabo can
actually get in touch or contact with
this beam and register a bit more detail
on examples of use of this so this is
basically what I mentioned before we
have a platform a system platform here
where we have resource services deployed
that are consumed by somebody our
service at the end is consumed by by a
user identity and this platform may be
extended by using resources from other
devices that are male so that's one
particular example of applicability of
this we can also turn that around and
think of the other way or the the in
versa scenario which is where we have a
platform complete platform so the
consumer of the services on their mobile
platform and that platform may want to
use resources Attell available in in a
data center that is available where they
use the user device the mobile device
attached to so these are no direction
Oliver is sent essentially the same from
the point of view of the mechanisms that
we need and then one particular X
solution that we are working on and we
have in this draft graph this graph is
only available zero zero so the zero one
version that we plan to submit in the
next few days will include some of the
solution that I will briefly introduce
in the next slide is where we have an
ipv6 base approach a pv6 environment
where we have we assume that devices may
come may come appear and disappear as a
result of a device connecting or
disconnecting from the network and what
we propose is to basically convey
information about the availability the
system of this device and the resources
that they may have on ipv6 in that so
basically what we have here is just an
example I will not go into the details
but is basically using a go discovery to
advertise the availability of this
resource
so in case that the nab other castrated
a system platform really wants to use
those resources it can then talk to the
whim and register so basically here is
where we embed extend and nd signaling
to advertise those resources and also
the identity of the beam and then here
we can do some registration of the
between the Navy and the wind so the
beam the NAB oh then can then use the
resources that are available at the
mobile table so that's basically an
example of an idea again this is an
example and what I worry more is more
interested in is to know whether you
think that this kind of mechanisms for
auto discovery functions in general in
the Navy monastic are useful I tried to
to justify that I required not only
because of fog dynamic environments but
also in in data center environments
because of the multi domain aspects at
Siena we already in defy this but I'm
not a worry they are really working on
this kind of solution at this point but
they identify that in - Tony it for
example they put this specific test text
that I put before and whether you think
there is something that we can continue
discussing in the in this research group
thank you please don't don't look at me
yes go to the questions no not for you
[Laughter]
this means that networks so I have two
questions for this draft are you going
to be fine data model of what kind of
information is going to be discovered
introduce some existing ones and the
second is have you thought about any
security issues that may arise by some
rogue one some element that's going to
try and find out what kind of resources
exist in already systems okay so thanks
for the question the first one at this
point we are kind of
trying to reduce the data model that
sits in its energy so we're trying to
use the same thing that for somebody in
the RPI there are some there is
something define I mean if I remember
but there is for this reference point
when you clear query the resources that
are available there are some models
available there so we are basically
reusing that if we discover by further
developing this that we may need
something else yeah I mean for sample
something that we need is this thing I
mean this kind of thing is basically
taken from a cysteine and every
documents but the the point of conveying
the the URI to get to the beam
discontinue because in in let's see this
is assumed that is know in advance and
then on the second point on the security
aspects there's a definitely very valid
point in the context of multi-domain
we have already some work done in
different projects on what is required
in the context of this but but in this
multi domain stuff typically you have
some pre relationship between the actors
the stake holders so you can rely on
that in the in the context of the fog
environment is something that we need to
see because of course you need something
you cannot do whatever you cannot expose
anything to anyone you can play with
different levels of granularity you can
play with exposing something very simple
and then depending on the relationship
you have with the other one provide more
detail so these kind of things are
details that need to be work out this
increments neurons have a Leon okay I
have two questions one is you consider
discovery and you also think about the
other way around I mean to have self
advertisement of variable resources or
capabilities so that you can other
because if you do discover it's an
active process you want to discover
something so it can work in some
situations but you can also have the
reverse situation and you have
subsidizing so you know that some
resources will be available when you
want to compose them so just yeah that's
actually probably a misuse the term
discovery because you actually in the in
the draft will cover both but it's
basically based on the advertisement so
we
define some mechanisms for advertise so
do attach to the network and your
birthday resources okay and then we also
support somebody big question the other
system devices to advertise that will be
like kind of the discovery part like
okay and there you have something to
tell me tell me but is everything based
on the advertisement okay thank you and
second point is I see not so in your
presentation that you consider different
requirements of discovery for different
interfaces or different situation again
I was also in different working group or
research group that there is this we
still come back to this need of
discovering new capability in the
network and you have a proposal here to
piggyback on IP visit um but II also
considered considering it kind of
generic approach to discovery where you
have want to discover capabilities and
then you have a model to say that kind
of cut what I'm looking for what the
network or the company can advertisement
because I see the need that in some
other working group we also designing
new discovery mechanism of protocols so
if you have one for nav and one for
anima and one for others so maybe there
are some common needs and having a more
generic design we can
I mean profile some of the capabilities
or dynamically you insert what you are
looking for yeah that's a good point
definitely we need to look into that
this this specific solution came from
one a scenario that we are working on
where it fits very well but it is I
fully agree that it's good to look into
other options and try to I mean have one
single solution with different profiles
instead of having like multiple
approaches thank you very much very
interesting topic in fact of
investigating this and wound up in the
context of edge so what we realized was
as you walk to the use case especially
the mobile limbs I mean as soon as
critical as the network functions are
the applications the one which actually
drive it so sort of saying that hey I
need air we are like the low latency in
the edge and then I need this need to
capitalize on mobile infrastructure
right so that said
what gets interesting is so how do you
manage the separation of concern so for
example especially you know you have a
constrained liberal source you know few
servers then do you really partition the
resources between applications and
network functions or how do you manage
them you know and also the who's going
to manage the service like is the
application be delivered by a different
provider or is it a load by the same
operator who is also dealing in the
network savvy some interesting aspects
to think about but it's a very
interesting topic yeah thanks I am NOT
here we just focus on the the
advertisement and discovery but it's
this is something that is to be I mean
for the actual services to be employed
you need to have that gonna be the one
actually deploying so who is in charge
so for example what is the entry point
for a service to be deployed in this
case the different actors that are
involved thank you thank you very lost
so next two presentations are going to
be made by the same gentleman who's the
one who's coming yes yes I will make two
presentations one in my name but also
the next one will be in the name of a
gentleman from China Mobile who couldn't
come because of visa problems and also
just to mention that we try to organize
four separate presentation more less to
elicit some additional feedback with a V
of the newly emerging very important
metric slicing concept within the nad
environment also just remind you around
a year ago at in in Chicago at the ITF I
made a big presentation and also a lot
of discussion
vo options what are how you can fit in
network slicing in an IDF concept since
then Etsy had issues three separate
reports always saying that this is
feasible and important but also
currently all the other SDL's are
issuing reports on on this topic
recently I made a substantial effort to
bring all the information available
together with a V of network slicing in
a form of a tutorial which was presented
two weeks ago in Montreal at a top
conference on networks authorization and
the topics are there and out of this I
felt that maybe it's a good idea to
present to you a good shopping list of
potential problems to be solved not the
ones which are potentially sorted out
that's the scope of my presentation just
to start again about the main concept of
network slicing which is presented here
with many characteristics is just to say
that this is different from partitioning
the connectivity fabric or connectivity
and computing storage fabric in a form
of additional to these partitions will
be required to map services and
management characteristics into wit as a
unit so to some extent in that sense
network status is not the obits and all
good as me or even older but on the
other hand it's a new emerging the
center of attention is a way of
networking and in that sense a network
slice has to be like any type of network
self-contained isolated because I
talking out many parallel network
slicing it has to be programmed in a
sense that you cannot just leave behind
of hewing and some extent this concept
is orthogonal to the infrastructure
architecture which exists today and does
not depend on a particular technology to
they wear it as a data plane the
partitioning which is only one part of
the network slicing this issue in mind
it's obvious that there is no point to
think in terms of building new or
deploying new services by creating an
infrastructure all the time this is
inefficient and extremely expensive and
is going to change substantially
potentially due to the advent of metric
slicing impact in the industry in my
view now there are many ways to look at
the where this sort of concept could be
used and this is just a shopping list of
potential massive user scenarios I will
point out only three of them the
emerging high precision networks which
need to be created bearing in mind that
IP is not deterministic and also does
not guarantee anything so the risk
Linnaean need to understand what to
change in network functions and grouping
them and how to bring them together with
resource partitioning trust services in
order to have specific guarantees for
quality of service or KPIs and you
cannot date for all the KPIs in the
world or all the types of partition all
the issue ethic quality of service but
needs to be done per groups ie per
twelve slice and this is a key issue for
example in defining very low latency
type of network and this becoming an
important topic I don't know how you can
do it without looking at slices overall
means that to redo the whole internet
and to end but there are many other
opportunity to look at the way in which
slice it could be adding value in in
user scenarios now dimension is already
Etsy has issued different three
documents actually
mainly as a whitepaper level about how
metric slicing can fit in and this is a
diagram which basically shows that this
how this may happen is a way of grouping
network functions in addition to
resources with services in a context on
V and this is an opportunity to move
forward in a big way okay I'm just to
say that in terms of I Kiev were some
around 10 drops individual dust produced
some of them describing architecture
others which need to be looked forward
and this diagram shows one related to
the framework in ITF for Network slicing
and one related to a research project
related to how you slice cloud now I put
together along the list problem still be
dissolved eating from outside includes
around 20 some are listed here and in
the area of multi domain nav network
slicing and there are different
granularity but also some related to
other elements which need to be built
and in order to ensure that the
capabilities of network slicing in this
context are realized some related to the
the winning services and more need to be
mapped into system concept are very
importantly look at the issues related
to guarantees slices with guarantees
other quality of service of API Gertie's
or scalability we're talking about
paralyzing the network not in two or
three but many tens of thousands of
dynamic quite some years ago nav
VPN was great if now everybody's using
it it's a time to sink in systems as
well so that the question put forward is
are these problems maybe all the
reporters could be resolved partially
not all of them but some
in this what you group and your feedback
now oh good either one viewpoint which
says that people are moving away from
NAV towards nad centered around network
slices which is at the center this is a
unit of networking which need to be
highlighted for different type of
services are many around talking network
services and they have to be supported
by some sort of lightweight smart fabric
voilá coordinator yep because this
diagram shows a slightly different view
of when AV architecture shown centered
around slices which are becoming the
unit or could become the center and a
unit of any visa for maybe this will be
thinner some sorts so it's the time to
work on it boss how you manage it but
also how you bring it together in all
the aspects and that concludes my short
introduction to this topic in the slides
are plenty of other references including
maybe a hundred plus references in
academic world plus another 20 from
SDL's related to lay the slices thank ya
reserved waived from Nokia Reza Reza yes
if you go back to a slide number four
there are a couple of thing that you
know in the context of network is
slicing first thing is network is
slicing is an end-to-end concept when we
are talking about end-to-end everything
that we discussed it should be starting
from Yui all the way to application
anything else is not really into it and
in that context if you want to be
pragmatic in the picture that you put
here for example is very simplistic we
have to consider distributed run crowd
rants
the on the EPC side you know 4G 5g and
if you see this one from end to end
not all the components are vnf there is
for sure there are P n FS v NS and
depends how you want deployed you want a
mutual PPO or you want to have the
virtual see you or do you and the escape
by PK transfer and so forth so one thing
is to meet if we want to have a real
picture here that should reflect not
only Vienna but PMF as well and it shows
the concept of the end to end and I put
a picture here mainly from 80s things
that they they don't look at all these
details underneath but they should if
you want to address you know in the 5g
you have to have you know that concept
look at the bottom of this picture it's
somehow addressing your point at
end-to-end covering all the aspects yeah
is it kind of you know in implicitly
saying that but this is very important
because lots of people you know that
that will add an additional set of
problems how to create this unified
end-to-end but really end-to-end
aspects but will have to be also
pragmatic to describe the infrastructure
above which is somehow independent on
the the legs maybe I can work with you
know and because I work on this one and
we are really implement you get dry I'm
just supporting the user if you take one
of these legs do a slicer in a run then
applies to everything else no no and
these are the complexity here you know I
understand but the one thing that you
mentioned and I really agree with that
net forget so I think 5g network is
slicing is not VPN it's not LSP is not
Hana isn't much more than that and this
is whatever you imagine and this like
and one last thing I don't want to waste
time here and it's life I have you
mentioned about tenancy and this is
something that I in my opinions
overlooked the multi-tenancy that we are
talking about 5g is different from
hierarchical tenancy or aka nest the
tenancy that we have in industrial this
is something that I the you know we can
you know talk pair off line and that one
but this is something that I want to
make sure that this is address in one
way or another because some in even some
context people talk about network a
slicing whatever they talk about is
really hierarchical tenancy they you
know they did already use this word you
know the the in the different context
and wait until the next presentation
okay great so just the very point okay
right thank you in this presentation are
plenty of other information and other 20
slides which are covering but at least
anyway this presentation was prepared by
Leon
China Mobile but together with the other
people myself included but he couldn't
come to deliver it and this focuses this
presentation focuses on the issue on
architectural elements of network
slicing management which need to be
looked at in particular here
just to recap the same concept then is
that the network slice is a set of
infrastructure resources and service
functions very importantly which need to
be put together in order to serve needs
of a big industry as long as a concept
is quite far reaching now slicing is a
mekinese about creating such entities
very easily across a data plan control
plan management and service plan
together and in that sense we'll have
other players need many slice provider
and Tanner ones which could be another
operator or
another operator or another company
which takes over a slice or slice number
of slices and add their own facility to
it so it could be managed by the initial
providers facility but also they could
be managed if you want and operated use
additional tools and techniques of the
tenant so this is quite an important
demarcation now did this slide always
saying that this mechanism is quite
absolutely essential and to some extent
is more important than the way in which
has a data plane you activate partitions
because the end-to-end issue as it was
mentioned by Raisa cannot be resolved
per leg of the component of the network
which is a radio access access core edge
clouds edge clouds on their own let
alone many technologies many think there
has to be the mekinese has to be looked
at the global things in order to ensure
the usability of this concept at large
what what was this group all suggesting
that one in two important interfaces
need to be specified at length in order
to exercise the slicing mechanism at
large end-to-end one is about what is
called the service the delivering
interface which will be is easily
defined as a way to map service requests
into the the container called the slice
and to activate it and so on and that
has its own complexity for end-to-end
multi-domain situation and the second
one is around the some sort of customer
service interface which is basically an
interface to the tenant via which all
these
facility will be provided and this is
clearly needed and another way to look
at it is that they need to be mapped
into the the legs underneath which means
that the information systems and the
information usage and the win which are
provided and the control elements have
to be looked at together so together
this is like a architecture the option
to political points which need to be
resolved they are not resolved yet you
know end to end but it could be but the
Reza my desk around 10 or 20 separate
architectural networks I see in the
research literature research projects
and as the other fields too much of it
and everybody's overruling clearly it's
a time to look at the granularity which
will have that in the context of being
pragmatic I don't see that a long time
but this architecture more let's try to
map tenants and providers who's
orchestrate notice that is a system
which is n2n multi domain coordinator of
all the activities who to make that
happen
underneath industrial tendrils to my
knowledge eight separate big protests
rate has developed now open source some
of them enormous very difficult to
configure arms around and so on some are
lightweight like the one who developed
at UCL but they are need to be put in
the context of a special function are
part of the type of resources and the
information models need to be defined
properly in order to ensure that
whatever end-to-end slicing mekinese are
put in place need to be mapped into the
separate underlying data plan
infrastructure which will recovery and
this mapping is not straightforward and
may involve many options and this
information system need to be better
developed just to say that the two
interfaces identified are missing and
the information model
replaced and this is one one suggestion
for maybe this group to look at in the
future if there is an interest that
concludes this short presentation about
specific API switch our identifiers
being all important doesn't mean that
others are not but this is actually seen
as a key importance to move forward ok
razor away from Nokia in my opinion
there is another model missing here is
from the orchestrator to the network
controller and this is that connectivity
API that it is something that again it's
missing here we can you know talk
offline as well so in my opinion that is
very important aspect from NSO that you
put here to the network controller or
network model that interface is
important why it's important because it
is not there already have underlying
network resources yet you have but the
network resources today everything votes
based on service based you say I want to
create an VPN from here to here and all
the say that connectivity is one level
abstraction that then interface that I
am referring to is a connectivity API
again to be pragmatic that connection
says I want to connect a node B to ask a
tree
I wanna connect a node B - you appear it
doesn't tell you which service to use
and how to do it that layer this
basically takes that one Turner - yeah
that is something that become that yes
exactly so we can work together to you
know the clarify that but anyway we can
talk thank you when requests
besides offline they could bring their
discussions in the group will be much
appreciated and also another thing to
think about I think the presentation and
mobile bins and the discovery was very
interesting and I do think it's very
relevant to network slicing because
today if you look at slicing still
looking at more of static static
aspects it's basically assuming it
closed the static
we're trying to connect them pray but
versus the real problem is then this was
a more dynamic raid and then then how do
you create a slice in the dynamic
environment
I'm just the suggestion here is to
create slicing in a dynamic environment
both McLeod's
and in a network is not static they are
not set up for the issue is to do that
on demand and in space or clouds more or
less to have them on demand something
which was mentioned here last time as a
way to move forward
because it's not clear otherwise if you
started to configure a cloud and say I
want this thing but that's impractical
and also the multi-domain aspects are
which was mentioned also in the other
presentation are having a bearing on
this for the dilemma city of creating
parallel slices and as well as
destroying them when the lifecycle
finishes it is that challenge it is a
challenge and it's also the second
challenge is to build the system is
actually that will scale up to many many
thousands of virtual sizes if you can
there was a I understand that some of
the operators in China chief executive
officer mentioned that they want to
virtualize maybe a thousand network
functions in the next five years the
same thing here I'm suggesting that we
have to create a system which will
visualize or create these slices in tens
of thousands as a target it's not doing
it one by hand I hope that clarifies a
bigger question which is valid thank you
I know that there are two other
presentations in a row so I would like
to pass this message to the next one
which is Pedro I understand would you
cover another aspect of slicing and then
sugar will buy the another aspect of
slicing
okay I am para mantener from the inner
city I will present briefly what will be
the roles our interface and interfaces
that are important for network slicing
especially in okay well the context the
context is quite straightforward we know
that current networks are evolving to
towards deeper bit to essentially
schemes we are here for that now in a
piece directly related to that however a
slice in physical and mental resources
in a bit is essential as you know force
protein exploiting the the capabilities
in this sense we are with a slice in
that plasticity and composability
provide benefits that must be
incorporated also to any system
especially in the future because for
commercial and engineering
organizational applications of energy
systems processes the end composability
are a must and of course we have to
consider also ubiquity in vnf hosting
services like edge of fork computing
that add additional flexibility to the
whole system so an in general apart from
from this week we can ask for improvised
distillation stability under civility as
we have okay so I will be brief from
these the technical viewpoints that we
find in this in this scheme are two
first would be from provided to consumer
that as debut that providers have about
the slicing mechanism and how they
provide this slice into the consumer so
in this sense for sambal NAB providers
I'm to maximize the exploitation of
their resources and so they is lies no
they restructure to processes to get the
largest set of smaller resources
okay
in this way both providers at consumer
are concentrated on their own business
on the same moment in the same time free
from consumer to provide that debut is
similar but in this case then a big
slice consumer or like we can say here
then ABO that of coming from operator I
will talk about this later I'm to meet
the requirements or the network's
said by the applications we provided
that the final users reduce the cost of
ownership a be able to adapt the
network's
etc and everything as fast as possible
of course so in this in this sense what
they do is to obtain every slice of
resources so they have their main
business here the main objective here is
concentrating only on those slice of
Russia's is not how they are a split or
how they are built on their underline
that sparked from the provider so these
two viewpoints have to be in some sense
considered when slicing NAB systems well
and here gives place the rolls I have
mentioned that I did Utley in the divot
from these viewpoints so I have I had
talked about the nippy provider it is
the owner of the physical orbital
resources I include also built or
because we can't have some sense of
relativity here some provided that that
leases one physical verses and provides
physical built or resources to other
operators so as I have mentioned this
provided slice is the infrastructure to
get a smaller portions first topology
changes and dynamic dynamical specific
parameters okay so it in interacts with
the consumers that I have mentioned that
enemy operators to execute they request
mainly create read update and delete so
the main concepts are managing the
physical network and addressing his life
requirement and improving ratios
efficiency and efficacy in the
underlying system in parallel the energy
operator
Manas
the slices of BNF that he has requested
on obtaining from one or D for several
being BNF providers an AP provider in
okay so this is performed through the
enemy controller it's configured by this
operator in order to execute these
objectives and as I have mentioned also
this can be rapidly implemented so we
can have a he here our CEO of NFB o
provided all providers so well at the
end we have the application series
provided that is which establish
requirements to the nabo and then we we
can as I have mentioned we can have
different variation of this instantly
theorem the network program every all
roles can be played by the same entity
or a separate entity as many combination
of them so at the end we have these and
those these are the roles and these in
wing we see the interfaces that are are
identified once the roles are
interconnected one to each over as we
can see here on the right we have some
that they the way passivity I have
mentioned we can see that in this in
this part sorry in this part and then
none more more classic approach in this
side with a provider operator and the
under plication service provider will be
their final consumer fees so the
interfaces are listed here and that's
all from my side so if you have any
questions I hope so
okay next one next one I guess unless
well guess just one thing is that if you
keep using any fee Oh follow operator
please loan me give you the - is not
know be careful because again you end up
with naming many different things the
same way it's okay so well our next and
last my name is Homer from entity
laboratories in this presentation I will
talk about the concept of getaway
function format for pricing so firstly I
would talk about the motivation problem
that was rising the network's rights are
trying to get away the stress get away
is a different function to handle
traffic for that was rising so after you
know in networks rising operation and
manage orchestration is built importance
meanwhile our little brain functionality
for the Box pricing is also very
important and thrust gateway internet
draft a will be helped to define
capability okay plan function for the
franchising and start to Gateway we may
be able to provide a different
functionality for providing Anatsui
and it was rising across multiple armies
native or heterogeneous domains so this
show's over be open it was rising that
was rice is a logical network deployed
based on service requirements for
examples of how connected people's rule
agency network is created and such
because connected to the network and we
expect that was rice would enable
subpart is to use network at work
associate as a part of it their own
subchief so this figure shows the
network ties in life cycles so tenant
sent service requirements to the Natomas
rights providers and network service
provider received requirement and create
network design and combat the design to
complete the network configuration and
enforce to the bottom and array server
resources and network choices will be
created dynamically and so the processes
in lead box will be very complex and we
would liked to automate these processes
so this figure shows frame love
framework of networks pricing considered
in cons companies both held in the last
IDF so network drives Orchestrator
received subsea requirement from tenant
via CSI and SDI and combat the
requirement to the complete conflation
and indicate to the underlay properly so
if a via each controller internal
network trustees will be deployed
dynamically and thus networks prices
would be
we arrived by using Sdn and NFV
technologists so this figure shows over
the all networks rising winds in every
architecture so if and if we are ticked
we use in every architectures so some
introduction between rice Orchestrator
and a network anyway ok ok splitter will
be required so in some cases for
counting starting communication 40 into
2 and networks rising will be required
in this case subnet networks right
subnet is created in each domain and
end-to-end networks Rises openly
achieved by connecting such subjects in
this case Orchestrator for integrating
much domain multiple domain so in and 2
and networks rising there are several
challenges so for example which
information will be required to provide
controllability or for to the tenant or
how to synchronize the domains and how
to operate in each subnet and its data
frame there there are also several
challenges so for example how to detect
traffic and follow the traffic to the
appropriate network license or how to
interconnect between the subnet and how
to keep isolation doing amongst choices
to keep something starts 40 so for
we saw these Oh being such a challenges
on data plane
we like to propose try to get away
concept so stressed getaway is a
functionality to provide some
functionality for it was rising and so
as gateways deployed on each edge of
subnet and provide connectivity or other
functionalities for the trucks license
so this table shows the comments for
Christ's gateway so first gateway will
be required to some functionality in
terms of to to access aspect master is a
hundred underway in Forrester improve
infrastructure to create which was
rising in the entire network and second
is controlled control services on
networks righty
for example some channel would require
two providers several services on a
network drive and thrust gateway will be
an H node and thus some control some
control such control loopy loopy leaper
or SK to be hungry
under a infrastructure such get away
with it equal to classification to the
quad so I get to the appropriate and it
was prices or some q s control oblique
were to provide isolation so you can
find more detailed requirements in the
original internet draft so I will
conclude my presentation so for
deploying
appropriate and student debt loss prices
based on the subsea requirements
definition of functionality on this
plane Opie liquid and stress gateway
will be we enables to provide and
students price across even multiple
energy estimates so at last I will talk
about next step of this document so we
would like to obtain some more viewing
and feedback to the document and I'll
Drive away you'd like to break down the
requirement to complete functionalities
and as you may know so that was pricing
includes whole network system operation
so we need to discuss
formerly magnets left even discussion I
have a bit of a provocative question and
on spitting on tomorrow there will be
also presentation on network slicing in
the network management research whoo
yeah so I think I like the presentation
that we're done today to give a
different of every different aspect that
need to be researched in an aviary or
elsewhere in ITF rhf why they don't
really get is if you want to have really
a discussion on this topic is do we want
to have research aspect investigated in
energy or energy on networks Dyson which
is the topic of today and tomorrow or is
there also the attempt to still create
one working group in IETF for this
aspect do we want to have both and I
just want to be a little bit more
anticipate a bit on the discussion and
what we could conclude on those things
because tomorrow there will be a session
I don't know if you have time to discuss
that sort of to know bit more what
people are willing what are we what can
really go into the research side what
can really go into the engineering side
it's not really clear to me today so
it's my personally the purpose of the
sauce writing is provide service
capability in the commotions network so
I would like to discuss the idea
just what some comment about this
question there are a number of research
elements which probably will take ten
years to resolve related to metal
slicing and these research questions the
best ways to handle it in RTF some
specific to management some specific to
other aspects in in particular Navy
which in my view is moving towards out
of network functions in tools into slice
functions that's my reading of the trend
on the other hand as you can mention and
as mentioned as okay this concept of
slicing has all the elements related to
the next level of networking which means
that there is an opportunity also in the
IDF to dedicate a set of specific
questions to be addressed in a group
rather than to spread everything into
pieces as it is happened now and in my
view that's a waste of energy and will
not converge ever just to give you an
example a lot of people told me oh
segmenting supports it but the industry
doesn't but clearly networks license
doesn't depend on segmenting it's about
the use of services of the
infrastructure underneath in the
combination so to some extent to answer
the question in a deal world we should
have a research set of question in our
ia RTF but also a dedicated impossible
group related to the engineering aspects
some of them in ITF where other issues
will be discussed and this has to be
arranged as best but I'm personally not
very keen to attach everything to an
existing working group in in IETF like
routing and so on because nowhere
already I have problems about well what
are these
drugs appearing to do thousands of drops
which are not put in the industry there
it's routine well it's a big question in
my mind anyway I'm just expressing that
in idea what this is I will do but we
have to be pragmatic in our next period
how to do to move forward better I mean
respective resource challenge this is it
sort of solving building drop problems
for example you have input from
different sources now you have you
optimized rate for example placement of
resources said because that's one of the
key problems you're trying to solve
saying it's a guaranteed slice that
means you shall be able to deliver the
test layer right so is that more of a
resource challenge versus the interfaces
then sense that perhaps you know being
standardized elsewhere I mean not as
part of research of course if there is
some critical element we need to think
about it but the standardization of the
interfaces itself happens elsewhere I
mean and maybe not even idea but some
other body it's something to think about
Makia
one thing that to be a game pragmatic in
my opinion the first thing that we have
to do we have to define the API API
between the API that was missing in that
picture the system is very important you
know as we speak we are trying to
implement that when we can talk about
that as well this is something that in
my opinion why the previous part wasn't
that successful this is my personal view
is because we didn't define exactly what
are missing parts and what we want to do
for example to define that API which was
missing you need a young model for the
connection connectivity API we define
that and that one becomes specifically
in 5g in 5g you know the connectivity is
a bit different from normal
point-to-point multi point-to-point is
related to that so this is one practical
aspect that we have to address that the
second one is the
multi-tenancy versus hierarchy or Nestor
Chauncey this is something that we have
to do in my opinion again that to model
that you put there that from 10 and to
Orchestrator and from the orchestrator
to the controller that to model they are
important by the in my opinion they are
not that important especially the one
from Orchestra from the portal from
customer came and in this context is a
customer to BMW you know the City of
Ottawa being owned or whatever so these
are the aspect that if I want to do it I
I start with dosing and you have to have
a basic goal is networking slicing
related to existing VPNs obviously it is
but this is the very it especially this
is very important to consider
implementation realization from the
concept the concept is connectivity with
the specification how to realize that
you can use segment route and you can
you all to you or CH or the optical
network microwave and O TN doesn't
really matter so basically the the
couple of thing which is practical in my
opinion we have to address it first and
if we do that one I guess it's a good as
a final reminder to sign the blue shield
any final remark as my final remark is
that the world of networking is moving
towards centering on slices as a way to
deliver network services if that's the
case then you have to readjust a bit in
our thinking too
and rather than to look at some
piecemeal silo issues related to this
topic which is much broader in terms of
usage
I suspect that 40 years ago when when
PPM's were invented there were similar
arguments do you need it or not but now
it nobody cares it's using it before
we're at the stage were to use it and I
also add two key research aspects of
this topic which is scalability large
number and also slices with guarantees
which are going to be the norm in the
future these are two subjects which may
refurbish a number of architecture
substantial in addition to all the
others which are I don't want to enter
in an argument right now here but let me
remark these groupies focus on anything
if I mean if we are going to change the
scope please and this is a plea for for
opening this discussion on the list
please think about what the means said
and discuss here and if you can identify
concrete research challenges or concrete
research activities to be reported here
that are related with any of your cost
ratio Network attacks are derived from
the application of anything performance
of beautiful eyes or mixed environments
I don't care whether this is a mix
that's our our matter as well when
you're talking about a mix or whatever
genius deployment of physical and
virtual functions all of this is in our
remit and whatever you feel like coming
with it would be welcome and we are open
to discuss it this said just let me
close the meeting thank you so much see
you next time
[Music]