and it's time to start so welcome
everyone
this is the first energy session for
this afternoon we have a second session
at the end of the afternoon I would
start with giving a short introduction
we have a full agenda today so I will
ask also the presenters to be on their
timing total maximum discussion for
today
can somebody also close the door please
the back of the room thank you so
starting with the no 12
so the IOT RTF follows the IETF policy
so please be aware of the different
recommendation in this note well by
participating in the IETF meeting you
will abide by these recommendations and
before we start the actual discussion
technical discussion we need at least
two person to volunteer for being a
minute taker and another one for being
the Charter scribe meet a co-driver
scribe so we cannot stopped without
having at least two volunteers for that
somebody for the minutes and somebody
for the scribe
yeah please for the a minute for a
minute thank you and we need still
someone for the job ascribe on mythical
will okay thank you very much
thank you a quick highlight about the
different aspects we will have with
energy during the ietf week even if it's
already close to the end but we have
this session one today which is a kind
of regular energy meeting which we try
to cover the ongoing and future items of
the research group and also some status
we have a follow-up session the last
session of this afternoon which will be
a bit beyond the energy but still hosted
by energy it's a OGF special session on
AI and Emily networking this will be a
more discussion meeting to understand a
bit more the relationship between the
detracting part and the AI ml part and
what we could derive from that either in
IETF or its most specially in RDF and
then also an announcement for interim
meeting of energy so on Friday tomorrow
we have a one-day meeting workshop
dedicated to intern base networking the
meeting will not be in this utterly it
will be hosted by ETS a Cola technology
super oil which is two blocks away from
from here so a nine-minute walk all the
information on the details on the
meaning list or if you are just it
please at the end of this session you
can come to discuss with me and pattern
which is also here in the room which
will be our local a stand helped me to
organize this meeting with a great help
thanks patty quick a look at our agenda
so this is the introduction and I try to
group the different presentation of
today under some topics so it's
sometimes not always the right way of
grouping but the first topic will be
around
aspect pertain
to telemetry with the first presentation
from Pedro on exploiting if external
even detectors and their use to do some
management activities the second
plantation going to be from are you on
the the network telemetry framework that
has been presented also in other groups
and understand what we can do in the
scope of energy around this telemetry
aspect and especially the more
forward-looking activities the second
topic will be on management aspect of
network slicing there will be two
presentation one from Alex on the
management problem or the problem of the
managing slides in the gap analysis and
the second presentation from Kieran
which will be blending remotely on some
use cases of the truck slicing and
finally the last topic will be on
so-called novel approaches to network
management it's a way of grouping
different presentation so we will have I
think it was crimson on the intelligent
network management using reinforcement
learning a second presentation on a
roadmap to a network class world from
being new then a remote presentation
from Jefferson on autonomic v dot zero
and finally Alex galley Alex Clare Torry
will give an update on ongoing draft
distinguishing intern policy and service
models any comment on the proposed
agenda modification thank you
so a couple of things I would like to
mention on the stake use of the research
group the meetings been for this year so
we had the begin of 1980 f-101 in London
because usually we try to co-locate at
least one of the early meeting with on
one of the scientific conferences in
network management this year it was with
announced 2018 in Taiwan in April so
this is past and we are currently having
this meeting today tomorrow it's an
interim still in morale and the last
meeting we will plan to have this year
will be here with ITF Onofre in Bangkok
in November
and in parallel to that you can come
discuss with the chair or suggest in the
meaning list a doc interim or topical
meeting we used to add this like for
instance tomorrow the meeting on Ethan
base networking so if you have any
suggestion or proposal or things you
like to discuss we are here to help
status on some documents for the related
to the research group so recently in
February we had new RFC published under
the energies or ever see eighty three
sixteen on autonomic networking use case
for distributed detection of SLI
violations so congratulations to the
author's because it was a long-standing
effort to get this published this work
initiated during the first phase of
autonomic the tracking in energy with
the use cases that were expressed
something like three or four years ago
and we still have also individual
documents that are active in the in the
group and some of them will be presented
in the follow-up shots for those that
are not fully aware we weld a what we
call the research agenda for the
research group in order to organize the
activities or the the document in there
in the group around a set of films
currently defined we have in turn based
network management the use of AI
techniques for network management and
another thing that we call for the
moment on sonic 3.0 or self driving
network or z-rotation working so the
idea is to understand what we could do
in the scope of autonomic networking and
new approaches to approach this isn't
this environment of course this is not
limited to these three themes based on
the presentation we can avalor
suggestion we can develop new topics for
the research agenda so it's based on the
interest and its contribution difference
so if you have proposal we are here to
hear you and give you a fluorophore for
some suggestions
a lot of those will say themes of the
research agenda
the idea is to derive more specific
research items identified with documents
activities of the research group
experimental result or experimental
validation but also possibly also work
plan and somebody's understand that it's
a research activity so it's not like a
working group where you have a more
strict time management but still if we
can derive some milestones for those
activity it's important to see the
progress and finally if you want to read
a bit more but the content of each of
those themes with lisandro we had
published in March in the I Triple E
communication standard series there is
some stat news which are very short
articles highlighting progress in
different areas and there is so a short
article for energy in this issue I think
it's free available otherwise you can
just ask me I can give you a copy and
just to mention also that almost several
others IETF activity is an IETF activity
that are reported in this in this March
issue now a word on the so-called future
of energy so I think for those that
follows the meaning list you are aware
that listen of all my culture decided to
step down after seven years of service
as coach of energy so I would like to
really address my thanks to to listen
role and for she cannot be here for
budget reason for all what she has done
in the energy and the interaction we had
the good thing is that lisandro will
still be an active participant of the
group not as a chair but as a
contributor so we will not lose this
good spirit here but there are also two
consequences our actions that we take
after this announcement so we search for
a new culture so the the call from
candidates has already been sent to the
meaning list a monster goes language we
already have some can yet but still
exciting
volunteers and we will review the
conjugates with the IHF chair the second
aspect and this is also following some
discussion I had this week with the rhf
Jay Allison we come to the conclusion
that it can be a good time also to use
this opportunity I said in the search of
a new culture to rethink what is energy
and what will be the next step energy
just for the memory energy started in
March 1999 so it's a I think one of the
oldest research group still active in
energy so the idea will be not to erase
everything but to reconsider maybe to be
a bit more in phase with the evolution
of network management and the managed
environment so to capture may be a bit
better in the Charter in the activity of
those newer those new things and also to
use this effort to have a big new
ambitions I will say trying to highlight
a bit more hot topics in the area of
network management but also understand a
bit more some orientation so what what
it means to manage or to operate at
scale and at speed in those new
environments so this is ongoing work
ongoing discussions ongoing thoughts so
we will propose an concert with the
research group for a new name for the
scope the Charter over the coming months
we think that by the next meeting in
November we would like to have
progressed on this thing we don't put
ourselves or had my my stone to to
conclude by the next idea but still we
would like to rather start it as this
new evolutions and of course you are
really really welcome to to send your
thoughts and contribution if you have
good ideas for all topics if you want to
candidate for new culture or any
elements you would like to see in the
future of this energy
and final note on that for me doesn't
mean that we get read about the existing
work this work will continue they are
this is good work but he's going
somewhere else oh we will keep these the
new charter will mainly focus on what
will be the next stage of an emerging
nothing this is my last slide
any quick comments on the research group
status before we switch to the technical
presentation thank you so I will ask
Pedro to come for the first presentation
oh okay good afternoon I I will just
present the quick updates on the draft I
represented in the meeting not long
after that I will give some some hints
about all the topic that I want to
discuss here first the context of this
of my job know this and also this update
would be it is that the to adapt
resources assigned to us to a system to
its dynamic demands in order to reduce
the cost increase the revenue of the of
the system avoid this carbon request
that's important for sales quality and
essential in emergency scenarios
meeting and estimate and anticipate
research demands by considering an
external information that can be used
for to avoid the need of over-allocation
and that is the result of normally
conservative method so threshold some
controls and achieve faster a patient to
to boast of the system well this is the
Avenue I presented in which they would
now I am concentrating how to get this
information from the external event
detectors to the system and I started
this in this update by introducing the
the information model and in Jongno that
is required in order to get that
information first it is quite simple but
it is based on two models is the the
events and the notification they having
one is based on pillows and the pillows
I have defined only three basic payloads
the first one is to
- mm-hmm to include any arbitrary
information that can be useful from
outside the system into the the control
plane and second one is one example of
this more specific payload to get
information from one system ohmmeter one
sensor about some tremors that can be
happened outside of the system of course
and become interested for the controller
management of the system and the third
one is the big data that some big data
analyzer can find some interesting
information that can be used to the in
the management of the system and using a
load it can be introduced and then I
have also we have also defined the
information model this even itself with
all the necessary fields that are
typically used in order to communicate
those events and finally the
notification that is basically this is
this this using this structure in order
to to perform this communication as a
notification that this in this case
coming from outside of the system ok so
that's that's all for for the for this
update if you want to check the draft is
very if you want commonly anything the
second topic I wanted to discuss was
about the essential artifacts that we
have will require in order to achieve
what we finance intelligent driving
networks well first to clarify some
concepts I want to define that here that
AI is not ml normally
many people consider machine learning is
hi Laura
yes but AI has a broader spectrum it is
based on perception rationing planning
and and and it is
not fully exploded but it's already
present in some part so we have not to
be a scary of incorporating AI
especially for network management as I
have I will present the family no later
also another concept is that
intelligence is different from
intelligent that means that intelligence
is more also more broader terms that
emphasize the Catalan of the information
and how on the management at information
intelligent emphasizes the smartness of
one device no they don't have to be
present at the same time or I mean so
why applying a damn book damn sorry but
can you go one side back I'm curious
which you say which methods are already
exploited AI methods are already
exploded in networks today today yeah
III I cannot give you all for example
any planning that you can be used let's
say in a rotor Rooter is constantly
taking the the best route from point A
to point B if it is taking some
heuristic in order to determine that for
example in geographical routine or
something like that that every stick is
part of a I what I I want to point
something ok
no sorry I want to point something
normally the definition of AI in my in
my in my experience according to years
is everything that is not being used
today if it is used it's no longer
considered a I because it's used
normally is that there are many many
many methods that are actually AI that
are being used today but they are not
considered AI but they are actually
as I was sayin is that why I apply this
deep application of AI into the network
management it's because Madison
management decisions are we know are
becoming more and more complex for
example one mention is that before we
had the what to answer the question is
there a problem my system
but today the question is more broad
like where should I meet this bit or
machine according to my goals and the
goals can be very complex so and that
must be resolved automatically for
thousands or even more elements at the
same time well also the operational
environments where the systems are
working are more and more dynamic and
this is emphasized by supposition and
probability and never returns a shoe and
automation are required for that also we
have that network devices are becoming
autonomic we have here also in IDF with
animals and there are complex decisions
that had been taken and Sylla touch
network for example they have to fully
exploit programmable elements and
finally when I why not why not using AI
is just a method on resources not
solutions solutions are made after that
well well I will go fast in this part so
to exploit AI in this intelligence dive
in networking we have access permit to
that technology to have access to his
amount of intelligence data from the
system that they are managing okay the
knowledge derivative can be used to
decide the stability response on any
event or situation so finally we have a
constantly evolving model that we can
why not say no let's drive a network
well so this intelligent driving network
is the the key factor there is that
structure of the network result from the
reasoning of intelligence from
intelligent data the network adapt to
new situations perceived and resonate
from that data and the data must be
properly managed and exploited as much
as possible and the avenues must be
adapted to work on network problems
specifically on network problems today
are gonna say dreams are quite general
and have not particularly specific
specific for networking and we have some
news cases like predicting traffic
behavior iterative network communication
or the assessment of administrative
policies that is quite important in
networking so the standardization issues
that are behind or imagine known from
this application would be to facilitate
in order to facilitate the system of
methods from different vendors would be
that the methods used to retrieve the
information must be the quality of those
the methods must be assured so we have
to assess the quality of the method so
when you should know customer or
whatever they they can check if one
method is better than other in some in
some terms that can be validated but
that stakeholder also the types and
quality of information that is retrieved
from a system or object must be
consistent consistent in terms of that
if we are receiving one mesh
you
data to support a ibises solution is no
single open source data available now
yeah yeah so I believe for the for the
different plane we may have a different
situation for the control plane we may
be able to directly monitor the
interactions of the routing protocols
and we also already have the you know
the lot of database for the management
management train data and also for to
monitor user as a Ras and the we are you
know the operators say is able to pin
down some user flows to monitor their
performance experience so I think we as
a winner we can provide the technologies
and the operator can I take mine jobless
technologies and to extract data out of
their network to do to achieve different
applications I think that that's
possible it's not problem damn
Bogdanovich it's not problem in the
possibility it's a problem in the
willingness and my other question is
which is my that was a comment and like
my question here is what are you missing
in the existing technologies that we
have today that you cannot develop to
collect the data from the network what's
what's missing for example I talked
about with several operators they said
they still prefer to have a some unified
interface for the data data collecting
and but now you cannot unify it let me
answer this you cannot unify different
types of data and single data is because
they have some they have different
characteristics that you cannot put in a
single database you have to have
multiple different databases one has to
be chronological and the other one will
be no transact
yeah yeah I mean that's a different
layer right you are talking about how
the data are organized for for the
application but there are also interface
how the data extracted from the network
devices so there are currently are
multiple different proposals and maybe
we don't try to unify to the single
interface but at least for each each
plane is preferred to have a sense of
one or two where few are standard
interface so they don't need to talk to
run it for battery in my opinion it is
important to understand the data in
which interface it comes over it is much
less because what we have today might
not be sufficient tomorrow and the date
the data has to be consistent but the
interface is more or less than it can be
adapted that could be changed okay thank
you one last comment please I think
there are a couple of things I'd like to
point out telemetry means different
things at different layers so if we look
at it at the bottom we are looking at
you know bites and packets per second
kind of a thing may be related to a
single connection like a per connection
information but very quickly it becomes
a response time calculation for HTTP or
it could be responsiveness for some
other application so at different layers
that means different things and then
there is also an inherent security
associated with this data which I think
may not be fully captured in your talk
so what was the second part what was not
capture um there's a security aspect of
using oh yeah yeah yeah so you mean for
security purpose are some security
mechanics to support the telemetry data
I mean
so there is an aspect of who can see
this data okay okay okay
and I think if the you know if you're
creating a protocol or interface
whatever that might be that would be the
that would be the thing to look at yes
but the question I had was actually
similar to the previous speaker in terms
of do you know exactly what you're
missing right now in terms of telemetry
data what is it that anybody needs so
what there are some ongoing work here
actually try to address those issues
like some institution right it's try to
provide the real-time traffic
performance measurement for force for
user flows so that's not available today
mm-hmm right that's just one example and
there may be some other other works for
example for the we are doing some work
on the control plane our monitoring so
we try to extend the BMP protocol to
support more thoroughly control plane
merriment so that some ongoing works but
there's not existing today so I so
that's why this work we want to identify
what's missing was again maybe some new
stuff I still need it so right now what
has been used in the you know what you
can get a counters that hardware windows
would set up in that devices right yeah
is there something missing in that list
of counters that you have there are a
lot of contour resources available but
but for example if you want to get some
statistics for some special specifically
user flows it's a difficult to do today
because there are limited resource and
sometimes you may need to dynamically
interactively a
hit that resource to include designate
what fellow you want to monitor so
there's something we also see hist you
thanks okay just commenting as myself
one area I think that is a research
group could contribute or work on is the
aspect of metadata because I think we
already have quite a lot of data and
measurement protocol and whatever but as
Dean pointed out it's to understand this
data usually we there is a challenge to
be able to describe metadata so that
this can be used by other application or
analytics in the pipeline to to
understand the data that is coming what
is it and how it can be exploited by
more intelligent with what Pedro mention
intelligent mechanism at the end of the
chain so how to attach those metadata or
to - by them I think it's something that
is not so much
moving down today from this telemetry
aspects yeah and also I think usually
there is a the aspect of correlating
multiple sources I mean usually you can
get one flow data
I mean protocol are designed to get some
one source of data the data they expect
to have but you if you are if you are
also a capability - if you have multiple
source you can collect data from
multiple protocols multiple points there
is also the aspect of being able to get
those multiple sources and correlate
them to get a different understanding of
what's happening from multiple point of
view either different dimension or
different endpoints very important you
know framework to have the the data
source from different plane also in the
same plane came from different devices
you do need to correlate other data for
some applications we actually think
about some real use case to support that
kind of a correlation I wasn't sure they
were going to close the developer funny
yeah I think I agree
the reason need of work here well then
wondering is whatever we need is because
there are several already several
protocols around and mechanisms for
changing data measurement another ligand
this work on going around the in the ATF
and as we're doing these that for
example just the BMW G that is dealing
with measurement so or pretty mutual
order that was made for remember the
name IP fix if I remember well so that
what they miss amazed and I think this
is important in the direction would be
basically a mechanism for not trying to
to build a theory of a unified protocol
for everything mechanism for managing
data I mean the for managing metadata
how you can a certain element that is
going to consume the data that is coming
from whatever the measurement points is
able to to know which others later on
how to process them yeah I think I think
that if we can move forward in a way in
which we would facilitate the
measurement points the way in which they
can be care which they are they are
going to provide and on the other hand
the the others to announce which which
data they are trying to to consume that
would be an advantage so that's more
than I mean two Maxima views that would
be more important that defining another
architecture but that probably is making
it more data centric unless that same
knowledge center yeah so we're gonna see
maybe what you sighs mostly the last
components about data analytics and
storage but that parses its current but
it's a little bit fuzzy there are a lot
of existing open source tools and
they're widely used but maybe here in
ITF we have more about the standard in
for other components
as you said for the data export right if
you the data plane we may use the IP fix
and UDP directly from the device of
holding phoning pass and maybe for the
management clean we use a gr PC and some
other protocol sleep we don't try to you
want news but we first we need to
identify what's available and even for
this existing protocols was missing so
that's a first task we want to want to
do
Yanis that precise naming maybe
something about thinking or something or
stop playing with the D and research
terms to start with how something that
would be similar to what John has become
for management would be basically how to
do declare the scheme of data that
you're willing to consume or produce
yeah just as a suggestion is something
that you could have a regulator on we
have to move on thank you for the
discussion in the comments the next
presentation will be from Alex on the
management slicing problems and gap
analysis thank you very much
maximum ten minutes okay
my presentation focuses on some
suggested future problems related to
management which may be over the scope
of this working group and I reflect the
research management challenges rather
than other engineering challenges which
are related to the topic which I'm going
to present this was driven mainly and
derived from a survey and the tutorial
which I mainly put together to and
delivered that two weeks ago with a V of
revealing most if not all the aspects
are which are published so far related
to the concept of Network slicing in
SDL's in research environment as well as
industrial context as well as in the
other aspects
so that's the origin of it and I'll make
some presentation but also I would like
to point out that there are some you
know a few some concluding remarks which
may be over of your importance next
slide please
by now everybody should know that
Network slicing is now concept which is
now not on research but it's engineered
worldwide by all the players as I
understand in some form of shape it's
probably as the concept is older than me
but it will outlive me by far and the
concept itself is not new namely that
the problem of network services is
partition different in such a way that
the infrastructure supporting it will be
able to deliver or to support each
partition account separately we are
talking about multiple networks to be
produced conceived managed operated as
well as closed down in parallel and on
demand I just point out that these
partitions are not related to virtual
networks or traffic engineering aspects
or only VPNs mainly because the concept
of network slices understand it now it's
a composite of three elements not two
not one one in definitely needs the
resources and network functions built
Jonetta functions which need to be put
together either from the network cloud
or the from on continued network one
part but the other parts are the
management function which you attach to
it as a group and more importantly the
services which will be delivered at
least one well so these three have to be
looked at one rather than separately as
usually
this sort of concept appears to be very
useful in a and a number of important
scenarios which are now as I understand
it driven from key requirements of the
industry there are many listed here but
one of the special one which I think
that the ship may be one focus point is
about the high precision service
networks which are appearing namely the
possibility to create parallel slices in
such a way that each of them to have a
level of guarantees either for the
quality of service or kpi's it's
unconceivable to have something new
based on IP because either is not
guaranteeing anything to guarantee let's
say low latency plus many other things
for all the type of services so it's a
good idea to split beyond the problem
space and to understand how to do this
well before this is fundamental but it's
something practical as well in addition
there is another practicality of this
splitting is that some of these IDF
protocols could be deployed in a slice
most of them cannot be deployed at large
because it will involve too many nodes
to be changed worldwide which is too
expensive okay in this reviews are many
frameworks which are suggested few are
presented here on the left side from at
ITF second on research projects mainly
dealing with the network cloud
however the things which I'm promoting
is at this new relatively new emerging
concept had its own management problems
and I'm listing seven or so I'm not
going to go through all of them just
saying that they need to be resolved
without the management elements for sis
networks as a whole singles stand out
some of the to shudder in place but
there is no single bullet to solve all
of them in particular the fact that this
our autonomic operations and mechanics
cannot scale it up without autonomy City
and many other since released it on on
this chart or the next and very
importantly is to understand the
intricate relationship between service
and data service is mapping into these
containers to make sure that this is
practical in addition that the problem
of how you compose decompose on demand
and how to do all the other things are
our least important in addition to this
detailed one I would like to add two
more namely about the way in which
networks I see could be scaled up in
particular management scale up not to
tens but maybe 10,000 maybe millions of
possibilities the practicality as well
as how you perform it it's probably a
key research topic now in the future as
well and also to how these slices could
be used for precision service or network
services now
I point out one thing which is it might
be that the networking element of the
future will be based on slices there'll
be many types and they are supported by
an underlying lightweight mechanism to
make the existing network fabric a bit
more soft but also if you aren't
controlled by the management which is in
slice management as well as overall
end-to-end
orchestration which neatly done
therefore there is a shift and once you
are in this transition it's a time to
move towards it and try to take
advantage and research problems will
appear automatically not as a framework
but in some specific areas now clearly
this is a scope or problems these
problems are in the scope of NMR G so
I'm suggesting that maybe you need to
look at it and your feedback will be
highly appreciated and once again
just to say that this material
is not driven by one RFC or many but is
a way to present some but a longer list
the management problems which need to be
resolved here as well another part some
some engineering problems as well that's
for sure but before concluding a part of
this tutorial which I presented two
weeks ago in Montreal at the academic
conference including around a hundred
academic references but also a road map
of existing references of work in in
slices which is resistances that
concludes my own presentation
now it's your turn to lock me down thank
you or not they are Bogdanovich so
network slicing is an interesting
management of network slicing is an
interesting problem and I spent
personally and within my work time
thinking about management of the network
slices of the control and management
pipe but I'm so struggling to get what
will be definition of the network
slicing in a data plane because with
whenever I hear the airplane I'm hearing
different impressive interpretation and
they all start dedicated network
resources are too expensive so I'm
thinking are we talking about you know
the lambdas in the optical layer are we
talking about you know VLANs are we
talking about you know how do we want to
do Network slicing in the data plane
then we can then map that slice to my
control point slice and make sure that I
can manage those resources in parallel
good question you want an answer or you
have an answer I don't have an I mean I
have some ideas but I'm curious to hear
in this case your opinion because
everybody yesterday in the tease and I'm
always saying dedicated network
resources are too expensive we all know
that but then well how do we define a
slice in a data point okay thank you the
question is extremely valid but my
suggested answer is that
the current important topics about how
to manage an orchestrate this new
relatively new concept now in this forum
lies was a management and control plane
and service plane obviously was an
interaction between the three in the
footprint in the data play the data
plane does not dictate this and I'm
fully aware that there are may be around
seven or eight ways to create to
activate as a data plane the slices you
want but this is to some extent not the
essence now mainly because an operator
like British Telecom I was here just or
anybody else had its own a way to
organize their resources and they will
not accept one of the seven and the
current things like I don't want to name
it you and they organize it was the
issue is or the current problematic area
is in the manage management plane and
interaction was a control trainer
service way and to act as one and bring
it down later who some ways to link it
was one of the many or all the way with
all the things related to data plane
instantiation if you start from the data
plane for example form the segment
routine you'll end up with not much
because segmenting will not be applied
to all the parts of the network as well
as other things therefore it's I would
suggest at the priorities to use a
management plane problem first and then
map to a number of options for the data
plan ok we have to conclude this
discrete I don't know if you want to
reply quickly you know no very quickly
okay so maybe followed discussion and
now it will be key run on a remote
presentation for the next on slicing
news cases not yet it's the power of the
chair
Kieron if you hear me you need to switch
to presenter presenter model ratio in so
that I can give you data flow can you
guys hear me no it's okay okay
I'm hearing some echo myself I don't
know why so let me get started my
presentation is slightly different from
what alex talked about it is initially I
thought we will talk about the use cases
in network management network slice
management but it turned out to be a
very high-level overview of the work we
have done in previous couple of box
related to network slices let's go to
slide number three please so in a very
simple way an informal definition of
network slices would be how we built a
purpose how we built networks for a
particular service with certain resource
requirements and constraints and we
should be able to allow logical
isolation of resources such as network
storage computer and maybe application
service or other network functions it
should support multi-tenancy and one of
the differentiating factor is that these
resources should be managed by the
tenants themselves not by the operator
of the infrastructure and
then slices should also have some sort
of dynamic capabilities if you want to
augment the resources within a
particular slice so this is just an
informal definition because if you try
to put it in one sentence you can't
finish it so let's go to the next slide
please and so why do we want to work on
networked slices first of all we have to
differentiate it from traditional
Network traditional VPNs because that
was one of the question that was raised
in one of in first boss of networked
slices and we said that the kind of
resource guarantees we want to achieve
are at per flow level and they are
different from Howrah pians are built on
top of that we look at slices in terms
of service verticals we want to do and
do an orchestration of all the different
kinds of resources and be able to manage
them in runtime and then how so how
network slices will be used they will be
provided as a service by the service
providers or the infrastructure owners
and in order to do that in a repeatable
and a standard manner we need to have
some sort of standard interface over
which they can talk to different network
components or management components
specifically and it should have
customization capabilities and maybe
some top-level data models specific to
services and the slices that can be
broken down into control plane or the
data plane related configurations or
operations and finally for me the most
important aspect is to look at
management of network slicing as a way
of understanding slices from end to end
perspective management plane is the only
is the only level from which we can look
at end-to-end slices how resources are
allocated abstracted or mapped in the
network so if you talk in different
working groups they are looking
some functionality related to the slices
but it is very difficult to put it all
together and if we take up this work
here in NMR see those are that's exactly
what we can achieve the entire
management view of this slice is
specifically in terms of OAM and ASCAP
saw operations next slide please
so when we were initially working on a
network slicing buff we first started
with the functional aspects of the
slices and we classified into three
categories first one is pretty simple
related to customization that an
infrastructure provider will provide
Network slice as a service to enterprise
customers and using word exploiting the
virtualization capabilities you could
allow enterprise customers to build
their own VC PE or Sdn solutions by
placing their network functions wherever
they want to in their networks the
second aspect was the resource assurance
which most of the people always talk
about generally related to low latency
broadband and mntc type of slices and
then we also identified another category
which was how can you evolve new
protocols in a given partitioned network
so this will be more like a low-level
partitioning of the slices of the
resources so you could choose to run
your own application protocols or maybe
other network or control protocols given
a particular set of network resources
but that work was considered pretty
broad so we just started focusing on the
network management aspects and from from
the management of slices we identified
that we would need some kind of end to
an orchestration capability we would
need ability for tenants to customize
the slices we need operations and
management of the slices F gaps
functionality and more importantly how
they will interoperate across multiple
domains that are under the control of
different administrators and how would
you interconnect parts of the slices
that belong to different Network next
slide please
you run your community ok so this is the
reference architecture where we talked
about that an NS provider which is
Network slice provider will have a very
we'll have a kind of northbound
interface to the tenant and it will have
Saltburn interface to network sliced
orchestrators these orchestras talk to
their own infrastructure and at at this
point when we are talking about
management we don't touch the control
plane or the data plane functionality
next slide please
and we identified some of the key
functions that will take place over
these interfaces which is describing
your network slice as the service
request what kind of resource
requirements and corresponding
parameters you have and how will you
negotiate for a particular slice service
not only in terms of which subnet you
want your net your part of your slice to
be in also the cost that will be some
kind of cost negotiation with the
infrastructure owners and similarly from
the Southpoint perspective we want to do
the capability learning we want to
aggregate information from different
subnets of the slices and put them
together map them to the tenant slices
then in services next slide please
so let's skip this part since I'm
running out of time and next slide so
the previous slide was just running
through the use case how SDI and CSI
interfaces are useful in terms of entire
flow of instantiate in your slice so
from an MRG perspective for me the most
important aspect is how do you see
end-to-end slices from management plane
and how do we integrate the operations
on the slices and the
sources together some of the challenges
with from management part is that we
will always be challenged that there are
so many yang models available which are
service specific or infrastructure
specific how are you going to use them
or exploit them or are you going to
write new models so these are the
questions we will have to answer and
identify going forward and of course
inter-domain is one of the big part and
stitching slices across heterogeneous
technologies will be another challenge
next slide please
so this is just my view what we can do
in this group that let's not worry about
the data plane and control plane part
just focus on network slice as a service
management aspect define the service
provide the monitoring and performance
capabilities define slices as some kind
of service graphs and it should be
agnostic agnostic of any particular
architecture like let's not think about
and if we SFC or anything and because we
need to be able to stitch all those
things together and we should be able to
stitch together a part of l3 network
with the l2 network and it should be a
very lean solution next slide please so
this is my final slide main thing was to
figure out that should we take up this
work in an emoji is it a suitable
suitable place or not and if if this
work is accepted we would start talking
about CSI and STI in more details and
that would be a very good starting point
thank you thank you can we have a few
minutes for questions yeah damn
Bogdanovich I will read whole again down
on the data point we always talk about
resource management what you know how
can I manage the resources if I don't
know the capabilities of those resources
so this is something versus are using
different you know capabilities there
should be one of my questions and then
the second question if you can go please
go to us slide number six
so you know in the reference framework
here I have you know essentially several
issues you are talking about the network
slicing service but where does your
service model sits on this are you
talking to this your infrastructure
configuration model or where's your
service model on that part and then the
last part saying that data playing the
control point will resolve somewhere
else without correlating you know with
that work I don't think we you know it
can be very successful yeah so let me
answer your questions in the reverse
order it's simpler that way so we have
to start somewhere
I what you have in mind is a bottom-up
approach which is perfectly fine there's
nothing wrong with that but what we are
trying to do is from an emoji we are
taking a top-down approach define the
management aspects of it and let's
tackle the control and data plane issues
those issues we have already identified
in our initial gap analysis document
it's just that we haven't discussed it
over here if you look at the original
gap analysis documents lot of things
what we wanted to do about data plane
was highlighted there it's just that no
working group is willing to take that
work right now and in terms of service
model my perception is that my service
model will be inserted from the CSI
interface and that's from where my
service description will come in two ns
provider the network slice provider
which is actually going to do the most
of the heavy lifting for the network
slice management rather which could you
just point on this slide 6 where would
you insert the service model from on CSI
tenant to provider reserve we nokia
service model the one thing that I
mentioned also yesterday in this picture
in my opinion the most important
interface which you not shown here is
from Orchestrator to the sir
so basically the model that we are
referring here is not the service model
is a connectivity model this is a brand
new model that I mentioned it to Alex
yesterday so I'm working on it now that
basically the interface between
Orchestrator and infrastructure is a
connectivity model and from there is a
service model basically you receive a
request that I want to connect a BB u 2s
gateway and we translate that onto a
service model so if I want to start with
this architecture I start with that
interface in my opinion is the most
important aspect the interface from to
the tenant is important but it's not
that important I agree I agree that
interface from tenon to provider will be
relatively lean but the kind of service
model you are talking about for me it
resides in provider it will be probably
some other internal interface within NS
provider to infrastructure so NS
provider is something at a level above
the interest network infrastructure
analyst it is
extract it is collecting the
capabilities from different
infrastructures and kind of aggregating
that information together so obviously
it does not own any infrastructure by
itself is not service model is a
connectivity model I'm just a stressing
that one David so the second one is and
I see this one in various presentation
under network as I say there are all the
time they talk about end to end but I
never see end to end concept whatever
they talk about is not really an network
a slice is a transference list we just
doing the connectivity at the transport
layer if address the end-to-end
I shouldn't see a picture that it starts
from Duran and end at the EPC and this
is really an to end and there are lots
of aspect that is not you know ran a
slice and Cori slice filed for exam for
5g points it is a little bit more
history behind that you are using you
have some kind of run and 3gpp network
in your mind and we have we were we were
asked not to look into the 3gpp aspects
of the
slicing so we look at just the transport
network yes sorry but we have this power
outage and we are really missing time so
we can not solve all the discussion on
network slicing and the management
aspect of metal slicing now and we are
really short on time just my my comment
as a chair is currently I don't really
see clearly what the research challenges
are so this can be worked out
offline the mailing list with
presentation if you Tod still
opportunity to express what really the
pain energy could investigate so you can
work all together on that but we have to
close this discussion now just a last
comment as far as I understand in my
presentation I made a list of around 15
research challenges management I said if
you believe that you don't understand
them that's your problem but to say that
this is it and I have to do or something
this is it - a bit opaque now things
thank you first we don't have time to go
into more discussion if you identify a
problem the point of the research group
and working groups is to find other
people who understand that problem and
help you rehash the solution of that
problem so if nobody understands it we
want to learn and understand what is the
problem to help you solve that problem
because many of us are working on the
same or similar problems yeah
thanks Dean this one uh submit my line
that I'm not saying there are no
problems and I think the way to present
them and make people understand and
adhere to the vision it's still not
there so we have we had this first
opportunity to discuss but I think we
need we did more sorry qur'anic
give you the flower we really all the
time and we still have presenters and
with respect to their also their
preparation we need to give them the
flow thank you so the next will be
younger
thank you
this is interesting that amendment using
the important running
my name is boom gone home I'm looking
for ETL I both this rep and his flight
prey attack the University and the pure
telecom help us to prepare so thank you
and this is the third Bojan also we have
a one time to good each end in last 99
meeting so it is the second time to
pretend yeah
so in this rep we want to utilize the
improved learning I'll show you what's
the region what's the motivation and
nowadays the team running are integrated
to other so we are also of allotted
approach in our researching yeah why we
want to use all the important running in
the tornado measurement there are two
reason the person region is the decision
problem as you know the supervised
learning in suitable for single decision
for example image electrician but in
real world in network it is not composed
of the single decision for example body
for Latin all were multiple links and
the Botsford or conjuration are existing
in the real world in real network so in
the sequential decision we've lifted the
important learning is water chute world
or through sharp the problem and the
other reason is to Dara it you know in
supervised learning it based on tour
lots of doTERRA so and is lon I am
it is Vera so in the immediate
recognition we can study and we can
teach what is a poor what is orange but
in the real world is Pedro set and a
song says that it is not possible
gathering Terra
so if we deploy and any preserved the
problem or we cannot learn by example so
another alternative is run by experience
it is the infection so tasks are
implicitly given through the reward
so in this trap we show three possible
at auction area with our air the first
one is the intraday trading management
the other is to network the peak
prediction the final is allowing
investment so in this time we show our
ongoing or research work for the
increase on threaten management yeah
yeah on Terrace so it is the a cheap
paste intelligent ready control scheme
using parallel so I don't know you're
familiar with rotary inverted pendulum
system so our core is to raise the
pendulum top or in this way so to do
this there are two input to state it is
a pendulum angled era and am endowed era
and this data are delivered to this each
component though so in this machine we
run the tiara module and the features
the action is to both power power during
the era so and then this motor power try
to raise the poor in this way so yes so
this for connecting this system we use
the wire connection the internet so
there are no problem so but or in real
world it is not the same easy
so make or
similar story award we try to make the
poor sleepy and then we try to stop the
apostrophe without ripping measurement
so nowadays we are industrial alte
service there is the load reimburse see
dependencies then and edge computing a
intelligent control system we are
succeed to integrate it for our
remaining work is to integrate to other
tripping management yes so we shows
flatly to our simulated environment we
use the open air GLM so the early
definition is racket is and we use three
data model to every jump the tip unit or
a through C and ACC so as I said that
there are two anger and the world the
motor power and the reward formula is
like this so you can find the detailed
information about this open source I
skip so it's the reader to of our
simulation so as you can see nowadays
the better than typical Network a - she
is somewhat successful resulting eqn so
our remaining words to integrate a
threesome order in our head so it is our
final phase so we you noted a we spend
much time in ITF ir tape to deploy much
money but for example ID net net
emotional named RG
but nowadays the animal is the best play
to handle the issue so we want to share
and discuss and the clerk and the lon
how to deploy on much learning in the
network and network management so to do
this the first thing is - yes so many
person asks me what's the reason to
deploy much money in network is the it
only research is it any other penny
to show to answer the question we try to
stimulate we want to simulate the real
world it is the industrial IOT it is
similar to those mad factory area and
the other is that where is the best
place to deploy interests the function
in a two area in every NATO node who are
one word to NATO note it is we teddy
stretchy and all the reason why we ask
that is if the environment and the
problem is too complex and we cannot
cuff labrum so simple is the best so we
believe that if we deploy in a tumble
machine learning a top function tomorrow
is from Barbara and the final is that we
show the Queen a to see and a-three see
there are lots of the new or existing
algorithm one metal more there so we
want to deploy in reality flow it is
algorithm in the network area and want
to check and want to find the
possibility what this visibility so any
other or the minerals do this what I
wanted to shoot thank you very quickly
please yeah so one of the hallmarks of
any deep learning algorithm is that it
is based on learning from data
representation as opposed to task
specific algorithms and I'm missing
where the deep learning is in your
examples yeah you have really not much
time Bing can you come for the next
presentation yeah I show you there can
answer that we have to be very you know
you can answer very quickly
because if you utter is takes much time
to click rate for each stage and action
because we tested in the 1000 times so
to solve that problem
not only are L muon but also the PRA is
more suitable to charge the problem so
let's our speaker is being loon which
will give us a plantation on levels of
autonomous network technology related to
the network s roadmap good afternoon my
name is Billy from Maui this work is
still in a very premature stage so we
just kick out some very rough ideas to
attract your attention to get more
feedback so as we know the network
effect is always a challenge in the
industry now there are always new
technologies emerging to deal with the
problem for example the STM for the
service autonomic service delivery and
the the new emerging intent driven
Network which we will have a dedicated
discussion on Friday in emerging and
also we had many effort on the how to
utilize artificial intelligence machine
learning technologies for automatic
control loop so we were wondering is it
possible that we can draw a map to
illustrate how we can get to the
ultimate goal which is defined as
natural ease in a draft
which means in ideal way the in a
perspective of an administrator there
just no network at all so that's a word
on net for this okay so we all know in
autonomous car industry they are a very
where we subject our levels from total
and menu driving to autonomous driven so
he is quite natural to think about how
about we have a similar levels in how to
odd numbers drive the network so so far
we figured we at least we need two
dimensions to this very comprehensive
issue the one dimension is from the
operators perspective what's a final
effect for example there are several
aspect the self-organization which
basically related to a various kinds of
a park and play technologies how to get
connect with a network menu system and
how to build identities autonomically
etc and self configuration how to make
the parameters automatically be
configured self optimizing we have
various technology to make the traffic
more in a more efficient way our self
diagnostic and self-healing is about the
fourth management another dimension is
the network system myself needs some key
capabilities to support the final effect
they are so in a mainly three areas with
the first one is the about the merriment
we call it a never perception
and also that telemetry and never visit
ization technology all belong to this
area and we also need more sophisticated
decision and reasoning mechanism and the
AI Armour selenium plays a very
important role here and we also need the
operation interface to evolve as well
from the primitive device API to maybe a
declarative API so we come up with this
table I'm sorry for the readability and
I don't have time to go much in details
I just peek maybe one a couple of
examples for example photo
self-organization the level sorry I only
include from the level 2 to level 5 not
in the level 1 because never 1 all about
something already widely used in the
industry and and from level 3 to level 5
does something we just imagined whether
the technology will go in this approach
for example for the self-organization
maybe the next step should be the the
network can figure out how to make
domains by itself or without human
interview that's only a very simple
example and further self configuration
may be the next next step is the network
element can can compel some detailed
configuration by itself rather than
every single detail will be calculated
in the centralized a controller or never
menu system by the way I I have several
copies hard copies of this table so if
you're increasing pre-cum up to me okay
so we we really want to hear from you
whether this kind of work is valuable to
have such kind of levels of the odd
numbers Network and we already have two
dimensions from the prototype
perspective of operators and the key
capabilities of the network itself so is
this reasonable or something missing and
for the self organizations of
configuration etc we we want to know
whether there's also something very
important missing in the in the table
okay so this work cannot be done by only
few people we do want to define it
ourself so the the goal is to attract
discussion attract contribution so that
we can reach consensus in the industry
okay I think that's all we have time for
some comments or feedback
developers hmm I think that in general I
have not had timing to go in detail in
the document or whatever it's been the
first news I have written I must confess
but I think that there is a clear
interest possessory in the what this
group Conda can do as a researcher in
providing precisely you know sort of a
theoretical foundation of what natural
management should become in the new era
and I think a finer this is available as
a research activity the message I don't
think that any kind of pure real
standardization could come out of this
but on the other hand it would be able
to provide for nation's forefathers in
the residual so I think is interesting
in the in despite land visits I don't
know exactly what the to DM dimensions
at the trace and in that I think we
would need some ma father thinking that
as a as a first move in providing
there's a new theory of management if
you like is something that I think it's
interesting
thank you
at the end retire I think I agree with
what Diego said it can be useful for
research purposes at the same time I
believe this is already happening I mean
we already have sawn surface or
organizing networks in in 3gpp and it's
actually implemented and used and so I
think if there is anything that can be
done is narrow down the scope to
something that is manageable understand
exactly what what is that selfish aspect
within within different domains of
networking in network management and
then that becomes something that is more
coherent to look at holistically but I
think it needs to be tackled on on a
kind of a domain by the main basis
because that that's what gets traction
yeah I mean ideally you would have these
but it they don't happen overnight okay
thanks okay thank you we continue with
the next presentation which will be from
Jefferson remotely and I think it
relates to some aspect of this
presentation
[Music]
okay so good afternoon I'm trying to be
home season I think that's that this
presentation can be very short so next
slide next slide so as we were talking
energy and the animal working Reuters
there is a minimum set of properties
that we we consider as necessary for an
autonomic system and these properties
there are different kinds of of
definitions for these properties but
usually we can talk about the network
can must be automatically adaptive in
our so this is translated into different
definitions such as have sharp meta key
and others and we use this kind of
research is usually addressed by a
network manager area so for example in
the conference such as I am norms and
seen the same and the in in IT actually
and I'm going to talk about this may be
the correct forum for that is DN
emerging so next slide so as an a
perspective this is the main the First
Nations in autonomic network in the
Accord 2005 to 2006 so there are several
intestines for that
for example the artificial intelligence
in network management what which there
are several
research activities in the 90s then
self-organization networks and
declarative partisan and so forth and
there are also several papers and some
of these papers were written by
contributors often MRG such as John and
other people
next slide so there is we can talk about
in research it's called for the
autonomic networking considering
different kinds of technologies and the
perspective and approach for that so for
example our chief intelligence policies
machine learning and some of this of
these topics were addressed by by by the
previous presenters in this meeting so I
believe this kind of something that we
can cannot become that and this the the
research but it's balanced in the whole
HD spectrum so this can be can be
applied for violet and wireless network
and fixed and mobile and so forth next
slide so the internal network movement
they did got a lot of momentum around
2007 and 2009 so there are lots of
papers from that and in each area in the
communications magazine journal and
other interesting and influent papers
were published at that point and also
there are some projects that started to
address this property known as the
automatic networking once next slide so
just to mention a lots of projects
especially presence in the European
Union considering autonomic networking
functions and properties and some of
this practice they use the term
autonomic network in another state use
some properties that are commonly
associated to autonomic networking but
they don't use they didn't use the name
out of network next slide so the reason
and adequacy interest in autonomic words
when considering academia research
perspectives around 2011
thousand thirteen and the there are
possibly there are some reasons that we
can we can cite for that for example
there are at that point other technology
that were gaining momentum such as Sdn
and NFV the researchers started to use
different terms for at our network and
such as cognitive network intelligence
briefing network so the terms they
change it a little at that point and
there's also something that we I think
that today is still a problem in that
area in this area which is the lack of
successful deployment K so for example
there are some some a lot of frameworks
and tools and the and the researchers
parks on our network but it's difficult
to find out especially in that point
successful deployment case and at this
point also we started some some work on
the standardization for Japan and et
assign and also in the IDF with the
animal work group next slide you have to
come to the conclusion person okay next
slide
maybe you can go to maybe can go to to
the next slide next slide so at least at
one point there's the animal working
group and at the the organization or
group you when the chairs were rising
the charter for the worker group there
is this definition that which the the
data points are the topics that are
outside the the charter can be
encouraged as an individual submission
but most more quarter as an emergency
submissions a next slide so there are
there are potential application and is
performed for these and considering the
areas that are not addressed by any
animal working group so for example
higher utilizing and programmable
infrastructures and there is this energy
internet draft at home
some of these kind of infrastructures
there is this application on 5g and IOT
and smart X is my selfie also it's
important to have a better link with
real world operations for example right
and OGG and other stuff and also it's
important to understand if there is some
effective deployment in the reasons for
the lack of whites gave the plant all-na
dominant work next slide and I'm trying
to be very fast so I want that so the
question is there is a need interest or
inertia for automatics 3.0 Indiana Marty
so if there is or is yes and I believe
it's yes there are I propose for efforts
on that and the first one is to
personally some some work on
intent-based networking and I believe
that the next presenter
I think it's Alex and he will talk about
that and also I think it's important to
have some some work on AI and ml for
network management that there is also
there were also presentation on this
topic also it's important to have an
integration with other Network
automation approach such as zero touch
network and service management and also
anything to make me we are in a point
that maybe it was seem to revisit the 75
75 s and five and six
we shall which are the the artsy's that
puts track animal working group so maybe
we can revisit these services for
example thinking what sort of anomie
scope in a long term the the ruby are we
charted on anima
i believe in in november so maybe we can
you know you can look at these these
documents and in the new chart and and
see oh maybe there is some some some gap
that we can never seen the number G so I
mean I think that is it
sorry about that we also we are already
over time and you may wish to be cut
Dinah's a comment and i would also like
to have a contradict comment i'm a big
proponent of autonomic networking i
disagree that we have to go ready to
autonomic 3.0 we have a lot of work to
do in the current framework and my main
issue is these days we still have one
problem all the exception handling in
networks is still done by the human
operator we have to figure out how to
automate the exception handling from a
service level perspective from a network
service level perspective instead of
just focusing on the device and if we
can display some foundation on which we
can build the next levels on top of that
that that would be great but we have too
many holes in the lower layers to go to
the you know to the next levels John
Strauss nur
so I broadly agree agree with Dean as
you know I'm a big fan of intent
networking I'm working on it actively I
think the biggest problem with going to
autonomics 3.0 or X dot Y is that
everyone forgets about knowledge
representation and this is a fundamental
requirement for any serious AI
practitioner or researcher also called
knowledge engineering what Dean was just
talking about has been called the
qualification problem so for any
common-sense rules that you want to
encode there's a huge number of
exceptions right so how do I make a
generic statement and then qualify it to
be applicable and that certainly present
in networking so without better
knowledge representation mechanisms and
not just intolerant ologies right but I
mean ontologies most IETF errs don't
even know how to spell the word let
alone what it means so we need to make a
focused effort in knowledge
representation and as a general thing
yes deep learning is important and
machine learning and blah blah blah
but they're so generic that we're just
gonna spin our wheels and not do
anything I think and grant I'm speaking
about as a contributor also to the
effort with Jefferson and the Chandra
with that the message you wanted to pass
is we acknowledge all the the body of
Oregon has been done in autonomic
networking cognitive networking whatever
you call it but they may be stuff that
we still need to address and I think
collectively as in mentioned John and
maybe others with previous presentation
we need to identify specific areas
domains where we want to concentrate
activity of this research group to say
there are still things to do on that and
that could could help the research and
that eventually also somatization so
it's just kind of a call for get
together and then and identify those
areas together
AHA we are over time we need to close
because there will be another working
group after that I talked with Alex so
he's not it's okay that we skip his
presentation thank you for your
attention thank you for staying with us
even with the power outage thank you for
the remote presenters it was not easy to
to understand what's happening so we
have still ization and after the next
after this one which will be a more
general discussion about networks in AI
and we also have this dedicated meeting
tomorrow on Ethan base networking
thank you very much and don't forget the
blue sheets if you have not sign it we
can still have time to do that can I
also yes to the ready for a minute