okay okay so welcome everybody this is
under network management research group
but this is not exactly about network
management or not only about network
management this is actually a special
session on artificial intelligence and
networking and this is a bit of a trial
balloon I would say I did a heart of RFC
in London on what not only what network
management could do with AI but mostly
what not even what AI could do to
networks but but also what networks
needed to do to help artificial
intelligence so that's why we're having
this meeting so I hope you're all here
for that again it's a bit of a trial
balloon so we don't really know where
that is going to go but we know that
it's a topic that has had a lot of
attention in the past a year I would say
and we felt it was important to at least
have an open discussion about it
so again so why are why are we here and
a cute little typo why are we here again
to discuss how this could evolve we have
a press two presentations what's missing
there we have a net
for AI and then I don't know what the
other title is but there's two
presentation so it's gonna take about I
would say 3540 minutes and then we're
going to come back and we have a summary
of some of the options that could move
us forward again by looking at it from
different aspects easier things the
low-hanging fruits for this and the
things I get to be more complicated and
again while you're here what we would
like you to start thinking is again a
lot of people have talked about using AI
in networking but how would also use
networking to help AI so I think this is
what a little bit with the first
presentations is about so Rachel are you
ready
Thank You chairman thank you everyone
for being here it's so late my name is
Rachel Chen from Huawei today my topic
is about AI Inc network the topic is
about AI in network which means
networking for our AI so which is the
chairman just mentioned so it's
particularly not about the artificial
intelligence or network so we can start
from the one typical use case about the
D on training platform so this this
diagram shows the process how idea and
training going so during the
distribution phase okay so maybe I can
just so during the a distribution phase
the model parameters are distributed
from the parameter server to all the
workers and during the aggregation phase
the workers calculate the gradient and
then send them to the parameter server
so the traffic model here of the two
phases one to many and many to one
respectively so if we reduce the network
traffic between the parameter and switch
we can accelerate the training which is
very important because long training
might take up to tens of days as this
table shows so we have done some kind of
experiment that the
shows that the data transmission between
the parameter server and the workers
takes the majority of the time so we can
see from dates table they for example
the via obesity model the calculation
time takes about 218 mini second yr one
single iteration it takes around seven
seven thousand millisecond so so it's a
majority of the time the data
transmission accounts accounts too much
so for the on the other hand
Scott Schenker's team from the UC
Berkeley they have to also some
experiment about this to add the English
world computing and multicast to reduce
the end-to-end training time of the
obesity idea on Jenny model for example
to 129 so theoretically speaking we when
we introduced the in network computing
and multicast we can still use the cheap
switch rather than they much more
expensive so it's a cost-effective way
to to do the a ira native training so
why why you might wonder the end-to-end
training time is greatly reduced so
let's take the aggregation face I
mentioned this traditionally the switch
just work as traffic over the traffic
the workers have note the traffic from
the workers to the switch and then the
switch just deliver the traffic to the
parameter server so what if we
introduced the computing and caching
capability into network after the image
work aggregation
and we can transfer the results to a
parameter server so we can greatly
reduce the traffic from switch to the
parameter silver so which is almost a
seminar during the distribution phase if
we add caching capability we store model
parameters and then it distributed to
the workers so we can greatly reduce the
traffic from the PS to the switch so
yeah
most recently the there are many
researchers about the in network
computing which has missed some of them
the most important publications for
example DeMarco Collini
proposed in that work computers at an
idea whose time has come the experiment
shows that a large number of notch data
reduction ratio and a similar decrease
in workers computation time and also
scar Shankar seem they propose to the
change Network even ocean for TNS so the
experiments showing that optimizing the
network fabric can improve the training
time and also someone from the granham
its structure they propose to the
scalable hierarchical aggregation
protocol which is also almost to the
same the same effect effective way Chile
in improved so and also this year in
August there will be a in network
computing related workshop in Sikkim so
you might be interested in that
and besides computing in network caching
and also the consensus are also being
researched recently with some extra
extraordinary achievements for example
the immigrant caching it can
obtain the capability which is similar
to the mouth cast
so all these that looks quite promising
but you might wonder if we add X
functions into the network it might
violate the end-to-end argument which
means we need to be cautious to add new
functions if they are not used by
majority of applications and also it
might impact the TCP transport the
security and the privacy issues might
emerge so or maybe we can first to avoid
develop ad hocs notions and also develop
new abstractions of data plan and new
architecture to make for yourself new
programmable devices and meanwhile these
capabilities are generic enough and
decoupled from specific applications
then we trial it first today in the
constrained areas for example the data
center related data center network and
also we we need to keep in mind that the
existing program of all network devices
are designed for forwarding so it's
limited for the X functions for example
that some of the limitations are the
size of the cache table the number of
bytes that the devices can duplicate
manipulate on each packet and also the
floating points etcetera so we believe
that we can propose a good research
topic which to to jump out from the
offshore of devices and to find the
sweet spot between the pens and seconds
and also to provide the requirements for
the next generation programmable devices
so that's all for my presentation any
comments I have a question
my chair off my chair hat off so
essentially what you're saying is that
you feel that to introduce artificial
intelligence and then network we need to
have distributed computing because you
you started from artificial intelligence
and you finished with it works ok ok so
I'm saying that from your presentation
we understand that what you are
suggesting is that to enable artificial
intelligence in the network
you also need distributed computing and
the network because you started your
presentation where artificial
intelligence and finished with a a call
a call for action on distributed
computing is that what you think is
going to enable artificial intelligence
I think basically in the first stage we
were mentioning that working try out in
the data center manner to the network so
the first trial of being the data center
in digital network ok well we can take
it off because there's a lot of of
activity around distributed computing in
the network and that actually I would
agree that this is a good application
any other comments questions okay well
you have a question I guess I'm close
enough right no simply a reflection
because you mentioned is a violation of
the enjoined principles of the
end-to-end argument I that can be right
as long as I mean the violation can
happen if someone some entity in the
middle decides without the other the two
ends of the of the communication to make
a deployment of anyway
computational facility but if it is
either of the sides and I would like to
see these more in terms of research on
the side of the users if I as an user
instead of using only this and
connecting to a cloud that is who knows
where I decide to push my function
somewhere in the in the network under my
control
we are not violating any end-to-end
principle I invest pushing forward the
my end just agree with you I completely
agree with you I don't know if Rachel
agrees with you but I do we can also
discuss after the second brick we can
also discuss after the second
presentation thank you very much Rachel
and I think she needs to be very thanked
because she prepared this on my request
like in two days so thank you very much
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
so Peter will give a second talk which
is on essential artifacts for
intelligent driven networks and I think
we are learning and improving because I
asked him to prepare this presentation
one hour ago I am actually reusing so if
you happy if you have been in the in the
previous session I maybe so but I will
mention everything from from different
perspective that means concentrating in
what artificial intelligence is and
means for for the network especially for
the network management because we have
two sides that means that artificial
intelligence can be used both in the
data plane and in the control and
management plane so but I will
concentrate in general and how AI is
coming exploited in the whole network
not just management or but I will
mention may not mean but it's not just
targeted not so but I will first start
clarifying science and some concepts in
general many people say Oh a I and an L
Honda Honda they are they are but no
they are different ml is one technique
inside AI a has a broader spectrum and
many topics like perception reasoning
and planning are not widely exploited
currently in both even in neither in the
network in the data plane or in the
management plane so on the other hand we
have to differentiate that intelligence
it's not equal to intelligent that means
that we can manage intelligence
information in order to to take
decisions for the data plane or
management plane but that doesn't mean
that that that decisions are being taken
intelligently that they can be
systematic based on intelligence
information taken from from from the
from the network in this sense
intelligence emphasizes in the gathering
of that information we can use that the
intelligence methods to gather
information and then use
systematic or AI that is the same method
in order to to take decisions from that
information on the other hand
intelligent methods would be we can use
telemetry information is more more
systematic in order to take decisions
okay so why I weigh AI must be in the
network in general and in the management
plane specifically first one the key
part is that decisions in general or in
management but also in the data plane
are more and more complex because this
the system as are bigger they are
composed of a Terrigen use elements that
you have built on machines we have
physical machines we have elements that
can be moved etc and and all of that
must be joined together to make the
system metaphor system work so AI is
required for that also the operational
environments are dynamic that means that
were just mentioned is not a static it's
very complex and it changed on time
moreover network devices becoming
autonomic we know we have here the the
the animal group that is working on that
so they have to take complex decisions
that on their place so they need some
kind of deliberation know and actually
zero touch networks that we had been
posted recently are based on that on
that sense and probability is shaky on
that approach and finally as where a
means is why not AI
we must not be scared of ai ai is just a
tool we can't use it
or we cannot use that we cannot we can
decide to use or not to use it but it's
not something that we have to be scared
also exploiting AI into the net
we can push the concept of what we can
say the 8id net is intelligence driving
networking because it allows to easily
process intelligence information and
take decisions to drive know the network
in this case aim AAI methods will have a
big impact in the in the management and
control of the network and the knowledge
needed from such data can be used to
decide the strategic to take staticy
decisions for the evolution of that
network we can talk now about some
knowledge no intelligence dive in
network using the this evolution from
data to wisdom say we start from data
then we get information when we qualify
the data then we get knowledge in this
in this sense when we understand the
data that information and finally we get
wisdom when we take decisions from that
information then in relation of this
intelligent diamond network we can say
that the structure of the network system
in general the structure is adapted by
taking migration in on the environment
and the all stimulus that are being
received perceived from that network so
we can use intelligent data to manage
the properly and exploit its potential
so we have different kinds of ways to
exploit that and but but AI methods in
general algorithms etc must be adapted
because currently they are focused on
the specific targets but we need to
adapt them to work on network problems
so during physical unbuilt or network
means can form a mass no and in order to
achieve the
system goes finally just to mention some
issues that must be work Adan would be
like methods that used that used to
retrieve the information must be assured
the quality of those methods must be
assured in some sense so we can be sure
that the information we are retrieving
for day what I mean is there for the
intelligence for less aid in the network
intelligence plane that information is
from good quality let's say the matrix
and data has been gathered following
some procedure that ensures that types
and quality of that information is
consistent also that information must be
formatted using some ontology that
common using common concepts so
different stakeholders meaning different
elements of the system and different
systems can understand that information
and finally the protocols used to
communicate that information must be
also adapted or at least well-defined no
to be sure that the information is also
to ensure the quality but also that the
information is transmitted know and
communicated properly and that's it for
my from my side question please thank
you can you go back to your slide number
two I think was it number two the window
was describing then I'll find the one
that says AI what AI is and with this
one number one um yeah I think this
could be almost like a slide that
everybody should should look at because
this actually is very I think it's very
the very important slide ok any other
questions comments also from Howie next
slide can you explain it be more wide
network virtualization enable Network
automation
I'll second it's not it's not yes okay
that the formation is that network built
initiation enables Network automation
there is not a requirement is that you
can automate things okay
in the in automate network management
but you cannot automate the network
without something bit work because you
cannot create a physical router but you
can create a bit order is why what I
mean in that sentence is that you cannot
omit the net or itself not not just the
management you can automate the
management of physical reuters physical
elements okay but you cannot manage the
network itself if it is if you are not
using built well some chai you can use
some slicing okay but this is some
technique of utilization so you need
some kind of bitter engine technique in
order to be able to automate actually
the network know to meet operation of
the network but automate the network
itself just to not contradict but may
complement what you mentioned we may
also automate the physical world but for
that we need kind of robot you can it's
just that maybe the threshold is quite
different if it's software base of
iteration base it's only your script or
Co here you need whereas in the physical
world we need physical ultimate today is
like something I would like to see that
just because it's funny no but there are
some people doing that yeah yeah but in
the future I think that the transition
will take over that's I think I think we
will need most of yeah yeah most of the
also the physical world
gone gone home the if you are lying I
have a one kitchen could you go to page
five yes
one more our next sorry Peduto pretty
poor yeah I missing yours or the
intelligence data which piece you you
said intelligence data so I I'm
wondering what's the meaning of
intelligence data because thought era is
is not a core it can be our method to
achieve of course so if we study or
teach or make up algorithm model then
there are is all sorts of the piece of
the corporation so would you want you
some intelligence into the data
no no what I mean here is intelligence
data is sorry here what I mean is that
is here is data gathered it for that is
gathered for the specific purpose of
knowing what to do in the network it's
not something like the data is
intelligent by itself no its
intelligence later sorry for the then
ones but it is that means that this this
data you are getting that for the
specific purpose of taking decisions no
you are gathering in general you are
statistically gathering it
no you are not systematically gathering
it so that's the reason and that's also
why okay then you know in in real world
there are lots of data in tera as it's
different the pictures and different
date on go there so do you want to put
it simple make out or standardized
garlic
we are configured to they are up Romero
do you need you need some do you need
some in the end you need some ontology
and some common format to let's say in
code that they tell that you have
gathered of course you need not but here
I push that the key is that
how you gather that the data and how do
you exploit you exploit that data of
course we need some format and I push
also the format ontology etcetera that
we need in order to manage all that
information in general that can be
extracted knowledge and in general
information very good presentation in
congratulation who is I have to comment
one related to slide number two related
to number three
the comment not the previous one so here
there is a very good example how I was
used and is used in networking with
success a tool from AI called rule by
system policies were invented seventy
years ago in our community but it's
embraced in networking because it's easy
to apply yeah in small not in big
numbers so that's a good example how the
whole thing and work in other words
something simple version of AI may
substantially increase the intelligence
and other things so there could be now
unfortunately I will come in the same
second number three is that why it is
obvious to me at least or maybe not the
management area ecosystem changed
substantially last period and is moving
towards managing the network service is
not the connectivity so personally I
will forget about the connectivity part
of it here and add value if possible
with some techniques in managing better
autonomically programmatically and 2n0
touch if possible this new service
network interfere either per slice or
any other form and look for something
simple to be used so for the name of the
game changes towards service management
in practice yes that would be my
recommendation how to move forward
beyond this philosophical question which
are valid but a simple version is needed
these are my two comments and we can say
that is AI applied in network they've
been in service management let's say in
that sense I stew card so I do networks
by day and I do machine learning on
nights and weekends and I've been trying
to bring them together for many years so
I agree with much of what you said AI is
not the same thing as machine learning
automation is not the same thing as
autonomy we've had all of these pieces
separately in our networks for many
years frequently with a human in the
loop
I think what's new is where we're
looking at deploying autonomous systems
that continue to learn online and so I'd
like to introduce into the discussion
the word surprise my work in machine
learning mostly uses genetic programming
I evolve code and it surprises me and
frequently it surprises me in ways that
are not conducive to my achieving the
engineering solution that I saw but if
it didn't surprise me I would argue that
it's not terribly interesting now in in
operating networks we generally hate to
be surprised by our networks so I guess
what I would like to to throw out there
is especially if we start for instance
evolving protocols there's absolutely no
reason why a genetic programming system
can't be used to evolve a protocol what
are we going to do if these things on
the one hand either fail to surprise us
which is indicative that they are not
really doing anything much new for us or
if they do surprise us now in both in
both scenarios I would either they don't
surprise us so everything is doing what
we want to do we will be happy but if
they should price us what I mean is that
we are in control of that means
intelligence doesn't mean that on
uncontrolled things no
you we will we will not just put a seat
there unless hope that the network or
network system or service is working
properly no no we tablet some policies
rules etc so all we're ecosystem of
intelligent methods is working inside
our parameters so in any way it would be
good okay so I'm laying a message from
the mythical from Jefferson since you
are using terms from the other area like
AI ml it would be nice if you could
bring some references and the second
point is more in the form of a question
would it be useful to have a document on
AI ml terminology in network management
okay
good comment maybe it's good to push
forward this technology and also maybe a
broader ontology in that sense that
means not just definition of concepts
but also the relation of the those
concepts that they have that's again
taking the words of this commentary I
don't remember the name
it was to define the a I make reference
of where to get proper information how
to get the proper definition of a IML
etc okay I would say this is very good
and maybe yeah generic sense of the
networking world yes okay
it would be really good any other
question I think there is another
question why Jeremy is going to the mic
just because we were discussing about
some references doing a bit of promotion
that I've been recently a survey
published on yeah machine learning for
four networks I can give you the
reference I can put it in the minutes if
you like it's quite I was extensive
survey and I think it could be a good
basis for this discussion or the further
steps German France we know yeah maybe
just to just very going back to the
previous question yes I think it's good
Frances then I don't think it's I think
it's not the role of the enemy are able
to define what is a in I think it's no I
sorry the reference okay but we will not
define that we will gather the
definition I we we should not I agree
with Susan I think you could can
probably you can really find nice
reference the difference to have that
dot all that references all that
definitions in one document so as a
guide to say well I can go there and
find what but which I would say that in
the area of surveys and think that that
refers and do these gathering okay but
you know just small interruption we will
close the line after Alex because we
still have also to go back to uni choice
lies because we would like to shape a
bit discussion and like quarterly and so
then maybe one question when you I think
slide six just let me know when I
stopped seven this is six six yes you
talk a lot up with you the data so we
said is that we should work and data and
data format a priori Oh could we rely on
artificial intelligence in order to
let's say define kind of automated way
the data we want yeah but we need some
kind of ontology we need to define the
concepts that were I mean the relations
and how and also the format and how to
encode that we can't rely on some
intelligent methods in order that can't
this for example that in mind
determine the attributes of the
information we are gathering but the
resulting piece of data in order to be
useful need to follow some kind of
ontology
so otherwise it would be difficult or
and you must adapt all algorithms to
that specific data if you follow an
ontology you can use any algorithm that
is of course using that ontology but
that that kind of noisy is there a
notion that if the problem is well
specified to bring you want to target
that the method can find the ontology
actually we have to so that's it I mean
not not manually no no the ontology is
it if you we can define extendable
ontology that can be increasingly with
the album okay but we need to contour
that part we need to define that at
least then let's say meta meta data you
should maybe keep this in my open and
keep this open too if you want me to to
think about the application of you not
want to restrict too much now I think we
yeah but we need that I insist we need
that because otherwise you are just
working on your specific problem and of
course that's not not bad but we are
working on general problems ok that's
what I mean that we need some some kind
of abstract contour getting something
that can you may disagree maybe we have
to still have one comment and good
actual imaginable also point not only no
it's fine it's perfectly fine that for
me Helen Helen can you hear me I'm
deliberately I just wanted to follow up
on the previous comment about and
surprise in networks and I think that's
a very good point for lots of network
operators don't like surprises
a very conservative kind of
institutional culture of very
conservative organizations and I think
it'd be interesting in the research
group to kind of look at some of those
and the broader issues about what's bad
about this AI in network management or
how it's going to change how operators
are going to run
network not a sort of very detailed
level but kind of bit of you know more a
higher level yeah and yeah I think
that'd be interesting this you know sort
of how do you it's the what happens to
kind of roll back of if you change
something at the moment have quite a
good idea oh we've made a little change
it didn't work we can roll it back and I
kind of feel that in this it's going to
be much harder to do that sort of thing
so people have their will the will the
human to have able to come in and
control in some sense if something goes
wrong or you just have to leave it to
the AI to work out how to get out this
problem that's happened and those sort
of high-level questions I think would be
very interesting research topics as I'm
not aware of of you know kind of work to
address that okay thank you for coming
I've fully support this comment and it
specially also because I think here in
IETF
it's also quite conservative I think for
instance most of our protocols are
really deterministic I mean we define
every states of the protocol the
behavior of the packets we expect what
and if something goes out of this it's
usually dropped or discard and if we
move towards more machine learning
especially in AI used to be different
machine learning approaches we have to
understand a bit more of randomness or
stuck at stochastic aspect of the
behavior which is quite different from
the determinism of current protocol so
when those things will collide and it
will be interesting to see
okay so now we go back to the slides
that we had prepared
your pusher okay so this is something
that we discussed together so there's
there's a number of options and I agreed
with the previous presentation that
machine learning and AI there are tools
they're not ends in themselves so the
current low-hanging fruit if you look at
what is being published right now in a
lot of conferences on AI networking is
that you take an AI algorithm you apply
it to a network problem and you see what
happens and you know this again a lot of
people have done that there's lot of
results and I think some of it you know
for a research group it's interesting
nice makes nice paper but there's
probably a more interesting way to look
at it actually a few months ago I
listened to a presentation from Andrea
Goldschmidt who actually had developed
an AI approach actually for the physical
layer of a network which was like a very
it was it was actually very refreshing
and everything was that she wanted to
develop a network specific AI or ml
algorithm to solve a specific problem in
your case it was diffusion of
information and then turn once you have
them then turn them around and say well
now we knew that they worked in that
concept let's turn them around and see
if they can actually themselves now
start produce new paradigms for and and
that that could be helpful in the ietf
so I think this is more interesting
because it starts from the knowledge
that people have from the network it's
not some some generic thing that we can
come out on the web I have and I think
this is what a little bit of Rachel was
doing I have another approach and I
think the second one is very much
appropriate for the people in network
management and people who actually do
fault detection and things like that
the other one which is a little bit what
Rachel was was
doing and it is some thoughts that are
outside of this room and relate to all
kinds of things related also to edge
networking is now you add some computing
in the network and then you see how that
added functionality because now you have
way more computing power and things can
be updated can actually support the AI
algorithms to perform network tasks I
tried to find the person but he was not
at the IETF there was a presentation in
London about somebody who had used an AI
approach to do congestion control in
networks which was kind of fun because
first it was new and second it was a
good application for training and
algorithm to detect when things start
going badly and it was very interesting
but then again see once we have these
algorithms that are part of the
computing inside the network again the
other thing is this is the thing that
Laura and I really believe in is the
same thing you flip them around and now
by flipping them around you can say how
these algorithms in their own way can
influence the behavior of the network
and not just being part of the you know
the non forwarding functions there is a
common issue for all there's a few
common issues for all of this there's
always the thing should it be
centralized maybe for some management
functions it's may be better to be
centralized as one to have somebody who
actually can make at one point it goes
back to making a decision about the
whole network obviously in the case of a
distributed intelligence and computing
the decentralized approach is more maybe
more appropriate but they all share into
a few things they need CPU they need
energy and then you get into
sustainability issues if you just start
distributing how do you make sure that
they're federated and synchronized and
again that's what what is needed inside
the networks you support that
of course performance if we're going to
do that and it's not more performing
than what we're doing right now it makes
nice papers but it's not the tools that
the first presenter was doing so we
would like to open the discussion we do
not have and just to start we do not
have a specific way forward we're very
much interested to know what the
community thinks about again if we take
a I as a tool it may not have and again
decentralizing it it may not have a role
as a specific research group it may have
a role in a number of research groups
obviously there's a lot of applications
for it there could be also future work
that's more into a single a single
research group so we want to open the
discussion to people who are here and to
see what people are thinking so now we
have about twelve minutes time flies and
please
you know we're open the floor don't be
shy
you will any up before for a comment so
now it's time just to express different
viewpoints different opinions ideas
things you think I'll not die girl she
should finish read not tackle whatever
[Music]
extreme so just as one comment I think
in terms of what I would find
interesting is when one hand busy there
are the AI applications and the network
management are genes of outsider
standard I think all those applications
are actually fairly straightforward
basically the applications about there
are not so many surprises there but I
think for research group is actually
more interesting is to apply to really
actually networking problems so not
specific in that network management but
naturally problem so for instance
routing decision as well can can how can
a I helped with that all the work I see
on the on the on the controllers path
computation that means a etc etc so I
think
trying to apply or see basically what
role I can play to make networking
better is I think actually the more
interesting question or the question I
would find more interesting as a
research group than looking at the
management problems so it's just from
virtual but above it developers yet
there's another reflection that comes
from India so mom
conversations I have had with other
colleagues he's about the idea that we
could start we should start thinking
about security as well normally we tend
to think about the AI as a helper the
tool but also can be always you can use
a hammer to nail down to network to put
a nail on the the wall and you can use a
tool tool you can use a hammer to key
someone and say I can be an extremely
complicated tool if it's used by wrong
hands you think about that the typical
script giving that instead of running a
person can have a high enabled for scan
you can look for vulnerabilities I'm not
talking about Skynet yet ok so figure
out no no think about that well so some
kind of these surprises that start to be
behaving in a way in which is not and
I'm not saying that we need do you
remember the turing institute in the
Neuromancer
and this is something that we should I
mean not talking about this exactly but
about an environment in which you can
somehow find ways of reacting to
potential attacks that are enabled by AI
they are supported by a race this is one
thing and the second thing is some
mechanisms for doing some kind of
attestation or security assessments over
the a behavior is something that we
should consider as well before I mean
let's put security as
I had in the design and the thinking
process Philibert lien i mean AI is
driven by data isn't it so if my network
is being run by the way way its
operating is being driven by AI
decisions as an attack all I've got to
do is work out how to get data in the
manipulates my AI to get my network in
some statements a disaster so I think I
mean in terms of this I think the first
one is fair enough and will continue to
happen but in terms of the others I
think it'd be interesting think about
what problems AI can cause and how to
solve this just sort of touched on one
Diego and I I can actually make a
comment on this I think also we have to
define what we call intelligent devices
and things I was at an edge an edge
computing conference last week or the
week before in Boston and people were
talking about the immense amount of data
that will be accumulated by intelligent
vehicles and this is actually completely
driven by the insurance companies we
want to have access to every
instantiation of every sensor and that
creates these terabytes of information
and data that have to be moved across
the network and that's why this is
actually where the bottom ones are about
a lot is one what is needed in the
network to support that incredible
amount of data which is essentially
coming to the edge and how do we need to
send it completely back to the through
the cloud for all the processing or
could there be some intermediate
processing that would reduce the load on
the hops this is actually why these two
other elements are there is that when we
think about intelligent elements and
data we I don't think we actually I was
shocking from
and they have the same thing with
surveillance cameras in smart cities so
I think there's this idea that what what
also can these algorithms can help us do
to to reduce the size and the sheer
overwhelming
you know quantity of information but mom
woman
so it's interesting because I had a
comment bolt regarding the surprises and
how much data we have to process there's
a couple of things that come to my mind
is regarding surprises is how much
control do we have what is the privacy
for example how are we going to maybe
reduce the amount of data so we reduce
the amount of surprises because we buy
feeling so much data we might I try come
up with answers that we didn't even want
to ask the question I was thinking that
security and privacy should be really
part of this of this of any kind of work
that we're doing that's one and second
thing I'm going to throw a buzzword here
but I think part of this is also what is
the intent of anybody who is actually
managing your network and does that
intent conflict to another letting to
different administrative domains and do
they have conflicting intents and that
makes muddies the water a little bit but
I think this is something we need to
think about as well is what do you do
when you have conflicts and you don't
really get what what is what is the end
goal when we're talking about goals
Juwan INRIA um so first of all just
emphasize what I've been selling
security and privacy so I think we
should take the opportunity of you speak
closer to the mic you should take the
opportunity of AI in order to actually
collect less that I think we are usually
talking about collecting a lot of data
with the AI which is not I mean always
necessary
so maybe from a user perspective I would
be happy if busy yeah we can at the end
phonetically this an opportunity to take
Segond regarding security yes I think
what which is our topic II and I of the
adversity are learning in machine
learning let's say address our learning
so if you put AI for doing some
operation you increase incredibly your a
let's say attack surface particular I
really like the idea of putting some
something to the networking network
computation but if you use on AI as
black box and you don't really know what
happens here it actually at the end you
can and you can add V the written very
nice attack because you don't really I
mean under the process and if you want
to keep an in the line weight and you
know exactly what happens and you can we
end any knife and loop or things that
really impact your performance on so I
think it's very important to take sector
doing to consideration this is a circle
roster just a linguistic clarification
coming from my background which was form
a telephonic informal network operator I
think we shouldn't be mixing their
intent and objectives regarding the last
thing one thing is the the objective the
network operating line may have and
that's that the network runs and I think
you may have the same and then you may
have conflicting policies but I wouldn't
use intently there in that in that
specific I would use simpler words like
objectives and policies
this is topic for tomorrow Leon from
China Mobile and I have a general
comments on this topic so um I think
artificial intelligence is a great topic
to be tackled in IETF especially you
know for for for network use
applications but in terms of skill but I
eat a variety of here I think it's much
more interesting to
to tackle the problem of network for
artificial intelligence instead of
artificial intelligence for network you
know and um well I think it's more
important for example as an operator
actually in the current network we have
a lot of data from the network no not
talking about using new technologies for
example a mentor seems losing the
existing technology we have a lot of
data but we don't know how to use it so
it and those data are not collected in a
very efficient way um you know it's it's
it's just useless it's there so it's
very important to tackle the problem how
we can collect the data from from the
network more efficiently and to filter
out the data to be the input of your AI
algorithm and to get the output you want
for example if we have a long massive
collection of bandwidth I mean live
bandwidth data from the real network
would that give you a prediction of how
you configure different domain of
network to to have to give you a out
spirit of for example for low latency
network I mean we have some research
project with vendors to tackle this like
like converting the dimension of how you
using some type of algorithm to
converting the dimension of from
bandwidth to latency using some existing
data yeah so that's what I mean it's I
think it's more interesting to to to
tackle the problem how the data can be
collected how the network technology to
support an AI algorithm instead of
investigating a algorithm for networking
thank you Alex we're out of time okay so
I don't I think just one an hour one
hour for this was obviously not enough
and I don't think we came up with a I
think we still have these two things AI
for network and network for AI and I
think it follows pretty well with the hi
and I had
discuss that maybe there could be two
different types of approaches to this so
AI as an application in the network and
the network being a feeder for the AI
and we can continue the discussion I
don't know there's a number of mailing
lists I've been involved and I don't
know exactly how we're going to do that
but we'll find a way yeah and to build
on that I would say if if you're
interested if you think we need to keep
having meetings discussion or try to
organize and structure this those
questions I don't I ate here for IOT F
scopes okay we are still here I'm here
also tomorrow so come to us I mean if
not only to us I mean anybody can
discuss but we have to understand you
can use the meaning list or if we need
to prepare something for the next
meeting in between the meeting but if if
you want to go beyond is just one our
discussion and all the previous attempts
we need to understand a bit more to
define some directions or maybe some
areas where we say we want to give
priority to this because there is five
ten person that wants to invest a bit of
time on that so just but we don't we go
to step beyond and and so because I'm
the one who started this and I launched
a balloon thank you so very much to be
here and again let's continue the
discussion I think it's kind of cool
stuff thank you very much