good morning everybody
dick okay so what welcome to the second
session of us a we have 90 minutes so we
we don't have the full two and a half
hour so only that first day in 90
minutes and so this is not well a fill
up from here with this make sure to look
at it everything you say and you
contribute is still under that in on
well a thanks to a Dan for being our
jabber describe and for Tony for a
voluntold to our to be I mean it blue
shirts blue seats will be and here's our
schedule for the day
so a Hannah's will start to talk about
apop tokens yes they to do that then
dick will talk about distributive
and then John will talk about a security
bcp and he - for this agenda and you
comment about this okay let's get going
test test so we'll see but it takes 50
minutes to discuss this may take two
hours there let's see
enjoy okay that's so who of you doesn't
remember the pop token work oh man I
mean that's not you guys remember
okay but I will very briefly go through
this so that the story was and you see
that sort of manifested in in different
documents is that and particularly also
in there is also it's a little bit of an
a so as a high-level introduction if you
will see it that way then so they we had
these two slightly different patterns
for symmetric versus a symmetric keys if
this start with a symmetric key version
first when the client talks to
dollarization server to get the access
and the Refresh token it it made that
request and indicated that it wants over
here he wants and a symmetric key
version and there are few parameters
that are pass along which I will
describe in in subsequent slides but the
important part is that the token comes
back a pop token comes back and along
with it
keys that are sent from the
authorization server to the client for
use by the client the access token
itself also has keys it's a pop-rock
natural but those us are in sort of like
they are so this is the usual pop token
so it's actually consumed only by the
resource server but in the symmetric key
solution the symmetric key has to be
sort of carried encrypted in that
payload and we have that data structures
defined for doing so in in all AHS we
had all the work with the JSON web token
and then the corresponding pop token
extension has been long done and we are
about to finish so if you attended the
ACE session this week you saw the
discussion about finishing the pop token
extension for the CWD de sibour web
darling okay Brian the asymmetric
version is a little slightly different
because the client doesn't need to have
the authorization server generate the
public/private key pair but instead it
just the client shows tells the
authorization server what public key to
include in the in the bottle
and that's described here and we use the
same mechanisms for doing so and as the
access token in this case just contains
the the public key or fingerprint of it
and there's nothing that needs to be
sent back from the authorization server
to the client because the client already
has that public and private key okay and
then of course then the client when he
talks to the resource server it has to
use the pop token in to demonstrate
possession of the and the key and it
does this in a variety of different ways
and specifically in in work done in AIDS
there are different ways defined to tie
it to specific security protocol there's
a DTLS based version as oscar version
and so on and so on okay
so unless I'm in comparison to OS where
we had this struggle with the HTTP
signing in the core working group people
came up with this the Oscar mechanism to
protect various headers and payloads you
know for for co-op and they also we had
that presentation a few ideas I go that
group also believed that they have come
up with a solution for HTTP but that's a
separate topic that I don't want to go
through here now so what's the status of
this of all of this so in in the ace of
our specification there's a there's a
framework document which builds on on OS
as the name indicates and it uses it
uses the pop token functionality only it
doesn't use bearer tokens and it also
has this points to the CW teen instead
of the JWT for efficiency reasons and as
I mentioned earlier there are also other
protocols used in HTTP we have also
worked on other protocols in OS on other
than HTTP if you remember that the
sample is AP gssapi for email that was a
little longer ago there was actually I
wasn't wasn't done in hours but then
under the supervision of in any case in
one of the use so the different use case
isn't there so long a use case document
available in is that tells what you
could use the whole framework for but
one of the use cases is where the client
for example is a smartphone or tablet
that talks to an IOT device and to
control it to configure it and do
something and their client the OERs
client uses HTTP to talk to the
authorization server just a regular OS
authorization server that supports opto
can you such a
instead of since the authorization
server can issued tokens with different
types it can in this case for
performance reasons can issue
CWD pop tokens but then as the client
gets all this stuff it passes it on to
the IOT device for example using coop or
some of the other IOT related protocols
like imputed ease and so the current
status is that in that document which is
going to end the working group last call
fairly soon in I think Jim said in
September it defines parameters for that
exchange with the bop tokens and I'm
going to talk about the parameters in a
second
it defines them for coop and HTTP to
cover those different use cases so that
text is there and some of it has been
taken from at that time expired key
distribution Bob key distribution
document that we have in our working
group additionally it turns out that the
web RTC guys they have also defined and
dokin format it was one sent for review
to the list and so they have a binary
encoding that is not C bore at that
times I think CBO didn't wasn't
finalized or this met up so they have a
separate but open format then of course
o us allows different formats so that's
perfectly fine and we did a review of
that and they use this with their thumbs
turn fireball traversal technology great
so more usage in this web RTC real-time
communication on the web mechanism and I
provided a little bit more details of
that work also in pointers in the link
you can see on the screen in any case
what that means is that we are trying to
at least in two different groups outside
of us trying to finish the pop token
work which was in this in this working
group a little bit underappreciated at
least with respect to that document we
have worked on other pop token solutions
so there it does that I tried to update
the documents with the help of my
co-authors and get them in line with
what the latest statuses and it turns
out that we ran into three issues which
I would like to get some guidance on
from the working proof to actually then
execute those changes I didn't want to
surprise you all with suddenly totally
different documents and the three issues
I believe are maybe there are others the
HTTP based parameters which were
previously in in in the document and now
in the ACE document is that something
you guys are comfortable with or where
should they go should they go back into
the oils group form and I will talk a
little bit more about this the other one
is there's this there's some
misalignment between what's in the
bottle can distribution document and
what's in the Azores document the
different parameters used and and maybe
one is better than the other or maybe
those are equally fine or talked about
those things and then finally there's a
there's a question about the encoding of
the key transport that's that those are
the main issues are haven't and happy to
hear others this one let me very briefly
summarize in case you haven't read the a
source document recently the couple of
parameters defined and I mentioned the
first one in previous always working
group meetings there's one the audience
are parameter and there are as the name
indicates and we had discussions and
contributions and drafts in this working
group are before this parameter is
useful when you for example in a
symmetric key solution when you when the
client wants to tell the authorization
server what the target of that
communication is going to be which
resource server am I going to send this
token finally do because the read the
authorization server needs to have that
information in are doing crypt the
symmetric key that goes into the the CWD
pop token otherwise it doesn't know
how to do that unless it uses some some
other some other mechanisms so but
that's where we use that parameter now
the second parameter is this
conformation parameter which is used to
carry the keys from the authorization
server to the to the client and also to
provide some parm
I think parameters to the public key
fingerprint from the client to the
authorizations onto other systems also
as a shoe seller there's also one other
R parameter that you may not have seen
before this is called RS underscore CNF
this parameter gives the client
information about bra public key to be
used with the by the resource server
okay I'm not going to talk about this
one any further but just to let you know
there's a there's a Kumpf and CNF in the
RS underscore CNF in case it's confusing
yes a chat question from Phil hunt
I think the Block in the OAuth working
group is the final step how to do
message authentication HTTP request
signing seems impossible Honus are the
techniques from the other groups that
could be applied more generally yes so
um so the other so in there in the 8th
working group the focus is obviously not
on HTTP so there are other protocols
used in the ID context where solutions
have been worked out on how this request
signing looks like and maybe you can
elaborate on that but the mechanism that
was defined for co-op is apparently also
applicable to other protocols that use a
restful paradigm including HTTP that's
what the presentation was about some odd
years ago when this topic was brought up
on the mailing list you may remember I I
can post a link again to the
presentation ludwik sites but there's
also the in ACE the the
Els profile which defines how to use
this conformation keys in the detail s
handshake in order to prove the
possession of these keys and I would
guess that this is applicable for TLS as
well I mean there was a draft in off by
Samuel and me recently saying how how we
did that and there was not a lot of
interest in itself we dropped that but
basically I assume that the stuff we do
with DTLS is really really easy to
transfer to TLS couple of observations
from the token binding work making
changes to the TLS stack and exposing
the ekm and all of the other things that
might be easier in other newer
environments is really really hard to
impossible so if you know it probably
reusing token binding which is already
going through all the pain of exposing
those additional parameters maybe yeah
is a way of doing it the other yeah and
we already have work going on on that
the other thing Brian and I put out a
draft on resource which replaced
audience we discovered that in practice
audience AUD is a parameter to the token
endpoint is really really problematic so
yes we need the parameter it's just
don't call it audience that it causes
all sorts of issues once you start
sending a jot to authenticate which has
an audience which is it the audience of
the resource server in the jot or the
audience that's supposed to be the the
the token endpoint it just we need a
different name so you suggest to
correlate the resource yeah that's
that's what okay that proposal was
calling this audience will
endless confusion okay so yes we need
the parameter that's just a really bad
name as it turned out and so since that
parameter has been defined in the ACE
working group which is defined for both
HTTP as well as coop as a parameter do
you see that that's a problem yeah
basically you can't generically use that
because the parameter already exists for
the token endpoint in some of the
authentication methods for no raw or
sorry at the authorization well at the
token endpoint and well you know if
we're know I was after of something
different do you see that if we change
the name of the parameter to resource in
a specification it will be applicable to
both co-op and HTTP with that would you
consider that as a problem so this was
actually not one of the issues that
thought it would be an issue Brian
Campbell I think that is potentially a
problem because it's it has completely
different semantics in in ace so and
there's only one registry so I would I
would prefer that it doesn't get used up
but why is that a different semantics if
I'm a client des which the authorization
so which so I but when I read it it was
a C bore and coded saying but before
it's a seaborne coded thing for the for
the coop as a for the point when it when
he's transported or coop but it's I
don't remember what what the encoding is
for HTTP so they're different different
encodings for different protocols as I
may have read it wrong it's read very
much the parameter definition read to me
like it was seaboard to the
authorization server we changed that
that's at some point through the
lifetime of the document so but but the
intention is to have our
all of those promises surrounded talking
about dia if they encoded differently
depending on whether they go on HTTP
verses to go on on co-op okay my mistake
done apologies so assuming we can sort
that out resource would be better than
audience yes if that was your question
no the question my question was do you
see a problem if we define this in the
ACE OS document for also for HTTP as
well as co-op not again it probably
depends on whether maybe the problem
with having it in co-op is that other
things make people may not find it etc
as part of of OAuth
I'm not violently opposed to having it
defined there but that may confuse
people and or cause it to be attempted
to be reinvented any number of times it
may be better to define it as a separate
separate speck in inoue because we have
a whole bunch of things in of' that are
going to want to use that this isn't the
only use case for that parameter so it's
not unique to pop tokens no no way how
the Braniff is different is it's more
generic you choices you could just says
the resource I'm I'm going to duck it so
it the the identifier that particular
parameter probably deserves its own
document so that it's easily
referenceable from other other aspects
or burying it down in in a co-op
document may be in an SOS talking to our
ace right so we don't need to sort that
out now particularly but we do okay we
really do because if we're sorting it
out now I would say for the sake of
clarity let's put it put that parameter
in its own document because again it's
been attempted to be defined at least
three or four times there there was
and a loan document on it in the word
Olaf working group right and that's
actually the downside because we as I
mentioned earlier the plan is to go to
working group last call in September
whereas this has been worked on in ours
for whatever reason because of different
objections are like four years and it
would be unfortunate if then there's
this dependency that where we start
things etc well that's also have
something to take into account if the
two people that objected to it last time
aren't objecting to it now than perhaps
we could do this relatively quickly
what's the one or the meeting min and
Finn I didn't I didn't say his name
don't know what do you think about this
Phil do you have an opinion about this
oh you want to briefly speak about this
topic what what is your sense now a few
years into that discussion he may have
gone back to us now no reason we it's a
middle of the day for him you know it's
more early morning in Vancouver yeah
yeah can you meet us we can't hear you
supposed to be speaking yeah it says
he's speaking but we can't hear you
Phil Phil you may need to unmute okay
okay a separate issue which is solution
yeah Tony
you want to come to the mic Tony Nidal
and I don't believe it's a separate
issue it could be an orthogonal issue
but I think we have to figure this out
at the same time I don't think you can
agree to this in in-state signing we're
gonna we're gonna totally forget about
it this time well we are talking about a
specific spec for adding a resource
parameter to the token endpoint we could
ignore it and allow pace to define it
for us I'm sure that that would that you
can see that option I think Tony the
question is not whether we are going to
define that parameter unregistered I
think we have passed that point that
decision has been made the question is
which document will it go and have two
choices ah yes a separate document order
as to a so our start here and I go to
senior thank you Tony so I think that
it's a better choice I didn't understand
John's point about token binding are you
[Music]
[Laughter]
the point is that if we're going to have
a presentment mechanism that's going to
start messing with the TLS transport we
already have mechanism we should focus
on that rather than trying to invent a
new if that gtp decision also has been
made already well we know in in a you
were just talking about well maybe it
may be a sought to rican if ace is
looking at doing a new presentment
mechanism over HTTP then perhaps they
ought to look at no not be using token
binding rather than it is not using TLS
bail mechanism it's not you it's not ace
is not defining a new presentment
mechanism over HTTP what it does is it
uses the keys as one of the
possibilities
the keys in individualís
shake to protect co-op okay okay so this
is DTLS specific it's a it's a it's a
there's a document that all right about
how to detail s in coop right so we are
not to worry about applying your CTL s
because we already have a mechanism for
that is my point
yeah for HTTP GLS that's fine yes okay
so good we we solved that issue that was
I I would expect it to be perfectly I
would expect to be used in doing co-op
over TLS to the the same mechanism to
DTLS that's fine
I would this time I've been expected to
work his what it's gonna be this its
permit from an API point of view is it
is identical yeah um some time ago Brian
Campbell wrote draft Campbell Oh auth
resource indicators I was colossal fit
and I think John was too yeah this
already solves the problem I fully agree
I think that we should now adopt that as
a working group document and finish it
well so there may be some stuff that
from the other co-op ace document around
encoding for other transports that you
want to call into it but yeah that
should be fairly quick work yeah I mean
Brian's already done the heavy lifting
we should just use it and I don't know
when the chairs want to call that
question but it there seems to be a lot
of people in the room who including
yourself we think that we need this
parameter it's already written down yeah
so maybe I'm maybe you can get the room
but just on this let the cute yeah
that's fantastic you're a gym shot I I'm
having a problem understanding John's
position on that the using the name
audience my understanding is that this
is basically
designed to be equivalent to the
audience in a CWT or a JWT so using a
different name seems odd well I'm not
saying use it as a different name in the
access token I'm saying that as a
request parameter where it conflicts
with the audience so when you're talking
when you're making a request to the
token endpoint adding an extra parameter
that says audience which is actually the
identifier for the resource server that
audience and the audience of your
request conflict once you put them in a
jot and send it as a that is one of the
can I can I try to clarify that because
John's confused although he's sort of
right audience has been a little bit
confusing we've used a Johnny we we've
used a Edie in our own implementation
and it's caused confusion with people
but the actual like conflict problem
that John's talking about is related to
the authorization request where we have
drafts that define a JWT encoded set of
the parameters passed the authorization
request and thus and it also allows for
the the audience then is a parameter
value in the JWT so there's a collision
with the audience name that I don't
believe that's so that it's with its
respected at initial authorization
request and implicit tokens I don't
think it's applicable in in the ACE
world um so I wouldn't say that but yeah
I took its if there's some already
defined parameters I didn't realize that
it's sort of defined implicitly defined
by being a jock claim
when the claims of the JA are used as
the parameters of the request it's it's
a weird sort of that sounds indeed with
but so I think it's perfectly fine that
there's a there's a claim with the term
audience because that goes from the
authorization server all the way to the
resource server and that's exactly what
we want we essentially want the client
to say I want to talk to example.com in
an audience when it parameter when it
goes from flying to authorization server
the authorization server supposed to
then take that information actually dump
it into the token and to pass it along
this is a this is exactly what we want
I understand the pattern young likely
though well there's some there's some
issues around actually the the client
being able to know and convey what the
the actual value of the audience in the
resulting token should be as where some
of the complexity comes up at least in
in a work we've done but but the problem
the the actual technical conflicting
problem is around the authorization
server when it when it says audience
that that audience has multiple meanings
in some contexts and with that
that's sort of the root reason that you
can't use audience at least in the
broader ooofff context as a request
parameter but then there's no other
claim that there's one only one audience
came as far as I know there shouldn't be
any confusion whatsoever soon in JA the
standard the audience claim is defined
Indian and that's the one we want to
reuse well we want to reuse that in the
tokens that are issued yes but there is
a standard two standards actually to
keep it interesting about how to use a
jot to encode the request to the
authorization endpoints and within that
applauded IANS is part of the John you
thought it gets overloaded as a request
prior you talking about the jar what
uh-oh
Jenny BSI or okay close okay yeah no I
said no I understand but does that mean
we would have exactly the same problem
with confirmations as confirmation is a
field which can go into a a job to the
extent it would be used on the
authorization endpoint yes yes is it
actually that mean that almost sounds
like maybe there's a problem if the if
the if that chant that if this are see
that we are going to pass along because
it it mmm uses stuff in her in a not
appropriate way what which which frse
become rc2 cha no Jar uses it as defined
in job the problem is that we're
inventing new parameters which are not
those parameters in it we'll trying to
call them the same name
the problem is in these new specs that
are trying to overload the existing
semantics so this is the requested
audience not the audience of the token
so you just have to call it something
else this is not the the confirmation
method of this token it is the requested
confirmation for the token that you're
going to issue me we just have to have
different names for them otherwise we
will create endless problems for
ourselves recites now I'm really
confused to tell the resource they're
all authorization server to put a
certain audience and a certain
confirmation key and a certain scope in
my token how do I do that I mean guys
you must have defined that honestly just
use a different name Leveque dunk
overload claim name that's the problem
because some of the requests are going
to be put in jobs and those claim names
are already used in those jobs so don't
call it CNF in your request don't call
it AUD in your quest you could call it
requested confirmation you could call it
requested audience there would be no
problem just don't use exactly the same
string otherwise you'll blow up signed
requests do you guys currently actually
have that problem in your specs today
because I believe stole is something
that you can put into a request and is
in a JWT no it's not part of it is it is
it's not defined as part of the boutique
by default but if you could you could
create a problem with scope if you if
you really for it
yeah yeah please head and I'm gonna cut
the line after Ludwick so that last one
here okay or no Brian are you in the
line
yeah after Brian so John Bradley yubico
but the claims are in that are that are
part of the job are fine the problem is
that if you want to add a new you're
sending a signed request in a signed
object either a jot or a CWT because
they'll both have the same problem yeah
things are both defined if you try and
say put some parameter of I want you to
issue a token with these things as those
claims in the token you issue me if you
since both tokens can have both the
confirmation method and and an audience
and a issue or etc if you use the same
parameter names
you only have one it's going to be a
problem the so we have this exact same
problem when we're using J to be keys
for URI signing and initially in the
early drafts we use the odd for
something very similar to what it looks
like here and it confused implementers
and the solution was really simple we
moved it to a cDNA specific claim name
that was specific to our particular
purpose and we could define it however
we needed to with whatever words were
useful and it gave us the odd claim back
which we could use for actually
identifying with whoever was supposed to
process the token Johnny I cut the line
two quick things first of all I'm not
opposed to rename stuff I just want to
know why because it's for me that is
more confusing like if I have a
parameter name that is telling the auth
authorization server to put another
claim claim with another name into the
token that
feels confusing to me but okay I'm not
going to fight this this is not little
I'm going to die on and to make matters
worse we define a scope claim so we
probably need to rename that as well I
guess we need a scope claim in the token
Brian Campbell again a few few things
John proxy and John I'm sorry it's
against the rules but he the the proof
of possession stuff that we've done to
date in OAuth the drafts that are
proceeding mutual TLS and token binding
haven't run into this problem because
the key material is implied by
whatever's going on relative to that and
mutual TLS is the client certificate
took - no combining so there's none of
these parameter conflicts it's just a
point of observation that's how the the
current sort of proof of possession work
is proceeding the the name conflicting
is actually a little bit more subtle
than we've talked about only Jacque
claims which are sort of meta
information about the token versus like
more contextual I don't even know what
to call it subject or contextual
information so audience and CNF could
potentially be conflicting to the extent
that that jot needs to be audience to
the to the Reese or to the authorization
server and might have a confirmation in
it about how its presented although
there's no nothing currently defined for
that there's no scope conflict because
the way just the way that scope U is
being used that it doesn't have context
in a jot of like it has its own context
in this presentation so it works okay
even though scope is used in both places
it's alright I didn't explain that well
at all no it's a weird subtle sort of
overlap of when you overlay a jot onto
the authorization request claims that
have context about the the validity of
that JA audience expiration confirmation
potentially then override request
parameters that might have the same name
so those are the ones you need to worry
about so scope doesn't have that problem
so my conclusion from this discussion is
that we have to check for the parameter
names and potentially rename the ones
where there's a conflict I think it's
good to point that out yeah and it
should be on the registry which i think
is coming soon because Mike's my and my
last day one in the point I also come up
captain like that I did have the
resource indicators draft but much of
that content or at least the concepts
have been rolled into the distributed
ooofff
draft that dick is going to talk about
here shortly which which itself also
tries to find a resource parameter so
we'll have one more place to talk about
it yeah but I think that would also be
confusing to reference the distributed
OS in a chest for a parameter like it's
as confusing as referencing a source I
don't disagree okay so so I guess I get
the feeling that most people kind of in
agreement that we don't want to use that
audience parameter and we want to call
it some some something else and do I
think maybe we need a home of that
because I've seen some nods not clear
about this maybe maybe there is still a
people I'm not clear on this one so I
would ask for a hum for this and and
maybe just to continue with this is that
that fair enough god maybe do a hum
after I present talk about the use of
resource and distributed OAuth and then
people can see that there's multiple
places they are needing it that's fair
enough
Mike are you going to do the hum to
adopt draft Campbell resource indicators
is working group document that would be
one of them it probably comes after that
but I just want to make sure that people
understand that there is a conflict and
agree that is on conflict first right
and that's my sense of that of the meat
of that of the room that most people
agree that that is the case but I want
to just make sure that this is the case
right
so maybe we should wait for then for
dick to present and after that take that
that hum and I'm fine with that
okay okay um that took a little longer
that was supposed to be a trickster um
okay so profile the profile topic so in
ace the profile has a specific meaning
and it just to summarize in case you
haven't read the document so in there
are different protocols being used and
security mechanisms between the client
and the resource server because there
are just different deployment
environments and in the way how this was
approached in the ACE working group was
to register a profile string with a
specification that defines exactly on
what the mechanisms and what the
procedures are so for example I listed
one here which is the DTLS a co-op
underscored idealist profile which as
the name sort of indicates it refers to
a specific specification and that
happens to use coop secured by DTLS and
it is finds on how the keys that come
out of the US I associated with the Bob
talk now used in that to secure that
exchange that's what what is called
profile it turns out in the key
distribution document we had a different
parameter at that time which was called
algorism LG barometer which allows the
client to tell the authorization server
what parameter it is going to use or
planning to use or what it supports
actually it on the uplink it's what it
supports what algorithm it supports for
use with the resource server back then
he was motivated by the work that Justin
did on the HTTP signing and it supported
different algorithms so their
authorization server was basically in
charge of figuring out or knowing what
the common or what
resource of algorithm support is and
then it would tell first of all during
the key generation but also it would
know what parameter to select so it
would basically make that determination
and it would send the corresponding
parameter down to the client that was
the meaning at that time and of course
it was used with the token in context of
the token type because if the token type
indicated that it was a very token and
that didn't make sense so it was if it's
a pop token that that was applicable
jim-jim shot I'm not sure that I
actually see a conflict here if for
example in the ACE world you were using
a profile of a score of co-op our score
is your profile you may still want to be
able to specify an L to say which
algorithm in aw score you want to use so
I don't know that there's necessarily a
conflict in terms of that okay those are
actually be different parameters right
now you couldn't specify the out one but
that would make sense okay so maybe
maybe that's uh maybe the solution is
not either-or but both um okay maybe
that's a that's a solution micros are
objecting at least to the idea of the
profile our parameter so I try to
elaborate on what is actually needed to
successfully establish the communication
session between the client and the
resource server so first of all a couple
of different profile protocols being
available different ones used there's
the tokens come in different flavors as
well so currently we have three
standardized token format defined in the
IDF most prominently the
CWT JWT and then there's also for the
web RTC guiity debased encoding there is
different security protocols currently
from the ACE working group there's a
DTLS / TLS there's also an application
layer oscar solution there are different
trenches torrential types
used which need to be somehow indicated
and and I talked about the problem the
algorithm sent the parameters already so
there's quite a bit of information and
that needs to be somehow either
avoidable out-of-band or needs to be
conveyed in the in the protocol exchange
to make it make all of this work
depending on the security protocol you
use for example on DTLS that goes in
here
details can do a lot of negotiation on
TLS negotiation for you so you don't
need the authorization server to pass
this information along for the profiles
some of that information is fixed so to
speak at the specification time rather
than literally negotiated during runtime
but deployments may have a different
different solution so the question was
what's the story with the ID in their
profile so is the profile myq you had a
strong view on this and and I've just
heard chips yeah just just compare
before Mike goes on so five minutes
you'll be able to pop okay mm-hm god
Mike yeah profile is in the earth world
typically something that is known by
both parties via an out-of-band
mechanism I know of no deployed
instances in which 100 auth client uses
two different profiles which are
selected at runtime and the only purpose
of sending this as a parameter is to
select profiles at runtime so I think
that this is you know not even in the
10% case this is in the beyond the 1%
case and you should delete the parameter
it is it it is an optional parameter at
the moment in the into a so ah Stockman
yeah but it's still encouraging people
to think of something really complex as
a normal thing to do
and I think it's a terrible thing to
even attempt to do
I think it's encouraging complexity so
it should go and do you have a number of
documents do you have a perspective on
the area under idlers and parameters
well you would you also consider that
out of an information or would you have
a different I would do that in Discovery
I wouldn't necessarily send that but the
discovery would be it would be a
discovery of what the authorization
server supports rather than here we are
is covering what the resource server are
can use well if you're sending the
information in a jar you know the
algorithm because it's in the jar so
that the client a client needs to know
what I person to use for per sentiment
in context of the presentment I mean I
this doesn't bother me very much because
it is something that it might very
unlike the profile which will never very
okay John Bradley yubico I largely agree
with Mike this is really a discovery and
registration problem rather than a
runtime decision problem
maybe algorithm at runtime but it's that
also seems a bit unlikely to me really
we have to we have this general problem
of resource discovery and allowing the
client to magically know stuff and then
tell it to the server you know we're
just you know it's Turtles all the way
down unless we actually deal with how
does the client figure out what it needs
to do to talk to the resource server
either through the resource server or
the authorization server yeah you do not
going to have any of these parameters to
specify you know the only the only time
that the audience that kind of makes
sense is if the client itself only
supports a subset of algorithms then and
you might have the same client ID across
multiple
client instances that had different
cryptographic libraries but even that is
a little bit tenuous so I get get the
feeling that day but I guess there is no
consensus on this is see yeah yeah I
just want to let that work first three
sites were just one comments you're now
discussing stuff that we're doing in ace
I would have appreciated that feedback
quite a while ago when we were defining
these things excuse me in October I sent
a review of the a south spec explaining
why profile was an encouragement of
complexity and should be deleted because
clients do not dynamically choose
profiles at runtime and the review
comment was ignored by the editors so we
did say this in the ACE mailing list
yeah you didn't do it yeah let's not
move that's a signal I'll be the move
forward yourself good way so which
parameters okay so I guess maybe I will
take a hum here first do people I want
to ask first if people understand that
the issue in if they have enough
information about and and and then later
on one or the other and so the first the
first one is just to ask if if you have
enough information to understand the
issue right so if you have enough info
oh the parameters those parameters
whether okay there's a removal or
okay okay
it is it is a working group item that is
needed by two other groups and then this
dependency we can of course shuffle
content around that's what we always
what we can always do but it is I don't
think we are now getting rid of a
concept that is coin is and also needed
with web RTC or I use suggesting that
Brian just because you you don't like it
just in richer I'm not gonna speak for
Brian but having something be a working
group item that is needed by lots of
people all over the world has not been
sufficient motivation for us to actually
get anything done in the past and I am
not convinced that it is still
motivation so I feel that your
counter-argument rings hollow given the
attitude of this group in the past
towards similar and in fact this exact
set of problems while I think we should
probably you know get our heads out from
under the rocks and do this I'm still
not convinced that we are and so I agree
with Brian statement that that is one of
the open questions if we are going to do
this or not
I don't think it's settled so just
instead yet so I'm trying to find out
what you actually trying to say is I
hear you say that since the work is
progressing in in ace maybe that works
with all together that type of work the
pop key distribution work should
actually be done there I think that a
should solve aces pop key distribution
work I think
a wall should solve a lot spot key
distribution working to the extent that
we can you know abstract things and use
common structures and common parameters
and stuff that's great but but the
promise that we when Ace was started
that was that Oh use OS because we can
reuse a common mechanism across the
board and that's what we said it wasn't
it wasn't all we do was here and then
you do ace there because it's a common
it uses a common technology it's not a
common technology though because oweth
is very strictly defined to http and the
ace o auth is doing OAuth II kind of
things in a different strata it I I
disagree with thought that's what it was
you're wrong I'm sorry okay and that's
your perspective yeah I could points to
a book it's Brian I I don't not even
sure what to say except that I think it
to reiterate that I don't think the
issue is well understood but which issue
exactly issues which issue but that's my
point
even what the issues are there's no
consensus you must be you must be joking
there are three questions that are
oughtn't to advance the document are
three questions and the question are
mostly about which document which
working group should work put the
content in a document that's that's the
issue how complicated is that it's it's
really complicated because we'll find
out okay we put stuff into the the the
ace document in but then we hear
comments oh this should be done in OS
and then some other people come along
and say oh this we should work on this
in OS because there's no energy do it in
ace huh yeah so it's complicated okay so
I don't know okay guys thank you I don't
think we can
take any home today I think we need more
discussion and clarity on on the issues
before we think any home so that's my
feeling here I thought that was exactly
my worry that we've essentially bounced
back and forth between the two different
groups are the area directors
unfortunately not here to raise their
head which I had actually asked them to
do so it's ultimately a decision about
the area directors from where they won't
want to do the work right it's like 50
and and I would like again I think I cut
the line sorry guys we need to move on
to two other topics because we are late
already
sorry purely process I'm good I
understand and I can I can understand
where you don't want to make a decision
not making a decision makes a decision
for as far as I'm concerned so I think
it's in terms of of Aizaz as being in a
chair my feeling is that that is
confusion and not enough clarity to make
a decision in the first place and that's
so easy okay and that's the reason I'm
I'm hesitant to take any any action
right now thanks Hannes dick hopefully
this presentation will be a little less
so well presented early draft of this
and Singapore anybody got Singapore saw
this yeah because I've got something
since Singapore Brian and Knapp joined
me as co-authors incorporated you know
what we've been talking about here the
resource indicator context into here and
that had some stuff around metadata that
we incorporated so the resources a URI
and the earlier draft it was just the
host added
oh that didn't constrain it to only be
client credential grants although it's
unclear how the other ones would
actually work yet or a use case for
those and then using the link header for
discovery so one of the problems trying
to solve is in a more distributed
environment the authorization server for
resource may not be known previously and
so it's discovered at runtime which
enables you to sort of change a resource
and you're more of a dynamic
configuration so you guys can just read
that or I can read that does anyone have
questions on this what the problem is
like here's a picture of it and so here
a client might be calling resources and
really what are different geopolitical
areas where the author is there are
different authorization servers for each
of those regions but the client wants
access resources in each of those
regions and so needs to go to a
different authorization server but that
in this particular example the Scopes
are potentially identical across all the
regions and so you're trying to have a
signal for the scope that's different
from where the resources one of the
issues that comes up when you do this
dynamically at runtime is there's more
challenges around access token reuse so
the the client potentially could be
using a token to go and access a
resource that it wasn't supposed to so
for example if you got a token and says
you had certain scopes but there's no
enforcement as to whether it's a an
China or the u.s. right you could that
client potentially could access the same
resource with the same scope in both
places and then another challenge of
course is that when you have a bunch of
resources one resource could be
malicious and just reuse that access
token access all the resources that that
same client is accessing if
that tokens can be used different places
so there's two ways of solving that and
this document we work with the first one
which is audience you're sticking the
access token
but there's other models where you want
to constrain the sender so in the
audience restricted essentially you get
a token for each resource and you use
the right the client needs to track
which token is for which resource and
then the other examples where the
parties are both a client and a resource
server so in this one you want a sender
constrained access token where there's
the same access tokens used but you want
to know that whoever's calling you is
the holder of that access token so the
bindings the binding is more to the
caller as opposed to the binding being
to the resource so example that you know
there NASA people so they don't really
make their stuff public but there's a
speck called UTM that all the people and
this the space thing you're working on
so UTM is you know made up another I
from UAS traffic management UAS is
unmanned aircraft system so essentially
for a traffic management system for
drones to talk to each other and talk
back to their base about where they're
flying to and in in this example the
aviation authorities such as FAA would
be the authorization server that says
who are all the people that can be
operating they want to minimize what
infrastructure they Iran all the
operators talk to each other to
communicate and coordinate flight
information so each party can call any
other party and so you want to make sure
that that you know the FAA is issued one
access token to that party saying that
they're authorized to participate and
then they each on each call each party
you once approve that they're authorized
by presenting that access token but you
don't want one party to use somebody
else's access token to call other ones
um that's a similar problem how that
salt isn't covered in the current draft
and so one of the things I'm wondering
is whether
other people have similar use cases
whether it makes sense to put this in
this because it's another example of
distributed a lot so we in the current
draft in the you call the resource is
how the whole flow kicks off you call
the resource and in the 4a one response
you get two additional things that are
in a link header one is the identify are
the resource and the other one is where
to go to get information about the
authorization server to go and call the
authorization server there was some
feedback this morning on the list about
these pieces whether it's the full URI
in awhile server metadata your I well
there was a better name for that I think
actually just turning it down to the
issuer makes more sense on that I have
some comments on that
so in this the key thing of course is
the client is able to know that the
thing that it just called that the it
matches that identifier for the resource
that the resource URI is part of the
path that it called and the identity of
the resource is partly determined then
by the TLS certificate in that call then
the clan goes in you know from that it
knows where the AAS is and it knows what
URI and so you know here's our resource
parameter and the access token request
if you're talking about before so we're
saying that you know the resource would
be that URI if we were take that out and
have that be a separate document I don't
think we'd have an issue with that
but it seems to make sense if it's
useful other places and so then in the
access token it includes your i if that
access token happens to be a JWT then it
would be the audience claim and then
when you call the resource server you
check that that that your resource URI
is in
your token so here's third of the
discussion points URI for the resource
anybody any questions any feedback I'll
make one observation for the server
metadata URI
while before the OAuth discovery spec
that would have made sense now we have
so we have two different formats for
multi-tenant one that's in Open ID
Connect and one that's in ooofff because
of path encroachment etc so doing there
isn't a single URI there isn't a single
base URI that you can use if it's a
multi-tenant server so we're probably
best off just specifying the whole URI
because now it's hostname dot well known
10/10 anti-d
so you'd have to actually have two
different parameters to be able to fully
specify a hoie server on a multi-tenant
host so I think it's just more
straightforward to use the entire URI
rather than trying to explain that to
people but other than that that's fine I
also think it should be alright yeah
just aren't that one of the threats I
saw was that the resource could
essentially say any URI and send the
client to fetch stuff from anywhere that
may not be where the a.s really wants
people to fetch stuff from that was the
good thing about the Open ID Connect
format so it's it hard it's hard because
it was limited to the one path hop below
the well-known I mean we we would have
to look at how you could constrain that
or valid
with the the OAuth discovery for format
for for multi-tenant and notes it would
be it's it's a real problem for sure in
some of the other other multi tenant
hosting things so something that we
would have to address how that would
actually work what you have if we just
did the base URI it would break some of
the multi tenant people who large multi
tenant people now I mentioned my comment
design is already on a UI but I also
agree with Mike that defining this
barometer and a separate document would
make much more sense because there's a
lot of context with the distributed o us
that I think is not relevant or not
applicable in other in other
environments and then there's also a
timing issue because this work has just
started and so so that's why I would
prefer to have it ident a separate door
to just keep it in an ace or sake you
talked about the resource parameter my
right so if you think this is a
different resource again from the
previous discussion but I'm referring to
what Dick said because he once wanted to
defer the call for that reflect was
supposed to make on the audience slash
resource on parameter to later because
dick thought that this would be exactly
the same and equally relevant is that
did I understood you correctly dick that
was what I was saying John maybe you
clarify why you think this is the
different resource this is this is the
the link header coming back from the
resource not the resource parameter
going to the authorization endpoint you
had this was one we're talking about
here ok so but that wasn't what the
pre-camp was on the previous slide so
yes but this is what he's talking what
he's talking about right but that wasn't
well no because that this is the
resource you
I as it's handed in the access token
request and so in the other side I had
resource URI it's just the parameter
called resource currently yeah okay and
everybody sits down okay any feedback on
using link header anyone opposed to that
okay so there was some comment on the
mainland about you so I I was hoping
that NAT would respawn Matt's kind of
listening in on the meeting but I was
hoping that would respond because he was
though he had some good arguments for a
while in Qatar okay so you wanna take it
to the list or do sure we'll take that
to the left cat yeah cuz I don't I don't
actually have a clear answer myself okay
and Matt doesn't know how to make XMPP
work yet so you can't type but he's
listening hi NAT another comment in the
list was supporting multiple resources
in the access token request for students
or talked about that I don't I don't
know it's unclear to me a use case where
that could happen you describe a use
case but but that doesn't really map
into how the sort of distributed off
kicks off which is that you call a
resource and you get 12 where to go so
you're only dealing with one resource I
just want to say Nats on by the way in
case you oh okay is he typing anything
that we can say okay great
so now we'll respond on list so I I'm
gonna stick with the sort of previous
position of we have refresh tokens if
you need you know multiple resources for
a single access token adds to the
complexity let's just if you need
multiple yeah if you have multiple
resources get multiple access tokens
there may be
different keys or different transports
or other things that you will eventually
have for those resource servers so I
tried trying to optimize it is probably
counterproductive so you want to have a
different opinion on that okay
well we'll see whether Torsen can
provide some crisp examples on the list
mister Torsten from Phil Hunt developers
hate getting multiple tokens developers
hate doing what what it is that they
don't like doing Justin Richard one
repeating what John said from the floor
years that developers hate security
which is marginally true but what's more
true is that most developers don't care
about security they care about
functionality and so as you know complex
as we can make a security system if it's
too complex they'll duct tape it open in
ways that we don't anticipate I'm not
saying that's what this is destined for
specifically but but it is definitely
something we need to keep in mind
especially because this is I think
relevant to the larger resource URI
discussion you look at what happens in
sam'l with audience and resource URLs
and nobody knows which one means what
like ever so I think we have to remember
remember our history as we are choosing
kind of what to call these and what they
apply to okay any suggestions on
different names oh I have no idea okay
so Lucy Lynch sort of a question and a
puzzlement about multiple resources in
an access okay given some of the current
drift towards delegation consent and
revocation do you think about that in
how does that mean the entire token dies
when one resources
but when one copes so yes so say it say
one scope is is what's wrong
mm-hmm then the entire token dies the
access token yeah yeah I mean so would
hammer be reissued with a more limited
scope right okay yeah which you know
typically happens if you don't if a
scoped revote and you don't have and
you're using refresh tokens and the
tokens are you know they're valid until
they expire then usually that would
happen on the Refresh but then you get a
new access token with the different
scopes I think I'm an imagining a world
post gdpr where you may be required to
refresh quicker than you think you are
yeah and so implementations do that then
do some bloom filters so that everything
can check to see whether that's a
revoked access token which forces the
client to go back and refresh again
right away all right so to Lucy's point
you know we designed refresh tokens so
that we could have short-lived access
tokens to deal with some of these issues
you know allowing you know we don't want
to encourage people to have long-lived
access tokens that are good for multiple
resources and start getting ourselves
into these these issues so it's you know
encouraging people to properly use
refresh tokens
keeping that keeping that and adding a
whole bunch of dubbings for multiple
resources just adds to the complexity
yes developers have to do a little bit
more but there are SDKs that take care
of getting new exchanging getting new
access tokens off of a refresh token
it's not the end of the world for
developers you have to deal with
multiples well if the developers dealing
with multiple resources that have
different authorization servers they
inherently have to have different access
tokens any yeah right this this is sort
of
only an optimization if the
authorization server happens to be
authority for multiple resources yeah
it's my last question is you know that
the proof of possession stuff is really
between the client and the resource one
of the challenges in a distributed OAuth
is the authorization server reusing the
client credentials at a different
authorization server and impersonating
the client and so that sort of drives
you to wanting to have a authentication
mechanism between the client and a s
that doesn't allow the a s to
impersonate the client if the client is
using the same credentials that
different yes ludovic sites why not use
an asymmetric pop kibum you just give
the authorization server your public key
and you do the proof of possession with
the private key and then the
authorization server can impersonate q
everywhere else only right but it's not
this is protecting the call to the a is
nothing call to the sole source so we do
have two current asymmetric
authentication methods - the token
endpoint JWT assertion well then there's
a sam'l assertion but we won't talk
about that and mutual TLS ideally you
know you shouldn't be using symmetric
credentials in a distributed system like
this that's just gonna go wrong so yes
propane you know that's something that
I've been fighting the GSMA and other
people with large distributed networks
you know just you have to bite the
bullet use a symmetric client
credentials and either use JWT assertion
or mutual TLS to authenticate the client
everything else will inevitably go wrong
in some horrible way yeah actually
okay the the treatment in so I'm gonna
cut the mic after just before hums I
think if I remember correctly in some
configuration even that JWT sort of
assertion profile wouldn't help because
you know you have to because it was more
used as a bearer token and so you could
actually take that one AAS could just
take it and relayed to another one so
there's an audience the audience would
be there
so the ears couldn't they could call
themselves but they couldn't call a
different air we thought of that let's
check that yeah there is another point
which is sort of in the code flow the
resource you are I could be a useful
piece that seems to make sense although
I'm still trying I'm Ser of any clear
use cases on the code flow whether we
wanted to do Senator constrain access
token and then of course this is still a
ID and is this work that's interesting
for the working group and whether we
should adopt this that's a question to
the chairs see if they want to put that
as a question yeah so so I guess we have
two questions and the first one is about
the resource a the audience a question
and I think the last question is the
most important questions yes if the last
question doesn't have the right answer
then the other ones are irrelevant okay
yeah fair enough and okay so I'm gonna a
call them for a week or adoption for
this this document and see if there is
enough support here so if you are in
favor of adopting this document as a
workgroup document hum now if you're
against hum now okay
now I think that's clear and just for
completeness there was one hum in favor
on jabber thank you awesome
okay so then quickly back to can you go
back to that to that slide that talks
about there the URI no not more yeah
yeah that's it
aim so I think that the feeling that
from the room that there they don't want
it to overload that a audience so I
wanna ask for adoption of that document
that defines the resource in server or
the resource as a separate or the
parameter versus a overloading that M
that the audience so if you're right
John I think those are slightly two
different questions one is whether or
not we should be using audience or
resources of parameter the other
question is should we adopt the other
spec and back out some of the stuff that
went from that's back into this fact so
that this spec refers to the the
resource but then the name and where the
work is done are sort of two different
questions
right okay should we have a document
that defines a prayer separate parameter
okay what someone would like to be in
the audience of an issue token yes which
I think Brian's draft was the starting
point right very quick comment what you
have here in resource and what I see in
the Campbell draft is different from
what is in audience it's like in
resource and in the Campbell draft it's
like your eyes or URLs even and in
audience it's more generic so
please align yeah there's there's if we
do a separate spec we're gonna have to
look at what my ace is done and and
other people to make sure that for the
different transports the the the value
of the resource parameter actually makes
sense for those transports but that can
be done in in thats back yep Stefan's on
the song I was just looking through they
they draft and they just wondering this
is yeah multiple resources requiring
different access servers and could you
could you have multiple choices of how
to for one resource or have multiple
choices of where you go yes you could
which authorization server and that's
what you're referring to yes sorry wrong
terminology authorization services yes
which would give you resiliency yes I
guess I've heard a few different use
cases for that parameter over the years
and I'm kind of wondering if all these
people consider themselves to be
distributed or I think that's actually
probably highly likely so kind of makes
sense to me to do that work here that I
know like tossed in the nose a few other
people that will see interested in the
resource so why don't we do it yeah okay
have a document define a parameter the
signal what should be the audience okay
so the question is do we need a separate
document to define that parameter if the
question will be sure we adopt Bryan's
document but but Bryan's document is
just that and the manifestation of that
right so is it specifically you want to
talk about that not right
[Music]
do this work in that document right okay
so then I'll ask about an adoption of
resource indicator document and okay so
if then yeah so if you are in favor or
adopting resource indicator document as
a regular document please hum now if you
are against please home now okay thank
you
Thanks no I don't think we have any
moments you guys so maybe we could
summarize what we sure so I just sent a
mail you may have not have seen it to
the list about asking our area directors
for a little bit of guidance on the
day's the synchronization between A's
and os I think that will be helpful okay
let's give him an two minutes here oh
yeah okay I'm gonna be quiet yeah the
security best practices document okay
this is gonna do something okay
what is it you should already have been
paying attention to this
it's an overview of the security topics
dealing with all the feedback that we've
gotten from the security researchers
we've divided it based on the feedback
we've divided it up reorganize the work
so we've got upfront recommendations and
then the detailed threat analysis and
proposed countermeasures our
recommendations are exact redirect URI
matching avoiding open redirect errs
through various mechanisms one time
parameters tokens or
values in the state parameter or
cross-site request forgery they s
specific redirect your eyes clients
using pixie to prevent the reinjection
of code using TLS based methods for
constraining the resentment of access
tokens and end-to-end TLS wherever
possible our current status we got some
review feedback after 101 we've
incorporated that into the latest
version we haven't had any torques
company's reasonable feedback perhaps we
got some unreasonable feedback we'll
have to ask Torsten what he meant by
that we have two proposals which we have
to decide what we're going to deal with
one about audience restriction which we
should probably add I think that makes
sense
crypto agility people can look at the
proposal on the on the on the mail
archive and decide whether or not we
want to do something with that my
personal preference is that probably
doesn't doesn't make immediate sense in
the document so we should decide what we
do with these two things and then do a
last call and try and move this BCP
forward thank you very much thanks you
[Music]
everyone okay