[Music]
so as people are walking in here just if
you don't know what that video was that
was playing before this meeting I wrote
a blog post which I shared with the is G
and the IAB in advance for comment and
it was titled something for everyone at
IETF 102 and it had a little bit of a
humorous flair to it and Allison
actually asked oh is that is that a
reference to comedy tonight because the
whole idea was that it was it was trying
to the blog post was trying to be funny
and I had never heard of comedy tonight
so we went in and dug up a video and
it's a song from a musical from the
1960s a funny thing happened on the way
to the forum by Stephen Sondheim thank
you sourcing but the lyrics are so on
point something familiar something
peculiar something for everyone a comedy
tonight welcome to the IHF 102 plenary
hi everyone I'm ELISA Cooper I'm the ITF
chair and it's lovely to be here with
all of you in Montreal the world home of
circus also somewhat on point for the
ITF and hopefully not for the plenary
but for the ITF as a whole people might
not remember this but this particular
meeting was originally scheduled to be
next week in San Francisco and when he
ended up changing it due to some
concerns about visa issues and
immigration issues in the United States
we decided to move it to Montreal and in
order to do that we had to change the
dates we had to move it back to this
week I think what people really don't
realize though is the incredible
foresight of the ITF administrative
oversight committee in making that
switch because what that meant was that
in addition to us having our working
meeting here this week we would coincide
with two very important world events
those being the world cup and world
emoji day so not only do we get to get
our work done but we also got to watch
the games and celebrate the emojis and
congratulations to France of course
something else new at this meeting
people might have noticed that there's
there have been Chromebooks on the
tables for the working group chairs at
the front of every session when the is
she first talked about getting these
added there was a little bit of concern
about whether there would be enough
space on the tables that remained for
the working group chairs to still manage
the meetings and you have the blue
sheets and there's all kinds of stuff up
there but it seems that that wasn't
necessarily a problem and in particular
some of the one group chairs were quite
inspired by the
and brought a whole family of laptops so
that the Chromebook wouldn't be lonely
this particular case let's see five five
devices sitting there on the table
big thanks to the Secretariat for
providing those I think I think that's
been a a well received change so getting
on with our agenda will first thank our
hosts are briefly and then we'll have
updates on hot topics from all of our
different constituencies so I'll give a
ITF chairs update Ted will talk about
the IAB or maybe not I can't we crossed
you out you're coming on later allison
will speak briefly about the IRT f will
have administrative hot topics and then
we'll hear from the NomCom chair we'll
have a section in memoriam we'll do some
recognition I will have that Jonathan be
Postell award from Cathy brown and
there's no technical plenary tonight so
then we'll go straight into the open mic
sessions so first an extremely
importantly a huge thanks to our hosts
at this meeting juniper
juniper is one of our global hosts which
means they've made a multi-year
commitment to support the IETF host
three meetings over the span of nine
years a support that we really can't
function without so we're extremely
appreciative for that typically we have
a host presentation but juniper wanted
to donate that time back to us for the
rest of the plenary and wish everybody
wish everybody a productive meeting so
on to the ITF chairs report i'll cover
some typical items participant
statistics for this meeting a little
note about the hot RFC session that we
had on sunday an update on i asset to
doe
a preview of an agenda experiment we're
running at ITF 103 and then just a
reminder about respectful behavior at
our meetings so here in montreal we have
1020 people on site we have 137
first-time attendees which is a pretty
typical sized group of first-timers
first time our meeting if we compared to
last summer meeting it's a little bit on
the small side
continuing with trends that we've seen
over the last few years and we had
participants from 56 countries this time
pretty on par with with last summer
meeting as well yeah I took the ITF
hackathon took place on Saturday and
Sunday we set another new attendance
record at the hackathon 227 people
showed up in person they had more than
300 registered 41 people remote and we
had 25 different project teams so that
event continues to just grow and grow we
also did the hack demo happy hour on
Monday night where teams could present
their projects and talk to other
attendees about what they accomplished
on the weekend we also have the World
Cup streaming at the hackathon an
additional benefit of a change and some
people worked very very hard as you can
see while they were watching the game
the next hackathon will take place again
on the weekend prior to the working
group session starting November 3rd and
4th in Bangkok
prior to ITF 103 so please plan your
travel accordingly this is a second
meeting where we ran an event on Sunday
night called request for conversation
hot RFC this involves lightning talks to
encourage brainstorming to socialize new
ideas to find collaborators to advertise
bar buffs and side meetings took place
on Sunday and there were 10 talks there
was a packed room there are more than
100 people there and you can find the
proceedings on on the web this is
something we've done experimentally it's
only the second time so the IHG is
looking for feedback about this whether
people think it's a useful event whether
we should keep doing it what we should
change and a big thanks to Aaron Falk
for doing the organization there and
taking the initiative to plan the event
I also wanted to give an update about
the IETF administrative support activity
to doe just been a project that's going
on and going on for a couple of years
now this is the discussion about how we
refactor the way that we administer the
IETF the current plan is to create a
limited liability corporation IETF LLC
to house the the IAF's administration it
will be a legal entity within the
internet society where we are currently
organized as an activity on Tuesday the
I asset to working group met and in the
room at least there was rough consensus
about the final big open issue that we
needed to resolve about related to the
LLC's board structure so the next steps
as that consensus is being confirmed on
the list we're also going to be
finalizing the legal documents that are
required in order to create this LLC and
those will go out for the last pass to
the ITF community and then the hope is
to execute those legal agreements and
start getting the LLC set up in August
prior to the changeover from the current
I Sox CEO to the new CEO who's starting
in September
so that's the plan for is a judo as it
stands I wanted to give people a heads
up about an experiment with the agenda
that we're going to be running an IETF
103 this has been mentioned on various
mailing lists but I wanted to call
people's attention to it in case you're
planning or travel and I take 103 we're
going to run working group sessions only
from Monday to Thursday there's not
gonna be any working groups meeting on
Fridays we are gonna have meeting rooms
of all different sizes available on
Friday for ad hoc meetings and the IETF
network is still going to be available
and you'll be able to sign up for those
at the same time when we open working
group scheduling so we're trying to do
this to see if we can have a little bit
more focused time and in the working
groups we have a lot of working groups
who typically request not to meet on
fridays anyway and we've we've heard the
suggestion that we try to schedule more
ad hoc time Friday might not be the best
day we're gonna try this they might try
something different in the next
go-around but we thought we would we
would do a little bit of an
experimentation we're definitely looking
for more feedback we've gotten a lot of
feedback already which we appreciate and
certainly once we actually run the
experiment we'll be asking everybody for
their feedback I just wanted to remind
everybody about our guidelines for a
respectful behavior it always seems
weird to me that we have this slide in
here on Wednesday when everybody's
already been here for three days so
hopefully I think everybody is already
aware of our guidelines for respectful
behavior but we have a number of
different documents that outline what
our policies are that that govern how we
treat each other here in the IETF so
please be cognizant of those and I think
in particular we're really trying to
establish an inclusive and open
community sometimes those two things
actually are at odds with each other
but I encourage people to take a look at
the at the documents and think about
them as you as you walk around the ITF
we always publish a report in advance of
the ICF meeting so there's a bunch of
other topics that are covered in there
that give more updates about working
groups that have closed and opened
notable documents that we publish since
the last meeting and so on also
currently running experiments that we
have
of Appeals we've had one appeal since
the last IETF meeting and lots more
detail from all of the other entities
that support the ITF the IAB the IOC the
RSC editor Ayanna the NOC Secretariat
and also some reporting from the
hackathon so please check that out we
like to use the IETF blog to expound a
little bit more about what's going on in
the IETF if you have something that you
think is interesting to the outside
world and you want to publish on the
blog please let me know we're always
looking for more content and we would be
happy to have more contributions we are
not gonna hear from dead until later and
with that I will turn it over to Allison
Lincoln for IRT F I don't have slides
this time if you want to see slides
about the IRT F there in the IRT F opens
proceedings but I wanted to just tell
you that we are a growing group we had a
tremendous we're very grateful to
everyone who cooperated with this
because we have a our yearly workshop
which is called the applied networking
research workshop which is co-sponsored
by ACM I saw can I RTF as well as some
corporate sponsors whom we thank
gratefully and we had it on Monday of
ITF week for the first time this was the
third of them and we were asked by the
participants to make it during IETF so
that researchers could come here and
participate and become involved in in
working groups and research groups as
well and would be interested to hear
your feedback those of you who may not
have registered for it are not the
people who came specifically for it
about how that felt to you but from the
point of view of the attendees it was a
great success it
huge difference because we knew that the
sessions were surrounded by people who
were working actively on the deployment
of protocols while this research was
being aired and that's a very inspiring
thing that's one of the things that
inspires people to come to ITF is that
there's a chance that their work will be
used and deployed so thank you for that
those proceedings you can find
everything about IRT f @ ir t org so
check it out and ask me questions about
a and RW but you'll find the report
about the statistics of a and iw and
things like that in my my more detailed
report which I gave to the open meeting
yeah hi awesome I thought it was great
actually I really like the TLS I guess I
would say resist the urge to put it on
Friday if we're in Bangkok okay where
it's actually the same yeah and I should
also thank the the magnificent
schedulers of AMS because we actually
worked to avoid scheduling relevant
working groups against sessions so that
people could drop in and out of the a
and RW and I'm glad that you appreciated
that glad you notice that the
magnificent schedulers of AMS
I think what else just as I thought the
workshop was great and I want to commend
to folks in the audience who weren't
there
Sharon Goldberg the workshop chairs
introductory presentation on how to help
new people get traction for their
proposals in the IDF it's I understand
it's posted on the proceedings page and
it's a few slides and if I run into
anybody who's from outside the community
who wants to get something going in the
IDF it's the first thing I'm going to
show after the demo that's a really good
point thank you yeah okay so next we
have administrative hot topics Glendon
and Porsche Wednesday an Li good
afternoon
so I I am NOT as nervous as I was the
first couple of times and I was up on
the stage thank goodness and so along
with not being as nervous I also have
really had a chance to get to work with
more people in the few months I've been
here and actually get to know people on
a different level and of course it takes
a lot to make oops to make these
meetings work and we really appreciate
the efforts of our host and our sponsors
and
everything that it takes to really go
out there and get the the the funds to
make the this meetings a success for
everyone who's coming from so far away
so our global host for IETF 102 is
Juniper Network and we really appreciate
I hope everyone has enjoyed the the
venue this time it has wheat I think it
was actually creative for I MTF because
of all the collaborative spaces around
it's been a great place so Thank You
Jennifer
for your help we also have a lot of
sponsors in addition to Jennifer to make
sure that we are doing everything we can
to make your experience work and I have
a couple of notes here
I want to make sure I don't like to
think from my head because it's never a
good idea
so our silver sponsors our silver white
silver sponsors are or going akame thank
you very much we appreciate your efforts
we also have our bronze buzzer as
Verisign and connectivity sponsors tell
us and met rafacz and open face and we
have two circuits that came in and I
hope everything has gone well with your
connectivity our what Welcome Reception
again juniper networks and I'd also like
to acknowledge our sisters lunch and
it's fastly and Comcast and NBCUniversal
I have not had a chance to attend those
yet so hopefully one day I will and
that'll go well tomorrow and in addition
we would also like to acknowledge
everyone who works on the data track our
enhancements in the code spread it takes
a lot to make sure that we are enhancing
the the tools to make sure that it's
working well on your path
our hackathon Juniper Cisco Deb net and
NBCUniversal thank you very much and of
course the NOC volunteers for the NOC we
have everyone who works with line speed
and me deco bringing the meeting to
participants on a remote level and now
we'd like to acknowledge that IETF is
going to be in Bangkok in November we
are still we are actually in
negotiations for
a global hosts for this meeting and
hopefully we have some negotiations that
are going on for for hosting
opportunities we do have a local host
that has been very instrumental and
helping us get things going there on the
ground
th Nick we are very thankful for
everything that they've done but also
like to thank Randy Bush for helping me
connect with our with our local host to
make sure that we were able to move
forward in so many different ways if you
are interested in hosting please see Kim
Borden and Ken could you please stand up
so sup people thank you and with that I
thank you very much Oh
you may notice I'm not Andrew Sullivan
so one of the big changes that happened
is Andrew Sullivan of course is now the
CEO and president as of September 1st of
I saw and that made him ineligible to be
the ioc chair so that's a speedy Andrew
set down from the chair position but he
remains in the IOC and I was selected as
the hello and 1 Dean if you don't know
me so the IOC right now is clearly you
know keep the lights on mode the LLC is
under way being developed and set up and
eventually when it's in full operation
the IOC will dissolve and be replaced by
the LLC so we are still in business
we're keeping the lights on going and
we're doing what we've always been doing
I'd like to say thank you for Andrew for
his time as chair of the IOC and I'd
also like to acknowledge Cathy Brown
but this is her last icy beating that
she was able to attend
she'll be retiring it would be not so
thank you both Andrew and Cathy so one
of the big changes that has been going
on in the meeting selection process in
the last year was the development of the
meeting venue criteria and there's been
a working group that's the media now for
about a little more than eager and
they've come to closure on my documents
going through the secretary or Sir the
RFC publication process currently we've
taken that document in the IOC and we've
updated our meeting process to reflect
its requirements and so if you go to
these URLs you will see the new
documented process for how many venues
are selected you can evaluate it and
hopefully it's very clear now and very
well document itself the other thing I
like to note that we have replaced when
we recently old meetings committee that
went in the IOC that took care of all
the stuff and with this new change new
meetings venue review process we've
created a new committee literally called
the media's venue review committee whose
job it is to take the venues we were
examining and measured them against the
criteria that were developed by the
working group so that's a significant
change about how meeting spaces will be
selected going forward in addition we
have a new meeting dates they're being
selected for this period of 20 23
through 2028 and they've all been sent
out to the list for input okay so here's
the the controversial one potentially we
warned you a while back that with the
media rates we're going to be changing
the good news is the earlybird fee has
not changed it remains at what it's
always been
or what it's been currently and but
we've missed other changes so the late
fees will increase just before the
meeting two weeks before the meeting and
at the meeting to $1,000 us
and the standard rate for those who
don't claim the early birth fee will be
875 and I'll show you a chart in a
minute that shows the breakdown of
windows kitchen so here's basically the
layout and so for the people who are
looking at when they can claim the early
bird feed it's going to open several
weeks prior to the meeting is when that
registration will open up and you will
be able to claim that feed and so if the
upcoming ITF 103 that means that
registration will be open no later than
August 13th two weeks prior to the
meeting ups are up to two weeks prior
the medium you can get this standard
rate which is 875 and if you are closer
than two weeks you will pay $1,000 this
was the best way we could balance out
the charging and a need for ITF to
increase the rates give people an option
that allow them to maintain the current
rates one point I would really like to
make Thailand is a brand new country and
we have not been to it as the ITF before
so the guidance we'd like to give to our
age nd wherever you're from even if
you've never needed visas before please
take a look at the visa situation for
yourself personally and see if you're
going to need a visa or not now on visas
typically visas require letters of
invitation the process that is now in
place going forward is that prioritise
IETF meetings can request once we open
registration you'll be able to request a
letter of invitation for attendees who
have not been tonight to have bt in the
past you will have to register and pay
your registration fee and then you can
request your letter for invitation if it
turns out is where I'm able to get your
visa through the process if you can't
attend because of a visa issues we will
refund your fee okay clear enough and
we're going to polish all this on the
website so it's very
when we do registration for 103 going
forward finally the very diesel rewards
you want all the gore and all the
details
they're available here on these lengths
so that's so far for this beanie it's
actually been very good very convenient
we are only three fewer than projected
attendees we're a thousand 27 which is
wonderful we issued the remote
participants 442 we should 221 the
letters of invitation for visas the
revenue from registrations is six
hundred ninety eight thousand sixty
sixty-five and sponsorship revenues for
forty three at three and three two
dollars it's a bit convenient looking
back I tip 101 in London we had 1211
prepared attendees 85 more than were
projected and I won't read every last
number out here bottom line we did
pretty well the revenues total were 1
million for nine three thousand 876
thank you thank you coin and Porsche
next we have the NomCom Scott hello ietf
community do we have we need some
attention you come on let's get some
energy going here this is NomCom it's
exciting stuff so the so I'm your new
Nam Kham chair coming in and so I have a
few slides that I've prepared so the
first slide is to show not that slide
the first slide is to show that it is
actually possible to herd cats and this
is what we're going to be doing for the
next six to eight months and so I'm not
going to tell you which who the cats are
any of that you can figure that out for
yourself but the the important thing
here is to acknowledge the fact that we
have a large number of volunteers that
are helping out with this process of
Allah
the next set of leaders for the ietf I
would like all of the voting and
non-voting members if you're in the room
please stand if you've got your orange
dot wave it proudly
one there's one there's another one over
there a couple back there so these are
the people that I'm going to be relying
on heavily I am a non-voting member
which means all I can do is make sure
the cats fill in the right boxes so it
is very important to provide feedback
and the way that we're going to interact
with the community is through our
wonderful set of IETF data tracker tools
so if you've never used it you can
probably have but if you've never looked
at it I provided the link to the website
and there are some tabs at the top and
so when you're ready to nominate
yourself or someone else you can click
on the nominate tab and fill out the
forms and then emails will happen and
then you know magic occurs and then when
we get to the point of having all the
nominations and nominees then you'll be
able to provide some feedback and
there's going to be some new behavior so
look you know keep your eye out for some
new behavior and new ways to provide
feedback to the NomCom this year if
you're looking to see what type of
experience we're looking from the
community we will have we have some
information there now but it's based on
whether that information is current
there's a couple of places we're still
looking for some more details about the
experience and so I'll I'll point that
out in a slide or two and then there's
questionnaires if you're going to be a
nominee we have a questionnaire that you
need to fill out those are work in
progress you can see what we did last
year and we're going to continue to do
some work on those so that's some hard
work that we're going to be working on
soon like in the next week or two so
here is my proposed timeline this is
published on the NomCom main page the
important date here that we really are
striving for is the August 16th date the
NomCom will be working very diligently
to make sure that we have all the job
descriptions and the questionnaires and
and our thoughts together to be ready to
announce the call for nominations on the
16th of August once that thing comes out
we expect a flurry of activity from this
community so that we can have a
wonderful pool a set of people that that
we can choose from something that's new
this year as you may have heard if you
were paying attention to previous
conversation tonight is this LLC board
member so I want the community to start
thinking about this because this is not
the type of position that the NAM IETF
NomCom has has asked for in in the past
and so there's some different
characteristics of people that were
looking for so please take time provide
some consideration read the background
and really provide the this NomCom with
a reasonable wonderful set of candidates
for this so I am going to end this is my
last slide I'm going to end quoting the
famous American philosopher Fiona Apple
that there are a couple lines we are an
extraordinary community right there's a
song that she has it says but he's no
good at being uncomfortable so he can't
stop staying exactly the same
she also says but I'm good at being
uncomfortable so I can't stop changing
all the time what I'm asking this
community to do is embrace the
uncomfortable we're going into a world
where things are changing we need to
make sure that we think outside the box
thinks of think of ways to make the ietf
community even better than it is and so
look around the room this is your
community it's up to you to make it
awesome so help me do that thank
Thank You Scott and thank you for your
willingness to serve in the role I know
it's a it's a lot of work Allison can I
ask you to come on back up this is most
of you made many of you may not have
known Bob Braden which seems almost
impossible to me because for the first
25 years of the IETF you would not have
been able to not know about Braden
but if you do remember him if you're you
know since we had this nice growth and
lots of newcomers
you probably remember him as the person
who took over the RFC editor after the
death of John Postell in 1998 and serves
in that role with Joyce Reynolds for
many years
Joyce is also gone now and also very
much missed the people who remember
about working with Bob will remember his
his work on the end-to-end task force
and then research group RSVP maybe some
of you remember that he was a fierce
advocate for the earliest days of
internet multimedia when so this is the
starters to just talk about him
technically because we are a technical
body he bridged us from the days when
there were lots of task forces and to
end task force and IETF for parallel
organizations in those days to a time
that that we most of us don't even know
all the different things that we owe Bob
for in terms of technology and and
things that we takes here that we take
for granted now
but then the other thing is that the
other night a group of us who had known
him well met together with his two sons
and with two nieces of his who came here
because ITF was such an important part
of Bob's life and reminisced about him
and I just want to say very briefly that
everybody who spoke spoke of his humour
that it was acute and mostly gentle and
they spoke of his genuine and warm
willingness to teach he was never a
professor but he was always a teacher
here at ietf and many of us who have
been in the idea for a long time a great
deal too the way that Bob taught
newcomers and and helped people to
become knowledgeable about the whole of
our internet architecture and then
finally people kept mentioning his great
dedication he was supremely dedicated to
the Internet and to the IETF and carried
out kind of heroic efforts on the part
of us that we still use full standards
such as the post requirements standard
that required just heroism on his part
to pull off and he he is being
memorialized here because of that
tremendous and and formative role that
he played in in our organization and our
technology I don't know if anyone else
wants to say a few words about Bob but
that may not be working maybe come to
the next one up Philip Rin de Ville I
remember being on my second job out of
college 25 years old working for
Wellfleet as a contractor on basic
security options and ripping my hair out
about the ambiguities of precedents of
the options and what options in felony
before or after and so forth and
bob was extremely patient with me
walking me through the logic of how
everything worked and they're giving me
great insight in what wasn't stated in
the RFC and I don't think it's a stretch
to say that I wouldn't be here today if
it hadn't been for him thank you and
also welcome back yep it's been 30 years
and one week since my last sigh eighty
up my foot's
we have a model you see in our science
there that ietf making your network
better I think about Bratton I think ITM
making their net work with dedication
and humor thank you okay we're gonna
move on to the postal award
[Music]
[Laughter]
thank you it's my great pleasure on
behalf of the internet society to
present the 2018 Jonathan the Postell
award jon postel the first editor of the
RFC series the first director of Vienna
and the first member of the Internet
Society in 1892 the Jonathan B Postell
award was established by the Internet
Society to honor individuals or
organizations that like Jon Postel
have made outstanding contributions and
service to the data communications
community since his death and his stuff
the award of the first award in 1999 9
17 times this award has been given to
esteem members of this community I
myself have had the amazing privilege of
doing the last 4 and now the final time
I do this the fifth what is very special
about this award it is a peer award so
the prior winners of the award are
picking the next person who is Stephen G
hooters
for his leadership and personal
contributions at the network start-up
Resources Center that enabled countless
others to develop the Internet in more
than a hundred and twenty countries this
year you are the winner of this very
special award which is stuck in customs
so when I first got your message a
couple months ago Kathy I was scrolling
through morning email and I read it and
then I decided to have a few more sips
of coffee and read it again to make sure
it wasn't spam and then I you know kind
of flashed back and I thought 1996
Montreal and the last time I was here
was the the joint inet IETF meeting that
was here in Montreal and I was one of
the volunteer of AIESEC folks helping
out with the inet workshops and and
there I made friends with with a guy
named idea at Google menu you know him
he he was came from know made Togo for
the workshop and you know we were when
it was over we went to the IETF meeting
to go you know check that out and we
were riding on an escalator and he said
hey man how do i how do I get this dot T
G you know my country code you know
top-level domain isn't delegated yet and
in a great moment of serendipity John
was coming up the escalator as we were
going down and I just said see that guy
with the long gray beard we need to talk
to him and you know I said John could
you wait for us at the top and he said
sure and so we rode up and you know idea
I introduced himself posed his question
and John chatted with him for a few
minutes and and said you know you know
the drill get the nameservers up and
fill out the template and sent it in and
I D I worked with actually a guy from
from Quebec here from Montreal Falls
normal who assisted him with getting all
that going and a few days later you know
that TT was on the net and so I kind of
thought back to how how in a way nice
and simple you know things were things
were back then and it gave me a nice
time to reflect about that experience
with John I'm happy to receive this
award you know on behalf of the network
start-up Resource Center and I feel
strongly that it really should be a
group award because there are a lot of
people that contribute to this from you
know folks at the University of Oregon
to international contractors and dozens
and dozens of volunteers some of whom
are in this room but you know when I
first started working with it in 1993
quite some time ago you know it already
had roots well before that and in the
original you know vision and inspiration
and frankly sweat was all Randy bush
randy had started in the late 80s
assisting folks in South Africa with
establishing some of their first
connections to research institutions
universities and that led over to the
neighbors want to use CP email feed in
Namibia and Botswana Zambia Zimbabwe etc
and and it led to this amazing set of
stepping stones that that really helped
several dozen countries with some of
their first tcp/ip connections and so
1992 randy teamed up with John Clemson
who was at MIT at the time and he was
working with a United Nations University
project under the international
nutrition foundation and they were
trying to get email connections in a
bunch of countries so folks could
basically do nutrition education with
people in their countries about this so
they wrote a grant to the National
Science Foundation to formalize what
they were doing and that's really the
roots of it and and another great moment
of serendipity there was a guy named
Steve Goldstein some of you may know him
and and he happened to be appointed as
the international interagency networking
coordinator about this time and really
needed to start internationalizing the
NSF net and getting connections into
countries where
u.s. scientists were being funded to do
you know paleontological research in
Mongolia and geophysics research in the
Rift Valley and all sorts of things like
that so several other people got
involved in Randi was awesome that you
know recruiting people for the inet
training workshops and and then starting
to cultivate network operator groups and
always infusing a spirit of cultivating
network operators helping each other and
that's really the essence of how the SRC
still operates today and you know we've
evolved the model and techniques to
today's Internet to do the training and
things are virtualized and all sorts of
other other advancements but but the
heart and spirit still really go back to
the roots that that I learned that we
all learned from Randy and and John and
Jon Postel was a close peer of theirs I
was fortunate to meet him by association
with Randy and John and really grateful
to receive this today so thank you
I suck Thank You ITF thank you
University of Oregon and various other
few dozen sponsors particularly NSF in
Google that have been steadfast over the
years and and thanks to all of you that
contribute to the work of the anistar
Sea and helping advance the net in new
places thank you
okay so next we have a somebody special
to recognize we thought you were gonna
get off the stage Cathy but you're gonna
have to come on back up not just yet
you can wait I'll give you a little
break so I knew of Cathy before I knew
Cathy going back to her days as a in
government and nad Verizon working on
telecom policy my father also was
working on telecom policy not always on
the same side is Cathy often almost
never on the same side as Cathy from
what I could gather from from from the
my family lore but I think the way that
Cathy would would characterize him and
actually she just did this the other day
was that she would say I love him for it
and that's really the spirit that Cathy
that I've seen Kathy brings to her role
at I sock in her role in the Internet
community when I did get to work with
her starting in the Ayana transition
process several years ago that was
always the mentality that she brought
even if we have opposing views different
parts different constituencies
she was always striving to see what are
the commonalities get us to focus on our
common goals and what we're trying to
achieve together even if she disagreed
with you she loved you for it and given
the success of that transition process
we are all the beneficiaries of her
leadership and strategic vision in that
process even closer to home Cathy has
been really integral to our ability to
carry out the is a to dato process thus
far and on a really short timeline for
something for a project this complex she
has really combined an openness of mind
to allow the IETF
to explore all different avenues of what
it is that we might want to do as an
organization as a community well also at
the same time constantly reaffirming I
Sox support for the IETF and the desire
to provide whatever it is that we need
in order to succeed and continue to make
the internet work better and for that
I'm very grateful and I think I think we
all are so thank you so much Kathy for
all of your contributions as AIESEC
president and CEO and we do have a few
gifts for you if you want to come on up
on stage we have the traditional plaque
you've given a lot of these plaques so
we got your plaque
of course it's not the real class we're
gonna send you the real play we know
that unlike some folks in our community
whose retirement involves sending many
many emails on mailing lists your
retirement sounds like it's going to
involve potentially staring at the ocean
and we wouldn't want you to forget about
us while you're staring at the ocean so
we got you an IETF emblazoned beach
towel again not the real towel the real
towel thank you this is a bit of a
surprise
it's it's been a experience an honor and
a privilege to be part of this community
to be part of the Internet Society the
work you do work the Internet Society
does is crucial to the to the evolution
of the Internet to its continued
opportunities that it provides for the
people of the world and so it is with
great appreciation and I appreciate this
Powell I now intend to look at the ocean
and figure out what it all means
except we have the IV open mic so if the
IAB could come up to the stage please so
while the rest of the IAB is assembling
I must note that tonight one of our
colleagues Christian we Toma was unable
to enjoin us because with death is his
family
our thoughts are with him and his wife
as they have returned to France to deal
with the situation as is traditional
we'll start with introductions Gabriel
what I used her Susanna Alison moonkin
Robert sparks Justin to elicit Cooper
check hoodie
Linda Shore Yaya
Marc Donegan Brenna Dremel Heather
Flanagan IRC editor he mic lines are
open
I totally
believe you you're really hoping I'm
gonna sing the Zero Mostel version
comedy tonight aren't you thank you
[Applause]
thank you for asking very I have a list
it's rather long first some of you might
have heard that we're working on
changing the RFC format is this is this
a shock to anyone in this room wait I
saw a hand okay what there's two I don't
believe you
yet so this is a project we've been
working on for quite some time the good
news is that we are in the phase that
the RFC production Center is actively
testing the tools so it's it's moved
from you know a gleam in my eye to
actual code that we're trying to make
sure is running once we have it to a
state that it works for the production
center that we're going to be reaching
out to the community and asking you all
to be testing it as well to make sure it
works for you
at this point I'm expecting that to
happen around the next meeting things
have taken a little bit longer than that
I have certainly hoped but progress is
being made just slow and steady so
there's that other projects however are
on my list some of which are a little
bit mmm I would call edgy there's things
I want to try and do like when we have
RFC's that are actual proper HTML with
the CSS wouldn't it be really
interesting to have a sandbox place to
say well what else can we do with this
can we actually annotate these with some
of the errata would that cause problems
in terms of the the where people
reference
archival version of a document I don't
know this is something I want to explore
there's a lot I can do with the metadata
in documents that can be improved
and that can do that doing that as an
add-on effect of making the documents
much more easily easily indexed in other
organizations sites and services and to
be very very clear I should have put
this in my email to the to the IETF list
earlier all of this is all well and good
but frankly the first priority the
priority that comes before all of this
is to publish documents if any of the
projects that I come up with look like
they're going to impact the rate of
publication that's something I do with a
lot of consultation and otherwise the
projects have to wait because we want to
get your documents out the door that's
the most important thing that the RFC
editor does so that's that's the short
short version Aaron I believe you're
next so there's a few questions here
some information mostly trying to get
some information so I used to way back
in to be part of the IRC editor I'm
currently part of something called the
RCA editorial board there's another
group called the part of CSeries
Oversight Committee which my
understanding is is the support group
serving at the pleasure of the ivy
wondering if you could maybe talk a
little bit about the relationship
between that group and the ie how the
IDE uses them maybe a little bit about
their involvement in last night was
something I didn't see come up on the
list or in the box and I understand that
the entire group is being is up for
potential replacement I was what if you
could sort of talk a little bit about
well first is that true and if so why
Thanks so the RFC series Oversight
Committee is actually an IAD program
it's set out in one
our seas the number of which I am
looking up frantically or actually ELISA
we are saying a look up for me okay so
during the whole like many other
programs it's part of how the IB
maintains long-term commitments that may
continue past the lifetime of any single
IAB member so the whole program effort
there has been put in place to make sure
that the IV can keep attention to
something over a longer period of time
than the lifetime of any single member
or chair and in this particular case the
the artsy sets out that the our sock
will be part of the oversight of the RFC
series sorry Phil do you have a
clarifying question or are you just
standing up for later okay so the our
sock is in fact at this point we have
put out a call for volunteers and there
are interviews going on this week some
of them have happened already for new
volunteers or continuing members of our
sock and it's actually pretty typical
you'll see that the IAB calls for
volunteers all the time for different
things and the appointment process will
go forward after we've had completion of
the call for volunteer after we've had
the interviews and after we've collated
the information from the interviews with
the public information that we got from
putting out a call for comments oh sorry
Robert did you want to talk about our a
little bit continue to talk about our
sock and then I'll talk about the
so the defining documents for our sock
talk about the reason for having it as a
separate body the IB manages it as a
program because it manages many other
things like a program but it is a little
bit more than a program in the way that
it's defined when we set out to call for
the people who volunteer to serve on the
our sock we realize they had been quite
a long time since we had done a serious
evaluation of everyone that was on the
our sock and IAB decided that we would
just re-evaluate everyone who was
willing to continue at the time the IAB
made that decision
everyone was fully cognizant that one of
the major reasons for having our sock as
a separate body was for continuity of
information that was expected to be a
relatively stable body of people so if
there were is concern that this was a
clear this late and put a new set of
people in kind of intended activity is
certainly not the case at all
is more exercising the responsibility
the IAB has for overseeing the are sock
itself and making sure that we're doing
the right thing
there's there are no terms the document
that created our sock has the principles
that define how the IB should manage is
constituency and the IB is very much
aware of what those principles are so
the artsy in question is artsy sixty-six
thirty-five somebody mumbled earlier but
has been confirmed since then my
apologies for not having it on the tip
of my tongue on the question of the buff
as you may have seen from the message
the IAB sent out earlier today one of
the issues there is we did not do some
of the coordination that we would have
normally done in a timely fashion and
indeed there was not a coordination with
the our sock in advance so some of that
is certainly one of the things we feel
like we did wrong about that and we
apologize
[Applause]
heresy is a reasonable path for how the
concern that motivated the buff could
have been expressed I'm trying to
understand sort of the wall of where
this what does this do and so I think
they mean responsibility I think that
there is a distinction here that that's
important to draw right the are suck and
the RC and the editorial board all do
things that are very very important but
primarily relate to how the RFC series
is now now there's a role that the RSV
plays in thinking about the evolution of
the RFC theory sorry the RSC plays and
thinking about how the evolution of the
RFC series is there's also a role for
the whole community to think about it as
I I noted this particular problem has
been called to the fore by the IAB in
the past there have also been other
suggestions for changes to the RFC
series for example the best current
operational practices effort that was
discussed some time ago that came from
external bodies to the ATF so I don't
think there's a limitation in who can
suggest changes to the series but
there's a very important principle that
those discussions need to be public and
I think that the problem that we ran
into here is in trying to pay attention
to that principle and making the
discussions public some of the external
coordination that should have happened
before that public discussion didn't
occur thank you
okay so I have Phil next and then I
believe I have that microphone and then
Bob and then back to that microphone
well I choose the question for the is G
and we looking at the RFC series I think
the part of the problem is that we have
this frame of how do we fix RFC's and it
might well be that what we need is
something that's a little bit between an
internet draft and an RFC because many
times all the people are coming to the
ITF and asking for an RFC is simply to
have something that is permanent and can
be referenced elsewhere now we've given
up the principle that drafts expire and
disappear there now
and that's great for me as a patent
expert witness because it's my prior art
sources I think that maybe rather than
trying to reform RFC's and solve problem
in that prayer it may be that you need
something in between something a little
bit less than an RFC and maybe what we
need to do is to work out yeah are the
dress something that the ihe should be
doing should be there be happening with
the RFC
considered together because you've got
to publishing streams here and you need
to think about where the best place is
rather than choose one or the other
there did you want to answer them I
think it's an interesting idea it's
something I want to explore I'm my gut
reaction is a bit of hesitancy of doing
one of the things we had is feedback the
other night is dividing RFC's into a
host of other things means you have you
have a brand to build and you've got
confusion that you're introducing to
solve other confusion how you handle
that can be really delicate so I it
makes me anxious to consider how we're
gonna do it it's not a no it's a we have
to be careful if we go that route phrase
you used which was continuity of
information I realized that can be they
can seem like a motivation to keep a lot
of stability in a governing board but
the contrary or what that makes me worry
about is stagnation and a lack of new
blood and you know it's which is a
constant problem across a lot of groups
that we have around this organization
and so I encourage you to keep the IAB
to keep in mind that flow to get new
ideas and new blood into these oversight
body
you're pointing in addition to
maintaining continuity in fact having a
regular turnover can be a bit a way to
maintain constantly because you're
established processes around the in your
life you know fallible individual needs
any customer so that's why more grants
the question I'd like to propose it's
opposed to the folks
I mean multistakeholderism is you know
thing that we're kind of keen on around
here since of making sure that all the
people who are affected and have a stake
in a decision are represented in making
that decision and so I'm curious what
Heather and the numbers of the I being
policy with the RFC series think what
you guys think is the set of
stakeholders for the RFC series and how
you're pulling in relevant feedback from
the whole collection of stakeholders in
deciding how this RFC series of Falls
Heather and then I think I'll answer is
one one of the things that frankly I
want to talk to just about anyone that
can spell RFC if they're technical
enough to know anything about that or or
incorporate that I don't know if folks
if folks realize that I'm not full time
doing RFC series editor I actually work
with scholarly publishers I work with
national research and education networks
I do a lot in the Identity and Access
Management space I have a lot of
contacts with some of the network
operator groups around the world through
the ITF I have contacts with a lot of
the corporate entities that use rfcs and
I have no shame in leveraging all of
those things to get the information I
need and I let intern I will come back
to this community and sort of the heart
of it all to say here's who here's the
type of group I've been talking to am I
missing anybody I've already gotten some
really excellent feedback about reaching
out to open-source communities which i
think is brilliant as well as talking to
ripe and a few others so open to pretty
much anything the one thing I would like
to add to that is that there are really
two classes of stakeholders here and
that's the people
we're producing RFC's and the people are
consuming them and it's much easier for
us to reach out to the people who are
producing them we're connected to every
single one of the streams here and one
of the reasons that we like to hold
meetings such as the one that was held
earlier at at IDs is because you have
ITF IRT f is e and IB all of the stream
managers are together at one time and
and that can be a failing right it's
very easy for us to look at the
production side of that and it's
extremely difficult to pull in who may
be the consumers of these RFC's and as
the stakeholder community that does
require some outreach that heather is
going to be taking on but that is very
general and we could use your help as a
community with I think one of the things
she just mentioned for example was that
adament suggests that the D open-source
community might be one as a consumer of
RFC's for which we don't have great data
and they're gonna try and work together
to get some additional data on that set
of consumers even though they're very
rarely producers of artsy's and
certainly there are other members of the
community who have other ideas for how
we can do outreach to the set of
stakeholders from that side of the
equation it would be very valuable
Thanks the only addition of that is that
given that I think this consumer
stakeholder group is the entire Internet
community numbers and millions it's
gonna be difficult to take kind of an
artisanal you talk to people approach if
someone goes and talks to people
approach it so I think I would encourage
you to take some innovation in
collecting data in different minutes
couldn't agree more
one of the meetings I'm having this week
is with some of the folks who do
communications and marketing at the
Internet Society to figure out if if I
was going to do something like a survey
how how does one do that how do they do
their outreach what's that going to look
like could I work could i potentially
leverage some of the Isocrates or you
know it's it's just a very initial
exploration but I think you're right I
as much as I apparently tried to I can't
talk to everybody I talked about a lot
of people but not everybody so yes it's
a good well taking point Bob I think
your nights thank you so I'm Bob Hinton
I've been involved in different degrees
of the RF series RFC series since you
know I worked at Jon Postel and all of
RFC editors since written a few RFC's
and so forth so I appreciate the alcohol
that apology you sent to the RFC plus
the IDF list about this but I would sort
of like to chastise the IB for the what
you did here the you know so if I'm
gonna read from you know RFC 66 35 which
defines this section 2.1 RFC editor the
RFC series editor is the individual with
overall responsibility for the quality
continuity and evolution of the RFC
series this activity should have been
directed to the RFC editor the IB should
not have taken it on it doesn't say the
IAB is responsible here for these the
evolution in these things so I think
you've seriously overstepped your
responsibility here and and so I think
you're some sense your apology didn't go
far enough
because it didn't get the impression
that you sort of we're willing to take
it back it was more of you just didn't
follow the right procedure but I think
this should have just gone you should
have asked the RFC editor to go look at
this issue and come you know consult
with the community and come back with a
recommendation you shouldn't have done
above the I guess you shouldn't have
approved it it appears that you did this
in a rush so the IAB which is supposed
to be the deliberative body who says
they're very busy decided to take this
on themselves I I think you know I think
you made a serious mistake here and
so I hope you take this and take this to
heart and next time or some other issue
you figure out what the right thing to
do is but this this was not very good
performance Leslie I think you're next
my remarks are probably gonna put some
context around some of Bob's and and
also maybe some of my remarks would have
fit in a little bit in the in memoriam
section because it occurs to me that
there's some stuff to this Kennedy to do
well to remember and probably if you
didn't know Bob rating then you probably
don't remember this part of the RFC
series history namely that for a number
of years I don't know about a dozen
years ago it was published out of ISI it
was funded by I sock it was funded by I
sock even before there was a nyasa
it was funded as a separate activity so
as part of the administrative
restructuring that we did the last time
around it was time for that part of our
universe to move on and become under the
same umbrella as the other activities
administratively but at the time it was
the RFC editor was a very independent
beast it was an academic function hosted
at ISI like I said and when we were in
discussions and I can remember which
airport I was striding around having
those discussions of the head of ISI at
the time to move the function into
something that was closer to the IETF
administration there was a lot of
concern over how to make sure this
remained true to the spirit of the RFC
series so how could it maintain his
support for the independent activities
that have published because the IETF
does not the IV does not look after the
RFC series for the IETF the IAB looks
after at the RFC series for the internet
community so it's broader and so even
having a bob here to talk about it stuff
is very very focused it's it's as
Richard outlined there is many more
people to reach out to you so on and so
forth but another piece of that puzzle
was how could we make
sure that the rnc series editor was
adequately supported with a broad base
of people who were familiar with both
technical publishing and the internet
publishing space and hence the artists
Hawk to be the heir Azov was constituted
not just to be another IEP program the
arishok is an IT program simply because
that was the mechanism that the bill but
the purpose of the Arisaka was to be
that collection of independent advisers
for the independent RFC series editor so
I think it's great for any committee
it's absolutely great to view them
periodically review the composition you
know adjusts the the mandate if
necessary but it isn't just that this is
an IAB thing to you know update and
twiddle with you know AB off on a Monday
night this is larger than the IETF it
has to be handle of the broad
perspective that the IEP has which goes
beyond the IETF um and it has a rich
history all of its own so Bob referenced
the artists II that details the
mechanics of how that's got brought into
the the IETF space but there's a lot of
rich history out there of the background
of the RFC series that people in this
room sure certainly should make
themselves aware of and I think that
maybe there's a little bit more reading
for the IAB to do before making more
operational choices and discussions
going forward
Thanks so just to point out two quick
clarifying things the independent series
editor also has an editorial board
called the I set which I believe Aaron
referenced earlier which does editorial
advice to them that's a distinct from
the arishok both or of course available
to advise both the independent series
editor where our talk is more for the
RSC the other thing I'll point out here
is that one of the issues that I think
that the IAB was thinking about here was
evolution and not just evolution for the
ITF but in particular for the IR TF and
for some of the other streams it was
very clear in the buff on Monday that
that particular concern was not well
expressed
we certainly apologize for it but the
the evolution of the streams and the
evolution of the output of the bodies
that are both present here as producers
is certainly something that we continue
to look at beyond just the IETF as we
said we're also going to be looking much
harder at working out how we can look at
the consumption side of the stakeholder
body but the the simple fact is the
movement into four streams has started
but not completed a change in how the
production works and we have to think as
a community not just the ITF but as a
technical community on whether it's best
to push that change forward let it
evolve on its own or make sure that the
change is limited in order to keep all
of them together and that's the
conversation we think Heather will be
having as she goes out and starts the
rest of this process
I hope you've gotten a lot of useful
pointers here about what prepara
preparatory materials everybody
participating in that conversation
should have read before engaging in it
we have RFC's and so on and some
thoughts about where to have it thanks
thanks and of course suggestions on both
of those are welcome
I believe andrew is next and then listen
hi my name is Andrew Sullivan and I
wanted to say thank you to the IAB and
to the iesg for approving this voff I
thought it was useful and the reason I
think that is not because it was perfect
and not because that conversation has
completed or the right results has come
out or anything like that but rather
because this is the sort of thing that
people sometimes go off into you know
rooms and talk amongst themselves and
don't talk about in public and I think
that you know this is a large community
there's a lot of different ways that
people can express themselves and so on
and this is a way that we can get out
amongst ourselves and say look here are
the people who are producing these
things and we need to talk to each other
about you know what though
issues are and so on and this is going
to be a fraught topic this would be one
that creates a lot of you know strong
feelings and there's a lot of history
and different people have different
views about this but I think that it's
good that we you know we can't came
together was like another plenary right
because there's nothing else against it
and I think that that's a that's a fine
thing to do you know III can understand
that there are people who who don't feel
that it was executed perfectly or
whatever I myself having executed a few
things and and publicly not always very
well understand that you know sometimes
you're gonna have a little bit of
trouble but you know I still think you
took a certain amount of bravery on your
part to say hey we're gonna talk about
this I'm going to talk about it public
hearing the people who have to do this
work and and it's definitely gonna be a
delicate topic so I really appreciate it
i want to thank you who's here next but
i actually want to change the topic
slavery several people have referenced
transparency and engaging the community
and conversation and whatever and i'm
i'm a person who likes people to show
their work that's parkway I like the
drafts that's part go ahead I like the
archival part of the RFC series I would
like the IAB to publish their agendas
and open their calls in the same way
okay
we'll take that under investment and get
back to you certainly all of the minutes
are public I don't know that we've ever
published the agendas I got and I will
point out a good bit of this actually
also occurred at the retreat with the I
be in the is she and those minutes are
not public either so I take your point
so I'm sorry I can't see you very well
but there is somebody at the back might
oh sorry I didn't see you at all
apparently I'm an Bennet view of the
negative feelings that were raised
around the RF C++
if I have comments on the very
interesting topics that were raised on
that off is it appropriate to post them
to the RF C++ naming this doors there's
some better forum for this discussion
the RFC first husband Thomas has been
closed so that's you're not going to be
able to post anything there anymore and
Heather I think has as requested that
they happen on the RAC interest list
which is a much longer running list it's
the RFC interest mailing list sorry yeah
if somebody could write it down for you
having um and just as a side note for
folks who would rather drink bleach then
listen to format conversation I think
there might be some of you um I'm trying
to focus the RC interest list on on
discussion topics and whatnot now that
we're moving to looking at actual tools
and testing tools and whatnot there is
an XML to RFC - dev list and I expect a
lot more of the operational format work
discussions to happen there when we're
ready to release the tools for user
testing so keep that in mind speaking
personally I have to know what flavor of
bleach before you tell me it's gonna be
a format issue and I Clement I think you
were first before Sinead but I'm sorry I
can't see you because there's a light
shining right at me from my chair
Princeville again so I attended the nrw
I think that was the first time that
they were here somebody dabbles in
security without trying to make too much
of a fool of himself since everything
has security implications these days
anyway I appreciated having
the academics present who will then
study my work and then tell me where I
went wrong after race or possibly even
during these meetings so that I'm spirit
that embarrassing so is that going to be
a regular thing the nrw Allison yeah so
the it's it's that was our third
iteration but it was our first time
where we had it during the IETF week
instead of the weekend before and that
was the inspired idea of the program
chairs that they wanted to make sure
that we actually brought it together
with the community here at the IETF so
we we actually already have the logo for
a and our W 2019 ready to go and we're
putting it making plans to get the next
one going and in the near term yeah yeah
so yeah come again next year
ITF first two it'll be here in Montreal
again too so a lot of local knowledge
will serve you again well drink hi my
name is Shankar I apologize this is the
wrong forum I'll sit down please don't
yell at me
but I been to a lot of side meetings
this week which were held in the venue
like with groups of 30 or 40 people
discussing topics that were highly
relevant to some of them working groups
that are going on and I noticed a trend
towards this over the past few years
that we start to have meetings that
don't have minutes or agendas or any way
for remote people to participate that
are happening in sort of semi formal
ways in the ITF and we have a kind of
there's there's pushback and boss and
you can only have two for specific I'm
sorry I might I'm in the wrong place
no you're you're actually for providing
an excellent segue because your question
is for the iesg
so I'm gonna ask them to come up to the
stage
as the IEP to step down and you can
continue with your question as they do
[Applause]
I'm just showing my ignorance of how the
ITF actually works so yeah so when you
that's basically it I know with with
boss there's a restriction you can we
have two boss for some reason
so I know within certain people that
have interest in topics they're kind of
afraid to have a Boff if they don't want
to waste their boss so that's where our
boss became kind of a thing but now you
have to register a barb off people have
things and they don't know what to call
these meetings because they're not
allowed to call them anything so I guess
what I would like to see if some of you
doesn't come to every idea but when I'm
here likes participate is that I think
it should be easier to have some sort of
official gathering here that doesn't run
into all these issues about what do we
call it how do we record it who's
allowed to know about it in these kind
of things
that's basically my observation I guess
Peter thank you so we're gonna do a
quick round of introductions and then
we'll take your question first we have
two members of the IHG who were not able
to make it to this the meeting this week
suresh krisshnan the internet area
director had a death in his family and
Spencer Dawkins is out with a family
medical emergency as well so Spencer may
be on remote participation and we have
we have their photos here so people know
what they look like in any event and
we'll start with introductions with Adam
Adam Roche art area director
nothing he knows about doing those
operations and management Warren Kumari
also absent management Ben Campbell art
area Elissa Cooper general area Mia
could leave in transport chatter div
chair
Benjamin conducts security areas
director Terry Madison incident area
director and right here is sheesh JEP
regard routing risk loss security Alexei
Melnikov for applications in the real
time
okay so to your question Shane I have
just a few thoughts and then I'm sure
lots of others will want to chime in so
this is a topic that I know we've been
wrestling with as long as I've been on
the IHG and and it's probably been much
longer than that
to try to bring some clarity to you know
what is considered an official meeting
and when does that note will apply and
all of these things what we've done
recently as the IHG to try and
facilitate that is we've created these
side meeting rooms specifically for side
meetings and they explicitly do not have
remote participation capability they
don't have projectors the idea of them
is to facilitate ad hoc discussion of
you know a closer interaction between a
smaller group of people than what you
would normally get with AB off with
microphones and presentations and slide
decks and so on and they have we have
this sign-up procedure for them they
open up at a certain time before the
meeting starts and people can sign up to
book them and then you know advertise
them and the usual way ad hoc way on
various mailing lists now it's seen that
part of the ideal of this was to bring
some clarity because it did start to
seem to us like there were these there
were more and more you know barb offs
that were happening in meeting rooms had
nothing to do with the bar and they were
looking more like buffs which go through
a more formal approval process so the
idea was to draw a brighter line between
these things it sounds like maybe that
hasn't entirely worked and that's that's
very useful feedback but that was the
idea behind them other people want to
comment yeah
so in this specific point in the wiki
you can also see which like when the
room is reserved right so at least you
have like a notion about what's going on
but I totally understand that it's kind
of confusing because you don't know
where you need to be and who to talk to
and so on but like I think we as a
community also agree that this is kind
of a value part of having a face-to-face
meeting that you actually have the
opportunity to talk to each other in the
hallways having a side meeting and and
and the thing we're struggling with is
like how to get this work at the right
point of time back to the whole
community
to involve our vetting discussion and if
you have further ideas would be more
than happy to listen maybe removing the
two boss limit might be a good start I
don't know something that annoyed me for
years just the one one other detail here
is that there are some conversations
that have started about the display of
the agenda in the data tracker because
it's gotten that has also gotten a
little bit of lack of clarity of which
events land on the official agenda and
which ones do not and it seems like an
area that's kind of ripe for a bit of an
evolution in terms of how we represent
things on the agenda for for clarity
purposes I see we have Spencer at the
mic Spencer go ahead thank you so I just
wanted to say a couple things real
quickly one is that the ho the IAT has
been talking about stuff like this for a
while and one of the things that we've
been talking about ended up as being the
hot RFC session it's on Sunday night but
basically trying to say you know you
could talk you can't put together we're
trying to provide a venue where people
can put together a group to go off and
talk all week long and I mean you know
if a lot of the United because the
within two that are from Aaron Falk who
has really been thinking about how to
empower the community the other thing I
would say is that
the tube off-limit that's in our BCPs it
would take like one sentence to do a
change to that BCP that says through
working group forming buffs because you
know I don't think that our we used the
word buff to be conversations but also
efforts to form a working group I don't
you know I you know there there was the
idea that you don't want to have people
coming back and try to form a working
group with the same proposal like 35
times but I don't know why we would ever
cut off a conversation that we just
happened to call them off so they can
give you know get a room that that's on
the agenda and not be scheduled to give
other stuff thanks Spencer Barry I think
you're next we have done the the eye is
a 2.0 bops there were more than two okay
so when it's the right thing for one
thing as a general thing I think the
iesg has gotten better in recent years
at doing the right thing even when the
right thing is not exactly along the
letter of something that's written and I
think we should continue that one of the
things that the the other guy mentioned
was getting having the ability to have
remote participation in minutes and
things like that when we have a side
meeting however large or small it is
it's not connected to the rest of the
community very much
and I think I'd like to encourage the
iesg to be more lenient about approving
box realizing that there are real
scheduling issues involved here so that
more of these side meetings can be
accessible to the community in those
ways the other thing I wanted to come
back to the RF C++ Boff but in a
completely different way and kind of
related to this I really liked that it
was scheduled with nothing alongside
this has been something I've pushed on
for a while Jen area boss conflict with
everything and yet you know there are
always other things going on again
realizing that there are real scheduling
issues involved I'd like to encourage
you to make the first addition of a
generic Bob as conflict-free as you can
manage because it's really helpful to be
able to get thank you I think Aaron was
next I have a new topic
so my principal area involvement in the
IDF is the transport area and transport
is obsessed with finding qualified area
directors because it's been a challenge
for years and one of the changes that
I've seen I think across the whole iesg
has been a real effort to reduce the
workload to try to get to something
that's closer to half time instead of
close to full time and so this is a
question for the whole iesg is I'm
wondering is that what you're doing and
if you're if you're getting it down to
half time are you able to keep up with
your work is there stuff that's falling
off the plate what is it you know if you
have to prioritize what's not getting
done is this a strategy that's working
for us or should we think of something
else we have a mix of people between you
know some of them are working halftime
or there abouts some are working
full-time I'm pretty close to full-time
myself for example I believe that
Alexia's is somewhat lower than that but
between among the three art area
directors we can cover the art area
because we have sort of that mix that
balance and I know that it's like we've
we've given instructions to NomCom that
we you know we can have people who
aren't full-time but we can't have
everyone not full-time let me just
to the list of things I wanted to hear
that is are you able to keep up with the
reading do you know what's going on in
the working groups or is it a matter of
benign neglect so sorry weren't so yeah
I think I said them said it depends
wildly based upon the person I think it
also depends a lot on how long you've
been doing this for I mean this is my
second year for the beginning I was
definitely overwhelmed I didn't know
what I needed to pay attention to I
still don't know what I need to pay
attention to but I'm less stressed about
it you know I mean I think that one
learns relatively quickly which things
you need to be paying a lot of attention
to which you spend less on for me it's
probably thirty five or forty hours a
week so you know not really full time
maybe kind of I mean I know that there
are a lot of people who manage to get
this done and a lot less time so I think
it's how effective and how efficient you
are how much time you want to devote to
it you know I'm also good at
procrastinating so some of the time is
spent you know rearranging my desk and
sharpening all the pencils but as for my
head managing to keep up with my working
groups I think so I hope so no chairs
have complained yet you know if I'm not
please come along and tell me I'm not
sure what snark Jim came up with but I'm
sure some does that answer your question
mainly so I'm kind of in the opposite
situation I'm in my fourth year as an
area director and due to some job
changes I have historically had been 75%
the full time most of the time due to
some job changes I've been kind of
forced to push that down to 50 and it
definitely has made some changes I think
it's doable
one of the things I've started doing is
paying a little bit less attention to
drafts that are outside my expertise and
trusting the other 80s a little more and
I don't give as much editorial feedback
you that I used to give as far as
keeping up with my working groups and
things like that I
become a little more squeaky wheel
driven than I was before
but if anyone I have not been complained
to a nice please help any of my chairs
our working groups that need to get
plain to me will do so what you're
seeing is everyone experience various a
little bit and I think we all develop
our little tricks and tactics of how to
deal with the load but to add is that
keeping up with the working groups and
reading for the telecast this only part
of what we do we are also responsible
for all the policies around the ATF and
we need to talk about buy offs and
agendas and a bunch of other things so
what that means is that at least in my
case that the load varies quite a bit
this is not that easy to say well I have
every other week tell us as I have to
read 600 pages for that but it varies
preserve different topics and so I think
it's important to keep that in mind in
terms of how much the ABS also want to
be involved in those other discussions
and those other things which made being
driving some of the issues but it also
means just you know commenting and
keeping up with those discussions as
well so there's a lot more than just to
tell chats all right can we bypass you
Warren and go down this way you know I
was just gonna suggest you should stay
in for transport ad be the change you
want to see in the world and seriously I
spend substantially less than full time
so you're my thirty percent if you don't
wanna stand for a transport area ad
there's interior eighty as well
so I would absolutely concur with all of
my ad colleagues regarding that the
fluctuation of time the the other
observation I would add is that being an
ad will happily chew up as much time as
you're willing to give so if you want to
give all of your week your weekends your
holidays to being an ad it will suck it
up and it will love you for it and the
IDF will love you for it but you must
have some discipline thank you hi
because it means I've noticed that there
is a significant stream of documents on
the standards track that are submitted
to iesg that do not contain sections
about raising awareness of running codes
nor are companies with implementation
reports what I expect from an
implementation report is quite simple
that for each normative term in the
drafts a implementer indicates
compliance not compliance not applicable
or something else and these reports are
incredibly helpful especially with large
protocol extensions protocol
modifications to assess the readiness
and operation considerations protocol
he says I would want to promote the idea
of having running coat before things are
submitted to the iesg and I know some
companies consider this is a chicken
heck situation the fight that's my
receipt but on the flip side I want to
encourage people to basically put their
money where their mouth is if you
believe in an idea you should implement
sits on a Banta branch or something
internally and I'm not asking for open
source and asking for running coats
because I think the same Exchequer
predominantly is about interoperability
and if interoperability cannot be
demonstrated I I wonder why it's in is
you
when it comes to protocols so my
question to you in review would it be
possible to put more emphasis on
researching whether implementations
exists Thanks do you want go ahead no
alvaro sure so I I agree with you in
principle I think there
just like every time I agree with you
it's a principle wholly yeah we are the
ATF right we believe in running code and
I think that yes all the RCS I will talk
about implementation sections for
example and torts are important in the
routing area we have several working
groups that require implementations
specifically IDR requires two
implementations information reports and
everything else which is actually what
you just said for every should and must
summon documents how that works
further implementation on the other hand
I think that that this is one of those
topics that is probably better discussed
on a working by working group case where
in some cases it is maybe more important
to have those that specific requirement
to have implementations in other cases
it may not be so even for the routing
area we have IDR which requires two
others require one others ask questions
but it's not it's not consistent so I
will argue that from the point of view
of tightening timeliness for example of
getting the documentation out and
producing actual results from the IETF
sometimes waiting for implementation
might take a while I understand your
point that if people don't implement
them maybe it means we don't we don't
need that
so what's justice either one of two
things one is a specific working groups
talked about the specific needs if you
think that there is something that we
really need from an IETF point of view
that would change the requirements of
how the RFC stemis trackers hussar are
produced and qualified which would mean
a proposal right so you don't write
something down and get the community to
just talk about that so you're following
on from that I think that this is best
handled on a working group by working
group basis and sometimes on a sort of
case-by-case basis some documents don't
really even standards track documents
don't contain stuff that can really be
implemented
more talks like you know how you do
stuff when this was first discussed
Indiana Soph I was somewhat resistant to
it but recently I've got a document that
I'm co-authoring with Duane vessels
which got implemented in the hackathon
and somewhat because of what had been
suggested people wrote back you know
this bit is not clear when I tried to
implement it when I tried to read this
this bit was not there so I think this
is you know case-by-case working group
by working group but I think that there
is definitely value in even if it's not
a formal implementation report just you
know implementers providing feedback I
tried to do this and I didn't understand
what on earth you mates at section 12
but I started thinking mutations pretty
important I don't I think we shouldn't
confuse that with implementation reports
you know um speaking some protocols I've
been involved with post TLS one three
and quick like seven to ten independent
implementations that have a goatee
um and you know on one three seven are
seeing already a pretty substantial
fraction of lights a loss traffic uh
might be pretty sad if we have to spend
the amount of time would take to
document every derivative every 2119
term in the document had been informed
by somebody real wallet bookkeeping and
I don't think without nothing cool about
you to do with it implementations and it
should perhaps the working group working
group up out of this send of the Asia
rather than that per working group we
decide well maybe we wants
implementations so
I pretty much agree with the choir so
far that this should be a working group
my working group thing but I'm gonna
give it a little bit of a counter
opinion is that I am nervous about
putting more structural barriers into
getting drafts to propose the standard
and I think if we're going to and I
agree if there are implementations
having the reports is really good but
one of the big differences between
proposed standard an internet standard
is an inner standard does require at
least two interoperable implementations
and maybe one way to look at dealing
with this thing is to once again we've
tried this we've talked about this many
times but once again talk about maybe we
can put more emphasis on progressing
things from thank you so on the opt-in
versus opt out etc Oh a while back I
can't remember when I think it's
actually all of routing had a
requirement for to two implementations
but then there was a RFC published I
think by Fenner wrote it or what did it
removing that as the requirement and
going back and looking at the history
for that would be interesting the way
that that happened though was there was
an RFC published I think if you're
proposing this what would be reasonable
is write it up in a draft and we'll
discuss it
I mean everybody can chime in and then
we will have basically sent text yes so
RFC 1264 created the requirement and 47
94 eliminated it so might be worth
looking into the history well thank you
the numbers so I think Kerry was next
yeah this is back to Shane's question
you also mentioned at the outset that
there's going to be some agenda
experimentation at the next IETF
reserving Friday as sort of a day for
I'm wondering if you and the IAS you
have any thoughts about how the
structure those meetings will actually
be and whether we will be able to use
resources like medico to actually
include external people I'm thinking if
this becomes you know really an
interesting trend lots of meetings at
hoc and use in the final day things may
still over into the final weekend or the
following weekend like sending this you
know even longer so anyway what thoughts
about structure and resources so people
can correct me if I have it wrong but I
think the plan is to have some rooms
that have me to go and and projection
your typical kind of facilities for our
regular or working group meeting I think
that's what we wanted to do but just
give people more flexibility to schedule
them ad hoc and so I think about
structure at this point it's very
unstructured because it's an experiment
if more structures and you know what I
was needed it's something we will learn
from this experiment but I have also
heard ideas about for example research
groups taking the opportunity in half
like hold a meeting on that day in these
kind of things I'm really excited to see
what will happen I think you're an extra
this is been one the best
ITF meetings have been at you know every
you know never run out of food at any of
the snack breaks every meeting has been
in a room that's me nervous
a reasonable-sized you know everything
has just worked and I think
congratulations for the people who
organized that but I was saying that
because I also won't give my thanks
aware see which I have found to be very
useful because it's connected me with a
lot of people who are interested in the
ideas I've presented that you know their
security ideas but are not really
relevant inside the security they're
relevant in applications that might have
a requirement I think that that's an
experiment that does work to go back to
the first question about ad hoc meetings
if I'm designing a protocol
I do not invite a hundred of my best
friends to invite it with me the reason
I come to IETF meetings is because if
you want to effect the internet you
don't need a hundred people to design a
protocol but you need a hundred people
bought in to start deploying it so I
think there's always got to be some
times when you're going to say a small
group is gonna go off and work on the
focus thing alone and you know that's
just the way that you have to do so you
can move facts however when people do
that they have to bear in mind that the
decisions they make in that khabar had
to be you know there have to be sense of
it to the people who weren't allowed
into the cabal and that's not a decision
that they made in private that is a
proposal that they've made in private so
that they don't waste the time of a
hundred people thrashing out things in a
forum that aren't ready to be thrashed
out so I think it's a question of tone
and acceptance of the fact that you're
not making decisions thank you
just just to tie your to of your
comments together I think part of the
reason this venue is so great because
it's because it has so many spaces where
small groups of people can sit down and
have the kind of conversation that
you're talking about so thanks John
two quick questions
not going to make speeches tonight the
first is that as we look at meeting
participation figures we're seeing an
increased number of remote participants
on whom we're getting more and more
dependent including I noticed tonight
for good or bad reasons I be and is G
members we've got a number of procedural
bars to treating remote participants as
full participants and I'm wondering is
for a general question when or if the is
G intends to address that question
second question somewhat related
actually is that you mentioned during
your summary that there's an appeal
pending that appeal interacts with some
of the things to club tonight about the
openness and transparency of the
leadership process and I'm wondering
what the is G's timeframe is for
addressing it so on your first question
can you just elaborate about the the
barriers I just want to make sure I
understand we've got a Nam Kham which
will not allow remote participants to
participate we have a number of things
tied to the NomCom eligibility rules
which discriminate against from both
participants unless they're getting we
do we have historically done as others
have mentioned this evening a number of
semi informal but not very informal
because they're officially authorized
meetings which do not allow remote
participation I don't know if that's a
problem or not no question is really not
that I'm looking for particular
solutions it's that I'm asking if the
isg considers this important enough to
address this so what the timeframe is
thank you so I think just on the issue
of general interaction between remote
participants and in-person attendees at
the meetings the way that the IHG has
thought about this is that we are fully
supportive of the remote participation
facility
we think it's great we think it's you
know extremely effective at helping
bring new people in and support people
who can't make it to the meetings and so
forth
we do like to optimize if we have to
have a trade-off between the
accommodating remote participants and
accommodating people in the room if
we're going to be in the room we're
optimizing for in the room if we have to
make a trade-off but in many cases we
don't have to make a trade-off so that's
good I think on the issue of NomCom
eligibility that's a real issue at least
in my mind there's been a few others
pending large administrative matters
before the IETF and it's hard to do too
many of them at once
but I do think it's something that we
need to talk about and and potentially
address in the future so it's definitely
definitely something for us to take on
as I tried to say I'm not chastising you
for prioritizing other things I'm just
hoping this will not get postponed
forever
fair enough anybody else okay
oh the appeal sorry yeah so so we are
discussing the appeal we discussed it
this week we're working through our
response which we intend to have out in
August that's based on vacation
schedules and so forth I think your next
funding so organized aside we need every
I took me one of the chances I have is
getting people to know where it is and
be able to find it and while they you
know we do announce things over email it
gets lost in the clutter of the actual
ITF week we only have so much email it
would be a big help even if you label it
as this is a totally unauthorized ad hoc
thing that's going on that we have no
control over so you're in scary
territory a slot somehow on the official
agenda structure so you guys should say
we're in this room at this time talking
about this if you want to come come if
you don't want to come
but that would be a really big help in
coordinating these little sidings it
would also give the opportunity for a
bigger part of the community to be aware
of where they're and where they are and
put them in their schedule when they're
laying out the schedule for attend unum
and planning out that our ITF week
couldn't agree more
from for me personally captain Kathleen
Moriarty I just a quick suggestion is to
go through the appeal or or a question
how do you considered just reissuing the
ballot on the conflict review since so
much research and discussion has
happened it should be quite
straightforward and it would be an easy
way to brown that out so I don't really
want to speak to the details of it
because it's in terrassa
thank you hi so this week we had the in
a and RW I get the right order of the
letters I was the author of C that I
think it was a great way to mix the in
to open the ITF community to the
research community so I think having
this workshop during the week was a good
thing
the other thing I'd like to mention is
that the IMS a set up a recycled badge
here which guess what it's here to
recycle the badges so I would like us
that we try to feel this being and not
being the only one to take my bat there
so on Friday morning put your badge in
this bin
thank you thank you Friday afternoon cuz
you're all gonna stay for the whole day
right yes okay no more questions for us
so I'll invite the IOC to come on up
thank you
I'll invite the IOC to introduce
themselves starting with Kathy Kathy
Brown the Internet Society blue burger
and I'm come upon it
Portia when Stanley interim IAT covered
I swear I use ELISA cooperate if chair
LC set her dia me Jim
John Levine I saw a pointed IAO see
Andrew Sullivan non-call appointed we
have one question I love this Mike bear
in mind I've only been IOC chair for
about forty or forty hours or so so go
easy on me are you against recycling
these badges Mike right after everybody
clapped we will make know that I do not
know why they got smaller and I until
you mentioned I had not noticed
cuz I guess it's too small yes well well
first of all my condolences I agree this
you know one things I've loved about
this venue is the huge amount of open
seating for us to sit down and talk to
each other so our hotel bar was here I
believe the hours of Montreal III a.m.
[Music]
trying to be organized you know our
meetings for the more expensive
beginning of the year are easier to come
by might be something to consider and
see and super spy that's a very good
point
something we have observed internally as
well so we have discussed experimenting
with switching to a slightly different
rotational remaking Asia as the March
meeting right now we have booked out
through 2021
most of the venues or in negotiation
with venues already but past that date
we're looking at doing that exactly
experiment your suggested yes Bob just
also respond to that so that's a very
one region view of it if you live in
Asia that's absolutely true
as I say if we do it will be an
experiment we'll see how it goes
we've tried this way for a couple years
and as you note if you look at ahead in
the schedule while we do try to have
tried to keep to the schedule of you
know North American March Europe in the
summer in Asia in the fall we don't
always do it even now we do mix them up
the fact that we're here in the
summertime and not in Europe right now
is a bit of a change for us so like I
said we're considering the experiment
we're gonna look at it the big thing
that really influences our choice and
our ability to meet at a particular
location is availability of meeting
venues that we can go to one of the
challenges we have faced in Asia is the
availability of venues that meet the
IETF requirements in November and so one
of the reasons my other motivations were
doing is little to see if that we start
going to Asia as an experiment in March
if that opens up new venues that we
can't access currently because they're
already booked many years out in advance
by other groups going once going twice
gone Glen before you go I might mention
that if the schedule for the animals if
the schedule for the LLC goes more or
less as proposed this may well be the
last time we see this is may well be the
last time you ever see the IAO see seem
to be the shortest serving I am see
chair ever thanks everyone
enjoy your evening
you