yeah thanks ok let's go ahead and get
started
this is quick if you're not here for
quick you're in the wrong room if we
could ask the folks coming in to close
the doors that would be helpful thank
you so this is quick we have one session
in this meeting
Lara's my co-chair wasn't able to make
it to this IETF so he's going to be
joining us remotely I'm flying solo also
our area director Spencer his remote as
you can see we have a lot of other
remote people as well on on media echo
so please keep that in mind when you're
at the mics speak clearly state your
name let's not have side conversations
and let's make sure that they can
productively participate this is the
note well hopefully by this part of the
week you're familiar with this these are
the terms under which you participate in
the ITF or a summary thereof really
regarding intellectual property
regarding your behavior and how you
treat other people and and copyright and
lots of other things so if you're not
familiar with these please do a search
for IETF note well on your favorite web
search engine and you'll be able to find
this document and understand what you
commit to when you participate in this
process so Joe has very kindly offered
to scribe many many thanks for that
heroic Duty you're performing the blue
sheets are on the sides if we can start
circulating those and once they get to
the back if you could please send them
to the center so those folks get a
chance to sign in as well that'd be
great our agenda today is pretty tight
I'm gonna try and keep things snappy
we're gonna have some updates from the
base draft editors we're gonna touch
base with the operational draft editors
we're gonna discuss some of the issues
on the base drafts excuse me and talk
then talk about the foreseeable future
what we plan for the next steps with
we're
can group what our status is what how we
think we're gonna finish this work and
then if we have time we have a
last-minute addition to the agenda which
is an update on the spin network from
Marcus any bashing of the agenda okay
so first up we have a quick update from
Martin all attempt to get your slides up
come on you can do it no no okay that
works yes apparently we have sixteen by
nine so next I don't make this really
quick so this is basically the things
that have changed in the last yeah it
was an anchor and no longer so probably
the biggest change that has happened
recently is the stream zero special
crypto thing has turned even more
special and now longer consume stream
means gonna go into details about that
in a little bit so we'll move on next it
looks like a lots changed in 13 and
that's because a lot has we added
support for ecn thanks Magnus for all of
the extra work that was put into that
one with my changes to connection ID
handling that's not the end of that
we're discovering now that connection
IDs are interesting and complex and new
ground and breaking that new ground has
turned out to be a little bit painful
Mike's got some more on that later on we
added the ability for service to
advertise the preferred address on which
they would like the connection to
migrate to we made stateless reset
symmetric
and we now actually can extend quick in
various ways specifically new frames in
this case there's a bunch of changes to
HTTP queue pack I think we're up to Oh -
on cue go one on cue pack which means
that there's we're still a little bit
early on that one and so that's that's
had a lot of churn next place so when I
wrote this which was last week we had
about a hundred open issues we still
have basically 100 open issues we've
been killing them pretty quickly but
they've been popping up just as quickly
this is a considerable improvement over
where we were six months ago mainly
because we've gone through and labeled
about half of these as part or version
two and for those people are not
familiar with the way we're dealing with
this with identified a bunch of issues
that we're not going to solve now and
those are still open in the in the issue
tracker but they're labeled with a quick
v2 label it basically means yes we think
this is important but it's not important
for us to solve right now a bunch of
other issues are labeled part and those
weren't thanks those ones we're sort of
committing to come back to them later
and that might be because it's to spend
it and we haven't finished our work on
that or it's because we need more
information or because we just can't
solve the problem right now for various
reasons of those remaining which by
various measures we have somewhere
between 30 and 50 issues my assessment
of these and I think the other editors
are in agreement on this is that they're
pretty close to done and the main reason
that they're not done is because it
takes work and if anyone can help us out
with any of this that would be greatly
appreciated and so we're going to be
looked looking to assign work to people
over the next little while but from my
perspective the end is in sight
yeah and it's just a matter of sitting
down and typing some of these will
require some discussion in the working
group to reach conclusions some of them
the conclusions at least to me seem
fairly obvious but we'll discover
interesting surprises along the way
but they're relatively minor for the
most part and so I expect that we'll be
able to have something fairly concretely
complete by the next time we meet here
at one of these plenary meetings so the
end is in sight that is the light at the
end of the tunnel thanks Martin this is
my nightmare every night that is the
light at the end of the tunnel so you
got any questions for Martin about the
status of the drafts or the recent
changes let's not get in the issue
discussion just any questions about this
subject matter all right yeah he's gonna
talk about stream zero we might have
some more details about that yeah okay
thanks so next up on the agenda is Ian
talking about stream zero while we get
ready for that I skipped something I
apologize John was gonna do a very quick
update of what happened on the weekend
with a hackathon just wanna use this mic
Brooke quick maybe Jenna and God very
quickly
we had a hackathon we had a number of
people show up and participate some
remotely implementers there were some
people working on draft 13 but many were
still working on draft 12 I heard some
mumbling about trying to get packet
number encryption right here and there
and people also seemed to be working on
that so I think it would be nice to
actually move forward to stream 32 to
draft 13 draft that you know is a big
big shift from what we've done in the
past draft 12 already includes back
another encryption not everybody's
gotten there yet but hopefully
by the next interim people will be on to
13 and working on stream zero issues
instead of being stuck on things before
12 okay so what they all add here is if
you go to the github
I believe kazoo has produced a PR that
has a NOC kazuo kakazu as bridge to PR
that has a example client hello with a
simple message as soon as a client hello
with a P any and so that you may find to
be a useful structure for figuring out
why your Pina doesn't work um I'll try
to I'll try to get mink to dump chip to
make one and dump out all intermediate
points like their crappy version
Martin's draft because like that does
like it's very it's very hopeful to like
have that kind of stuff that's the one
case where like basically you can just
ingest the message with no state at all
and like running and we produce the
exactly the crypto everybody else adds
so um that may help people get PID
workings peony I know is it all tricking
people okay thanks I'm just hoping one
last thing that if people as they're
implementing peony can can can find out
the the symbol got just that they got
stuck on be useful to add them into the
drug so please keep note on that okay
that's about it thanks Jenna just just
for folks who are new to this or haven't
been following closely we have a very
active group of implementers I think we
have what on the order of 10 ish
implementations right now we've been
meeting before in the hackathon before
the main IETF meetings as well as
adjacent to our interim meetings and
they use a slack group to communicate if
you're interested in all of that please
get in touch with me or Lars or or any
of the editors and we can introduce to
that effort so in string 0 alright so
I'm gonna do a summary mostly what we
talked about in in Shuster so if you
were there then it's pretty much just a
rehash I am gonna go fairly fast just to
because most these issues are fairly
decided but I want to kind of go over
them because Martin in particular is
going to talk about so in the later next
slide so this is literally a still kind
of a copy-paste of sorts from London
these are from accrue slides about the
various issues with the the stream 0
design at the time
so next slide Rock'em actually these are
mostly for reference as a background
TLS over TCP you have TLS messages on
TLS records and those may or may not
line up with TCP segments so TLS record
can span multiple segments or it can
line up or you know there could be
multiple TLS records within a segment
that's sort of sorted that architectural
model in the next slide in the draft 12
which is prior to the stream zero
changes this is sort of the quick stack
as you can see it's a little more
complicated
you have TLS messages that are on TLS
records that are inside quick frames
that are inside quick packets which
themselves have kind of a record layer
as we'll talk about in a moment
inside datagrams so you know at the very
least it's probably one expert level of
indirection here next slide
so draft 13 the design the otherwise
known is the quick record layer design
kind of squashes this down by one layer
and it makes it so the TLS messages are
in quick frames which are then in quick
packets which is sort of the like crypto
record layer for the transport and this
was already like very much have one hour
to TN 0 rgz worked anyway so one or two
T and 0 RTG there was no TLS record
layer involved unlike TLS or TCP so in
some sense this is like a unification of
the design we already had where before
it was kind of half in one world in half
in another next slide we had a new
crypto handshake frame so instead of
actually putting it over stream zero
there's a special frame it removes a few
features like you can't fin it because
you never really wanted to be able to
fin a crypto stream there's no SKU ID
because that doesn't make any sense
and each encryption level restarts at
offset zero to avoid any ambiguity about
like what happens if the start offset of
like the next encryption level is before
the end offset of the previous
encryption level and like various other
weird things
is not a stream frame so therefore it is
not flow controlled by default we
discussed that briefly and she said and
decided that the effort to flow control
it was more effort than it was worth and
if we did want to do that that would
potentially be a TLS working group item
next slide so the the Newport has clear
rules about where every handshake
message is sent there's no double
encryption quick doesn't really need to
know anything but the TLS handshake just
basically Keys get exported it and Kayla
says like send this and that this
encryption level and vice versa quick
passes messages and data back to TLS and
says this was received at this
encryption level yeah no double
encryption and you also get built-in
path validation so before before we
actually had path challenge and path
response and they were allowed during
the handshake because we didn't have a
good way of actually making sure that
the peer is on path but now the receipt
of anything at the second encryption
level well technically the third uvaca
can tell us but of handshake encryption
actually proves that you're on path so
in practice you don't need a separate on
path validation next slide so where the
costs it basically requires a new API
for TLS that's that's probably the
largest cost at least that we're aware
of
obviously regards a few changes of the
quick traps as well but at this point
there are already some implementations
available and at least that the
interrupt thing is actually a little bit
okay I think there might be three people
who have interrupts now but I'm not sure
so next slide huh the code was three or
four he thinks from echo three or four
so another change we made at the same
time there were some issues around not
having separate packet number spaces in
particular there was an issue that
Christian identified the long time ago
where by spoofing at I'm an unencrypted
packet you could essentially create a
hole and the peers
Paquette scream and then they would
never be able to recover from it for the
rest of the connection and that hole
would actually be in the encrypted
portion of the packet number space non
the unencrypted portion kind of the
details are on issue thousand 18 but the
the critical thing that needs to happen
is when you get an acknowledgment you
need to know whether that packet you
know what encryption level that packet
was at that this is being a so you need
some unambiguous way of knowing you know
this peer is acknowledging five and it
was at this encryption level the other
issue that was open is that
acknowledgement of packets at one level
could actually at least in the current
loss recovery dock at the time caused
spurious retransmissions of packets a
different encryption level so you could
you know receive a initially encrypted
packet and that could come after say
zero RTT maybe you can't process here
are 2t suddenly you acknowledge the
initially encrypted packet and fast
retransmit kicks in and says like oh
this peer must uh it must have lost all
the 0 T and you retransmit it anyway
even though the real problem is you just
couldn't decrypt it and so therefore you
couldn't acknowledge it next bug so the
design for separate record number spaces
is basically using an acknowledgment or
an AK frame in the packet number space
you want to acknowledge so there's no
special Act frame or a new akram it's
just you know act frames in initial
acknowledging initial packets actually
Amsden handshake in knowledge handshake
packets
you can't send out frames in 0 to C
because there's no point and one RTG at
frames obviously acknowledge but
actually they acknowledge about 0 to DN
1 or T packets so next slide so it's all
the the issues we identified it
clarifies exactly what level you should
be sending your acknowledgment set
before there is some very weird wording
and kind of confusing wording about like
you should always try to send it the
acknowledgment at the highest possible
level but you could actually end up in a
situation where you could acknowledge a
packet
but the peer couldn't actually see your
acknowledgement if you sent it for
example with one arty tikis because even
though you received a one or two t
packet does not actually mean that the
handshake is completed for example on
the server set to you know the head of
line blocking of the of the C's earth
thus you can so it also makes the rules
quite simple so the rules for recovery
for all the different packet spaces are
pretty much identical there's no like
special cases like if this is at this
encryption level do this and so on and
so forth and yeah I removed some
temptation to do some some relatively
stupid optimizations that we came up in
the meantime with and the more we went
through them the more we realized they
were they were foot guns that would get
you in a heap blow Dro yeah so next
slide so the big cost is basically due
to structure cost in tracking cost so I
think the logic is fairly
straightforward but the you do need at
least temporarily to potentially keep
around multiple kind of AK frame data
structures you may need to keep around
multiple flights and packets data
structures and the other cost is you're
gonna end up with more of what we call
coalesced packets previously referred to
as compound packets where you have two
quick packets in one UDP Datagram so
excellent ah so transport retry so this
wasn't really in the original list or
this kind of got baked into the original
list of comments about issues with
stream 0 but in this process it also
became clear that there is a desire to
have a non TLS kind of retry stateless
reset mechanism that's much more similar
to like TCP syn cookies and you know
this is mainly for DDoS reasons so the
idea that it really should be a really
easy way to do proof of source address
that doesn't involve like consulting
your tos doc or doing anything complex
and then some cases people actually
wanted to put these on separate boxes
from the main main host
but there's also the issue that the
current retried that we had before
complicates TLS interaction
there were some fairly like confusing
rules about whether you had to send an
HR are in a retry packet or not and in
general no one really see if we're happy
with the stay of the world so the big
goal is to move retraining to the
transport and that is largely worked out
well but there are a variety of G's
health issues that we kind of didn't
fully think through when we first wrote
up the text so next slide but I'll go
over them that the design here so the
retry is not encrypted at all so it's
just plain text it's a long header
packet it actually repeats the
destination connection ID that was in
the clients initial and the reason for
that is to do proof that is on basically
and then it has token content and so the
server sends me a read/write has a token
in it I put that token in the next
initial that I send back to the server
and then in theory this token is proof
that you know I am on path and I am the
IP that I say yeah and as you can see
the initial has the Chokin content kind
of where at the beginning right after
the long header so yes and the other
issues that this this token is actually
also used for zero RTG so there's a new
token frame inside the encrypted
envelope that allows you to refresh your
token once you're forward secure and of
course you must not mix these tokens so
you know tokens that are are used in the
handshake and they're used for basically
DDoS prevention you know must want to
not be used later for 0td next slide I
kind of went over these before but retry
minimizes CP usage on the server side
when when under DDoS and other attacks
situations and it definitely simplifies
the interaction for for the stateless
reject use case so oh yeah and there's
no packet type and pigua TiVoed like
where you put things next slide
all right so these are the issues that
are currently open an additional
description there were a lot of things
that were intended to
written down and just word not written
down quite right so draft 13 just has a
bunch of little errors that thankfully
Merton mostly fixed at this point and
and did a nice job of but then there are
a few other issues and at this point I'm
as well just like that's next not quite
not quite
okay bit later yeah well coming soon
just slides near you
all right that's it thank you in any
questions about the stream zero
transition I've heard a few from folks
about how this might affect our schedule
we'll talk about that a little later in
the session but anything else okay
thanks Ian next up can figure this thing
out we have I believe Brian if you can
make your way up talking about the
operational drafts hi I'm Brian for
those who haven't already asked I have
said skiing accident yeah here to talk
about two drafts ITF quick manageability
and ITF quick applicability um it does
work
operations drafts does anybody remember
these we actually forgot about them for
a while
and we're the editors the point of these
is to provide advice to application
developers and mapping designers on
using quick write so we are chartered in
this working group to work on one
application wrapping two HTTP with htv-2
like semantics this is however a general
first transport protocol so we'd like to
have sort of either template information
or other considerations that you have to
have when you're mapping something other
than hbt you onto quick um and then we
wouldn't have another document which is
advise to application and network
administrator's network management tool
designers on what deploying quic is
going to mean for management tasks that
they you know commonly do so the idea is
to say sort of a users guide to the
quick wire image for people who are only
looking at the wire image so they don't
have to go into the 2d protocol itself
so this is really the fifth focus area
in the working group Charter um
applicability we updated at this time we
made basically no changes because there
had been no text added to it since the
last time we just revved it to keep it
from a core - unexpired we'll talk a
little bit about the scope of this
document because I'm not sure we have it
quite right like so originally we had
one document which was applicability
manageability we decided to split those
in part because one looked like it was
going to be done way earlier than the
other one just you know with respect to
the amount of discussion we needed to do
we haven't changed as much but there's
been like no controversy so there's been
no attention right like so it's like ok
great um well we'll take a look at the
open issues and and talk about how we
might want to scope if we want to
restock this in a couple of minutes in
the meantime we've done some thinking
about manageability um
the flux in the wire image so as we've
been developing the protocol basically
trying to track changes in the headers
was completely pointless so we just
didn't do it it looks now especially
after CID PNE and some of the stream 0
interactions with the wire image the
retry stuff that's all settling down now
so it's time to basically write it up
and we did some of that for this time
but will need to do at least one more
rev on that so the changes in 0 1 we
updated to the rev 13 headers we added
coalesced packets we fixed see IDs we
encrypted the packet number this
actually allowed us to delete a lot of
text because we were talking about what
the packet number might be used for and
it turns out now it can be used for
absolutely nothing we mention sni for
application identification so when sni
gets encrypted
may have to tear that back out too we
point to the experiment for on this thin
bit for potential RTT measurement and
also point out that you can do initial
RCT based on the handshake so those
dynamics have not changed like all of
the names the packets have change but
but at that point hasn't changed there's
a little bit more work to do on load
balancing and usage of the connection
IDs but it's our opinion as editors that
this document at that point is mostly
done right like so the the the protocol
has a relatively minimalistic wire image
so the users guide to the wire image is
here so you can do with it not much
that's by design right we there may be
some commentary that comes into that
where we you know talk about why not
much but in terms of the technical
content this is pretty close to done we
looked at the open issues and pretty
much all look like originally I said
okay well and classify these by
applicability and manageability and the
manageability list in terms of open
issues on manageability that we need to
actually talk about is empty um
classifying the open issue is the
applicability draft we have sort of
three classes of these one is endpoint
implementation issues an endpoint API
issue so this is a little bit less about
writing bindings and more about what
sort of interface the the transport
protocol should give to the layer above
great so we originally envisioned this
as a document or a be like a binding
writers guide and it turns out that we
almost that the a lot of these issues
came from discussions on the base drafts
and they were sort of shunted over to
the ops drafts and it looks like there
might be from these issues some demand
for some sort of abstract interface
document whether that goes in the
applicability or abstract interface
specification where that goes in the
applicability document or has its own
document is something that we should
talk about there's a second class of
these which are sort of additional
endpoint behaviors these are you know
pointing out things that you could do
right like so there's a do we want to
talk about the fact that you can use
streams and stream resets to give you an
emulation of partial reliability do we
want to talk about multiplexing over
like some multiplexing multiple sets of
streams oversee IDs on the seam on
5-tuple talk about trade-offs in whether
or not you do keep a lives or decide
that you're going to do RT t r 0 RT t
presumption when you have an NAT state
drop and then the third of these are
sort of operational guidelines for
serving quick so this I put a question
mark on applicability here because
they're currently filed is probably on
applicability and they were in the
original scope of applicability but it
also seems like you know yeah right so
if there's there's a scoping question
for the open issues that we know belong
on applicability we marry and I we can
suggest text but we might not be the
best potential authors for some of these
like so some of this is like version
roll out and roll back in large clusters
and migrating Google quick to quick
right so people who have experience for
that I'm not looking anybody in
particular might have um you know better
input than we have on that if you want
to if you look at one of these issues
and would like to assign yourself to it
that's graciously accepted PRS are also
graciously accepted I wanted to have a
bit of a talk now on um document
organization audience especially on
applicability cuz right now we're
talking to implementers we're talking to
sort of clients at the application layer
and we're talking to deployers with that
document right now and it might be that
that's too much and we might want to
split this out into a third document um
we might want if we're doing too much we
might want to push them all back into
one document right I mean there's since
we're picking this work back up now and
hope you know that manageability should
basically be done in the in the Bangkok
timeframe is my my optimistic hope if we
stopped changing the wire image
obviously
and then applicability is done as soon
as we get text on but since we're gonna
spin that work up we should talk about
the organization now I think okay
Chennai and God so I think when we
talked about the applicability document
a while ago the application layer users
and deployers were sort of important and
cold parts of this what for implementers
are you doing in the document I don't
see anything in there that I think of as
these fundamentals really so a little
bit kind of CID generation port number
use right like so so not necessarily
like directly implementation level stuff
there was actually a discussion about
how to handle ICMP quoting which got
pushed over to the ops drafts and then
got picked back up in the base drafts
because that's actually where it
belonged but there's still some stub
stuff about like so handling ICMP what
your error interface should look like so
these I think are things that are really
talking to - to implementers also
there's touches really the mere could
have been this touches a point about the
the interface discussion because the
interface needs to be implemented by the
implementers and then used by the
application right so and it currently
the document gives hint about where an
interface should be but maybe what want
to say more than that yeah I think the I
personally think the transport interface
that you that you were talking about
earlier is an important piece of this I
think it's something that we should
really try to get down I think that's
probably to me the most important piece
of this one and then the users the
questions on 0 RTP how do you deploy
this those are important but not as
important as the do you have an
organization opinion do we put all of
this into applicability or do we take
the interface stuff really it's a it's a
it's almost a disjoint audience as far
as yeah it's tempting to think of it as
a separate document
when I look at these issues and I was
trying to classify them that really was
the feel but I got I'm not trying to
like load the question but I'm
interested in other opinions so the way
I think about this is if it's if it's
valuable to as you start writing it out
if it starts becoming too big the
document that's usually something I
think ok yep because I don't know how
big it's gonna get yeah so gory
Fairhurst
and I think the there's a very different
audience between people wanted to know
an API and use this to those who are
trying to run operational Network and
want to know how its behaving and what
packets are important for them the
details probably not in your list the
details in how you write it
right so we should be careful as we
write it that we've picked the audience
because experience that the ITF is
people if you direct it in the wrong way
that group of people won't read it so I
think there are two different groups of
people who you could write the text for
okay so that's the that's the split
between applicability and manageability
right yeah okay tell me Polly Apple I
would just like to read area which what
I think you and John I've been saying of
the actual abstract interface feels like
it should be a different document that
can certainly reference this so I think
this should describe all of the bits
that are required to give a more
normative claim about what an abstract
interface should be but that should be
left for a separate exercise which I
think we should also do soon and start
working on is that um volunteering to
edit yes okay cool Thanks we talked to
Lars about that a bit more I guess now
that we're having a chat at the table
we're chartered right now to deliver
these documents at the same time as that
the base protocol it occurs to me that a
lot of the folks who could contribute to
this work right now heads down on that
work would it be beneficial do you think
- maybe just delay these documents
publication by not work on them but
publication by even just a month or two
so you can get a little more their free
time we'd see one
I would suggest basically like one um
interim cycle right like so a half
meeting cycle is probably enough really
there's one and a half months right well
we're gonna we're gonna talk later about
yes
yeah yeah so x plus x plus one half
cycle I think is good but these
documents weren't to ship at exactly the
same time as the bass traps that's fine
okay yeah uh hardy let me just make sure
I understand what what you're proposing
before I come in because there's a
little hard for me to hear mark what I
hear heard you say was you were
proposing that publication of these
drafts might be later than the
publication of the protocol that's is
that correct I was asking if that would
cause pain I wasn't proposing I think it
might cause pain speaking personally I'm
particularly concerned about some of the
operational guidelines aspects coming
later than protocol documents in
particular because we're putting the
protocol documents out once we've got
significant interoperability testing
under our belt I'm concerned that people
will then almost immediately start using
these in fact some people are already
starting to use these and that those
guidelines might be useful earlier
rather than later
I think the trade-off is just the
quality of the documents could be
significantly better I think the way I
agree but there are some core pieces to
both of them and I think it would be
very valuable to have come out as close
as possible so perhaps some more
discussion on a list of which pieces
might get more attention so that we can
get those out early might be useful
Mia Cuban and
I agree I think they should be punished
at the same point of time but for me
publication is like when the editing
phases is finished and we actually have
the RFC published right and I think that
can be aligned like even if you send it
to publication for the is II is she at
different times and so on we came then
at the end like wait until we published
II hope I don't want to get too deep
into the planning of this I just wanted
to see if there was a amenability
obviously we need to talk and think
about a bit more yeah okay
well so I'm gonna I'm gonna put people
on the spot a little bit um show of
hands who here sees one of these open
issues that they believe they could help
with that's not committing
I'll close my eyes okay
yeah so yeah a few that well okay good
all right so we'll basically follow up
on the list with with the heavy guilt
I guess all right excellent thanks
there's stairs over there right oh yes
that ends yes thank you
thanks Brendan okay so next up we're
gonna go into if I can figure out this
thing discussion of open issues on the
base drafts the editors have selected
six different topics of areas they have
questions for working group and in
clusters of issues we're gonna go
through those we want to leave some time
as we mentioned before for planning and
then future looking kind of planning at
the end of the session we also have the
presentation on this bin bit so I'd ask
we not let any of these sessions get
much more than 15 minutes long if we do
that we should be okay first up Martin
we've got retrying sorry yes mark yes
ELISA gender best a little bit we have a
pattern of like spending of like
discussing for 15 minutes then deciding
oh well now we're like me on the next
thing to close some of these issues
rather than just like you like oh like
like we spent like like 500 message the
mail and retry so like I'd like to get
retried done rather than what I don't
care like if I don't get to like you
know I don't know what connect ID like
management like that's sad but I'm not
sure I get retried done think every
trying fashion as each quarter done so
Martin Jonna from Year's Day you know I
think we should do this one first then
connection are these in priority order
that this there is completely random no
that is random its retry than managing
keys then stateless reset connection ID
is HTTP and recovery okay let's do that
is that a good order list we stick
and that's as I understand it a summary
for the HTTP working group not a
decision-making so specially my Mike
points out there there's a couple of
issues that he wants to talk about so
yeah there's this is separate yeah yeah
we want to solve some problems okay so
let's get started
yep smells good let's not talk about
talking so oh yeah I mean I made slides
sorry do you yeah we go I'm just gonna
get straight into this one okay so we
have a retry so that we can do this so
this kind of address validation stuff
that Anne was talking about before token
based it's pretty simple however we
identified a whole bunch of issues
around this so this in spoofing problems
we've talked about for a long time the
format was you know
looping 0rt to interactions and how you
do coalescing so let's talk through this
so the summary and talked about this
supply sense an initial the server sense
of retry it's got a token in it close
puts that token in its next initial and
we continue along with the pattern
interesting point here is because the
server chooses the connection idea that
the client uses the connection ID from
the retry packet is in the subsequent
initial packets a property that was a
little surprising as a result out of the
of the stream zero design teamwork was
that retry can be sent multiple times so
there was a number of deployment
scenarios where it was necessary to do
this and so we can have a number of
round trips going back and forth with
initials and retries and initials and
rate rise anyway you're not actually
making any progress but you're just
going back and forth I thought Colin
Perkins are someone who hasn't been
deeply involved what's more surprising
is the initial can be sent more than
once
II in fact you can send initial under
and under also
conditions and it's crazy it's very
confusing name I'm sure we can paint
that bike shed any color you like but
that's not important okay so first issue
was that the format was complete mess in
13 at the top there is a little picture
of the octet that we have in the in in
the format in 13 but there was an
observation that it is basically
impossible to decrypt and decode one of
these messages because of the way that
the packet number is encrypted and of
arbitrary length people have pointed out
it's a bit of a problem we did this
because we wanted to have some
consistency consistency between the long
header format and the short header
format and we just missed the fact that
we dropped some of this information into
the wrong place also the point that
retry apparently included a packet
number which is apparently encrypted but
we don't actually know how and so
there's a proposal out there that's got
a lot of positive feedback and we simply
just reorder the the packet around and
we don't include a Packer number in the
retry message the consequence of that is
that we can't coalesce retry with
anything else but then we don't actually
have any need to do that as far as I'm
aware so I wouldn't suggest we're not
worried about doing that now is your
opportunity to tell me that I'm crazy
and this is a bad idea
because I haven't merged the pull
request yet but I fully intend to
because we got a backlog of things
behind this change right salt and next
so because we have this multiple retry
packet interaction there's actually no
reliable way at the client to
distinguish a retry in response to their
first initial or the second one and
there's an interesting problem here if
you retransmit your initial as you might
have to do you can get multiple retries
coming back and ultimately with varying
delays on the networking and get retries
from the
initial mixed up with retries from the
second initial and you don't know which
one is which
particularly when connection IDs aren't
actually changed at the server end so
the suggestion is that if the server
doesn't intend to proceed with that with
a handshake or it might not proceed with
the handshake after this initial it has
to provide a new connection ID there
must be different to the one that it's
received and it's got to be a certain
size I mean this relatively
straightforward just gin up another
random number and shove it in there
that's not particularly difficult for a
server to do and there's no reason for
it not to do that but this means that
every single retry that you receive will
have a unique value for this original
destination connection ID that you see
as a result you can identify which
initial it is responding to guaranteed
as opposed to maybe in the past and so
in the case where you have a packet
that's retransmitted from the client
that arrives after the client has sent
another initial you can distinguish
between the one that's just echoes from
the past and the one that's actually a
response to your your currently
outstanding initial on this on this
connection so that fix is also in that
PR so we're moving on feel free to go if
you if you disagree with anything here
so spoofing it's relatively
straightforward to spoof or retry if you
see an initial basically all we have
there is the randomized destination
connection ID that's in the initial
packet if the attacker can see that
value then it can generate an retry
there's no other proof from the server
end that it's seen the packet there's no
encryption on this there's nothing
nothing fancy like that
this can cause connection failures
particularly if an attacker decides to
spoof these things and they can
successfully do so multiple
the clients eventually going to say this
server is sending me infinite retries
I'm going to give up and kazuo had
identified an interesting one where you
send a you can have the the attacker
effectively spoof or retry and propose a
different connection ID if they strip
the token from the the subsequent
message if they're able to strip the
token from the subsequent message then
because they're man-in-the-middle
ultimately what the real server will see
is something that looks like a real
initial but it's actually got the
attackers choice of connection ID in it
not sure what you're going to do with
that but that's just what it is
johner on the previous slide if you
could avi over here saying that the
server infrastructure has to basically
provide unique original destination
connection IDs across all devices for
this particular set of retrace no no so
the destination connection idea that the
clients ultimately can use is they the
one that is randomly generated for
itself or it's one that the server
randomly generates for it and really the
only requirement here is that the the
values are unique across the this
particular one this one particular
exchange there's no there's no
requirement for them to be globally
unique or anything crazy like that of
course they're really big random numbers
chances are they're gonna be unique
anyways so that's out of Quigley unique
it's adequately unique yes yeah no is
this one even if it's yes that that's
that's fine with me I wouldn't even
bother checking for collisions I just
chin up a new random number and move on
yeah that's that's probably the best
recommendation yeah
thanks Kyle nekritz if we are allowing
this kind of spoofing does this make
retry part of the invariance
it's none of the invariants we're
promising but maybe it's one of those
things that we were not actively
clamping down on yeah so if you if you
think about the way that we've done
invariance is that we've made there's
there's a wire image the quick version
one has and that that wire image has a
certain set of properties some of which
were actually guaranteeing that will
maintain across individual version two
this is not one that we're going to make
that promise for no it's not an
invariant stuff it doesn't need to be
the the the main reason we have
invariance is so that we can maybe one
day ship version two so if we if we're
allowing anyone on the path to send a
retry it may very easily become an
invariant yes ossification is a real
thing yeah yeah so I mean I'm starting
to think that we went off the rails when
we decided that the the OD CID was the
was the thing that proved that I was in
the corner correlated the request the
response um and we did that I think
people were sad about scrape scraping
pieces of the of the sonication tag but
like you know this is a lot like
mechanics here going on trying to like
basically substitute the CID for a
random challenge value and like we
already have a random challenge but we
already have a random value of the
packet which is like the crap at the end
which we already agreed is like a random
value because we're using it all over
the place or the crap after the end or
whatever like I mean there's just like a
lot of stuff here that like you could we
could work with and I mean or for a
matter you could use the you could use
the ciphered PN from the form that was
also now random right so I guess I'm
just late like making a lot of rules
about I just like starting getting very
sad about killers well with the CID when
like actually we have other entropy in
apakah we be exploiting and all weird
which I use roundtrip
so we discussed this on the issue and I
know you you raised this point and for a
couple of people having to remember the
output of the
encryption was difficult I appreciate
that
but I think this is lame so um you know
I I guess my point is like I don't think
I don't miss it if I think it's an
argument yes yes and I know too I think
that your argument is particularly
convincing on that front either I think
it's it's just it's it's a choice women
well I mean I think you've like we now
like a bunch of like a bunch of the new
complexity about how these generated
this huge in terminal a non-terminal
on then that'd be much easier than do
would be to like always if you're if
you're a server which like quite you
want a shiny at all like generate no
connection IDs um very neat bouncing
around a lot it just like there's a lot
of new additional complexity in the
protocol to handle like this case which
would be held on their ways so I'm not
sure that I agree with that assist okay
well so a server that wants to do this
every time they send a retry they send a
randomized connection ID that's all they
have to do there's there's no additional
complexity on that front um I you're
assuming that people know where their
terminal terminal
no even even the terminal one can know
has a terminal warm what's an empty CID
because it doesn't need it doesn't want
waste space in the packet and so now you
have to know that's apology that was an
initial packet they're always gonna be
the same size no no it doesn't want
business in subsequent packets
yes but the server gets to change the
connection ID with the it's its initial
that's the final determination of the
connection ID this is only only for the
for the subsequent initials that it's
gonna fit yeah again this is just comedy
weekly screwing crashing ID like that's
you more like why don't we just
say setup properly in the firt the first
time the server responds okay and
I guess like um like I'm not sure where
to go from here but like the I want to
hear from someone else yes sir yeah I
mean if you know the only one who thinks
this is a problem then what so far
you're the mean for cypher proposing
this so I don't really think we're like
you know this is what we got right this
is what is gonna tell us about something
else you know I mean I think it's sort
of related to this but like basically
right now we have this rule where you
once you've bound to the destination
connection idea I assume the D 1 D 2 T 3
are different destination connection of
these right so it's like once you're
bound to the destination connection the
server a server initial case you stick
without connection area even if the
server responds with retransmissions or
different connection amenities or
coalesced packets or different
connection ladies
I wonder why is why we made the
different decision to do a retries are
special and they're allowed to change
the connection a T because if we bind to
the original connection ID with retry
then this wouldn't be a problem at all
or mitigated at least so it's a you get
one retry which decides your connection
ID but you can do multiple retries and
that's for the spoofing case so there
was one reason we actually there's an
explicit reason we allowed from multiple
retries was was that you know had the
hollow retry request a model of retry
was actually subject to the same like a
worse attack that if you could do only
one other request because TLS enforces
that on you and so of like two questions
I guess no those are two questions one
was that like why don't we just buy into
the connection ID at the first one and
the second one was if you're gonna open
new old issues that we've already
irrigated at some length I think we
probably need a little bit bit more
warning for that one and I'd suggest
taking that to the list okay because we
have talked about that in sweat Google I
I think this is this is fine and I think
we discussed this at length as a
proposal I don't have a particular
objection to
his approach in in practice because I do
realize that this is only for initial
packet so as long as it's I only have to
repeat like eight or sixteen bytes
saving whatever magic eater sixteen
bytes of the initial is like a special
case and I can just throw that into a
buffer so I don't I don't really have a
strong opinion I do understand
Acker is kind of situation where you
you're forced to change the connection
ID so in our case I think we probably
will never actually use multiple Rita's
in our deployment at least I don't
expect to in the near future so this is
sort of like a non-issue from an
operational perspective but
aesthetically it's like I can get a
little ugly hey I kind of agree so but I
don't really have a strong opinion so
but it'd be fine it's not causing me any
pain we've got Tommy and Martin and then
we'll get into the remote kill Tommy
Polly Apple I agree very much with Ian
that I can kind of live either way this
is a little bit convoluted seeming just
seems like a perfectly reasonable way of
solve it Edgar's proposal also would be
fine the point I wanted to make was that
as I had I think I gave you feedback
during the hackathon I think we need
reworking of connection ID text in
general and what would help a lot for
this is if we just had a more clear
section explaining the best practices
around connection ID in the overall
philosophy for it that would help
because I think the disagreement I see
here is kind of around what is this
connection ID about when should we be
generating them and if we have more of
an introduction to that it may help come
into this convolution a little bit more
clearly yeah we've heard that and the
editors plan to do I think the
requirement for that section even more
yeah I think that that doesn't really
engage with the the core question that I
could echo was doing I mean we can
explain better but ultimately the
concern there is that we're offloading
this in ways that it may be not ideal
that isn't all miss you in the
applicability document I mean we can
discuss if it belongs here but whatever
the applicability document says the the
transport document has to be coherent on
connection IDs and currently it's
not ideal so we plan to fix that I'm
fine little person like please pick up
I'm fine with his proposal as well as
with ekiz proposal what I'm worried
about is the spoofing so middle box
could advertise that it's a feature that
is validation and thereby add around
trip to every - every quick connection
and there were a couple of proposals how
to prevent that basically by putting
stuff into the into the handshake to
validate that no men in the middle did a
retry and I think we should we should go
with some of those solutions Nick banks
is next yes little letter will be good
though Nick you're breaking up pretty
badly um can you take it to Jabbar and
we can channel you from there
can you hear me any better yeah turn
your video off any better yes so being
able to use the tag assumes you have
easy access to it if you're using
something like encryption offload the
quick server that's are the quick client
that would have to validate that
wouldn't have access to that very easily
so I'm the CID is something that has a
lot of direct easy access to and think
think it's the best solution which you
need the tag for PA don't you know Eric
was rolling I mean you even seen you
need to say for texture peony which is
the same location as the tag crate well
I mean if you offload all the encryption
essentially the code it would just pass
down the unencrypted value the hardware
could do peony and payload encryption so
it would have never had access to
whatever that ad tag was the absolute
about and later yeah that's true um it
was putting out to me separately that
this is actually a consequence of a
decision not to encrypt we try and have
we just encrypted retry we actually we
are generic solution would work so I
think but I'm really sad if that is
another generic solution for this that
like doesn't souffle girl Ally custom
screwing around so I agree my solution
is informatica better um so we had one
we prevented it okay riffing off of that
the the retry that we have doesn't need
to be version independent and if this is
happening after version negotiation we
could say that retry as a version
version dependent and therefore
encrypted frame it's already version
dependent yes so we can do whatever we
want with it
that's that's not the problem we can
decide to encrypt it but the but the
conclusion of the the design team was
that they didn't want this encrypted
specifically because that that was for
that would make the implementation of
the offload and and whatnot far more
efficient yeah my understanding is that
this was basically the the point was to
be as close to the yeah to be able to do
this cheaply when you have DDoS attacks
so encryption would be considered a cost
that they don't want to bear all right
that was Mike Bishop and John Iyengar by
the way so let's get back to the queue
Martin Duke is next yeah I just meant
that if the point attackers we finished
rostov not sure what the actual savings
are said you were spotted er yeah no I
agree s not about saving that suspect I
just think this is honest attack
so I guess if if what I'm hearing is
like people buy a large or neutral and
like there are some people who like
think
that you know that I'm wrong so an
interest of like getting forward okay
all right thanks we have some talk about
spoofing I think the suggestion that we
validate the choice of connection IDs
that we used in to start out with is
probably a good one and will should we
should look at doing that I've heard
this from a number of people now oh yeah
this is that this was the proposal that
I have so two options so we don't
actually make any promises about
successive handshakes or whatnot
in the presence of an attacker that has
the sort of capabilities that we're
talking about right here so specifically
we don't prevent attacks during the very
first phases of the of the handshake
from a tactic that can see the client
hello it's is possible for an attacker
to generate a server hello that a client
will accept there won't necessarily
ultimately result in a successful
handshake but we're not doing anything
special once once the attacker has men
in the middle capabilities then we're
not taking extraordinary steps to
protect can you characterize with the
attacker concerned about his circuses
not the attack this is not masked
attacker I thought you were concerned
about so the the only the only attack
that I'm aware of here is that the
attacker gets to choose the destination
connection ID that is attached to the
client initial packet that ultimately
reaches the server sorry this is a off
path or on path attacker it is a man on
the side would be able to mount that
attack yes okay so right so just just to
make sure we're all on the same page the
that the premise of the previous slide I
guess two slides I'm sorry she surprised
the previous law plus I'm in a military
requirement for that for that for the
for the DC ID or that's the ID actually
from that from the initial um obviate
any minute obvious path attackers from
the correct
yep so so one of the things we agreed to
do was was ensure that you had to be
able to see the packets in order to do
any of this we off path attackers don't
get any leverage over this modulo the
probability of them being able to guess
one of these things pretty low so we
have agreed previously that we would not
do anything special in this case so
[Music]
maybe you do nothing just to make sure
that people realize that way and the
attacker with a ability to see initial
packets and trades they can even attack
you at very negotiation stage in fact
even to a point of replying with with no
such work and go away so that's even
they can disrupt since even before
client in New Zealand and so we
ultimately concluded that until we have
a shared key with someone that is
authenticated attackers were these
capabilities can do just about anything
to disrupt that denying God I largely
agree obviously that's that sentiment
but I just know that this is a slightly
different slightly different flavor of
attack and then it's because it allows a
man it allows a man in the middle to
basically direct all traffic towards a
particular server potentially because
it's able to restrict the connection IDs
so this is probably something that this
is something that came up in the
conversation and we also that we
concluded that an attacker does not need
to bother doing this in particular
because if if they wanted to go and do
that then what they would do was act
would it would be far more efficient for
them to us act as a client and simply
set the same connection ID on every
request that they sent to the server so
I don't believe that to be a problem
this is probably advice for the
applicability / manageability documents
that if you're running a server maybe
you shouldn't be using the connection ID
in the initial packets from a client to
determine routing because because in
that case you could have a very large
population of clients you had send all
their packets to you know the one
poultry little instance sitting in the
back end that suddenly gets overwhelmed
and then they could do that you know
that one and then they move on to the
next one and kill that and so on so
there's a there's an attack there so
there's that is more interesting
actually yeah there's an interesting
case where the four people might
actually have more entropy than the
connection ID yeah picking this
particular attack but it's definitely
worth documenting and I think in the
security considerations and in the
applicability yeah document as well so
the the proposal here I think we
probably wanted to separately discuss
the idea that we might have Finnick
eight the destination connection ID
that's originally chosen but the
proposal here was basically we're not
going to do anything special but we
would suggest that maybe clients that
see an initial packet could use that
even if they've seen if even if they've
reacted to a retry just in case is
supposed so I agree that there is no
security concern about this because and
oh I know but device could always forced
the client use the same client ID and
that effectively minutes the reason why
we a yes encrypt us occasion because
having a study came is that tell me no
application at all right and so the
point there is if you can force someone
into using the same keys then you don't
get to ship the next version of the
protocol because every now now they're
also fight around that particular key so
it's an interesting point and probably
motivates the the suggestion that one
that I'd like to come back to that idea
later I think well we don't have time
for that now and I haven't looked at
that yeah okay so another thing is on
the list of PRS that are about to be
merged largely because I've gotten a lot
of good feedback on this is the
what happens if you go to retry to what
happens to you zero RTT
and so the proposal here is well yes you
can send zero artesian again and acres
analogy there was well tcp fast open
didn't work but you would still be able
to until s0 ICT at that point it was a
version there is that version
negotiations fairly similar in this
regard is unlikely to work in the sense
that if you're changing quick versions
it may not be the case that your zero
RCT ticket is any good for whatever you
do in the new version but there's
nothing inherently prohibiting that the
rationale for this was well we don't
have any strong justification to say
that you can't try zero RCT so we'll
allow it
there's catch it's unlikely that the
keys that you're using to protect zero
RTT packets will change as a result of
having received a retry and effectively
starting again and so there's a there's
a requirement here in here that when you
get the retries and another initial
starts anymore 0 while TT you don't
reset the packer numbers back to zero
because two time pads they're awesome
and so that's the primary reason there
was another reason I forget now what it
was but the two time pad thing that was
the primary concern here though you
could technically we transmit the exact
same packet that would be fine yes we
generally advise my advice very
tactically okay it would be technically
okay and so there's the observation in
the in in the PR also points out that
there's a very good chance that the zero
ICT Packers that you sent last time
might be lost but what they might get
then we don't know what servers gonna do
so what's the berlanger yeah so I was
about to bring that up but could could
we actually say that if you get an retry
packet then the server's officially said
that I'm not committing to State anymore
that would be very convenient to say
client should retransmit zero RTT data
immediately
very clear semantics in that regard the
the advice of the the PR basically says
yes you should expect to have to resend
them but it doesn't say should because a
client might decide not to continue with
zero RT t at that point that's that's
entirely up to them
there's no interoperability cost of
going either way on this I'm necessary
you can resend the same because
connection are changes maybe it didn't
change I don't know some service won't
change it so but yeah good point so so I
mean I joined the analogy TfL which I
thought all the time is a good analogy I
think it is harm in general but I mean
we also make some noises about how this
is conceptually a new connection and I
wonder if the right noises are you
should generate that you should ditch
all the TLS tape they're a new client
hello and and that would then you
wouldn't have to screw him or the Packer
numbers arms every German analogy right
uses new connection that would be fine
as well I think I I suspect that it
doesn't matter no I just I don't
remember like like I'm glad somebody
caught this this packet number reset
issues good um and so like I just worry
it's subtle right and so um I don't
think it's a stir but it's like saying
you could easily get wrong and you and
it would only in a would not be it would
like just like if you just screwed it up
EP sorry right so um so let's say I mean
like I would be taking a different
different metaphor for this would be
saying like this is a new condition
metaphor as opposed thank you like you
got a reset I can TCP resets every TFO
but it would be a reasonable way to
think about the world so yeah that's a
good observation I think we could allow
either one frankly yeah so Pat McManus
so I think the raising the issue was
really great because I had just allowed
this in my code because you know it's
not actually zero RTT anymore after the
retry there's been a round trip and just
intuitively this made no sense so it's
good to clarify and I agree it can
actually be done because it's you know
now call it one less RTT or something
that's still still win and I like the
with new packet number rule because that
is consistent with the overall
philosophy that one does not retransmits
right yep
yeah deviating from that seems seems bad
so I so I would I would actually suggest
that you can keep the same counters for
all of the packet number spaces that
would be the way to think about it right
I think I think like having people
resend initial with zero and then other
things with like you know 52 that's not
that's like not gonna be okay
I mean I don't least gonna cross
problems I mean it's gonna causing
confidence um so um but um I think
either we should either we should say
ear we should go with like discussion
that we send the initial with that with
the next sequential packet number or we
should go or or we should do like when I
said I client hello but I think having
gonna be alright that's good feedback
yep Mike Bishop the other reason that we
didn't reset them and something for
server-side implementers to be aware of
was that the if the 0tt packets were
either buffered or delayed they can
arrive after your new initial or be
processed after your new initial and
they are still valid for the connection
so you'd better not change the data that
send them all right Thanks so uh yeah
same thing so different angle on the
same question if you get a zero ICT
packet you haven't seen an initial what
do you do with it
currently we we have a write up that
basically says if you get a zero ICT
packet
you must not generate a retry in
response to it you're only allowed to
send a retro and response for initial so
the support for doing this is pretty
weak there's not really too many reasons
in either direction for this one but
basically rather than shrug our
shoulders on this one we'll say should
not for this one or May or something
along those lines basically because
there's no reason not to do this sort of
thing and it may in some cases improve
performance if a server receives a zero
ICT packet and wants to keep things
moving along it can do address
validation immediately rather than then
wait for the possibly lost initial
pattern that the client sent because
that can take time far too much time no
problems for that that's that talk all
done thank you okay Thank You Martin
please stay there stay inside the pink
box
pretty much yeah next up is managing
keys yeah yep that one you know
discarding and rekey saris near for name
so this is another one that I think's
relatively urgent although not hugely
important we've had a lot of discussion
about how to manage keys one of the nice
things about the the updated design is
that it's pretty crisp about when keys
are used and what what packets are
protected with what keys and what
cryptographic handshake messages are
protected with which keys but we have
this sort of fuzzy bit when it comes to
getting rid of those keys so here's my
summary of the handshake there's a lot
of messages going back and forth you'll
notice that there's a lot of coalescence
potentially involved in this but one of
the things that you will observe is that
the that there are initial packets being
exchanged for some time but at some
point you stop having a need to maintain
those keys what do you do with that well
initial is pretty straightforward not a
lot of no I mean not exactly secrets
we're maintaining here but still be nice
to know when you can clean that stuff up
same applies to the handshake keys so
you've got handshake messages initially
starting from when the server sends its
first flight of messages and ultimately
ending when the server sends its
acknowledgment of the clients handshake
messages and maybe at that point you can
get rid of those keys except for the
fact that we have this tile problem on
on these things we never really know
whether this the halting problem in the
sense that you never really know that
the handshake is done and the other side
is done with that the handshake because
so the simple solution for this is to
treat each packet number spaced
separately and you say that the packet
number space is done when the read and
write keys for that packet number space
read and write keys for the next space
are ready
so for handshake keys when you have your
one RCT keys and you're using them then
you're done with the handshake keys and
there's a little bit of a little bit of
nuance to that because of the
arrangement of the handshake but at that
point you can just set a timer and so
you set a timer at that point and that
runs for I don't know a couple of RT
owes a couple of round trips it doesn't
really matter it could be a pretty long
time in fact we've sort of established
because of the way that the tellers keys
separation works that you potentially
just keep the keys forever it's just an
overhead its memory they're not actually
a threat to anything at that point but
still you set a timer and during the
time that you're maintaining that key
you'll be able to receive
acknowledgments resend crypto frames as
necessary and send it knowledge modes
and so that seems pretty reasonable once
you've gotten rid of the keys obviously
the packets that you receive that might
have been encrypted under those keys
will be done unintelligible and you'll
just be forced to drop them and that's
probably okay so the way to think about
that is is you look at each packet
number space and there's also some
consideration here for serial ITT but
I've got the two kind of critical ones
here so at the point that the client
receives the server hello and at the
point that the server sends the server
hello
they're basically finished sending
crypto frames to each other
and that's the point where they set a
timer and at the point they set the
timer they can set that timer for a
number of round trips and we're just
maintaining that time first long as
we're willing to effectively continue
acknowledging things essentially or or
repairing the cryptographic handshakes
day the same applies I mean that
direction of messages is different but
the same basic procedure applies for
handshake messages you just when you see
the last one right to set the timer so
there's been discussion of a sort of
implicit acknowledgement system for for
all of this you can use the fact that
you've moved on to the next phase of
keys just sort of as a signal that says
that the other side has all of the
crypto frames from the previous
iteration so if you get a handshake
packet pretty sure that all of the
crypto frames in initial packets drop to
their destinations because you can't
derive those keys without actually
having access to those messages
similarly if the server receives one RTT
packets from a client that means that
the client has received all of the
crypto frames that the server ever might
want to see sent it's a little more
tricky on the client end for one ICT
that packets because the server sends
then before the clients really done or
it could at least and so the client
actually has to look for acknowledgments
of its one RCT packets to signal that
and in that case you can stop sending
the crypto frames now of course what
will happen is that there's the
potential for acts to be lost and you'll
have acknowledgments in flight and you
might potentially want to do some more
acknowledging at that point but you can
actually safely drop the act frames if
the other side agrees that this is
acceptable there's a couple of corner
cases in this and I don't think we need
to worry about that someone's gonna jump
up and tell me that's wrong but that's
I I'm not planning to document that
optimization by the way I think people
who want to embark upon these sorts of
optimizations will have to think through
the consequences of all of this and be
absolutely certain they're not going to
break the other side there are there are
models that you can use for this that
require that the other side is aware of
what you're doing because what will
happen is it will think that it needs to
retransmit crypto frames and you don't
need them it doesn't need them but it's
resending them and expecting
acknowledgments and if you're dropping
those packets on the floor you could end
up with crypto frames being sent for a
considerable amount of time after the
handshake is well done and it's just
wasteful at that point so there's a
little bit of care required in order to
get this logic right I'm not gonna write
that down because it's too damn hard a
number of people have suggested that it
would be nice to have a signal that the
the handshake is done that is a positive
signal once you get the one RTT keys
from maybe from each side but I'm
thinking probably from the server
although I've shown it in both
directions here that basically says I'm
done with a handshake I have everything
I need in order to proceed with this
connection and once you've received that
message you can stop sending any packets
on the previous back a number spaces you
just throw everything away at the point
that you received that that message in I
was gonna come and I'm the zero to tikis
I I think you could probably drop those
at the same time safely because you're
sending Zarate in the first flight and
by the time the handshake done would be
sent that would be in the clients second
flight so you'd still allow for a full
RTC of reordering of 0tt packets that
seem right and so this is that's an
interesting observation it's yes it
doesn't perfectly solve the problem but
at the point that you're an entire round
trip after the zero ITT Keys have been
done it's not quite that good I don't
think because the the handshake done
is sent in close proximity of the last
of the zero RCT messages so I don't
think it's as good as you think it is
the client-server right this is this is
in the direction of this server so the
server when it receives handshake done
will receive that handshake done
basically sometimes I imagine in the
same packet isn't as 0tt now I think
it's a fault RTD you later round it's
not it's not because in order live
streaming of the 0tt data the client
continues saying CRT TV until it's
process until it's process the entire
server first flight and so basically
they'll last like like essentially like
last circuit a packet is like you know I
say is like sent like you know
milliseconds before like the see fit
yeah yeah um so I mean now you're like
Tyrone I mean now you even do it you'll
have me all it's gonna happen is you're
gonna like you know they all hakuna and
the data but like you want a time or a
bit I mean a smarter pollination one a
timer over the Hat yep back in them back
in the soup so this is my proposal
document that you might want to clean up
the keys suggest that you might want to
use a timer for that purpose and leave
the rest of the optimizations for those
people who want to have fun debugging
thorny key management issues I don't
care so micro I will point out one other
other open issues is now that we have an
extension framework we're looking for a
poster child extension to exercise it
and check done would be a fine extension
I don't think it would be but I mean if
you want to use that as a safety valve
and for anyone who wants it nothing
stopping you from proposing it I guess
I'm David's Ganassi Apple just want to
say that I really really agree with this
mentality there are already too many
things in the spec that like sound a
little bit too smart
sometimes and as an implementer first
reader you go away what is going on so
if people want to go crazy and optimize
something and maybe documenting on site
that's fine but keep it out of the main
spec people who prefer having panchik
down could implement the same facility
using ping frames so I don't think that
we need a special frame project right
that's the optimization that I did I
outlined essentially suppose I know I
agree with this as well in the previous
iteration before the stream zero
proposal there was be more dangerous to
this but now that separate act spaces
and separate packet number spaces it's
like much cleaner and much safer to do
this error control I also grew this on
the one thing I would say is that the
text doesn't state when it is safe to do
this and yes I say it has to say like
the last time but that in the sequence
the last packet which you will get with
this is here I'm happy to assist for
that text yep that'd be that'd be great
yep yeah your proposal is that we don't
actually say do you want us do you want
would you like that to have like here is
a set of timer rules which you could
follow or just you may wish use a timer
and this is when you this is this is the
time you should be setting the timer if
you were to set it yeah and basically
acknowledging that once you've hit this
point then it's all about
retransmissions and acknowledgments and
you say the timer based on how long
you're willing to spend retransmitting
things and acknowledging them but I
always can drive it even the simpler
version of that I mean if infinite is
okay we might just need some essentially
non-normative text that acknowledges you
know if there is some point at which
this happens and you know you may or may
not make use of that fact I wouldn't I
don't think we need to set timer values
in particular I'm not gonna suggest a
specific value no no that's that dick so
thank you great stay there
I'm stuck in this pink box and have
dreams about that next up is stateless
reset oh yeah
yeah we have those done we're time it's
on yeah so this is one that will never
die oh that's right all right
so Mikkel made an interesting
observation
turns out stateless read reset is by
design indistinguishable from a quick
packet you can't decrypt it no one can
decrypt it that's kind of the point
but it's also the case that you send
stateless reset when you receive a
packet that you can't decrypt and both
Clinton's server can do this it doesn't
actually take to quiet their client on
the server to produce this problem
because you can certainly point to
service it and each other if you really
wanted to do that so that's a little bit
of a problem it looks like this
[Music]
there's no amplification so if a packet
gets lost it eventually ends but I hear
that some people are operating networks
that don't drop packets that often
nowadays and I'm not sure that I want
this problem so we've discussed a couple
of simple solutions and there it's not
really that dire a problem when you
think about it this way and it turns out
stateless reset is pretty small its
variable length for various reasons but
it's pretty small and so it'll be
smaller than most packets that you're
gonna receive certainly most packet sort
of receive that you don't don't know
obviously there's already rules in there
that if the packets too small to
plausibly be a quick packet just going
to drop it on the floor anyway so
maybe we can be guys send it if it's
smaller than the packet that was
received if it isn't correct thank you
I should proofread I'm learning that my
perforating skills are you know double
negative only send it if it is smaller
than the packet that was received thank
you Mark
there's also a slightly more complex
solution that says well maybe it's nice
if you send a stateless reset in
response to these packets because if
someone is say doing that's for instance
telnet and the first path and the first
backup that I sent after a long idle
period is control-c it's a single
character and that's going to be a small
packet and your connection ID is small
there's a pretty good chance that you
will have this packet be relatively
small coming in and wouldn't it be nice
if maybe there had at least some chance
of being able to benefit from the salaat
the Malaysian that we have that will
kill the connection off and so you have
some sort of proper built probabilistic
dropping and as long as their
probability is not not zero I'm dropping
it then everything should ultimately
resolve yeah you'll get a couple of legs
on that on the you know a couple of
bounces in the in the sort of perverse
scenario where both sides have lost
state and have decided to stateless Lee
reset each other but it'll ultimately
resolve itself and so I think that's a
reasonable solution and that's all I've
got on this deck did anyone have any
questions or suggestions or
disagreements I wanted to get this in
front of people who've got a little
experience with this one just one my
name's Tim Shepherd it's just one simple
observation that there are networks that
rarely drop packets but there are also
networks that occasionally duplicate
packets
and some of those might duplicate
packets somewhat more often even though
it's rare somewhat more often than they
drop packets in which case you have to
choose a and B I mean a little more care
is required is just what you're
suggesting sure I don't know what the
answer to this is it's just a thought I
had I thought I should that's a good
question since we have so many people in
the room who might actually know things
about this does anyone have any idea
what the duplication probability would
be in those networks relative to the
drop probability because we could at
least provide some general uninsurance
there there are a lot of weird networks
out there there may not be the norm of
the internet but I couldn't possibly
tell you what they are numbers are for
every weird network that exists up yeah
so weird is the norm so I guess we'll
have to make some allowance for that
let's hear from non editors for a second
Cory why don't you go ahead so Cory
Perez I mean there are networks that I
should drop package due to a QM and
other things etc and there are pet works
that duplicate packets for odd things
so it's questions do you want to work
everywhere in the internet or do you
want to work on just one part so it's a
trade off for you numbers won't help you
I'm afraid because there's always gonna
be this tail end of stuff that is really
weird yeah well if the drop
probabilities is high enough do you
think what I said I hope that yeah maybe
maybe we get you to look at it and and
say with you whether or not you believe
that this is a problem sure explanation
the way I understand it more to it and
I'll try and help and the courses can be
robust to this not optimal yes yeah
that's really what we're looking for
yeah are you jabber channeling David one
sure go ahead
Thanks there's kanasu jabber relaying so
to people Praveen blossom Runyan wanted
to say that randomization makes it very
hard for debug ability let's keep things
predictable
and Mike Bishop was saying that acts are
another oh yeah well it proved een asked
me to relay you anyway I'm gonna
continue to ask the editors to let
others cycle through and we'll let you
guys have maybe the last word
Eric Eric Nygren I think the a key thing
is making sure that whatever we have is
very deterministic that this ends fast
because even if they're the same size of
an attacker can induce this Pinconning
by by injecting something that two end
points start ping pong game back and
forth it doesn't matter that that the
size that their small packets not
increasing in size it's that ping pong
itself
they just keep injecting things these
drugs are having a growing set of stuff
ping pong NC not the proposal here was
not if though if they did not decrease
in size you would drop them so it would
always be strictly smaller right
and I guess that may be worth thinking
through are there any cases where you
can trick things and in ways of various
format might make it look to two
endpoints that they're different so for
example if there is some if there's some
encapsulation or translator in between
that is going and adding a little bit of
stuff on to them so that between those
two end points you get something with it
that violates that property so maybe
we're thinking of of is it worth having
something more explicit here that really
guarantees that that it that it
terminates or the determinates fast okay
over here next Tommy so I'm not sure if
this will help by wondering if there's
another tool in the toolbox of things we
can do to help here I understand that
the set this preset is stateless but can
an endpoint carry some decaying State of
the number of resets that it has been
sending and essentially just have some
plausibility like you could very easily
say that if within the past ten seconds
I have sent a ridiculous number of
research I've detected that there's
something pong and just stop doing it
for an hour just back off and actually
have that drop rate be relative to the
amount that you recognize ping ponging
possibilities we do actually
okay something along those lines yeah
okay come on next okay so Jonathan axe I
mean that my first point is does it
actually have to be that the condition
is that it's the packet is you know you
know small or equal to say recenter
could it just be if it's exactly the
size of a say let's reset it's obviously
something smaller can't be causing the
ping-pong either so they're variable
sized they are variable sized yeah all
right
and the other point is I was gonna say
is in the case we were describing of the
you know they tell that I mean so I mean
even if your probability is quite high
like 50 percent you're still going to
almost certainly get us a let's reset
within three or four RTT so yeah I think
I think it's probability if you want to
do probabilistically I think you can
safely be quite high to cause a very
fast decay and in most preset cases
you'll get recovery within two or three
graduate retransmissions yeah that was
my that was my entry intuition as well I
have four points first point is let's
remember say is an optimization it is
not like it is a nice optimization but
it's not the position the second point
is you must do something bookkeeping
anyway if how many say this recess you
sent because otherwise you end up like
sending our crap close save this resets
like for like the enormous fault of
packets that are coming in and I believe
three locations I think it's gonna say
do this any right so um so so like says
justice and bookkeeping anyone any
suggestion is eminently reasonable um
third points can you go to this slide
this that this really seemed this really
seemed like it might be okay because if
you're only getting really small packets
you know I'm like that much in flow and
any real any real application that like
a replication refine shutdown is gonna
send you big packets and so I just give
it going back to principle one or
principle 0 depending on what kind of
computer scientist you are that seems
like they probably be just fine um and
my first point is I I concur with I
think Nick's point about randomization
random being bad and in that but in that
um in in in that vein it's possible the
turistic algorithm where you part by you
hash the incoming packet and then they
blah blah
we're gonna close the Q's John if you
want to get in get in now okay go ahead
yes I was gonna basically say what I
Korea said BER me which is we use
something we call a time waitlist and do
exponential back-off for first a lisp
reset to try to avoid situations like
this the other is on packet duplication
we have seen this before in real
networks it basically never happens
unless it happens all the time so you
have like one broken switch that just
basically sends every single packet
everyone yeah something like that so
it's it's like a very bimodal thing
we're like everything's fine into like
all of your servers are ddossing each
other and then we also had to solve this
exact problem for client initial a long
time back because it wasn't the keys
weren't asymmetric or there was no way
to tell the difference between a server
initial area one and in that case we
actually decremented the TTL so we would
like make sure the TTL decreased as the
client initial went back and forth and I
wanted to add that that's one potential
mitigation is you can copy the TTL in
and that does ensure that there's no
infinitely I don't know if that leads to
much input information but it's a very
simple solution and it totally works so
I was hi friend Trammell I was basically
gonna come up there come up here to say
what he had just said um there's another
thing that you could do so I really like
the simple solution there's another
thing that you could do this simple
solution by tweaking the size of the
stateless reset and saying that the
state like not just saying don't send it
if it's smaller in the packet was
received but say that the stateless
reset must always be packet size it at
most pocket-sized minus something and
then you essentially the TTL itself is
encoded in the packet size if you can
that requires probably a little bit more
rethinking of how stateless reset works
but um what wait what are this what are
the packets they're smaller than
stateless reset the the problem here is
that the this reset has to be large
enough to be plausible alright yeah and
you don't know how large the other side
has set its connection ID to be oh okay
the largest possible connection idea the
other side could have which means they
end up being something any order for the
octet thirties were doctors okay so my
ideas ox and onions ideas awesome do
that
Manistee they will enter so they're you
know if we compare this behavior to TCP
with TCP we see there are some state
machines that are triggered a connection
termination so and they are primarily
you know at least some of them are
around we switch offload terminating
tunnels you know removing state in the
software based on the termination of a
connection so it would be definitely
good to have this deterministic because
otherwise it leads the software to
basically go through a huge number of
slows and in concept it's simple but the
scale is quite quite huge so it's it's
not very easy to say like just run a
timer and delete things that have or
expire flows so that's my feedback here
I would prefer it to be deterministic so
I'm for a long time a significant part
of me has held the thought that
stateless reset is something we should
jettison altogether because we have a
nice beautifully authenticated protocol
and you know allowing someone that's
clearly not participating in that chain
fluence your behavior just feels wrong
I've been convinced that operationally
like you you can't work around this at
some point but I think that does argue
for the simplest possible solution here
the probabilistic things you know make
me it's a lot of machinery for something
that for a party that's not really
participating in the protocol and that's
concerning right and Jen I ain't got
this to me does bring back the question
of do we really need this to be
symmetric
that's symmetry doesn't help us here no
point to serve it as service of each
other with this all right suppose we
have that from yes sorry you're right
you know yeah
all right so I like I like the
suggestion of the TTL that may not be
accessible to a number of people but
it's it's certainly something we could
we could strongly recommend particularly
in this sort of too small case and we're
talking about the IP DDL right IP TT oh
yeah yeah and so so then then your
acting is effectively it'll just keep
driving itself down to zero and
eventually work it through right thank
you that's all I'm thank you you may
leave the pink box so next up we we've
got three more issue presentations on
mic if you can make your way up the
connection ID then HTP then recovery I'd
like to finish these three up in the
next 25 minutes if we can so connection
IDs okay so we've had connection at ease
and quick for a while they're very
useful for helping a connection survive
changes to the four tuple and I think
we've all had these all right good I
think we've all had a lot of intuition
about how we think they ought to work
and it turns out that trying to specify
that gets kind of hairy so where we
started out in pre and pre peony land
was that each connection ID was in
sequence had a specified packet number
gap to help avoid having a packet number
of give you likability and then they
have a stateless reset token problem
with that is you get head of line
blocking because if you miss one of them
you can't use anything further down the
list because you have to know the
cumulative packet number of gaps and
once we had probing and connection
migration it gets really weird trying to
sort out while I use this other kin
with the packet number gap on the other
path but what do I do here on the main
path where I haven't changed connection
ideas so once we had packet number
encryption we said great we can get rid
of all of that and packet numbers are
just this class not packet number so our
connection ideas are this cloud of
things that we've received when we can
use any of them all right we can use any
of them anytime we want head of line
blocking isn't an issue great this is
simple but to break link ability if your
peer changes then you also need to
change and exactly how do you figure out
that the peers change was in response to
your change and not the peer changing at
the same time so you need to change and
I started trying to write down the rule
of how you would figure that out
and I couldn't and if somebody
implemented it and actually did figure
out a rule that would be nice but what
we came up with was we actually do need
that sequence number so it's not
entirely clear to me that when you're
pure changes CID you need to change
so any pair might changes Yeti for fun
um that I mean well you do to change
your CID the time you change your CID is
when a path has changed and so the
question is is that P is the pure
changing CID the only see only how the
path has changed it's not clear to me
that's true
so the spec recommends that you change
your connection ID when you think there
might be in that rebonding like you've
been quite quiescent for a while
sure and if you want to any kind of
unlink ability across those if you're
pure just responds with the connection
ID you were using to you're new to your
new point of connection no I understand
the point but why bother saying is that
so you have you have a behind in that
and B not behind that and any thinks he
might've had a not rebinding and so he
uses in his CID but B knows he didn't
have in that refining and so B knows
that B knows that B knows that the path
changed and so-and-so be responsive I
mean so so in that case you don't have
to change your CID so it may be the case
that the only way to detect this they
could be conservative but like but like
I'm not yet persuaded that it's not
possible to turn where the path has
changed without like using the CID as a
trigger
are you are you using and B as two
different clients or I'm saying they're
they're they're Pierce so if he knows
that he knows that IP didn't change cuz
it like couldn't see the incoming
packets so I believe we're being
conservative and we're also in this case
when a changes their connection ID they
might want to appear to be see so that
the folks on the network might think
that there's other people behind that
net Forest and I I appreciate about what
but what I'm saying is that if you if
you receive a new key if you receive a
new connection ID from someone whose
dress has not changed then it's not
clear to me that you actually have to
change your own connection ID and so
like that that could see that Mikey you
add this lock step I lost that condition
i I think we chose the lock step
condition because it was convenient for
other reasons that's all okay but I get
I guess but we're talking about has
inconvenient so I'm like you know that's
one I guess I guess I like like this is
her like I guess I'm trying to figure
out like how much this is a historical
talk and how much this is like a
motivation for pretty good design if
it's a historical clock I'll sit down
and shut up but if this is like driving
us towards like some particular design
like as our eyes as a motivation then
I'm not gonna shut up visits
right way decal so this piece this
section of it is historical of how we
got to what's in draft 13 okay but it is
new and draft 13 and if you think it was
a mistake we could revert it and take a
different truck well I mean it's like
well I'm seeing like I see you back to
add some epicycles and so like like
that's why I'm asking like before we
throw example cycles like whether we
should be like going back to that
principles so I guess like so one thing
it's like I mean like curly design half
of my head which means apply is wrong
like like like why can't you just
straight the rule to update like you
only update when you believe that heroes
it has
sent you a new to transport parameters
sorry new transport address than the one
you're currently receiving the CID on
Sojin I and God I don't know that you
need to you could be very easily assumed
that all of these are associated with
path changes right and I think the the
problems or whatever you're going to say
is still going to hold true like each of
these events whenever the connection
area is changing if you assume that the
path is also the network is also
changing that's final assumption if you
need to make that assumption notice the
text in the document right now requires
the pier to change the connection ID
every time it sees a connection any
change no I know that's but that's but
the reason you're carrying to infinity
is because everybody's ping pong ping
pong in the pink point in the the it's
changes right and so if you like if he
what I'm saying is it's like imagine the
case where like the dresser completely
stable right and one side changes
because as mike says he thinks he may
have had an hour he's been offline for
45 seconds he might have an hour binding
event on and so it sends it but he
hasn't changed then then if the other
side doesn't respond with a change that
you won't come to infinity and if you
have changed and you and if you have
changed and you do send it then like I
think you can put that from the from the
you know from the from the initiators
her from the a spur stretches behind the
NAT when he receives the second CID like
he doesn't have to change again because
other guys guys room I said dress hasn't
changed so so so that's a bit just let's
stop let's let Mike get through his
presentation and then have our
discussion so I think that is a an
interesting suggestion let me talk about
the other issues that we have with this
model and it may be that going to that
would solve more than them more of them
and that's one of the solutions that can
be on the table so there are some
advantages to having a sequence number
so that's what we have in draft 13 which
says that there is a sequence for each
connection ID that gets issued by your
peer and that makes the behavior pretty
easy to specify if you are starting a
new path then you have to use a higher
sequence number than you have ever used
before for this connection and on each
path
you will never send a packet where the
connection is a sequence number is less
than the highest you've ever Center
received so that forces the ratcheting
behavior on a per path basis so to give
you a quick example I'm using a B a B
and C so you can keep track of the
sequence numbers multiple paths are hard
to draw so forgive my bad drawings so we
have a connection both sides are using
connection ID a which is a different
value in each direction and also they're
doing some probes on a side path to get
ready for a potential migration they use
B for that the fact that you probed
doesn't change that you're using a on
the main path and if on the main path
you change to see the other side moves
to see that doesn't change the other
path you can stay on B if the other side
tries to roll forward again to D but for
some reason you don't have D you just go
to the next one that you do have and
then the Pierre has to match you so that
way you only have consistent rules for
how you move through the connection IDs
that have been issued so that simplifies
a lot of the specifying what you do win
but there are some problems with that
let's say you're using a on the main
path and you have lots of other paths
you want to probe so I'll use B C and D
because I just got those from the Pierre
but they all get dropped because those
paths don't work now one side says I
have no spare C ideas the other side
says I don't need to give him anymore
he's got three outstanding so you send
any mode indeed
so it's possible to become unclear
whether appear has actually used the
connection ideas that you've issued him
and we need more that's one problem that
we still need to solve in this model
also
if the only packet that you ever sent
that a given connection ID gets dropped
and eventually you forget about it but
it's not actually dropped it's just
severely delayed that can trigger a
stateless reset so they're actually so
there also needs to be some kind of
coordination between the peers when
they're no longer going to consider a
particular connection ID to be
associated with this connection or you
get into some weird states a common
easier place for this to happen would be
let's say you use that to probe on a
side path and one side considers the
path to have been abandoned because you
haven't probed it in two minutes but the
other side says well I just haven't sent
a probe lately but that's still a path
that I have available and I know it's
validated so if you have a long lift
connection and you're rotating
connection at ease frequently it's not
practical to remember all the connection
ideas you have ever used particularly if
the peer can force you to move to new
connection IDs
that's also especially true if the all
the connection ideas have to be plumbed
into the load balancer so that they get
routed to you but if you can't
coordinate when it's safe to forget a
connection ID and remove it from state
then you can trigger a trigger stateless
resets and there are cases when you
might actually want to expire a whole
swath of Si IDs for example let's say
it's encrypted you're doing Q rotation
you're about to rotate again you have to
make sure that everything that was done
with not just the previous key phase but
the key phase before that will never
ever ever be seen again
for the life of this connection so if
there's a PR right now for two more
frames that say hey I need more C IDs
and hey I'd like to get rid of these C
IDs there is another proposal for how
you get rid of connection ideas which is
to say that there's a certain number
outstanding at a time
and you can just Auto expire based on
how many new ones you've gotten I think
that we'd have to work through that
carefully because again there's
confusion about which the ideas doesn't
appear actually have and agree not to
use but that's also a possibility so
then this is a proposal that I think we
need to sort out I think this is true
even if we don't force the pier to
advance and lockstep so I'd like to know
how we solve it in that world if we if
you want to go there Jen eyeing that I
don't think that at a connection ID
works reordering that was reordering
which can cause race conditions like so
could send a stateless reset and then
some the data a connection ID of the
data connection ID sent drop in the
network retransmitted but before that
the stateless reset is sent all kinds of
things the way this is in the PR is that
the the client will stop using a
particular connection ID once it
receives the phone and the server will
forget it once it receives the
acknowledgement of that frame so you
won't get a stateless reset until you've
act now if it's reordered across the Sun
okay so the client sent it before before
the retire CID frame arrived but then
the server receives it after the ACK is
what you're saying yes so oh no actually
the solution to that is when the client
removes the CID it also removes the
stateless reset token so it won't
recognize that stateless reset as
belonging to this connection anymore
all right go ahead mark yeah so nan
Thomson I'm not a huge fan of this and I
know I proposed an alternative design I
think that ultimately was kazuo
suggestion originally which was that
endpoints would advertise a an absolute
number of connection IDs that they are
willing to to remember and that number
would be the sum of the ones that they
would be willing to remember posture
those that might be in flight and that
would work I think much more simply than
what you have and the only thing you
would then need is because we have this
reciprocation requirement you would
require if if I sent you a connection ID
with an ID of 10 you would have to make
sure that you sent me all the connection
eyes these up to 10 in response and then
it says I think that that'd be a simpler
design I agree that it feels simpler I I
would need to work through it I think
some of these problems about getting
confused of who has actually sent what
will make the peers not agree about what
this current set is but there may around
that so I don't think they have to agree
actually but not not entirely but the
only thing that's important there is to
remember that if you support 10 if you
say that you support 10 different
connection IDs you have to count the
ones that you sent but not how to
acknowledge yet in in that set otherwise
that yeah you have to assume that the
other sorry you have to assume that the
other side remembers 10 plus the ones
you haven't had acknowledged yet this is
pretty complicated and made my hair fall
out let me for that yeah first of all I
think like given that we have another
proposals here or I think like trying to
merge this at this moment is going to be
very problematic
I my am um and frankly I'm trying to
think we need like a Tamron model this
like figure out like whether or not it's
gonna break because I'm having a lot
more reasoning about it um which I mean
what really worries me cuz like these
things like like my sprucing things is
like we spend a lot of time building
things and then like about two weeks
later because you ho sent some email
saying like this is totally screwed up
because of this use case or and like I
like Marshall I appreciate that service
I think we could we can work that I
worry about having the rival and I put a
call predicated and kazoo hopping a
brainstorm
so um the with that said I think this
would be the first time we declared the
semantics of some place to the protocol
dependent on receiving in knowledge Minh
from the pure and that makes me kind of
sad um like I normally think of like
packets going into some bucket or they
just like gradually migrate to their
side and then like you know ideology
mints remove things from the bucket and
so having that fed back upward to me so
I have to like do some other action like
scares me
so um I think to be the first time we've
done it if it's not which if it isn't we
should take those things out and and if
it is we probably shouldn't start I
think isn't but we have and we have
previously taken out the other instances
it doesn't sound like we're gonna
conclude this today so I'm going to cut
the queues go ahead dude skin Ozzie
Apple all at a co-worker's point about
this being pretty complicated and
starting to lose hair also most clients
and my understanding correct me if I'm
wrong will probably be sending c.length
connection ID so we're sounds like we're
building a lot of complexity that won't
necessarily be used just something to
consider please keep it simple human
tornado so questions that's come up is
could this be simplified a little bit by
not requiring the need just with retire
when you action of retiring my trigger
computer send the Union ones up to X or
whatever yeah I think that's another
flavor of you have a certain number that
are outstanding right the other way of
doing it is the action of issuing new
ones retires old ones
Atlee but either way and also the pier
has to match them for the to issue yeah
although you did I think you did justify
why we're trying specifically some would
take care of the delayed it would be
more explicit you had one more slide
might be needed I can I propose a way of
moving forward if you can do it
succinctly yes yeah I think we I was
thinking the same thing
yeah and then perhaps get it together
and talk about it in New York is that a
reasonable timeframe okay show of hands
who's interested in participating on
such a thing the usual suspects okay
Mike do you want to take charge of
collecting those folks together
sure okay great so if you're interested
in helping out with that design team
talk to Mike and we'll expect to hear
back before New York okay and then the
last slide is just to say that in
addition to the things that could
actually cause your connection to break
there are also some annoyances involved
in this the spec currently says the CID
from the handshake has a sequence number
of negative one
some people don't like negative numbers
the surface preferred address also gives
you connection ID and it doesn't
actually say what's number that is and
the client the handshake connection ID
doesn't have a state list reset token
for the client and if you want to be
able to define one how do you do that so
these are all other less connection
critical CID issues that have been
discussed on lists okay thank you so
stay there now you're trapped in the box
welcome the box next up is HTTP we have
this and then we have recovery so like
to try and at least fit both in let's
see how we go
come on go ahead all right so quick
overview of notable changes since London
I will try to move through these and it
fairly rapid pace so we can get to
recovery if you've read the drafts that
should not be news to you the HCP frames
no longer defined flags on every frame
type priority was the only thing that
was using it so now it's just part of
the priority definition yeh saving bytes
its GP to uses zombie streams that were
never opened and are implicitly closed
to maintain the priority tree that has
some not happy implications on server
memory consumption and also quick can't
implicitly close streams so it's GP over
quick now has a partner priority
placeholder explicitly defined and also
along with that we now have to account
for the fact that 0 which used to mean
the root of the tree is actually a
request stream so we have to have
something know something else to handle
that this lets you do more aggressive
pruning on your servers priority state
because you can keep track of which
nodes are in active active or
placeholders placeholders never get
removed you can remove and trim out the
inactive ones with some fairly simple
rules like you can take out any branches
that are all in active nodes you can
collapse down any interior regions that
are all inactive nodes and the client
can predict that you're going to do this
and so it helps the server in the client
have a consistent view of the priority
tree from both sides
we're in h2 it was actually fairly easy
to get confused the other big change in
HTTP is that we have now put a tight
bite on unidirectional streams they are
essentially self describing the first
byte tells you what type of stream to
expect it to be and this is
a point of extensibility we have four
types defined currently - 4q pact and
then - in the core spec one is for
control stream the other one is for push
if you don't understand it
abandon the stream which may involve the
stop sending frame at the quick layer
and in terms of recommendations -
extensions if it's data that develops
over time like the cue pack table use a
stream if it's data that you have in
your hands all at once go ahead and
define a frame like you did in h2 but
this is this gets basically the same
semantics as new frame types when we
discussed it and she saw the hum was
roughly split between yes we want this
and we're not sure yet we had a
follow-up discussion on the list that
was mostly positive there were some
drawbacks that we know are no come along
with this debugging without tools gets a
little bit harder because now you can't
remember what stream ID belongs to which
what stream ID is to control stream you
can't look at the unidirectional stream
and say oh of course that's push but
considering we're talking about an
encrypted binary protocol I'm really
impressed if you can debug it without
tools anyway
and there's the slightly annoying state
that if you receive data on a stream out
of order it becomes open but if you have
it receives the first byte you don't
actually know what type it is to assign
it to a handler everybody that I've
heard who has tried to implement this
just has a handler whose job is to
collect unknown stream types and it
holds it until the first byte is
readable this has an interesting
implication on the structure of the
document which is that push is now more
or less separable push streams are just
another unidirectional stream type that
you don't have to support and if you
receive you're never gonna get one
anyway if you don't send max push ID
greater than zero you don't have to
understand max push ID frames or
generate them if you don't support push
priority explicitly has pushed out
something that can be prioritized but if
there are never any push IDs you don't
have to care about that combination of
bits we have a ton we removed a setting
that said I support push or I don't if
we add that back-end as a master switch
push starts looking kind of like an
extension like any other extension which
is kind of a nice property for the
protocol to have so if we want to add
the setting back even if we don't I
think this is where push stands in HUP
over quick and past that when I first
did the slide deck there were no other
non non editorial non parked non quick
v2 issues in the HCP of a quick spec
then I opened one this is I think just
left over we missed something so quick
says for 0tt if the server accepts zero
rqt data the server must not reduce or
reduce any limits or alter any values
that might cause the client to
accidentally violate its true settings
when you finally get the transport
parameters that's very sensible its GP
over quick actually has what we decided
way way back in the Tokyo interim and
then later decided was a bad idea and
the transport which says the server will
permit the client to violate its
settings temporarily until it knows the
real settings and then the client has to
retroactively Li comply that gets really
ugly with things like Q pack where you
can remember that the allowed table size
used to be 64 K so you say all right I'm
going to use 56 K of that stuff at 32 K
cookie and they're send a request using
that cookie and then you see the
settings frame and find out you're
allowed 4 K what do you do at that point
you can't you can't reduce the table
without evicting the value for a stream
that's already in flight and you could
kill the request but then you kind of
missed the point of zero TT
and I think the right solution here is
we got it right in transport and we just
missed updating the HTTP dock but that
has some architectural implications
which means if we were to make HTTP
match the transports requirements now
you have to ask HTP about a particular
0tt ticket
whether you're allowed to accept zero TT
on that and that is also kind of painful
so I think the question to the working
group is which type of ugly do we prefer
and I'll note that the server already
has to dig out the old HTTP settings to
figure out if the client is violating
the old ones and to distinguish between
malicious versus confused Eric rajala
and they fight the premise a quick is
tight integration between the layers and
so like wall it is like disgusting Oh
like it seems like that's the disgusting
we decided to mean like like it I think
I suppose this is him things I know I
know I know he's like things everything
should we tell the bottom but I mean
like you know our philosophy I think is
to have tight integration and so when we
discover a new point is that integration
that's like that's like that's let's go
with that faucet feed relay it most we
have to unless is are really good reason
as opposed to like a new piece of like
Cronus that we haven't like previously
like does I do accept but I mean I don't
feel strongly about that do my instincts
I suppose I think are I completely agree
with that as well
getting flow control right and other
components right it's like hard enough
in its own we don't want more edge cases
okay I hear unanimous let's do ugly and
make the layers match great so once I
fixed that we will be back to there are
zero actual functional issues and open
against the dock so please implement and
find the rest because I know they're not
all going okay thank you Mike you leave
the pink box
so it's 1143 we've got recovery we want
to talk about forward planning and if we
have time Marcus has some updates on the
spin bit
I don't know if we're gonna get to
Marcus but we'll try it depends on how
much people want to chat and if you it
can you do five minutes gold I want gold
if if you can just limit yourself to
five I think so there are a few
editorial issues open for recovery but I
tried to pick out some of the non
editorial ones that I would like to
resolve at some point before v1 they
don't need to be resolved today but at
least start thinking about them next
slide so this one hopefully we can
resolve right now the earlier transmit
threshold is currently one quarter and
the dock that actually followers I
believe the at least initial Linux
implementation I don't know if that I'm
still using one quarter for early
retransmit on the other hand in the
other spots in the dock we recommend 1/8
of an RTT of Ray during threshold so the
inconsistency is a ugly and B I have
data in map RG tomorrow that indicates
probably 1/8 is a better number for
quick anyway so my proposal would be to
make both of them 1/8 until we have some
more data both for consistency and
sanity and that also allows us to use a
more rack like logic and combine the
early retransmit timer in with the
time-based lost attention more cleanly
gordy fires to very quickly we talked
about this in TCP an where the
mechanisms to use with TCP is it not
better just do the discussion in one
place and and be over with it
or do we want to talk about congestion
control separately and recovery
separately for the two things and just
used to meeting slots Janet July you
could certainly discuss this in PCM also
just to be clear I think it's we are
building our own mechanism quick is
building its own mechanisms using TCP
ones as informative it's not it's on it
so it's these are basically similar but
not the same mechanisms
sure and that has big issues I think
that we really really need to delve into
so this this makes it complicated when
we really don't know what we're doing
with TCP even and then we start doing it
account here but um I'm don't take up
time but it's just hard to do this so
the proposal isn't to do this now and
when you say more data you mean before
we ship the final product right yes and
then if people come up with data in
three months or six months then you know
we can of course reevaluate this with
more data but right now we don't all the
data I have says eight one eight seems
fine so I think one does not object I
will I will do that and close us next
issue
max data before sending an act this is
actually kind of important this came up
with the ecn conversations the current
text attempts to be a little bit more
general than the current than the
default TCP implementations and that it
allows you to send acts less frequently
than every two packets and a lot of
networks this is an excellent
optimization and decreases the ACT low
rate like very substantially
experimental evidence shows that this
can be very valuable
however reno is also the documented
congestion controller and reno is act
clocked and so you will end up with
slower slow start growth and a few other
issues if you use reno and only acts a
every 20 or 40 packets and so i think we
need to kind of reconcile those two
things of you know if we're gonna
recommend we know we need to have
reasonable default acknowledgment
behavior and the proposal that gentleman
came up with was to send a transport
pram indicating the sender gets to
indicate how many bytes the pier should
receive retransmit oval bytes before
sending an acknowledgment and so the
default would be tcp style maybe like 20
400 bytes or two packets which every one
we decide this is a quick question and
agreeable coins that appropriate back
accounting because this trick is the
video confusing to me if you use if you
use appropriate ibaka by Counting
this should be okay this is then the
popping on them so this isn't really as
much about appropriate by counting as it
is about the fact that right now the doc
literally says as long as you
acknowledge you adhere to your delayed
act timer of whatever you say it's going
to be which defaults to 25 milliseconds
you can act as infrequently as you want
there's just no prescription whatsoever
about say asking every two packets or at
packing effort after every n bytes and
so I'm proposing adding that back in but
how Island appear to specify what they
want the receivers behavior to be
because for some concession control
algorithms PCC and BB are for example
it's completely fine to send an
acknowledgment say like after every 10
or 20 packets and for things like Reno
tends not to work as well so that makes
sense do you have any clarification
texting the draft I think I need to
understand more clearly we are running
out of time
it's okay these are the two most
important issues okay okay sure we're
okay that generally anger Yoshi I think
this might help you understand the
difference quick does not require you to
act after every two packets so you could
actually act once every half hour didi
if you want so the main point here is to
allow the sender to compensate for that
in its controller by saying this is I
can't really compensate so you must send
acknowledgments every two packets or
something like that so this is really
like the sender string the receiver how
frequently it it needs acknowledgments
back from the receiver based on bytes
Marcus and then Praveen in the record
enclose the cue out of necessity Marcus
- system is these bytes of packets we
discussed both on the issue
I think we're leaning towards bytes at
the moment okay I will join that
discussion then okay okay all right so
so because of appropriate by Counting we
don't really need an act every two
packets we just need an
immediate act if you will process at
least two packets in the current batch
so we can still do stretch acting like
if there's bulk data flow and you got
like hundred packets you can still send
one immediate have you don't need to
send fifty acts and I think that's still
good enough so that's why we should mind
it that you should generate an ACK at
least every two packets but it could be
more right the proposal would be to add
text actually that allows you to if for
example you can you do do you receive a
message in such 40 packets out of the
deal idiot I don't think I understood
that very well but I think I'm running
out of time so I can I'll follow up on
the issue or are in line with you okay
thank you very much okay I've left a
sliver of time here at the end so we can
talk about the future so planning for
future activity than working group we
have a September interim planned in New
York City it's on the website
registration is going to close in three
1/2 weeks if you haven't registered yet
please do so very soon it is I hope
we're not going to be space constrained
it's the same size of venue
approximately as we've had before and
the number of people coming has been
falling so that's hopefully we'll be
okay we're gonna do an interrupt
beforehand as we always do and we're
gonna need to figure out the scope of
that Interop work so we're gonna need a
Sept 7th implementation target are you
sure okay cuz website says six we need
update the website then we need somebody
to own driving that definition is
anybody willing to do that mum Thompson
I proposed the same one that we had last
time because what it says is draft draft
thirteen with a couple of tweaks
unfortunately and please please PLEASE
HTTP so HQ yeah more emphasis on HQ so
we did we did thirteen plus fourteen
ninety eight editors so the so whether
you
14 or not you propose we just we we just
go without like a like patch applied
version okay unless you want to produce
a 14 that happens to have 14 19 in it
nothing else so we could potentially do
1498 and nothing more in it in the new
revision if people said on slack I guess
I guess what I propose is something with
just semantically come on to that I'll
leave it to the editors to sort out what
the how its instructed then if we get
all of the changes to retry and I think
might be a reasonable thing to do that
yeah well that that would be the nice
thing about that is a bolt-on so if you
don't do it it'd be fine okay I can help
you update that we can take this to the
wiki and enter the list if necessary so
talking to Lars talking to Spencer
talking to the editors we think we're
getting close to done and that's a
message that we want to send to the
working group very clearly you know
we're are chartered milestones are
November there still seems to be an
intent that we want to try and meet
those milestones in in in spirit at
least we may of course come across
issues we can't resolve by then or have
further discussions but there still
seems to be an intent to try and ship it
on schedule so if you haven't started
reviewing the documents now would be an
excellent time you know we anticipate
the editors are gonna do not only be
able to share a number of issues to
resolve as you heard we also have a fair
amount of that a trail work to do
they're gonna try and make the documents
more reader friendly so so don't feel
like you need to go in and pick apart
the grammar or the spelling or anything
but in terms of what the documents
contain or don't contain please start
looking at that with the eye that we're
gonna be finishing pretty soon you know
we had one big change as a result of
previous meetings with a stream zero
work and we've incorporated that's good
I think that it's it's fair to
characterize it's to be progressively
harder to make a big change as we move
down the road towards completing so so
please do keep that in mind I think we
talked briefly before we're talking
about shipping the base drafts we're
talking about shipping the OP straps
possibly at the same time or at least
that's the default if
we want to vary that we need to come to
some agreement about it it doesn't sound
like we have that easily yet we have the
invariance draft as well which will
probably do a slight refresh on but
otherwise I think it's gonna stay the
same those are all ship at the same time
the other elephant in the room is the
spin bit which is probably why Brian's
standing up if all goes to plan Bangkok
is working we're going to make that
decision you know we said before we need
an experience that it demonstrates it's
useful in managing operating networks so
if you are gathering that data please
bring it to the working group ideally
before Bangkok it gives people time to a
Viton to look at that data and get
comfortable with it and and feel free to
talk about in a working group list if
you want to coordinate with other folks
but I don't think we're gonna be
delaying last call if we don't have that
kind of data this is a decision we need
to make to ship may I make a friendly
suggestion here sure so we've taken in
the past um information about to spend
that off the interim agendas just so
there's no you know perception that you
know you have to like actually addressed
a lot order to do this noticed a lot of
the people who are doing sort of core
work on the spin bit or at the interims
anyway um so maybe we should revisit
that for New York so we excuse me
because we blew the schedule today so I
don't really have a time to talk about
it and like I'm trying to talk about it
with a large part of working groups
would seem to be useful before we spring
it in Bangkok we've kept it out of the
interims mostly so that it doesn't
consume too much of that time that we
have otherwise used when we're done with
time consumption at this point right so
sorry I think we're done with time
consumption I hope so also practically
it becomes very hard to find a venue of
all the people for all the people who
might be interested in that discussion
we already have problems with finding
venues that would make it much worse I
anticipate carving off a very healthy
amount of time in Bangkok and probably
even holding a side meeting beforehand
to prep everybody and get some
discussions going alright ai-ai-ai-aight
will miss you guys in Bangkok that's
kind of unfortunate that that's sad to
hear Brian if we can have a controlled
discussion in September that somehow
moves us towards having a more
successful conversation in Bangkok
I'm
into talking about it I just I have
concerns so we've also you know if we
finished up in Bangkok the idea is we go
to working group last call then wgl see
made collect some issues we need to
discuss
IETF last call if it happens in a timely
fashion may collect some issues we need
to discuss so we may need an early 2019
interim
larva I've discussed this and we think
what we're going to do is start putting
together the arrangements for such an
interim you know January or February
something like that but not actually
pull the trigger on it and and say we're
going to do it until after Bangkok so we
know if we need it we don't know when to
waste people's time but just to give you
a heads up so that's the way we're
thinking we've been doing this pace of
having one interim between each major
ITF and if we do that it's going to be
in Europe Asia because the next ones in
the u.s. any questions about that okay
one other thing that's come up we have
two minutes left is the name of quick
itself from what we've observed still
causes confusion amongst implementer is
amongst people who are writing about it
in the press potential users and this
has been bothering us for a while
because there's quick google quick and
ITF quick and we say gee quick and quick
but we don't do consistently in people
outside of this room don't use it at all
talking through this changing the name
of quick at this stage doesn't seem
realistic I mean after all we have
really nice stickers so instead remember
community made of what we think is a
very good suggestion is to maybe when we
ship this thing when we ship it will
call it quick version - with the idea
that Google's verse no quick was version
one so I'm not going to open this up to
a working group decision I almost
consider this an editorial issue I
wanted to give a people heads up about
that if it gives you heartburn or you
have concerns come and talk to Lars and
I just a little bit of comparison from
acne we discuss we had the same
discussion about renaming because we had
let's encrypt acne and ietf acne and
they were originally available for a
long time
and what
has ended up happening even though the
working group decided to do nothing was
that the industry is calling IETF Acme
v2 so calling anyway
yeah okay thanks so that also has
another implication we've had this
background discussion about quick
version to what the next thing is after
you know quick for HTTP obviously that
would become quick version 3 or
something else but since we're now
talking about getting to the end of this
work those sorts of conversations become
more in scope and we should start
talking about what the thing after we
ship quick version I was about to say 1
version 2 is going to be so please talk
amongst yourselves talk to Lars and I
and we'll start figuring out what that
next phase of work might look like I
think we're done for today so hopefully
we'll see a good number of you in New
York City in September and then of
course we'll see everyone in Bangkok
thank you
oh and and Marcus
so Marcus had slides on the spin that we
didn't get to those they were kind of
requests to the last minute Marcus do
you want to use the room to maybe give a
presentation for those who are
interested because it's lunchtime or
should you want to just send the slides
of the list any preferences I'm sorry
where's Marcus there I'm sorry I'm
that's you that's why you look so
confused
yeah you want the rim