we basically have two three drafts that
are not yet completed one is STP
examples which we think we're pretty
much ready to go s after this but we
don't really need to talk about we have
IP handling where we have this one issue
about hem DNS names for most candidates
and security our architecture document
we have a couple of pyaara pyaara later
than that and so sorry so most of the
PRS got merged which was good so there's
that there are two that are outstanding
which is delicious because that means we
could almost be done but I guess so we'd
like to start off with the IP handling
stuff but before we get there the whole
plan here right is to get it done at
this point we need to pick this thing up
and get it across the finish line and we
need your help so I think we're in the
process of doing that and we're
cautiously optimistic that we can
actually do that all right I think with
that I think we have what Justin is
gonna be up one thing more about getting
finished I I want to note that one
outstanding document before get started
is topic in the working group which is
the document and that's hyacinth
reviewed comments is that right it would
really be good if people comments or
cetera or reads and comments and gets
this help getting this done because
that's otherwise it's gonna be the last
document out so noted Thanks
all right just
and I'm Justin Uberti from Google UN
from Apple's gonna join me up here to
talk about this all right so I'd be
handling let's start by sort of
recapping like what a point of this
draft is and the goal here was to you
know take four obscure web pages
previously we gave out all ice
candidates and this created some
problems the two most specific problems
were that by giving out every single
sort I address that the I station and
find this and a lot of people who are
blind behind VPNs to have their public
eyes be address identified this was not
good
in addition not giving out all the set
of addresses allowed more fingerprinting
you know and we'll get to more about
this later but these are the two main
things we're trying to address with this
draft and in addition to solving these
problems we also learn to maintain the
ability to actually establish direct
peer-to-peer connections and why do we
care about our trailer pages being able
to able to establish peer connections
well it turns out that this is actually
a very frequently use functionality
there there's actually five times as
many page loads in Chrome you did a
channels as use actually RTC web for
audio and video and this traffic has
been growing exponentially over 400% you
every year is actually starting to make
a blip on me compared to over HTTP
traffic data channels I started actually
the traffic theory is that starting to
become actually comparable all on its
way to becoming humble so like this
actually big deal we don't want to
unlike cut this thing off it's a very
promising emergent technology we want to
find some way of having your cake and
eating you - all right so we solved the
first problem with the first version of
this draft and this was basically saying
that we what page doesn't have consent
it should only be able to access the
public IP is that the website would
normally see and so this was done by
basically determining what interface
will be used to talk to the website and
only giving out the IPS associated with
the adapter that would be used you know
the same way that we used to touch from
the website over HTTP using that for
actual web RTC traffic and so what we
ended up doing was we gave out just that
one public IP but we all
gave out its associated private IP and
so we considered this an acceptable
trade-off you know because we wanted to
make sure we could allow these direct
connections we thought that the actual
IP before information given out was
fairly minimal I wasn't really
identifying and overall the you know the
cutting off the ability to have direct
connections you know seemed like a
pretty big downside however like that we
knew there are some cases that you know
the IP for adjusters might actually
contain valuable information there are
some efforts going on to try to reduce
the number of fingerprinting surfaces
you know on the web and in doing some
enumeration of what people are actually
doing with WebRTC and analysis of Chrome
stats show that there is a non-trivial
number of pages that basically create a
peer connection get addresses and then
do nothing else and even after we
implanted this solution for problem 1 so
what to do turn it over to un ok so in
Safari we went to our team and basically
they said there's one rule you can send
anything but it's already public but if
it's private please do not send it so we
decided to use what free by default what
do you when get you the media is on and
this it's better to ship something
than nothing so and some people were
happy so it was already good still we we
broke some existing applications that
are running you know the browsers we got
something back we had some pretty good
feedback actually from things like web
torrent where they do not really care
maybe no kind of okay but still there
are some applications like games where
latency is important so turn is not very
good and there are also some apps where
that are like sending a massive amount
of data between devices and we're turn
might be too expensive or very small
apps where turn is also is already too
expensive so
[Music]
okay so we looked at muted it and said
hey why not choose mdns so when you
gather Eiskant days you have host
candidates with ipv4 addresses so why
not generate a new ID register it for n
DNS and then replace in the field V IP
address with this new ID that's what we
did we implemented it into Safari behind
the flag so it's available you can
activate it and play with it it's not
100% well implemented so it could be
optimized but still it's available you
can play with it and then the good thing
is that we're able to get some early
experiments the good thing is that it's
working very well as expected on
unmannered networks meaning like small
offices networks home like if you play a
game maybe it's at home and not at work
so maybe maybe there it will almost get
everything working it's really it's
adding some potential latency you to
immunise resolution to connection setup
it's not I don't think it's a big deal
but still it's something that you should
be noted it does not always work on
enterprise networks that's for sure so
it's not like full solution some
networks will disable multicast if
you're not on the same network segment
then mdns will probably not work as as
well I should note that only add that
expects direct host to host connection
working in an enterprise network might
face some issues anyway because you have
no guarantee so you need to have anyway
some of a solution like turn servers
like something like that that will allow
you to actually ensure that you will
connect the people you actually want but
still
behind the flag if you if you enabled it
to test it right now when you're doing
the ice candidate presentation are you
presenting the mdns and a public IP or
just mdns so what we're doing is that in
case getusermedia news media access is
granted we do not use Indian as we
submit via private IP addresses right
before when we get you access is not
granted no consent we're just sending in
DMS candidates okay that's useful for
following this analysis because okay it
means that in this case there was no
public IP and therefore no possibility
of using a turn server for the current
set of tests you're giving their results
from yes so what's it to get back to
just a me okay so to try to you know
come up with the best possible solution
that gets the mineral sort privacy
impact and the maximal my code of
connectivity you know the thing we sort
of came up with was to use mdns to hide
private addresses I any a v4 v6
addresses that are public and how I
determine that's public is like
something we can talk about on a later
slide give this out because that's on
the website to see anyway and then the
nice sort of thing about this solution
would be that as i p v6 deployment
proceeds the need to rely on MDM DNS
goes away and so you can see from the
diagram here kind of what would happen
that you have this client and it's
multihomed
it's got you know cell interface WN it's
got Wi-Fi interface which has both v4
and v6 the v4 address is your typical
mattad before that gets hidden and is
covered by the this thing work yes the M
DNS name the v6 address is public that's
here and then the actual public you know
server reflexive address doesn't launch
from the stun server is also given out
you can see that the local address here
is emitted from the are ever so this is
what we propose you know is the sort of
sweet spot
in terms of what we can make work today
yep sometimes just to clarify the v6
address you determine that it is
actually public by observing it as a
reflexive candidate so we'll get to
exactly how that works later but that's
the I think the way you can actually do
that is by actually having stun over
ipv6 now that has his own set of
complications compared to later but like
the seem safe so it just made history
clarify first so so you're exposing you
had four dresses you're exposing three
candidates is the idea that that UID D
references to both IP addresses in some
way um I think she won't speak to us
specifically usually what happens is
that if you resolve and if you have
grown from ipv4 and ipv6 family in that
case you instead had one new ID / / /
Canada you would not even expose now
instead of having it's like like what is
that saying for three kiddos why don't
y'all for which to run course behind a
one who's wrong one course by one I do
huh no their show you have plenty
situations with it where you'd have
addresses right um I guess I just don't
understand why like I also read in your
draft you said that you only advertise
one MBS for both IP through firm V sex
so like Isis I'd have one candidate per
address right yes
Thompson I think the I think this is a
good observation it's very simple to say
that I'm gonna buy into this address and
then do whatever is necessary for this I
think this is just an optimization on
their front I don't I don't think it
actually changes the the the nature of
this at all to use the the same label
all same mdns address to refer to
multiple host candidates I mean that's
it's it's just an optimization if you
can solve em DMS then you're good I mean
the whole reason we give out the I could
be six at all is just in case where I
mean us does not work no III remove that
but I guess what I'm saying is that you
know these are some priorities faces and
so and so and so so gluing oh the glue
all these sort of private objects
together into one thing here just going
to glue the e46 with the Wi-Fi address
but yes I that is true that they would
have different priorities somebody I'd
also like to point out that there are
will be cases where the ipv6 address has
a different scope especially on wired
interfaces so you may be able to use em
DNS and have a different scope then you
would have the public ipv6 address so
you may be getting a different ipv6
address than this ipv6 address because
it reflects a different ipv6 scope so I
think having a separate UUID if you want
to use a UID to front that separate
scope is a good idea so just because it
would be a separate new idea for v4 and
v6 f per UID this per address so I was
gonna say that's that's probably
necessary in this case because of the
way that we do that the pairing up and
the prioritization and all those things
I'd missed that point and that's that's
a really good point John thanks yeah the
ice spec does say that if you have a
name and a candidate you only take one
address from it preferring v6 if there's
both but you never take more than one
address for a candidate by name so yeah
we need to have a different different UI
deeper address you want to
right and so you need to make some
changes in the meal too which is Dean
asked not mes video actually it's a
superset so I think this is okay I
looked into this and I was a little
concerned about the use of these labels
but we kind of get away with that mdns
supports more labels than names can
express so we'll have to be a little bit
careful about the soyoung's all the
characters in terms of privacy the
lifetime of their names could be tied to
a page for instance beef right nice time
I should damn well I'm sorry but our
origin would be what would be what I
would recommend but I wouldn't I
wouldn't do anything special to retain
stability over multiple uses that's
double gate origin yeah yep actually we
had we had this discussion and yeah it's
tricky yeah we decide on this later so
my hope is kind of get three of the
stuff that is mostly not confident and
controversial first and that we can get
to the tricky stuff okay so I'd like to
try to
sense of given you know the detergency
to get across the finish line as our
cherish reminded us earlier you know is
this a path that we can agree to move
forward with so your choice would like
you to amend this consensus goal and
that is to change IP handling documents
to documents because we believe that
what's in one of the documents is in
fact quite well understood where some of
this is still being worked out on the
floor and that they don't necessarily
need to appear at the same time and
having some IP handling document would
allow you to move forward with the
security architecture and get the the
baseline covered and then bring the mdns
stuff along will keep the working group
open to handle it but not gate on it yes
I'm not in Thompson I think that's my
preferred approach for this if we can
find a way to just adjust the IP
handling document so that it doesn't add
this this new stuff then and describe
some modes and maybe recommends the
safer option of the set and then we can
later on update it with the new things
with I think that the base thing would
be requiring a type II handling is to
note that other modes may be published
right and make this the first of the new
modes right and then once the new mode
is published we can decide as we're
processing it whether it becomes the
preferred mode or not in the meantime
we'll have ones with which we have a
fair amount of experimentation and
experience available for the community
and we can cross the finish line while
the new modes are being experimented
with and this hybrid mode in particular
see some real deployment to get right
because this is this is a in this is now
on the critical path and there's a lot
of other things that are very very very
close to finished if we put another
thing on that critical path right now I
think some people might get stabbed
right cluster 238 can go if we if we
release IP handling and note in IP
handling that more modes will be
published and keep working on this as a
new mode that makes sense but I think we
also will probably need to amend the
problem statement
say we are been trying to solve this
sounds good okay yeah and we can put in
the problem statement that new modes are
being developed to solve that problem
sounds good yeah I guess I would um III
was the perfect lovely informative
reference to this exact raft that's um
say you know losing wealthy including
this drive here I guess I can imagine
and I do this home but on you know like
in terms of practical matter on like
blocking these documents were a lot
making this will not make a change in
the policy change any faster here is
Jabbar scribe do I understand correctly
that the current default mode would
remain as of draft version oh nine for
now it sounds like what is being
recommended by the chairs is that the
current IP handling draft would not
change adding additional modes or change
its default but that a new mode could
change the default on publication sure
essentially just adding some text in the
problem statement section to say there
are other modes that could come along we
can point you this document
informatively which me you ain't get
along faster someone said this already
but the intention would be to publish
the new mode as something outside of
this working group would be for one work
but IP handling could go and we could
start cluster 2:38 processing without
this since the reference to this would
be informative normative but the new
draft would still be on the standards
track when published and therefore could
update the default mode okay and we
would be open for that last time that's
a different question I think it probably
would be but the the critical thing is
getting the documents out if they're
working group has to stay open to
publish this then your your chairs will
be willing to do that okay you can have
more crows then yes I am we're hoping to
make them ever smaller
cuter as time gets on this is dJG so the
idea that we're going to try to get this
out the door with the default mode being
the one that leads to private addresses
just by adding text that says we are
going to add a new mode later or new
roads may be added later does make me
nervous as someone who would like to see
this thing published so I am concerned
that that what we're doing is we're
basically saying here's the way you do
it not even mentioning what the privacy
implications are and something will come
along later and then the we lose steam
we do know what the privacy implications
are in a document just just declared and
and say this is a problem with the
current specification I mean I think we
would say that this is not yet solving
the specification and who knows maybe
define I mean guess is practically
speaking like each browser now has made
its decision of what it's going to do so
I don't think this will actually change
you know any actual implementations
everyone who is involved here is kind of
at the mic or in line or standing up
here and so my way he will be implanting
the new draft and think as soon as you
know we actually have experimental
details Bernard I'm open Microsoft I
just want to point out one little thing
which is we have had a it's an issue
that probably will be a PR soon for a
change in the web IDL to address to make
it capable of carrying those in DNS
names and we were willing to take it
because people hadn't implemented that
thing yet and I'm kind of a little
scared that they'll implement the old
one and then we'll have an argument
about changing it it could be a little
nasty so it's okay if you do the new
thing but please do it quickly because
if this stays as it is
it'll probably be a web IDL argument
about it well not for me
yeah and I think I mean well I would say
is you know you know we're interested in
this mode like understand how that works
I think you put you right to accurately
which is some serious it works in some
cells many more interestin scene
measurements about like how eleven
there's two things occur which i suspect
you are as well and that you know but
that like having these documents tough
negotiator queue for a year and a half
while you buy eight those questions or
whatever it is is not gonna like that's
not gonna make it's not gonna make us
like more aggressive babbling about uh
you know i think there's a lot it's hard
to make this call because there's a lot
of unknowns we don't know about this
like we have questions about like does
just enabling this allow you to do DDoS
attacks on the multicast traffic inside
the enterprise just by creating a lot of
these and what are sort of the rates and
stuff of that how well does it actually
work in enterprise i mean the case where
this tends the the way you described
where it works and doesn't work i agree
in fact i think it may be even slightly
better than as you described it doesn't
work in some large enterprises but not
in lots right it's uh those are of
course exactly some of the places this
is most valuable in the home residential
in that situation it didn't matter that
you hair pin through the GNAT anyway it
wasn't like you went across the land
because the address filtering was such
that you could hair pin on the map
versus having to go to a tremor so i
think we start looking at some of those
statistics now the thing I'm interested
in about at this is this is not just
strictly a security improvement it makes
a bunch of security much worse and what
it makes much worse is it now forces a
whole bunch of traffic that didn't use
to have to go through middle boxes to go
up through middle boxes that are
typically run by somebody who's not
really fully trusted by the end users in
these cases and anytime that we start
taking traffic that could have remained
on a local network and not have to push
it through a place that's an awesome
place for law enforcement to intercept
it yeah it makes me a little queasy I
mean I it's this is not a win-win a
situation there's a lot of things to to
think about the the trade-offs on on
which way that you end up with best
security
you may be very sick so to return to the
Consensus call which has been up here
for for a number of moments I'm gonna
take three hums the first is do you
think you understand the problem okay
I'll move up to hybrid solution so we're
gonna ask do you think you understand
the problem we're then gonna ask if you
can live with this being in a separate
document and if you cannot live with
this being in a separate document
because I think that if it's in a
separate document we can progress it
after we've gotten some of this
experimentation in front of the working
group if it has to be in this document
we'll move forward a different way but
what we really want to know is whether
or not you can live with this being in a
separate document or not so anybody have
questions on the hums before we take the
hummus I think if you think we shouldn't
do this at all that is it shouldn't even
be in a separate document you should be
at the mic you want to tell us that okay
sure I mean I think that we will need to
see a lot more of the details on this
before the working group comes to
consensus about this is awesome or what
it is not to us tonight so I think the
worst-case scenario here is we put it
into a separate document that goes out
with a very limited applicability
statement or never goes out but of
course I thought that I think that
putting it into another document is no
guarantee that we're actually what
happens right the working group will
come to whatever consensus it comes on
on whether it goes in the same document
or a different document there's a lot of
work that needs to be done before we're
done with this and it will need working
group consensus yes it ate I think just
before we clean for document exceptions
now or more something for separation the
three are I heard with the homes work
okay the home - yes we can live with it
being in a separate document comes
through then we will talk about
accepting
the draft as a working group draft okay
Ronnie yeah you have to go to the things
we have remote participants even but you
said that the reference for both in the
main document which makes it like so we
can put a reference in the main document
if in that reference doesn't even have
to be an accepted working group draft to
say people are working on it for example
over here in case people read me is the
other way I will be humming in favor of
accepting as a working group document
right like I think that was almost
inevitable that it'll get that looks
across this nightmare if we come to it
so any more hum questions before we take
the Hummels hum now if you think you
understand the problem I'm relieved if
it was dead quite at that point though I
would be like you're gonna have to bring
me a live crow at this point that
picture is not cutting it okay hum now
if you can live with us separating this
document out from IP handling how now if
you cannot live with that solution okay
I think that what we're gonna do then is
okay I heard the hums as enough people
understood the question to go forward
with a working group call for consensus
on separating or not separating and then
the strong consensus for separating the
document out of IP handling so I'd like
to propose we adopt this as a working
group item as soon as we can sort out
milestones with our 80s and now could
you take a hum on this point all in
favor of adopting the draft is a working
group draft how now is there anyone
opposed to adopting this is a working
group breath um now okay so it is
adopted as a working group draft we work
with the ADA to add a work item and the
schedule of CRO consumption thank you
very much what is 2.4 the minutes that I
guess
Justin's gonna update the IP handling
document to update the problem statement
I have a forward reference an
informative for reference okay
I think you had something beyond
consensus to try it about how much time
you have I think I will sir note there
are many issues as things that we can
you know think about you won't have them
at each our discussion I'm guess I have
two three minutes at most
okay okay so one of the things I
mentioned earlier was what to do about
ipv6 addresses that are not public so
first of all to even determine if a v6
addresses public and you need to hit a
stun server to see if you get that
reflected back to you this is problem
and this can occur for nat64 addresses
where you have basically an ad which is
a v4 and then you get a v6 address
that's only usable behind that net in
order to figure this out you need a stun
server that can basically receive v6
traffic I am not aware oh they're very
few of these today so we would basically
be asking digital applications to be
deploying v6 down servers and then even
once we have this then if you are behind
that six four you won't be able to use
that v6 to actually give a direct
connection so we'll do some experiments
here will understand if this is a big
issue you know one of the options could
be we just always give our v6 a--'s and
well one of the most coolers give our v6
is regardless of whether they're
considered to be public or not just has
some you know some questions for privacy
but since we're not coming out before is
it still a move in the right direction I
want to see what the experiment show how
low this gem I'll notice this problem is
not unique to be for physics it also
occurs with before who can't tell from
an address whether it's private enough
or you can tell from some others is that
they are private that if if you address
this not in those ranges no absolutely I
mean yeah fortress none before is for
all deployed very I agreed to be safety
you need to use stun it also means that
no application that doesn't have turn
service will work whatsoever translates
as sensitive stone service button right
even if the Euro correspondent has a
public IP right Thompson I think we're
if we if we're judging is based on on
the principles that we've established
then yeah too bad if it's not if this is
not the address that the site is seeing
as well probably the site is seeing is a
matter of communication with it then why
are we giving this hell you know we
could take a very sort of hardline
position on this or if we see that you
know it has like a 75 percent impact on
my kitchen all traffic then we might we
might take a more compromising position
like a English you mission now let's get
painted in by concerns okay I'm
wondering why the principal decision is
not the one to take you I mean do you
think we'd say that we would lean toward
the principal decision but like we would
probably want to see what the impact of
making said principal decision would be
so I don't think what Paul just said is
entirely correct mainly if your
counterparty knows they have a public IP
address ipv6 address they can advertise
it just want to talk to them even with
v6 wait it won't work so like if there
are server first as well will work is
two clients right no clients right that
you don't deploy Stein silver in your
address or public key still can connect
you see no the small this year and I
guess change
you know the Nandina sadistic surround
the one second when are you ever going
to do it registration does not take that
much time it's so nicely the resolution
that might take some time
registration requires that you have the
dye just on the network and and then
wait for a while to see if anyone
they'll sponsor we're testing we there's
no 1 second delay for a connection setup
that's interesting
the second thing is that you know so for
the first connection you might have a
small delay in solutions we we had like
200 millisecond delay it's highly
depends if you want Wi-Fi or not if you
are like packet loss so we might be
about to measure to make measurements
here to precise you know yeah I don't
think you need to worry about this one
these are extremely high entropy values
the chance of a collision is basically a
catalyst if she's a packet wasn't the
resolution is is is a concern yes I
agree but the concern that Harold has
with result with respect to advertising
your name do you have to check that
someone else has it I wouldn't bother
checking in this case so what they're
saying is that you can get away with
breaking the protocol for NDMS that will
be interesting to see we gain by the
other working group so so if people are
uncomfortable with that we can go talk
today and SSD and and talk about having
an exception an exception carved out for
that I think that that's a perfectly
reasonable thing to do so again that's
not a big concern contest I it gets a
little bit more complicated when the
address went out through multiple
interfaces and then the SD proxies
forwarded them back to the other things
this just it gets more
located that's all I'm saying I'm soon
like like regularly on MDS when the bugs
is your printers show up on multiple
networks when you have a complex
mystical technology some different
addresses moving the same DNS name will
resolve two different addresses
depending on which interface you take it
on but no I mean like you're gonna
what's gonna happen is you're gonna pick
you're going to advertise the you take
the host candidate and you're stuffing
them the MS record that's what you
broadcast what happens is that
inappropriate address appears on
multiple networks but it's the same
address all those networks because
you're gonna generate a new horse
candidate for your new MV s entry for
each choice candidate and so what will
happen is like it'd be just like
ordinary ice which is say if you make a
pile of addresses none of which you can
use on on but on that that shouldn't um
it's just goofy right um but it's like I
still I see Heron like you feeding this
way um I think that will happen is like
maybe you're gonna get a bunch of like
weird packets like networks praise you
like a bunch of packets like you don't
want the same address yeah news old man
um one clarifying question so this is
you need to stun server only for nat64
or are there other cases where you would
want to require a stun server because I
I'm not quite I don't have like all the
details for nat64 in my mind but I think
there are like other ways to detect that
you are on the net 64 out there metaphor
is the only case I know but I cannot
grant even I'm correct
you want to go into the next slide yes
you want talk to this one yeah so when
you have a single WebRTC connection
between two peers you can identify
whether they're running on the same
device by checking the latency of the
connection some might say it's fine
some might say that if you have two
pages with two iframes that our trackers
and you are trying to isolate these two
trackers that so that they do not state
which is actually what is implement in
severy then allowing these two Tigra
tracker iframes to know that they're
running in the same device and start to
use WebSocket to share stage cookies and
everything might be an issue so we are
actually investigating that the the
point where is should we document this
issue somewhere
is it an issue and if so what's the path
forward
I mean this is an issue there's a lot I
mean I guess I mean I'm you know I got I
feel like or worst nightmares about like
co-located code have now come true so
like the the it's a quaint tour in the
face of Specter it's can equate to worry
about like determining you're missing
the host team at this point in the game
perhaps if you're chrome you feel
differently but here people don't so you
come so I I'm we're also working on it
I'm more seriously they're just a lot of
ways to determine I think if you're like
on the same post um you service Lee if
not not poker solution or v6 but as far
as I can tell there's no clear solution
at all um unless um I mean maybe or
perhaps you can disable
seeing in like some context but imagine
like the common thing would be the two
parts like these two double key right
you're still gonna have the same mdns
problem on it's up to the browser to
decide which you I need to share with on
which contexts no no but no I I miss I'm
assuming user different you IDs but then
basically what I do is I take the you
know I take the - I I did I you know I
had to dive to two domains that I want
to see they're co-located in the double
keyed and I have both of exfiltrate the
addresses and then yeah I'm trying to
grab pretty call and like it works then
like I'm on basically the same machine
or I'm that same or in the same local
network so um so I I don't know I I tend
to think that like this is a Emmy it's
fine to put this stuff doesn't that be
handling document is innocent paragraph
but I don't think much else is gonna be
is it is use for what it's really open
research question so um before we're
gonna cut the line because we do have
one other presentation and I guess we
should float the idea maybe even having
a virtual in or something that's talked
about something's issues specifically
because I think we can go down a rabbit
hole on this one for a while since we
were trying to progress the document
should we just can we agree that we
should add the paragraphs of document
this issue and then we can resolve this
in the to be announced sequel absolutely
in a similar way that we identify and
w3c documents say a fingerprinting issue
I mean I think it's calling out this
issue is perfectly fine I mean but there
are so many ways you can track this like
as you the which way is up force sensor
on iPhones seem to be a high high risk
candidate let's convert over yeah no one
wants to kill the really high runner
ones so what about this one the question
here is I don't understand what the
solution would be for people like I
don't and how we solve this at all for
new v6 or before yeah you can have you
can ice my friends so one potential
solution is that's for party I friends
do not have in DNS if we're gonna allow
WebRTC connections like like where I'm
going here is the only Slough
- this is to add huge latency to our
real-time communication system that's
not really sure and then you can use
probability to actually measure whether
it's fake latency and so on
III don't have a good solution there
right now so so what's your take on
should we try to solve this it's not a
priority because it's true that there
are other issues but I think it should
be in the one map and maybe we'll find
some solutions maybe on our side when we
just disabled like when we are spaced in
Safari where we are very restrictive and
what we're hoping to do is to open the
door a little bit so we can open video
like just a little bit or a little bit
more not on iframes maybe a my friends
we have some granularity there that we
can play with since we I think that the
current proposal is that we will
document this issue in the IP handling
draft and then consider solutions in the
follow-on draft please indicate when
you're standing up at the mic line
whether you have any problem with us
documenting the issue because I think we
can postpone discussion of the solutions
till the discussion of the follow-on
draft if we have agreement that we're
documenting the issue my only point was
that sorry Neil told me is that I think
the RTT is actually not the biggest
problem I mean if you have like two
iframes being able to establish data
channel they can exchange whatever they
want I'm in Europe far worse with so if
you would like to document something
else a PR is welcome this is DJ G I'm
for documenting the issue I just wanted
to point out because it seemed like
there was some confusion and discussion
that this is a web RTC issue and not an
MD NS issue okay he's making sure that
we're all on the same page on that I
think we are on that page twenty one
final note one more in common choice I'd
mentioned that Mike if you can't
stablish a track connection will
typically fall back
hair pinning through that and in doing
some tests here I was surprised by how
infrequently hair printing actually
occurred even in today's internet on
some from popular nap products and you
need did you see the same thing yeah
working in local conditions personally
so but I my testing is irritating I hope
that as soon as we get there so you can
confer from that popular Google and
Apple Wi-Fi products may not support her
pending super well but anyway there are
the tests that will do will probably
bring some more concrete numbers on this
anyway
tax time so thanks both of you for the
presentation today and for agreeing to
move forward I think it's it's a good
thing to move forward with this in in
the way that we've described I think the
cherish will caucus offline with their
Area Director about having an intra
meeting as I think dkg pointed out just
making this afford reference as a
promise and losing steam is probably
problematic so trying to keep some of
the discussion going on the list and in
an interim meeting seems to us like a
valuable way to avoid that and we'll do
what we can to do so I think the next
speaker is crystal
okay so I did as to be the Directorate
review or obvious TP attribute which is
defined in this RT civil security
architecture document just to clarify
this is not my document I'm not the
author is the reason our period is is
because well I have indicated I'm
willing to help with STP issues and so
on but but before really starting to
write text there were some some issues
that I think we need to turn me on or to
make sure we have a common understanding
- not how to really write lower things
as also to make clear least this is not
generated general overview of the whole
document only the STP I attribute part
of it so if you have other issues you
know with the IDP and an identity
assertion in general they this is not a
time and place place for that
so this and also I'm not going the
review that I did
for example Martinez already created a
request in that I think the link is on
the mailing list is also I'm going to
show it in other presentations so there
are basically a couple of main issues
which I'm going to bring up here which i
think is is is what we need to agree on
and to make sure okay okay so basically
yeah but background I also said about
but the the Assumption here is because
this draft is foreign foreign as it's
written in this in this working group is
very web RTC specific but assumption
here is the best EP identity attribute
is a generic attribute which can be used
to carry identity Association also in
other environments not really the bar
can see specific and even if one pair is
of a party CN point the other pair may
not not be a but it could still use the
same identity assertion mechanism to do
so that's the assumption to have a
generic
attribute which can be used by anyone
supporting in an iid p assertion
mechanism so this is
one of the issues with which I raced in
this is that currently in WebRTC
the fingerprint is is used to create
this identity assertion one of the
question I raised is that do you have to
use the fingerprint always or could you
use also something else and the answer I
got
and now when I say answer here is this
discussion I had and I both people have
indicated on the list is it's not
something we have agreed on but but what
those who have provided input instead
from a protocol expect that you could
use something else than a fingerprint
it's outside the scope of our TC web
draft we're not going to document that
or make an instance but but but
basically the way for would be would be
to have some takes saying yeah you could
use something else but if you use
something else you need to write a draft
or some Scott specification describing
how you're gonna do it how hard a JSON
structure that you're gonna put into
this attribute it looks like and so on
because the the digestion structure
defining the document now contains the
fingerprint and the identity so if you
use something else you may need to
define adjacent structure which carries
this other thing it's already just a
clarifying question you have here in the
answer from a protocol perspective but
here what you mean in particular is this
usage of SDP is allowed to use other
information not J cept the protocol will
use other information but this SDP
identity may use other information
that's what you mean by protocol yes I
mean I'm not suggesting any changes to
chase or RDC baby that's a good con
about I should have made it clear I'm
not suggesting any changes to what we
have in J said or any RTC VapoRub a bar
can see specification this is pure pure
STP so to say this is about making sure
that the definition of the STP attribute
is consistent with other attributes and
all those things largely editorial what
Krista has actually done is highlight a
few places where there's a little hole
or two and that's been quite helpful but
other than that yeah don't change
anything we did change something by the
way but
that issue was which is interesting is
if you have a subsequent offer a server
actually the pair or even yourself
updates the identity and and I have one
example where this cause case we often
talk about this third party call can
cross and call transfers done just by
updating the STP so you have your
browser for example is communicating
with another pair and then you have a
call controller which is going to to
make a call transfer the only way it's
gonna do is to send you then this DP of
this new peer and obviously this new
pair is going to have another identity
so so you're gonna get an updated STP
and updated offer within you within your
identity again the the feedback here is
that you gain from our pure purko spur
sexy we we shouldn't we shouldn't
disallow this it's allowed however it
may not be supported by the receiver and
for example web RTC that's not allowed
to update the identity of appear so they
suggested way forward here is that you
say yeah you can do this for example
when you send us you can do it but also
to indicate that this is not something
that that anyone must report if the
receiver doesn't support it it doesn't
accept it it could for example not
accept the offer also or do something
else I mean we don't need to go exactly
into those details but I think there the
important thing here is that we're not
going to mandate endpoint to support it
but but the game it is allowed from our
from our protocol perspective well
that's yeah that's more or less the same
thing I mean you you're basing your
providing you you change your modifying
the existing identity by
moving their existing identity but it's
the same thing I hope Jason already says
that if you ever had yet it'd be all
subsequent offers your answers have to
contain the same identity so the web RTC
Martin Thompson sorry the WebRTC specs
are very clear on this point once you
have an identity for a Pierre you can't
go backwards from that point it has to
remain the same thereafter so any any
session description you receive from
that point onwards has to have the same
identity because we don't know how to do
anything else nothing else really makes
any sense if you want to have a
different identity make a new peer
connection and then first and actually
what I'm going to put in it you know it
takes about this is there's going to be
a section about modifying a session and
there is going to be a must you must
include identity and of course if even
if it's the same as previously not not
including it means that you're actually
removing it so so so of course if that's
what you want to do that's what you want
to do but if you want to keep the same
identity as previously then then you
must include it in this subsequent offer
right yeah I think a general policy I'm
in favor that's the general policy here
is what you do with identity is
effectively a policy decision about what
the security and it means in whatever
you're using application in WebRTC we
have very clear things of what that
policy is and other things they might
have different policies and different
rules and you know even the the call
that way of doing transfer is not
generally how it's done because of all
kinds of problems like this so it's not
like we're losing transfer in WebRTC or
anything but like the way most SPC's do
transfer will work fine with Park UCS
yeah I just wanted to bring it up
because unfortunately why I wanted a
whenever we talk about it it's very
often when people when we talk about
something and someone asked how does it
work it's third button so those were the
two actually the main I consider
technical issues or clarifications so
the way forward is and asaba indicated a
I'm willing to help with this for
example one of the things I didn't bring
up here what would I had in my review
was that we should also use this
template for for defining your SDP
attributes this if you read I mean
sending a mission offer or sending the
answer or modifying a session and so on
and so on and I'm now willing to help to
put a pull request regarding that
together but but I want to be spirit
things clarified because those things
affect what it takes there would it
would be ya know an everlasting was that
they'd be here's a link to this request
which which Martin already put together
I wish I understood has been known most
things there were some for example
related to day to day today to the a B
and F and so minor things yeah I'm good
for loads um so thank you for doing this
review and thank you for if you just
reload I think those are all great all
gone yeah there you go it's linking
interview and thank you for catching
these um um I guess I'm reluctant to
screw the structure at this point in the
game um I understand your willingness to
do it but it seems like it seems like
that's really kind of like gonna make
our lives harder um maybe there's
pacific points do you think maybe you
called out I'm really happy to add into
the document but I think having a baby
talks that we don't have to review like
seems like kind of mother away but IIIi
think I had a look at a document
currently there did attribute is defined
somewhere in a subsection level 3 or
level 4 so my yeah something like that
but my idea would be just to move that
into a separate main section and then of
course we have to add this sending an
issue of her answer and blah blah blah
but it's going to be very it's not going
to impact other parts or the documents
so it's gonna it's gonna be a big pull
request in a sense that there's a lot of
takes that's going elsewhere but most
reduction that most of the existing text
which is not or all of existing text
which is not related to this attribute
is going to remain the same things like
going review so I think like unless
there's like some like actual other
instructor this way I look for not yet
but the terms do not believe that
there's a natural law so we would
recommend that you generate the pull
request and have it reviewed but it will
be up to the editors discretion to
or not except the pull request depending
on the the amount of confusion and work
he believed it will take so the the key
thing is that the material be right and
the structure is not normative and
certain and solely if you have any
points if you need pacific points you
think we're missing please do call about
specific weeks I'm happy to put them in
well I think that means we're a mission
now is they're sending this initial
offer and modifies a session I mean it
could be written in other ways to and of
course those things that we previously
discussed you're clarifying that that
for example if you use something else
and fingerprint is in name just could
prescribe and also about this updating
identity there there's nothing about
that but I mean I'm okay
but again again I think I big there's
like a huge PR and a half detective with
the same that's gonna be like
unfortunate and my suggestion since all
these peers here-now emerged my
suggestion to make life a little easier
would be that we submit a new version
now where we merged or include SP this
PR and then this other PR would be based
on that new version because then it that
way we avoid you know requests conflicts
yeah that's all I had okay from a timing
perspective if you were to produce such
a PR obviously you're not gonna get done
this week
do you have a timeframe when you might
think you be today be able well I'm this
is not gonna be I'm gonna be in a way
after this week for two weeks so
vacation but but let's food it I mean
let's say in a month so the only other
thing of note is that we are gonna work
a new blast call the STP examples drafts
probably and and we have fun in several
outside reviews for it I really want to
thank Paul and Fleming and the other
reviewers who have already done that but
it is a big piece of work
to look at please do take some time grab
a few of the examples go through them I
think anybody who does the whole
document is is going to be very tired
indeed by the end of it because the
productions are very very complicated
but please do sample a few of giving
your expertise and give us comments as
fast as you can I believe that closes
the meeting uh thanks if you haven't
signed the blue sheet please do so
before leaving where are the blue sheets
by the way okay in the back Thanks