I think Kirsten alright I think we're
gonna get started good morning this is
the suit working group and I ATF now
this is the seal working group and I ATF
102 if you're not here for a suit you're
welcome to stay and join us this is the
no well
please note well the note well so we
have a few administrative tasks this
morning we have just seared to be one
note taker can can we thank you can we
get a second note taker we also need
that rich thank you for for that a
second note taker will happily wait
okay love it that would be fun there's
also a jab more information meet echo
and etherpad if you're interested I
think jess is taking notes and etherpad
so you can join her there this is our
agenda for the day any agenda bashing
alright so before we move on with the
agenda to give a really brief status
report
so um so we've adopted the architecture
and information model drafts thank you
to the to the authors for all their work
on on that On June 6th we held a virtual
interim where we focused predominantly
on the architecture and and manifest
drafts we generated a lot of comments
out of that and work is progressing on
those drafts on the minutes have been
posted so if you missed that meeting
feel free to to check out the minutes we
also had a hackathon project both at the
interim as well as at the ihe appointed
to hackathon and Hannes will be giving
us an update on the ITF 102 hackathon
activities later in the agenda so we're
doing fairly well on our our milestones
we actually managed to close out our
first few around adopting an
architecture and an information model
draft we still have the serialization
format to to adopt we're probably not
going to get to that today but we will
likely have a virtual interim
in in in between this and and and the
next one the next IETF meeting so I
think a focus of that might be to to
work on on adopting a manifest
serialization format we we have a
milestone to submit an information model
to the iesg so we'd like to really focus
our efforts on on that as well as a
missing milestone which I think we need
to add which is submit the architecture
document to the is G so yes exactly
so if it's okay with the working group
we would like to submit both the
architecture and and manifest
information model to the to the is G so
we'll go ahead and add that that
milestone and we'll focus on those two
topics today once we can stabilize the
information model will be easier to to
consider manifests so all in all we're
doing I think fairly well on on our
milestones and I think that's that's it
so on to the hackathon yeah I will keep
this very brief from last week's
hackathon so we a colleague of mine
worked on a board that we used and you
can have a look at it over there if you
want but the purpose of generating this
custom hardware was to use it as a sort
of reference design to play around or to
work on the different use cases that we
have identified some of the more so all
of the board support the basic use case
for a firmer update but we want to also
have the more sophisticated ones where
you actually have and see they were here
is a probably don't there's a external
flash I'm so push it to the external
flash rather than the on chip flash
there are multiple ins use here so
that's that's nice a hard worker
the module with ECDSA support miss curve
and and so on and so on also the
possibility to connect to other ports if
you want to have an off chip in our F
off port microcontroller so a couple of
different use case that we are going to
talk about later on in in one port so
that's I think quite useful and that's
what we have been playing around with
that at the hackathon itself we had
several new people new in the sense of
new to the IDF but also some of them
were new to the hackathon itself so
first-time hackathon participants and I
would encourage you to use that
opportunity also at the next meeting
not just because maybe you are a little
reluctant to get into sort of like such
a hardcore topic from an embedded space
but I think it helped the participants
door so then get familiar with the
embedded development with the help of
the others on the table so I think that
amy has been great in supporting the
newcomers and he produced an excellent
write-up and you can you can see the
link later on so I think it's even even
if you are relatively new to the suit
work I think that's something one and a
half days well-spent where you actually
take away a lot of info in and and the
board this world so we can play around
with it later on so join us um this is
what we produced there sits detailed
write-up take a look at it won't go into
the details but we try to come up with
different manifest format sign them and
sort of goes through the whole chain and
then verify it on the on the board a lot
of fun what was learned
so actually we I believe we learned a
couple of things one is probably we need
to do a little bit more homework before
going into this hackathon next time in
having everything the whole development
environment set up already ahead of time
so we don't spend half a day more or
less to just install stuff so that would
obviously be useful so we will take that
into account
the new hardware was required some
learning curve on the coding site I
think we're not quite there for a
reference implementation in my opinion
so we have the from the last London
hackathon to this one we now have a cosy
implementation which is awesome produced
by the India guys um unfortunately at
some licensing issue for some of them so
we are going to release another cosy
implementation with a different license
any day now so hopefully that will
satisfy their needs for some of you but
also the SIBO implementation there's a
lot of stuff there that can be sort of
stripped down and maybe there's a
possibility just for a very constrained
SIBO implementation only for these boot
loaders so we'll have to look into that
the spec itself um as soon as you all
know from the discussions on the list
there have been lots of changes and we
get to that and that obviously made it
more difficult to work during the during
the meeting the API of the tiny Co
implementation is also everything but
intuitive um so there's and there's some
some pain there that you need to go
through just to give you a flavor of it
um so you you traverse the different
objects in this in this C board
structure and this manifest and you read
something you advance it you need to say
oh go Chum to the next object and it's
okay that's fine but then there's some
read operations that automatically
advance so you you have this sort of
like somewhat inconsistent behavior so
sometimes you have to advance to the
next item manually to the next element
and sometimes not a little annoying and
there's no ease or no obvious and not so
obvious on how you would traverse some
of the data structures in the end that
was good so we the participants thought
that I was a cool project and so we
won't have a price think thanks to the
participants who bought it for us
nice picture at the end so that's great
what's next I believe what what we could
and that's not just my my thinking what
we could do is as we advance in the
manifest format we'll have to keep up
with the code as well I so that would be
something to do already maybe ahead of
time before them before they win also
the cozy libraries which I mentioned
earlier
and then finally going into some of the
more advanced use cases since we now
have the bought encryption Russ has this
post Kwantung based thing maybe that's
something to look into so there's
definitely if also for students who want
to do some projects I think there's
there's something there for them to look
into also performance energy power
consumption etc etc and and have you
some of you involved please join us and
talk to me and figuring out how how to
be actively and what how you could
contribute do you intend to have a
hackathon for for 103 I think so and so
I hope that my coworker Brandon will
come along next time as well and so we
can sort of split a little bit I want to
work with Dave on the deep stuff next
time and Brendon may be able to delete
the effort on the on the suit stuff so
we can sort of create something bigger
yes so so that's the plan but sort of a
little bit of organization and also I'm
finding out on who is actually going to
be in Bangkok a Bangkok it's not around
the corner so maybe we can start some
discussion about that on the list yeah
thank you for all your work with the
hackathon yeah it's a lot of fun still
have to figure out how to unbreak the
boards that me
[Laughter]
yeah not waste time okay
architecture document so there were as
they've bottom I I said that we had the
virtual interim meeting and for that one
we submitted the in preparation of that
we submitted a serial version which we
discussed BEC them so I'm not going to
focus on those changes again but there
have been a lot of changes on the
document that also in the 0-1 so we
tried to come up with new terminology
and I'm going to talk about that and
hopefully we can settle on this because
that obviously led to lots of changes in
the text and there was a desire to sort
of change the description for operating
modes and I will talk about that briefly
as well I hope that's also a
satisfactory direction we had a few
examples provided by David Brown and
which I incorporated he also became a
co-author for his text contributions in
a lots of editorial changes um the
entities that we have now there they're
also in the device so that also is the
entity that trades the firmware and in
the manifest
explicitly point out that they are
multiple also potentially because we
have on a single device there may be um
as mentioned before there may be
multiple microcontrollers they even
within one a single microcontrollers you
may get software from different sources
so I'm trying to highlight this fact so
then and that's a terminology we sort of
like took a lot bit over from the itu-t
if they allure suggested that a little
while ago and have been trying to find a
way to best incorporate this so this
communicator is a component of the
device that acts with interacts with the
firmware update server
it basically receives the firmware
images and triggers then the reboot the
update of those and start up the new
image
it there are different ways it can
interact it can borrow it can get a
notification and sort of more a push
versus pull mode and there's also some
text in there that talks about that you
know in a practical deployment it may
actually be a little bit more
complicated because there may be
multiple images that you need to
download because there's some
dependencies and so on it's on so to
take care of those cases as well not
just focusing on the most simplistic one
um there's a status tracker which is um
a little bit out it's part of the
architecture but outside of what we are
currently standardizing so this is a
sort of a device management
functionality our component that keeps
track of the firmware update process and
it knows what firmware is installed on a
device and what sort of state in the
update the device goes through it's a
common component uh people deploy in
these systems and so it allows fine
grained monitoring of changes in the
whole fleet of devices that a device or
a device operator would use and I will
show a figure later on on how these
different boxes fit together the
firmware update server as quite
uncertain blight surprisingly it stores
the firmware images and the manifest and
and it may be multiple of them admit
along a chain of sort of communication
paths the they are in this device
network operator that's a new
terminology that we added the device
operator is sort of responsible for the
day-to-day operation of the IOT devices
versus the network operator who is
really about operating the network where
the IOT devices are connected and we
introduced those because we were in
discussions at the inter meeting and Nas
at the lan an IDF meeting we were
talking about the cases of what is the
level of influence and an authorization
or the mission decisions that those
entities take when deploying a firmware
update solution and that's also
documented in some of the threats and
use cases so so I was necessary to
introduce those
Frank from Nordic semiconductor
suggested also to add another entity he
called it the OEM operator um well um as
the name indicates his sort of the
entity that builds a specific component
so you will I haven't so he this was a
little bit buried the bird in another
email threat on the on the human the
human rights our review so it's a little
bit less visible but um but if I I think
it's worthwhile to brainstorm a little
bit about whether we need to have the
terminology for the OEM in this whole
picture as well to to distinguish
between the guy who is running these our
maintaining these devices and someone
who actually builds the different
components not yet in the document
obviously so if you have some
perspective on this let me know and then
and that was really the difficult part
is how do we actually separate the
communication architecture from the
whole key infrastructure and
authorization infrastructure and then
they I introduced what I call it
couldn't come up with a better name
trust provisioning authority and what it
does is it distributes trust anchors as
well as authorization permissions to the
different entities so so when you think
about the case where a device gets
produced and that manufacturer decides
that it it wants to delegate the rights
for making changes to the update to some
other party or if a network operator
needs to do another signing an
authorization step so that the devices
he wants to make sure that certain
device is only running in his network
there's some sort of orthogonal
infrastructure that has to exist that
besides the communication infrastructure
and I'm trying not with a figure but
mostly with text explaining that there's
something going on here that there's
permissions distributed and maybe there
are some examples that we would have to
provide in there to make this more
obvious
it makes sense cass naumann yeah i think
this this the cover-up sites the last
couple of slides you have presented kind
of indicates that that there are two
different problems that need to be
solved one is the manifest that we have
been talking about here but there's also
a need at least in many situations to
actually describe the the set of players
and and what specific authorization
function they have in the overall flow
and that's maybe a good follow-on thing
we could do in this way before a
different working group so a device that
has a certain role in in such a flow in
such a sequence of operations can find
out when it has to do what so we have a
sequence of processors in the manifest
right now but that's a bit weird because
it comes from the original source so
yeah maybe we can discuss this in
somebody here yeah yeah well this is
this text was added and this entity more
in response to discussions we had
earlier because we were trying to say
okay the author of the firmware it adds
the manifest and obviously it as signs
it and and somehow the key that it's
used for signing it needs to be
verifiable by the device but then we add
it on the possibility that the network
operator also signs for some other party
signs and how do you make take care of
this that they they don't create any new
firmware they just create new manifest
and and provide this authorization so
how do we deal with this and and the
stuff that you mentioned the change is
on the manifest recently they were added
much much later yeah yeah so essentially
there is something like an overseeing
principle for for this device and that
obviously in principle decides on on
which steps are required and one or more
manifests may play a role in that
sequence of steps and we cannot expect
the initial manifest from the firmware
author to
those steps that shall be overseeing
principals to provide I expect in most
cases I'm sort of this the story is
fairly or the processing steps and the
trusts aren't changes fairly simple um
but of course there may be some more
elaborate cases so um maybe documenting
them and then figuring out what to do
afterwards is it's a good idea so Erik
monk have you guys actually thought
about what are the different use cases
for this because I think that in the
past there's been other ones that have
come up like what happens if the
manufacturer went out of business and
you know hard can you actually sort of
insert things in here so there's that
aspect it's also that if I can break
into this part of the system I can give
any device any trust anchor I want to so
it it operates at a different level from
a security threat perspective right so
is there any of this sort of larger
pieces actually written down from a
user's perspective yeah there are
various use cases described in in both
more so in the information model
document that deal with sort of threats
of our problems that relate from the
different trust chains web so let's say
more focused on the operational side
rather than the worst case where
companies go out of business and which
in general is that sort of a little bit
of that case um okay so maybe the
dependent there because because one way
of architecting the system is saying
that okay a device will have one or more
trust anchors they they might be a
separate process of being able to update
those funds right adding removing
whatever but that could be separated out
from the core okay this our drive the
software updates and then have a support
one under different security concerns
about what does it mean to reassign a
device and give it new trust anchors
through its life cycle go ahead Brendon
was essentially that it was going to be
a mechanism that allows a user of a
device to
puts some kind of trust anchor onto the
device the trust provisioning authority
was intended to be the entity that we
usually refer to as the OEM the problem
that we run into is that om ends up
meaning a lot of different things to a
lot of different people and so by
putting this this extra layer in this
trust provisioning authority it starts
to make a lot more sense so you can
imagine a white label vendor who's going
to sell their devices and they're not
necessarily going to care what kind of
software runs on them and they're going
to let their customers put their own
firmware on their devices in that
situation that white label vendor isn't
going to want to have to assign trust to
different different users for different
devices so in that model the trust
provisioning Authority concept starts to
make more sense what it allows the the
OEM to do is it allows them to provide a
channel and that channel is what's used
by the by the customers of the OEM to
put their own trust anchors on to the
device thus and then make the device no
longer claimable if you will with those
trust anchors so the idea here is that
the trust provisioning authority
provides a mechanism by which trust
anchors can be established on a device
but so that sounds like in my mind you
didn't finish manufacturing the device
yet because it doesn't have basic
software on there when until it goes
through this area which is actually
different than saying as part of its
life cycle it goes to resellers it gets
you know reacquired because someone
bought the building that it's in
whatever right I think they're very
different concerns about the initial I
need to complete manufacturing on the
device which you actually need to do as
far as I can tell in a in a Faraday cage
whatever right where nothing else can
come in and interfere with it because
you have no security to build anything
on it anyhow because you have no root of
trust already installed I mean there are
kinnison surround that this is this
isn't about ensuring the that this isn't
a whole solution right this is talking
about a channel is talking about a
framework than what you do this a device
has to make decisions do I trust the
person who's trying to give me a new
trust anchor and how do I trust the
trust anchor and I'm not saying that
this is something that has to happen in
the Faraday cage there can be keys
associated with this I mean the way of
managing it is to put say print a
pre-shared key on the outside of a
device an H Mac the thing you send to it
then does its match that yes then the
person must be in physical possession of
the device right so there are there are
mechanisms that you can install to deal
with that the point here is that there
needs to be a mechanism in place on
devices by which trust anchors are
installed I actually disagree because I
think suit can be perfectly successful
by saying we assume that there is a
manufacturing process whether happens in
one place or in two places where some
basic software and a trust anchor is
installed and now I can go and update
software on this device from by someone
who is actually trusted by that original
trust anchor right someone is part of
the original thing and now you can offer
update you cannot do ownership transfer
but that's a different problem so don't
cancel them that's my heritable sorryi
one more thing I'll say on that and it
was not intended to conflate those two
ideas the the point of this is that
there are two roles here there's one
role with it's the person who writes the
software for the device and there's
another role that's the person who puts
the authority for writing software onto
the device and there's in no way is
intended to say that those can't be the
same people this absolutely can be part
of the same workflow in fact the trust
provisioning authority might provision
trust on the manufacturing line and
that's fine the point is that that's not
always the case and we need to
distinguish between those use cases
sounds overly complex
hi Jonathan hammer from CSC I just like
to mention if possible could we
coordinate language with the trust
anchor management protocol existing
RFC's with tamp they're in there there
is a management trust anchor and the
idea is similar to this yeah I actually
thought about that but the issue here
and and I is that it's not just about
trust anchors it's also about
permissions so one of the things that we
talked about was there are different
elements in the manifest and we are
there is a possibility to allow others
to override some of those elements some
of those elements for example we had the
use case where the network operator
wants to override the place where the
ffermwyr should be retrieved from by the
device and so if that network operators
giving the permission to do that
override on that specific field then
this has to be communicated somehow
rather than overriding other fields and
so I felt that using a trust anchor
terminology for also for this
functionality seemed a little bit dumb a
long shot I don't know just move on
maybe one form of coordinating
terminology is just to pointer it and
explain what's different yeah I try to
do that um but I will double-check okay
getting to the operating modes so we now
have these three modes that I think they
Taylor proposed which is a client
initiated server initiated and a hybrid
update the in in short the client
initiated uses the communicator to talk
to the film updates to figure out
whether it is a new firmware on and be
done with it
the serve initiated is one where you
can't just reverse the roles because in
a typical deployment you have some nuts
and fire
or sitting around so it's actually the
status tracker who knows and as the name
says keeps track of the status of the
device knows what firmware versions are
running on it individual devices knows
actually what devices out and they feel
in the first place and knows how to
communicate to those potentially because
there's a long lived connection with
that status tracker and then when it
when that status tracker figures out
that it has to do an update it basically
sends in tracks with the firmware update
server to provide that update to their
client the hybrid update is essentially
a combination of both words the client
is given a pointer to retrieve the man
to retrieve the firmware rather than the
firmware itself that's sort of the the
three modes that have been added in
response to the discussions we had last
time
if they were I remember at the inter
meeting there was a comment on the
terminology I think there was some
confusion around the term modes which
implied to some people that a device had
to be capable of multiple of them and so
that's not the case here this is you can
pick and choose or whatever so maybe
operating models or something like that
okay I think I can change so in case
anybody else here is confused
I want to preempt that confusion years I
added the picture on the communication
architecture I think that's fairly easy
in other than them sort of like the
trust architecture
so here's if you listen to my
description of the determinants of the
terms you've status strike sort of talks
the device keeps track of what's going
on to communicate on the device talks to
the firmware updates server one or
multiple authors on providing firmware
images to the server and there may be
multiple servers and maybe even a
sequence depending on for example if you
get it from a server store it on a
smartphone or tablet and then push it on
on a device using UART or really or
whatever maybe I could make that more
free
so based on on the feedback from from
David we added a few examples and I
think they're quite a quite nicely
illustrate what we had discussed on
actually on the manifest document itself
but just in a in a use case example he
also provided links to existing hardware
that does this of course I admitted the
links but you can look it up if you if
you want to even get more details um so
this is the first one is very briefly
walk through those um in case you
haven't been following the details on
the list
there's SOC is system-on-chip so there's
a single chip on on the device and it's
obviously the most simplistic case it
contains typically in the same package
contains flash and aram and and also
father prefers um in so there's only a
single firmware image that needs to be
updated and it's sort of like the
execute in place that David is often
referring to where he wants to sort of
like not move code around on the on the
flash because it it's obviously
consuming a lot of energy so that's
that's the simplest most simplistic case
then it gets a little bit more
complicated when you have a petition on
a device normally partitioned between
normal and secure space we've seen that
from the deep discussions and and of
course those exist also on these IOT
devices so there's a case where so the
cpu supports the scheme and in general
the way how it works is the secure mode
will then do the update will then decide
on where things go and maybe and you
need to figure out on what you're
actually updating so you may the secure
mode may just update the image on the
normal site sort of mate then there
needs to be a way to indicate on like
what a what are you actually updating
which part of the component and of
course independently or potentially both
of it um so you need to have a way to
describe this in the inner manifest
are more complicated scenarios when you
have a dual CPU that actually use a
shared memory um and they access the
data so there may be still or there has
to be a mechanism to prevent but to have
some locking mechanism but typically one
CPU then controls the update process and
swaps everything out so the others see
it's similar to the former model but
just separate it out into two CPUs
rather than one CPU having a secure non
secure petition and this is just having
a sort of two CPUs doing these different
tasks he also provided a link to some
handsome IOT hardware it does exactly
that so I'm sort of looking at these
models and named Keith
oh sorry Keith Moore I'm looking at
these models and I it seems like that
there's a lot of value VAT I hear that
for instance I worked with the CPU that
had a lot more non-volatile Ram that Co
who'd run out of then it actually had
RAM so when you're actually updating the
firmware for this you have to update it
in slices and you have to update each
one of those slices one at a time and
have the thing keep running while you're
doing it
and yet it's it's a single system on
chip it's a sink you know it doesn't
sort of fit the description of the of
the model you have that for that matter
or the notion of a you know a system on
chip encompasses a wide range of
capabilities and so you know a
BeagleBone is a system on chip
fundamentally that's basically yet it
runs up into and you know it can do all
kinds of things and you you often have a
need in my experience to update things
in layers because for instance you don't
want to pay the communications cost of
updating the entire image of something
because if you're using cell networks or
something like that yeah so I basically
I just want to say I think this needs a
lot of work and I'm happy to contribute
input but I wanted to say something
yeah but combined yeah definitely
okay David you're up
we don't have volume no no it's on your
end David we can't hear you
very very soft now can you use jabber
if you post your comments in the chat
Bert somebody can relay but we can't
hear you
we can see you yeah we it's very the
very lower voice extremely and then one
other you can reach through the text in
the document itself which is on Everett
but the other model is where you have a
bus between the CPUs and you need to
indicate in the manifest on which CPU on
the device you actually updating but
it's not in the same sort of address
basically what it's just separate we
also had an interesting discussion
triggered by review human rights review
and I included a link here which I'm
asked for a couple of I provided a
couple of comments and I think the most
interesting one that left after some
feedback and some email discussion was
really about the encryption of the
manifest
I believe the encryption of the firmware
itself got sorted out and and I think we
are have the understanding that we have
to have the feature but whether you use
it or not depends on your deployment
environment but the encryption of the
manifest is something that surfaced in
other discussions and we didn't I don't
think we currently have that
functionality so that may be an item
worthwhile to think about a little bit
whatever you want that and whether there
are some privacy implications in certain
situations
on what benefits we could actually get
from this so I see it doesn't as an open
issue that may require further further
debate I don't know if anyone here has
has fought about this yet
it's a more advanced figure but in
theory with cose the functionality would
be would be there so one could make use
of it yeah the on the mail list if you
take a look you'll see that the Human
Rights review person was saying that
when a device is easily associated with
a human that is when this becomes an
issue and so I think we we need to
recognize that but at the same time
maybe not overcomplicate the entire
architecture because not all devices
have that problem definitely definitely
in fact I would even go as far as seeing
many devices don't have that problem um
because the manifest doesn't include
user information right indirectly there
may be in some cases so I think we need
to study this a little bit further to
figure this out I was just gonna add
that there's some proposed text on the
mailing list around scoping encryption
as a right there's a solid
recommendation for the human kinds of
use cases so I would encourage everyone
to take a look at that text us so we can
sort that out but there was a lot of
things more on focus on the firmware
encryption itself rather than the
manifest encryption but um go ahead I'm
in queue behind you and in front of you
people
benkei no you're just pointing out that
you know the distinction between devices
that have been associated human and
those that don't
there's kind of a funny question and you
know we hear about all these issues
where you can dn on Elias anonymous
datasets and that sort of thing so
there's lots of sort of side channels if
you will that can make this pop up more
often than you might yeah sure we have a
relay from jabber yet yeah
yeah okay then you're up next right uh
yeah this is from grocery bod I think
there are general advantages to
encryption of the firmware imaging
manifest but it's up to the working
group whether the draft needs to sect
requirement levels for devices
associated with humans or not and
recommends encryption of the manifest
also because it contains device info so
Dave they were individual saving that
trip over there if the goal was to allow
it without complicating anything else if
there's not another convenient mechanism
right you can always treat the manifest
as like another encrypted binary and
then you decrypt it the same way you
have the binary and then recurse next
steps so we still have to do editorial
cleanup on a document and get some
feedback from the working group I also
from earlier discussions and there was a
desire to have more text around the
bootloader our design and how it in the
implications are for the whole
processing of this so I haven't gotten
to that yet there's also a need for
better lined with the information model
because the terminology sometimes one
version of the document lags a little
bit behind so those that those are the
major items I don't think besides the
one that I just mentioned I don't think
there are huge open issues with the
document I think it's among the three
that we are discussing here it's a lot
it's further along in in a chain the
information model so version one was
published in time for the deadline and
version zero was published at in
preparation for the virtual interim
meeting if you look at the diff
there are lots of changes so I can't go
through all of them and some of them are
probably a little little out of sync
with the presentation that Brennan is
giving when he talks about the most
recent version of the manifest format so
I keep those I focus just enough on a
few core issues and we added two threats
regarding the unqualified firmware so
here's the case that was discussed and I
hopefully appropriately captured so
imagine you have device and network
operators and the device operator
creates the firmware or has the works
with the also to do so in a network
operator needs to decide whether the
this specific IOT device with their
firmware is fit for purpose on that
network which may be a situation in a in
some of the critical infrastructure
environments in the device operate the
managers devices that are deployed in
all sorts of different networks and so
the attack scenario is the following
imagine an attacker gets obtains the
manifest
from a device that is deployed in
network a and then he takes that
manifest and sends it to a device in
network B so the device it's fine for
that device because it's managed also by
the same device operator but network a
and network P under different control so
implying that firmware update to this
other network network B would be a
problem would be an early violation of
the the policy of that network operator
so it's perfectly like from a signing
point of view it's perfectly fine but
just not complying to the policy the
other cases where you have multiple
devices that interoperate um they are
working on the same network so we have
only one Operator rather than two but
multiple device operators and you so
some some of the devices are
manufactures and managed by device
operator a and other spy device operate
the B
and now is a firmer release for device
operator a that breaks the
interoperability a compatibility with
those of the device operator B so the
network operator may want to have some
saying or some may need to qualify which
one of those firmware images are
actually allowed to be used in this in
his network irrespectively of what and
device operate diminishes them which can
obviously be used to cause denial of
service or potentially other other
problems so we added those two threats
but I don't remember who suggested them
but I covered them there's some this is
actually terminology from the from the
architecture document but because it's
used in a subsequent slide I would just
want to remind you so there's one case
for the heterogeneous storage
architecture where a device stores the
firmware image from a component at least
in in in different ways in a system so
for example you have a device that has
on chip flash and off chip flash so
those would be stored differently
whereas in the homogeneous storage
architecture we are talking about
storage of firmware images or different
components in the same way so they may
be just in different address spaces in
on the flash so those two terms so for
the for the case with multiple
microcontrollers there's there's a need
to have our component identifiers to
actually distinguish between the places
where these firmware images have to go
in in the case of a split between code
and configuration on the same device
what the manifest needs to provide is
sort of a dependency structure because
it it has to sort of get the to the code
and the data somehow somehow aligned so
you can't just swap out one and not have
any say anything about the other one
that this firmware image then depends on
so this is sort of the
dependency structure whatever the name
in and in in some cases you have the
firm was split into multiple chunks
maybe different libraries that you
update separately maybe for performance
reasons or for bandwidth or conserving
bandwidth and so you also have to create
the dependency between the different
firmware images that you allow on on a
device um we had Kay we had a few
examples and they also in a document
where we have more sophisticated cases
where multiple different versions are
sort of supported or possible versus
having only a very specific from our
firmware version supported on a device
so we have those added and in to get a
bit those use cases obviously the
corresponding information elements added
as well I'm going to talk about them a
little bit there's one use kit that
David Brown suggested the rollback use
case which is not yet covered in the in
the document and so he has the he came
up with this case I'm in talking to some
some others
it's a about a battery powered device
that is connected to a bandwidth
constraint network think about the low
power wide area network and the device
keeps the old firmware around aren't
just in case it needs to do a rollback
so it has multiple slots for the
firmware image and then the document
doesn't say on how such an update would
happen because it always talks about
advancing the firmware images in rolling
obviously when you advance the film
image you need to provide them new
firmware image along with it so um he
was he thought that it would be good to
also describe this case where the
rollback the new manifest which contains
a new sequence number actually doesn't
contain the firmware image because it is
already on the device and so and it's
impossible already with the way how the
manifest is structured but it's just not
described and maybe a little misleading
so he thought it would be worthwhile to
cover this case
so all you then in the end need to do is
is to send a manifest with the new
sequence number pointing to the old
firmware image just wanted to point out
in this particular use case the person
doing this actually decided to not use
rollback protection so that they could
support this case that it was more
valuable to them to be able to rollback
than the security aspects of the anti
rollback protection yeah maybe because
they didn't know that it's possible so
it's probably useful useful to describe
it and to make people aware of it yeah
so I think we should definitely add that
use kits on this description and David
your audio was great that time - Robin
Wilton from Internet Society
I'm so just thinking of some of the
security implications of this it strikes
me that having a rollback mechanism for
large networks of distributed devices
could open you up to a kind of downgrade
attack so if the purpose of the firmware
upgrade was to add a security function
and someone can at a mass scale roll
that back on all the devices they open
those devices up to be a botnet for
example I'm in this specific case I
don't think so because the aim because
the entity has to or the party rolling
out the firmware update actually has to
create a new manifest a new manifest has
a new sequence Tomaso it's newer than
the ones that device had seen before but
I think the optimization here is really
in the area of not sending the image
itself
okay Benjamin down I assume the sequence
number is not strongly connected to the
firmware version so that if you if they
really had a downgrade attack that was
that bad you would increase the sequence
number but typically you wouldn't let me
leave we faced a situation all the time
where you have to downgrade it Brenden
Europe the intent with this mechanism is
that it it proves the intent of the
author so if the author says actually
the firmware that's just been rolled out
is not fit for purpose and we need to go
back to the previous firmware they have
to prove their intent to go back that's
the defense against creating botnets the
the issue in the botnet situation is
that you don't have the intent of the
author the author hasn't proven that
they want to roll back then you you end
up with a problem if the author can
prove that they intend to roll back then
that eliminates that possibility
now I'm not saying that they don't have
vulnerabilities and they're all firmware
they might well but if there is an
intent that you can prove to go back
then presumably they have a reason for
that and that is open to them they could
just create the same firmware again and
ship it again and that would give the
same result but this does it in a
slightly optimized way well maybe a very
optimized way okay no from oh yeah for
me okay so in terms of this rollback I
believe is there a need where the
manifest is attached with a date after
which that firmware does not have the
veracity to live in the device and then
it rolls rolls back I don't think we
have a date where you sort of there's a
a date if I remember I'm an element in a
manifest on where you could indicate on
when you want to apply there the thermal
image but not when it stops becoming
valid I don't think we have that element
in the structure okay
I very briefly wanted to talk about the
manifest elements about it skip I would
be very brief because I want to get the
time to do Brendon because he has this
new structure so referring back to the
discussion earlier with the different
types of use case and different types of
sort of more sophisticated hardware
components so this we have this concept
or this element of storage location and
which then allows you to distinguish for
example are you updating in OS are you
updating in application this is sort of
the the to storage location case are you
putting something on a file system so
that would be the path in the file
system or are you putting something into
flash memory where exactly in flash
memory do we actually put it this sort
of like the offset or address of the
space where you put it so that's an
element that that has been added or has
been clarified there's also um anything
there's also this component identifier
which was added because in the case of
heterogeneous storage architecture this
this storage identifier that I just
talked about is not sufficient to
actually identify where to put the
information that firmware so it's
component identifier was was added as a
new element the conditions and that the
condition element was there all along
but there was a lot of confusion and
discussion so on on the different
elements and it was then later split
into two types of conditions
preconditions and postconditions
and that change has been made in a
manifest format but hasn't been
populated back into the information
model document so you still have a
little bit of an out of sync situation
yeah
custom custom over can you go back to
the previous slide so in about half long
ago you said something that really
intrigued me which was part of a
component
I cannot repeat reduce the entire
sentence but I can in my we have a
little bit of work ahead of us thank you
so probably the most dramatic change was
also it's currently out of sync is and I
included the link to an email here from
from Brandon on a list about the sort of
changes on the directive elias's and
dependencies which had been turned into
a new structure resources and that text
isn't there yet in the information model
document we'll get to that in in a
little while Hannes can you go back to
slides I don't think you finished your
thought about conditions what work needs
to be done so the work that needs to be
done there is to take the the split or
incision to split the conditions into
pre and post conditions also reflect
that into the information model document
currently it's not and this one is brand
new services are also not there and I
think this this is something the group
hasn't maybe not even decided for a year
to answer probably that's the reason why
it's not there this sort of combining
several of those concepts that look very
similar into one new element in the in
the manifest hi
yeah I was very curious about the
resource processes targets input node
output node composite that was in there
I basically because this night I
submitted a map based manifest as an
alternative I was really just copying
that because I had no clue what the
semantics were I mean I got a little bit
but yeah yes yet said there's a gap here
so one of the things I think my lesson
learned from sort of this whole exercise
is I mean probably wasn't a great idea
to separate in early stage the
information model from the serialization
format because now you have all these
inconsistencies in from a document point
of view simply because reviewers like to
comment on a more specific thing while
they should actually be commenting on
the on the higher level abstract thing
but they don't because we're engineers
so we like to write things down in a
more specific style for some reason and
so you see things being somewhat
misaligned so um if I if I would do that
again I would probably have just one
document in split later on when I
actually figured out exactly how the
structure looks like but it's too late
for that um but okay and I hand it over
to the Brendan or and yet a comment yeah
sure so didn't already missing again see
is required version thingy in the
information water that didn't make it
into the manifest at the moment right ah
there's a version number yeah yeah but
this is this there's multiple versions
like major minor or whatever revision
and then this is a pre requisite
prerequisites for being able to update
that in a multi segment or multiple
forever positioned from where each
having its own precondition basically
yeah that that is the precondition
concept that's there I I don't think the
major minor version number concept is
there I have to look in every Brendon
can answer that question he talks about
that says that it's not an information
model for sure because it just talks
about maybe maybe maybe it should talk
about my mind okay hello Steven pang
heart I had a terribly boring question
regarding both the architecture and the
information document the documents
switch between uppercase and lowercase
must so it's kind of hard for me to know
when I'm reviewing the document what you
intend to be a requirement and what you
don't so if you could update your
section two to use the new vcp on
uppercase and lowercase requirements
then really helpful for me as a reader
okay thank you yeah so in general I
think impregnable also talked about this
um I don't think we have fully decided
yet on on what is the mandatory to
implement elements and so we will have
to do that in some point in time yeah
brenneke jump into the queue thank you
and go ahead okay so the I want to start
by saying that the manifest
serialization is under a lot of flux so
I am for instance there's this whole
thing that Hank mentioned about the the
manifest processors and resources and
targets and I honestly now believe that
that's probably a mistake and that there
is a better way of handling it which
I'll talk about in a moment
so suggestions welcome there's a lot to
be done yet to get this to a point where
I think we can standardize it brand-new
we have a terminology comment the
civilization is done that's in RFC 70 49
but you're really doing here is the data
model right yes okay so next slide
please
there are a lot of open issues the first
one as Hank brought up is should the
primary object be an array or a map and
then there is the question of whether we
should use a graph as I described in
manifest 0 2 I'm not convinced and but
if we use trees to to deal with this
then there's a there are open questions
of how they're overridden represented
and whether or not they break any use
cases there's also so the question of
whether we can have one type of digest
for the whole manifest or if there's a
good reason to support multiple
different types of digest at the time
you sorry can you elaborate on what your
intended difference is between a graph
and a and a tree I can you give me a few
slides and I'll elaborate sure ok I
should write sections be severable so we
we introduced the cons
of separable text at the art well I we
started talking about it during the
hackathon at the virtual interim meeting
at the idea behind this one is that we
cut text out for devices that don't
require it text is meant to be human
readable devices don't really need to
process it and it can increase data
sizes so by making them detached I
believe is the term is used in most
containers are most crypto containers
the idea is that it texts can be
delivered to the entities that require
it but it can be prudent when a manifest
is delivered to a device we have an open
issue that Cosi has no algorithms to are
no algorithm identifiers for digests on
their own so I think that we probably
need to file another draft for cozy to
add algorithm identifiers next slide
please
there are more encryption of the
manifest is something that we might need
to address explicitly it's also
something that we might need to address
one level higher up with the concept of
severing more sections of the manifest
rather than just the text maybe it's
possible that we could wrap that
particular problem up in one of the
sections that the manifest references
while still maintaining the ability to
[Music]
still maintaining the ability to process
manifests at intermediate steps which is
important for routing considerations
among other things it we need to work
out the encoding of processing steps
directives and conditions and extensions
and there's a lot of enums used
throughout the manifest and there are
going to be Ayana implications because
of that and with that list of open
issues shall we dive into a couple of
them a ray versus map I'm still more set
on arrays than maps largely because most
of the fields are mandatory
I have yet to see a compelling argument
to go the other way if there is a
compelling argument I'm definitely open
to it so Cass Mela again we had this
interesting hackathon in June the tennis
talked about and one piece of feedback
that was pretty strong from member
Mendez on the embedded side was that
they really like to do put it pauses and
pauses essentially means that the
control flow in in the program that
actually makes use of the data it's kind
of bound to the civilization sequence in
which the data comes in and that of
course means the more deterministic the
more predetermined the series agent
sequence is the easier it is to run this
pull apart so that's actually an
observation that that's both relevant
for this and for the next question so
for the array versus map decision the
obvious advantage of a map is that it's
easier to extend the disadvantage is
that you are not predetermining
predetermine a the sequence now you can
do some things of course for instance if
you should go for consistent encoding
you could say the fluids in would not
have to be serialized in a sorted way
and so on that that's one way to fix
this but I agree with your assessment
right now this is a pretty stable set of
fields so why can't we put this in into
an array and of course we have to have
an idea where we would put extensibility
and since I have to run away in a couple
of minutes they quickly say something
about trees trees essentially
graphs what arrays are two maps so trees
again allow Apple aza to tie its
controversial to the sequence in which
things come in why with a graph that may
be more complicated that's not always
true because there are some some
elements of a graph that you would just
stash away and and then use in the
following so this is not that quite as
clear cut as it was it's not but is a
general observation
I think trees are actually easier to
process in an ability limitation hi this
is sorry
hi this is Hank again any Asha of course
trees are easier that's that's a plus
also I think out of twelve fields five
are mandatory and seven optional think
it's the wrong way around also I think
we why not do one thing and also not not
not to the other I mean there could be a
fixed envelope and we have one that is
the cozy the payload resides and maybe
the payload is the staff member and we
put everything that is about the
metadata into the secure header for
example just spinning from the top of
map okay so we can we might be able to
leverage both benefits of maps and
arrays and don't have to stick with one
necessarily I think also I would agree
with the the idea that if you want to
prove something out of a fire and a
district offset you have some additional
problems of heading I think it's like
word wise copy I think there's a brought
up on the email list I think this photo
brought up at the ITF hackathon Hannah's
maybe you can remember I don't really
know the source anymore but there was
this idea that were just blindly I can
and grab into the manifest if there's a
firmware in there and put that out
because word wise copy there was some
very very very strict and naive we
there's like basically want to do
nothing I want to be sure where it is
going to receive at the end maybe it
will never be that easy but I don't
think that maps are such a big disabler
for that because at the moment we are
looking if an array is empty and if it's
not empty there's an error in it and
that might be empty and it's also very a
lot of work I mean looking for members
basically the same effort so I don't
think that's huge at the moment a huge
difference of efficiency here Dave
Walter Meyer as an individual I'm just
to kind of touch on some of the points
that Hank and Carsten made I I think my
preference would be for using a map in
this case for a number of reasons I
believe using a map will actually reduce
the amount of branching I don't like the
idea of supporting both arrays and maps
because that's another source of
branching and and and and parsers but I
believe a map will reduce branching
because the code points that are
effectively used as the as the labels
can be used to to drive code like Carson
was was saying in in pulled parsers I
think it also gives us a way to add
extensibility into into the model by you
know by allocating additional code
points for different kinds of
information that we may want to include
in the manifest in the future if we get
something wrong with our current
representation of information within the
manifest it allows us to issue a new
code point for maybe an alternative to
that in the future which I think also
eliminates a lot of the need around
versioning within within the the
manifest effectively the parser can work
off of the the code points that that it
you know that it understands from from
that perspective so I think I think
using a map has a number of advantages
as a solution over
over an array okay so by the way David
and Brennan are back in Cuba since
Carson you have to leave we're taking
the Harris Prager if it'll let you jump
the queue and then leave so just two
quick comments one anything that can
help avoid versioning and to weather an
array really gives you a lot of
advantages over a map depends a lot on
whether you can process these elements
in isolation if you'll need to see the
whole picture anyway then then the map
is fine but if there's something that
you specific then a map is fine because
it doesn't make a difference in which
sequence you start processing it let's
have conversations at the mic yeah
trying to say is an array is really
beneficial if you can do processing
without having seen the whole thing if
you need to see the whole thing through
the processing there is no difference in
presentation complexity between an R and
a but Europe alright first point I'll
make just in response to that um the
inin cozy curve actually see bore if you
use a canonical format which we should
be using if we're signing these the map
will be in a specific order it's
sometimes a confusing order based on how
the numbering system works all positive
numbers come before negative numbers
that kind of thing and then it depends
on the size of the number I guess the
point I wanted to make perhaps it would
be useful in our document if we actually
identify the processing sequences that
will happen I especially this notion of
a pull parser that that's a great way to
describe by the way what I was trying to
state that the data needs to be parsed
without reading it into a data structure
these are some of these are very
constrained devices that are acting on
the data and I think that needs to be
really taken into consideration perhaps
even included in the document how this
will be processed so
that's just my comment really have to
run
so one observation there is something
called canonical encoding in FC 1749
it's a recommendation not a
specification the recommendation for how
an application could be find the
economical encoding we are no longer
happy with everything exactly that's in
there so we are going to in the revision
that's going on Zeebo working group we
are going to define a slightly different
consistent encoding and the main
different difference here is that the
new one will have a map ordering that's
slightly less surprising it will still
have a negative after the positive ones
maybe that there is a bug in the
location of major types but at least you
don't have to look at the links because
that really hurts implementations a lot
so the other observation is you don't
have to be canonical or consistent
choose I'm so you are free to choose
anything else but I think the the can
you make your choice you want to make
life easy for the embedded side and may
want to accept some hardship on the side
that actually builds the manifest so
putting my onus there and less honest on
the embedded side is always okay great
rinkie luck just think about David Valle
tomorrow's comment about using the map
as a extensibility point generally when
you're thinking about sort of
extensibility thing you want to consider
the possibility that a new extension
might be critical and that if it appears
and you don't understand how to purse it
you just fail entirely I'm not sure if
there's a good way to incorporate that
with the because I'm a poor not Superman
think again I'm just picking up on the
previous comment yeah it's bad if you do
not do updates before updates because if
you're uncertainly unprepared for
something that's in the manifest that
should be support what about the client
you staged something wrong I think so
please bill could compare campaigns
that's important all the wavy losses so
and that's one but I'm also the map
thingy I was my point
yeah the the canonical ordering is an
option I think and yes everything that
makes it less necessary to look for
versioning and the new canonical an
organization of support will also reduce
the need for looking for lengths in
values makes life really really easier
and the what was mentioned before about
that you would like to have a pointer to
something from the manifest another copy
of it because smaller constant no device
but but benefit from that that's just a
true problem that's that's that's not
not a problem of of either Maps arrays
all this should manifest at all I think
and I think Chinese simple care just do
it just copies it Brendan you wanna get
back and you want me to go but thank you
so
suit to Brendan that you still there
here comes I was trying to sort out
becoming a presenter with me deco I
think we may have it now
[Music]
yes so I I take the the points that are
made and I particularly like the idea of
pull parser and I think the that one
thing we might be able to do here is try
and actually merge these two concepts so
what I mean by this is that if we
deliberately flaunt canonical encoding
and put elements in the order that is
needed by the target device then we can
actually get perhaps the best of both
worlds David Brown wants to respond to
that so Brendon I have to move on to and
even speak so yep come right back and
cute David go ahead um it's one thing I
pointed out on the sea bore mail the yes
the Seabourn mailing list in the
manifest that we currently have we use a
syntax that is allowed by the grammar in
the sea bore spec but not explained what
it means which is basically an array of
pairs that may be a useful format it's
basically treated like a map but the
ordering can be specified so I don't
know if that's useful to contribute to C
bar in that regards
and yeah I mean maybe that's something
to contribute back to seaboard but I
think the yeah treating it as a an array
of Pickers I might be the right answer
and I think that we can probably handle
it that way yeah I like the idea of
deliberately reordering Maps rather than
sticking to a canonical encoding and
this is thanks speaking as an awful City
da yeah who could use that this
two-dimensional array but their Maps
[Laughter]
yep let's keep going right so as Hank
mentioned earlier on so so well the the
information around what exactly the
process description is is a little bit
thin on the ground so this all comes
from a fundamental requirement for a
device to be able to assess whether it
can process a manifest up front if it
can't assess that then there's no point
in having separate metadata of from
payloads so the intent is that a device
can determine exactly what it needs to
do to process the content that it's
being provided with and for that it
needs to have a description of exactly
what it's going to do so if we start by
moving things that are asset the things
that are installed into their own
section then what you need to describe
them becomes quite small likewise if you
describe how to obtain that thing that
you install separately you need to
specify where it goes so that you know
which thing you install you're referring
to and the most sensible way of doing
that I think is to put the same
component identifier in both sexes
then you need a list of steps that you
have to go through to to process these
devices or these things you installed
this could include things like
decryption decompression have multiple
kinds including things like Delta which
is a little bit more complicated since
it requires two inputs and then finally
resources things you refer to that
contain firmware payloads what-have-you
those need to have a URI or a component
identifier in the case of a delta input
so that it can refer back to something
that's already local onto the next slide
please so here's a fragment of CD DL
that explains roughly what I'm thinking
of doing you have this thing called an
asset which has the component identifier
an explanation of how the device is
encoded any parameters that it might
take at the size of the resource and the
digest for the resource I should go back
and say that the encoding really needs
to change to a an enum but I had with
that still needs to be discussed in the
working group and exactly which kind of
are which kinds of encoding zhh will
list under there which is why it's still
a B string the parameters need to be a B
string to deal with individually defined
in codings the component identifier I've
got listed as an array of B strings
following on from discussions at the
hackathon I have come to the conclusion
that a component identifier and a
storage identifier together are just a
generalization or sorry there-there's a
specialization of an array of
identifiers so let's just use an array
of identifier z' then this can be
thought of as a as a path
if you will but it's a machine
processable path so you can imagine a a
UNIX path but instead of having slashes
between elements you have a C bore array
which is easier for a device to parse
then there's the digest taking in the
feedback from the list that we may want
to have more one more than one digest
algorithm in a particular manifest this
approach to digests has a digest
identifier for every individual digest
next slide please
alright so this explains how the how a
particular thing that you install gets
installed you start by having a
component identifier and then a list of
processors now processors are things
that manipulate the data in some way
either by producing it if it's the
resource type or by decrypting
decompressing on Delta relocating all of
those sorts of operations now because
some of these can happen together
there's a list of inputs now those
inputs can either be a URI list if they
are remote resources a component
identifier it's a local resource or a
map of inputs if it is a non resource
type so this is for most of these it's
relatively straightforward to decrypt
for example it would take one input
whereas the undef' or I guess undealt ax
would take two inputs and the reason for
the map is so that it's clear to specify
which input is mapped to which index
into the array of processors in the
asset installation info block allow
override tells you whether the asset
installation info can be replaced by a
dependent manifest and extensions as
previously discussed may not be needed
if this is
coded as a map next slide please
so why not leave container information
in payloads it's so that we can reject
the manifest if a device can't process
it and this is particularly important
for low bandwidth and not using enums
for aggregate formats is largely due to
the specialization that's necessary to
do it each of these different blocks
would have to have their particular
arguments supplied and that leads to the
possibility of many different
configurations many different structures
that need to be registered or as
breaking them apart makes it somewhat
less complicated Brendan I'm sorry to
interrupt this is Dave Walter Mayer had
a question on the previous few slides
actually if you can go back one more so
on relating to the component identifier
here have you put any thought into how
you might namespace component
identifiers to avoid collisions it may
make sense to have some namespace
identifier and you know component
identifier is still instead of
concatenated them all in a single key
string well indeed that's why this is an
array of B strings well I mean but how
would you identify a an individual
component identifier the namespace of a
individual component identifier that
would be the okay so so in that respect
I'm the component identifier as I said
you can think of as the entire path to a
particular component a to a particular
thing that you want to update
so the namespace would presumably be the
first element it's not quite the same as
an OID
but it is somewhat similar I'll give you
that
I see okay yeah we should be make sure
we're clear about about how that may be
used and then you go to the next line so
under type is the intent here that the
negative end is used for extension
correct yes
one one option here might be to use to
to maybe provide for you no special
specification required or standards
action for one type of extension and
maybe private use for another so you
might want to maybe use like positive
values for for specification required
and negative integers for private use we
should maybe think about how this
extension point might be used a little
bit you know going forward and how we
might want to manage manage those
extensions I mean maybe that's a general
comment too for all places where we have
extension we probably want to follow a
common a common pattern just to make
understanding that a little bit easier
the I agree the the pattern that I have
suggested so far has been that negative
integers are used for extensions and
positive integers are used for
registration gotcha
Thanks hi this is Hank again okay
looking at this slide up right now I see
extensions that's fine it's a map that
is basically everything and it's huge
and there's also the idea of having a
CDDA extension point so this is for I
think you're doing it quickly by
yourself with negative numbers for
example yes and and if you want to do
with the positive numbers maybe indicate
that you should do an acidity a data
definition extension and not just
arbitrarily for more stuff into the
extension map because this is that it's
not very defined at some point if you're
really going for an extension of the
manifest which would write a draft about
it and use this CDDA data division
language extension point and not the
extra map yeah I think that's important
to highlight also I agree also I think
you have only one member in the inputs I
think you said said
the difference more than one year yeah
so you're you're right although URI
lists are significantly more than one
input as a possibility you only select
one of them but there's a list so there
could be Muslim okay and the other one
is the map of inputs now again that is a
specialization that deals specifically
with Delta updates or differential
updates and that's because you need a
local input the thing that you're
comparing against and the remote input
the different the stream of differences
okay I get a better not thank you and
then reading processor I'm pretty sure
that in the main array
it's not called processor and this does
not really compile and I try to compile
it this night and there's some no-name
discrepancies yes there were some name
discrepancies and I believe I have dealt
with most of those but I haven't
published the updates yet okay excellent
that you can't see can you see my thumbs
up yes
also there is in your resource decrypted
saw integer value is fine
and you continue this enumeration across
different semantics I think they're only
getting larger and larger is that
correct still looking I'm just looking
at the current submitted 12 so I believe
that they are restarted for each
different semantics okay maybe I have it
wrong from the top of my head ever check
but I think their continuous of our
semantic types I think I believe they
all start at one if if there's a good
reason to start them hot to restart them
than that that's another question
so an example here all right we have a
raw binary payload so there are no
arguments needed then an encrypted
binary payload is the next possibility
you would need a key identifier an
algorithm identifier those who both need
to be arguments to the to the payload
descriptor then the possibility of
encrypted compressed binary or encrypted
compressed Delta payload you can see how
each one of these has a different set of
arguments that are needed to describe it
properly and when we go through this you
could this is essentially my
justification for not defining aggregate
payload types as enums because with each
of them a new structure would have to be
redefined to encompass all of the
arguments that would be necessary to
process that payload next slide please
there I've already said the same thing
it would be easy to miss if a reasonable
combination of supported steps so we're
I'm suggesting that we describe each
step instead as any each one can have a
defined structure they can all be
represented in the same way but then we
have to define how flow is described and
because of Delta we know that flow is a
tree rather than a linear sequence and a
shared resource between two steps might
turn that flow into a graph but as was
mentioned earlier graphs make constraint
processing hard so using multiple trees
instead is probably the right answer and
I haven't seen a lot of examples of a
shared resource so and even if they were
I don't think that would increase data
size or make processing particularly
harder so I think it's probably the
right choice to defined it the flow
between these steps as a tree rather
than a linear sequence next slide please
so the way that this would be
constructed together is that each asset
would have a tree that defines the
installation process as I defined above
to reduce the nesting depth in the
parser the trees encoded as a list now
this is important for early verification
it makes it easy for a device to check
that it supports each of the processing
steps that are defined without actually
having to construct the tree or parse
down a deep tree the output identifiers
are the index of a processor in the
processor list and the inputs are a map
of indices into that processor list
resources are also encoded as processors
but with no inputs or rather with inputs
that are redefined to either URIs or
component identifiers and an asset is
Dafoe is designated as something that
has a single tree that feeds it and the
output nodes that I had mentioned
earlier can be marked as none over
rideable that's where the the allow
override or allow alias I forget what I
called it I is in the CD DL previously
and again dependent manifests can
override any installation tree and
that's the whole tree that's not marked
as none over rideable now this is to
address a use case that was brought up
in one of the previous meetings where
you have a gateway for example which
will pre process a payload for a device
suppose that the Gateway is the
termination of the encrypted channel
that it is needed then your gateway can
decrypt a payload for you and then send
it on but that needs to be represented
to the device in some way so in this
case it redefines the installation tree
and the device then can pick up the
installation tree out of the dependent
manifest and still validate the asset
out of the canonical manifest next slide
please
so how this would work and for a raw
binary payload you
would have a component identifier this
is to the explaining how it gets
installed you'd have a component
identifier and a resource and that would
be all of it the whole installation
information section the asset
information would be exactly the same
you would have a component identifier
encoding as raw binary and what's not
listed here the size and the digest next
slide please
here again a delta payload e here we
have two different processors first
there's the one that provides or the
sorry there is the component identifier
of course then three processors one that
is the Delta which actually unpacks this
this update then the resource which is a
list of your eyes and then the resource
which is the component identifier for
the existing image and then in the asset
information we'd again have that
component identifier so that the device
knows which where to store this and can
link the asset information with the
installation information the encoding as
raw binary and the input node I think
shouldn't be there right
I missed a section I was supposed to
delete my apologies there's an error in
the slide please disregard the last
bullet point there would be a an
additional digest and size in that asset
information as well next slide please
right so that's that is the end of the
that the material I've got prepared on
the outstanding issues if there are any
questions now that would be good on the
the tree structure or any of that - can
I'd like
um for me it would be interesting to
know whether we sort of made a
conclusion on going to the map structure
away from the array that was the first
point that Brendan brought up and the
second thing is whether we want to go
forward with this sort of processing
structure that that Brendan has just
presented because that would be
obviously useful in going forward and
refining it we had a longer discussion
on the mailing list on those topics or
if there's a different a different
direction then probably would be also
good to discuss this as we are going to
move forward as we update the this data
model document we also have to then get
the corresponding information doctrine
information model document in sync
dealing with some of the conditions and
the already asset and the other things
it needs to line up otherwise it's very
difficult to understand order for thing
so the chairs were thinking that the way
to go forward here would be to let the
authors do one more update and then do a
call for adoption does anyone think that
that does anyone have a better idea okay
does that work for the author team that
works for me okay yeah well so the map
versus the right thing I was thinking
that we'd let the authors make an update
tell the list what they did and then
when we do the call for adoption if
everyone thinks it's right we're okay if
they say it's wrong we'll hear about it
at that point so it makes sense manifest
from a information model should be
agnostic right agreed
Honus is coming back to the mind um but
it seems at least on that issue from the
folks in the room and there of course
there are other people on the mailing
list but there was a reference more to
them on a map site rather than the area
site at least that's how I understood
the discussion I would note that Python
are you there sorry Dave camp with
Department of Defense if the information
model says that you have an ordered map
that is then you require a serialization
that will preserve that ordering
property I'll notice that that Python
just recently decided to make their maps
have an ordering property to it so egg
says well you could use a
two-dimensional array but a map is a map
well if you have a serialization that
preserves a designated ordering in your
map then you can use it if seaboard does
not provide that then then you implement
it so that it does Rick Saul's so one
lesson learned from the old XML schema
days is if the ordering doesn't matter
just pick one and then you get the
chimerical form and like I said doesn't
matter that's also a lesson from the
asn.1 days since we have like three
different ways to do it we learned
that's bad
yeah I wasn't gonna go back I heard two
related but separable discussions one
was on map versus array and one was on
ordered versus unordered if you have a
map could be either right if you have an
array it's obvious that it's ordered
right and so I said that map versus
array doesn't impact the information
model I ordered versus unordered could
be said in the information model if we
said it had to be ordered than the
information while it could say that if
it had a reason why independent of any
serialization format or any data format
if it needed to be ordered it could say
that and I saw some discussion
that I heard people arguing yes it
should be ordered was what I heard I
what I heard was the reason the ordering
was important was so that everybody does
the signature the same actually I was
gonna add to that I I heard I heard that
we need to at least discuss and define
where ordering does matter within within
the information model which i think is
something that the group needs to do the
other thing that I would say that we
should prioritize is documenting these
concepts in the information model even
before we focus on any additional
updates to the to the to the data model
because our goal is to ship the
information model you know sooner than
in the data model if the edits were
being done by different people there's
no reason that they couldn't be done in
parallel but if they're good by the same
person please prioritize the information
model updates between the two yeah this
is thank you can any of you if you
really really invested in having an
ordered map you could in theory register
SIBO check for that the once was a
effort that have an implant to introduce
a super check for a ordered multi map
that even though the members won't in
unique this is of course not necessary
but so but but in theory if you're
really invested in this you could
attempt to register attack a simple tag
on that and see how is geo multi map
would give you one advantage here and
that's that you could essentially turn
the entire thing into a essentially a
bytecode interpreter yeah
although moti maps have other issues so
there's a benefit to it this is the
desert but there are also very messy
with respect to consistency and
redundancy and an infinite I mean
there's a reason by
didn't do it and there's a reason but I
see what still doesn't do it and people
abandon the idea just want to highlight
the option I'm not for it but I'm for
transparency why did you push the button
hopefully this doesn't just make you
Brennan just to see if Davidson CUSO
okay
hey and I still see Brandon great um
just wanted to point out I I think
there's probably two reasons for
constraining order one is serialization
or signatures which I'm not sure is
actually important for this case since
you're always signing a specific
manifest not it's not a signature on
something someone else will be
generating but the other reason was the
argument of making poll parsing easier
that if somebody if the ordering is
specified correctly the processing can
always be done in order one thing I
wanted to point out I brought up on the
mailing list just to make sure we
consider that these processing steps may
have different actors that will do
subsets of them I don't know if we want
those as separate processing blocks or
how exactly we want to do that or if
that's addressed
I think the way that this would address
it is that each successive actor would
define a new process tree which would
define what the recipient of that
process tree needed to do and if the
recipient is another partial processor
they'll have to again define their own
manifest that does the same thing again
this can get pathological of course if
these are all signed but I guess the
question is how plausible is it that we
get multiple levels deep in that kind of
a kid yeah I envision maybe two not 30
so parsing 30 manifests is probably not
a good plan parsing 3 might be difficult
on a constrained device but doable and
David's reasoning for summary of the
ordering reason was the one that I had
heard that was referring to yourself all
right all right
well it looks like we've got some time
left so I can talk about some of the
current changes that we've got in place
these are things that were in the draft
that was submitted not things that are
open so the primary structure is
currently an array I may have to change
that text is severable which means that
we can cut it out and deliver only
machine readable data to machines which
i think is an improvement multiple
payloads are allowed which was one of
the requests from various meetings and
mailing lists resources were separated
from assets that so resources the thing
before it's installed and an asset is
the thing after its installed we can
work on the terminology if you don't
like that I'm not tied to it I
description of the installation process
goes into the manifest conditions were
divided into preconditions and
postconditions we've added the component
identifier which replaces the story
in fire and the timestamp has been
removed and replaced with a sequence
number so I this is pretty clear that
they're still ongoing development this
is still a work in progress next slide
please
so separable text text is for humans
it's not used by devices to make
decisions or at least that is the
guiding principle of the separable text
concept if there is some kind of text
that's needed both by humans and devices
this proposal would mean that you'd need
to duplicate it so devices typically
don't need to receive text these are IOT
devices but it's still needed in
management systems next slide please
so the way to deal with that is that we
divide it into two pieces first there is
the authenticated manifest which is the
container that has both a an
authentication a Cosi authentication
block in it its signature or Mac and a
seaboard text map now inside that text
map there is the map of keys to strings
next slide please
David is in cute but oh yeah go for it I
just want to point out when we create
this new top-level thing as well as our
lower level things are we intending to
create a seaboard tag or to allocate a
seaward tag for those so they can the
type can be identified it would need to
be yes deepwater is coming up and like
so
Dave Walter Meyer as an individual I'm
an author of another draft in in sack
I'm around Coast web which I think we
briefly talked about and some earlier
working group meetings and that's a
draft that's actually really targeted
towards management systems and you know
providing a lot of the human text that
might be used in in those management
systems perhaps we might want to
investigate how we could use curse wit
to provide some of these more human
focused capabilities leaving our work
around manifest to be more Machine
oriented would sounds like a great idea
to me hi this is Hank also a this came
up a author of the concise off identify
a draft we have had a resource
collection edit that was dealing with
describing defining filter for one a
half year now and we decided to detach
that resource extension and Saturday to
suit because it's not suitable to have
that firmer stuff here I think and I did
that tonight so it was a very short
notice that didn't bring us up basically
know what whatever we had read it before
not maybe at the intro and and this is
based on maps basically and know now I
didn't see this turning of events that
this would be a norm actually saving
maps so that's great maybe have a look
at it maybe we can find some compromises
its merging
and the Sunnis I was wondering that Hank
yeah the question to you like you you a
cause of the of the information model
document so it's a feels a little bit
strange when you suddenly overnight work
on some stuff and put it out and then
say oh maybe we should cooperate when
you actually the cohorts
yeah that's my my problem was I was such
a strong disconnected in the data model
and things Brendan just explained
I couldn't just use the information
model and also there was a need to do
this for second because were second on
Friday and we want to move on with Co
switch and the fire of hiware the shrim
where stuff really was basically holding
us back
that was never gone through the last
call in any case we had to cut this oz
in this iteration and I had to cut it
put it somewhere and so the most obvious
solution was just to cut it out right
now and put it here it's not it's not
even adopted I mean it's just associated
floating around so it's an individual
submission it's just in this context and
I think I indicated this last to suit
sessions also redundantly but this
should not be a surprise that that we
were cutting that out and bringing that
here because I think I advertised that
ready
last year I hope everybody I'm all about
that
if not I'm very sorry so inside the
authenticated container so that's inside
the manifest itself the text is
authenticated with a digest or
potentially the Coast Whitlock is
identified with the died with a digest
and that is about all there is to it for
several texts on to multiple payloads so
payloads have three components a
resource identifier which is to say
exactly where to find the thing
installation instructions and with that
can include cryptographic info when it
comes to decryption and the asset
description which is the
the size the location to store it and
the digest of the asset so what we've
done here is split payloads out into
multiple parts and at the same time
allowed for multiple payloads to be used
we needed a an extension to this concept
specifically for Delta and other
advanced use cases and what that did was
it turned a leonis dependencies and
payloads all into resource references
which makes things a little bit easier
assets are now separate from their
resource identifiers so that they can be
overridden independent manifests and
installation instructions are separate
as well so the resources were separated
from assets which makes all resource
temperate references effectively the
same there's no need to distinguish
between an alias to dependency or a
payload resources define a local or a
remote input either a URI or a diet
sorry a the local or remote input in the
form of a URI and a digest assets define
an installed image which is the size the
digest in the location so due to some
discussions on the mailing list
particularly with Frank and avi and
sorry if I pronounced that wrong from
Nordic they in particular there's they
had a requirement to be able to check
some conditions after installation now
specifically that was some kind of
digest or a custom condition of which we
haven't elaborated on yet I'm not sure
quite what goes in there as some
obviously need to be checked before
installation so there were two choices
here we could make two lists of of
conditions or we can duplicate condition
identifiers to specify the summer
preconditions and summer post conditions
it seems like separating it into two
lists
is the right choice because again in as
with the pull parser concept it makes it
quite clear for the device exactly what
it should be doing at any given time and
with the duplicate condition identifiers
that would not be the case the device
would have to process that list multiple
times and the cost for making two lists
is not high next slide please
the component identifier ad has replaced
the storage identifier the storage
identifier was it would not necessarily
adequate for all use cases so devices
can be aggregates with more than one
processor with two or more different
storage systems and the component
identifier allows for designating which
storage system you're on on top of that
storage systems and hardware components
can be nested so it seems like the
component identifier really needs to be
a list and if it's already a list then
rather than having a discrete component
identifier and storage at the fire we
can merge these two things into a single
list
I saw someone go up no no okay
not if I'm right shall we continue then
is that the last slide it's not the last
slide it might be I think it is yep all
right so that is where we're at on the
serialization then
I think chairs wrap-up is investing in
each other's stuff hey thank you Brennan
thank you do you wrap up we're calling
Dave back busy wrangling blue sheets out
there where are the hood did you get all
the blue sheets checked out
hey where is the big blue sheet if you
see a blue sheet nearby pointer hold it
up this one there should be another blue
sheet out there somewhere over there
okay okay so so today we talked quite a
bit about a number of some changes to
the architecture that need to be done
but mostly changes to the information
model and and manifests so I think it
would make sense to talk briefly about
when we could expect those updates to be
completed so let's start with the
architecture when do you think you can
have an updated architecture posted with
the changes discussed next week that
would be great and then information
model probably more more extensive the
changes yeah that's a little bit more
that's a little trickier because of the
the changes on the other documents or so
I think that would be more like
synchronize that in September so I think
we might want to also discuss when when
we might have a virtual interim because
it would be ideal to have that update
done before then it seems natural that
we might have a virtual in mid to late
September
and how does has that sound as far as
timing good for me I am I was just yeah
I was just wondering about some of the
other guys who are very active on the
list but I just don't happen to be here
in the room and they would probably have
some comments on the format as they had
comments before so that will so if we
distribute some of the notes that we
gathered today and have some time for an
entire group to digest those because
some of that is obviously a little
detailed right and so if we then pull
that stuff together into into one or
into into the document beginning of
September maybe the second because it's
September then we could have the intra
meeting afterwards yeah so are there any
concerns in the room with having a
virtual maybe towards the end of
September sounds like something that we
can we can plan around then yep so yeah
data model so we talked about some of
the changes that need to be done on the
data model Hank you also posted a data
model so I would encourage the authors
of both drafts to get together and to
try to sync up on on the differences
that may exist between between the two
I'm are you willing to do that
can you get it like so high this is
again not at the mic
the driver was that announcing this over
and over again we are now in the state
that we are will drive go straight
through working group last call and we
had to cut that out and before I cut it
out I made it cementec equivalent to the
current submitted data model so that
there is no confusion there why is this
differently named and that's what
recognize everything it's just all
written in maps now and it's not in the
coast with a core draft anymore it is
now again cut out and and this is
basically what I announced here and
twice already so it's not a big surprise
again and I tested that and there's no
problem to consolidated I think because
it is easy to make so what he did is
especially if it snaps right yeah so
what I so is it but what you did is you
took the information on a print
percentage cop and changed it from area
to maps is that no actually we had a map
structure for firmware in close but for
over 18 months and we started to align
more that it suit suit formed and we saw
all those what firm word that we should
maybe wait for them and then the data
you did
manifest the data map format and um and
this all took a lot of time so we
aligned with that but we'd never aligned
with the information model is very new
we always aligned with the data model
because it was very easy to align with
it was very specific and also in sea war
SPRs the coast weights so that that's
why I did not use the information model
to allowed to create the update the
I'm from extension but I used the
current data model because would be
easier for people to compare them yeah
the current data model that print
percentage is brand new
it's like was published in 2nd of July
and so it and that's a that's what he
presented back then now with this in
Mumbai we made already some changes so I
don't I don't see like if there if the
contribution is should we use maps
instead of arrays and that's justifies
the publication of the document that's
fine but I don't understand the
relationship then to end the working
class called before cosby'd and so on if
it will most likely change again as we
are getting the feedback from the guys
the difficulty is in this is not the
decision about area or maps I think that
the more time went into discussing on
how the whole structure looks in the
first place because different people had
different use cases and trying to
encapsulate all of those was sort of
complicated yeah that's why I used a
very fresh one that's been right now all
right now and it did the difference
between the manifest that is there and
not become an episode think and the one
that I submitted is that the one is
tailored to be a resource extensions to
concise software identifiers so they are
embedded in software I'd its width
and coach weights and the manifest
cannot be just embedded in crosswords
and as I think someone's highlighted
before there's a lot of benefit to use
cause weights because there is this
texture representation for humans
already there can be detached from the
other stuff and and there are other
semantics like like the supersedeas
patches or absolutes other things is
also already there and entities and and
I mean everything about software is
already defined and then we don't have
to reinvent
the difficulty with this working in in
the working group I believe is well I
will ultimately be to get those
companies who then need to make the
changes to their code in the discussions
that's that that's the difficult part
it's whether you can reuse some existing
snippet of a few text lines it's great
it's great if you can even use those
data structures but that will not make
the difference it will it will make a
difference whether Nordic semiconductor
di Infineon etc Celia use case is
represented and feel comfortable to up
put that into the bootloader I think
that what will make it the difference
sure I'm Dave altmer as an individual
contributor I think I think the desire
with with curse word is you know there's
some historic work in this space that's
been done there um we'd like to see some
convergence between um that historic
work and the work that's going on within
within this working group so you know to
some extent Hanks draft is a starting
point in which we can maybe drive some
of that convergence you know going going
forward and I believe that that the
coast would draft represents a good path
forward as far as representing some of
this management information there's some
adoption of a closely related
specification in the industry already
around an xml-based format which curse
width is parallel to and so I think it's
worth exploring whether for management
news cases whether that the coast would
might be applicable here um I think we
could arrange a presentation for the
virtual interim to maybe explore how how
Coast wave might might be useful to
decipher those those use cases if
there's there's interest in
in doing that um and I think Hank is
interested in you know talking about
some of the improvements that he's made
to the manifest model as well I he's
he's fixed a number of issues but but I
think that Brendan also fixed them but
they're not just submitted yet so though
I think that's that's not an issue
actually sure at least that is my
impression so now the thing maps are in
there because coach boots are basically
hierarchal Maps so that's the only
reason why they are I use maps so and
also again I'm surprised that this is a
surprise because I actually really
reiterate it a lot so sorry I've ever
heard
please don't do this here or just stop
with that and I would have done I'm
sorry if I disrupted any processes by
that yeah okay so um so I think this is
yes
chair head back on so I think we have
some issues to discuss relating to the
to the manifest will be helpful to get
an update of that draft out and I'm in
early September and I think we can talk
through I'm more of these issues during
during the virtual interim yeah Brendan
does that timeline work for you yes that
timeline should work for me
excellent okay so we'll we'll start to
coordinate on the list around scheduling
we'll probably put out a doodle pull to
try to narrow down some some dates for
the with the virtual we also have taken
an action we need to add the information
model to as a milestone so we'll work
with the ATS to get that milestone
approved is it the arc
I'm sorry it's the architecture yes any
other actions that
okay so um so with that any any other
comments we can we can do open mic for a
little while if there aren't any other
comments or questions
honest so close question ah yeah sorry
but I was wondering whether some people
already know whether they are or they
are planning to be in Bangkok and
planning to attend the hackathon yeah I
don't know if people make their plans
already so fine advance but would be
good to see a show of hands to
coordinate with some of you if in case
you know it's actually number I see five
six maybe I'm some of you going to
participate that the hackathon as well
not just at the ITF meeting yeah sure
okay hey me know it but now I see a
different number of hands I do so so
raise your hand if you plan to attend
the hackathon at the Bangkok IETF
meeting so do you have 610 would you be
interested in attending the suit
hackathon raise your hand yeah so I'm
seeing I'm seeing maybe four or five
some hand waving oh yeah and also um
maybe we should a remote participation
that works pretty nicely last time at
the Berlin hackathon I was surprised how
many people were remote if you're
interested in remotely participating
would you raise your hand I see a couple
okay so that's maybe something that we
should explore then yeah sounds good
honest anything else
okay I think with that we will conclude
the meeting thank you all for attending
I will see you in Bangkok hopefully
[Music]
specially given there's a number of I
think it could be great
[Music]
and then ran off before I could ask him
a method we'll have time
you