all right John come up you remember
working with run mm-hmm
so as opposed to like earlier meetings
we don't we're not spending more first
ten minutes of the meeting field
figuring around will blood connectors to
the predictor because the nine
secretarial people provide well for us
all right
this is token mining at IDF 102 on the
final homestretch of the IDF um Montreux
and you know this is one note well you
know take a take a note of the note wall
and I think you will know what it says
so um what we're gonna do today is to
briefly update you on core document is
you status and then we're gonna do proxy
and and we're going to talk about at the
station and then open mic if you're if
you if you think you're missing the 0 RT
+ 1 or TT stuff here
that's because first one it couldn't be
and he said some message that he hadn't
really made any significant update so I
think we was gonna cover those things on
the list
um so John do you wanna do you want to
do status update the so we have a core
document status update which is kind of
like in the RFC editor queue for all
three documents
so I think I think you have to do that
in the pink box okay yeah let's do that
again
because I'm not sure yeah yeah the
interpretive dance celebration of core
document it is alright alright let's
keep going yeah but it didn't yeah
alright so yes documents are in the is
yeah in the RC editors queue as of like
literally 5 minutes ago which of course
is a good thing and you know
yay for up yeah toss for having done
this very well done alright so Brian
let's see if we can there's a there's a
kicker here do you want it you want it
yeah but that Mike doesn't seem to work
try fiddling with it or something about
turning it on there you go big crowd
here at the last Friday meeting thanks
for coming out stating my name I'm Brian
Campbell with me identity and I'm here
want to welcome you all to not San
Francisco it's a joke
this meeting was supposed to be in San
Francisco that got changed okay I'm
gonna talk about hcp s token binding
with TLS terminated reverse proxies I
have this here
all that work that was user error so I
just want to kind of cover what what the
problem statement is why proposing this
work and trying to push it forward it's
really common for HTTP applications to
be deployed behind some layer that
terminates TLS a reverse proxy or
something like that in front of the
actual application terminates may be a
tough word because oftentimes TLS is
re-established with the back end but the
the client connection to the the
application as the client knows is
terminated by some sort of reverse proxy
and then content has passed back to the
the back end server the application
server you see this in all sorts of
things in actual commercial products in
all sorts of open-source implementations
Apache and in Ex and more and more so
now and as a service type deployments
CloudFlare Amazon application layer load
balancer and for Microsoft has some
variant of that and tow combining is
something we've all been working on in
here but in general for applications the
back-end applications to take advantage
of the benefits that token binding
brings some sort of information needs to
go from that front end layer that's
terminating TLS back to the the
application layer in the absence of some
kind of standard to facilitate this
everybody's going to do it different
which is a real pain for I'm sure all of
us have experienced in one way or
another or they won't do it at all thus
sort of undermining you know the benefit
of token binding or the potential for
adoption there's also an alarming
shortage of acronyms in the world so I
wanted to thank Jeff for bringing TT rp2
to me after I fumbled over saying and
writing it a few times so TT RPS TLS
terminate in reverse proxy and sometimes
say that for sure so that's why I'm here
the solution overview the draft is now
in in draft 5 and basically it's to
define a set of HTTP headers which
enable the T TRP in the backend
application this to function together as
though they're a single logical
deployment of server-side HTTP tow
combining the TT RP gets the message
validates the token binding message
passed in in the normal sector combining
header and removes it from the requested
dispatches at the back end what it does
instead is assuming it's valid
as a new header this SEC provided token
binding ID it's a little long but that's
currently how I name things and it
includes their the basics t4 URL encoded
provided token binding ID directly in
the request if there's a referred token
binding ID it includes that with a
different name refer to a mining ID same
encoding and then kind of for
extensibility
there's the SEC other token binding ID
header which then is formatted as a
comma separated list of additional token
bindings with each one with a hex of the
type which is just 1 byte concatenated
with a period and then concatenated with
the same encoding of the token binding
idea itself the solution requires some
kind of trust between the TT RP in the
backend server at deployment and then it
also requires that the PRP sanitizes
these headers so the client doesn't
inject them directly to bypass the
security controls they get at this is a
very common pattern and in reverse proxy
type deployments just to give sort of a
visual of the overview sometimes it help
help me the client does sort of regular
old-fashioned token by name over issue
yes with the with what it perceives to
be the origin server or the server in
general which in this case is the TT RP
it negotiates it as usual then start
sending the messages the reverse proxy
the TT RP validates the token binding
message sanitizes in the headers and
then passes the encoded token binding
and as the new header to the backend
just shown in here and obviously the
referred in the others as well if
applicable and this allows the the
backend application server to bind
cookies or other tokens to that tow
combining ID or verified into the
binding there of a few changes in
happening since London we've had a few
reviews thank you for those that have
done that published drafts 4 and 5
largely editorial updates and
clarifications but I did add a section
on TLS versions and best practices
pointed to be CP 195 and also made
mention of Nix tow combine negotiation
for TLS 1/3 draft and mention of TLS 1/3
in general just to sort of make it
clearly expanded use and scope of the
scope of this isn't just to TLS one too
but try to make it sort of variable and
so it would age a little bit better in
the document just changed at a
suggestion change the hex change to use
the hex didge core a B and F rule for
the encoded token binding type rather
than and mention in the text the case
insensitivity of insensitivity of it
rather than spelling it out directly and
a be enough I sort of invented it myself
first and somebody pointed out there was
a better definition to refer to so I
just did that there added some examples
with the with the other type editorial
dates and I added a few people the
reviewers the acknowledgement list and I
also removed the little piece that said
hey let me know if you if you think you
should be acknowledged and I forgot you
so that's not in the draft anymore but
it still stands please let me know
willing to provide a little bit of
design motivation and rationale for the
way things work as they do now
the main idea here was to make the
common and simple usage simple and
that's particularly true targeted at the
web application developer that could be
read as sort of a slight to a web
application developer but I can say that
because I am one it's good to make
things simple for them but we want to
still make the other cases the other
other things possible which is something
that working group is requested so the
overwhelming vast majority of usage of
Toe combining is going to be the
provided token binding it's going to be
the only one and and it's going to be in
every HTTP request and this oh sorry
following my own notes and just quoting
a bit of the protocol here basically
it's a token binding protocol
implications should make token binding
IDs available to the application as an
opaque byte sequence that's exactly what
we're doing here we're providing and
there's an encoded because it has to be
for a CV and encoded opaque byte
sequence to the back-end application
this is really simple for the
application developer to do tow
combining if the roughest of the
infrastructure is in place they just
grab one well-known named header and use
the value done that's it the same is
true for refer to combining in terms of
usage it's simple because it's specified
and we we know what it is it is probably
going to be a distant second in terms of
usage
for a relatively specialized use case
which is the an IDP or a token provider
or some entity that's issuing tokens for
another domain which is less common but
still valuable let's try to make that
case simple as well same pattern and
then we have 250 for other currently
undefined took combining types with some
text quoted in here about sort of how
they should be used and shouldn't use
they should be ignored but it could
possibly contain them so really it takes
a proxy that knows what the type is to
pass it along and a back-end application
that knows what to do with it but it's
somewhat more complicated encoding of
the type and a string concatenation of
the encoded value is used to allow for
all these other types to be passed so
it's it's not restricted in that context
but it is intentionally a different
encoding type to keep the simple cases
as simple as possible while still
allowing for the more complex cases so
leaving Montreal as the core three
documents I'm not going to dance but
thanks John for that good RFC on
basically at this point going to ask
requests that we consider moving this to
a working group last call and then
because we're in Canada I imply it and
said please and I did it in French
because we're in Montreal Cebu black so
open working group questions anybody
feel but this isn't ready to go to
working group last call does any meet
anybody feel it is ready to go working
group law school anybody want to say
anything we can do a hum but if nobody
has comments at the mic on this you know
I'm ready to go home and here's dick
dick hard Amazon I think you know if
we're gonna have token binding deployed
we're gonna need something like this
all right and I think we're gonna do a
hum now two two options for and against
giving a working with Glasgow will
confirm at the list and hum now if you
if you support from or it's different
you wanna did you want to say something
yeah just a short question I asked you
before whether there would be any reason
to provide any means to authenticate for
the for the application server to
authenticate that the relate tell
combining information actually comes
from the reverse proxy and and you said
well there's you don't want to do that
extra complexity I still have a question
whether if there would be a good reason
in the future is it there's an
extensibility possibility where you
could add that in some sense if it would
be important to one common on that is
that there's still something required
it's just not specified the mechanism
within the draft so the proxies should
authenticate to the backend with mutual
TLS with private network and you know
restricted IPs with some other
authentication so that that that it
knows that's where it's coming from
there was discussion in this group but
it wouldn't be appropriate to do it in
this group of defining a more
generalized mechanism for a reverse
proxy to convey to a back-end which
headers it had in fact looked at and
processed to to to do that as a more
standardized mechanism that didn't seem
to be the the appetite in in the HP
working group to go forward with that
if in fact though that was work that was
undertaken my expectation would be that
it would be generalized such that it
could be applied to any specific header
used in this kind of context security
aware context between the proxy in the
back end and and thus this would be as
applicable as any other similar content
to that kind of protection is going to
be very important and I just wonder if
the door is closed completely to add
type of I do not I dunno I think it's
closed completely certainly didn't know
anything we didn't have a conversation
with the relevant other work it was a
consensus and discussed here with the
electors that this is not the place to
do it right this is not the work you
have to do it and it's a general problem
but so far there hasn't been appetite to
do it that doesn't preclude you know
anybody including you right from going
to go to it HTTP work here don't say hey
I need to solve this problem you know
would you consider a raft and I think
the main I think is appropriate pain
point and concern of the question was if
in fact that happened is there anything
in here that might preclude it from
working with that and there's certainly
nothing that I'm aware of or put in
there intentionally it should be fine
and applicable to that kind of thing
okay someone comes to me I think there's
a there are too many options in this
place for us to actually know anything
anything down concretely we're talking
about attestations client authentication
I don't think the suggestion of a
private network is actually a good one
but but it happens it happens
unfortunately till I said SSL added and
removed here I remind everyone I noticed
that there's nothing in the draft on
this point certainly not other security
considerations I couldn't find anything
specifically on that point I think it's
probably elsewhere there's probably
worth calling out really really firmly
with the expectations about it so in my
own mind as the writer I thought I was
pretty clear about it and a security
consideration I'll double check but and
if it's not it should be so I agree with
you but I my intent was to have that
spelled out both if I can make it cool
yeah if we do a work if we actually get
to harm that actually we were working
with post-cold today right in that case
would you okay like doing that as your
as a like a beautifully got to say one
thing which is that you can just decide
to do a working good last call at this
point you're not aware of any open
issues no-one else is raising any I
don't think we need a hunt
I'm certainly not going to get a hum in
a room with this a few people so no but
I know what I know the Rebbe said I was
gonna hum them if you want us to hum on
something I'm sure let's just do it
neither any reason for doing a broker's
cordless yeah all right anybody opposed
all right all right done thank you I
think that's it all right
let's see it's Monday all right
I think speaking of clothing jeff has
said this is the first time he's ever
seen me in casual clothes so I'm waiting
for Tony to follow our lead
so this is a continuation of Tessa TLS
tell combining this draft has been in
the group for a couple years now but we
only started seriously considering it as
of London I'll apologize to the group
because I did submit a revision this
week I don't think that that's normally
the way generally like to do things
putting a putting a draft on everybody's
plate during the meeting but I actually
got some very good feedback in the past
couple weeks from our Andre Microsoft
and and I thought it was good to
implement it as much as I could so I'll
try this I'll go over this okay we go to
the next slide yeah well you can just
click power Kim and okay
so you know to give a recap of well I
think everybody knows what TLS token
mining is about it's a little bit more
than just bearer tokens it's also proof
of possession of a private key and the
current specification requires that the
ekm be signed and there's also the
so-called tope tope bonding type talk
line key parameter so they have to be
exchanged as part of the as part of the
it's part of the score the whole message
flow so where does that a station come
in the browser could maintain private
keys associated with token mining but
the problem is is that user agents are
in user space and therefore there's
they're subject to potential compromise
and particularly browser maintained key
stores are vulnerable we seen we've seen
some advances at all yo and platforms to
actually to actually actually better
protect key stores but right now I think
we see with a lot of TLS token binding
uh implementations that that's what you
have user user space protection of keys
native applications it's not much better
you know there's a there's a lot of
reliance on open source libraries
there's code obfuscation and you know in
basically crossing your fingers that
your binaries don't get reverse
engineered so I mean even if you're
talking about native clients
implementing TLS tow combining they if
they maintain a private key store there
are still vulnerabilities with the there
are still vulnerable --'tis with that
so this is where attestation comes in
so attestation wanna go one definition
is given here and now I know we've had
two bar boss this week where you
discussed a lot of different views on
whatever attestation remote attestation
is about but it's generally a piece of
software providing a sort of providing
information that's cryptographically
verifiable about the environment in
which
the private key is stored specifically
in the case of token binding it could
also be more general purpose about the
security profile of the device and you
can include several things in there
including the health of the device you
know for instance Android safety net
attestation is an example where you
actually get a runtime assessment the
integrity of the operating system
another thing could be an inner
third-party application is in the
environment where the where the talk
mind implementation is running it more
specifically where the key store is uh
this door some of applications may be
now where also any suspicious events
that may or may have occurred on the
device so attestation data is generally
combined in a structured format and then
assigned potentially encrypted so it's
cryptographically verify verifiable it's
a relying party this recap sorry this
isn't coming up perfect on there let's
go through yeah so if we look at the
current at the current draft for a talk
by protocol specifically was called out
when in where the extensions are defined
that that attestation is envisioned as a
potential extension so this is kind of
trending a little bit of new ground now
that we have the three main drafts going
into our C status now we can go ahead
and say ok how do we would want to
define extensions this is the first
draft that I can see where we've
actually trying to define an extension
and it's consistent with what I think
the vision was of the group when
extensions were when the extension
mechanism was defined in first place so
based on input from the last meeting I
was told to reach out to you in the
chrome and the edge teams to see what
should be the initial attestation
formats and there are a couple of things
I that have been pretty clear the chrome
team the chrome team is maintaining a
browser-based keystore
you could provide an attestation for
that I really see a point I'm hoping
that one day we'll get to a point where
there's enough performant eStore
implementations where Chrome will be
able to but it will be able to move off
from a user space maintain key store so
I defined an Android key store
attestation is one of the initial
formats and the anticipation of that
that's open to any cut in put from the
group for edge there's also a problem
with the problem there as far as
performance is current concern for TPM
based key stores I think though based on
some offline discussions Microsoft will
come in as so if this giraffe goes
forward Microsoft will come in to extend
it with their preferred approach using a
more performant key store than a TPM I
put in a TPM just a boot it you know
just to you just to seed this
attestation this has these attestation
what will hopefully then should become
an attestation registry for token
binding yeah yes for all remote
attendees places
my question was Eric not mark by the way
why explicitly version 1.2 supposed to
$2 certainly difference in this respect
in terms of key store Bart heavily from
what often and what about the know about
the no but a web part and we defined it
with respect to 1.2 my interpretation
was that this isn't kind of a general
TPM attestation that you see as part of
the secure boot that you see generated
secure boot this is something specific
to the token binding operation and I
thought the version 1.2 solution was a
was sufficient for that but yeah there's
a lot of different this isn't even the
only TPM attestation in the spec but in
the web author inspector is also there's
also an EC DAA
version of version of that at a station
as well I'm open to other I'm open to
other things the 1.2 I thought was
pretty well understood it's 509 based
you could uh it serves a job for this
particular purpose so all the current
proposal attestation having a spec or
based on signing of the ekm for people
in room who had actually been following
the web often stacked they want to
compare it and I guess said that
borrowed heavily from that because there
was a lot of a hard work not so much
just for the Android key scores and
keystore much for interpreting the TCG
specifications for the TPM attestation
then I wanted to leverage there are some
primary differences the web oven at a
station signature is over a combination
of what they call client data not data
the client data where the client data
incorporates the challenge a server
generated challenge in this case I
didn't see a need for a server generated
challenge because we have a km so that
binds to the so that binds to the TLS
session it works for the token binding
message I don't see why I couldn't work
for the attestation other thing is web
often requires between reach of the
actual algorithm used outside of the
certs
I personally worry about such things
because I figure because there's always
a slim possibility that the algorithm
you received out of and could not be the
same it may not be the same as what you
see receiving the x.509 so I just say
okay let's leverage the algorithm feel
in a certificate um but even that's
something that uh is easy to it's easy
to separate out and if it helps out the
relying party for a quicker verification
can do that yeah you just said if I
expel annoying yeah there's an algorithm
fielding Android key store we do now go
ahead and feel notify by going for the
for the TPM attestation
so Android key store a station is
basically a 509 cert there's a there's
nothing else
okay just because like from online the
other IDs don't correspond one-to-one
with actual signature loops
yeah okay so I think I'm a I think I
need to go back and verify this what
with the TPM five the 509 for Android
keep strong I'm pretty confident that
that's yeah as far as I can tell that's
the algorithm that was used for the
creation of the signature
the thing is though if you read Google's
documentation they don't specifically
require inclusion of that field in the
search so I'm just saying that like that
um you know fiber on keys or like I've
typed RSA encryption and so it could be
any signature and we can actually PSS or
pkcs1 and you can't tell or maybe maybe
you are say encryption and say and then
the same thing is true quasi true for
like you know sometimes for easy so like
you can't you can't go from the five
lines aren't necessarily notes in charge
of what yeah so actually why I got you
online
so what do you so what is your
recommendation if if the client ok the
client in this case a token by Incline
knows what algorithm it used to create
the signature because it you know I
commanded whatever key store to get
create that signature so what it what
should a relying party do when the
algorithm conveyed by the client is
different from the algorithm in the
search well I guess it depends what we
mean by I mean so I mean it's only
search video to our business or
obviously ones the one that covers the
surface and sure to ignore nails when
that tells you kind of key you have um
so I mean there's I mean those do you
need to match up um or you know are
going to work right on the yeah I mean I
think
so you mean like it's you know it's it's
the the the algorithm in the services
like ECG essay and and and and that and
the one with one group and like this
sorry it's like it's like claims to be
like ECG is a one group and like the
little group I don't know like I mean
yeah okay so I'll do that and on safer
next version I'll just separate out
algorithm thing to do some different
efficiencies for doing that but it yeah
like I said it's that's the one thing
that it kind of been scratching my head
over and I think you know for web ought
that I'm scratching my head over that's
you okay could go down okay so this is
actually changing I'm not sure this even
if the group wants to do this
I'm they even sure it belongs and I'm
not even sure this mechanism belongs in
this draft basically yeah unfortunately
Dirk and the rest of the Google guys
don't seem to be here today and I don't
like talking about people when they're
not here okay yes okay so Dirk convey
Dirk convey to me in a one-on-one
discussion and he said that there needs
to be a mechanism for suppressing in
attestation in case the relying party
isn't interested in wasting bits over
the wire on that so I kind of looked at
it a little bit I kind of looked at it
and said well how do i how what would be
the best way to do this and I thought
that a simple way to do it is the way we
treat cipher suites in the TLS handshake
and therefore I proposed a new TLS
extinction code point for token for
token bonding sessions when extensions
are used where the client hello was this
includes a list of supported extensions
and the server hello would include would
include a subset of those extensions
listed in the client list now I've been
scratching my head over this a lot first
off you're bloating the TLS handshake
which is not particularly fun second
thing is I don't like the idea of
defining
top mining Kok mind uh ty6 in Chico
point I'd rather you said there wasn't
the one that's already there third thing
is I'm still not sure if servers have an
interest in suppressing extensions in
which they have no interest in because
they can always ignore them oh yeah
undrinkable Microsoft so the bigger
issue with this proposal they think is
that it doesn't solve the stated problem
if the stated problem is that the client
avoids generating you know an
attestation statement which can be
expensive and you know putting a little
bytes from the wire because those
statements tend to be large right it's
they involve a certificate changing
stuff certificate chain so if that's the
the goal then just saying you know hey I
support at the station you know and then
waiting for the server to respond
doesn't solve this problem make it
should be much more expressive than that
you have to say I support GPM at the
station DSM at the station key store at
the station you know whatever you
support and the server has to say well I
can verify this type of attestation with
these possibly even with these trusted
roots or not like that's a separate
question of you know do we want to send
trusted roots that we trust but like we
want to at least agree on the type of
attestation they do and possibly the
signature of the rhythms we're willing
to verify and all of that stuff so I
think you know just advertising support
for this extension is not very helpful
so we weed out I mean we discussed this
quite a bit in web Orton as well and I
think the balance between we wanted to
we wanted to basically follow the WBC's
fingerprint device fingerprinting
guidance which is minimizing exposure
potential privacy privacy violating
information which could include
additional device capabilities so Minoo
if we feel the way this risk isn't so
much which feature like token mining
then yeah I think you know advertising
the capability is one thing
I think as far as trusted rates and I
think that corresponding with you on
this private way I actually propose that
in web authentication where a server
could actually say these are my trust
anchors that is interested in and
conveyed it to the browser so they could
actually use that for selection of
authenticators and I was told I was told
in that context at least that service
providers weren't interested in such
capability so right so I'm not insisting
on the specific components we can
discuss them at length like what needs
to be negotiated but they think it's
more than saying I supported the station
versus greater not supported the station
and this mechanism does not solve that
problem yeah fair enough it's not very
expressive and but I also want to do
before I went into defining on that I
wanted to get the group's interest as to
whether this is even something work
worth pursuing in the context of token
binding and that is basically having an
ability to negotiate extensions and yeah
and and therefore ergo not having the
client send extensions in which the
server has no interest in I agree that
if you first server to make an informed
decision it should be a lot more
probably than saying I just support
extensions it should be what I should
just support attestation should be what
types and potentially even what routes
if you want to if you want to even go
that far it's an open question right so
so to this question under HIPAA both
Microsoft again so to this question I
think that it's kind of overkill to
advertise your extensions before you
send them the the draft currently says
that this over ignores extensions that
you know the server doesn't understand
it's you know it's as if in TLS first
you negotiated that you will send us an
i10 you sent us and I you know it seems
like a second layer of negotiation that
so far I don't see this work but okay
thanks Andrea if we if the group feels
it doesn't need it then I don't even
need to define a new extension code
point so what that means is that you can
live with the existing TOS top bind
extension extension code point and the
client supports an extension it sends it
off the server is interested in it find
it it goes ahead and
it goes and parses and interprets it and
acts upon it or adjusting noises it
tosses it to the ground so I haven't
spoken this visited Dirk about this but
to to try to show interpret his I think
one of the issues is that it's not
enough just about support it's also
about if you're comparing to web bottom
the reason that we have the
authorization conveyance professional
reference there is that in many cases
the server does not want explicitly does
not want at the station because it's
privacy reveal and server may not want
that that could be because the server
does not want the data because it ends
up logs it could also be because in web
often the client or the browser may
actually throw it back so you I for that
and that's probably a concern that is
not necessarily valid in the context
we're talking by me but it's it's not
just about supporting optimizing what
goes on the wire but it's also that
that's one of the other reason for
deterrence yeah yeah I thought it I
thought about that too so there's two so
one of the things we talked about in web
off and not just with that a station
where the extensions in general is that
the attestation was originating outside
of the browser
therefore removes the privacy violating
the browser wouldn't necessarily be able
to do anything about it they couldn't
modify the data without killing the
signature right I think in this case so
they talked mine stack it's fully
controlled by the browser so at least if
the browser feels that okay I don't have
the user permission for this it can
suppress it and the server the server
just would never receive the extension I
think the problems a little bit better
bound in the talk-line context tell you
what can you go back to Dirk and ask him
if this is really necessary because
you've heard Andres opinion on this and
this is what I very privately from
Derrick yes can can I make a suggestion
there if you know no we know I mean this
is not a working what document and we
haven't even talked about that yet but
what I would suggest is that you go talk
to that TLS working group about this but
it because it seems to me that you're
gonna have like similar situations in
other extensions where a person's
encrypted sni right where well you know
the client is you know deciding to send
SNI information to their server and the
server doesn't have a say whether that
client does that or not right there's
there's no negotiable okay with me
sending an SI request
right before you send a as now so and
this sort of seems to me to me to be
like a similar situation right so you
know maybe have a conversation with the
TLS folks some of whom are in the room
right to figure out whether this even
makes sense to try to get out of this
yeah so so so here's the thing
attestation being one example there
could be situations where the server is
not interest in the a data in an
extension a talk mind extension that's
being produced by the client but now in
the latest IDE I put in a way for the
server to suppress this particular
extension but it's kind of more general
it can be used with all extension what
problem where you heard us off so
there's a so as honoring it brought up I
think you would love to wait for a
second if an extent if for instance like
an attestation extension is potentially
privacy all includes privacy privacy
tracking information a server may say
look I don't want you to send it at all
yeah well I guess the attestation is
tension like why is why is that to
Association attention to being tied to
tell us rather the token binding no my
point is is that okay see so like the
wait that relationship works right is
the client gets his extensions first the
server sends extensions right and so the
if you want to send the if you if you
want to access it so so if you're saying
I support at the station which I think
it's been extension I support at the
station or like
decision information it's I support
attestation the attestation information
yeah the wait else works is like
basically you advertise you get the
advertise what you support and me Ike I
like you know like lots of and
he'll doesn't like leaks like sniff I
kind of figure pre information about you
about your client and maybe we should
solve that problem don't like we're not
house all year yeah so is so in this
case the way the way I'd kind of propose
it to summarize is that the client sends
a list of extensions of sports one of
them could be attestation the server
says the sends a list of what he would
select among that that he could support
and if it's not interested in
attestation it would just say no so how
long is out how was that information was
super then then but then even next time
I connect a tones in that station
extension yeah you wouldn't you the kind
the client would never include that in
the top line message is what it we're
never including extension that the
server says it doesn't okay there's the
claim hello and then there's the talk by
messages right yeah the top and so they
talk by messages there were the
extension dater good okay so I mean so
the retailers works now right if you
didn't want if you if the client does at
the station but the server doesn't want
it then the pattern would be the client
offers it the server agility more is it
and then the talk - doesn't happen
that's the pattern the expect now right
okay um so I guess what I'm saying is if
what you want is to suppress the clients
offer about so station yeah in the
client hello like at all which is I say
isn't no no that's not okay I think
you're fine all right I don't Microsoft
so I would also say that the the premise
that the server will suppress
attestation on privacy grounds to me
doesn't make sense because first of all
privacy of the client is something the
client should be more concerned about
than the sovereign and they think any
any attestation mechanism that we devise
should not create fingerprinting
possibilities like or or you know client
tracking or link ability possibilities
so so I don't think that's the like the
motivation okay
yes I'm Alan Thompson I think you've got
the basic design is is the same as with
token binding the client advertisers the
that enter station it supports the
server list the subset of those that is
willing to accept and the advantage that
you have in the case where the servers
don't want particular forms of
attestation is that the client doesn't
have to generate them and then spend the
bytes on them but that's exactly the
same analysis as you have with the
standard talking binding so nothing
changes no nothing's no extra
complication they did okay so I've got a
alright think so maybe Google we can get
a get a little bit more thought from you
guys have R&R I can go back home Thanks
okay so we have the opening we have the
opening questions is what MOA says
should even be in extensions negotiation
mechanism because the server can always
draw up extensions that it doesn't care
about um you know I'm personally not
that convinced about saving bits over
the wire but for your client generated
extension to the server doesn't care
about but uh you know maybe it could be
a it maybe could be consideration of
future should supported attestation
types the advertised the current ID only
says whether the client supports
attestation I was going by the web
author and model on that but as I
pointed out it can be more expressive we
should support the attestation trust
anchors be advertised so that's another
thing that's enough that's another thing
that that's another item that uh that
you know we need to you know I need to
consider you know and also the proper
format Andreea you to guess something
there's fgd ends and such to do that as
well
Martin yeah so mutton Thomson I think
that the mechanism that we discussed
just just now covers the first two
points I don't think there's much value
in us having a single boolean value here
I mean if you say you support
attestation and there could potentially
be multiple types of them it sort of
makes a bit more sense to actually
negotiate the types okay
don't advertise trust anchors we don't
do this anywhere else
and it's a cork Meyer I don't know what
the current listed that was basically
that was basically TPM v2 and Ricky
store that's that's yeah when the
verification procedures are related to
that that's you have to read the draft
the situation with respect to other
stations might be further improved by
the other work that you're doing here
rather than trying to solve that problem
here we will have to make a call as to
how how mature that work is with respect
to those other things and and how well
deployed it is before before we get to
that data point and that's probably a
working group last call point we make
that sort of decision or certainly much
further down the path for this and I
don't know what the verification
procedures are but ya know that's I mean
in the you know we're and I'm having a
pre verify and REE verify we've been
doing this in the context of web often
as well if I'd I was setting up a server
certification program so we're trying to
actually do that or trying to make sure
those verification procedures were
accurate so I have a question for you
related to the verification stuff we
covered a large portion of the token
binding header structure with the
signature we don't cover the extensions
with the signature do we so we're going
to have to make some sort of assessment
about how the signature and the
attestation in interim interact with
each other such that we don't have any
problems with say copy/paste attacks in
all essence of all things and people
will Microsoft that's that's a valid
point we'll need to think about that but
I think before we even get to that there
is a bigger issue bigger open question I
have for this so in the current draft it
talks about using the TLS I am in the
attestation message validation and then
generation pass obviously all right and
so that to me does not make a lot of
sense we need to first like figure out
how long those at the station statements
will last whether they will be generated
for every TLS session which to me
wouldn't make sense right so like if I
am attesting the token binding here and
probably generating that statement once
and it maybe lives for a while
so we need to kind of
think about that basic question first
okay so so the question that would be
what are we attesting to whether that be
the fact that there is a key oh yeah all
of those things yeah yeah so okay okay
that's fine I mean an attestation
signature and I'm talking about the
attestation signature specifically not
the talk about message signature to me
it doesn't make sense unless it was a to
me it doesn't make sense generating it
without a potential to prevent replay
right and he can just seem like
low-hanging fruit in order to get it you
know it creates challenge data I mean we
can do some you know but that's that was
what my motivation was behind that right
so again in favor of Microsoft so the
replay is mitigated in my opinion by by
providing a token binding signature in
the token binding message on every like
and that is based on the qiam right but
it but my thinking was that there the
station Draft is about attesting to the
fact that the token binding key that I'm
using is actually stored securely like
in south and GPM and VSM whatever it is
in the key store so so I'm thinking that
actually at the station statement does
not need to be generated every time but
of course the token binding key will
sign the a.m. every time as it doesn't
know combining okay so what would you be
thinking of as far as as far as how the
attestation signature would be generated
over which data would it be generated I
think that is just a signature with the
like in any attestation mechanism that
I'm aware of and I'm not in at the
station expert by any stretch of the
imagination but basically there is an
attesting key that will sign the the
probably the public portion of the token
binding key or something based or
something including that right so
basically it's a signature over the
token binding key if that's method
that's adopted then that would be yes
you're right that signature would not be
generated and every year every T lies
connection yeah yeah Thompson I think
that's about right I think you need to
contextualise that's a little saying
that there's a token binding and this is
a token binding key and put some sort of
parameters around that but okay so yes
that would be sufficient and I don't
know what the
horns characteristics are here but I
think it would mean as long as that is
sufficient that has some pretty nice
performance characteristics so how'd
make things a little bit easier to do
and you could only you could potentially
omit it in subsequent token bindings but
potentially yeah depending on usage
patterns but that's that's the whole
problem yeah I can keep getting a minute
maybe you'll have different relying
parties particularly using a TT RP in
the middle right yeah no that's fine we
can we can do that we can create a
signature over the public key in that
way it doesn't change per connection and
uh you know and we relied anti replay
through the token binding message itself
and that signature yeah that's solid
input I'll take that back right and
remove Microsoft so if it saves us you
know a signature on every you know
connection that's a good thing and the
signature verification potentially if
the server is able to a cache maybe
those things we'll see so the other
thing is you know if we were to sign the
key em you know a key M is a bag of
bytes if your TPM is willing to attest
to the to sign like a random bag of
bytes that the something is broken in
that at the station so just a comment on
that ma'am
fair enough okay so that's something I
need to correct I'll get it so I think
first off those are the open questions I
got some feedback on that I think the
second one needs to wait adopting the
idea standards track until they get a
new version the other thing too is I
want to get the Google answers on what
they want to see as far as extension
negotiation and extensions approach and
they're concerned and also co-editors
are welcomed I will say will message to
the chairs though that even though the
you know once we get through this and
this becomes a working grade graph and I
think that I think that opens up
possibilities for the for people to
extend the attestation registry so I my
probably my my recommendation is not to
let this do I got too long before making
the decision to get this
yet the standards track so getting to
that so um it it's sort of um I think
the limiting factor here are two things
right how you know how quickly can you
spin another version and get some review
on that and then we'll actually have to
be ascertained that the working group is
interested in working on this and I
think it has to happen very quickly
because none of the core documents are
out and proxy is getting there I don't
think we're going to be around for that
much longer if we don't have active work
so my my suggestion here would be for
you to spin a new version very quickly
and I'm gonna ask a couple of questions
for the working group if just sort of
well while I have everybody here right
um um the and I also want to ask a
question of our ad whether he thinks
that this is actually in scope for the
for the working group because that's
number one it's actually why I got up
I'm looking excellent I'm looking at
this and I'm not this is not like it's
in scope today no it's not it's not
abused to me there right I get to
recharter right it could very well be a
reach all right in which case you know
on the other hand if the working group
is really excited about that you know
I'm I'm sure we can talk about it right
yeah exactly right but I think but but
one question I wanted to ask the working
with right now is how many have read
this draft or any of any of the versions
of this trap let's say that yeah all
right so it's a fair number um and no
I'm not actually gonna I don't think we
should ask for adoption today but oh
yeah right but I want to get a sense of
the room who how many here actually are
interested in this work enough to keep
working on it if there was a read
shorter
you know are you scratching your head
Tonio or you're expressing interest
you're expressing interest both alright
that's fine
alright so um one thing that we would
have to think about is there's a
concurrent a cessation work going on in
other parts of the IETF I'm assuming you
coordinate with those people so I'm not
saying that that's a problem also
Qualcomm yeah exactly right exactly so
um so but you know it might be the case
that if this is the only remaining work
for tofind
that are we better to consider doing and
doing it in a forum rather than trying
to keep tofind alive right so that's
anything else on John Center absolutely
all right um but I think the quicker we
get to an erosion and some rule that the
quicker we get to that point where we
can even have a discussion where this
goes if it goes point on seeing one next
week right all right thank you all right
thank you
and that gets us to open mic um TLS 1.3
yeah we're gonna remind me we were gonna
ask for yeah yeah our author is not here
so I don't think we can do much I think
we'll have to do that on the list I
think there was a I think he's sort of
raised yeah he raised the question of
whether it was ready for law school
right so you know there I think we'll
have to ask that on the on the list and
just just as a you know quick show of
hands how many have read the last
version of the TLS 1.2 a draft and I I
noticed Mick Sullivan it was racing you
were racing your hand Nick have since
you've reviewed it have you do you have
any issues with that there after you as
in TLS contributor
all right that's fine
I know I think we'll have to do do this
on the list all right
over mic or really the illustrious
agenda had mentioned fetch update I was
just wondering it
oh that was a copy paste error from last
time actually so yeah right I don't
think anybody has a fetch update but if
there was a fetch update if there is
ever one it'd be great it could be
listed - I'd be curious awesome so I
just looked at digit Jeff Hodges I just
looked at the PR this morning on the
original PR got closed and because the
conversation had gotten so long it took
minutes to load that page on got moved
to a new one this was at the end of
April there's some outstanding comments
on it from somebody whose name I'm
blanking on right now and Anna pom is
move jobs in Google it's on my list to
add my review to it I haven't gotten to
it yet there's a couple other things on
top of the stack so it's still a work in
progress
but it's getting closer it looked like
last activity was in May
all right thank you everyone um it seems
like when when we might meet in in in
Thailand but who knows yeah all right
thank you and safe travels