[Music]
hello welcome to trance hmm I'd hoped a
more verbose link to the note well but
um if you've seen the note well pay now
and just assume this is the same one so
on our agenda there's not much as to
69-62 piece if we've talked about threat
analysis and nothing much has happened
so those are our item schedules does
anyone have any other items ok so then
let's continue so the 696 to do base we
have six items left you can see them at
the bottom of the screen that we would
like to resolve so that we can get this
document out so the first item is the
document status has been some
description on the list - changes from
proposed Stannah to experimental i'm it
seems that everybody is okay with extra
mental but there was some pushback so if
there's anyone who wants to say
something about this yeah rich Sol's
Akamai yeah I was I think the major push
back against it was like it was more
about a process question and there was
question if there was support to do
another round of experimentation it
seems that there is so as long as
there's consensus on finally yeah I
would agree with that
who are you exactly - Malik did assert
it's unfortunate the nature of public
certificates are that we have to do
experiments on the public Internet and
that's some what's undesirable at times
but it's unavoidable in order to figure
out how these things work at scale
there's no there's no test environment
you can use for the public Internet and
so yeah to clarify the the
we're doing an experiment on this
protocol it's at the protocol itself
because it hasn't been implemented and
tested is experimental state so you know
we we believe that there's a commitment
to implement over the next few years but
just it's you know it's transitioning
from the current format to the next
format it's gonna take time it's gonna
take effort so yeah I completely agree
with that comment you just this it's the
only thing we can do and yes the yes the
new improvements we're making the new
improvements were making our very
important and it's important that we get
them out there do you guys run a CT vlog
yeah we do
can you say anything about transition
transition plans is there anything that
you could we we support the draft we
intend to we're working with Google we
were at their CT days we work very
closely with them having the only other
implementation other than theirs
and so yeah we're very supportive about
this we have internal desires to do even
more exciting stuff with CT that I hope
I'll be able to talk about in the future
I
I'm a Devin O'Brien from the Google
Chrome team so kind of piggybacking off
of what Tim said oh we actually do have
plans to begin experimentation I mean
right now our priorities have been
bringing CT enforcement and so that has
taken our you know limited engineering
resources and sort of funneled it
towards there but within the next
probably six to nine months we we're
laying out our plans to do
experimentation to sort of get like
hardened data so that we can back up
some of these like aspects of 696 you
list so it's on our roadmap we don't
know exactly have that roadmap ready to
share yet but as soon as you do share it
on list um but I just wanted to like
voice that this is absolutely something
we stand behind and we're gonna be
working on it just right now not just
not yet okay so the next item and this
came from a Curry's unfortunately not
here but he suggested to remove the
preventing track and Klein's claim
because it was a bit too strong and it
would cause problems with RSA PSS so
we've got a full request for that and
the question is does anyone object to
this claim to be removed
okay so everybody seems okay with it we
see here no objections we got a remote
on so let's see
go ahead Andrew hey hi I'm Angie oh yes
I change that I did right onto the list
to explain why I object and the reason
why I think there's been a
misunderstanding which is that using a
deterministic signature scheme isn't the
only way to achieve this it's also
possible to just sign a message like an
sth just once and then you know just
store that signature and just return
that signature for future requests for
the sth and I think this is important
because we don't know yet exactly how
gossip is going to work and it might not
be possible to deploy gossip experiments
if there's a concern that that's going
to lead to tracking so this is the sort
of thing which we could always you know
remove this requirement in the future
but if we don't have that requirement in
now then it could lead to trouble
getting gossip experiments going and I'm
not the only one who has expressed an
objection to removing this section Tom
Ritter and Linus Nordberg also chimed in
on lists saying they object to this
so obviously this means really
discussion on the mailing list before so
then the next item also came from a
cursory few is the no security
implications claim georgg hackers not
here okay okay okay so some me not so
let skip this for now Mew I'll go to the
other one so there's another proposal to
clarify what we mean by the current ntp
time there was there was some some
discussion but I think since these are
new items I think we really need to be
be a little strict and say if someone
doesn't give us text and we have nothing
to talk about that so will not continue
with these items so if anyone really
strange feel strongly about this they
should actually volunteer to also
provide the text so does anybody here
feel strongly about this any concerns
from this like do people don't care like
okay so if it's not this important then
we're pretty late in the process and
we're just not going to do anything with
this so so we'll see if we can get focus
to propose some text and then maybe
we'll see if it goes anywhere but it's
just not not a strong participation
we'll just come to drop it so next item
is the using JSON format for error
reporting I would hope we get a little
more input on that item because you have
implementers here I koribo know
Trustwave obviously I'm the one who
proposed this the idea here is that in
section 5 the actual response body that
defines any additional error data is
that as it should
there's no actual requirement for logs
actually returned any data just besides
the HTTP status code but my thought here
was that if we if we use the JSON
problem reporting format logs can send
back
or metadata so that consumers of the log
can basically automatically respond to
any errors one thing that came out of us
CT days is the potential some thoughts
around rate limiting based on roots or
intermediate CAS if if if submitters to
those logs could get more information
back from the lot of operators say like
you know you're being later limited
because you're intermediate here and in
change being currently what rate limited
try back in two thousand seconds or
something like that that information can
be provided through this format and
what's nice here is that the Jason
response format it doesn't mandate that
you support any extension metadata
fields so at a later date if we decide
that some CT log endpoint wants to go
and return additional metadata that can
be done at a later date maybe in like a
further draft this is kind of just
laying the framework such that we have
this error format to fine now and we can
leverage it later okay so are you
willing to write up some text for this
yes Corey again um yeah sure I'll give
it a shot okay great thanks yeah Tim how
big I'm assuming that Corey I'm assuming
that you're modifying a should here
right so your are you thinking that this
is going to be a proposed format that we
may change later or not sure I'd want to
make it mandatory well it's still kind
of half-baked but I really like the idea
of having a format that we can start
experimenting with and returning error
data because one of the feedback that we
do get from lots of the people who
consume our logs is in fact that they
get error response codes back and they
have no idea what's going on and what
they should do in response quote from
Trustwave again um so the the JSON
format it's actually defined in RFC I
think it's 78 oh seven and it defines in
there
there's a couple standard fields in that
Jason problem document but it also
allows for extensibility in the future
it basically says that if a if a client
consuming that problem document sees a
field that it doesn't understand it must
ignore it so if that's not treated as an
error case if you know it'll later at a
later point we want to add some
additional metadata all right Tim LD so
your proposal would be you you should
report errors and if you do they must be
in this RFC format I inquiry again for
justice us so yes well I I think it'd be
great if we could say must like you
returned so I believe from every
endpoint to find in 69-62 beast
there are error codes and error messages
to find it would be nice that you know
that they all come back in this problem
document the document format yeah just
because of the fact that it's kind of
late and we haven't really played with
this I think I personally would prefer a
should and should according from trust
with um so yeah I mean I guess if it is
late in the game you know and there's no
provision to change this and I guess you
know maybe just remains it should right
if we're talking about publication as an
experimental standard at some point in
the future you know if everything goes
well we're going to transition to a
different standard status and at that
point that's a new document and if this
turns out to work well and it's and
people like it we can turn it into a
mosque but you know it should for now
okay now is the last item I don't know
where this where this came from it just
was it appeared on a list of of items
that were sent to the list but I don't
know who originated this and I can't
find any discussion of it but the option
for City log so signal when rejections
were due to rate limiting and again
we've got the same thing
if this is important and we would need a
volunteer to write text Tim hobby I
would think that Cory's proposal covers
that adequately that's actually true
okay okay any other 69-62 biz items not
so we're just sort of waiting on a curve
okay so okay so so we'll skip those
items now so let's go back to the D
Trans threat analysis so this has been
mostly a work of steve canned and and
and then the last about three IETF
meetings I think we see you know small
updates every four months and two people
mostly arguing about what it should be
and most other people not caring anymore
what happens to this document so we
really don't want to keep the working
group open for just this document so
we're sort of pondering what to do here
and it doesn't seem to be that much
interest talking it's pretty far
finished as it's also a ways of it if it
doesn't get finished but but we really
don't want to have more more infighting
between two people and just waiting
forever on this you know I I think the
one way to frame the question is is the
value of the document greater than the
cost of getting it closed and at this
point right and at this point we're just
not seeing a lot of interest in the
document right it's it's I don't and
it's hard to know if it's that people
have lost their taste for discussion of
it and but and that they really do care
or that they just don't care I should
say you just don't care so rich Sol's
Akamai well you know it's got like the
same level of interest that the rest of
trans and gossip has these days I would
say yeah maybe
less interest because it's been worn
down by the infighting flip a coin call
for consensus and move it forward I
think it's a worthwhile document it's a
shame that it's going to get wrapped
around the axle over this one discussion
of what is or is not an attack or how to
describe that attack cut the whole thing
out then I don't I don't care but yes
I'd like to see it published I can leave
it at this point you know it's only
those who have egos involved in this
fight
we'll take it back Paul and I'll discuss
it after the meeting and then take it
out back out to the mailing list okay
then just a summary on on some of the
items that haven't really seen much much
progress as it's the gossip city gossip
decline behavior end up binaries I think
I think it would be good if that if we
see more work going that way that that's
just a new working groups will be
started up or above started up and did
that work there I don't think we need to
remain open for it because the the
progress is really really slow at this
point we also seen this with the NTIA
sponsoring a workshop soon on software
module transparency and it seems like
you know if there's an interest to end
them
you know specifying something it may
cover you may cover these and similar
for the DNS SEC transparency I did a
draft PowerPoint which I've presented at
Athena's option you can have a look at
it there but I also don't think we need
to keep the working group open for this
specifically also because it will
probably not reuse much of the
certificate transparency format so it
would be something fairly new anyway so
I think it can also find it's a new way
into the into the IDF
okay so then who wants to fill up ten
minutes with interesting discussion
before I crush yourself Ben Schwartz I'm
very interested in in the possible
interaction between redaction and IP
certificates I wonder if they're not
considered considered that specific case
so yeah you're right actually I skipped
one item it's the redaction the
redaction has come back and forth to the
working group like three or four times
now and and again I think we should we
should just if there's an interest in
there we should do you have those people
that are driving it to start up off and
maybe working group because they've come
here and vanished on a number of
occasions so I think that should just be
split off from this work amateur from
Linda there's folks that I mean this is
a browser vendor you're kind of imposing
their view of the world no offense but
chrome has proposed a mechanism that
sort of addresses kind of indirectly
redaction through on through the use of
basically enterprise in an enterprise
namespace defined in chrome it's to
permit stuff that won't get logged at
all rather than stuff that has a label
edited and I that doesn't really address
your juice case in the slightest
so maybe the chrome folks could say
something about that Tim how big the
lack of interest is actually entirely
due to lack of interest from the
browsers that a lot of people who remain
interested in redaction and I think the
the fair summary is that none of the
current methods work particularly well
so but there also is until we get there
the chrome folks were very early on this
and everybody else has been just
starting to come up with their own CT
policies and so I would encourage people
who think redaction is important to you
continue having discussions with the
root programs about their root policies
if we can get a root program
interested in discussing a concrete
proposal then we can start discussing it
again but yeah I don't think this
working group has to hang around just
for people to come back and do that we
have 8 more minutes do you want to say
more about your use case you know the
question of redacting IP addresses sure
so this is this isn't exactly my area
but it seems to me that the IP
certificates have very different
security properties from the perspective
of a client who's establishing a
connection in particular there are fewer
intermediaries in some sense the client
validates the location of the validates
the name by its route ability it
depending on your perspective so I think
I I'm a little concerned personally
about essentially creating a system
where any IP end up with an enumeration
of all of the IP addresses that have
ever requested an IP certificate that
that seems unfortunate to me I guess I
you know I I agree that this doesn't
need to hold a river but I mostly wanted
to come and see if anybody else is
interested in talking about these things
maybe outside the group I also would
like to see the binary transparency work
received in it and my my group is very
interested in binary transparency in
something like a JavaScript context with
maybe a browser extension so again if
anybody wants to talk about that outside
the group please let me
so on the questions of IPS IP
certificates are weird and actually
quite rare a nomination of the IPS that
have IP certificates is a little bit
less dangerous because they have to be
public IPS anyway and the information
that you're leaking is that a certain
ipv4 address has have a HTTPS
certificate at one particular point in
time that's perhaps not the most
sensitive piece of information in the
universe the IP certificates have a lot
of interesting problems that are being
actively discussed just because of the
fact that as you mentioned the security
properties are very different and the
lifetimes of static IPs are often very
different and much less stable than DNS
names and the and in particular they get
farmed out to various entities on a
regular basis sometimes very quickly so
there's a there's a reasonable position
that perhaps they shouldn't exist and
the validation rules for them is kind of
being actively discussed as something we
will either clean up or we will just
eliminate this I think we might be one
of two companies in the entire world
that actually issued IP certificates on
a regular basis but just to be clear
there's there's no additional
requirements on my 69-62 bits for any of
this right yeah as far as I'm aware they
look just exactly the same for the
verses of Trance yeah yeah well that's
an interesting question actually in many
cases actually IP certificates are more
commonly used in non browser use cases
even if they're issued off for publicly
dressed recruits just because of the
fact that they're used in server to
server in IOT use cases where the trust
store generally is the same as the trust
or that was stolen from some root
program so they have to be publicly
trusted but there probably are people
using I teach their IP certificates with
browsers I think captive portals would
be the most likely use case
this is a Devon from Google Chrome again
trying to wrap my head around the point
that you brought up about the numerating
IP you said you knew bringing IP is
concerning I'm not sure I understand why
it's concerning is that is it possible
if we still have I think we thought
sometime sure so I don't want to take up
lots of working group time if there's if
this is outside the group but this is
Ben Schwartz the my use cases generally
are about services operated by by
clients that they want to be able to use
securely from a browser but the whose
existence they want to be confidential
because otherwise those services could
be subject to various kinds of attacks
such as for example a DDoS attack so if
the if the certificates are logged
publicly then it makes it potentially
much easier for an adversary to discover
the existence of the service and mount
an attack against it in ipv4 I agree
that you can essentially enumerate the
ipv4 space you can zmapp for these the
existence of these certificates but n
ipv6 that's at least not so clear that
that's possible so personally for my use
cases it would be nice if if browsers
would take ipv6 ipv6 IP certificates and
not require them to be fully enumerated
in the in the certificate transparency
box well and that that's complicated too
right because one of the goals of
certificate transparency is we wanted to
know who is issuing what so we pay
attention to naughty practices and the
dark little corners of validation is
exactly where the naughty practices tend
to be so I personally find a lot of
value in logging these I think you're
right that there's ipv6 is a spot where
you could
hi if you wanted to but I'm not sure how
what the how that sort of weigh the
benefits and I think I think the world
is moving to a place where you know you
eat a lot of the redactions stuff people
thought they were doing a better job of
hiding than they then they were and they
had semantics for example had an option
of please don't log my ICT certificate
and it was rather popular most of them
ended up getting logged by Google anyway
so whether they were actually getting
what they wanted is a little bit
questionable so I think I would sue I
think I would suggest to people that if
you have a public ipv6 address and your
security is based on the fact that
nobody knows your public ipv6 address
you should perhaps revisit your threat
assumptions yeah I think one of the
things that we saw a sort of anecdotally
was looking through logs and we and this
is in the context of finding
certificates with likes maybe malformed
se T's in our a so we're doing a big
analysis trying to help CAS get up to
speed with that and one of the most
common responses we got was like sheer
surprise that these will publicly know
like these things were that they were
like these are behind lockdown intranet
they're like no this was crawled and put
in here and it's not just by Google
crawler right
there's tons of white hat security
researchers to do these things at scale
and yes currently mathematically ipv6 is
so much harder right just as an aside
for that but echoing Tim I think any
model that relies on those things not
being discoverable for long it may not
be like a mall you want to build a lot
of foundation on sort of not addressing
your concern but sort of the rationale
for your concern
thanks for coming
so we briefly had the your items from
the adv fee which you can see the bottom
just like and so we're just wondering
about your your updated views on those
items so there seems to be no no
potential by changing the document
status to experimental so that that
one's resolved the remove tracking
preventing tracking clients claim
there's still some disagreement but
where it should be removed completely or
revised so what is your a few unsure I
mean that's a working of decision so on
the my position I think is that on like
they good I strike I was trying to get
out is like that what the maybe you
could pull a PR from my understanding is
when I read it was that when you say
well new terminal signatures like that
that there's a sit the thing that says
don't do to or ministers integers and
yet simultaneously the ITF is pushing
people use RSA towards PSS and so there
seem to be in conflict and so um and I
understood and so I thought okay no one
was trafficked to be um dad there was
some question about how to manage that
in particular on like ever who was where
we said that you could you could deal
with this by like storing might
exploring the city or somewhere and then
then the race that wasn't practical and
like um I guess like I think exists easy
walking decision you how to proceed and
you could proceed like we've
deliberately decided that we think PSS
is stupid
and we don't do PSS and because he has
one one five or it could be we're gonna
like remove this text it could be we're
gonna we're gonna like you
we're gonna say what you have to suppose
integers but it's like like I just think
these things are just some things
intentionally you guys need if we have
to resolve oh so I'm like not pressing
for any particular resolution um but I
do think that something's got to give in
terms that triangle um so I don't know
if that helps um I didn't really
understand like oh ye my way to the no
list was a frankly pretty inconclusive
but any any of our solution the chose
are willing to stand behind I'm willing
to stamp on okay and then the next time
the most have removed no security
implications can you pull it up I read
it myself their day but I have to admit
I'm a little rusty on her what this is
about huh maybe that this is finally me
on the road gestures Ennis I'm fine with
that
but I guess I'm reading so okay hang in
a second moved yeah okay I try what was
my complaint about this and I remember
now is that we able to find that not
quickly I think you actually wanted to
remove it and there was some pushback on
not removing it but I think it does seem
like what most likely happened here
another wise what am i complaining about
well I think he objected to removing and
I think echo suggested removing it and
then now confuse cuz this is issue you
should remove it it in order or did or
did you put that in respond response did
you put that in response to my comments
and now he objected and I guess to have
to pick it I got again alright sigh so
Andrew here so um I think that there was
some confusion about why this this was
why this was in here in this from its
Roque I'm trying to think now uh right
so it all goes back to why a log has to
validate the chain to a trust
anchor and I think that originally there
was a misunderstanding which was that
the only reason the log had to do this
was for anti-spam you know to prevent it
from being spammed with certificates
from you know someone's you know own
trust anchor so that I think then led to
the suggestion that we say there's no
that I think that led to your suggestion
that we should say that there is no
security implications to requiring the
check to the trust anchor because it's
just anti-spam but as I pointed out it's
not just anti-spam it's ensuring that we
can attribute every certificate in the
log to some certificate authorities so
that browsers can take action against
the certificate authority so because of
that and we do not want to put in that
there is no security implication there
is a security implication it's just not
anti-spam something else so that make
sense paging back into memory and I
agree with you I'm happier with this
text I think it might be productive for
somebody to add what I what you just
said somehow because apparently at the
fact that apparently several were
confused about this suggests that maybe
a bigger and it is a subtle point about
CSS but have you documented but I'm fine
with a planet is PR yeah well actually
the I suggested some text in my email
and then Rob actually included that in
his PR so the PR will add in the
explanatory text for what is required
okay what's that if you're our new sex
yeah if you go back to the PR yeah if
you go over to the drink
yeah files changed right right right
there we go looks good to me
yep this one's fine awesome thanks okay
so then my minds are all stiff need that
from you
while Teresa and then I can ad review
and make them shipped off yes I mean I
think make sure that they got yeah
double check and then we can go right
thank you so so since you may be elisa
knows a bit more about what happens to
adopted working group work when the
working group closes ELISA Cooper it's
so it's kind of up to you it wasn't
really clear to me when you were going
through if it's just that you that the
working group doesn't want to work on
these anymore and there's individuals
who would like to have things ad
sponsored it didn't really seem like
that but that's one possibility but the
other possibility is the drafts expire
and that's it it seems to mostly that
the works been really slow and if people
haven't haven't had these cycles to work
on them we've got a gossip draft that
there's a there's continuing interest in
it but there hasn't been a lot of
progress it was intended for publication
as an experimental standard is it can
that be ad sponsored sure it could be I
think honestly on the one holding that
up so maybe it will be better would be
if we try to resolve the remaining
issues and then just and and and and
then um you know III guess I grown I
like what were you hoping to Colonus
actually ask you that I'm sorry were you
hoping to close let me ask you that like
now um I am yeah I mean unless you know
we've been discussing this with several
meetings now there's been no serious
objection and by the way my can you aid
the sponsor this was a speculative
question rather than a request just
leave it so technically yes I could but
um I guess his ended which these are all
working with documents it'd be better to
and unless I may feel differently and
like I this I think guides the charity
fight we're here but um it might be
better to just like keys are working
rely for the month or two of law hard
lanolin is that what do you think yeah
well I would
only keep the wooden group open until
the Biss document is through the IHG
because you never know there could be
something that comes back where you need
a working up consensus call so if you're
going to do that anyway
and there's energy to just process the
other document relatively quickly then
just leave it open until those two are
done I think I can get through that
pretty quickly when we another okay any
other business hi again
sorry this is more of a procedural
question due to lack of familiarity so
bear with me um so as I mentioned we
plan on doing some experiments to get
like that at the back like we mean
because basically there are like
material improvements and in bits that
aren't in sequencing - right and there
are things that I think are going to be
very useful in the long run but maybe
not be in their final state if the WG
closes and we come up with these results
half a year later
what sort of procedurally happens then
and again it's just because I don't know
um we could potentially spin up a new
working group or because this would be
what we need basically dropping about as
fans assume um ultimately transitioning
something from experimental to standard
um potentially them I don't know I may
be another ad sponsorship but we could
spin up another working group pretty
quickly on this I think okay yeah and
just the reason why I asked this concern
is just that like these things move as
glacially as changes in the PK ecosystem
do and that seems to be a pretty big
mismatch to the speed at which like IETF
WGS go
it just hello Maisie it seems that
extenders laughing right next to me so
yeah yeah
IETF working groups don't sort of work
in an area and cover top you know
covered topics we have specific pieces
of work to complete so precision music
the concept of process which movie star
which means are slowly that IETF process
because there to be a pacing in a rapid
pace uh-huh I think I think like um it's
craft or aggression when we do you think
you have possible
white feedback from this process we're
hoping to have initial feedback by 104
right yeah so I think I guess what I
would say is there are really two
possible like we have the procedure the
coupon they're two possible like
outcomes here right one is that like we
think expenses - this is essentially
correct and in which case like we could
simply read we could simply you know
rebadge it is standard as proposed
standard or you know issue like a Navy
sponsored small things as well some
small Corrections the second is we think
is not substantially correct and like
more what needs to be done in which case
we would we would have that one if our
working group in order to do the work
given the time frame you're telling me I
think I'd prefer to close this working
group and then spit up a new one rather
than because we're gonna ice for like a
year or two so I think what we do is we
just basically spin up you know eight
commands to and maybe even call it trans
elastic and tell me I don't know if
there's like these things get like you
know trans - OH - or something um but um
you know to do that but that'd be the
process but think yeah again it really
depends on what the feedback is the
feedback is it's basically right then
like just promoting is easy the feedback
thing you don't want to work then like
you have to do that work someone yeah
this is Tim I think I agree with that I
think actually the document is I don't
know about you guys are what you guys
are thinking about proposing we probably
will actually have proposed improvements
before you do if you're not gonna do
anything until 104 but most of the
things that we're thinking are basically
augmenting trends with new ideas and
different features and things like that
and I think those are better handled as
new drafts as opposed to a business and
so those can just go through the normal
IETF process and hey we've got a new
draft it's got great new trans stuff
there's no where it can currently go
please tell us where you want to send it
no so I think the existing process will
work fine even if this close group
closes there
a bunch of other groups where you close
the group but you keep the list and this
seems like a good candidate if you
follow this process okay
has everybody sign the blue sheets and
other than that I guess we're done see
you on the mailing list ending is even
short when I'll go through the recording
[Music]
okay by the way
yes
[Music]