well well thanks so much it's an honor
to be here for my first crypto we we
won't count another one that I snuck
into when I was in Santa Barbara for
another reason but so this will not be a
sort of a general talk about quantum
computing and crypto although you know
that that might have been good too but
you know I'm not gonna talk about Shor's
algorithm or about quantum resistant
crypto or about quantum key distribution
I'm going to talk instead about some
brand new connections between quantum
computing and cryptography ones that you
probably haven't heard about okay and
I'm not you know going to sort of give a
sort of basic introduction to to quantum
computing but if you don't know the the
subject you can just sort of Nod along
okay because you know I mean I mean I
mean I'm mostly I'll just be using you
know some facts about quantum computing
or some assumptions about what is hard
for quantum computers and what is hard
for classical computers as black boxes
okay so you know you know we don't
really need to know quantum mechanics
for this talk although you know if you
want to learn quantum mechanics and you
haven't you could do it and you know
anyone who's here could do it in a
couple days
okay it is you know really totally not
scary once you take the physics out of
it and you know just just think about it
as yeah unit unit vectors of complex
numbers okay that's so so so the main
part of this talk is going to be about
some new work I've not yet published on
a certified randomness from quantum
supremacy so this term quantum supremacy
was coined by the physicist John
Prescott in 2012 this was before the
word supremacy USA reacquired a bunch of
really nasty connotations and so there's
now a lot of discussion about changing
this term that were that we've sort of
been set
so one suggestion has been a quantum and
imitability meaning you know inability
to imitate something with a classical
computer well if you can pronounce that
you're welcome to use it you know and
others another suggestion has been
quantum ascendency that sounds too much
like you know we're ascending to some
quantum UFO in the sky or something so
I'm gonna stick with this term and
anyway then in in a second part of the
talk if there's time and by request I'm
gonna say something about uh some joint
work that I did with my introducer guy
Roth Blum well in the past year when I
was on sabbatical in Tel Aviv about a
new connection that we have found
between gentle measurement of quantum
states and differential privacy and here
I have the great advantage that Cynthia
already introduced differential privacy
so I don't have to ok so ok so as you
may have heard right now happens to be a
particularly exciting time for quantum
computing maybe the most exciting time
since a lot of the basic concepts were
first discovered in the mid 1990s ok and
the reason it's so exciting right now is
that you know the experimentalists
finally have qubits that you know that
work pretty well in isolation ok and so
it now sort of finally makes sense to
try to scale up to you know significant
numbers of them and you know try to do
something interesting so a bunch of
companies are now sort of in a race you
know Google IBM Intel some startups like
Righetti this ion queue with trapped
ions you know a Microsoft is sort of
pursuing a longer term thing but you
know but all of them are sort of
invested in yeah
$100,000,000 you know level and actually
building systems and and and in
particular many of these players are
right now trying to achieve the first
clear demonstration of quantum supremacy
by which they simply mean doing
something that we're pretty sure is hard
for a classical computer to simulate
okay notice I didn't say useful okay
I said hard okay so you know proving you
know what what I what I like to say is
that quantum supremacy targets but for
me has always been the number one
application of quantum computing okay
more than breaking RSA more than even
than simulating quantum physics you know
for all the industrial applications that
that could have for me the number one
application is refute Oded gold rife
refute gilko I refute Li in 11 okay I
would just like them to admit that they
were wrong and that and that quantum
mechanics is right okay so well excuse
me
yeah yeah right so so you know so so so
basically just you know experimentally
prove the point that you know you can do
something quantumly let's say in less
than a second you know that would take
you know at the very least many days or
weeks to simulate with Google sighs
classical computing cluster okay and
what is exciting is that we may be on
the verge you know or you know some of
some of these players may be on the
verge of doing that okay so they have
now you know in both superconducting
qubits and trapped ions they have
systems with about 20 cubits you know
that work quite well and Google actually
down the road from us and it's lab in
Santa Barbara you know and which is
maybe the world leader right now is
trying to scale up to a 72 qubit chip
that they call Bristlecone okay and I
think it's fair to say that it you know
we'll be working in O of one years okay
so
you know I mean whenever
experimentalists tell me that you know
for certain something will be you know
ready in a year like I've learned to
actually trust them that probably there
will be something in three or four years
okay so so so yeah so it's an exciting
time now how what what you know suppose
that they build the 72 cubit ship and
suppose that it that it works what
should they actually do with it
to demonstrate quantum supremacy so that
is where we as theoretical computer
scientists come into the picture you
know I mean quite quite literally
they're you know the I talk to the
system builders and they ask us what
should we do with this so so so so the
the most basic proposal for you know
demonstrating quantum supremacy well you
know is you know is almost tautological
right it's it's simply you would just
sort of take some some kind of sequence
of gates or some unitary transformation
gives me um on your on your qubits you
know that leads to sampling let's say
from some probability distribution over
and bit strings you know if you have an
N qubit quantum computer ok and so each
time you run the device you can get a
new independent sample from some
distribution over n bit strings right
and at its core
you know quantum mechanics is a way to
calculate probabilities that you will
see various outcomes you know when you
make a measurement right so it lets you
calculate what this distribution is but
of course that you know each time you
run it you may get a different sample
and and then you know we can sort of
conjecture that sampling either exactly
or approximately from that same
distribution would be hard with a
classical computer ok now of course
being complexity theorists we hope to do
a little bit better than saying you know
all those dreams hard to us
okay and you know we we we wish to give
reductions and you know to some extent
we have been able to do that okay so
that's a long story that I mostly won't
go into but you know very briefly we can
you know it turns out to be very easy to
specify probability distributions that a
quantum computer can easily sample from
such that if a classical computer could
sample exactly from that same
distribution in polynomial time then the
polynomial hierarchy collapses to the
second level for example okay you know
like you know for me that's actually
more convincing than you know then a
classical computer could factor right
because you know a fast classical
factoring algorithm yet might collapse
much of the world's economy but you know
I mean I mean you know the I mean III
think that I think that our
administration and you know in the US
may you know achieve that goal and much
more prosaic ways okay it's just it's
just not very impressive to me you know
what's more what's more impressive to me
is the collapse pH okay so so for for a
proximate sampling you know the the
situation is if we're you currently have
to make stronger conjectures than just
that the polynomial hierarchy is
infinite but you know things that seem
very plausible and which would imply
that even approximate sampling would be
would be classically hard and
furthermore you know could even give you
ways to verify the samples where then
you could say that under some plausible
complexity assumption that doing
anything you know that passes this
verification test would be hard for a
classical computer okay so so those are
the types of tests that you know that
Google in particular you know is going
to try to do within the next couple of
years the theoretical foundations of
this sort of experiment I mean I think
it goes back to a paper of thar hall and
davinci ENSO from over a decade ago the
the connection to things like the
infinitude of the polynomial hierarchy
it came later that was in
pendant ly by me and Alex arkhipov in
what we called boson sampling which was
you know one particular proposal for
doing this and also a Bremner josa and
Shepherd and then since then we've been
studying uh setups that are that are
closer to what people like Google and
IBM are at you know actually going to be
able to do in the near future okay so so
you know so my line you know for a while
when I whenever I gave talks about this
as well this is exciting because Google
may be able to do it soon and because it
will refute Gil kalai and you know
enforce the the quantum computing
deniers or skeptics to you know admit
that they were wrong
now clearly obviously sampling from
these distributions is completely
useless in and of itself right you know
it has zero applications to anything
other than you know just proving the
skeptics wrong right because you know
who would actually need a sample from
the output distribution of some randomly
generated quantum circuit or something
right it's just yeah it's uh it's like
you know if the experiment is working
right you're good you're all you're
gonna say is a sample
well not exactly from the uniform
distribution you know I mean that would
be easy to sample from okay but from
some non-uniform distribution you know
that the you know there's really hard to
tell apart from the uniform distribution
right you know you just see a bunch of
samples that look like completely random
you know gobbledygook like that if you
don't know what random bits look like
okay and so okay so so so this is the
genisis for the new work that I'll talk
about is simply the observation that
will random bits can actually be useful
okay there are people who want random
bits particularly if you can in some
sense certify that they are random or
let's say publicly prove to a skeptic
that they really were generated randomly
and not backdoored or biased okay so
obviously if you have private randomness
or ran in the shared only by you and
your friend well you better have that
you're gonna be doing any sort of
cryptography you know whether public key
or private key now for to do to get
private randomness with the sort of
scheme that I'll talk about you would
need to own the quantum computer
yourself okay so that might be good for
quantum computer salespeople but you
know that that that's not going to work
for cloud applications like we're in the
near future where we would envision a
bunch of people accessing a very small
number of quantum computers over the
Internet
okay so for that second scenario oh well
you know you better not be downloading
your private key over the Internet as I
as I as I shouldn't have to tell people
here okay but but but you could use that
as a source of public randomness okay
and that too has many applications as
many of you know better than me could be
used for lotteries for choosing which
precincts to audit in an election
setting parameters for crypto systems
various zero-knowledge protocols also
you know if you want something trendy or
well proof of state crypto currencies
require a large source of public random
bits in order to sort of run a lottery
effectively where you decide who gets to
add a new block onto the blockchain and
then get paid for that right you know
and the advantage of these crypto
currencies is that they may not use 1%
of the world's electricity to invert a
hash function okay but you know but they
do require lots of public random bits
okay so you may say well as soon as
we've got quantum mechanics what is
absolutely trivial to generate as many
random bits as you want right randomness
is sort of baked in to quantum mechanics
so that is famously why Einstein didn't
like it right so and indeed you know
here is um you know I mean I mean you
know I hope I hope that you know you
could at least parse this quantum
circuit this is a very very simple
quantum circuit to generate a random bit
okay it just says take a qubit that is 0
put it into an equal superposition of
the states 0 and 1 that's what this
Hadamard gate
and then measure it and force it to
collapse to either zero or one randomly
right I mean a you know something that
can measure the polarization of a photon
you know or a Geiger counter or even
will effectively have that behavior
right and you can eat indeed by devices
over the internet that will you know at
least claim to use quantum mechanics for
random number generation okay but the
issue that we are worried about is well
how do you trust it particularly if you
were getting random bits over the
Internet
right how on earth do you know that they
really were generated you know quantum
mechanically at all you know let alone
with a circuit like this one okay you
know we're of course you know so so I
should say that NIST has something
called the randomness beacon where you
know every minute they released 512
fresh random bits to the world and they
actually do use quantum mechanics as
part of how they generate them and even
now as a very recently they apparently
use a bell experiments okay to get a
higher level of security okay but you
know the to their their Alice and Bob
are not nearly far separated enough to
get through cryptographic security okay
and you know been that you know and
actually it was only only two years ago
that the first experiments were done
that violated the Bell inequality you
know proved the reality of entanglement
in our universe in a way that closes all
the possible loopholes these all the
same loopholes that a skeptic could
think of right so that's very very
recent you know it's a it can be done
today but it's a it's a difficult
experiment okay but you could ask the
question even if NIST were doing that
that right kind of experiment how would
anyone accessing over the Internet know
that right you know the you know they
would just have to trust NIST okay and
you know if you know about the you know
the the Snowden revelations and their
their pseudo-random standard that it
turned out was backdoored by the NSA
then you know someone might be leery of
that okay so so how can you get
certified randomness okay well as I
alluded to there was an earlier approach
to that problem which emerged from a
beautiful a sequence of works starting
with a Colbeck and renner a decade ago
okay and they were thinking about the
famous Bell inequality you know which is
uh well for computer scientists it's a
to prove ur protocol okay
it is a game played by two cooperating
players Alice and Bob who can agree on a
strategy in advance but who can't
communicate with each other and a
referee generates random questions sends
them to Alice and Bob and then demands
back responses that satisfy some
condition a typical choice is that the
the exclusive-or of the responses should
equal the end of the questions right
that's called the CH SH game okay and
then what you prove is that this game
can be won with a higher probability if
Alice and Bob share quantum entanglement
than if they don't and in particular if
they only share classically correlated
random bits okay in particular for the
CH SH game you can show that with
classical correlation they could only
win that game in three-quarters of cases
whereas if they share entanglement then
they can win in 85% of cases okay and so
but what people notice the deck you know
and once again people said okay this is
obviously you know hugely
philosophically important right this is
what disproves Einstein you know and
shows that you know quantum entanglement
you know or spooky action at a distance
as a in some sense you know a real thing
in our universe it has experimental
consequences
you know it can't be talked away okay
but obviously it's completely useless
for anything okay except a decade ago
these people realize that it's not so
useless okay and the reason is that when
you play this game and you win it with
85 percent probability meaning when you
violate the bell inequality
it's not just that you're proving that
entanglement was present it's also that
you were proving that your responses
must have some real entropy in them okay
they must not have been fully known in
advance they must have been at least
partially random why because if Alice's
response were deterministic function of
her input and Bob's response were a
deterministic function of his input then
you know and they won the game more than
three quarters of the time then you
could prove that that would allow
instantaneous communication between them
okay so so under the assumption of no
faster-than-light communication you
actually get you know assuming that they
passed this game you get certified
randomness right certified entropy okay
and you know amazingly the the argument
never even needs to assume the
correctness of quantum mechanics okay it
just assumes that you do the experiment
and they do indeed pass this test as
experiment shows that they do okay so
you know there was a problem which is
that you know in order to even generate
the challenges to send to Alice and Bob
well that that needs to be random as
well so at first it looked like maybe
the diffusion reactors that exists today
right they generate power but in order
to run them you need to supply them with
more power right you know I D look a
unique you would need to feed more
randomness in then you get out okay but
you can be more clever and you can save
entropy in your choice of questions that
you ask okay and so by doing that these
guys showed how to get a linear
expansion in the umber of random bits
that you had these guys showed how to
get a quadratic expansion and then it
became an exponential expansion and then
a few years ago with these guys
they said with with just a fixed initial
random seed you can then get arbitrarily
more random bits you know effectively by
just plowing in the new randomness you
get as a new seed okay so you know so
this is great because it doesn't even
require a quantum computer it needs only
current technology meaning current as of
two years ago okay
but the downside is that well let's say
NIST is doing this right or Google or
someone if you're getting these random
bits over the internet how on earth do
you know that Alice and Bob really were
separated by far enough to be violating
the Bell inequality right you don't
really know anything about what is
physically going on you know over you
know at this remote laboratory okay all
you know is you can submit challenges
you can wait some amount of time and you
can get a result right and then you can
check it okay so for this reason it
would be great if we could use quantum
mechanics to generate certified random
bits using only a single device okay so
so that's what I'll talk about today for
this we will need a quantum computer but
what is particularly exciting about this
is that it looks like what we would need
is just the bare minimum type of quantum
computer that is able to do anything at
all that is classically hard okay in
other words you know a 70 qubit device
for example that can you know achieve
sampling based quantum supremacy should
already be enough to do this and in fact
you don't even want more than that for
therefore this application for reasons
that we'll see okay so the basic idea in
the sort of scheme that I'll talk about
is that we have a classical client say
you know it just has a deterministic
classical computer you know and and of
course you know I'll assume that you
know the classical code that they run is
is is fully trustworthy because you know
of course classical code is you know
it's gonna be fully trustworthy and free
of any bug okay or any back to work I
mean you know I I have to assume
something right and the classical
verifier will start with a small random
seed okay we'll use that seed to
generate a sequence of challenges that
it sends to the quantum computer when I
did a Google image search for quantum
computer you know that's a pair
apparently what they look like you know
I mean if you could go down the street
to Santa Barbara I think they look a
little different
but you know and the challenges will
basically have the form you know just
like give me a sample from the output
distribution of this quantum circuit
okay and the client will demand back the
responses within a very short amount of
time like let's say half a second for
each okay and it will wait for each
response before sending over the next
challenge okay and and then the key
insight here is that you know the the
verifier can then check if these
responses pass some tests
you know if they pass some check for
sort of you know are these sort of
consistent with having been drawn from
the right distributions okay and then we
will argue based on some complexity
hypothesis that if the samples pass that
check and they were you know efficiently
generated by a quantum computer then
they must have some real entropy in them
okay so in other words a cool you know
we will give a test that a quantum
computer can quickly pass but that even
a quantum computer can only quickly pass
by sampling from the distribution and it
cannot do it in a deterministic or
nearly deterministic way okay so this
requires just a single device so it's
good for remote use and it's also good
for near-term quantum computers because
you know we just for this you know we
just need basically a clear gap between
the running time of you know the quantum
computer and the running time of a
classical device that would be trying to
fake the results right so you know
seventy cubits or you know even 50 or 60
cubits or are probably enough okay and
and I said we don't want more than that
well the reason is that this scheme also
has a downside which is that the
classical verification with this scheme
takes something like two to the end time
and being a number of qubits okay so if
n is 50 or 60 or maybe even 70 you can
do that at least if your Google or IBM
or someone like that okay and
you know this has even recently been
shown experimentally okay but you know
it takes quite a big cluster a long time
to do okay so with a thousand cubits you
know the randomness generation scheme
might be working fine but you could
never prove it right you know so yeah
yeah yep look so so that's - thank you
thank you - that's my very next slide
you might wonder does this inherently
require quantum mechanics I claim that
it does okay and the the reason that was
not a plant the the you know well let's
suppose that we had a classical device
for generating random bits like we know
a lava lamp or something but suppose
that you know you also believe in the
classical polynomial-time Church touring
thesis right then that lava lamp or
whatever it is could be simulated by a
classical computer with access to a
random number generator right in pilot
you know in with polynomial overhead
okay but now we have a problem because
now what would happen if I just took
without that random bit source that my
simulation was using and I replaced it
with the output of a PRG right now you
know my device will still pass whatever
test it passed before but the output is
not truly random anymore right it
doesn't no longer has enough entropy in
it okay so that that is a general
argument for why you cannot do this sort
of thing classically okay so the you
know the way that quantum computing
evades this argument is that that sort
of transformation of you know just
taking out the randomness and swapping
in something else that doesn't work for
quantum algorithms right there's no
analogous notion to that for a quantum
algorithm yes
hmm oh that's a good question I know you
don't for this because we will be you
know a suit you know the assumption that
we'll make well you know basically be
that you know will imply that this
problem cannot be solved in quantum
polynomial time or sort of takes
exponential resources even if you have a
quantum computer so you know so in order
to fake the results if you believe the
complexity assumption you would need a
much much much more powerful quantum
computer yeah you are in fact ok wait
wait wait wait no I'm sorry sorry that's
ok that's going to be on my next slide
though ok so ok so you know notice that
our protocol requires certain tasks like
finding you know high probability
outputs of a quantum circuit to be easy
for quantum computers ironically it
requires other tasks like finding the
same high probability output each time
to be hard for a quantum computers so we
use both the strengths and the
limitations of quantum computers ok now
you might say well you know this this ok
so the protocol is going to require
challenges to be sent to the quantum
computer the challenges are going to be
generated pseudo randomly ok now you may
say isn't this kind of circular if we
already have a PRG then what do we even
need you know true random bits for ok
but there were several advantages ok one
is that you know even if the PRG were to
be broken in the future well as long as
it's not broken now then you know then
we're still ok so we get this sort of
forward secrecy property ok also even if
the seed was public as long as it wasn't
known to our quantum computer at the
time then the random bits can be private
ok and also we get this freshness
property that was just asked about ok
that the random bits were not known to
anyone even the quantum computer before
it received the challenge and had to
respond to it ok so here's you know I
sort of already sketched what the
protocol is but just to say it
more carefully so the classical client
generates a list of n cubed quantum
circuits say c1 up to CT pseudo-random
ly okay is outputs of a pseudo-random
function in a way that mimics some you
know random ensemble of circuits that we
think is hard then for each T the client
sends the tia circuit to the server
demands back a response S sub T within a
short time in the honest case that
response should be a list of K samples
from the output distribution the results
from applying that circuit to say the
all zero state okay then the client
again using its seed picks a small
number of random iterations and for each
one it solves a checks whether the
output st solves a problem that we call
heavy output generation or hog okay and
if the checks pass then the client
collects together all of the outputs
from the server into one big string s
and it feeds it into a well-known
classical tool a seeded randomness
extractor okay which is able to produce
from that and again from our short
random seed you know a long string that
is a nearly uniformly random okay so so
this hog problem you know so the test
that we that we check whether the the
the quantum computers output satisfying
it is basically just you know take a
couple of outputs from the quantum
computer each of which is an N bit
string let's call them s1 up to SK and
then just calculate what each of their
output should be you know from an ideal
quantum circuit right you know see you
can do that if you have to to the end
time
alright just check you know what is the
probability that each of these were
supposed to have been output okay if the
s i--'s were chosen completely at random
then I expect each of these to be 1 over
2 to the N on average and I expect their
sum to be like K over 2 to the N okay
but if I'm really doing valid sampling
then my outputs should be biased toward
the ones with higher probabilities
right I should never see anything with
that's predicted to have probability
zero and you know and and the prior you
know and as I said the distribution is
not uniform right in fact we know a lot
about what the distribution looks like
it the probabilities are exponentially
distributed random variables and you
know in some special cases we can even
prove that that's true in other cases we
know it to be true by way of MATLAB okay
but so you know so there are little
fluctuations what physicists call
speckle pattern in this distribution
some outcomes being you know a constant
factor likelier than others and so so
now we just sum up all these
probabilities and we check well is it
greater than is the sum greater than K
over 2 to the N by some constant factor
okay with a completely errorless quantum
circuit you would expect you know this
sum on average will be about twice K
over 2 to the N what one can calculate
okay so we just pick some constant B
between 1 and 2 and then we just do a
threshold test where we say is the sum
at least B times K over 2 to the N ok
then that's the test that's all ok so
then we have to make some hardness
assumptions and I'm going to warn you
that the hardness assumptions that I
currently no you know suffice are our
strong ones ok so this is my first
assumption I call it the long list
hardness assumption or llh a so
basically you know well I wrote it here
but uh you know to maybe to just to say
it what it says is look if I give you a
random quantum circuit and I give you an
N bit string you know it should be hard
for you you know to determine whether
that string was chosen uniformly at
random or whether it was sampled from
the output distribution of that quantum
circuit right sounds pretty plausible
right ok good so now let me assume that
that's still hard for you even if you
yourself are a quantum computer ok after
all you know it is an exponentially
unlikely output
right you're not going to be able to
sort of reproduce it you know and even
if you're a quantum computer running in
sub-exponential time with a sub
exponential amount of quantum advice
okay but I'm still not done because now
let's assume also you're an AM protocol
okay so you get to send a poly sighs
classical challenge to Merlin who sends
back a poly sighs classical responds you
know but that shouldn't help because
that's just like approximate counting
but you know quantum circuits are like a
sharp P type of problem right so that's
you know okay but I'm still not done
because you get an exponential you
actually get random access to an
exponentially long list of quantum
circuits and an exponentially long list
of strings and now you just have to
decide whether all the strings were
chosen uniformly around them or whether
each string was chosen from the output
distribution of its quantum circuit all
right so just assume that that's hard
okay oh but by the way I can prove that
this is true in the random Oracle model
okay now you might say well it's not a
lot of good to generate random numbers
in a world with a random work all right
but but but these are actually rent you
know I can the random bits that you
would get would be random even to
someone who knew the random Oracle and
who had unlimited computation time so
it's a it's a non-trivial statement okay
okay right and then you know
so the basic theorem that one can prove
is that if that llh a holds and we just
analyze a single round of this protocol
then you know you know you know and and
it passes the solves the hog problem
then in each round it generates you know
well you know you you have some good
amount of min entropy so like you you
know you the the output distribution of
your quantum algorithm must have at
least this fraction of its probability
mass on outputs with say it most this
probability okay and so so now you just
have to sort of get your quantum
computer working well enough that this B
times Q is greater than one right Q
being the success probability of the
quantum computer right so that tells the
experimental
exactly what target they have to aim for
right you know to get min entropy
generation okay what expert like let's
say eight to the end okay but you know
not not nearly large enough that you're
gonna see like a completely trivial
quantum circuit anywhere in it yeah but
but we're making a hardness assumption
okay
so you know and then you know the proof
idea is well but you know if you assume
that there was a low entropy quantum
algorithm that quickly solved this
problem we can exploit that to get an AM
protocol that would violate this llh a
right and the intuition comes from we'll
just imagine that we had a zero entropy
quantum algorithm right a pseudo
deterministic one okay that always
produce the same output in that case you
know you know sort of it really just
reduces to an approximate counting type
of problem where Merlin would just have
to tell Arthur like here is where in
this giant list you can find strings
that are you know the ones that your
algorithm will output and there will be
a larger number of such strings in the
case where the strings are being sampled
you know then in the case where they're
just being chosen uniformly around them
right and then it just reduces to a em
approximate counting okay so um you know
the more general case well you have to
do more work okay now a second
assumption that we need to make is that
there are pseudo-random functions that
are hard to invert even with a quantum
computer I mean that's a pretty safe
assumption but again I'm gonna have to
go a little further and saying I want
pseudo-random functions that are
indistinguishable from random even to a
hypothetical quantum computer that could
make multiple non collapsing
measurements of a quantum state okay or
if you don't like that we could also say
that are indistinguishable from random
to a quantum statistical zero knowledge
or QSC kay protocol okay so lattice
based crypto is no good for that okay
but you know anything based on let's say
some AES type of completely scrambling
function I think it should be fine
okay so so yeah all right and this again
holds in the random Oracle model this
assumption okay so then the main result
is basically that if our assumptions
both hold and you know the server is a
poly time bounded quantum computer and
it passes our test then then you know it
must be generating at least a linear
amount of min entropy per iteration okay
so after T iterations you get TN min
entropy and there actually there's a the
most technical part in the analysis is
to show that the min entropy accumulates
from one round to the next right like it
could be that each round was
individually random but they were all
conspiratorial II correlated with each
other or something and you know you have
to rule that out okay uh what yeah
that's right the verifier runs in two to
the N time yeah that's a good question I
would have well one would have to think
about that more yeah let me let me let
me not give a confident answer without
having thought about it okay so yeah so
oh I should mention that there is a
beautiful independent approach to this
problem in a paper by these authors
recently and what they've done is
actually you know shown how to again how
to use a single quantum device that's
untrusted to generate certified random
bits they need to assume only the
quantum hardness of breaking lattice
based crypto systems so much more
conventional assumption and their scheme
has a further I won't have time to
explain how their scheme works it
involves some you know exotic types of
trapdoor functions but you know theirs
has a further advantage over mine which
is they give a polynomial time classical
algorithm to verify the results okay so
what is the advantage of my scheme well
mostly just that it could actually be
implemented in the near term so mine you
know you know works sort of as soon as
you have a 70 qubit device that achieves
quantum supremacy there
seems to require at least about a
thousand cubits you know to get any type
of security and at that point you're
talking about quantum fault tolerance so
you might be talking about millions of
physical qubits and then that that's
further in the future okay
so there are many open problems about
the scheme you know can we get certified
randomness by sampling with the same
circuit over and over can we prove our
scheme sound under less boutique
complexity assumptions
what about soundness against yeah you
know so the adversary's that are
entangled with the quantum computer but
we wanted to say is that you know this
may actually be so so so so Google has
sort of gotten excited about this and
you know the rink the reason is not that
this is a world changing application you
know we know you know other ways to get
you know probably good enough random
bits but you know this may be the most
plausible application for a very
near-term quantum computer that that we
know of okay so you know it can be done
with seventy cubits you don't even want
more than seventy cubits somehow all the
weaknesses of quantum supremacy
experiments have become strengths okay
so I probably don't have a lot of time
to say a lot about differential privacy
do i oh I have ten minutes all right
good let's go you ready let's go okay
all right so BA so by request I want to
say a little bit about my work with a
guy Roth Blum about gentle measurement
and differential privacy this is also
not yet written up all right we've got a
lot to do so so as you may have heard
measurements in quantum mechanics are
destructive right you you open the box
you check if the cat is alive or dead
well guess what it's not in
superposition anymore okay so but
measurements are not always destructive
okay if you were kind enough to ask the
cat whether it's a live plus dead or
alive - dead then it may just tell you
yeah I'm a live plus dead and then it's
state is completely unaffected by that
right so you know when quantum mechanics
the general rule is if you measure your
State in a basis where you know the
state happens to already be one of the
basis vectors right I would say the
outcome of that measurement would have
been almost perfectly predictable to
someone who knew the state then that
state is damaged only a little bit by
the measurement right and you can keep
reusing that state over and over and
make many measurements on it okay so
this is known as gentle measurement okay
in physics you know it actually has many
experimental applications okay so more
formally given a quantum measurement M
that acts on n registers let's call em
alpha gentle if for every product state
meaning you unentangled state on an
registers call it row and for every
possible outcome Y of that measurement
the state of ro if I apply the
measurement and get the outcome Y right
so that you know the state changes to
something if I get the outcome Y but its
trace distance this is just a quantum
generalization of variation distance
between two distributions
you know our usual distance metric
between quantum states you know it
should be should be small from from from
the original state rail should be at
most alpha okay that's a gentle
measurement so here's an example
you know let's say I have n unentangled
qubits and I want to measure the total
Hamming weight okay well in general
that's a very destructive measurement
because the I'll have a superposition
over possible Hamming weights that has
some Gaussian distribution like if you
don't know what a Gaussian looks like
it's that okay physicists would call it
a wave packet okay but then I measure it
and now I force the thing down to a
single Hamming weight right I collapse
the whole thing okay but what if instead
I asked for only the Hamming weight plus
some random noise of order at least
square root of n well that's much safer
right because now it's like I'm not some
I'm not damaging it by too much the
physicists actually know this this is
actually used in you know photon number
measurements and this is how you do it
non-destructively okay all right now
let's talk about a completely unrelated
topic differential privacy right let's
say we want to protect the privacy
rights of
quantum states okay well how can we
generalize the definition that Cynthia
showed us this morning to the quantum
case well let's just say given a
measurement M that acts on n registers
let's call it epsilon differentially
private if for every product state again
on my n registers row and for every row
Prime that differs from row on only a
single location a single quantum state
dropped out of the data set the
probability that my measurement returns
why is that most one plus epsilon times
the probability that my measurement
returns Y or on row prime right this is
just a natural quantum generalization of
DP okay
so here's another example let's say I
want to measure the total Hamming weight
of an done entangled qubits well that's
not differentially private but if I add
a noise term okay then it becomes DP as
we heard this morning okay so what
happened was I gave a talk last fall at
Weitzman where I talked about gentle
measurements and guy came to me
afterward and said this sounds a lot
like DP and I said come on you can just
you know everyone can connect anything
to whatever they work on right it's
probably just some some random noise
okay you know itself noise okay but then
we thought about it and hmm turns out
that there is a theorem that proves you
know I think an incredibly strong
connection between these two concepts
okay so so here's the what our theorem
says first of all any measurement that
is alpha gentle is also oh of alpha
differentially private okay
so in that direction it just completely
tight okay in the other direction
there's some more caveats but you know
it but something goes through okay if a
measurement M is epsilon D P and it has
some you know special form that actually
encompasses all the examples that we
actually know or care about that it
consists of some classical DP algorithm
that's applied to the outcomes of a
bunch of quantum measurements then M can
be implemented in a way that is o of
epsilon times square root of n gentle
okay so I lose something but like
Epsilon is between 1 over N and 1 over
square root of n and that's still
interesting right
so both directions can be shown to be
asymptotically tight we have to talk
about product states if we talk about
entangled states we can prove something
but it turns out to like only really
give us anything for completely trivial
measurements okay and you might wonder
about computational efficiency well part
2 preserves computational efficiency as
long as your DP algorithm has the
property that its output can be
efficiently Q sampled which means you
must be able to efficiently prepare a
coherent quantum superposition over the
outputs of the DP algorithm with no
noise now most of the DP algorithms that
we actually looked at do have that
property but that but that is something
we need now this could be seen as a
quantum analog of the known connection
between DP and adaptive data analysis
right the entire point there was you
have this data set and you want to sort
of look at it without sort of damaging
it by too much right the difference is
in the classical case the damage is just
something that occurs in your head right
the damage could always be reversed if
you just forgot what you learned right
in the quantum case the damage it's an
actual physical thing that happens to
the state or someone else who measures
that state could see that it was damaged
okay and this actually has had an
application so in a paper and the pass
stock I proved something that I called
the shadow tomography theorem basically
it gives a new measurement procedure for
quantum states where if I have some
unknown quantum state in d dimensions
and I have a list of known to outcome
measurements you want up to a m then
what I can do is I can learn the
approximate probabilities that each of
these measurements accepts my state so
the you know for each AI the approximate
probability that it accepts Rho using a
number of copies of Rho that grows only
Polly logarithmically with both m and D
okay so even if I had a state of
exponentially large dimension
so you know like n qubits two to the N
dimensions and I wanted to know its
behavior on exponentially many different
circuits like all circuits with it most
N squared gates or something I can do
that using only polynomially many copies
of the state okay so that was that was
kind of cool now but now we can do is we
can use known results from differential
privacy in particular this private
multiplicative weights or a pmw
algorithm of Hart and Ross Blum somehow
guy knew about and as well as our DP and
gentle this connection and we can
actually improve this result okay we get
down the dependence on log of M from
fourth to second power more
interestingly we give a procedure that
is online so it can respond to the
measurements one by one as it receives
them and in itself is gentle it's you
know after we're done our copies of Rao
are still good to use for something else
okay so there are many open problems can
you prove a fully general connection
without the conditions you know what are
the optimal parameters for Shadow
tomography and finally can we go in the
other direction and use quantum
computing to say something new about
classical differential privacy I think
that would nicely complete the circle
here okay thank you
[Applause]