thank you and thank you for eval for a
introduction and for organizing this
workshop I think cryptography has really
been leading in a lot of ways in
theoretical computer science a lot of
the things like interactive proofs
actually originated from cryptography so
maybe even this workshop should have
been called behind cryptography rapid
beyond cryptography so I'm going to talk
about optimal algorithms and assumption
factories in the at some points I'll
mention some work some of which have
been published some of it not yet been
published by several joint with several
people including speak about curse keys
I'm Hopkins I used Jane Ellen K per fish
Qatari hand come with and with the hi
okay so let me start with talking about
something that I see as a puzzle so in
cryptography we kind of use to the fact
that you know people have sat down in
the 1970s and looked at a problem like
you know the RSA problem and they try to
you know they try to the obvious ways to
solve it and they couldn't and it has
we've stood until this day so in some
sense we have the intuition in crypto
that if you think about a particular
hardness assumptions if it doesn't get
broken it's probably is because it's
actually inherently computationally
difficult and in other fields people
have some kind of the opposite intuition
they think like most problems are
actually easy there easy unless proven
otherwise so you know almost every
problem they solve in machine learning
is np-hard and they still solve them all
the time like you know optimizing over
deep neural networks or any anything
like that is always NPR and they still
solve it every day
every time also if you look at economics
there even though we have all these
books that which in equilibrium is
computationally hard there are some are
unfazed by these proofs and they you
know one way avatar which once told me
that they face it there is milk on the
chef so there is obvious proof that
people manage to find equilibrium that
you know the stores and the customers
manage to come together in equilibrium
even though we have all these
theoretical proofs that this is supposed
to be hard so you write their shelves
that put well Amazon doesn't have shells
in it maybe so in some sense it seems
like if you think in all these fields
people kind of think if you think of
hard versus easy problems then they
think that the problems of one types are
a small island in the sea of problems of
the other types but a crypto and the ML
econ disagree what is the island and
what is the sea is the sea had problems
and there is a small island of easy
problems or is the sea easy problems and
there is a small island of hard problems
so this is somewhat of a puzzle and what
is it should we think of a great problem
as easy and less proven have otherwise
it was hard unless proven otherwise and
and and maybe in some sense there is not
as big a contradiction because if you
think about this first of all in crypto
we have these kind of ideas of what is
the best algorithm to apply for a
certain class of problems so we have
these you know generic group models
random Oracle models etc where we try to
capture what's the certain types of
algorithms that could be applicable to
attack a certain a certain problem and
if you look at machine learning it's
also not as if they believe problems are
easy because whenever they're faced with
a new problem they would come up with a
brilliant new and unexpected algorithm
they always use the same algorithm so so
they also have the intuition that for
the class of problems that they are
interested in if they are solvable
they usually may be unsolvable but they
are solvable by
kind of algorithm and in economics also
what people do is not you know a market
doesn't run
I don't know stress in the first matrix
multiplication or something like that
it runs basically converges and to an
equilibrium by some kind of best
response dynamics you know people modify
the prices based on supply and demand so
so in some sense both all of these
script these fields the intuitions agree
with something that is a little bit
different than what we learn in you know
algorithms one on one so if you learn in
into an intro to algorithm class then
probably you've learned it from a very
thick book and and the thick book kind
of describes it as if there are like all
these problems and for every different
problem you come up with in brilliant
different algorithm but maybe in real
life it's more the case that you know
all sorts of problems in a certain
domain are solved by the same algorithm
and and if that algorithm doesn't
succeed then no algorithm will succeed
so that's kind of the question I want to
talk about and in the the question is
instances it should we expect to have
like an optimal algorithm for a wide
wide range of problems not all problems
and what kind of an algorithm could be
optimal and what what can we use such a
such things for cryptography and let me
say that I'm going to focus in some
sense I'm going to do the equivalence of
searching for your keys under the
streetlight in the sense I'm going to
focus on the easier class of
computational problems for which we
could maybe more reasonably hope to
understand this kind of a optimal
algorithm I'm going to focus on
combinatorial types of problems which in
crypto land might correspond to private
key
things like you know pseudo-random
generators and in algorithmic
optimization will talk about
satisfiability graph problems in some
sense maybe the things that are most
interesting to us is to understand the
difficulty of problems like you know
lattices factoring where there are more
algebraic nature there were publicly and
there also were a quantum and quantum
speedups seem to become possible but
maybe if we first understand get a good
picture of the combinatorial domain we
can move to the algebraic domain and
this is not very well defined and I'm
not going to also it's one of the I
think the main questions in this
research agenda is how to define what is
combinatorial and don't know how to do
it yet but I'll give you some kind of
buzzwords or intuition so they may be
prototypic prototypical combinatorial
problem is satisfiability and may be the
prototype i put a typical algebraic
problem is integer factoring and you can
think of it as you know so this
probability you want to maximize some
objective in the integer factoring you
want to kind of put together like a very
big widget puzzle and in some sense if
you think about what is combinatorial
versus algebraic we think of you know
maybe in combinatorics we talking about
maximizing number of constraints
satisfied it's more like inequalities
versus equality's in algebraic things we
have more types of interesting
consolations we're talking about exact
and it's more about widget structure or
like less less about noise but again
these are passwords or intuitions and
for now let's see let's use the kind of
I know it when I see it kind of focus on
things like satisfiability very simple
pseudo-random generators for these
lectures and certain graph partition
problems that somehow seems like there
are more combinatorial in nature okay
and the algorithm I'm going to talk
about as a candidate for being an
optimal algorithm is the sum of squares
algorithm was proposed by
several researchers including Joe
Perillo in the cell and this is kind of
a metal algorithm it's meta in two ways
first of all it's not an algorithm for a
single problem you can kind of apply to
really a wide range of problems in some
sense any problem you any problem in NP
or some filling in and and it also has a
tunable running time parameter so so you
can also tune the the algorithm for both
the problem and for how long how much of
a come budget do you want to give it to
one so and so you can ask the question
of how fast it runs on a particular
instance a particular problem and it's
kind of a common generalization of
linear programming semi definite
programming spectral algorithms and also
encapsulate some kind of many
combinatorial types of algorithms like
local search and ingredie and indeed in
many cases you can show that it captures
the state-of-the-art in the sense that
whatever algorithm gives the best-known
performance for a certain problem sum of
squares will also embed this algorithm
it's not necessarily the way you would
want to run it because it will involve
like solving a huge semi definite
program which is polynomial time but not
really efficient but but it does embed
it and in fact in many cases it is the
state of the art in the sense that the
best known algorithm we know was
obtained for this for this algorithm in
the reason I'm interested in this
algorithm is that in some on one hand
it's powerful enough that you can make
the claim that it's plausibly optimal in
some range of parameters and in fact you
know if so-called I'm not going to focus
on worst case setting is in this talk
but for worst case setting there is
formal conjectures a unique games
conjecture that says it's if it's true
then this algorithm is optimal in an for
constraint satisfaction problems and so
on the one it is powerful enough to be
plausibly optimal unlike say
things like restricted models like AC
zero something like that way you know
depth they too bounded funny no like
these kind of models which we sometimes
prove lower bands for but they are not
very strict but but it is still weak
enough so we can vigorously analyze and
show that it fails on a certain so so
it's not so powerful that basically
proving that it fails sometimes is as
hard as proving that P is different from
NP so it seems to kind of strike this
balance which makes it quite interesting
so not going to go over all this list of
like these are specific cases recent
work has shown that the sum of squares
algorithm gives the better results than
was known before for a variety of
problems so and a lot of problems come
from machine learning but some of them
also from quantum information theory or
you know community optimization etc and
this is just a partial list from more
recent work and this talk I'm going to
focus on the relation between sum of
squares and simple pseudo-random
generators and I'll stop by before view
of sum of squares and then I'll talk
about how it applies to pseudo-random
generators but I do think that this
optimal algorithm paradigm could be
relevant outside of pseudo-random
generators and specifically I will talk
about some attacks on pseudo-random
generator candidates that were recently
proposed for for obtaining
indistinguishable obfuscators and some
evidence for the security of others to
the random generators which at the
moment seemed to be just beyond what we
need for obfuscators but still very
interesting in their own right okay so
these are the two parts of the talk and
I am going to start with a part one ok
so talk about what is this sum of
squares algorithm very briefly and then
how does it apply to pseudo-random
generators okay so the sum squares
algorithm this is by the way a spectral
hitman which is kind of the object that
you optimize over in this algorithm so
the sum of squares proof system is
basically the algorithm is obtained from
a poof system and what is the proof
system you're trying to prove a
statement that of the following form you
want to say that for every X that
satisfies a certain Impala nominally
inequalities it's a it also satisfies
another inequality so that's the kind of
statements you're trying to prove and
this can be very general because you can
write like for example you can express
something like X is an independent set
in a graph as a set of polynomial
inequalities you know your other
equality X I squared equals X I that
says that X every entry of X is 0 0 1
then you can add like inequalities that
say it's an independent set and so for
example if you wanted to prove a
statement like every independent set in
a graph as size at most at most K
vertices you can easily write it as a
set of you know statement of this form
so these are polynomials in various
polymers of the wheels and the axioms
we'll use a very simple 1 axiom is that
a square is always non-negative and our
axiom is that if you know that for every
X in that satisfies your condition P of
X is non-negative and Q of X is
non-negative then P times Q and P plus Q
are also no negative and this simple
proof system turns out to be complete
every two inequality every two statement
of this form can be proven using this
proof system and this is a result like a
fundamental result in real algebraic
geometry known as the positive standard
sets and it allows it's like a
generalization of the solution of a
Hilbert xvii problem it said that every
non-negative polynomial can be expressed
as a sum of squares of rational
functions
and now you can also keep track of what
is the maximum degree in the proof that
you used and the way we'll do it is we
will talk of SiC tactic degree which
means we don't allow cancellations if P
is the greedy q is the greedy Prime we
say that P times Q is the greedy plus D
Prime and P plus Q is the maximum of the
degrees and even if for some reason the
worst cancellation we kind of just keep
its intact ik and then it turns out and
this is this sum of squares algorithm
that you can find the greek' proofs in
time which is basically n to the K so if
K is constant this is polynomial time so
basically you have this sum of squares
poof system it can prove anything and it
has a parameter called the degree the
smaller degree the better the running
time in actually finding puts and one
example of something you can prove with
this is like say the Cauchy Schwarz
inequality so the Cauchy Schwarz
inequality we can think of it as the
following theorem
you know the dot the dot product of P
and API P and Q is smaller than the
product of the norms you know let's
square both of them so the dot product
squared is smaller than the product of
the norm squared and and you can just
write it you know you can just open it
up and see that this is a sum of squares
so you can express it as you know you
just you just write the left-hand thing
is obviously a sum of squares so it's
obviously non-negative and then you you
open it up and you see that this is
really equal to 2 times the polynomial
that's and 2 times the thing that's
that's above so it's so that's a proof
it's not negative you just express it as
a sum of squares okay and there like
many other results showing that lots of
interesting theorems have low degree sum
of squares puffs and also some results
showing that interesting statements have
a high require high degree sum of
squares proofs and the one thing that I
want to make sure is
to emphasize is that low-degree sum of
squares poof's is not the same as
simplicity for humans so you can have
like things like these results on a
majority stablest which are like papers
that were in the annals of mathematics
and still can be proven using this sum
of squares proof system with only a
constant degree and on the other hand
you can have like the result that a
random 3sat formula is not satisfiable
which is like five lines using the
probabilistic method and that requires a
very large degree for sum of squares so
these two and the notion of having the
small small sum of squares degree in the
notion of being simple proof in what we
think of it as intuitively is not the
same thing but the important thing is
lots of interesting interesting
statements can be proven with low
degrees some squares post with the
probabilistic mess of being an important
exception so how does this sum of
squares algorithm work so I'll just give
you a cartoon of it and so this slide
may or may not make a lot of sense but
if it doesn't then just ignore it and
say okay there is this algorithm it it
just works so the idea is the following
think of like a statement like the like
the simplest things they think of a
statement we're trying to prove that
there is no X that mutually vanishes on
all these polynomials so it turns out
that the sum of squares proof of that
you can collapse all this all the
derivation steps and say at the end it
has the following form it says it has
the form minus 1 equals P plus s where P
is the sum of P IQ I for some arbitrary
Qi and s is the sum of squares now if
you think about it P if there was an X
which were all of these P is where value
would vanish on then P of X will have to
be 0 s of X would have put to be
non-negative because it's a sum of
squares and then you would get a
contradiction that minus 1 equals a
non-negative number so so this is a
proof so this is a proof that there is
no
if you assume that there is an X that p1
of X P and P 2 of X all are 0 then you
get a contradiction so this is how this
sum of squares looks like and if you
think about it it's if you look at took
two convex combination if you look at
some P and s that satisfy this equality
star and then you look at some peopie
man s prime that satisfy this equality
star and you take a convex combination
of them it also satisfies this equality
star so that means the this is a convex
subset and it turns out that this convex
subset is like a nice convex subset that
can you know be expressed basically as a
specter hidden so you can find so you
can determine whether this convex set is
empty or not using a semi definite
programming so that's really kind of
very much a cartoon but that's basically
[Music]
how the algorithm looks like so it's
semi definite programming to search for
these proofs and the number of variables
you need in this program is n to the K
where K is the degree so now if I
confused you and I think there is a good
chance I did let's say just kind of step
back and say what is the take-home
message so this sum of squares proof
system is on one hand powerful you can
prove many theorems using low degree a
sum of squares on the other hand it's
what's known as automatize Abell so you
have an algorithm to find proofs like
that when they exist
oops and the third thing it's useful
because it gives you like this
algorithmic paradigm that canyou can use
for many many problems and I haven't
demonstrated to you right a list of all
sorts of problems and we can also wonder
whether it's optimal in the sense that
because it does seem to capture the
state of art for lots of problems often
so you can wonder if maybe that's it
when that fails nothing succeeds and
that's basically would be the sum of
squares optimality conjecture and if you
assume that this is optimal then you
basically get an assumption Factory in
the following sense that for every
concrete problem
if you show a sum of squares lower bound
for it it's immediate in a new assume
that sum of squares is optimal then you
immediately get a conjecture that this
but or the assumption that this problem
is hard so so this kind of say so if you
if you believe and are able to state a
conjecture that this is the sum of
squares is optimal in a certain domain
you basically get a factory that gives
you many concrete hardness assumptions
from very concrete problems so let me
now move to part two and talk about the
relation to pseudo-random generators so
talk about simple pseudo-random
generator so simple pseudo-random
generators want to think about it is
every output pseudo-random generator
takes n bits expands it into n bits
where if so it takes a seed of size n
and outputs a longer output of size M
where m is bigger than n and and you can
define what is it means simple so the
one notion of simple is that every
output is just you know say depends on
just five input bits another more
refined notion was recently put forward
is that every outputs depend on saying
just a few blocks of the input bits or
think of the input the sitter's coming
with a larger alphabet and you can also
think of the Greve it as a polynomial
and in the these have been widely
studied and let me just give you kind of
like the flavor of some results so
people have shown that if you if this
simple pseudo-random generator of this
exists you get all sorts of cool
applications for example a constant
overhead a multi-party skew computation
or you can reduce their is a work of a
challenge of reducing the requirement to
indistinguishability of Fuson to just
constant degree maps and if you assumed
even more simple to the random generator
so if you assume super simple to the
random generators then you can get magic
and by magic i mean you can get these
obfuscation from standard assumptions
by linear assumptions and super simple
we'll sit in it but roughly speaking
degree 3 is simple degree 2 is super
simple so so and one of the things is it
like understand what yes what will
happen and we'll focus on the degree
case that also works on locality etc so
think of every output is just a degree D
polynomial if you think of it as a
polynomial of the over the integers and
and there was this work of lenient
tercera that shows that if you have this
notion known as block locality which is
kind of a weaker it's kind of a stricter
notion just being just simply the grid -
it's some of the grid - of a particular
flavor then you can get
indistinguishable of whiscash in this
holy grail of crypto under basically
standard assumptions but unfortunately
in worked with Bukowski comodo ski
Qatari and also there was a simultaneous
work of Lombardy icons and we we showed
that sum of squares breaks block
locality to pseudo-random generators and
very recently there was a work just
showing that you can relax the
assumption in two ways first of all only
need the grid to and certainly you kind
of need a weaker notion than being like
a full-fledged pseudo-random generators
and you can still get the same
conclusion and very recently in work
that's not yet put online we showed that
a sum of squares strongly breaks these
degree - pronto generator so it also
breaks the kind of assumption that we're
puttin in these recent works and this is
what I'll talk a little bit now and I've
mentioned now a little bit more although
again not with so many details so how do
you break this degree to pseudo-random
generator so the idea is you think of
the following think of these inputs as
you know you get in think of now your
goal is to break it completely so you
really want to recover the seed not just
maybe predict or distinguish from
uniform so you're getting this G 1 of X
still G M of X you getting these outputs
for degree 2 polynomials you know that
the polynomials but you don't know X a
new goal is to recover X so the way we
look at it is we rephrase this question
and we think of it as the following we
think of this unknown X as being a rank
one matrix and then this g1 the GM
instead of degree two polynomials now we
can think of them as linear measurements
on this matrix so getting these M linear
measurements M linear functions the
output of M linear functions on this one
common matrix X and our goal is to
recover X so it's just a rephrasing of
this problem but if we rephrase it this
way this is becomes like a problem that
people actually have studied this is
known as the low and recovery problem
and has been studied in great depth and
etc and it known that to be solvable
using some other semi definite
programming which is a special case of
some squares if this GI satisfy the
condition known as matrix restricted
isometry property and we showed that
basically all the candidates that we
recently put forward do satisfy this
property and and that's about as much
detail I'm going to show it turns out
that you can actually this SDP in this
case is simple enough you can actually
run it in you know it's about five lines
of giulia code and and you can show that
basically in this case we ran it like
so we got like when M equals n we got we
got already 75% agreement with they
recovered something that was 75% close
to the original seed and when M is like
2 n will basically be covered completely
there yes so the particular candidates
there the the do artists that do satisfy
it I believe this week condition is not
needed for pure G's but then it becomes
a little bit more delicate because you
can you can probably make sure that you
don't weaker you don't recover X but for
example just ignoring information about
say half of the bits of X and then you
will not satisfy the whip condition but
it also doesn't seem useful in that
sense so but I think basically any
candidate where
the polynomials are drawn from some
distribution and each coordinate is
drawn iid then the fairly weak
conditions on the distribution and that
will ensure it satisfies with if M is
say n times poly log n so so so let me
say why do people study these matrix
recovery that also will bring us to the
distinguished distinction between simple
pseudo-random generators and super
simple pseudo-random generators so why
did people study matrix recovery they
didn't do it to break through the random
generators one of the motivations was
something like the net flix problem so
suppose you are given so suppose you
know you you are like a streaming
service and you have some reviews of
user for movies and now you want to
predict what what what the user will
like about movies that they didn't see
it so another way to say it is that you
have this matrix of users versus movies
and you have some observations about it
you have some measurements about it
which is the ratings that you you
haven't you want to complete it you want
to get the entries that you don't have
and how do you do it the idea is that
you kind of think of it the following
things and you think of each user they
have a certain things they like and
think certain things they dislike so you
know maybe they like kids movies they
you know they dislike action maybe they
like horror or something like that and
each movie has a certain features and
basically the rating of the rating of a
user it's kind of like up to some noise
it's like dot product of the vector of
the features of the users and the
vectors of the features of the movie and
this basically means that this matrix X
is low rank so then it becomes really
the low rank recovery problem this is
with measurements that are particularly
like looking at just coordinates of the
matrix but you can generalize it to any
linear measurements and then this has
been very well studied and widely
studied and you know that if say R is
constant in our case R is 1 then
you only need basically often Oh tilde
of n observations which means which
corresponds to you cannot get a
pseudo-random generator that stretches
too much so that's basically why these
results end up breaking degree two
pseudo-random generators yes integers
but they are embedded in the wheels so
it's kind of as opposed to yes finite
fields yes yes and and now you can ask
also what what what is the degree freak
pseudo-random generators correspondent
that would correspond to a problem like
tensile recovery which is also well
motivated so for example sometimes maybe
the particular movie you want to watch
somehow depends on the time of day you
know and in my household for example if
you look at if you look at the movies we
tend to watch at Netflix at you know 11
a.m. on a Saturday when the parents are
maybe trying to sleep and the kids are
awake and it might be very different
than the movies we watch on 11 p.m.
we're just kids
I mean like you know my kids just you
know what's the deep deep educational
documentaries well you know I just wait
till to go asleep so I can watch body so
so so these sometimes maybe they you
know you have like this kind of tensor
where it's it's like a three-dimensional
thing you want to and it turns out that
there there is a difference it seems to
be difference sum of squares does
recover but it needs more measurements
in particular if they think of D as
equals to three like it's a three tensor
then you need n to the one point five
think of their bankers constant you need
n to the one point five measurements as
opposed to only essentially n
measurements so we know how to week so
they we did that approx protection story
we did it exactly we know how to recover
with n to the one point five
measurements and it also follows from
some previous lower bounds that sum of
squares actually does require
exponential time for if you have less
than n to the one point five
measurements so this leads to this kanji
that may be the maximum output length
for a pseudo-random generator is if they
have to the random generator is of
degree D then it's roughly n to the D
over 2 so you know degree 2 basically
it's roughly n so it doesn't really have
like significant stretch the gray 3
might have stretch m to enter the 1.5
degree for n to the N squared and if you
believe that sum of squares is optimal
then basically this is the this kind of
conjectures basically says you know if
you think of super linear stretch then
you can break
you know these pure G's when there are
degree at most two and the known lower
bound show that some squares at least
will require exponential time what the
degree is for your mo so you could maybe
so this is obviously insecure and but
you could conjecture that degree three
or more
is secure and that's basically how you
could if you believe in a source
optimality you can transform an SOS
lower bound into you know cryptographic
hardness assumption and in particular
people have been working very hard on
trying to use that cryptographic are
this assumption as a basis for basic
mosquitoes and standard assumptions and
if you kind of say yes yeah so you have
to give particular candidates like say
in that case like but many candidates
actually it requires exponential time
yeah in particular quantum things yeah
you have to be not silly like in some
sense for there are some kind of silly
things you can do which even in the grid
Android will not be secure pseudo endo
generator in particular you can have a
bias or something so if you kind of step
back a like we we have this a similar
issue with both say machine learning in
crypto where we deal with average case
hardness and how much I have a time to
have anyway okay so I'm very good so yes
so so if you can so so both machine
learning encrypted a deal with average
case harness
and basically machine learning we try to
solve it you know so in and in both
cases we basically cannot really use NP
hardness to get insight for it and in
some sense it's very hard for us to even
use reductions at all there are very
concrete case where as well there are
like worst-case to average case worst
case to average case reductions but in
many of these cases we don't know and
also in many problems the the type of NP
hardness reductions they modify the
distribution so they will not give you a
harness on of a problem on a natural
distribution so an pianist gives us very
limited insight on difficulty for these
both these fields and maybe this is
again like a case where they both these
fields agree in a sense that machine
learning people are not worried machine
learning are not worried when when when
a problem they're trying to solve is
np-hard and cryptographers have learned
the hard way the lesson that they should
not be rest on their laurels when the
problems that they're trying to base the
crypto system is on is np-hard so so
both fields kind of kind of agree that
NP hardness is not the right measurement
of of difficulty for and in yes so much
machinery you try to solve and you're
happy if you succeed but in crypto we
are like in more difficult situation
because you know you try to solve it but
if you can't you you you just hope that
no one can do it and then in some sense
if you have these optimality conjectures
we can maybe make rather than basically
the idea of like the cycle of you know
build pray break we could maybe get a
more systemic way to analyze this
problem and this kind of assumption
Factory so to do that we really need
some kind of formal optimality
conjecture so let me talk about this sum
of squares optimality conjecture so the
current status of the sum of squares
optimality conjecture is the
following this is my conjecture so
haven't yet been able to formalize it a
conjecture that it is possible so a
conjecture that the reason is a Musquin
so maybe this is the meta meta some
skills optimality conjecture maybe there
is even a meta meta where there is i
conjecture that there is some optimal
algorithm I don't know if it sum of
squares and I context that for this
algorithm there is also conjecture so so
the main bottleneck is in some sense
what does it mean to be combinatorial
and what's the clean general way that
doesn't seem like you know you're really
tailoring it to five places where and
its answers again like the I know it
when I see the definition basically
talks about say constraint satisfaction
problems certain graph partition
problems and and more generally the
intuition is basically if some squares
is plausibly optimal when you're talking
really about approximating solutions in
cases where it's not it's not as if you
you maybe you don't get you instance
precisely you have you get it up to some
noise so like you know linear equations
but noisy one so you really talking
about approximation versus the zig zags
and you're trying to optimize over kind
of nice low degree varieties so what are
nice low degree by varieties one is like
the bouillon cube the unit sphere low
and matrices or low and tensors these
are the kind of things that are like
there are mighty technical ways to try
to phrase nice in terms of Grabner bases
or something like that but basically
it's so you trying to basically have
some kind of so it seems like these two
two concepts are important they're that
you try to optimize a relatively nice
space but nice can be the boolean cube
which is not easy just it's nice but
it's not easy and
you you're not talking about exact which
is kind of crucial to avoid issues like
the fact that Gaussian elimination
unfortunately exists which of course I
think every kept ographers struggled at
some point with this annoying fact that
Gaussian elimination exists so and so so
so the formal statement is still work in
progress but I do think that there
should be one and I think it would be
very interesting for cryptography in
some sense one way to think about this
is the following so typically if you
construct a you have a crypto paper you
put it on the ePrint you try to make you
assumption as weak as possible that's
sometimes why you have like you know you
you you if you know some caveat that you
only need in your assumption then you're
added that's why I like assumptions in
crypto maybe sometimes I've like you
know five adjectives like linear DPL man
in that and that because you kind of try
to you know assume the least and in some
sense the optimality conjecture is sort
of the opposite philosophy it like
instead of a you know assuming the least
you say you know this I say speak loudly
and carry a big bullseye on you back in
the sense that make a very bold
assumption and which is basically an
assumption Factory which makes it easier
to break in some sense but also might
make might means that you if it survives
then you're more confident in it because
it's not very tailored
you know he didn't invent it just for
this particular it's as far as you can
from the assumption that the
construction is secure because our
conjecture is that the congested
construction is secure and then so I do
think this is very useful for for
cryptographers to try to think about
these kind of meta assumptions and and
in some sense they had like in the
general group model etcetera although in
cryptography sometimes you have this
annoying thing that whenever you try to
formalize these kind of generic models
assumptions you get up you get something
that's obviously false and then and my
hope is that there is like a concrete
conjecture you can make because it's
really not a generic or black box type
of assumption the sum of squares
algorithm has full access to say when it
solves that it doesn't treat a formula
as a black box it has full access to it
so it's not an ideal model type of
assumption and and I think it's it it
has a chance of being one that you can
formally specify yes well I I mean
actually like I think that would be like
too delicate in some sense there have
been kind of works where you basically
you can use there is the fake hakeem
effect in interesting thing which is not
an algorithm as much as a certificate
but it uses its combines actually SOS n
and Gaussian elimination and I hope that
basically the idea would be that if you
add noise to your problem then algebraic
algorithms like Gaussian elimination
stress and etc they go out of the
picture they basically you told me you
moved your problem into the streetlight
where you know the Gaussian elimination
monster doesn't look so so once you add
a noise to your problem I hope that the
only candidates can be this kind of more
continuous optimization of algorithms
and not gosh elimination
I guess it depends it like yeah yeah I
mean the street light there is not
necessarily the easy part but rather the
part maybe which is more analyzable yes
yes that's problem like basically
Gaussian elimination is like the curve I
mean I guess it depends like defining
Gaussian elimination is a little bit
hard because you for example you could
basically say you could possibly modify
your input so you know for example gosh
elimination of you know what group or
something like that you could maybe
present your input as something that
where it's not obvious it's not like X
or something like that it's not obvious
that it's Gaussian elimination but but
it is but it is after you know you
interpret like your input in the right
way then it turns out that it's it's
embeddable in say some abelian group or
something like that and in particular
for some sort of random generators for
example it seems like you can have these
say non non abelian non abelian linear
equation problems which Gaussian
elimination doesn't apply but for
breaking the pseudo-random generator it
only matters that there is an abelian
group hiding in there so somehow if the
group is solvable it might still you
could still break it so sometimes you
might need the Gauss elimination but you
need you need to massage it and the fake
hakeem effect is a very nice thing which
I cannot explain the details of here but
it's again like it's a very nice thing
where it kind of combines Gaussian
elimination but not just by running it
as a black box it's more like finding
some subset of the subsets of a few
formulas where you can run - elimination
on these subsets yes
yes
yes yes so that's that right yes so
that's that's actually like a great
question which maybe leads me to the
next slide and I think actually that's
all that the definition of an a great
question right that leads you to the
next slide so so in any case I just want
to say that even if you don't think if
you you think I'm kind of full of
and you know in some squares is not
optimized it still makes sense if you're
like proposing a new assumption on
something where some of could be
applicable to use it as a sanity check
so that's definitely the case and let me
say in John maybe exactly two V naught K
is like there is this issue some squares
right the some squares kind of is really
makes sense for problems that are
presented as low degree polynomials over
the wheels and if you look at certain
cryptographic problems that feel to us
may be combinatorial like say block
ciphers where they have more depth to
them or as opposed to just one round
function or parity we've know is the the
the problem is somehow not naturally a
low degree problem so it seems like some
squares is not applicable even though
it's does seem combinatorial in nature
and understanding exactly and understand
whether there is a generalization of SOS
so there is a way to view things that
still place this in the combinatorial
domain it's also very interesting for
both parity with noise and their
learning with error problem it seems
that these are problems that change
their nature when you change a
quantitative parameter so for example if
you look at learning with errors so we
know there is a certain regime of the
noise magnitude where the problem is
np-hard then you reduce the noise to a
certain level it's no longer np-hard
it's in NP intersect when P and then it
becomes useful for crypto and maybe it
feels a little bit algebraic and then
you reduce it so you reduce the noise
even more and at some point it just the
problem just becomes in polynomial time
so it seems sometimes like the you can
have a phase transition where the nature
of a problem changes where you change
the parameter a quantitative parameter
and that's again something we don't
completely understand and but it seems
like more noise makes it more
combinatorial super less noise could
make it even easier
or maybe algebraic and and I should say
that the after we applied this the which
was joint what we've actually I usually
meet or like part of this play of this
your paper now they have a new PRG
conjecture which is somewhat between
degree 2 and degree 3 so it's somewhat
and it has it is actually interesting
mix of algebraic and combinatorial
because it's kind of like degree three
but they you build something under lwe
so this is something we have not yet
analyzed and it's not we don't yet at
least I don't have yet good intuition
for it so and so this is one compare
concrete open question to understand
this conjecture which they have and we
really want to understand where these
kind of sum of squares could be
applicable and how we could apply it to
our crypto settings where we polynomials
seem larger a higher degree at least
naturally and there is this work on
trying to understand like difficulty of
some squares and getting lower bounds in
the natural thing to apply it for lower
bounds is when it's unsatisfiable but we
want to understand with satisfiable and
there are some interesting new work that
tries to be connected to statistical
physics predictions of phase transitions
between is in how the domains and you
can also ask whoever you know to
understand relation between that and SGD
etc and again
lots of open questions there and lots of
things we don't understand and I think
that's it
[Applause]