hi everyone
and thanks for participating in this
talk
during the presentation i will talk
about the risk associated with the
iot devices and in particular i will
share my personal research on
security cameras and
before we even start i would like to
briefly introduce myself
i'm pietro oliva and that's my twitter
handle
i currently work with researcher
as mattel said and i previously worked
also for sony jp morgan sc
group pwc and gmv in a variety of
different security roles
which include also red teaming
penetration testing and security audit
now let's talk about the agenda what are
we going to see
during the course of this talk so first
of all why would they even perform
research in account what's interesting
about it
then the next thing will be talking
about what's been done before
so what was the information available to
me before even starting
and and then once i figured out what was
done before then i put myself into a
challenge that we'll see
very soon and then i will describe what
are all the steps that i took
to achieve success in this challenge
and then i will talk briefly about what
are the lessons learned
and possible future work on these
cameras and conclusions and q a
so let's get started why would they even
perform security search on a camera
well the starting point was that many
people just say all these devices are
not secure
and i say okay that's fair enough but i
want to verify these claims by myself
and i was also looking for a challenge
and a learning opportunity so
i thought this will tick all the boxes
for me to start looking into it
so let's talk about the previous work
once i bought this camera
i get out of the store and the first
thing i do is to google this
nc200 camera and i find
these vulnerability from
march 2016 and it's a command injection
affecting these two cameras nc200 and
c220
now this was already patched on the
latest film version so it's not very
exciting
and i also thought is there really only
one one vanilla video effect in this
camera is it possible that
they made it so well that this is the
only thing that i can find on the
internet
so that's when i started putting myself
into a challenge and the challenge was
to hack the latest and greatest
firmware image and i wanted to do it in
a special way because remember i was
trying to
get something out of it i wanted the
learning experience not just hacking
it by any means so i started from
the hardware because i want to learn a
bit of hardware and
how to dump the flash and all these
things so i dump the flash
and performing reverse engineering so
deliberately excluding uh
fuzzing and black box sort of test
and the interesting thing was that this
also
different architecture than what i was
used to so
this was a good opportunity for me to
learn some mips
and some other interesting constraint i
put myself
was to use some tool that was free and
open source so everyone could
replicate my steps
without having to afford any expensive
reverse engineering to license or
anything like that and something that i
could use
basically everywhere because i like a
lot to do some
hiking on the go so without any sort of
operation like i found that
there is this tool called radar that i'm
sure most of you know
that is service engineering tool that
can basically run almost everywhere
including on a mobile phone
so hardware analysis and flash damping
how did they start
so the first thing that i did was to
literally just take pictures of the main
board
of the camera which you can see here at
the bottom
and also search on google this
this picture and the way i found it was
you see this fcc sort of logo
this is basically a standard for
electronic devices
and they all have this id that
if you search it online of the on the
official website
of the fcc which is an organizational
controls
[Music]
radiation emission from electronic
devices
you can find all the documentation and
internal pictures of the electronics
that they
basically index and this was very useful
in my case because i didn't have to for
example open this metal shield
in order to see what was inside and i
could clearly see
that it was this processor and this ram
now without this i would probably have
to
remove this and probably risk him to
prick
my device so it was really handy for me
to
to find that now apart from that
this is great we know the processor and
the ram but we need to know more
so i started literally just searching
all these labels
these components will just have ids that
you can search
on the internet and you will find data
sheets very likely if they are not
something really unknown or really
custom
so what i figured out was that there
were this to
flash memories that are spi speak the
spi protocol
and i dumped them
so that was the initial step
now once i figure out that we had the
splash how did i dump them
i mean how what was the process that i
took
so i use the bus card you can use any
other tools but
it's just the tool that i had at hand at
the moment
so what it does it's this board that you
can see in the background of this light
and basically it gives you a serial port
on your laptop
you connect it via usb and it gives you
a serial port that interfaces
automatically with the all the spi
chips or even i2c or
it speaks a range of protocols and you
can just use it as a proxy
to talk to your devices and in order to
do that i use the
flashroom which is basically a tool that
automates
these commands that you send over serial
so instead of
me manually typing every command dump
basically box blocks of
bytes one at a time i just use a tool
that automates that process
so it will do that correctly without any
sort of
problems and i figured out finally that
the eight megabytes flash
contained the main firmware so we got
lucky
let's see now what we do with this
so once we get this raw image it's just
in a raw format you need to do some
tooling to
kind of extract it and further analyze
it so in my case i use bin walk
plus jefferson for file system
extraction
basically it just it's just scanning
signatures
until it finds for example the jefferson
file system
and then it invokes jefferson to do the
firm
the first system extraction itself and
as i mentioned before
i decided to use radar as the main us
engineering tool
and i picked one target which is one of
the most critical
binary in this firmware which is the
finally called ip
camera this basically handling all the
http requests going to the fcgis
now let's talk about some
vulnerabilities that i found using this
technique
[Music]
the first one is as you can read it's an
all pointed reference
and this is a login function
it's a function that gets called when
you from login on the web interface of
the camera
and as you can see here i will lock you
briefly through the code
you have two arguments username and
password which are user controlled they
go to this
much password method that just checks
your config file for your password
and if it's incorrect it just keeps the
entire block
and will give you some authentication
failure message otherwise
it goes ahead and defense the first
thing it does once the authentication is
successful is to check
what is your browser so it takes the
http user agent header
and then it takes iponter to this string
and passes it to sdrsdr because it wants
to check
if your browser is firefox so as you may
have noticed
there is this arc 58 which is argument
0.
it's basically the pointer that comes
from http attempt
now the problem is that this will
normally work until you remove the user
agent error
because if you remove it then this
method will return a new pointer
and then you're going to have a new
pointed reference right here
when you call strstr so
because of this bug basically when you
trigger it all the web interface goes
down
because you cannot do anything without
this binary
running so this was the first back
and of course after as a result of this
bug i started the event with the
disclosure process with tp-link
so i put a list of stages to kind of
show what is the pain
of this process just to show how long it
takes to get something fixed
so i started reporting it on the 4th of
december 2019
and the answer i got from tp-link was
yeah the account is not supported
anymore
so basically kind of we don't care
i said okay fine so i left it there for
a bit
and then i said you know what i'm going
to see if other cameras are affected
so maybe they're not unsupported and
they will be forced to fix it
and after a short time
i realized that all of the nce serious
cameras were affected by the same
vulnerability
and after warning them they didn't take
any action
and i decided after almost four months
to drop it as a zero day
and magically after roughly a week
they fixed it so they needed a little
extra push
to find the motivation to fix the
vulnerabilities and they fixed it in all
the cameras
and starting from there they started
taking the reports and deadlines
much more seriously and
in the end i promised that i wouldn't
report any more issues as a result of
them
asking me can you please confirm
this is the last issue we report because
we have released two firmware updates
in the past two months so i said okay
fine
okay let's talk about the next pack now
this is a stack overflow
what is this about so we have this
feature that is called
delete multi-user method and what it
does is exactly what it says it deletes
multiple users the way it does it is
basically creates a proper to this
delete user method
and basically goes in a loop and in this
loop
it takes the usernames and just deletes
them it's a comma separated list of
usernames
now the way it does it is it deletes the
user
and then takes the error code
and it puts it into a string that is
stored on the stack
and then the string is then concatenated
in an array that is again on the stack
it's basically
a concatenation of error codes from all
the deletion operation
right the thing is if you look closely
at this
at this loop it will basically go until
the next comma is found and it will just
if it's uh zero it means that there is
no next comma so it just
breaks the loop otherwise it will keep
looping as you may
have noticed basically we control the
number of iterations and we are storing
effectively i mean we are concatenating
strings on the stack
in this fp plus 40 because of this str
cut
so this means we control the number of
iterations and we are storing
things on the stack we are concatenating
so this bad this
[Music]
buffer gets bigger and bigger and bigger
until you basically overwrite the stack
so this will of course crush the process
because it's a stack overflow
and i initially might sound
exciting but it isn't too much because
the only thing that we really
partially control is the error code
and it's very let's say unlikely that we
will find a combination of error codes
that will allow you to obtain
arbitrary code execution so we classify
this as a denial service
and if you are wondering what the
concept looks like looks like it's just
something
that you can fit in a tweet it's just
literally usernames equal
a bunch of commas and that is enough to
crash the ib camera process
which is ridiculous
now the next bug is an according
encryption key
so this is there is nothing really too
[Music]
too complex in here i mean we can see
that this this p backup
file there is this link and there is an
e-backup
and then there is a call to des encrypt
okay so we know everything we know there
is a
this encryption algorithm we know that
there is a plane backup and an encrypted
backup
and there is a tp-link which is probably
the encryption key
now it looks straightforward right but
we still have a problem to solve
we know the algorithm and the encryption
key fine
and i was able to find a tool that will
correctly decrypt this configuration
files
and i would get random data if instead i
used
any sort of standard that's
implementation and i could understand
why
and i was thinking i was doing something
wrong
until i realized that you don't simply
use an encryption key
and this is what i figured out after
basically checking
all this code which by the way is hosted
on github
this bitcoin me this random guy
and i compared it with the this
standalone implementation which you can
find some information about in wikipedia
if you look at this initial permutation
table
and start comparing these constants
you will figure out that they just
changed one unit
in every single value of this so
this is the reason why i could never
ever
be able to decrypt this configuration
files
with any standard test because they
literally changed all the constants this
is just one
because there isn't enough space on this
slide to show all of the tables that
they changed but they basically changed
all of them
so these are kind of um funny thought
process that they had
they could just use a strong encryption
algorithm but they decided instead to
customize
a weak encryption algorithm so
effectively creating a
security by obscurity situation but of
course
we managed to solve the mystery so now
we know everything and we can
decrypt backup files and we can find
we can figure out the structure of this
backup files
so this is what it looks like in a nc200
camera
it might be slightly different for
others but the concept is the same
so what they have is just a small
leather which has a magic
the total file size and the md5
then some null terminated string that
says fingerprint
just it's just recorded there is nothing
special about it and then some padding
and then after the small letter you will
find the file entries the file entries
are very simple there are like
four bytes for the absolute offset of
the file content so they have this
list of files at the beginning and then
at the end they have the contents
and then the file size some zero padding
and then the
null terminated file name plus padding
and that's it that's what the format
looks like
so before we go into the demo thinking
about this
what we have in this configuration file
we have
file paths right we have paths and
contents
so i think this can give us arbitrary
file alright
so let's see how that works in practice
in this demo
so i prepared this little script
one.sage
all it does is creates a config for the
nc200 camera
and it includes this demo one and demo
two stm files and it's going to upload
them
in user local www and then after that it
just encrypts them
using the nc200 key and it's going to
output this old demo cfg file which is
basically the encrypted configuration
file
now we're just going to the web
interface
and we're going to restore
this backup file which is called
all demos cfg restore
now this is going to take a while
because it's going to reboot the device
because usually we'll just
reboot because you need to know change
some
service configuration that needs to be
restarted so they didn't want to go
through
the pain of figuring out if your change
is required to start or not
so they just decided to just reboot the
entire device so
all the services will just restart and
everything will hopefully be fine
right so hopefully the camera should be
back
relatively soon all right
here we go
so the first language i want to show you
is demo one
right cool so what did i do in here
what i did was to just replace this
camera frame
with a very well known game called doom
it's just an example right it could be
anything really
it's just to show that you can really do
anything you like
because you will basically overwrite
files as root
so you have all the privileges to write
anything anywhere
this is not very useful apart from my
simple demo
now i want to show you something a bit
more useful so if you notice this
tip you need to install a camera plugin
in order to be able to watch the stream
of your camera
now i found this ridiculous in 2020 and
i decided to
do something about it so i made demo2
and after i authenticate effectively you
can say this is my hand you can see the
live stream
without having to install any plugins
now let's go back to the presentation
okay this is the next back it's about a
new command injection
so this command injection before we even
start you may have noticed that
this is a screenshot from my mobile
phone
this is very interesting because this is
something that
this is what i was talking about this is
the
this is proving that you can find
security backs while
you are bored maybe i don't know in a
long travel in a plane
where you have no internet connection
you have nothing to do and just decide
that you're going to find them
vulnerability and maybe you'll find it
that's what i did and that's what
happened so let's start from
the cm command this same command is a
wrapper to system so it's just executing
commands
and if we go backwards to figure out
what are the arguments
we figure out that it is this echo
percentage
so it's second something to somewhere
and we can see that we have this encrypt
key
which is something that we control as
the user in a http request
and then we see this tmp encrypt key so
we know what's happening right
it's echoing this encryption key that
you are providing and then it's storing
them
in some encrypt key folder
and then it just executes the command
now
as you may have noticed there is
absolutely no check anywhere
about this particular encryption key so
you can effectively
eject shell meta characters and get
arbitrary command execution this is
great but it only affects
mce 260 and then c450 cameras
it's only a feature that exists there so
let's see if we can do something better
than that
and that's when we talk about this
bonjour command injection so this
venture service
the way it's started is like this we can
see this cm command
again so it's a good sign we know that
we are executing stuff
and then we see this these arguments
that are like
mdns or standard posix and then it's
passing this percentage
now this percentage is going to be this
a1 argument one which comes from v0 v0
comes from this
uh so
what's going on here so we are basically
getting the name
right of this device and then from some
configuration file
then we are putting it into v0
and then we are passing it to sim
command so we are building this and the
inner suspended process
our injected command is going to be here
and then
everything will be okay for us we can
execute code right
but there is something that we need to
take into account so it is
before you can even set an alias there
is this
check that gets executed right before
and if you look at this method there is
nothing really special going on
except for this strlam call with this
alias string that we control
so all he's doing is making sure that
you not provide a string that is greater
than
this 0x81 and otherwise everything will
be fine
now this is true for all cameras except
for the nc 210
where basically this check is done
properly and
you cannot just set any values
so you need to figure out a way to set
an alias
and then exploit this vulnerability and
in order to do that i will combine the
previous vulnerability
the account encryption key to get
arbitrary file right so i write the new
device name
and then i will use this command
injection
to take the command from that device
name
and this must have been the logic of the
developers you cannot inject commands
if you check for long strings that's
something that
they probably thought so this is a bug
that i call one bag to rule them all
because it affects all the dnc cameras
it can be triggered very easily and it
gives us reliable root shot
without any problem let's see if that's
true in the demo
right so let's
demo two all right so as i said i was
going to combine two different
vulnerabilities for dnc 210
so i want to demonstrate that i have the
system.com
that is where the product name is stored
and as you can see as a product name
i'm putting this it's basically a
command injection what i'm doing is
setting some executable
and then some file textual sorry and
then just executing it
now in this 2.6 what am i doing i'm
generating a payload with metals flight
which is going to be our payload that is
going to be executed
and then i'm creating a config for this
camera
and i'm going to upload it in system.com
and the next thing i'm going to do is to
add this payload
hotel in this edc slash s
and just encrypting this configuration
file because
the camera needs encrypted configuration
file to work
so let's run it now this will start
automatically the
msf console so in the meantime we go
here
to the web interface
and we just upload the configuration
file in the background file
so this is a bit slow because it's
running on qmo
so demos
to right system
safety restore
now this is going to reboot the camera
again and it's going to take a while
because it's
in pm so i will go in the meantime to
demo free
demo frame what i want to show you is
the command injection in the simple
version which is basically without
combining it with the
arbitrary valve right so all i did was
to make this metal split model that
explode the
poncho command injection that i showed
you before and it's just setting some
very simple parameters like
the remote hose the port the target
username and password for the web
interface the payload just
under the meta split payload and then
why do you want to receive the shot
basically so this is the nc200 version
so i'm going to run this on the
physical device that i have and this is
another camera which is dnc 450 that i'm
running in vmware as well
so let's run both of them and let's see
if you manage to get the shell on both
of them all right cool
it looks like we have a shell here yes
and as we can see we are root and
we can see here
our wonderful command injection and it's
running as a booth
and we are in this user local spin
directory
now if we check the other camera it's
the same thing so
we are basically executing all of this
wonderful command line
and we are in the same
and we got a shell in both devices with
the same
exploit so this works on all the
all the cameras right but i just put
a couple just for as an example
okay it looks like the other camera
rebooted so we're going back to
demo 2
now i want to show you what happens as
soon as we start the
http server so this is start sage it's
uh
just a helper that i built myself
because usually we'll have
the http server starting automatically
but it's all emulated so i have to do it
myself so once the http server starts it
will just
start the mature service and as you can
see
we got the challenge
cool let's continue
let's talk about lesson learned now what
did we learn out of this experience
we learned that code reuse means you're
going to have the same vulnerabilities
across different devices and this
apparently
more often the case than initially
thought so
don't exclude ever that what you find in
one product
only applies to that profit always cross
check and you'll find some surprises
something else that i wanted to uh
reinforce is that dropping a zero day
after a fixed deadline has been passed
you can get the vendor to fix the issues
because maybe the vendor doesn't really
understand and is not very keen to
pass the issues so if you give them
enough time and they still ignore you
and you warn them and they still don't
understand they
don't want to patch things then i don't
think it's a bad idea to drop a zero day
something that i wanted to reinforce is
that previous engineering can reveal
backs
that are hard to find or in some cases
even impossible to find
via fizzing or blackbox testing for
example the bonjour command injection
was very unlikely to be found via
blackbox testing
that's also probably why it was not
discovered before
and the reason why is that the interface
didn't
really suggest that you would even
change the device name
anywhere so if you didn't know about the
setsistname.fcgi url you will never know
that
probably and it will be kind of hard to
guess now if you
like this kind of research and you want
to keep working
on it because i probably won't because i
i won't report any more backs as i
promised
i have a few ideas to get you started so
you can look for vulnerabilities that
can be exploited from the cloud
so ceo more interesting because you
don't even need to be
in the same wi-fi network or hope that
somebody has misconfigured the network
to allow you to access their camera from
the internet
something that is also interesting is to
look for the finalities in the
browser plugin because i'm sure judging
by the code client you have seen
until now that is going to expose an
interesting attached surface in your
browser
and then something else that you could
do is to definitely look for randomly
this in the mobile app
which is available i think for android
and ios
and the fourth step that i suggest if
you want to look into these things
is to look for basement vulnerabilities
so imagine if you could just
get a shell on these things by just
being in the same wi-fi range without
even
being connected to the network
now let's talk about the conclusions we
can definitely say there was more than
one banana video on dnc cameras
and you don't need any expensive tools
so any
anything special in any preparation to
find this issue
you can find them on a plane where you
are traveling
when you are bored and you don't have
anything to look
and it reversing is necessary if you
want to find bugs that are hard to find
via
fuzzing or black box testing so make
sure you complement your test
and i can say for sure that it was a
good idea to use my camera
for any actual uh
real camera purposes but just for
research
fun and now i can say from experience
that
indeed some iot devices are insecure
not all of them i mean i can talk for
all of the devices but i can say the
devices i looked at
are not secure enough and something that
is really important and i wanted to make
sure i delivered them
this message is that we have a shared
responsibilities
um security researchers and vendors have
a shared responsibility at making these
things more secure so it's not just
about us
finding bugs or about them trying to
make things secure by themselves but
it's the
collaboration between these parties that
allow things to
be more secure
and that's it thank you for listening
if you have any questions just
make sure to write them in the chat
thank you pietro and
so we are it is pretty pretty early so
maybe we'll uh we'll be we'll do a
longer break
but we have some questions from from the
chat yeah
so max asks if
it was it hard to emulate the firmware
on qemo
so it was not that if you try to use
for example the film analysis toolkit
which i did try
is supposed to give you a wonderful uh
script that does everything for you and
just spawns a qm
but for me didn't work so i found it
easier to actually
take a random qmo image
like at the vm image and just basically
install the files that i needed from the
camera
and i had to patch the ip camera binary
because there was some error related to
some hardware that was missing
something about the network of course we
i didn't have any
real physical network devices or any
wi-fi at all in the qm
image right so some things are likely to
fail
it really depends on the device you are
looking at and the firmware it's running
so that is the the way that i decided to
approach it and it did work
i hope that answers the question thank
you
and we have a non-technical question
that is uh if the tp-link has a bug
bounty program
i mean the direct question it is uh is
it
if they pay for for vulnerabilities but
i think the the main question if they
have a
backbone program so the answer is i have
no idea
so so i invite you to search for
this program i mean it's very good to do
research and find these things
have some fun with it and learning
experience but if you can monetize your
efforts it's even better right
i mean i didn't even think about that
when i started my research
and so i wasn't just interested so i
didn't look for it
but i invite you to do so if you
want to get some something
out of it some bounty definitely
possible if they had
okay thank you another question pietro
asks
if you could provide some ways to use
these vulnerabilities
during one red red team at red teaming
activities
sorry so i as i showed before the meta
split module
i forgot to mention that actually thanks
for reminding me
the meta display module is publicly
available it's on
github of the official metasploit
framework
repository so you can just git clone
and get my module to exploit these
cameras
and i will also release at the end of
this conference a
standalone title script if you're not
very keen on using metasploit you can
just
quickly test it with your
python script
i hope that answer the question thank
you
last question is if you report a bug
from michaela if you report a bug to a
vendor and this company doesn't give an
answer can you publish it on github
i don't think you can do that straight
away i mean you will have to give them
the opportunity to fix things
so you only require to
you should be a last resort right
dropping a zero day you should never do
that unless
there is really no hope that these guys
will fix anything so if you feel that's
the case
usually the standard deadline is free
for months
so if after that they still don't patch
anything even though they are aware of
it
then i think it's time to consider this
closing a zero day