[Music]
so she'll be are you ready for the next
speaker
i am i definitely am and the talk title
is really interesting so we have
had a speaker chain so we do have a um
really exciting talk actually um so we
do have randall who'll be joining us
very soon and um i've been looking
forward to the talk obviously it has a
very interesting title um 12 factors of
pain and suffering so that in itself
like kind of definitely excites me as
well and um from what i understand we're
going to be learning from you know his
experiences and he wants other people to
sort of gain knowledge from that as well
so we'll bring randall on and you can
tell us a little bit about what he'll be
speaking as well hey randall
hey what's up shelby hey vandana so cool
to see you all again since we were just
hanging out in person a few days ago
that's pretty neat i know we were just
talking about it like we were all in the
same city and now we're all like
literally across the globe and uh
fighting different time zones and trying
to sort of stay awake and randall's
living the hacker life staying awake
late at night what time is it at your
end
it's only 10 p.m so it's not that bad
but i'm in california and so we are i
think literally on the opposite sides of
the earth from each other right now but
that's what's so damn cool about the
internet you know you get to like make
friends and hang out with people in
person and around the world it's the
best so yeah totally agree with you
totally agree with you and thanks for
jumping on at the last minute so that's
really amazing thank you
and we before we start the session we do
want to know about a little just a
snippet snippet about what this talk is
going to be all about
okay i will tell you so this i wrote
this talk a couple years ago so it's
about two years old maybe
and at the time so i've i've been
writing code for pretty much my whole
life so i got started when i was 12
years old i've been writing code for
over
21 years now which tells you about how
old i am i'm pretty old at this point
but uh
you know
it's been like my entire life's passion
and through that time i've gone from
being a complete noob when i was a kid
to nowadays after writing code for 21
years still being a considerable noob
and so not much not that much has
changed and i would say that one of the
things that you know when i'm talking to
new developers and people they're sort
of getting into the space
they they always have this like idea
that like as you practice and get better
and better and better you make less and
less mistakes and i don't think that's
true you know like i screw things up
literally all the time i'll be the first
person to admit it you know and i
thought it'd be fun to talk about the 12
factor application which is a series of
these 12 best practices for building
scalable dependable web applications but
instead of just talking about like
here's the principles here's how to do
things the right way i thought it'd be
more fun to tell you about 12 ways i've
actually screwed up each of those things
over the years and so that's what this
is a series of my 12 personal factors of
pain and suffering that have screwed me
up for a long time
that sounds amazing and i'm i'm really
looking forward to it and you know as
you said it's quite well put like we can
all learn from each other and it's um
it's so good of you to actually share
this with the community so i think
without further ado we might just throw
to you and let's hear about these 12
factors
let's do it
let me know when you got the slides live
and everything looks okay
wait looking good
all right cool so as shelby and vandena
said um this talk is called the 12
factors of pain and suffering um and
really it's just a list of my own sad
programming uh sad programming stories
so feel free to drop some comments in
the chat i'll do my best to answer them
afterwards or you can always tweet at me
um but these are real actual things that
have happened to me none of this is
exaggerated these are like the story of
my life basically
so real quick about me so i'm randall i
work in devrel and community at sneak so
it is amazing to meet all of you here
today and a couple things you should
know so i'm a python javascript and
golang hacker these are sort of like the
three primary programming languages i
work in nowadays in the past i did a lot
of lower level operating system
development stuff but this is sort of
what i work on nowadays
i've also been doing open source like my
entire life so i love open source i'm an
author so i write a lot of technical
articles security stuff programming
pieces etc um but most importantly i
would cons i would say that like i
associate with being a builder i just
really love to build things and i think
because of that i've had the sort of
good fortune to work on just a
ridiculous amount of weird unique
interesting projects over the years some
of which i will share with you tonight
so
first of all what is the 12 factor app
well if you haven't heard of it before
it's a methodology for building simple
scalable and dependable web apps at the
end of the day it was created by adam
wiggins so he was one of the founders of
heroku with like the app hosting
platform and if you want to learn more
about this you can go to the website
it's
12factor.net like the number 12 then the
word factor.net it is one of my favorite
websites of all time because it's really
simple it's really like just dependable
and it lays out these principles in a
really crystal clear way that i am going
to do a huge disservice to tonight i'm
sure
but
as i said when i got started the reason
i thought it'd be fun to share all this
stuff is because as an experienced
developer i've screwed things up a lot
in my career and a lot before i even had
a career as a matter of fact i still
screw things up constantly today and so
you know these are just fun stories to
teach you some of these principles
all right so let's get right into it
principle number one code base
so when you're working on a project
generally speaking you always want to
have one code base that's tracked in
version control that you deploy many
times so what does this mean
well let's say you have your a project
right
you would take that exact same code base
and you'd deploy to like a production
environment a staging environment maybe
a local development environment or
multiple local development environments
but the important thing to note is that
it's one code base that you just deploy
to these different environments and this
is sort of a best practice for dealing
with the code base i think we can all
sort of agree upon this you look at it
it looks pretty straightforward so
you're probably wondering how did you
screw this up
well
back in the day this was in maybe 2009
um i had started a website with a couple
friends of mine and it was like becoming
a full-time business and basically the
way the website worked is if people
would google a phone number online they
would land on our website so we were the
number one ranked website on google
search and we would basically say like
hey click here for more information
about this phone number people would
click through to our webpage and they
would see a bunch of information about
this the person that owns this phone
number like this is the person they live
it you know this area they're not a spam
bot you know just basic information
maybe their their cell phone provider or
whatever
and what we would do is we would sell
affiliate links
for basically these visitors to get more
information about a person given their
phone number and that's how we'd make
money and we would make something like
fifty dollars per affiliate sale so it
was a lot of money coming in from this
website
now
this was all running extremely well and
we were getting paid a lot of money
until
google released their panda search
algorithm update now i believe this was
back in i want to say 2009 2010 but when
google released this major like search
algorithm update it completely destroyed
our business overnight so our entire
website it was tnid tnid.us
got completely delisted from google and
so we showed up in no search results at
all and so we went from making like a
lot of money every day to making like
zero dollars a day and it freaked us out
so i was actually on my first vacation
in like two years i think when this
happened and it was so annoying because
the entire vacation i worked on this but
basically what i did is i said okay well
we have two things we have to do first
of all we have to like con figure out
how to contact someone at google and
like figure out how to get our website
unbanned there must have been some issue
on their end and like we'll sort it out
in the meantime though what i'm going to
do is i'm just going to go ahead i'm
going to copy and paste the code base
for the existing site tnid.us
i'm going to purchase a new sketchy
domain name for this
for this thing i'm going to
make a new logo i'm going to like
rewrite the the wording on the home page
i'm going to change this color scheme
and i'm just literally going to relaunch
like the same code base with these minor
changes under this new domain name and
hope that this new domain name is going
to get picked up and indexed by google
over the next few days so we can still
have some revenue coming in
so that's what i did and this took me i
don't know like
eight hours or so of work something like
this i got everything live and i sat
back and i was like obsessively checking
you know google webmaster tools to see
if our website had gotten picked up
well the next day things started working
a little bit we started to see some
traffic we started to get indexed on
google and after a few days things were
starting to run pretty well on this new
domain and so i thought oh you know
maybe we're going to be okay after all
but then this new domain got banned and
so then what i did is i freaked out
again and i said okay
i got to keep the original domain
running and this domain in case this
gets unbanned and i'm going to create a
couple additional domains so i copy and
pasted the code base again into two
different iterations i bought two more
domain names and then i
went through the painstaking process of
like changing all the the logos the
color schemes the name and all these
things
and
these websites also both got picked up
by google but then shortly banned a
little while afterwards and so i was
basically in like this massive copy
paste cycle for about a month and a half
where i was essentially trying to
outsmart google and what i would do is
every day i would work insane hours and
i would literally copy and paste my old
code base buy a new sketchy domain name
run some code i'd write like spit out
new logos and images and then like
alternate color schemes and do all these
things to like try to trick google into
thinking that like these are different
websites and over time as you can
imagine this this method slowly stopped
working all together and so this allowed
us to continue on for another month and
a half or so but it was brutal now the
worst part about this and the reason why
it was so brutal is because every time i
did that i was maintaining now 20
different copies of the same code base
and i was literally every time we had to
make a change going into all 20 versions
of this code base and editing things in
order to make this happen what i should
have done if i was smart which would
have saved me a ridiculous amount of
time is i should have templatized all
the things in a single code base and
just deployed it to these different
environments and so i know that this
isn't really the exact perfect scenario
described by the 12-factor application
but i think it's super relevant and so
the lesson learned for me is follow the
code-based rules and you will not feel
as much pain as i felt
all right second factor is all about
dependencies so whenever you're building
an application you always want to
explicitly declare and isolate your
dependencies now again this sounds super
simple makes sense right so again how
did i screw this up
well
here's how it works
when you're first of all when you
declare dependencies like let's say
you're building a javascript application
you're going to have like a package.json
or something like this and you're going
to specifically write out all your
dependencies that you need to build your
application and then when you isolate
them you're essentially saying you know
i'm going to go install these things
which is going to take all the things
that i've written down and build a
little environment so i can run my
application and again this all makes
sense now the way i messed this up was
years ago i was building an image
optimization api service and the way
this worked is if you were a user you
could essentially send my service this
image whatever image you had like this
really super cool image of a crow
holding a knife which i thought was
awesome
and you take this image you send it over
to the image optimization api service
what i would then do is i would say okay
let me go ahead and optimize this image
for you so then i would send back the
optimized version of the image to the
user and it'd be a smaller file size but
quality would be the same and so the
user would be happy
well on the back end the way this worked
is this was all running on a vps so
on this vps server this was just a
single server you know service i had
installed a bunch of these command line
image optimization tools so there were
things like opti png jpeg optum gif
sickle there was a few others i don't
remember but basically the way things
worked is
every time an image you know would be
sent to the service i would literally
shell out to one of these command line
tools to optimize the image take the
resulting image and then send it back to
the user
now
this service was working absolutely
great i put it online it was a an open
source github project i wrote i put put
it online and over time i started to get
some like a sizeable amount of free
users and what ended up happening is one
day i started having all these you know
um
service notifications from my provider
saying like hey you're you're going over
your usage limits your your vps server
is like running out of memory and so i
thought oh cool i took a look at the
traffic i saw i needed to scale it up
and i thought all right what i'm going
to do is i'm going to literally create a
second vps server put a load balancer in
front of both of these things so that i
can then you know just route traffic
between both of these things and i
literally took my javascript code base i
copied it over onto the second vps
server i ran my npm install and then i
updated the load balancer and thought
everything would be fine
unfortunately things were not fine
and the reason things weren't fine is
because of course on my second vps
server i didn't have any of these
command line applications installed that
my application needed in order to run
yes i had all of my javascript
dependencies my web app dependencies all
those things but i hadn't fully
considered the entire spectrum of
dependencies than my app needs now at
the time if docker had existed it would
have made this problem like moot because
i could have packaged everything up
including like my code all the command
line tools all these things into a
docker image but this really goes to
show you that when you're thinking about
dependencies for an application you have
to think about it holistically you can't
think like oh yeah it's just these one
this one little part of you know things
over here over there you really have to
think about it in the terms of the big
picture and so that's how i screwed that
one up
so next let's talk about configuration
so the 12-factor app states that you
always want to store configuration data
in the environment aka environment
variables now
if you think about sensitive things that
you're going to update from time to time
in your applications you might have
things like a database url a price for
something max you know max number of
threads you want to run for like a given
you know application server or api
credentials right
now
the way i messed this one up is back in
the day i was doing a lot of telephony
work in my first my or in my earlier
jobs that i had this was around 2009
2010 11 12 things like this and a lot of
the work that i did was based on top of
this open source linux software called
asterisk now if you haven't heard of it
it's really cool it essentially lets you
write code to program like phone calls
sms messages you know things like that
and just makes it super easy for you and
at the time i just started scaling up
this free teleconferencing software that
i was working on and i was trying to
deploy it to like a really hot cloud
provider at the time aka rackspace and
this was before things like terraform
existed and so i was trying to write
some bootstrapping code which would
essentially take all the code that i
wrote deploy it to a cloud server or to
a new cloud server and then set
everything up for me and so what i did
is i manually provisioned a rackspace
api key
and i wrote some code that basically
took my my rackspace api key and used it
to provision a server and copy over all
of my asterisk stuff onto the server run
all the setup commands etc
now
i was working on this and i decided hey
you know what i'm trying to test this
out to see if it works so what i'm going
to do is i'm i was i think i was running
like hudson or jenkins at the time a ci
system and what i wanted to do is i
wanted that
that ci process to basically kick off
this bootstrapping procedure and so i
was i was like in the testing and
development phase of this this was all
open source and i thought you know what
i'm just going to go ahead and hard code
my rackspace api key directly into my
open source code base on github just for
a little while just to see if my ci
system will pick it up run all the
things necessary and actually do the
bootstrapping
now i knew at the time this was a
terrible idea because like i was putting
my sensitive api key public on the
internet but i thought you know it
doesn't really matter like no one's
going to be looking at this thing
whatever and so i went ahead and pushed
it live and i tested things out things
worked absolutely great i didn't notice
any issues and so i went to sleep
well as soon as i go to sleep this is
what happened i presume
some jerk out there was running a bot
that was looking for noobs that were
uploading their sensitive rackspace
credentials to github like me
so they scraped my api credential and
immediately started making requests
from using my api key to rackspace and
basically provisioning these massive
servers that they would then run as tour
relays
and so that takes a ridiculous amount of
bandwidth so
i woke up in the morning and completely
freaked out because i saw all of these
billing emails from rackspace and when i
took a look at it i noticed that i had a
negative negative 25 000 account balance
and rackspace at the time had actually
tried to bill my personal credit card i
hooked up to my rackspace account and it
failed because my personal credit limit
was like 2 000 or something at the time
and so of course i had like absolutely
no money to pay for something like this
and so
this scenario was absolutely terrible
now thankfully i eventually figured out
what had happened i contacted rackspace
support and they were absolutely amazing
they they were like look it happens all
the time don't worry about it we're
gonna like reset your billing stuff so
they were amazing but the lesson learned
is don't be lazy and in a lot of cases
even when you know better like i did
you're sometimes still lazy you
sometimes still do the wrong thing and
this is just a reminder that that can be
very costly so you know
try to store your config data in a good
place like the environment or maybe in
like a secure environment storage like
tool like hashicorp has some options
there but this is sort of uh the lesson
learned
right next let's talk about backing
services um backing services so what are
they well basically you have a
production deployment somewhere and you
have all these services that your
production application relies on so
maybe if you're sending emails you might
rely on an smtp servers or maybe if
you're deploying or storing files in a
bucket system like amazon s3 you're
going to need like the amazon s3
deployment url somewhere or if you're
talking to a database you might need the
database url to connect to
and the 12-factor app states that
whenever you have these like backing
services you want them to act as like
attachable
resources and what that means is you
should be able to easily just update
this one url here and instantly have
your production environment switch from
one postgres database to another so you
should have these things just be easy to
add and remove that's really all it
means
now
this here is a self image of me that i
drew of myself as a really young
programmer super happy i had great ideas
i was really you know positive about
everything
and uh
i was maybe 12 13 years old something
like that and i thought you know what
i'm an amazing programmer and people
need to know about this so i need to
make a blog so i started my first blog
on the internet and i was really excited
i used to write on there all the time
about things i was building and research
and stuff like this and it was pretty
exciting
and this was a blog that i built custom
myself of course in php and used my sql
and i ran it on a shared web hosting
service one of those cheap ones back in
the day and
when i went to college um i i was a
really shy nerdy introverted kid i
didn't really know how to make friends
and so i thought you know what
you know what's gonna make me some
friends
is if i give out uh pirated movies to
everyone at school now i went to college
or i got out of high school in 2006 so
like i think i went to college in 2006
or 2007 i don't really remember but
this was like a super cool thing of the
time because like piracy was like all
the rage sort of still is you know but
hence the flag back there
but uh but i thought hey this is going
to be really fun i'll make some friends
i'll i'll be like the cool person on
campus and so what we did is my
roommates and i ordered the netflix four
dvd per week subscription service so we
would order four dvds a week they'd come
in the mail i would rip them myself i
would upload them onto my shared web
hosting provider and i would just hand
the link out to all my friends at school
and this worked so i made made some
great friends and met some really cool
people it was super awesome
until one day i run out of disk space on
my shared web host
and so at this point in time my blog i'd
been working on it for maybe like you
know seven eight years at this point and
i thought hey i've learned a lot i know
that i need i can scale this thing now
and make it way better properly
architect the entire thing and so i
decided the first thing i'm going to do
is i'm going to take these you know this
massive blog which is consisting of like
hundreds of these php files just strewn
all about the var dub dub dub folder and
i'm going to
uh i'm going to rewrite it so that
instead of using the free like local
version of my sql installed on the
shared web host i'm going to create a
separate independent mysql database
server i'm going to move all my logic
into there and then i'm eventually going
to create a separate file server to host
all the movies and then just like you
know architect the thing properly
so the first thing i did is i
provisioned this mysql server copied all
my data over and then i went and went to
go integrate it back into all of my my
blog code and what i realized is that
this was actually ridiculously hard to
do and the reason it was so ridiculously
hard to do is because in all of my php
files like hundreds of them by the way
i was just randomly connecting you know
using my sql underscore connect and just
like not supplying any parameters
because i was connecting to my sql on
localhost with no username or password
on the default my sql port and so i had
to actually go in and rewrite like i
think thousands of my sql invocations
all across this project and it was a
total nightmare
and so the lesson i learned here is
whenever you're using attached resources
whether it's mysql or you know an s3
bucket or whatever always treat them as
attachable resources make sure you're
storing these credentials in an
environment variable ideally and make
sure that it's something you can easily
swap out so that you're not relying on
just thousands of lines of custom code
like i was
and that's me being extremely annoyed
when i realized how terrible of a
programmer i was by the way
all right so next uh build release run
you always want to strictly separate
your build and run stages
so what does this mean um
one second there we go so you have your
code and when you're going to get it
ready you uh you have a build process
and ideally speaking you want to have
some configuration data which is like a
package of your environment variables
configuration information everything
like that and all these things get
created into what we would call a
release and the release would be the
thing that actually goes live and does
stuff in in the real world well
i don't know if i mentioned this before
but i was sort of a script kitty as a
kid i think you get the idea by now and
basically what happened is um when i was
working on my personal website on that
shared web host back in the day i had my
website code on my computer
and i had my web server running live on
the shared web host and so whenever i'd
work on the the shared prod on on so
excuse me what i would do initially when
i went to work on my website is i would
write some code locally then i would scp
it over to my live web server then i'd
refresh the page and test it out to see
if my php code worked now this was fine
except as your project grows this this
scp command gets really really slow
because you're just copying tons of
files over all the time and it just
takes forever and so what i said is i
said you know what i don't really need
to do this anyways whatever i'm just
going to ssh straight into my web server
modify my code files directly and then
test things out without all the delay
and then what i would do is after i
would do that uh
it would you know if once i got things
working i would then try to copy the
working code back onto my computer so i
had a local copy of it but then
sometimes i would lose track of which
one was doing which and then i have to
like copy code from here on to there and
it was just a massive nightmare and so
uh it was bad and it was really
frustrating and that's why you always
want to
separate those build run and release
stages of software if i had known that
back then and followed those principles
i don't think i would have had such an
annoying time
now unfortunately by the way everyone i
realize i am talking incredibly slowly
here and telling these stories slowly i
apologize i i realize i have about six
minutes left so i'm going to probably
finish uh one more of these but i don't
think we'll be able to get through all
12 of them so i apologize
now
going back to the story real fast
processes
uh the sixth factor in the 12 factor app
talks about the always want to execute
your application as one or more
stateless processes so what does this
mean
well the key here is stateless so when i
was building this conference calling
services free conference calling service
back in the day i had this application
it was deployed in a data center and i
had multiple instances of this thing
running and the way it worked is these
were all running on separate physical
servers and so peop i would basically
have like this massive pool of phone
numbers and each of these phone numbers
would be assigned to a different server
and in reality there was like 100 phone
numbers assigned to each server but you
get the idea
and what happened is what was cool about
this free conference
app is that like you could set up a
conference room and you could custom
record your own voice prompts for it you
could customize the entire thing and so
people really enjoyed it
and
what would happen is when people would
call in and it you know manage the the
custom voice prompts for their
conference lines
each of the recordings they recorded
would be stored on the server in which
their phone number was assigned to and
so this was sort of the way i'd
originally architected this application
now this worked pretty good until one
day one of these physical servers in a
data center in pennsylvania like
completely went offline
and when that happened my code worked so
my load bouncer over here essentially
rerouted all the phone numbers that were
going to this server to to the other
existing servers but what happened is i
got a lot of angry user complaints
because people just said hey my my
conference number's working but all my
custom voice prompts are gone and what
ended up happening after i did some
debugging is i realized well when this
server went down the custom voice
prompts that were on this server
were were not on these servers and so
this this wasn't really a stateless
process you know like this was a very
stateful process because each of the
instances of this conference calling
application essentially was very
stateful and it was bound to a physical
server and so
this is not something you want to do
now
let's talk about port binding real fast
i was just told by one of the hosts by
the way that i am allowed to go over
because there is a break so i apologize
but you know what this is zoom or it is
virtual excuse me and so you could
always just take a break and watch this
if you want um
now moving on poor binding so the 12
factor app states you always want to
expose services you're building web
services via port binding now this isn't
as relevant today because things have
changed so much and you know people are
using a lot fancier systems that this is
sort of like dated information but
regardless i think it still rings true
especially if you're talking about
deploying things in a manual way
now
you know back in the day when people
build web applications they would bind
them to port 80
or port 443 things like this to have you
know tls
but this is just a really bad thing to
do essentially what the 12 factor app
states is that when you're doing things
this way you're shackling yourself to a
very particular port and instead you
really want to let your routing layer of
your application whether that's your
elastic load balancer or like you know
your kubernetes your kubernetes cluster
that's managing things you really want
that to be able to assign your
application ports for you dynamically
this way you can run as many instances
of these applications as you need to in
order to scale things up horizontally
next concurrency
so the 12 factor app states that you
always want to allow your application to
scale via the process model so what does
this mean
well imagine you have a web application
and you have a couple different
instances of your web server so you have
web one and web two these are two web
applications two web processes if you
will that are both receiving incoming
requests via a load balancer
now
you also might have different types of
processes so maybe you have a web
application process but you also have
worker applications running behind the
scenes and you should be able to
dynamically add and remove these
processes in order to scale your
application as needed
you might also have other types of
processes etc but you get the idea right
you should be able to dynamically just
add more things when you need more
capacity and remove things when you need
less capacity
now
my story here goes way way way back like
one of the first big projects i ever
built as a kid was i built my
like i thought it was super cool by the
way i thought this application was like
super next level at the time but i used
to go on irc all the time that's how i
met friends and learned about
programming and things and i built an
irc web application that would let you
just join irc from a browser and
interact with people in the chat rooms
and at the time like i don't think this
had been done
i might be wrong but this was like a
really long time ago and i thought it
was like
super amazing so i built this
application i showed it i share shared
it with some of my friends on irc and
people really liked it and so i decided
i was going to scale this thing up turn
it into like a proper business and just
like you know
be like the next you know internet
celebrity basically but um
the way this application worked was the
web app would literally allow you to
join different irc rooms and though i uh
in order to scale this thing i was
writing this entire thing in c by the
way
um i decided to run the entire
application as a linux system demon and
so it would basically run this massive
master process that the operating system
would boot up and it would fork itself
off into a bunch of child processes one
for each irc chat room that people would
join
this worked pretty well but as i got a
few of my friends using the service i
noticed that like over time what would
happen is one of the processes would
eventually die for whatever reason
and then that would cascade and that
failure would eventually kill the demon
which would then restart all the entire
process and so therefore all of the
child processes would die and that would
therefore disconnect people from irc and
you know kick them off the network so
they'd lose some chat history before
eventually reconnecting and so it's a
huge pain
now
i worked on this application a lot like
i put
you know hundreds maybe maybe even a
thousand plus hours into this thing and
i was never able to completely solve
these problems and that's because doing
inter-process communication in c is
really hard especially if you're like
you know a 13 year old kid and you're
not that knowledgeable but regardless i
think that if i had known about the 12
factor app back then and i could you
know better think through this in my
mind what i would have said to myself is
hey instead of building this one massive
application demon that is doing its own
you know multi-processing and all this
work why not just have each process be
its own stateless small contained thing
and why don't i just make a way for it
to you know for me to be able to add
processes horizontally and not have this
one amalgamation that's sort of doing
everything i think that would have
dramatically simplified the types of
problems i was solving and maybe today i
would have a really cool you know
business or story about a successful irc
web application is that one that just
sort of
you know failed and sort of fell into
obscurity
so next the ninth factor in the 12
factory app we're almost there is about
disposability and the rule here is that
you want to maximize the robustness of
your app with fast startup and graceful
shutdown
so
you always want your application to shut
down gracefully when a sig term is
received
you also always want to shut down within
a few seconds you don't want to let
things linger and finally you want to be
really robust against sudden death so
even if your application is killed with
no warning whatsoever you know like kill
dash 9 it should still you know be able
to spin back up and handle whatever
things it was in the
in the middle of doing without causing
any sort of weird side effects
now going back to that free conference
calling app i told you about earlier um
this at this point in time i was
starting to scale it up and things were
getting a little more successful and so
we had requests coming into a load
balancer the load balancer was basically
dynamically scaling up and adding
various processes to essentially handle
more and more calls as they would come
in through different times of the day
but i was running into issues with my
auto scaling code because as i would add
new processes
i would realize that like i would start
them up and then after about 30 seconds
or so they would they would like fail
and then just restart indefinitely in an
indefinite loop
and as i was debugging this auto scaling
software that i'd written
it actually took me quite a while to
figure this out eventually what i
learned is that and by the way this is
all written in python um and this is
like pretty accurate like this is pseudo
code but it's pretty accurate to what i
remember the actual code was like but
essentially what i realized the issue
was is i had the startup routine and so
the process would start up and the first
thing it would do is run this download
audio function and this would
essentially go off to like a rackspace
file server and download all of the mp3
files for all the custom audio prompt
recordings for all of the conference
lines assigned to this particular
process
and once those things had been
downloaded it would then bind itself to
the appropriate port everything will be
running and
the the process would start accepting
new incoming calls and so this this like
worked okay in test environments but
when i ran it in the real world it would
cause this behavior here well what i
later came to realize is that this was
actually the issue
running the download audio thing when
the process started up was causing
problems because
when my auto scaling software would boot
up one of these sub processes it would
then go and attempt to download
something like you know
700 gigabytes of audio files and that
takes a lot more than 30 seconds to
finish and so what would happen is
i would download every audio file not
just the ones for the particular
conference numbers i needed to and so
therefore this process would take longer
than 30 seconds to complete the process
would never actually bind itself to the
port and so the the auto scaler thought
that because it never bound itself to
the port the process had failed and so
it would kill and restart it
now
this goes back to those 12-factor
application principles because had i
sort of followed those rules about
having a really fast startup time you
know really fast or be being able to
recover from like you know shutdowns in
a graceful way this this wouldn't have
been an issue and i wouldn't have had to
do all this debugging so just a reminder
that like these things do make a huge
difference in the real world and it's
great to keep them in the back your mind
all right next dev prod parody so you
always want to keep your development
staging and production environments as
similar as possible this one's super
important
um this is something i've done by the
way i'd like to admit that i've learned
this lesson but i i literally do this
all the time because it is so convenient
and it's sort of you know i don't know i
i'm a bad person i guess but basically
let's say i have some code running in
production
and that code is being deployed to
postgres in the real world i love
postgres awesome database well a lot of
the times when i'm working on things in
development instead of using postgres
i'll use like a sql lite database
instead that way i don't need to
actually run a postgres process or have
a fancy development environment
somewhere remote i just literally run
things locally it's super fast and easy
but this has been me
way more times than i care to admit
because of things like database
compatibility issues you know
like for example uh did you know that if
you're using sql lite and you define a
var char and you give it like a
particular length that sql light
actually completely ignores it and will
allow you to store any length of uh of
varchar inside of that that item and so
that becomes an issue because maybe
something in your test environment when
you test with sql lite that works when
you go to production will break and this
exact thing has literally happened to me
a handful of times just from the ones
that i can remember and you know like i
said i still do this today so i'm
embarrassed to admit but
if i were the type of person that really
wanted to do this properly um what i
would do is make sure that my
development and production environments
were basically identical you know like
if you're using postgres in production
use it in development too you know make
sure you have things as similar as
possible to the real world scenario that
way you minimize the risk of stupid
things like this happening to you
all right next logs
you always want to treat logs as event
streams
so imagine you have an application that
generates a bunch of logs well the rules
are a you always want to store your logs
ordered by timestamp b you always want
to write your logs to standard output
and c you want your logs to consist of
all of your process and backing services
that way if anything ever happens you
can always go in and reconstruct log
log based information to figure out what
essentially what went wrong right
now again this all makes tons of sense
now
this one in particular something i
screwed up that actually cost me a lot
of money so pay close attention
um that
that free conference calling app i told
you about before i sort of previously
described the telco infrastructure now
i'm going to describe the web
application side of it so i had this web
app that people could go to to get one
of these free conference calling numbers
set it up record voice prompts and do
all this stuff
and that web app talked to an api server
i had it was built in python
and all of my astra servers which were
running in an actual data center
whenever a call would come in
essentially they would then send you
know an api request to the api server
the api server would basically like
write an entry into a literal csv file
called calls.csv and that csv file would
essentially have like the phone number
that called
and then the number it was calling to
like which conference number called to
and then the duration like the start and
stop time of the call and then a bunch
of other metadata but those were really
important pieces of information because
this information is what we used at our
company to get paid so what i would do
is at the end of the month i would
literally run an scp command and i would
essentially copy this massive calls.csv
file from the root of this api server
onto my my my local laptop then i would
send it to the telco they would
literally add up all the billable
minutes and then pay us a certain amount
of money for how many billable minutes
we we used on the service and so that's
literally how we got paid
now
one day i was doing this and i
i noticed something was wrong right away
i ran this command i was trying to check
to see it was about halfway through the
month i was trying to check to see where
we were at and what our business
projections were going to look like
and the the command completed super fast
and i was like that is so weird this
always takes forever and so i was
looking into it and i was looking into
what i did and i realized oh my god i
ran the the scp command the same one i
always do except i reverse the arguments
i put scp dot
root at you know
ipaddress calls.csv so what i had done
is i had copied the the empty version of
the calls.csv file from my local laptop
over
onto the production server completely
overwriting the original calls.csv file
that contained the accurate count of our
billable minutes for the month
now
what i should have been doing at the
time
which i was not doing is i should have
been taking the logs from each of these
independent services and dumping them
all into some sort of log router you
know it could have been into a service
like sumo logic or logley or literally
you know log dna anything that this way
i could have gone in and actually taken
a look and reconstructed these calls
unfortunately i did not do that
um i specifically disabled logging and
only use this system the reason why is
because when i first built this i
started running out of disk space on
these servers here because they were
generating so many logs and so i thought
i don't need them screw them and so i
completely disable them
but
the
the the end thing is that this cost me a
lot of money because we completely lost
a count of all of our calls for about
half a month and that was you know
hundreds of thousands of dollars at the
time
so
yeah this is a real world example of how
logging can actually uh be detrimental
to you if you don't do it sometimes
so
final factor is admin processes you
always
want to run your admin and management
tasks as one-off processes so what does
this mean
well this is a real world thing i did so
i had to run a database migration on an
application and this was really simple
basically all i had to do was i was
modifying a database schema and all i
really had to do was run the command
python manage.pi migrate and this would
basically take my my database migration
code executed against the database and
things would work just fine
now
ideally if you want to do this what you
do is you would code this into like a
task you deploy that task to your
infrastructure somewhere to on in
production then you would fire off some
production task to actually make this
work
what i did instead was this so i was
working on a new feature one night
um and i you know had to alter the table
to add a new column to make this feature
work and so i wrote all my code i wrote
some database migration code and i was
ready to deploy this thing and get it
running
and i basically said to myself well you
know i only need to do this once and i
sort of want to get out of the office
like i've been here all day so i'm just
going to go ahead and do the database
migration from my laptop instead of
deploying it like i said into a separate
code task and like having it run in
production all that stuff
and so on my laptop i literally just ran
python manage.pi migrate
the database migration was executed
successfully and i hit deploy the
production let's get the new feature out
there
so i do this and deploy the feature and
uh
you know i start immediately getting
calls from my boss and he was saying hey
um
the entire uh platform is down
and uh he was so mad he's like what what
were you doing
and so uh after doing some some
debugging later what i realized i did is
when i ran this python managed that pi
migrate locally i had forgotten to
update so i was actually doing a
migration on against the sqlite local
version of my database and not the
production postgres version of my
database
and so this is just another reminder why
you always want to keep these things
running even for simple management
administrative tasks in official
production infrastructure you want it
coded tested the whole nine yards so
don't be lazy like me
so
that's it those are the 12-factor
application principles i hope that was
fun um if you want to check out some
more of my stuff you can always check it
out here um ignore these things this is
from a while ago but my personal website
is rdex.com
i also work at sneak it's an awesome
company so if you want to check it out
please go to sneak.iosnyk.io
and yeah i'll be around so if you have
questions tweet me hit me up in the you
know in the devs icon chat and thank you
so much for the time everyone
adios
thank you so much randall it was amazing
people were totally totally smitten by
it
and there are questions i would like
simply take the question which is
wonderful one
yeah definitely thank you so much that
was awesome we've got some amazing
content people have taken a lot from it
and everyone's loving your slides as
well and i think but then i i totally
agree we might not get time to address
all the questions but there's one that i
particularly want to know and it's i
think it's come from mooney uh and it's
like what coat would you like on your
hacker hoodie
what code i like on my hacker hoodie
uh maybe like uh something like a seg
fault or like something like that just
to represent like all the things i've
screwed up that would actually be pretty
cool
uh but i'm also a python pythonista and
so also just any python code really
would be awesome uh i really like that
too a great question
amazing yeah so if anyone wants to
settle randall hoodie you know what to
print on it
i will wear it for sure if you send me
one
amazing thank you so much for that and
for jumping on as well i'm sure everyone
enjoyed and i'm glad we had those extra
15 minutes to actually go through it
because i'm i was thinking we might have
to have part b it's like a suspense
movie you've had the first half and it's
like what comes next so sorry for
running over everyone
no it was great it was great
we loved it we totally loved it well
thank you for having me and have a nice
night thank you so much thank you take
care good night
[Music]