[Music]
um i think next up we do have matteo
rossi and paulo stagley who will be
talking to us about
automating serverless security testing
so obviously serverless is something
that is increasing a lot in adoption um
you know there's a lot of that that's
happening so this is quite a
um interesting topic and quite current
as well um so we are definitely looking
forward to the topic as well welcome
mateo
thank you very much hello everyone
i'm quite excited after tanya it's an
honor for me
i agree with you that's our house is uh
in front of you and now you're gonna all
jump back for the talk
have the uh i have the
all the slides but
paulo took in the second part of the
episode of this speech
so uh
i can start now and we
[Music]
absolutely so you're going to start now
and then paolo will join in right well
okay but i i should i should
he should uh
already in the backstage but
sure so we'll just pull your slides in
yeah and get started with the talk
um
amazing
yep
okay
perfect you're good to go mateo your
stage is your uh all yours
thank you very much so
morning good morning everyone
i'm mata rosie i am a
security researcher in
in contrast
and
in my past i'm jo i am a worker has a in
a defensive and offensive
field of security and also i
i i was a software developer so i uh
merged all the uh souls for
for
this talk and there is also paolo my
colleagues
hi everyone sorry for the inconvenience
obviously chrome
goes in the exact moment
the stream starts so i'm hi everyone i'm
paulus pali
i'm senior security researcher at contra
security
uh in the past i worked at becky hughes
for uh in cloud engineering and
architecture for
almost five years
okay so
we are starting to talking about a cloud
native application service application
and
for us
this kind of application is not only the
development path pattern
yes of course
we don't
have
the difference from a monolithic
application is quite clear in the
cloud native application we have many
many resources many metro services that
are configured
to talking each other with the events
in monolithic application we have a
great code base that handle all the flow
of the data flow
and to support to develop to create this
kind of application we need to change
all the phases of the
development
we have to change the cycle we cannot uh
proceed with a waterfall approach when
we try to develop this kind of
application we need to go with the agile
method but not only agile high fragile
we needed to approach with the devops
process
the abscess ops process of course
because
we needed to deploy many times
in production
for day
so we need to uh
handle the security we need to handle
this development in different way and so
we have the many uh
many steps to do to deploy in production
and in this kind of application and so
it's a
mandatory need to automate every process
every step to go to
permit the application to go in
production
and also the developers the developers
has more responsibility for
this kind of application because every
developer say usually
needed to deploy in production more
times for a day
so
of course more power
bring more responsibility i don't
remember who said that but
and and so we needed to change
completely uh this kind of approach
we bring in an example of a cloud native
application this is the this graph to
represent a a small application from our
customer so you can you can see it's a
a huge
number there is a huge number of
components
connected each other and communicate to
each other with eagles
so
that's the testing manually this kind of
application is really difficult it's
really difficult to testing manually to
deploy with a
a single process now like i said before
with a single deployment process
uh like a monolithic application
what means i have to change all the
components together no i need to uh to
have a devops approach change see a
single component
why while the other the other
components continue to work with it
so a agree blew up
for example a a green blue meter to
deploy in production
you this is an aws application so you
can see different components with
different color the powerful one is
a gateway so each video will expose the
internally externally
some endpoints
and the orange components are the lambda
why we're talking about orange
components because the lambda is the
component that contains the code
developed by the developers by the cost
the customer
so uh we're talking about events
the architecture
of this kind of application is a event
driving architecture so every components
are talking each other using events the
events trigger the execution of the
components in that case we have a many
trigger
that
sorry many components that generate
events that trigger a lambda function
the lambda function contains your code
and
and how its work the cloud service
provider when
an average trigger the lambda create a
container boot up a container with your
code
run the code and after the execution
terminates the container usually and
this is a another another thing because
the service provider
for performance issue for
issue for performance usually uh can not
terminate the container but reuse it to
handle in other events and this is bring
some so you can bring some security
events we're talking about later
and so in that case your code inside the
lambda and of course with your code
usually
there is also your mistake and your bags
another overview about security aspects
in the lambda
the lambda usually is running in a
container in a read-only environment
except the tnp directory is the only
directory where where you can write
something
it's not wired to the internet
but can reach the internet
this is mean you can talk about you can
talk with the container
with the api gateway with the other
components that expose the service uh
on internet and you cannot communicate
directly with a container but the
container can reach the internet and
with the demo
after the slides
i can show you how to exploit a
vulnerability inside a lambda and the
lambda communicate
to the internet some sensitive data so i
can implement an exfiltration from that
container
the data
usually is a temporary because the
container is ephemeral but
of course for performance issues
sometimes
a container can be
reused and also the code it's inside the
environment it's inside the container so
if you have a
local file inclusion vulnerability lfi
you cannot lost the privacy of your code
an attacker can explicate your code and
also it can explicate the environment
variables and in in this kind of in the
container there is all the sensitive
data the
aws key secret key inside the container
inside the environmental environment
this is some
aspects
we need to understand to create a secure
application
so what could go wrong
in that case uh this is a
simple uh the simpler uh application we
expose this application expose an api
rest to the internet we have the client
that communicates with the api gateway
the api to generate an events that
trigger
the lambda the lambda
run with a call with the contacts with
the rule the rule is the permission the
alarm
used by the lambda
inside the cloud service provider and so
the lambda can access
or read or write i don't know
with a dynamodb instance so could go
wrong with this kind of application i
can test it using a
always up application i can test i can
generate http call to understand if this
application is vulnerable or not
yes
it's true but uh this is a
a kind of cloud native application
what's happened if the events is not
generated
by the api gateway but by i don't know
in alexa skill for example i don't think
they always puts up working with the
audio
trace audio
with multimedia and able to generate you
know
malicious payload in audio it is
different it is a completely different
and we cannot test with the
common security tools
and
i will share with you a
youtube link where um our head of
research fall melamed
try to exploit a sql injection
vulnerability inside
a
an application
with this architecture i i i shall
after this speech
so a quick
demo uh
i want to show you how we can exploit
a
famous spring vulnerability is not
spring for shell but the other one the
spring explosion language vulnerability
this is these generate a remote code
execution this
is a bug
and so i will show you how we can
exploit this to exfiltrate some
sensitive data from a container
of course one of them effect it's not
the effect so you can see
i insert a payload in a header http
header the root expression header from
spring
i run the uh i make the call with the
postman in that case
and i try to explicate this data using a
server in my control
and you can you see in the bottom part
of the
of the screen
the secret key exfiltrated from the
container
what's happened what happens
i uh
if there is a bug a vulnerability inside
the spring framework if you want to use
spring spring framework in the lambda
you can do you can use it
and when you
trigger the lambda
the counter cloud service provider are
going to call a function from the frame
of the spring framework that function
has a value
this buggers can exploit it in this way
with a simple payload inserting an http
header and
something can happen in that case i
experienced the secret and so using that
secret i can run some code in the same
context of that lambda
with the same permission of that land
so it's quite clear that the
one of one of the things that we we're
going to lose
when we approach with the cloud native
application
we lost the perimeter
in the monolithic application we have a
load balancer or reverse proxy in front
of the application
sorry
in front of the verification and the
load balancer route every a very cool to
the components that have to handle that
that flow
and every
after the load balancer every
flow are handled by the monolithic
application
in the cloud the native application the
serverless application doesn't
it's not true it's not true anymore
because okay
i have an api gateway that
root
a single call a single kind of call but
i i can have more api between
that cool that trigger more different
kind of lambda
but also if i have to upload the file i
have s3 bucket
that take the file trigger and events
and call another function so we we're
going to lose this perimeter
and so we needed to
change
the way how we secure the application
we need to go to a zero thrust approach
a least privileged approach to uh secure
the
the perimeter of each lambda
and of course we have to go through the
self-protecting code
we we need to ha to harden each
components of this kind of application
another example in this case i talked
about the list privilege approach you
know we have a very simple uh
lambda
2020 line of code
this is a
lambda that creates that place
in order in e-commerce in a
cloud-the-native e-commerce and you can
see in uh
in this line we have a dynamodb instance
a table or the stable
and we can see the code
going to put an item inside that table
no only one order
so the context the rule used by this uh
uh this function is a this this is
the rule is uh the permission of how
the lambda can do
um
in that case we have an action so the
permission and the resources over uh
used by the
in that case this lambda can do any
action in dynamic b
in any table of this distance of
dynamodb
it's quite to open permission
so we we see
we use only pathetic so we can
harden this rule and
put only the patent action to
avoid
this
lambda make some other
action
and of course the resource
only the orders database or orders table
the all the access to the other tables
is not unused in islam so why give the
permission you know
so it's quite easy to do this manually
with a only one function
of
20 hundred line of code 20 uh line of
code but what's happened if you have the
of lambda code
more long
more
under the line of code of under the
lambda it's quite difficult to do this
uh manually and so we need to automate
these process
using a der cycle that is approach
so we're talking about uh available
driving application now
so we're talking about the change
approach change how we can see
how
you can see the security in the cloud
native application and also
i think everyone knew the top 10 hour
was that also was the
change the top 10 adapter to the cloud
native application in the case
i show you the top 10 for a service
application and of course the first one
is event injection we're talking about
event drive and application so it's a
natural it's obviously
so
uh paulo up to you thank you very much
guys thank you very much
so
um
how we can test uh serverless
application
uh let's see how low we can okay
now we can see okay thank you sorry
um
so how we can test a serverless
application i have taken
uh this example from aws case studies
website
uh it's a
from from the irobot roomba
system
this is just uh one flow of the entire
system but it's a good uh simple example
uh to see uh
for for the torque so as you can see
a device
sorry a device in a robot roomba try to
register himself on the system so you
have an
api exposed using
api gateway api gateway trigger
lambda
that talk
with the ws iot and send a message into
the queue
the message in the queue trigger uh
um
another lambda
that
called another lambda that completed the
registration process adding
the the right information in the
registry
setting the policies and the iot rules
a simple application and let's see what
we can do with traditional application
security tools
on this application how we can test it
let's start with the easy one sca and
image scanning
uh
so you can you you can run sneak or
clear or any other tool there are many
also open source and provided also by
a cloud service provider
with this
type of tools you fix
the problems that you import using the
third-party library so which is a
good thing
as we have seen recently with the
most
important
vulnerabilities
but this
this scan covers a small part of your
application
it doesn't cover your code
the infrastructure that support your
code and the configuration
as mateo was talking a few minutes ago
of your
lambdas and yours and your cloud
services
uh the next infrastructure is code uh
fantastic thing so we can shift left we
can
do
devops we can run
a security scan
of your
terraform template or if you're using
polumi you can
scan
your code
but
again we have
zero code coverage limited visibility
and also we don't have prioritization
because these type of tools
for example
give you that as a result that you have
hundreds of public buckets
without so much context so you have to
go and check each one of them but
if you are for example exposing a
website is lazy to have
public buckets and but maybe in some
cases no so you have to check one by one
and is uh is adding effort and noise to
your to your um to your work
i asked so iest is the modern upset tool
i think is the
most accurate and reliable tool that we
have today enables devsecops
but
again
in this environment we don't have
servers to instruments so it's difficult
to put in place ios in a serverless
environment
dust
duster is another
great tool
but it needs uh
endpoints to be tested
it needs the response to uh
to be checked
and in serverless environment
is not always the case uh looking at
these
at our example
uh
you you may be able to test the this api
exposed by the by the gateway and maybe
the code of this lambda if the lambda is
synchronous but in many cases
the
we have an asynchronous response like we
got your request you are all set
uh that's it so you don't have
something to check in the response
uh so again maybe you are able to
to test this part of your application
but for sure you are not able to test
this part that is triggered by the
queue message so you is
not possible to reach and to cover this
piece of code using
using dust
so
[Music]
you may have nothing to test
with dust
sasta is another great tool that can
give you
uh great feedback on the code of all
your lambdas you can run fast on all
your lambdas even if maybe you may have
some uh issues on scaling if you have a
lot of lambdas
but the main issue with sasta is the
fact that you don't have context you
lose the context because
serverless is not just code is code and
infrastructure
and sas tools are not able to are not
configured to look at the
infrastructure and the configuration
so you may
lose
context and also you may
have some difficulties due to the flow
because the flow
is not
linear so you may have in the in the
middle of your lambda accord to another
cloud native service
and
so the the tool can provide you
a
strange result or increase the number of
faults positive so
as you can see
uh
there are um
many tools each one of them is giving
you something so it's good to run
but it's also a lot of effort put them
in place in a serverless environment and
maybe it's not worth it because
the results are not
effective uh in addition to this uh
there is another key
point in in cloud native and serverless
environment that is scaling so
uh it may be enough or if you have
few lambdas
but
what if you start having
thousands or if not million as we have
seen in some of our customers lambdas so
in that case you have a lot of services
it's difficult to understand what is
connected to what
also you are you have frequent
deployments because
devops and cloud
are environments that
increase the number of deployments
you obviously
if you have many lambdas you have many
developers and
the number of upsec
people remain normally the same
so it's uh and as matteo was showing
before
security is not even the same in a
surprise environment so
basically you you may lose what the
focus on what's important because as you
know in security uh
it's not possible to look at everything
so you have to prioritize based on the
risk of
of of of vulnerabilities and
so with all this noise and all these
things to look at you can lose the focus
on what's important
so we suggest to have a different
approach with a different mindset
that is installing us an agent in our in
your
[Music]
cloud environment
using a seamless and fully automated
onboarding that is possible in the cloud
with few clicks
and then this uh agent can run a full
discovery of
of your of your cloud environment
looking at resources
the relation between the resources the
interfaces policies
and also all the services that are used
within the environment
when the discovery is done
we can the agent can run an analysis
that look at your code first and
foremost then are the weaknesses at the
other surface the flows that you have in
your system
so that then using this information the
agent can generate and execute dedicated
attacks on resources and flows
for example if you have a lambda
triggered by
an s3 bucket
we can the system can generate
dedicated attacks to see if the the
the lambda is vulnerable to local file
inclusion or other type of attacks
so
when going continuing in the flow
as as we have an agent installed
in the in the environment we can see we
are internally so we can see
uh
if
the simulation
have an effect so if there is a real
exploit or not so we are not like dust
uh
that we are outside so and we test the
application as a black box in this case
we are in and we can check many we can
check the logs we can check the database
we can check
we can use many uh services and tools to
check if we have a real exploit and show
and and send it back to you
in addition to reporting and integration
because maybe if there is a
vulnerability or some or some findings
you can send a message
into a slack channel
the nice thing is that we can also
continuously monitor the environment for
changes and drift so if a developer
add a new api or
change the code of the lambda we can
change what has been changed
in order to have a faster
feedback loop
and give immediate feedback without
doing anything without any action from
the developer
and so you can
keep the environment under control so in
this in with this uh
approach
uh also if someone creates something new
we can run again
the complete analysis if it's a new
system or a new land or a new service
and and
do the loop again
so we have we can make continuously
monitoring and continuous scanning of
your cloud environment without
intervention
or
something similar so let's see
an example a very simple example
so if mario the developer had a
new api
uh that trigger alanda we can identify
the flow
of of these of this
api
so we can see that
it triggered the lambda that then upload
a file into a bucket that then notify a
lambda
and the lambda send an email to to the
customer
so
we can scan these
flow for vulnerabilities we can scan
each component
in isolation by themselves and
we may be able to identify a
vulnerability in this function
so we can get the result
maybe we're able to get the access key
and so we can identify the impact
of that vulnerability so you can see
that the
the the yestery bucket the function
the email for the customer and maybe
more important
the
dynamodb tables can be accessed
by a potential attacker
if is able to exploit that vulnerability
so this is it uh
we are at just few words so our contrast
we recently
released a
cli uh
we
called the code sec by contrast
is uh
for serverless so you can use it for
free
and
you can start playing with it you can
get result in less than one minute
and you can see uh if
result for your lambdas you can you can
have a least privileged approach as
mateo was talking before you can see if
there are
vulnerabilities and so on so feel free
you are more than welcome to go to the
website and start playing with it
your feedback is more than welcome
at contrast we also
contributed uh to a couple of
os projects the serverless top 10 as
mateo was mentioning before
and also the classical
vulnerable application developed
using serverless technology for testing
purposes
thank you very much for joining us
feel free to reach out
with for with your questions
we will be more than happy to
sure
thank you so much mateo and paulo it was
amazing i was just going through every
part of it and you really stitched it
very well especially service is
something which is right now needed the
most
yes
yeah yeah it was totally amazing and a
lot of people are waiting for you on
the uh the channel that we have on uh so
please do check out check that out and
yes everyone
do uh join us on discord as well now
before we head out uh i do see one
question for you
um
oh actually
uh they've actually said that it's good
great work team security in serverless
cloud any eta for codesec sca
which is software composition analysis
is
i think is a planet for this summer
so a few weeks
of and you will be able to use also sca
at the moment we have only
serverless and scan
amazing so coming very shortly yes
keep an eye out for that yeah and and
please please uh send us feedback so
it's is we made this for developers
so
we because we want to help developers
secure their serverless environment and
or any other application with sca and
scan
so
but and we need your feedback uh to make
it better
sure thank you so much for joining us
and please do join us uh for the chat at
this discord and we look forward to
having you in the future sessions as
well
thank you very much for having us a
pleasure thank you thank you