[Music]
ah there we go fantastic hello rotom
hello how are you that's a great flag
you've got in the background there
thanks it's from my last defcon i spoke
over a little bit
fantastic so our next week uh rotenbar
um is head of marketplace integrations
at cybersecurity and you're going to be
talking to us about package managers and
security uh road terms so i will keep
the show on the road and i'll pass
straight over to you
and uh the floor is yours
great so i'm walten and i'm going to
talk about package managers
and part of like
what i do actually i'm a cyber paladin
already took 20 years now
and i'm building a marketplace on
application security marketplace at
cyber security
cyber security is helping organizations
all over the world protect their cicd
pipelines
and because i'm building and looking at
all the different attacks that govern
their past even in software supply
chains
i decided to talk a bit about package
managers about how they
how you can what you can trust and what
you cannot trust in these different
package manuals so i'm going to focus on
a few and i will give a lot of examples
and i hope you will enjoy
um i do a lot of bug bounty as well so
there's a bug is a group
i'm organizing once a month we have some
meetups and i'm just hacking and
building stuff since 2002 since the army
and all over the place automotive
company satellites production plans
banks whatever you want
i i help protect them and less hacking
into them but this is a part of what i
do
but today i will talk about package
managers
so
if you go to wikipedia and you try to
look what is a package manager
it's actually a program that wants to
install upgrade and configure
and remove programs from the computer
but most importantly it does it in a
consistent manner it means that if you
want to install something it will
install every time the same package
that you want and you won't have any
surprises
and this is now
in my presentation i will show you where
it goes good and where it goes about the
different areas in these package manuals
so back in the old days
i was downloading lots of stuff and i
used the get right because i wanted to
download it all night and then
disconnect from the internet uh
now nobody discussed from the internet
but then you had to have different
programs that help you manage manage
your download
and more easier ways to install and you
can just like say i want to have a
package like called dragons i just pip
install dragons and magically appears
inside my computer and magically all the
versions everything happens
and even
i'm so lazy and today we are we are very
lazy so we even can just clone a repo or
have
a different uh project we want to
install do npm style or paper style or
whatever install and it just knows from
a configuration file
exactly what i wanted to install
installed it i don't even know why it
installed and how it installed and
it's kind of black magic
from
this area today so we are
we are having
much lots of trust in the package
managers themselves to install whatever
they want to install
but we are talking about a lot about
package manuals and i want to talk a bit
about what is what is a package
so a package can be
[Music]
a lot of stuff it can be a very large
package that has a
[Applause]
years of
changes and lots of people working on it
and it can be something like is a number
i get i gave an example over here it is
number is a npm package
it has 250 million
downloads per month
it has four gigabytes to download i
don't know what's a gigabyte downloading
github but it's a gigabyte download i
think it should be millionaire but it
had like so many downloads and basically
if you look at the code this is the code
it just
does like i think seven eight lines of
code and that's it
and it was maintained it was last
updated i think five years ago if i'm
not mistaken uh and if you you can see
there's an open ssf there
a program that goes over the most common
packages and
sees
and sees a what's their skulls and they
have different categories and you can
see
it wasn't maintained it doesn't have
code reviews it doesn't have a best
practices
it does have a license and that does
have different stuff so it got a 4.8
scope
and everybody uses it you have 250
million downloads a month
and the big question over here is what
will happen
if someone one day will change this
package a maintainer
can go and add this two lines of code
and you know that hack system just is
something that is really bad that you
don't want it to be happening in your
computer and with the moment he will
update it it will start new new
packages and new programs that want to
download
this specific package we'll download the
new code and we'll run it inside the
development
computers inside the ci cd inside
different areas
and the
question is who can change this package
so we have the maintainer itself
now
we have like carlos and faker and there
are a lot of now because of a
different politics and wall stuff
people just say yeah i'm maintaining
this package i i'm the maintainer i can
change it i will add this code
uh to the package and
just ruin it for everybody and sometimes
the people just like pull the plug on
the package or they change something or
they do other stuff and
and the thing is it starts breaking or
even can hack into different uh
uh areas
the other way is hackers if i have let's
say we have the ui puzzle js or call rc
these packages were hacked and someone
got a the password of me it's very easy
to find the email of the maintainer and
then find his password over
in other ways like phishing attacks and
stuff like that they can hack in they
can hack the account of their maintainer
and then
and then again inject code and have fun
with the packages
the first thing is confusion attacks
uh alex adolson showed us i think last
year two years ago
dependency confusion attacks the way
that if you have private repositories
and public repositories and you update
something in the public repository which
is private
and package managers get confused and
can download by mistake something from
the public repository and start from the
private one
and this is this was a very interesting
attack and he was able to hack lots of
companies and lots of different areas
and so the question is why is this
happening
and this is happening because we are all
lazy
and we don't want to have fixed versions
and in the dependencies like all the
package managers have different areas of
supporting this
and the package i can say i don't want
1.21 but i want every time it will be
upgraded automatically to upgrade my
package so i want to i won't need to
have different types of uh
development and the adding and checking
and verifying i trust the package to be
that everything will be okay this is why
we have this
character
that says you can
you can upgrade any
minor and the patch version in the
semi-semantic version over here
um
to fight these problems and to fight and
to find a way that we can create
reproducible bills and have
to know exactly what we want so
we created log files and log files mean
i know you wanted to have 1.21 but
actually one the developer tested and
the the pipeline test that the in the
testing area and in the developer
machine
actually what he checked what was the
1.4.8
version
and actually this one the version had
this this integrity this shaft 512
integrity and this is what was
downloaded so anybody in the future that
wants to download this
version should go to the log file and
should not download anything else if you
download
please stop downloading installing the
and check what what was the difference
and this means that now developers need
to update the log files
additionally to update the json files
that's in npm
but the question here is what can go
wrong and this goes into a research i've
done
and
lots of other people are also
done in the internet this past year and
even a photo pack
about
package manuals and if you can uh this
is not a live show so i don't have uh
i i cannot ask the crowd over here but
if you look at this docker file and
you probably can see a few problems i
will go and show you the different
problems that i found maybe you can find
one
but
the docker file if you use the latest
dockerfile
every time you will upgrade
it will
upgrade
every
every time someone will push a new tag
into the docker a hub for instance or
vcr whatever
it will download the latest version and
not from a specific tag or even a
specific
hash that we wanted to use
the other thing is over here you didn't
see in the pack we added only the
package.json by mistake to the dongle
file
and now
we then copy the log file into it so
what happened is inside a double file it
didn't know
which versions were locked and it they
guessed and wanted the internet and went
to the latest copies and downloaded the
the new versions with the manual virus
whatever we had over there
and the other thing is if you go to the
left you have npmi
npm install does
actually np install updates the lock
file
and it doesn't it it tries to go away
and find the water the locked versions
but if it doesn't find it doesn't force
you to use the locked options npmci what
it's supposed to do is
validate the log file and validate it's
only the locked version that in the
package dock
and this happens in all the languages
not only in npm but i'm focusing on npm
because
actually they had much many problems in
the last year and it's a good resource
ground
so
i went to
for instance into amazon
in the past and when i was creating a
new lambda function i thought the docker
file
had uh
the same problem the copy packet json
and they didn't copy the log files and
this means that this was the default
template for
lambda functions that everybody that
uses the different template
vulnerable
so i contacted the aws and we fixed it
and now every time they added the
asterisk so
it will also copy the log files but also
there's a recommendation to run npmcr
minus mass production because it's much
more secure
uh running npmcr now the npm install npm
install
doesn't verify the log file itself so in
production we always
recommend to use the log files
and this is one thing i want you to
learn from and see from this
presentation use the log files don't uh
don't
delete them don't disregard them you
make make sure you use them even if they
are there and if they are not there
you just
it's very important for
the healthy the help from the csc
environment
so using npmci let's say we installed
axios with a specific version and they
have this package like a file and when i
do npmci because it found
0.21.4 and psi should always install the
21.4 function
and this is happening
this is how it should behave and this is
how it behaves in npm6
and
if you can see when we changed it in the
package json i was lazy i went to the
github changed it
to dot one it did npnci and it failed it
failed the build and then
it couldn't continue until we change it
back or update the package lock
file the thing is
i investigated npm seven and the in the
start of the npm eight also
and i found out that when i do the same
thing with npm seven
nothing happened like it didn't it say
yeah okay
it's great
you changed it so maybe i'll just
add uh
install the the version you wanted to do
it so it didn't look at the log file at
all and actually because there was a
change in the package.json and didn't
find it in dogfight it went and
downloaded
a different version a 22 version because
the 20 version was the latest
so it was kind of a mind-blowing event
for me you know i saw that ci doesn't
really work
and this went i went to the internet and
then i uh i saw actually before i wanted
the internet i saw also i did another
game
if i created the empty log file with
only on an empty json
it just worked it added everything so if
you want to bypass all protections you
can create a package lock
with an empty json file that
continues without asking questions
uh unfortunately we fixed it after one
year like npm
fixed it uh i went to the github and i
wanted the issues and saw someone
saying yeah last year the npm succeeds
when package lock doesn't match so i
tried to understand we opened the cv for
it
i think the cv got a critical base call
but i don't know if it's that
i would give it a seven point something
another 9.8
still it's not shell shock but it's
really interesting to see that
um
this was
getting serious and after a while they
fixed it uh
get up one and fix this
problem and now in the latest npm
version i don't i think 81.4 and above
it doesn't happen anymore
but if you go to
npm and look into the issues you see
there are other issues when you use
overrides it doesn't work correctly when
you use the integrity is sometimes not
repaired automatically by npm and not
noticed so there are still different
problems and
and i think one thing we need to learn
about this that
the packages themselves the package
managers are there to help you download
the files but you cannot trust them
entirely not to have bugs in them and
not to have like they're constantly
trying to improve but you should verify
yourself all the packages and verify
yourself
and that the integrity is uh
properly and before you download and
after you download you need to make sure
because the package manager some will do
it from you some will not some will say
they do and will
not do it correctly or not understand
and this is a game that we need to
understand play
until we have like a
proper rfc or way to verify
that
what you wanted to download was really
downloaded and that's it and
i don't think i don't know if there's a
standoff today for downloading packages
and this gives me to another bug that i
found last year and this is actually i
spoke at def con
last year about
a different malicious code analysis
and i was investigating scanners and the
security scanners and how i can make
them execute code so if i'm a hacker how
can i attack
the scanners that are scanning my code
and i found out that the same problem
happens also on npm
so i'm saying npm but it also happens in
different package rentals so i will show
you this
soon
but if we go into npm and
i want to find a way to
run it safely without running any
scripts without running
any code that can happen from the
package.json
from
the different areas of the repository i
just want to install to download the
packages and do nothing with them
and this is why we have npmcr you might
as well signal scripts we can download
the we can download the files and they
under pre-install post install
all the scripts they shouldn't work
and this is a good practice because
sometimes when we use a
package managers we have credentials to
our repository and the other different
credentials to push stuff to say a cd
and we don't want to
mix the different environments so i want
them not to run any script
so for instance if i want to
have a
secure way i have an npm token i run it
with management signal scripts and then
unsucks the ampere token and run my post
install scripts so and this way i'm but
i'm more secure human they don't have
any way of a leakage of a npm token
the thing is that npm does look for
dot npm lc files and this is by
definition and these dot npm lc have
instructions of
what npm should do
so
if you go and
you put let's say a dot and pmlc inside
your repo
then when npm will run
it will have to look full let's say npm
6 looks for unload script and in this
download script i can inject a
javascript script
inside my environment
and
inside my own repo that will execute and
this is a way to bypass the minus my
signal scripts actually it's not really
bypassing you because ignoscripts wasn't
never was never intended into
not running scripts in different ways it
was only intended to not run scripts and
in the post and style and green style
and all the
all the live sites
script life cycle
so
it's a bit confusing and there is no
real way to prevent
npm to
run it
in lpn 7 and 8 they fixed it and there's
no unload script anymore but you can
just replace the git
shell file with evil get and then
do they happen the same it will just
like create the same
same option the thing is over here you
will need to create another npm a
package that gets from a get repository
instead from the uninstall npm
so the attack scenario is pretty
interesting the developer can add data
and pmlc file push it into
his repository even it's a local
repository if it goes through different
scanners or different the jenkins
[Music]
ci build
build files the ci pipelines can go and
run and they
execute npm and then you can run cisco
they
steal the site secrets they have
production access network access
it is a part of jenkins is also a code
execution as a service platform but
you never intended to become from and
from the packet json itself from from
different areas over here
but this also happens in python if for
instance someone has a pip install
and the paper star is looking for sata
py and set up cfg
then
set up your wise python
you can just like
put whatever code you want over the day
and it will just work and there's no
it's by definition
imposing python and running python so
you don't have anything really to do
about here there is like very refined in
the setup cfd it's much more hard but
setup cfg now usually
is invoked by setup ui i think i think
in the future like those changes now
that you can run it without but it's
still not mature enough
uh again with
requirements.txt so you have a different
way to install requirements.txt
and
you can just like say give a list of
requirements
and over here in the requirements file
usually it's a line by line but you can
have special flags
the minus r flag
tells access
another requirements file from a
different source you can put a file like
etc plus wd and get the log files
and they pass the led into the log files
or you can just like access the local
network by http and have a sslf target
and start attacking in
resources outside inside the area of the
network
so it's pretty cool to how to abuse all
this functionality
and the same goes for ruby it's just a
gem file just ruby fire that is executed
so the same thing happens
and this is like
by definition package managers will
execute code
and we need to understand this and we
need to
understand that this is what they do
and put the product
protections
around it too so when we execute
something and we know it has access to
different artifact uh repositories it
has access to
a secrets it has exited the
environmental variables it will have
absolutely access to everything
and
someone with enough intent will be able
to execute code or folder even if it's a
static configuration file that doesn't
allow you to
execute code
i think the last thing i want to talk
about
is auditing
and if we see other things so
we have lots of security auditing and
different we have
lots of tools but also npm gives us out
of the box
a security auditing for vulnerabilities
and this is uh usually i just like
install the package i do npm edit or
just even by default when i install it
tells me how many vulnerabilities you
have inside the package
and it's very reassuring that to know
okay there's a critical
vulnerability i will update it
so
i'm going into when i'm signing like
pack result for 4.2 point zero and i
know there's a high severity
vulnerability then npm will just tell me
there's a one high stability
vulnerability you should fix it
uh maybe 4.2.1 will be fixed or when
they go to the latest version and then
we should have a
proper way to fix vulnerabilities
don't just not use log files and then
they will do latest all the time because
we will have the problems from this
start so we need to make sure we have
log files we need to make sure we have
these vulnerabilities and when there's
availability act upon it install
uh upgrade the
availability upgrade the package and
test it before we're just automatically
testing a viruses new viruses
but
what i understood in there i found out
in
npm project 6
when you give an alias to a package
then it won't validate the package
so if i gave like pack results from the
same alias exactly
as packers although so it does nothing
for the code and it actually works as
intended but npm audit or even other
package scanning
solutions will not
will not see this alias and will be
fooled by the syntax i don't know why it
really happens but it will find zero
vulnerabilities
they actually fixed it in the
uh version and the latest in npm seven
and then eight
and then you can see there are different
ways so
to bypass this so if we go to
uh
out of store
package let's say github.com
i go to the github depositor itself
still npm does some magic and goes and
tries to resolve the pack resolver and
it knows the github and goes
and find that this has a vulnerability
that's pretty cool that it was succeeded
in doing it
but when i'm going into and i i try to
play with the syntax a bit and find out
how to
bypass it so if i go
and download it from a specific git and
i added a dot after the github.com
then i successfully bypassed
the protection of like the mapping that
lpm did
and
was able to
download without any audit and this
means that if i'm a package
if i'm a
package maintainer oh i have some code i
can add this
piece of code and the audit will not
find it it will not find the any
vulnerability inside it
which means that also the security team
will not know about
it will not know that there's a
vulnerability but it will not know also
that
the package might have skipped this
vulnerability so
like i i asked them and then we talked
about in the other circuit i talked to
the npm team to check if we can add an
rfc another like not found zero
vulnerabilities but how many
packages were skipped in the process of
testing it because we have this package
that is skipped and it didn't it didn't
succeed in violating this
and checking if it's vulnerable or not
and because it depends on the cursive
then you have a problem
that even if you have this awesome
project and you have
a dependency but this dependency has out
of stone dependency that you want aware
of you will still still see zero
vulnerabilities and you don't even know
that
it did some kind of cheating and
bypassing the whole production of
in the future and this is a good way to
add in malware or add in a version that
in the future you can just update it and
it will automatically update
and
so
it's a good way and it's uh too bad that
we don't
validate our own vulnerabilities and
this is something that i want also to
think about that you should always
even that you have inside this package
of angels you have s bomb and
suffer bill of materials and you have an
already analysis and you have all the
tools
you should trust them
that they
they
want you to get a job but they don't
want they they don't do the more
advanced uh
testing and you should have a
solution that creates
proper s-bomb creates public
vulnerability analysis proper
testing and
most importantly that you know when it
fails when it doesn't do
so you need to know what it that it does
be able to get the phenomenons but also
that it
failed is for some reasons over
some or somewhere
uh we had
actually last week there was a bit of
talking about the npm package
maintenance and then someone just like
filed and they create a tool that to
check
unregistered domains so if we have uh
maintain them
that is a maintainer for a very known
package but his domain got expired
someone can just buy the domain
and then reset the password into his
account
so this is a
something that happened and then here we
saw lots of people starting to scan all
the packages and found like what eleven
thousand
a
hijackable packages and there was a bit
of a lot of noise in the week uh last
two weeks i think
and just you should know
you cannot fully trust the maintainers
because they created a package they
sometimes they forgot about it sometimes
they didn't continue they are people
they are hackable also they have domains
that are hackable and the dns and
there's
the whole game and it's very hard to
protect everything over here
so your next task is to find all
applications in your organization
organizations
that the maintainers don't have an email
that don't have a domain or the domain
expired this is very hard to do
it's nobody is really doing it and if
you will do it you will see how much
problems you have inside all of the
packages
so a quick recap
package managers install what they want
they execute unwanted scripts they added
checks
easily bypassed
and just random people maintain packages
and everybody uses them
but we rely on open source we cannot
live without package managers if you
will tell a developer now
not to use
any package manager it would be a
problem for that they
like it's part of our day-to-day life i
use it every day
but we need to know how to protect
ourselves
so we need to make sure we use log files
to verify log files on the news to
manage our correct software materials
database
and to monitor for every package
download that is not in my
software with materials
i want to make sure that packet managers
don't have any permissions
put them in a container put this
container in a box put it in another
sandbox
give them as many much minimal
approaches as possible
monitor what they do
treat them as viruses
and or
least with a permission and just don't
let them do anything
i know they need the internet access so
and
from other checks just like one other
checks with external
checks with external tools make sure
you're taking in account also the
specification file itself and also the
log files don't
you
if also you have a log file sometimes
it will be lost in the way sometimes you
will have a
differences a difference between the
specification file and log file what
would happen you you don't you cannot
rely the the package manager will always
use only the log file or user
specification file or maybe a developer
will remove it and delete it
at the end the
most important thing
you can do is make sure that in the
binary and the
container itself
you have the same packages that are well
supposed to be in the log file and
responsibility in the specification file
and this is the way to validate that
it's everything is there to and
enough nothing to drift enough nothing
moved into production and if you have
out of stock packages just verify them
manually i would just like say
everything that is
not inside the package manager
repositories you have to verify manually
you have to check it to test it and if
there's a change
and i'll sign it and make sure that
everything is
valid over there
any questions
i don't know how much time we have
thanks for adam um i think we've we've
got a minute or two so we'll take a
couple of questions i think andy had one
for you
hi thanks for the talk that was really
fabulous um
that the main hijack you were talking
about at the end
um
there's lots of things that we can do
there um and it looks like a lot of the
a lot of the problems that you
demonstrated there were to do with
malicious updates to maybe an untrusted
developer something like this
do you think there's a space for code
signing
in
the package registry
people
first of all yes i think like code
signing is everybody's talking about it
and it's the next thing that people want
to start to do it's a code signing from
cosine commits and the code calls a code
signing even
different areas inside the packet itself
you see we have integrity but it's uh
it's not enough
and
the more we have ways that we can sign
different areas if i can sign the code
and then sign the container and sign
everything else and validate the
everything inside the container and
inside the build systems so validate
everything inside of the
different steps in the way
it will be much more
easier the thing is
when you validate something when you
sign something you need to make sure you
have the proper solutions and the proper
security controls that you just
not just sign on blindly you need to
verify it and then sign it so if someone
adds a very like execution code
so maybe this time some static analysis
and then after doing static analysis
sign it automatically
yes
okay and uh
one more question are there any
statistics of the prevalence of attempts
of attacks within the most popular
package managers
um this is hard actually i don't
i didn't play with statistics like i'm
all on the defending side and looking at
different like from the overall view and
trying to find the problems of the
future
i don't do too much incident response
so i don't know what statistics but we
do see that like in the past
like we had because of code com for
instance a lot of uh shares started
popping up around the world
when they had their ipo uh
risk
that they were hacked today because
their whole code base was still could
have been stolen
so we do have different
risks over there but
because every company because it happens
inside the companies themselves
and it's not like public public
information i don't think we will ever
have proper statistics
okay that makes sense great um thank you
very much rhodam excellent thank you
[Music]