[Music]
i think next we have a lightning talk
from um joseph hadouri
um
but before that i did want to obviously
like call out as well i think a lot of
the proceeds that come from devsecond do
go towards um charitable trust um
looking at inclusiveness within
technology and i know and then you're
really passionate about that so i just
wanted to take a moment just to
appreciate that that whilst this is
amazing for knowledge sharing there is
uh you know another really good reason
behind all of this as well
totally amazing
amazing so we might get joseph on board
just out in regards to the lightning
talk don't trust code from strangers
hi guys
hello we're glad to have you here and
especially
uh the talk that you're gonna have is
like don't trust quote from strangers
that's something which interests all of
us a lot and that's like the need they
are
yeah
so uh i'll press uh can you see my
slides
yes we'll just bring it in
all right cool
so i have 15 minutes so i'll try to be
quick
hi everyone my name is joseph i'm
heading the supply chain security
engineering group at check marks joined
last year
uh talking about software supply chain
this is a diagram
very simple to understand i think we all
uh
doing that in some way uh developers are
writing code source control is storing
it we have all kinds of real processes
ci flows collecting dependencies
basically responsible for building up
our source control packaging up into a
build artifact
might be stored somewhere uh and then
eventually being consumed by
a different software or user
looking down at this software supply
chain flow
you can see uh three major threats you
have source threats build threats and
dependency threats this was created by
salsa but not this salsa
uh it's a framework initiated by the
linux foundation
uh and now partnered with google
citibank a lot of giant companies uh
basically creating the standard in
software supply chain
i want to focus on this area on the
dependencies because in my personal
opinion this is the wild west this is
what scares me the most uh and
breaking it down and thinking about our
dependencies
everybody is using open source i mean
it's very great i myself love to
contribute into the open source and
consume
when we build application ended up you
know compiling our software
uh it's mostly constructed from open
source code
uh it makes sense because all of us
developers
basically wants to deliver fast and be
more agile we don't want to reinvent the
wheel i love to say a good developer is
an efficient developer
so this makes out of sense
we are originally asking for specific
dependencies
uh but we need to understand
most of the time we are not asking for
uh the side effects like the transitive
dependencies
uh so uh we can end up with all kinds of
forests uh when we it depends on the
specific packages and then we end up
with a lot of money giving one example
is cnc js this is what happens when you
install it you get
800 over 800 additional packages
contributed form different um over 600
different contributors it's very hard to
go through all of what you got like when
you install a specific dependency
we're just with like a jungle of open
source
uh the ecosystem is growing uh
everywhere we see
a lot of more packages being published
into the ecosystem
focusing only on npm
uh we can see as of today we have over
500 000 packages released
every month
and we'll have to trust open source
uh and the reason we do that is we get
the feeling that it's open for everyone
to take a look at it
if there's an issue some
magical character will notice
and there are a lot of scoring
mechanisms
like stars and forks
to rate and measure popularity of some
of the projects
what i want to talk about now is like
when we assess and i would start to
choose the popular packages to choose
the popular open source projects to be
on the safe side uh and i want to give a
couple of examples when some of these
popular packages went rogue and gone bad
eventually caused a lot of victims to be
under attack
meet faisal a very cool guy from
indonesia uh he loves contributing the
open source
one of these cool projects called ua
parser js
which is a small library
published to npm to
help parsing the user edged strings very
compact minimized
maintained a lot of years over 10 years
and having more than 10 million weekly
downloads a very popular packages it is
used by many organizations even facebook
and you know what most likely you're
already using it if not directly
transitively via one of your
existing dependencies
let's go back uh october 5th 2021
not so far ago from now
on the russian underground
hackers
posted this message
i'm selling an account on npmjs having
more than seven million weekly downloads
there is no two-factor authentication
enabled on this account
it's suitable for all kinds of things
miners creating the botnet
bidding starts 10k
sounds interesting
what happens couple of weeks later is
faisal posted this message
on his own project
he was saying that he's sorry and
someone was hijacking his npm account
publishing a couple of versions
containing malware
sadly what the attacker did we know that
someone was buying this publication on
the russian underground
uh and published simultaneously free
version containing the same malicious
code
uh this was the the attackers preserved
the original functionality to not
causing any uh functionality damage
but to add
uh
trying to do that silently to add a
crypto miner and a credential stealer to
all many victims using these packages
two weeks later
uh additional two packages popular
packages were compromised uh in this
case it was cora and rc command line
parser and configuration manager
combined having over 22 weekly downloads
same malicious code looking out at the
timeline we see the activity of this
attack group
and
it's a very sad case we see a lot of
innocent users relying on popular
packages getting these bad malwares
another example
is a developer uh lives in california
goes under the name brandon zuckee
miller
he's a very cool guy riding motorcycles
electric motorcycles taking them to the
track has a youtube channel um he's
making a youtube
a positive impact he contributes a lot a
lot of packages having over 40 packages
on npm
one of them is node ipc
uh used for inter-process communication
uh a very popular project having over a
million weekly downloads maintained for
many years
and a couple of months from now not so
far ago on march 7 2022
brandon himself added a new
functionality to his own project uh this
is
the commit and this is what he added
one line of code
uh breaking it down and purifying what
we see here is this code uh very short
code
uh
basically what the code is doing is
going into making an http request into
ipgo location a service
resulting with
the country name and what kind of
information where the request was came
from
and then brandon checks
if the country of the victims is coming
from russia or belarus
then
let's wipe down his files on this
computer
uh
basically sending uh a malware to russia
is go he calls it a heart attack malware
clears the content of existing files
from whatever was stored in to heart
emoji this is his delete logic
you might be wondering yourself why
would brandon like you know he builds up
a name for many years to contribute to a
lot of projects why would brandon flip
and do such a thing
this was his way to protest against the
russia ukraine war
he was not willing to sit down and do
nothing
and took a step into side you know in
like targeting russian uh
developers victims and wiping them their
computer
he was saying on social media you
download my software so i'm allowed to
wipe down your computer and this it was
the first time we saw the term quarter
square
uh in news
some of the cool i don't know cool but
some of the interesting comments were uh
posted on these
variant social
medias uh brandon that's abuse of power
don't become what you hate
thank you for teaching me not to take
handouts and code everything myself or
do i try
uh
this one is hilarious
that's this takes let's go bear them to
a whole other level
and this was
causing us to think
you know bernie has a lot of other
projects what about them he still have
access
even though even to know the ipc still
have access to his other projects
um and you know a good reputation is
something that is very hard to build but
you can lose that in a snap so brandon
lost his reputation in this case
and
a lot of
other examples where popular projects
used by many users were gone bad is this
list but what i want to show you right
now is
how easy it is to publish a malicious
package
this is called package lab it's a tool
created internally by our research team
um and what i'm going to do here is i'm
going to use
uh an already created identity on python
python package index to publish a
malicious package over there and show
you how easy it is
in order to do so we need to choose a
name for our package so i'll go with
supply chain demo
and then choosing a version
i'll go with 1.2.3
this is optionally but
you can see in the next slide why it's
important we can select and state what
is the
source project
on github where this package is related
from
um so let's browse the trending projects
and choose some random projects having a
lot of traction we'll go with this one
and
this one is having
over 9000 stars on github a very
interesting project
so this comes the fun part this is where
we can state our malicious code
uh when we plan this attack this is the
step we were currently at we're going to
publish a malicious package
victim is going to install our malicious
package and then we're going to go into
a service called pastebin and we're
going to store
a code is going to be downloaded inside
of our application and then injected
runtime and this is where our malicious
coin is going to play
eventually
sensitive information such as ssh keys
our environment variables are going to
be exfiltrated into a web book service
hosted on interactive sage
and this is two lines of code we're
going to add into our malicious package
an http request into pastebin and then
statement a built-in functionality in
python called exec
so whatever result from this space mean
is going to be injected into our
application
that's it
let's launch it
after a couple of moments we're going to
have our malicious package live
and even though it was published 10
seconds ago
our malicious package is highly popular
it has look it down the statistics it
has over 9000 github stars
this attack technique is called star
jacking we saw that uh in the past year
used by many attackers usually combined
with all kinds of techniques such as
type of squatting
but
look how simple it is to publish a
malicious package
no one checks whatever you provide the
metadata the code uh
very very scary to me
from attacker points of view whenever
victims installs our malicious package
you can have it multiple ways either as
a sub dependency but let's go down with
simply like people installing it right
uh this is what happens you know nothing
very suspicious on the victim side but
from an attacker's point of view you can
see ssh keys
uh environment variables
a lot of sensitive information being
sent
and breaking down the reason why it's
that easy we have no vetting uh accounts
are being taken over as we saw in one of
the examples
uh we have a lot of automatic updates uh
it takes a lot of time to detect such
attacks
we have a lot of moving parts um
and
uh eventually what do we do i want you
to remember what if there is a thing i
want you to remember from this uh short
talk is vulnerable is not malicious okay
we can live okay with some
vulnerabilities because they are not
applied on our application but you never
want to have packages or components
containing malicious code
you need to get rid of them as soon as
possible
um the industry needs to share more
information
uh we need better standards uh to
catalog
all of these supply chain incidents we
don't have a standard as of today so
each vendor is like creating its own
ids so for the uh ue parser incident
this is uh like a couple of examples
where every vendor created its own
ways
um we're in this together we share a lot
of information with all of our
competitors
um
it's our software it's our
responsibility
don't take out from strangers and i'm
inviting you to talk next week at the
open source summit uh where i will have
more time to share more examples more
demos uh
it's called the simple yet free full
anatomy of a software supply chain
attack you're welcome to check it in
thank you guys
thank you so much joseph it was amazing
like a quick and short talk you were
talking about and then punches all of
those things they were amazing it was
true truly a lightning talk
i'm looking at the timer and it's 15
minutes so i'm glad
you've done well and as you said
vulnerabilities if it's vulnerable it's
not malicious i think that's a great
little takeaway
um from that talk as well
great thank you so much joseph we'll
have you in our sessions in our future
sessions as well please do join our
discord community and check out the
questions that people uh have asked
and thank you thank you for joining us
today
thank you guys have a great one
thanks joseph
[Music]