[Music]
all right so i think without further ado
let's bring nilu on to start up sessions
there
hey hey nilo let's unmute you
hold on a second there
needle feel free to unmute your mic
uh in there
yes
i'm getting a little bit of feedback i
don't know if that's just on my side
eric do you hear that as well yeah i'm
getting a little feedback
um
can you give me no
yeah we hear you but it's a little bit
staticky the mic sounds distorted a bit
for some reason okay just leave me a
second
sure
hey neil hi can you hear me now yes
fantastic much better okay great
so let me share my screen
sure
and i think um what was happening there
is your your microphone you know no pun
intended intentionally right there but
uh it was going full throttle right it
was like
overpowered and ready for your next
session that you're going to be speaking
to us about
yeah i think i had to reset a reset it a
little bit but uh can you see the screen
now
yes we have it we're ready to go and uh
if you want to take it away feel free to
go ahead
thanks thanks eric uh thanks a lot uh
for having me here at devsecond so um
it all starts a few years ago actually
and i was just thinking about the the
entire subject that i wanted to talk
about a few years ago when i joined my
current organization
those days where the pre pandemic days
when we used to go around meeting people
so i was pretty excited i
went around talking to the tech leads
tech architects
i wanted to meet the heads of tech and
security and you know i was trying to
understand at the time what is their
one main problem statement that they
were trying to solve
and that i could help with
uh and almost unanimously everybody was
talking about just one thing you know
the main ask was to
make security more proactive given that
it was an agile development environment
and they wanted their teams to be unable
to do security on their own
and interestingly uh having been from uh
you know an offensive security
background and having done security the
typical way for a long time many of us
would uh sort of dread the idea of
letting go you know losing that control
that many of us as security teams have
um and that felt a bit out of place for
me as well
but i kept that in mind i came back and
i was thinking of you know how do we
tackle this
this particular problem statement that
was given
um and i kept thinking about it while i
was you know into automation and doing
assessments and other things
so um
one day i was just talking to someone
and they just sort of threw this
statement on me while they were talking
and very casually you know they
mentioned
um culture eats started strategy for
breakfast
and this is a famous quote by peter
drucker and um at that time it was new
to me uh and
it just struck me when they said that
and i was thinking about it for quite a
while and when and then i realized uh
how true that is
so essentially here what what he's
trying to say is uh whether you have
strategy and tactics and they have their
own importance if you want to succeed at
an organization scale
culture is something that you need to
focus on so that is what stayed with me
uh but just for us to understand and the
rationale behind what what we are going
to discuss further um i wanted to also
show you this other side you know which
is more logical to the whole thing is in
the past few years we've been seeing
attack trends moving from you know the
network uh side to the application side
and now the new attack surface is more
like cloud and it has moved to you know
the supply chain and we are seeing more
and more attacks happening in this area
uh it could be because of changing
technology
or newer environments
or even the ease of provisioning systems
and scaling them these days
but whatever be the reason when you when
you look at it a little more deeply for
example if you just pick up the supply
chain attacks that have been um so
prevalent these days you will see that
many or most of these have happened
because of either
for example insecure pipeline components
or insecure product
or just unmanaged secrets
and the common denominator in all of
this is that we as development teams
have left something open or
misconfigured or something like that
now
the other thing that i was thinking
about when i was thinking of this is
that
given that there is a lot of change
there are a lot of variables there is
something else that has changed as well
for these kind of attacks to be very
very prevalent now
so and that's when i i thought about uh
agile we have been
working in the waterfall model for quite
a few years long time back and most of
us or many of us have in the last decade
been moving to primarily agile forms of
development
um agile as many of us would know is
hydrated incremental you know it's time
boxed um but one primary thing about
agile development is it is it has it is
very fast paced you know there are
faster releases there are faster
deployments happening and the context is
evolving uh very very fast
um what happened in in the this this
last few years was that uh the speed of
development and agile was so fast that
operations had to catch up they had to
automate a lot of things
and i would say it worked wonderfully
for them
but the idea is can we equate that with
security or will it equally work for
security
so when you look at the products which
are available now there are a lot of
products in the market to do
product security of sorts but
um you can in fact do code reviews uh
you can do dependency checking you can
do dynamic testing infrastructure
assessments or even container scanning a
lot of things that we can do
however even in that
that
attack surface you will see that things
like business logic issues api security
um
issues around idols or session
management a lot of these kind of issues
which are not picked up by these
products
so i wanted to actually give you a quick
idea of the extended attack surface that
we are actually dealing with in terms of
development um as it's a very rough uh
sort of an indicator of what i'm trying
to say but you know you understand in
terms of these are the components in
terms of the agile development
environment you will have a developer
who has you know who's pushing in the
custom code to source control and then
there are a bunch of libraries that
people in
um we build that and you know create our
container artifacts and essentially push
that to production
now it's not just these systems there
are many other systems like at the back
end like the data stores or databases
that you're dealing with other public or
private repositories from where you're
pulling in your images
and these are not just these instances
that we are talking about when we say
development
particularly in agile we are also
talking about all of these various
actors who could be vulnerable or could
be compromised in one way or another
that means the real attack surface is
not just any of these components which
could be vulnerable
um in fact i think there is there is a
talk on the on ci fuzzing uh later today
which you should definitely watch i will
look out look out for it individually
there are a lot of vulnerabilities that
we can exploit for these components
um but there are also a lot that can be
done for the actors themselves who are
maybe configuring these systems setting
them up or writing the code base
that means that
there are a lot of other attacks that
can happen as well like there are supply
chain issues
the social entering phishing endpoint
issues um and as you would remember
recently uh you know there were a lot of
zero days that sort of gave us a
rollercoaster ride so those things are
there as well
so that brings us to the other point
which is
uh the other layer which you generally
talk about which is people
and people becomes then the center stage
of if you are trying to make any
long-term lasting impact in terms of
security
um when you talk about people in an
agile development environment um the
main set of folks that you will think of
or who should be the centerpiece of your
or the target audience that you have
would be the development teams right so
when you're mainly dealing with the
developers or development teams what is
it that you're supposed to look at when
you're trying to actually drive a
mindset change for them
so essentially first try and understand
what are their development challenges
many times as security teams we forget
to even think about it
uh they're already being attained
they're working towards you know faster
time to markets they're working towards
performance indicators that they have to
meet usability environments that they
have to meet and all of that they are
doing in an entitled delivery timelines
then uh before you go to them with uh
with the product for automation it's
important to understand what is their
current tech context like for example
how do they manage their dependencies
currently right what is working for them
what is their process of prs
and
if you are going to introduce a process
change for them
it's also important to see where they
are in terms of for example awareness to
even pick up that process and make the
right sense of it and not just make it a
checklist in their entire kind of things
um and hence i uh
came back i'm so so sorry to interrupt
but i just want to give you a heads up
that we're getting a lot of that static
audio feedback again so if you can
potentially reset and we'll just pause
here for a moment
okay
i know how how it can feel so
like no worries about the technical
difficulties and stuff like that we'll
get through it and we can uh adjust
timing on things too okay
cool no problem all right so
just to continue
where i left
yeah thanks
um
when i came back and started
looking at you know how do you drive
that mindset change
it was something that
i was looking at more from a people
standpoint and how do we bring about
that cultural change
i started designing a security change
program that would bring about that
change
and the idea and goal for us was to
actually have security champions uh in
every team who would sort of
um catapult security into the the
projects and and stay close and drive
that culture change
um
so whenever you are in that journey as a
security team when you are trying to
design a program yourself there are some
key considerations to look at when you
are starting that
so the first thing is keep the problem
statement in mind uh many times there
are so many issues that we are dealing
with that you know we get into rabbit
holes so you have to understand what is
the problem that you are solving for and
how relevant it is for your target
audience in this case the development
teams
and what kind of outcomes you're looking
at
secondly look at the stakeholders that
you have it could be the participants
the development teams themselves uh it
could also be uh for example influencers
and projects right who you want to work
with to take this further ahead also the
leaders in your organization and stuff
like that
um and finally also look at basic things
like tech stacks you know what are the
technical constraints where the budget
you're working with the timelines that
you're working with things like for
example timeline is not just delivery
timelines but also the time that the
teams will have to invest
in your program once that rolls out
secondly when you're creating a program
always keep in mind to make it lean
because you're doing it for an agile
development environment
so for example in in our case when i
started we had this whole nine step
process
to go through to the right outcome and
it did work for us for the initial
pilots
but what we did was soon we came back to
brainstorm and make it much
uh leaner from that perspective so that
we could roll it out to you know larger
set of teams because we were to work
with hundreds of teams after that so we
made it very simple three-step process
on including onboarding where we would
focus on awareness workshops where we
would focus on more practical
high-intensity tasks which we would
enable the the sect charms for and
followed by governance
when you are defining any process
changes that you want
them to pick up the teams to pick up for
your program
it's very essential when doing that for
an agile environment is to align with
the key agile rituals
uh that ways what happens is it ensures
that it becomes a practice for them and
and that it becomes more like muscle
memory right when they're doing
development so in our case when we had
threat modeling like at at the heart of
what we were trying to enable them for
and um for example for iterations right
we would have a sprint plan or an
initial iteration planning meeting so
when that ritual happens we made sure
that we are looking at we are the teams
are picking up the features right at
that time for which feature would be
threat modeled you know in that
iteration
secondly rotate and iterate so uh it's
important to have frequent but smaller
threat modeling in this in this parlance
is to do it more frequently but in small
sizes so for example rather than doing
an entire thread modelling for an entire
application we would uh rather focus on
smaller threat modeling on features but
do it more frequently
thirdly make it official you know
whatever threats that came out of our
threat modeling we're supposed to go to
the project dashboard so for example
your jira or your confluence you can add
it to that directly
secure your source so it's good to start
with secure defaults uh create for
example baseline secure baseline images
or or
harden configuration or a safer code
base to start off with totally depends
on the program that you are going for
in our case for example we had in terms
of threat modeling because that was at
the core of this program we were
focusing on giving them an initial set
of scenarios that they could look in the
context of which were generally the
commonly occurring scenarios for for our
teams
and lastly uh
leverage the pipeline so
i think this has been discussed a lot
and tremendously in in-depth
so i will not uh speak too much about it
it's important it's a very special place
in development where you can add and
automate a lot of stuff so leverage that
but ensure that you have the right kind
of api set for it for example when does
it really break the build you know or do
you have the slas to go ahead and fix
the high critical issues that you found
in that particular run
so
before
going in with it we had the onboarding
process where we're looking at awareness
but some important things to do when
you're going for developer awareness is
apart from the general awareness that
you're looking at it's also important to
look at role specific trainings uh in
the sense that what can they do in their
respective roles so we know that a
developer can code securely um a ba
they will be gathering requirements
right so they should be explicitly
asking for security requirements as well
and they should be adding that as
acceptance criteria in their stories as
well so those are the kind of things
that you want to tell them and how to do
that
so that the securities everyone's
responsibility actually becomes true
um
secondly there are many times that we
create a lot of these baselines and
checklists and you know um
even images and stuff that i was talking
about but many times developers may not
have
uh awareness around that so do they know
where it is can they just pick up and
run with it when they are starting off
their projects
is something you should ask yourself
and lastly look at a format of awareness
where they can stay updated there are so
many new attacks coming up every day are
they updated about these recent patches
any recent issues that affect their
systems
so things like that should be discussed
very very frequently and one efficient
way of doing that we figured was to
create and nurture a community of all of
these people so we create a community of
created a community of spectrums where
everyone especially sections and the
development teams could actually
interact around more hands-on fixes and
you know talking to each other about
these daily issues which they could then
pick up and and you know discuss with
each other and as well
um in our case
i'm so so sorry to interrupt again i
don't mean to keep doing this to you but
that's that it keeps creeping back in
somehow for some reason
for us we were looking at so in terms of
awareness uh we were looking at agile
threat modeling and what we were
particularly trying to do is apart from
the academic side of it you know apart
from understanding how to do a
strike-based threat modeling uh quickly
we were looking at how to operationalize
this better we were looking at
essentially telling them how you can
time it better rather than running into
rabbit holes uh we were trying to tell
them um or teaching them
around getting together and adding their
perspective when they're doing threat
modeling how do they prioritize issues
so once you have the threads out how do
you prioritize the issues and add them
to your project dashboard how do you
turn them into either acceptance
criteria or stories
um and or or tasks for that matter and
then add them to the project dashboard
so these were the practical aspects that
we wanted to focus on something that
they could pick up would be more
hands-on for them and they could pick up
and do it in a more agile fashion
for communication uh one important thing
to understand is try and leverage as
many channels of communication as
possible uh emails
you know chat channels create channels
if there are not any um but
in an agile development environment what
i have seen works best is the face to
face communication and that
i think stays for a very long period of
time
in the past couple of years that has
become really difficult but even when
wherever you can interact with smaller
groups uh or pair with you know
developer teams rather than just
remotely or working in silos and just
sending an email and forgetting about it
one thing to keep in mind as a security
team is to change our own mindset before
we go to the developers asking them to
change the mindset so in this case uh
focus on people interactions rather than
you know set standards that you may have
remember that
to make
you know the function secure you will
have to make security functional so
always go with a working solution
third very important is to collaborate
with the teams as much as possible you
know sit down pair with developers or
pair with devops and and all of these
individual roles and understand what
their challenges are
and lastly
uh adapt to changes in technology red
technology for for development teams is
actually changing really fast so we
should adapt to technology as much as
possible
how do you engage uh the developers
which in our case we were mostly looking
at sections and their engagement one
thing that
that i would like to share is
rather than you whenever we go to the
team sometimes we make that mistake of
throwing in security words or keywords
or jargons like for example rather than
telling them
zero trust on the first day it's always
good to start off with discussing more
concrete and actionable tasks um or
items that they can take up maybe before
the next stand up you know something
like that
um secondly keep them motivated as much
as possible and aware of of the recent
issues uh one great way of motivating
these set of folks is to let them own
their journey rate let them own the
changes that they want to make in their
projects be it automation be around
adding some other controls and process
changes and stuff like that once you
have told them what the goal is let them
own that
and lastly you can also gamify the
experience right so across your
organization or delivery organization
if you're looking at engaging these
people or all the development teams way
more it's always good to gamify that how
can you do that maybe you know you might
have heard of the systems of badges or
levels different levels in security so
it's always good to create something
like that where they can move from one
batch to another and always look forward
to something new so that sort of brings
in a healthy competition as well for
them
so rather than giving them a one-time
solution it's
rather good to teach them how to fish
that's the idea
so all of this works well in a smaller
scale and it worked well for our pilots
also
but when you move on to address this at
scale like with you know in our case it
was hundreds of teams that we were going
to roll it out
i have some more learnings to share
first thing is simplify the goals as
much as possible so that everyone
including
a developer or a leader understands it
equally well and everyone is on the same
page you know that ways it becomes very
easy to interpret solutions that you are
recommending as well
atomic success
is
very important before you get success at
scale
which means that for if you're
introducing a process of practice always
try and test it on some of the teams it
has to succeed in in a unit scale so
whether you're looking at unit being
your project or it being your squad or
streams
it should succeed or succeed there and
work well there for it to function well
at scale
thirdly
having a set of secure defaults really
helps so whatever be your program that
you're building it around it's good to
have a set of secure defaults to start
off with now what it really helps with
is to give that
a quick win to to the developers also
and once they have that quick win it's
like a win-win situation where they can
start psychologically at a stronger
place and then they stick for a longer
time to the changes that you might have
recommended through your program
um the other thing that is important
while doing that is
remember what you're in for so you are
trying to drive a mindset change and
it's very important to build a mindset
for edge cases so uh
essentially take them through the entire
journey that you will have as as a
security person right if you were
playing all of these roles you would ask
yourself questions or try to answer some
of those security questions are they
asking those questions do they have a
critical mindset
while they are playing their role within
the development team so that is
something to look for
leverage automation wherever possible
once they start you know identifying
threats early on in the life cycle they
will start seeing more
things or issues that can be predicted
early on and or are recurring and can be
automated so for example if there is a
solution to add
stages right to a certain type of
pipeline and you're dealing with
multiple different kind of ci's in your
environment then what's created for one
can be reused for another always
depending on how many different teams
are using that so leverage that as much
as possible
when you're introducing processes or
practices uh it's important that they're
effective so the first thing to ensure
that is that you align with your agile
development life cycle you know the
delivery timelines the life cycle
and the rituals like i was talking about
and you are when you are adding
practices uh ensure that they are
effective and they are driving a
behavior change so if you have an option
of
two processes or two different ways of
doing something similar it's always good
to bank on the one that will drive the
behavior change in the long run
and lastly
communicate the why i think this is
something that i cannot emphasize enough
uh i uh realized this only when we you
know started addressing this issue at
scale and then we started working with
hundreds of spectrums
the initial part of clearing the why
becomes or helps you way
longer in the program or until much
later you know so
for us this is an ongoing program and
once this why part is clear for all of
them and all the stakeholders there are
much lesser questions and there are way
more solutions so the overall attitude
of
uh your target audience will definitely
improve and become way more positive if
you have clarified the why for them
so some of the results from what we had
done earlier um for this
uh we started with the pilot a bunch of
teams and then we started doubling up on
how many teams we wanted to uh roll this
out to
um some of the the early wins for us
where essentially discovering hundreds
of threats we soon started discovering
hundreds of threats alongside the sec
champs and the development teams and
also fixing the high critical issues
from there
sec champs soon became the point of
contact for security and everybody
started reaching out to them internally
and externally for anything to do with
security so now everybody become way
more proactive
and one of the things that
definitely changed for us which was not
the goal of the program but was quite
interesting is that the entire push
model that security generally struggles
with became a full model so initially we
would reach out to teams for them to
enroll for
the sec champ program
and as of today all the new teams that
are coming up they reach our course
directly to enroll for the program
themselves uh even for that matter for
doing a threat modeling so they would
loop us in when they are doing a threat
modeling or let us know that how many
issues they have and what are they
prioritizing
so that makes the job of if you have
been a security team
that makes your job much much easier
than working in a push model
so in an ideal setup how the people will
play a role in the development would be
something like this where you are going
through
ensure that the development teams are
going through their role specific
awareness but also the tech tax specific
trainings you know because before you
start development you generally know
what is the kind of tech stack that you
are going to work with
um when you are in the design phase uh
leverage threat modeling
to identify threads early on but not in
silos
or not only with a security expert but
the entire team should be involved along
with your sec champs if you have any
once you have your security backlog
created ensure that all of these
security acceptance criteria or stories
or features that you may have discussed
are moving to the project dashboard and
you allocate the developer a deaf pair
or a bandwidth for that
to address that issue
once you start development definitely
leverage automation um for every
everything including sas or dust or you
know your container scanning and things
like that but towards the end of it uh
take time to have sort of a retro like
reflect upon or inspect upon what are
the issues that you got from
the threat modeling that you did or from
the automated runs or even for example
if you are doing an external vendor
assessment what are the kind of issues
you are getting
how many of those are really recurring
which can be coded right or can be coded
into security unit test for example or
can be addressed through design or
through acceptance criteria in your
future stories
so for a mature security team it will
mostly look like this where they are
it's much easier for them to get into
security huddles like huddles in the
sense you can just pick up a feature and
start looking at doing a quick threat
modeling or
checking the workflow for security
threats iterative threat modeling become
a common thing
when you're defining the acceptance
criteria for your stories it should show
the security validations essentially
should be showing in those those stories
as well which can be tested later by a
qa
of course leverage automation as much as
possible
and
add security to the definition of done
so a story is essentially not done until
it's securely done
finally
focus on the process and pipeline to
ensure that you can gain velocity and
ensure coverage when you are trying your
change program
understand that the ecosystem should be
secure by design rather than the
individual components in your supply
chain
and lastly leverage culture to add
security to your organizational fabric
so
there there'll be many things that you
might do or to you know bring in smaller
changes add controls in place
um have automation in place from time to
time
but if we are driving the mindset change
it's better to play the long game thank
you
that was excellent nilu and a round of
applause for uh dealing with all the
technical issues too there
you handled it very smoothly so
i know how to do it live yes
i know how jarring that can be and you
you handle it so professionally kneeling
so well done on that and uh thank you
for that excellent session so i think do
we yeah if you have a few more minutes
here we have a couple questions for you
if you don't mind that sound good
sure
okay great all right so first question
that came up was i believe it was
kavitha over in hopkin thank you kavisa
for the question
and uh
their question was what tools were used
in the process journey were there any in
particular that you could call out and
share with folks that enabled some of
what you learned and shared through this
process
so for us when we were driving the sec
champ program particularly so we have
other automation specific programs where
we have tools which we recommend you
know for adding controls because this
was mostly a people-focused program and
we were looking at agile threat
modelings uh that is a framework that we
have uh sort of created in within
thoughtworks and that's what we used uh
particularly for agile threat modeling
it's based on top of microsoft stride
model itself but a faster and much
quicker way of doing it we did not use
um specifically any tools there are
tools for threat modeling as well
but given that our organization is more
like a service based organization there
are you know multiple clients and
different tech stacks different
compliance requirements you know the
context is entirely different for all
the clients
so uh we kept it simple and we kept it
agile
excellent excellent
um
the one thing that hit home for me and
we have a couple more questions but
really quick one thing that hit home for
me was when you
uh talked about security as part of your
definition of done
you like it really brought me back into
recalling some of my earlier developer
days where we as a team were defining
this definition of done and we didn't
have security included in there honestly
speaking but we had things like testing
and like what like deploying it in a
staging environment to make sure it
works there and so this that like
thank you for sharing that part in there
and like i'm thinking back like how did
we not think about okay how do we
include security in that definition of
done too so uh that's it's just awesome
to see and i think this can be super
helpful to the older me as well um and
folks that were there so one more
question i think we'll take real quick
and that is um
were there separate
were separate projects created for cloud
and on-premise applications throughout
this
um we will so we were essentially
working on a security change program
and we were not delivering any projects
however we were dealing with uh if i
understand your
question correctly correct me if i'm
wrong we were dealing with various
projects some of them were on cloud some
some of them were on-prem
and
in fact some of them were also purely
infrastructure projects right so the
agile threat modeling one for example
for us it was threat modeling we were
working on we when we talked to about
threat modeling it would be different
for for example specifically for
applications or just web applications or
mobile applications right because you
look at different issues which are
commonly found in mobile rather than web
so web would be different mobile would
be different infrastructure will be
different because then you might
actually do an infrastructure threat
modeling uh and also architecture review
from that perspective so
this context was different for us and
with cloud we would definitely have or
look into different scenarios for cloud
so that was the the degree of difference
that we were following um within that
also there were many uh you know
subdivisions but we didn't go that far
we wanted to keep it simple so that
everybody could pick up and understand
for example if you are looking at mobile
then
you should go for also mobile top 10
issues rather than just blindly looking
at the web top 10 you know so just
giving an example from obvious
there are very contextual issues to look
at and that's what we were focusing on
during answer mode
gotcha that makes a lot of sense and
thank everybody that was posting some of
the questions in there
uh eric do we have any more questions
maybe that are coming to mind for you or
um yeah well simon asked one i was
should i find it in our list
i'm just going to ask it from the chat
it says uh when you say iterative threat
modeling what triggers an update to the
threat model that was created before
would bug fixes or minor improvements
counts
yeah that's a good question so uh when
when we say i did a threat modeling it
is to pick up a bunch of features right
so when you start developing uh
your services
you would have certain features being
added uh with every release generally it
will not all happen at one go like it
happens in waterfall so when you have a
bunch of features which are being added
uh with in every iteration or you know
every couple of titration you will have
a bunch of new features coming up we
would pick up a bunch of features and
then start whiteboarding and thread
modeling around it and that is what we
call iterative because it would be you
know every one or two iterations we
would have a threat modeling because we
would have new set of features that we
would threat model on
that's great
great way to keep things fresh um as the
as the application changes
you know one of the things that actually
i i'm going to steal this i'm going to
quote you on this one i i love when you
said
uh that you need to
hopefully i won't butcher this to make
the functionality secure you need to
make secured security functional that is
like a genius quote i love that thank
you so much
yeah you realize so much of that once
you are on the agile side of things that
uh you know
but just to add to the previous answer i
think
just to clarify it further if you've
already done a threat modeling for your
entire application or your entire
service for example
and you are then making a change whether
it's a bug fix or your it's an update uh
you will have to look at functionally
what you have really added sometimes
minor enhancements should not we should
not go to that depth because then that
will that makes it too much uh to a
micro level and you may not end up
getting too many threads so when you're
looking at the roi because you're also
counting time of how many times you're
getting into a threat modeling it's good
to see what is if it's a major change
that you have done a major update that
you have done if you have something
majorly functional that has been added
or changed to you know go about doing
another threat modeling for that change
very cool
excellent well thank you nilu so much
this was super insightful and uh you did
an amazing job we appreciate you helping
us kick off the america's region for
devsecond and we'll hope to see you
again soon we'll see you in the in the
chat maybe on over on hoppin and youtube
thank you thanks brian thanks eric thank
you
[Music]