[Music]
let me bring that even to the stage
please i'll just turn these banners off
okay yeah so
so uh
hello eva hello
so eva is the uh thank you for coming
eva is the principal product security
engineer at the uh orth product unit of
octa
um and today she's going to talk to us
about lessons learned from helping scale
a product security program from startup
to acquisition so eva over to you thank
you
so uh hi everyone i'm super excited to
be here and in the next 30 minutes i'll
share what i learned from being part of
a product security team from a startup
to an acquisition
a few more details for me uh
i said i'm a principal product security
engineer of zero of zero is a product
unit of octa
i joined with zero back in 2018 back
then
had roughly 200 400 employees and the
product security team was doing small
steps
fast forward last year of zero was
acquired by octa and at that point all
zero had roughly a thousand employees at
a mature secure product security program
so this talks about those four years and
the journey and what i learned through
that journey on my free time i do dance
classes balear contemporary i play the
piano the clarinet i love outdoor
activities and this is my dog tropha
which i also love spending time with
uh
sort of a disclaimer what this talk is
about and what i'll cover and what not
this is about my observations and the
things that i learned
through that uh
journey of what zero from a startup to a
mid-sized company and myself being part
of the product security team i will this
talk is known about how xero product
security program or team look like what
decisions we took and so on
and to that regard the rest of the talk
will be about a fictional product
security team and the different stages
that go
for example a small team short stuff
uh laying the foundations how you mature
and how we scale
and with that let's say that
there is a company and they you get
hired as one of the first two product
security engineers and the new product
security team is formed
one question you may have is where to
start
and in two big buckets we can split it
into should i focus on the security of
the new features or should i focus on
the security of the existing product
if you were to focus on the first one on
the security of the new features
you will succeed you will successfully
start applying the shift left approach
you can start having design reviews um
security reviews during the design and
this will be effective in stopping
vulnerabilities from entering the coding
new product features
but if you were to only focus on this
one uh any undiscovered vulnerabilities
in the existing program the product
would still remain and this would pose a
significant security risk
now if we're going to go on the other
side let's say we're focusing only on
the security of an exist of the existing
product
here yes we will uh
uncover uh vulnerabilities and based on
that we will be able to assess what is
the risk that we have and plan
mitigating it
but we will suffer uh
the same thing on the new features if we
do nothing for the new features we will
have a vulnerability to produce there
of course it's not a one or the other
there is a balance uh but my suggestion
is during the very early stages at least
for the first couple of quarters you
need to give some um
some attention to the existing product
so that we have a baseline on what is
your security posture up to that moment
and at the same point you will start
rolling out um
processes and tools to help on the
security by design journey
on the topic on security of the existing
product when you first join a team a
company you may not know the product and
asking the question where the bodies are
buried uh where the security bags are
hidden it may be a difficult or
challenging task
my suggestion is ask engineers the
engineers who developed the product to
develop the features
know when they took a shortcut know when
they did things not perfectly
when they did it they may didn't know
the impact of it but if you ask them i'm
pretty sure they can point you to some
pretty interesting directions
if you want to make it a bit of a more
fun activity uh collaborate with your
engineering peers and conduct some
engineering wide back hunting days so
engineering teams and security teams
group together to hunt some security
backs
and the third one is it's possible that
the company you are joining already had
done a third party pen test
but my suggestion is have another one at
that point that you're forming the
product security team and you're
starting to roll out a program because
this will give you a baseline of of the
existing posture you will know how how
the product looks like from the external
vulnerability surface
this is for the existing product but we
said we also need to do some work on the
new features and a question we will
always ask whether it's in this very
early stage or further down the road is
how we prioritize how we work on on
assessing on consulting on those new
features
what i've seen that works really well
is a risk assessment questionnaire a
risk assessment questionnaire is a list
of questions
that engineering teams need to fill
during the start of their uh of their
design
and it it's a list of questions that
help determine risk some examples are uh
does the feature you're building change
how authentication authorization work
um are you going to do some sort of
encryption do you handle secret
sensitive data or personal data and so
on
and try that the answers in those
questions have a yes and a no
and the reason is we want based on the
answers
to quantify the risk and this is where
you would need to create a risk or
scoring algorithm
now in the beginning the rescoring
algorithm will not be perfect and the
reason is you when you create it you
don't have past data to validate it
against so maybe in the beginning you
can use a combination of your gut
filling and what the risk scoring
algorithm says but this means you will
you will need eventually to iterate on
that algorithm
so based on that
with that questionnaire that is filled
by engineering teams and ideally it
automatically provides there is score of
this project you can assess the risk of
an upcoming project and this allows you
to work on a risk-based prioritization
you can start working
on on design reviews for high-risk
projects and depending on your on your
capacity you could move to to more
medium risk once
now
this doesn't mean that for medium and
low risk once we
we offer nothing to our engineers and
this is where i think that security best
practices documentation is a good start
in this very early stage of a product
security program it can be used both for
engineering training but also as a
material to point your engineers for
projects that you will not be able to
to consult them as closely as you would
like
and on that regard it's sometimes
difficult to see how you prioritize
there are so many things we need to we
want to educate our engineers and
security best practices and it's not
always clear how to start my situation
is map
one question every question of the
security of the risk assessment
questionnaire map it to a security best
practice document
and to go back to the example if there
if there is a question that says are you
using encryption and they have said yes
there should be a security best practice
document on how to implement encryption
correctly and that document needs to be
short and actionable and like those two
are quite important the short and the
actionable and the reason is that
our engineers
need information
to make their implementation and their
design more secure
it's possible that uh you will want to
create a document that explains
why encryption when do we use encryption
and a bit more of a training material
but my suggestion is keep them separate
and have at least one document that is
how do i do it securely how do i design
and how do i implement something
securely
um
on the security testing tools in this
very early stage it's very possible that
there is no budget for commercial tools
this doesn't mean that you cannot roll
out some some security testing
evaluate them very well before the
integration the fact that they are open
source doesn't mean that rolling them
out teaching the engineers to use them
and to and to um make actions based on
the findings doesn't mean that this is
called it has zero cost on the contrary
another thing is roll out security tools
progressively
if you want to roll out many tools
roll them little by little and also if
you want to roll out just one tool don't
roll it out to the whole organization
again in both cases the point is we
don't want to overwhelm our engineers
because they will not have the time
uh to learn the new process to learn the
new tool and take action on the findings
another point is integrate into ci cd
and especially for security testing
tools like static analysis or software
composition analysis like sneak
you want to be able to add those
security testing tools as a check in
your prs because
you don't have time for manual code
reviews especially in this very early
stage but those testing tools can
can be
an automated security code review
the final thing and i know it's uh it
feels obvious is don't rule out a
security tool with high number of false
positives
doing that you train your engineers that
security testing tools do not give
valuable
valuable results and you train them to
not really pay attention to them so roll
out tools
that have a low number of false
positives or do the first trials to give
them to give to the rest of the
engineers a clear state
vulnerability management i said in the
beginning that during this first uh
laying the foundations of a product
security program you will do some
security testing on the on the existing
product and also we just said that we
will launch out some security testing
tools in both cases this means that we
will have vulnerabilities
as a first step on creating a
vulnerability management program
create something lightweight it can be
as lightweight as the diagram i have on
the side
and something very important is to train
your teams the engineering the product
and the security teams on this new
process remember that vulnerability
management is not a process owned only
by security it's a collaborative process
between
engineering product and security and the
success of it depends on all those teams
finally i know that
we are security people we like
slas if it's a high vulnerability it
needs to be fixed in x amount of
days
but
don't rush into creating streaks as a
lease if this is not feasible to be met
you are just rolling out a vulnerability
management
program you are building the foundations
for security pro product program
it's possible that
slas will not be bad and putting strict
slas from now
you're mentally training the rest of the
organization that strict slas for
security issues are not that strict
and you'll have heard me in the last
couple of slides saying how you mentally
trained your engineers in the wrong
direction if you do something you know
the other and this is where security
culture comes into play and every time
you take a decision or to do or to not
do something keep in mind how this
affects the security culture and by
security culture i mean how i train the
rest of the organization the engineering
and the product
to value security in the different
processes that we roll out
so this is so far the first uh a first
overview of
of laying down the foundations of a
security osmo product security program
we have security training minimal with
security best practice documentation
we do secure design reviews for starting
from high risk projects and going down
depending on our capacity we launched
some open source security testing tools
and we did some security testing on our
existing product
and because we found vulnerabilities we
also created a vulnerability management
process
on the next iteration you can think that
the product security team scales you get
more members and you get more resources
in that next phase the goal is to expand
on the different aspects of your program
that you launched in the first
generation and start adding some
structure
one thing that you may consider when you
get more resources and
you increase the the number of engineers
in your product security team in
security partnerships
when i say security partner is a product
security engineer that is assigned to a
few engineering teams and they become
the security point of contact
security partnerships have some great
validity affairs but also some drawbacks
that you need to take into account
before rolling out such a program
i cannot emphasize enough how great
relationship it helps you build
um you have security you have security
engineers working closely with
engineering teams and this really
fosters it fosters the security culture
and it builds great relationships
between security and engineering
also the whole organization has the
confidence that we release features that
are secure by design because we have a
security engineer who also becomes the
subject expert on that specific domain
of the product
now on the other hand
if you roll out a security partnership
program you may see that some
engineering teams can become too
dependent on their security partner and
by two dependent i mean that maybe
they
uh they don't spend so much effort in
learning some security processes that
you're rolling out or some tooling
because they know that they have their
security partner who will nudge them to
the right direction also maybe at some
point in the growth of both the company
and the
product security maybe you have a good
enough ratio so that one product
security engineer can be assigned to a
couple of engineering teams as the
company scales this will not scale well
and this is the scaling issues i
mentioned and on that regard
i have a couple of options as
alternatives not alternatives different
forms of security partnerships
one is instead of assigning security
partners to all the teams assign them
only to teams that are working high-risk
parts of the product
or another option is instead of
assigning security partners to projects
assign it to teams assign them to
projects
for example if you know that
there is a
new project coming up that will be i
don't know a couple of quarters
this is a good time it's a high risk one
this is a good time to assign a security
partner for that project
and the second option it helps because
engineering teams cannot become too
dependent because they get a security
partner only for their project and not
for the whole for the whole the folly of
their team
moving forward from security
partnerships security champions i said
that security partnership may have some
scaling issues security champions is the
solution to the scaling issues that you
will face in your product security
program
my suggestion is invest in a security
champions program early i know that when
you start investing in such a program
you may not see immediately the return
in this investment and this this is a
reason that you may be prioritize this
my advice is don't do it
it needs time to train to train your
engineers into becoming security
champions and further down the road you
will actually see the benefits of doing
that
give them a clear path
uh
and my advice here is
don't
teach them into doing uh
web security testing
teach them things that are applicable to
their job and their job is how to design
securely software and how to implement
securely software
and on that regard train them to do some
product security work because again this
is closer to what they're actually there
is actual job designing and implementing
secure software
and start assigning them some
responsibilities so that the training is
not theoretical but they can start
applying it
design reviews in the first iteration i
only mentioned that
following a risk-based prioritization
you can you will do design reviews uh
you will do security reviews during
design i think now it's a good time
after you've said those different uh
practices of the security program
throughout the structure we said and in
that regard during design i think we
need to start moving on threat models
because threat models
train
mentally you
train mentally your engineers in a very
specific way and looking for threats
my suggestion is also create a template
it's um you keep consistent
format to your engineers they know what
to expect how to expect it how it will
look like
it helps understanding what are the
threats when you have a specific threat
model template and as i said before
train your security champions to threat
model have them shadow you in the
beginning or have them um read your
thread model and discuss with you
how you approached it and so on at some
point maybe they can do it with your
consultation
security testing tools in the beginning
we
we didn't have budget and we all doubt
some open source tooling maybe now it's
a time to move to some commercial tools
because this gives us some more rich
features
i said it in the previous
time we talked about security testing
tools but take time to evaluate those
tools
when i say evaluate it's not only
about
the
the quality of the findings it's not
only about the ratio of false positives
and to evaluate them well come up with a
list of requirements before you start
the evaluation and in that list include
things like tool management can i
customize it can i extend it can i get
metrics out of it
um
does it integrate well with the workflow
of my engineering teams and so on and
one more thing to to pay attention to is
don't assess only the tool capabilities
but also the vendor relationship
the security testing tools vendors are
not
vendors they are partners in our journey
of making a
product security program successful
vulnerability management i said in the
first iteration don't rush into creating
strict slas but we need to start putting
some slas in place so now it's a good
time to start building a cadence of
resolving vulnerabilities in time
you need to get some leadership buying
for that
but
always take a risk-based approach in
your slas and sometimes this means an
fla exception
an example of an sla exception is the
following let's say that there is a
vulnerability uh that can be fixed
within selena's very specific way
but there is also the possibility that
instead of fixing this very specific
vulnerability
the engineering team can build a more
holistic solution that can help that can
harden the
the product
on that regard
maybe there is a good trade-off there to
go a bit out of sla to get that that
more holistic solution that is actually
better for the security of the whole
product
another thing is build metrics around
vulnerability management
what metrics each its company will need
is very dependent on the company needs
the security culture and so on but there
is one metric that i find super
important which is metrics on the
vulnerability types
get a
vulnerability taxonomy system it can be
the cwe which is the common weakness
enumeration or any other one that has a
short list of vulnerability types and
start assigning them to your
vulnerabilities
what you get out of it is great metrics
on where you do well and where not for
example if you see after a while that
you have too many vulnerabilities and
sensitive data exposure this is a very
good data point both for what kind of
training you need to give to your
engineers but also where where do you
focus your security testing um
capabilities
this is uh this is like a wrap-up of
phase two of a product security program
and
of course this is not just one iteration
there are multiple iterations to get to
that maturity
but at some point
you will reach a mature product security
program and when i say mature i mean
that
engineering and product know when and
how to reach out to you they know what
are their responsibilities what are the
different touch points in the secure
development life cycle
you have loan style tools there is a
vulnerability management process that
where slas are being appeared and so on
this is this will probably free up some
time from the product security team
that you can use to do some more some
hardening now on application and
services
it's time that in this time you can
start engineering solutions to solve
groups of vulnerabilities i have some
example here and there are only examples
you can work on hardening against xss
or you can do an assessment on what is
your current application logging and
monitoring for different security events
and then see where there is room for
improvements
or the most hot topic of the last years
is supply chain attack how well is your
organization in detecting them in
preventing them what processes do you
have around it and how can you improve
these are just examples but depending on
on the metrics actually you go from your
vulnerability management pro
vulnerability management program you
will see
where you need your focus your
engineering solutions to start hardening
the code and the product
this is mostly what i had to share i
have some some closing remarks
the first one is work on a product
security program iteratively don't focus
on solving one aspect of the program
while leaving the rest unstarted
and also by the iterations
the more you work on the product the
program you the more you realize how you
need to improve so this this iteration
comes a bit naturally
another thing is there is no
one-size-fits-all approach what i shared
today is my lessons and what
i i learned from being in a specific
company with a specific company a
security culture and so on take from
that talk the things that may be
applicable to your the company you work
for
based on the security culture of that
company
and i i've mentioned security culture a
lot and i just want to reiterate
the company culture on security will
affect your journey and will affect how
successful the product security program
is so in every little detail
in every little decision think how how
what you are doing actually improves the
security culture of your company how you
train their their whole organization
that security is not only the security
team's problem but it's a problem of the
whole of the whole um of the whole
organization and actually it's not a
problem it's not a problem it's
something it's part of the engineering
uh workflow
that's all i had to share
thank you very much for for tuning in
and i'm
open for any questions and this is uh
details
okay even that was
brilliant very sort of hard one through
experience thank you you uh
to the viewers and
um
mad
security champions initiative
and team
and then the security champions maintain
the balance demands
this is a great question
uh and again this is you need great
collaboration between engineering
leadership security and security
leadership
there is no there is no right solution
again it depends on your company but i
think if you can get a buy-in from
engineering and security leadership that
x amount of hours per week are assigned
to security tasks
this is
sometimes it will be less or sometimes
it will be more but if on the leadership
level you get an agreement i don't know
three hours per week
or something like that their security
champions are entitled to work on
security features
uh this will this will
this will help because using the program
the problem is security wants security
champions to do more security and
engineering wants their engineers to
actually do feature development so i
think the the most important is having
an agreement on
what is the balance there and what it is
the number it depends on the company
yeah i think that's an interesting point
isn't it you know what kind of where do
you draw the line about i mean we've had
other other speakers today talk about
you know not trying to solve
absolutely every security problem
because it's impossible right you know
the only secure software
the only completely secure software that
you know is one that actually probably
has no code in it so
you know it's uh it's deciding
those things are always about risk
versus versus resource aren't they
exactly yes
i think that was the only question on
the talk um so
thank you
well thank you thank you i don't know
what's going on with your audio sounds
terrible to me maybe is it just me
yes okay it sounds like you're in slow
motion at the minute
let's try disconnecting the audio and
reconnect it again
so thank you very much for joining us
anyway either that was uh that was a
really good talk i i very much enjoyed
it um hopefully you'll stick around for
the the remainder of the content
um today
yes thank you for having me here i
really enjoyed it pleasure
[Music]