[Music]
now um ashish will be co-hosting with me
we did have vandana before doing and
thank you so much vandana for cohes
hosting with me all this while um we do
have steve now with us as well and i'll
bring him on and steve hi steve
it's chief wow camera quality is amazing
man what do you have like an slr
oh you're mute i think you're a perfect
uh rookie mistake i just spoke about
hybrid remote and you just about the
rookie mistake of having yourself on
mute i started off the thing with being
on mute so i think i've already like
popped that
[Music]
yes yes i have an okay i have an okay
camera
it looks like i'm okay looking through a
glass man i don't know how it's an okay
camera
no
i like to stay you know quite clear and
uh steve you're talking about pointing
the ci workflow and how to prevent it um
so if you're ready to go we might give
the stage to you and let people hear
about your talk i'm ready to roll
amazing good luck thank you i'm gonna
need it a lot of moving parts
all right uh let's go some great talks
wow uh she's always very difficult to
follow um but i'm gonna do my best i
haven't got a dog in the room but i will
i don't know maybe bark myself a little
bit if somebody comes nearby
this is uh pointing the ci the get up
action edition uh welcome my name is
steve jager
uh let's let's do the obligatory a
little bit about me
uh i'm a developer advocate for bridge
crew i've been writing code since uh
actually should be 80. that's even more
embarrassing
i i was involved in quality automation
which is an automotive oddly we're very
uh very gene kim
and i've been doing cyber security since
2014 working for a bunch of companies
i have i am co-organizer of the
devsecops and gathering in london of all
places what a surprise
i have a cloud native security twitch
show called c9k and i have huge jet lag
and a cold because i just spent a few
weeks in canada seeing my family i'm
based in england so i feel awesome right
now if you like to connect to me and you
just like to randomly click qr codes
we'll do a whole other talk about that
but there it is there
all right brief agenda just talking
about what github actions are what could
possibly go wrong different threats
different
styles of insiders
and the attack factors associated with
that and then a little bit about
prevention so that we have some
takeaways here today
github action workflows a lot of the
github actions contents i'm putting in
here i'm taking straight out of their
documentation because i don't want to
misquote and i think it's important that
people get familiar with the
documentation that is available and this
is a quote directly
from there
they are
workflows are defined in the dot github
slash workflows directory and repository
and you can have multiple workflows they
can do a whole bunch of things and the
examples that they provide already are
for example a workflow to build and test
pull requests deploy your application or
maybe add a label every time someone
opens a new issue these are just some
examples that you can do
very simple example here again straight
out of the docs
just to break down what it looks like
written here in yaml
on an event of type push
then certain steps will run and you can
see it will run on a runner it can be a
github-provided runner or it can be a
self-hosted runner and we'll get into
that why that can be considerably more
dangerous should any of these things i'm
about to do become realized in your
repository
so you can check it out install
run and etc etc there's a whole load of
things you can do with them very very
straightforward
the fundamental problem we're coming up
with here is that
github can and often will run new
workflows in the github workflow path
even if those workflows are the commit
metadata issues like issue name issue
description that are associated and
maybe
visible to workflows
are often used as unsanitized inputs in
a very sort of traditional app set kind
of way
and finally the workflow directory
shares the same access controls as the
entire repository by default there are
ways you can mitigate that risk and
we'll talk a little bit more about that
in a moment and in reality this is not
your ideal scenario is it there's a lot
of power in that workflow directory
now a few github action attack vectors
okay well we've got the three different
categories there adding a label build
and test deploy your application
well what if i were to try dixie to
execute a command
injection via the creating a new issue
perhaps i could well we'll see what we
could do
no spoilers
a workflow to build and test pull
requests i could push a new workflow
using the github api to bypass the
required minimum approval
okay
or pardon me a workflow to deploy your
new application well that might mean i
have environment variables that might be
damaging to my particularly if i'm on a
self-hosted runner so what if i tried to
exfiltrate all of my environment
variables maybe and my secrets
what if i were to i don't know could i
create could i create a reverse shell
via a workflow
there's a lot of things i could do given
the right credentials
so here's my attacker's guide this is
probably a really bad slide to have if
there are any attackers viewing
hopefully all defenders
my plan a would be a very simple
external attack i would submit a
workflow i could be new to the
environment
now when that happens we can see over
here on the right
it doesn't automatically run my
workflows there is a button there that
says approve and run now the confusing
thing about that is that unless i click
on this learn more
very subtly here
and i've i will be taken to the
documentation you can see above that
does provide you a warning that says you
should be especially alert to any
proposed changes to the github workflows
directory
but it's not a big red flag with the
sound to tell you
this is a first-time contributor who's
never run anything who's submitting
something to the workflows directory
that is
a let's say indicator of compromise kind
of thing it's bad
but the reality is that a lot of your
workflows are there to check
code content so there's a lot of
potentially security checks in there and
you why your instinct might be to click
approve and run why wouldn't i want that
i want to check this content so if
you're not careful and you do just click
that
bad things can happen
the second of course is plan b if you're
not going to be so bold
become a malicious insider submit some
good first-time contributions maybe a
read me maybe maybe some actual helpful
approval helpful workflows
to an environment being a force for good
and then attempt to become a
collaborator where what you can do
radically changes
what's interesting is that they're the
the github defaults are pretty good like
github is very securable it's a little
bit like the cloud but it's not
necessarily secure by default i think
that's one of the key takeaways here and
what we're going to try and learn from
this talk
all right
now here's an example this is a real
world non-fiction example
of what happened in our actual
environment i work on an open source
project regularly called chekov
and
we had a pull request you can see it's
closed
called build.yaml
and
this is what it looked like
they had i'm thinking we our conclusion
is that this was somebody else's account
takeover and this was a bot that came in
it deleted our entire build workflow
and changed it to
and you can see we run on self-hosted
right so this is bad if this had
happened it just ran a ps and an end
and that was going to the results of
which would be in our logs which could
have been bad exposing all sorts of
things to
our github blogs that this person could
then read now this came in and the
proven run was there and we did not
click the improvement run it was so
blatant it was ridiculous but
this was out there this really did
happen not that long ago
all right
now we're going to do number one and in
order to do that though i need to
introduce you to the characters involved
in this in this story
there is
a
webhook receiving site this is
webhack.site if you don't use this in
demos or for debugging it's amazing just
recreate just creates a receiver for api
calls
i have this malicious character called
loud canadian
and over here i have steve g who has
created
a repository
very simple there's nothing nothing
really in it it's brand new
and it's just a readme
and i have a default this is the default
if you just create an action and it says
what's the basic one that you have
created
that they give you just so i have a
workflow directory created that's all
i've done i haven't created i haven't
created anything special else in here
super super simple
and now
i'm over here i'm as loud canadian the
trusted
everyone trusts canadians right
so i'm looking at this and you're okay
all right great so what i'm going to do
is i'm going to fork that so i have a
copy of it in my own world
and i can start to create contributions
to it
wonderful how about that right
so what i'm going to do is i'm going to
create a workflow
actually and we'll see all those things
i just said play out
and i have my workflows directory
looks pretty good i'm going to add a
file
enter here and it's called issues
check.yaml
looking
good so far
so i'm being helpful to this repository
i'm a good person
you know i am
any open issue it's going to check the
title to make sure it adheres to a
certain format
i like it
i'm going to commit to my main
yeah
this is just locally at the moment right
you understand that
looking pretty good at one commit ahead
of your gig main
seems pretty good i'm gonna create a
pull request back across
fantastic
looks good i should have a pull request
over here now
now remember what we saw earlier the
approve and run there it is because i'm
not i'm not a contributor anymore so
this is good now i'm also committing a
workflow that will not trigger because
only triggers on new issues
i can go back and check the files
changed and i can say oh yeah i like
that i like that this person is helping
me
i'm okay with that
and so that's not a big problem i could
approve and run
because i do want my checks to run
and you can see that default one run all
it does is print out readmes
and it's
it's okay i know i can i can confirm and
merge this it's not gonna be a problem i
can go look at my actions here
and see that it's
in progress it all passed
i'm a bit now euro gig is a big fan of
uh loud canadian so
we're going to merge that
because they are so helpful wow thank
you loud canadian
i don't have any special privileges here
nothing nothing at all
and so what i'm going to do now is i'm
going to create an issue
maybe i get my friend my friend to
create the issue
and my issue is going to be called now
before i do this let's just
well now i'm going to do this now
we're going to go ahead first we already
started the demo so let's do it live
and my issue title is going to be
extremely readable
there
just a normal issue
okay
that's a crazy title isn't it
now that was a new issue so really
realistically
this action should kick off and there it
is
that's queued up because you know it
doesn't have priority there it is 12
seconds it's in progress it's running i
guess my title was uh was legit
uh oh what's happened over here
what did i do i
i piped an m to a curl and sent it up to
my web hook site and now i have all of
the environment variables i have kind of
accomplished
what that person was trying to
accomplish with us and i've done it
completely as an outsider by sending
something very innocuous in that was
just checking issue titles to make sure
that they were sane i was actually
actively doing input sanitization and
then the process
i
you did something that kind of
circumvented and created my own lack of
input sanitization which is bad
and that's essentially what just
happened now how real is this problem
if you search on github the entirety for
bad things
you see people doing things like this
all the time like there's one example
where somebody is actually generating
a a hugo website based on to show how
well they're handling actions and
creating the post title out of this
github event issue title
now if i were to say create a title that
was
session expired please log in form
action etc etc i can actually when
someone went to look at this title which
was generated through github i could pop
up a mock github login and say you were
logged out and start
you know getting github credentials bad
what's the other one well
searching other users in metadata found
thousands thousands of examples where
people are doing what like what i just
did i didn't even straight up echo i
just copied my issue title into
a variable but because it was in quotes
and i used those back ticks
it reconciled the meaning of that
backstage command because it's still
running in bash and it then
my quote became all my environment
variables
and then i was able to push that out to
an external source
so
lesson one
input sanitization be careful what you
do with this metadata it's really
important
we already gave it a try so we can skip
now what can you do with environment
variables wow wow on a private runner
there can be cloud or aws sequences
available secrets available passwords
and connection strings i can change
logging level and by that gain access to
sensitive data and logs all sorts of
things that can be on there i can
potentially gain access to the get up
token and enable code modifications
there's loads of things i can do by
by getting access to
a self-hosted runner in particular
how can i protect environment variables
well here's a little dowel into
prevention there is something called
environment protection rules that in a
summary this is again cut and pasted
from the github docs and there's a link
down there it's really long but i have
it again at the end um you can scope
environmental enviro the environment
variables and the secrets to certain
workflows so a new workflow wouldn't
have access to all of this
particularly so only production state
would have access to production details
so
this is your this is how you prevent
something like this from happening and
the information is just there
and but
more often than not these aren't in
place by default and it takes a more
astute security team and knowledge of
github to make sure that this is done
appropriately
all right hack number two now hack
number two i'm only going to do in
combination with three in the interest
of time
but just to give you an idea
and introducing branch protection rules
branch prediction rules are off by
default
uh there are a lot of tools you can
automate to check that they are turned
on and we'll talk about that at the end
but when you first turn them on
there are some great defaults there
uh defaults or when they're on of course
uh can be good but can be not
necessarily
perfect like for example
when i first turn on my branch
protection and i took require a pull
request before merging sounds awesome it
says require approvals great i turn that
on
the important thing to notice there is
that there's a really subtle one there
you really ideally want that to be two
or
use what we call a code owner's file and
github and i'll talk about that a little
bit more later
but that's not that's a very uh
circumventable number and we'll see why
if i want to submit a pull request to
the new workflow
it's possible if i'm a collaborator that
the github token gives me enough access
to auto approve myself and this is just
a quick example of what that looks like
now i'll show you what that means in a
moment but
something that's key there is i need to
be a collaborator
caveat as of earlier early 2022 now this
happened while i was creating this
presentation
the settings within github changed
for a particular repo and it's worth
noting this
so
if you look under the github action
permissions for workflows there is now
three tick boxes
read repository now this example i have
right here is the correct
example this is how new repos tend to
get created by default
but any repo that was created prior to
around april 2022 doesn't look like this
instead it looks like this
because this
is legacy this is the what the
permissions were before april and that
is probably still 99 of all repos out
there still have this setting these
settings set up which means a github
token
does have the ability to read read and
write permissions and does have the
ability to create and approve pull
requests
so that because that was the default and
this was some research i think it was
created i want to say cyber security but
i might be wrong there but they did some
research and found this and disclosed it
and they changed this but that does mean
that the default is still wrong
all right so this is hack number three
pointing the runner and this will
include the approval
so what can i do with a github token
a lot
based on the permissions and the
timeouts available let's talk a little
bit about the timeouts a github token
lasts for a maximum of 24 hours okay
that's a lot of power for a lot of time
what usage limits how long does a github
action job last so that would indicate
another limitation well the job can last
up to six hours
i can get a lot done in six hours if i
have a token
how can i get that token
and what permissions do i have this is a
confusing part of the github
documentation i find a little bit
because
the default access there's two defaults
restricted and permissive now restricted
is what i had permissive is kind of what
i want
and the final warning is that if you
look in the documentation about github
action get up tokens if you don't have
the permissions you want the suggestion
they give you is to create a personal
access token and save it as a secret
that might have
a lot more permissions
and what if i can exfiltrate secrets
well then
i kind of can potentially get the keys
to the kingdom there
all right so here's an example workflow
that i'm going to use in a moment and
it's a little it's a little zoomed out
so let me just zoom in a little bit on
this little bit right here
what i'm going to do now is i'm going to
echo the secrets into a file and i'm
going to push those secrets out to my
bad url and then i'm going to do my
environment variable one same thing i
did with the issues so i have all my
environment variables so now my secrets
and all my environment variables if this
works
already sounds bad doesn't it
the hacker scenario around this and this
is this is a real possibility based on
just looking around github now i hope i
articulate this properly
the reality is if i'm a baddie
i'm i went looking for
um site or actions that insist you make
a personal access token
i found one that was called i think was
called auto merge plus plus i may have
changed the name to protect the innocent
and
its instructions were to create a
personal access token with auto merge
for auto merge so it had the ability to
merge prs
which sounds pretty powerful and it is
so what could i have done there well i
could have become a part of that so that
i could you know just almost like what i
did push or read me do some good work
get access
such that i can
become a collaborator on that project
you probably think this sounds like a
lot of work it is it's
perhaps far-fetched to an extent but
it's still possible
and i can then submit a workflow then if
i could do it right can exfiltrate that
secret once i have the access token i
can now submit code that i can merge
myself
if i can merge my own code
then i can that once that code is in i
can start pushing that code at scale to
other people and the example i found was
was a company that used the auto merge
to create further github actions
that were then used at scale so
what you end up here with is a very
traditional not traditional but a
serious supply chain attack where i'm
able to manipulate code based on a token
that can auto merge prs that will be
then create code that will be used by
other people complicated but
maybe i need to rethink that diagram if
that wasn't clear
um once again we have the a way to
protect environment variables and
secrets
and so here's what i could do i could
pause
and give myself access to that token to
do things
or if i wanted to be a little bit even
more mean i could do something like this
which is
a reverse shell
okay
let's try it now some things i need to
do beforehand is let's assume i've been
a good a good boy and i've not
automatically tried to create an issue
that exfiltrated secrets
i'm
and
thanks to good behavior
i have been added as collaborator so i
need to do that and go in here and say
all right
i really like this loud canadian
i'm going to make him a contributor
there we go
which is going to change what i can do
and how powerful my workflows are
we can see that i've been invited to
collaborate i have to agree i went to
this presentation where i forgot to
click accept and it really does make a
massive difference now i can get back
here what i'm also going to do
is the preventative measures that i just
showed you
i'm going to add my branch protection
main oops
i'm going to require there we go
now i mentioned code owners
we should do code owners but i'm not
going to do it this time but here we
have one merge now you can see here this
is branch protections are absolutely
essential all require status checks
include administrators these are all the
things i should do
don't take these but what's interesting
about allow force pushes is that unless
you have
a branch protection rule you can do a
force push so there's a lot of important
things or defaults that are really
effective so we're going to create that
excellence
and we're going to go down remember
those workflow permissions i was talking
about you can see i've got read write
and i have i can create and approve so
everything is
set up
for my attacker now and but i do have
branch protection on so here's what's
going to happen
let's
do a few things one
i'm over here waiting
and i'm going to
listen on my remote command and control
center let's call it this kind of big
finish i hope it works i have five
minutes
i'm going to create a new file
it's going to call it called
really obvious pawn.yaml
okay ducks
let us i'm not going to type it all out
because it's way too long
there we go
looks lovely now we can see i've got the
approved thing i just put on the screen
i've got a few baddies down here as well
and you can see look i've got branch
protection on so that looks good i'm
going to create a new branch
i'm committing back i'm going to propose
this new file
and create a pull request
let's look at it through the eyes of our
receiver here now
now review is required that's awesome
and you can see it's cued it's going to
run my workflow because remember i
already got past that hurdle
oh look my changes are approved
hey fantastic who approved that the
action bot that was step one
uh oh
i have a shell on my runner all bad i
wonder what's happened over here
i have my github token i have my
postgres password
my aws key oh boy that's not good and i
have all my environment variables off
one workflow it didn't take me long to
get there did it
now there's a sequence in the interest
of time there's a sequence of things i
could do over here
to really create a whole load of other
problems
for example
i can run i get fetch
i can see my new branch
and
i i could
do a bunch of kind of really bad things
over here
um
that can change the state of what's
happening over here
now i'm not going to quite do that
well maybe i will but i can what what i
can do is i can delete the entire i have
enough credentials over here to delete
the pull request
and make it so that the progress is just
completely gone now realize i only have
two minutes left
so i'm going to progress with the
lessons learned here
um i just had way too much credential on
that and the end result would be i would
have persistence on the runner
and yet the pull request would be
deleted now you can imagine how much how
bad that would look
i could run a reverse shell and
potentially while self-concealing how i
did it i could even i could even do a
new commit that deletes
what i previously created so i could
delete the phone file i could delete
everything
and
i could make it look like it would have
somebody else did it
so ounces of prevention
be careful when adding contributors turn
on branch protection do not run
workflows only 100 sure use environment
protection do not add permissive tokens
and some nice to haves
single sign-on
uh scan your rift container images
and use events to log activity and i
mentioned the code owners file what i
really should have done is i should have
had a code owner's file in the github
directory that said only certain people
can approve workflows that changes the r
back essentially
automating your security is two ways to
do it i think that i really i'm a big
fan of one is using the open ssf
scorecard that has checks to make sure
branch protection is turned on it looks
for some of the things i did in terms of
dangerous patterns for workflows
and it also has checks to see you have
more than one person
as part of your organization as
contributors
and of course the project i work on
chekhov also does scans for exactly the
sort of things i was doing it's looking
for reverse shells it's looking for
exfiltration of secrets it's looking for
curl commands it's looking for all the
every bad thing i did could be prevented
by running a checkout scan on your
workflow prior to checking it in or upon
arrival
i'm out of time so we won't try that but
the key takeaways here are
design takes a lot of work defaults
aren't secure
use automation for security
and i'll stop there i almost got it done
in time
great job steve now i know how to hack
positive
that was a really really good finish to
um devsecond24 just seeing things live
is always a really good like it's a good
way to learn and uh kudos to anyone who
does it because like there's so much
that can go wrong in a demo so you were
very calm throughout it and it looked
like it all worked perfectly
right
yeah you can compare that sweat now
which is very clear on your uh
camera
definitely i agree it was amazing
especially oh canadians you're amazing
canadians you're amazing and the way you
were flowing through it was so amazing
totally love the energy
thank you thank you i do my best
yeah she just tries his best and turns
out to be the best is probably uh
starting a new standard pretty awesome
and uh thanks for uh finishing up as
well it's really great to have you no
worries thank you so much for joining us
cheers thank you
thanks steve
[Music]