[Music]
so um
uh looking forward to hearing from uh
aqua um from mr siemersing and
we'll be hearing about cloud native
incident response so how we automate the
many different and good afternoon
wherever you are
good morning for me it's uh 6 a.m i'm in
canada right now
thank you for getting up out of bed
early to join us
very much would you like to share your
screen sir i'll get you uh
all in the uh
ready to go
there we go
just gonna make it bigger
all right can you folks see um the big
presentation
uh i think we can oh it's just it's
redrawing extreme slowly at the minute
for some reason there we go
got there in the end fantastic so the
floor is yours
all right um
uh hi this is samar um i work at aqua
and i'll be talking about
how you can automate incidence response
with
possible climative risks
um
i was just listening to the last
presentation and then it was great to
hear that security is a
people's problem first and you know not
a type problem uh
that was that was great to hear um so
i'll just be adding on that a little bit
today
um so this
brief agenda for today's talk will be
you know some patterns that we see um
challenges with those and
some solutions that i have and a quick
demo
um so we've all heard um or overheard in
the office or wherever you are
that security is a requirement and not
an option
um
and for that you know we always
end up running multiple scanning
solutions these are just some of them to
list but then you also in the morning
wake up with this
mailbox full of notifications um
and then you start to realize what you
signed up for
um so alert fatigue is real
nobody wants to see this everyone wants
to strike friend doctor at least i do
um and this was um
very well documented and basically god
people could um
all know this better than anyone else
and they came up with some really good
recommendations for
what makes
a good alert
and some of them i'll just summarize
are
a good alert let's say you're in the
midnight um
start a minute and you just wake up with
the page um should be actionable you
should be able to know what to do with
it
um it should be descriptive but most
importantly should go to the right
people you don't want to get a page for
something that you have no control over
or you don't want to do
but what makes
an ideal alert would be
all that
plus
if it was automated and now
there are many definitions and
people go um
you know
various
definitions of like what it needs to be
automated
some call it self-healing some call it
self-resolving automated playbooks
whatever you might call it but ideally
the alert
should know what to do um when it comes
or at least have a course of action
before a humor operator gets involved
because as you all know human
time is expensive
and some of these alerts can get
repetitive especially if they
are known to the person
before it happened
um so the title of my talk sort of
posted is actually an acronym which
you know stands for security
orchestration automation response
um so for this talk i'll be focusing on
the automation and the response piece of
uh posty
and what you can do um today uh with it
so without further ado i like to
introduce
um what is posty uh posty is essentially
a message routing system so it takes
messages from
one producer
operates over them and then
sends it out to uh
to a different consumer
or a place that's listing for them it is
policy based so we use rego
um
to basically design our value
for for all the messages that come in so
you can write your own policies
depending on how you want these messages
to risky rabbit
and most importantly uh we are
there is enforcement on alerts that you
get
um so you can essentially have what we
call post actions depending on where you
want to do them
so i'll give some of those examples
today and we'll see a few demos of that
as well
so
this is a high level overview um
you know
uh don't uh
don't be worried if you you know can't
understand the details but essentially
there are three parts to closely versus
the input
which is essentially
where all the production of messages
happens so this could be any producer or
messages could be
your
monitoring out could be your application
itself could be anything
um and then the second is the process
which is supposed to itself so this is
where your um
policy based running comes in um
messages are sent
uh they're templated um out before
they're sent to external applications
and basically the whole engine um the
policy engine lives uh within this
process
and the last um
bit is execution so where the messages
are actually sent out
um
from positive to other applications
so
we uh we wanted this um experience of
using postdb as seamless as possible
with our existing um apps so
trivia is a vulnerability scanner that
you can use today to scan
a bunch of images
um or or other artifacts and trace these
runtime protection um scanner that you
can
set up in on your machine and
and have uh runtime alerts come to you
so today uh hostie and tracy um
and hosting work seamlessly together and
that's not to say that these are the
only things that work together
these are just one of the examples i'll
be giving today um to showcase how
closely can help you automate um the
risks that you have
so you can have any producer again um
and then post the and that producer can
talk over a bed hook and work alongside
each other
so for example postie and tracy um can
work like this so tracy as i mentioned
runs on the host
it basically monitors for
any runtime alerts that you may have
while
you're using your system or your node
and tracy will basically observe this
behavior using evpf uh technology and
then generate an event and send it out
to a consumer like fosee
so postie gets that
and then this is where the enforcement
or the post the actions happen where
postie again
you can tell posty what to do when a
certain kind of event happens so
for instance you can have
a process be terminated if it's doing
malicious activity for example um and
postie can enforce that
on the node after it receives the event
from crazy
so
very quick demo um
on the right side of the screen you can
see the configuration of posty it's
basically a yama file you can configure
with certain rules so the input that you
see there is actually a regular policy
it's a very simple regular policy that
looks for
a certain signature
and i'm going to start
posty and it's going to start listening
for requests
in the middle i'll start tracy which is
basically remaining as a docker
container and then i'm going to specify
the output to go into webhook
which is developer where is
listening
so then tracy's gonna start up it's
gonna start looking at stuff um
and this is just a test um instant so
right away you can see that there was um
you know the kubernetes service account
was accessed
and then posted took that and send it
over to a webhook because that was one
of the um
outputs that we configured closely to do
so you can see all the historical
events that have come in in the past as
well this is just
a way to look at them and this is the
um the actual output of the
tracy event that has come in so these
are all the details of the producer that
has sent us in this case tracy and
kosti has forwarded them to their books
so that's one
um
we're just having some problems with
your screen not updating um can you just
try uh unsharing and re-sharing again
okay
if that fixes it i just didn't want to
uh
need to um carry on
just super slow updating for some reason
he said um
do you want to try sharing it and if i
just remove it from there and
unshare and reach it
otherwise we may well just have to
accept it but
um
try i tried resharing right now
okay
i'm not sure it's whether it's your
connection or whether it's powerpoint or
yeah it's still super slow updating
yeah it's uh
that's unfortunate um
i'm trying to see where what my screen
is showing right now uh in the presenter
plane
yeah it is really slow i can see that
see
um
let me see if i could try something else
really quickly here one second
[Music]
sorry about that um
oh
i'll try to share this lights
um
screaming already that will help
[Music]
it will not let me because of
size is more than 50 megabytes that's
unfortunate
okay uh
i'll try to see what i can do here
so it did seem to work whenever
something was updating so i don't know
whether you can bring the terminal
window up and just drag it around so it
senses the refresh try that
okay um
yeah i think i'll just go
yeah every time i change the slides
for some reason it's very slow to update
um
yeah
not sure what's going on um
[Music]
try different screen maybe
is that any better i
i'm not sure like is it
is it updating better now uh
than before
yeah it seems to be a lot better um i
don't want to be like the window
okay um
all right well
i'll uh
i'll say we'll be here well we can um so
um i'll just uh start at this slide um
uh i was saying posty and tracing work
together um and then
uh
just one of the producers that
tracy
tracy is just one of the producers i
post you can use um
tracy is powered by the pf it can
generate events when it's his malicious
behavior these events can be sent to
um posty and then
post you can act upon them um
in in any way so for example
if you tell posty to
terminate any process that
is malicious that is observed by tracy
you can do that
or
you know other things as well
um
in the interest of time i'll skip over
and
talk about trivia and posty so trevi is
a vulnerability scanner that can
scan your images other artifacts um
and then these reports that triggy and
this outfit that trivia has can be
uh sent to posty um and then post you
can take actions like
you know if the base image is vulnerable
it can update that um
if you want to remove that image
altogether from your cluster you can do
that as well so essentially it's
it's all in your hands um what actions
um
so this is where you know the automation
piece um uh happens uh for
for posty so um if there's thing if
there are things that um you know happen
very often like for example you think
that you scan
images often
um
[Music]
and then you expect them to be
vulnerable
you know as vulnerabilities happen over
time one common action could be you know
update that image that is vulnerable
um or
you know issue a jar ticket for for
instance um we have several integrations
for posty that come out of the box
um
for example sending messages in slack
um or microsoft teams or creating a
jared ticket
or you know any web hook that might be
listening um so some of those i was
gonna demo um
in in the in the slides today
um of how you can basically um
take an event create a jar ticket out of
it so that the operator can come
tomorrow morning and doesn't have to be
open up in the night
to to handle the alert so you know you
can create a ticket they can come take a
look at tomorrow morning and
act appropriately so the scan results
for instance can be sent as a content as
the content of a jared ticket
to jira and you know you can take a look
at
uh what happened when you were trying to
scan that
um
so
in the interest of time um
let me just quickly check how much is
left
well i'm already past it so uh
you know these projects that i mentioned
today are all open source um opposed to
each facing trivia
uh we welcome your contributions um and
we you know look forward to hearing from
you if you have any
ideas or
if there are integrations that you like
to build um as i mentioned postie
works with
anything any producer um it just listens
on a web book so
anything that any producer wants to send
here they can handle
um and that's about it um thank you for
for listening and sorry about the show
um
thanks for that so i'm sorry about the
technical problems there we'll get one
of the team to uh to reach out to you
and maybe we can uh we can record your
your talk again uh so that we can get it
on youtube with the demos and stuff uh
in it i know
i was super interested in uh in all
those projects so i would like to see it
in its full glory but uh thank you so
much for joining us i know it's been an
early start for you but uh well i'll get
one on the team to reach out to you
behind the scenes and we'll see if we
can get that that talk
thank you for having me
[Music]