hey everyone and welcome to my talk
today in order to have future foresights
it requires that we look back at events
that have already taken place and that
is what i'll be doing in my talk today
i'll be presenting a retrospective of
2021 and do some analysis and insights
of some of the major security news and
events that have taken place over the
past year just a quick introduction
about myself i'm a cloud architect i
specialize in security and enterprise
cloud architecture and i help large
organizations adopt aws my research
interests include privacy surveillance
encryption and disinformation and i'm
also involved in policy advocacy work on
these topics as they relate to national
security interests i'm also a bit of a
aerospace nerd my twitter handle is at
jared nordia and my blog is at
criticalvoid.com
in my talk today i'm going to be talking
about the year of the supply chain 2021
has really been the year of the supply
chain with many supply chain issues as
well as supply chain attacks i'll also
be talking about some other issues for
example about the apple csam debacle
disinformation the cybersecurity review
board ransomware trends as well as
the software bull of materials as well
2021 was really a challenging year for
the supply chain
fire drought geopolitics and the
pandemic really stretch the supply
chains to their breaking points and
there is a worldwide shortage of rubber
lumber a specific type of chlorine due
to a massif fire at a production
facility
a shortage of semiconductors and chips
which have
had a massive impact in the automotive
industry as well as in the shipping
and transportation industry as well
where there isn't enough containers as
well as very long wait times at the
various ports obviously we all had a
joke at the ever given that got stuck in
the service canal but really the big
challenge here is that due to the
pandemic consumer spending has shifted
away from services to consumer goods
which has created a massive
demand for these consumer goods
texas also had a massive issue earlier
this year where they were not able to
meet the electricity's
demand
with the supply due to cold weather and
they were actually four minutes away
from experiencing a total grid collapse
in the digital world we had a number of
supply chain attacks and probably one of
the largest supply chain attacks that
ever took place against solarwinds which
really started out with the fire eye
breach in december of last year firearm
detected a malicious activity on its
network a user account that had newly
registered
mfa device
which was also used as a secondary
device triggered an initial alert which
then triggered a massive investigation
to kick off firearm knew immediately
that a nation-state actor was behind
this breach due to the crack tradecraft
that was being used during this
investigation
farah honed in on the solar winds
deployment and they reversed engineered
the code to actually find 4 000
lines of malicious code that was added
into solarwinds
for those of you that are not familiar
solarwinds is a item service
platform that provides remote management
and monitoring as well as some other
features
for it service management and due to its
specific function it actually requires
privileged access to some of these
systems in order for it to work
the main issue with the solar wind
supply chain attack was that in the cicd
system when they released software one
of the components was a jenkins machine
which was exposed to the internet with
the password of
adversaries were able to
break into that jenkins machine and then
able to add malicious code
which would create c2 channels as well
as web shells on victim infrastructure
from a timeline perspective in august
2019 the initial command and control
setup was done in october 2019 a dry run
of the attack took place and in december
2019 the first payload with cobbled
struck was actually detected a lot of
commentary has been made in the
community about the fact that they were
using a cobalt truck given that a cob a
lot of security tools can actually
detect cobalt struck and it would seem a
bit unintuitive to actually use cobble
truck in an attack of this nature
malware known as sunburst was actually
then injected into the orion platform in
february of 2020 and in march of 2020
the first sound backdoor version of the
solarwinds platform was actually
released to customers who received it
through an update process
at the end of december
fire
announced that they had been a victim of
a nation-state attack
fire disclosed the supply chain attack
to solarwinds who thereafter then
notified the customers as well as filed
the sec statement
for their shareholders
what's very interesting uh
the finger was pointed at this being a
russian operation very quickly however
president trump at the time uh insisted
that this was a chinese attack and
rather than a russian attack and at the
end of december to 2020 uh microsoft
actually announced that some of its
source code had actually been breached
as part of this
and as the new year started so that
would be the beginning of this year
a lot of people started realizing that
this was going to be a fairly
significant breach and a joint statement
by the fbi caesar
the national intelligence office as well
as the nsa really alerted people to this
significant breach
in terms of impact
this attack allowed adversaries to get
access to microsoft source code as well
as to the saml signing tokens for 40
companies which allow attackers to log
into services and infrastructure
directly without mfa
in most cases when you log into
something with saml that's typically
done by some kind of identity platform
and by having those keys you effectively
can bypass that
infrastructure which would also then
enforce mfa in the process the access
gained by the adversaries allowed them
to move laterally in the customer
environments of microsoft customers as
well and 30 percent of the private and
government businesses affected by the
breach had no known link to solarwinds
a number of u.s agencies were affected
by the breach and up to
000 private and public entities were
directly affected by the supply chain
breach
microsoft president brad smith was
ordered to testify in front of congress
and he was actually grilled about
microsoft's licensing policies where a
lot of logging features for example are
not available on the lower tier plans
this is one of i think microsoft's big
failures from a licensing perspective
and on the side notes i think
you know if you compare this to aws for
example this is one area where aws
actually does really well actually
another supply chain attack that we
learned of is a code cov which is a code
coverage tool adversaries were able to
use a vulnerability to gain access to a
vulnerable docker container where they
were able to change the ip address of a
specific configuration file which
allowed them to pull sensitive
environment variables out of codecov's
customers which included a number of big
names including hashicorp the
washingtonpostmonday.com
and uber
some companies had limited exposure for
example hashicorp only had its bgp
key exposed whereas other companies had
more sensitive credentials exposed
another interesting supply chain attack
was that on cassette vsa cassette vsa is
a remote monitoring and management tool
primarily used by msps to manage
customer networks a vulnerability
allowed an authentication bypass on the
platform where attackers could install
malware on the hosts managed by the
specific
platform affected systems were encrypted
with ransomware from the revo group and
the revo group claimed that over a
million systems were actually infected
where
this was actually disputed by cassaya
they said that between 800 and one and a
half thousand systems were actually
impacted
one of the most notable impacts was a
swedish
retailer called coop
800 stores had to close down due to
their payment systems not being
available and this actually had an
impact on the food supply chain in some
small villages where coop was the only
retailer
a food retailer in that area another
interesting attack
was on travis ci a vulnerability in
travis cr allowed environment variables
to be exposed during the build phase
this meant that open source code
could be used to actually retrieve
environment variables of systems using
travis ci and to make this even worse
travis here i actually tried to hide
this from their customers
once it was actually disclosed to them
which i think is completely unacceptable
the next attack was against the linux
kernel
an assistant professor at the university
of minnesota
actually tried to fix real bugs in the
linux kernel but in the process of doing
so also intentionally introduced new
security flaws as part of a research
project
this led to the university of minnesota
getting banned from the development on
the linux kernel as the open source
community found that this behavior was
completely unethical
one of the other interesting things from
a supply chain perspective was
compromised packages so there have been
a very large number of new
uh mpm packages registered i think after
the solarwinds breach everybody wanted
to get into the
supply chain attack and you can see on
the right hand side there how many new
npm packages were actually registered at
the beginning of this year following the
solomon's breach and what attackers
would do is they would use compromised
repositories and accounts to add
malicious code to popular npm packages
and those included uipulsa rc coa and
web browser file which together have
over 30 million downloads per week
tapas squatting was
also on the increase this year with over
3 600 packages on pop pi with similar
names that also contained malicious code
another interesting discovery made
earlier this year was this issue of
dependency confusion this is a risk
where ides and package managers are
unsure whether to
fetch a package from an internal
repository or external repository so
you could tell
a system to go get a specific package
and if it fetched the wrong one for
example from an outside source you could
actually introduce
malicious code into the system by doing
so
a researcher actually managed to do this
into apple microsoft and dozens of other
companies
some other notable supply chain attacks
that have taken place in the post an
attacker distributed a version of xcode
which was backdoored and what it would
do is whenever new ios applications were
created it would actually inject this
malicious code into the ios
app that xcode then created this
resulted in thousands of compromised
apps on the ios app store in march 2016
a popular open source bittorrent client
trans
mission was compromised to include mac
os ransomware in its installer
in june 2017
the not picture malware was actually
spread through a breach at a ukrainian
software company
and this then turned into a wormable
exploit that did spread worldwide
and affected many organizations in the
process
and a few months later avast sea cleaner
tool was also
compromised and used to attack large
technology and communications companies
worldwide another interesting supply
chain attack which was actually not done
by malicious actors but rather by law
enforcement the fbi actually managed to
shut down
and arrest the uh operations team of
incra chat and phantom secure these are
platforms used by the underworld to
for drug trafficking as well as other
nefarious activities and
after the fbi did this they realized
that there would be a massive
hole left in the underground market for
a secure messaging platform and they had
this brilliant idea of creating their
own backdoor
secure messaging platform that they
would want to share with all of uh their
members of the underground so that's
exactly what they did they teamed up
with the
australian federal police and europol
to basically set up a bunch of secure
backdoor phones and they then created a
new service called the nom
that was only available on purchase
devices they already used the trust
networks that were already
presence in the underworld and
they ensured that the the system was
only invite only and they used
influencers in the underground to
basically spread these devices around
and the scarcity uh made people believe
that this platform was actually really
secure
what they also did is they used a clever
cryptography so that
the messages were into end encrypted but
they had the master key so that they
could intercept and decrypt all of the
messages as they were being sent around
the world and the fbi let the service
run from eight to 2018 to 2021
and during this period uh 200 million
messages were intercepted from 11 800
devices in over 90 countries
and yes a map you can see uh law
enforcement agencies in north america
europe and australia and new zealand
were involved in this operation
when arrests started to take place they
seized a large amount of currency as
well as phones you can see a specific
you know drug trafficking arrangement
taking place here they also then went uh
to seize the drugs that were being
currently trafficked
and you can see a number of interesting
containers
as this occurred
more than 800 suspects were arrested and
more than 40 tons of drugs were actually
seized as part of this operation as well
as 250 firearms were seized
one notable thing about this is that the
fbi routinely complains that they are
going dark due to encryption but one
thing we can actually take away from
this is that actually these initiatives
allow law enforcement you know to go
after their targets without requiring uh
back doors in our
on our phones
moving on to ransomware
over the past few years ransomware has
really exploded in both the number of
victims as well as the amount of money
paid to ransomware groups
the infection mechanisms have changed
somewhat in the past that was always a
system compromise whereas today phishing
as well as software vulnerabilities are
becoming the primary entry point for
ransomware the internet crime sensor has
actually noticed a 62 increase in
reporting of ransomware tax
on the first based on the first half of
the year compared to the previous year
and you can also see some of the common
variants that are affecting people
around the world
one thing that people don't often note
is how organized these ransomware groups
actually are they actually have
affiliate programs that they they market
and this really allows them to scale
appropriately
and
when we start looking at ransomware as a
service um you know many people are not
actually aware that you know there's
actually the ransomware group which
creates the actual malware there's the
affiliates which actually then go
infect and attack people as well as deal
with the operations of of running the
ransomware
and the typically during an attack um
the ransomware group would give an
affiliate
software that has a unique id so that
the ransomware group can actually track
the targets that they are hitting and
when a victim is actually infected with
ransomware they would typically the
victim would pay the affiliate
which would take a 75 to 90 percent cut
of the ransom and the ransomware group
would get a 10 to
25 percent cut of the ransom so
sometimes the ransomware group and
affiliates will actually work together
when they go after a large target
and sometimes the media thinks that both
the ransomware group and the affiliate
is actually one entity when it actually
it's two
completely separate entities and this
can lead to some interesting factual
errors when
they report on these stories
one of the benefits um of having this
affiliate model from a ransomware group
perspective is that they can scale their
business to have multiple affiliates and
therefore
a lot more targets one of the other
things the ransomware group does as well
is that they actually use
master key encryption so that the
ransomware
group has the master key so that when
affiliates go attack victims and if they
were to attack a high profile victim the
the ransomware group would be able to
offer a decryption tool to the victim
bypassing the affiliate in that case
and then many affiliates will actually
use multiple
variants of ransomware from different
groups to try evade detection from law
enforcement as well as some ransomware
groups don't allow affiliates to attack
certain targets so for example some
ransomware groups won't attack hospitals
while others have no problem in doing so
one of the interesting supply chain
attacks from a ransomware perspective
that took place was at the attack
against colonial pipeline
where an unpatched legacy vpn was used
by the dark side ransomware group to
encrypt all of their systems and they
demanded a 4.4 million dollar ransom the
colonial pipeline processes
45 of all of the fuel in the us
and this led to a number of fuel
shortages as
people were holding fuel including some
unintelligent people who
for example this person on the right
hand side of the screen who used the top
inside his pickup truck and then filled
it up
with fuel which is not a very smart
thing to do
after this attack had taken place and
could the colonial pipeline had actually
paid out the ransom um 2.3 million
dollars went to the affiliate and 2.1
million dollars went to the dark side
ransomware group the justice department
was actually able to seize and recover
2.3 million dollars
of the 4.4 million dollar ransom payment
another
large ransomware attack was against jbs
which
is the world's largest meets
processor based in the us and australia
the rival group was behind this and they
demanded an 11 million dollar
ransom
last year i spoke about
somebody that passed away after a
ransomware attack hit a hospital which
actually delayed treatment
and a subsequent investigation actually
turned out that the patient died of
other causes although the ransomware
incident was actually a factor in the
death what came to light this year was
actually
the first death that's actually almost
directly attributable to ransomware
an expectant mother went to a hospital
to deliver
her baby and she was not aware that the
hospital was actually in the process of
recovering from a ransomware
attack the ransomware attack took out
the
rt network that the hospital was using
and this rt network supported vital
monitoring systems that would look at
fetal
vital signs and this was not
communicated back to the nursing staff
who was looking after this mother-to-be
and they were not aware that the baby
was actually distressed as the umbilical
cord was actually wrapped around
the baby's head and this led to severe
brain damage and the baby then passed
away nine months after
birth this came to light this year
because the family is currently suing
the hospital because they argue that had
they known that the hospital was under a
ransomware attack they probably would
have gone to another hospital
the response from the federal government
to ransomware has been quite fierce
the fbi and state department have
offered a reward of 10 million dollars
to the dark side ransomware
group
as well as a separate reward for 10
million dollars for
targeting the leadership of the rival
ransomware group an additional 5 million
dollars for information of of the
affiliates or partners
one of the interesting things that
happened was that
paul nakasoni who's the director of the
nsa and the commander of cyber command
actually spoke at a recent conference
saying that you know in the past the fbi
always dealt with ransomware because it
was criminal activity however when
ransomware starts touching critical
infrastructure it now becomes a national
security issue and if you read between
the lines here what he's actually trying
to say is he actually believes that the
government should actually allow
intelligence agencies around the world
including the nsa to actually go after
these ransomware groups and cyber
command actually took out a bunch of
infrastructure from a number of
ransomware groups including darkside
actually after this event
one of the other things that the
government has done is they've set up a
number of resources including
a website where people can get immediate
help
during an incident
if they need to
they also went after the people behind
the kasaya vsa
breach
one of them has been arrested and the
other one is wanted by the fbi
in the indictment they claimed that
these two
affiliates
they were able to get 6.1 million
dollars from the various attacks that
they were involved in
earlier in may
president joe biden actually signed an
executive order to improve the nation's
cyber security as part of this they
wanted to improve the software supply
chain security as well as incident
response as well as the security posture
in the federal government
in 2018 cesar was actually created but
they realized that they actually need to
go further than that so um the office of
the national cyber director was created
biden hosted a number of tech ceos to
at a security summit to discuss how they
can actually improve cyber security and
when
joe biden actually spoke to vladimir
putin
he actually warned him that russia needs
to take action on these groups
as well
the nsa released kubernetes hardening
guidance as well as
guidance for securing
5g cloud infrastructures they also put
out guidance on how to embrace
a xero trust security model and they
really hope that many u.s government
agencies will actually start migrating
their architecture into a zero trust
model which would have a significant
impact on
the nation's cyber security posture
one of the other initiatives is uh
the creation of a software bill of
materials so the idea behind this is to
manage vulnerabilities to have
software inventory software licensing
and supply chain data as well as
tracking component metadata in
enterprise software and the way that
this would be done is whenever a new
piece of software is released
all of the high level components are
detailed in those documents
what the version is other identifiers
the dependency
relationships and this would effectively
allow these systems to be able to track
when a specific component is actually
vulnerable what other systems could
actually be affected by that
vulnerability
at the security summit uh google
actually
committed to
securing open source so google already
has programs in place to actually
improve the security of open source
software but they've committed a whole
bunch of money to actually take this
even further
one of the big highlights of the
executive order on national security is
the formation of a cyber security safety
review board
and
the purpose of this is really to create
a board that can really investigate
cybersecurity incidents
so when a plane crashes that
is typically investigated by the
national transportation safety board or
the ncsb they're one of the most trusted
government organizations in the world
and their primary purpose is to
investigate transportation accidents
across aviation railroad highways marine
and pipelines and to make safety
recommendations when needed they've
completed over 150 000 accident
investigations and have made 15 000
safety recommendations
to 2400 recipients one of the main goals
of the ncsb is
to determine not just what happened but
why it happened so that it doesn't
happen again
and the ntsb is actually part of a
worldwide
group of agencies that do these kinds of
investigations and a lot of them have
bilateral agreements with one another in
order to
investigate various accidents especially
aviation accidents and we really need
something like the ntsb for cyber
security one of the problems that we
have in cyber security is with that when
breaches take place we often get second
hand or third hand information about
what actually happened and often the
information that is shared is often
actually just the um you know the
indicator of compromise
and or the attack factor but we don't
actually get any information
beyond that
and what we really need is for example
if an attack took place and there was a
monitoring system and the monitoring
system didn't detect it you know why
didn't did it detect it and if it did
detect
it um you know and somebody wasn't
notified what you know why wasn't that
the case and we really need to get
visibility into these kinds of failures
if we want to move forward as a cyber
security
community
these kinds of investigations exist in
many industries
but until we actually get a really
concrete solution for cyber security and
we're going to be kind of in this
this place that we have been in the past
so the ntsb has a very formal process of
how they investigate incidents so when
an accident occurs they establish
parties to the investigation and and the
investigation protocols they gather all
of the information that they can they'll
then actually brief the media where they
hand over this factual information that
they have at the time to the media they
will then hold investigative hearings to
get any additional information for
example from the vendors etc
and once all of this has been completed
and the investigation has been completed
um they will actually meet to finalize
the probable causes and safety
recommendations after which the report
has been released and just to give you
some examples of these reports in 2010
an a380 had a fan
bladeout event that actually
caused shrapnel from the engine to
actually sever the electronic trunks in
the airplane
which made
controlling the airplane fairly
difficult and it was only due to proper
crew resource management that the pilots
managed to land the plane safely and
interestingly enough crew resource
management was actually something
introduced by
the ntsb a few
uh many years ago
to help decision-making in cockpits
one of the findings of this incident is
that when those
cables were actually severed
the pilots received over 400 alerts in
the cockpit and this was a problem for
them because they were overwhelmed by
the number of alerts so various system
changes were made to make that easier as
well as the fact that those electronic
cable trunks are no longer run together
they actually
are separated now
and it's not just big accidents that
need to be investigated but it's also
the near misses as well where you know
nothing major happened but there are
always lessons to be learned from you
know
near collisions or near mistakes or near
accidents as as well another example is
the miracle on the hudson so a plan
departed a new york
airport in 2009 it flew into a flock of
birds which resulted in dual engine
failure
the aircraft was actually ditched in the
water um everybody was rescued and there
was no fatalities um
what was observed uh during the
investigation is that um pilots can't
actually practice water landings in a
simulator because they didn't allow them
they didn't have the capability to do so
and many pilots thought that if you
actually landed a plane in the water
everybody would actually die so one of
the safety recommendations that came out
of this incident was that simulators
need uh
must allow pilots to practice water
landings earlier this year um a tron's
air quagga flight that departed hawaii
had a dual engine failure um the pilot
successfully ditched the plane in the
sea
they were rescued by the coast guard
they never had any injuries
but the interesting question to ask is
had they not been able to train in the
simulator to do the ditching
with this uh event have turned out any
differently
and there's just some images of the ntsb
during the recovery they actually pulled
out the plane about
two weeks ago you can see the front
parts of the pane
plane in this image as well as the rear
section and the reason this is so
important is to actually have a feedback
loop in the industry so the ntsb reports
are often
used in airline training
programs so that pilots can learn from
mistakes that have taken place and
there's also a dedicated youtube
community of
youtubers who actually take these
reports and actually make really high
quality
videos from those reports and even if
you're not interested in aviation
you know these videos are still quite
interesting
and it's not just aviation
this
expands across engineering as well so if
you
if you studied engineering you probably
would recognize this this is the hybrid
uh regency walkway collapse that killed
114 people
and this event resulted in
from a small design change that was done
and had obviously a tragic impact
the u.s chemical safety board also
investigates accidents in chemical
manufacturing
and again you know they use this as a
lesson to learn thing if we want to move
forward in the security community we
really do need an agency like this um to
be able to give us factual information
as well as to solve some of the common
challenges that people are having
i think one of the big challenges that a
lot of companies have is uh enterprise
crepeway uh one of my favorite
conference talks is actually uh by harun
who actually presented a talk around
how broken the enterprise security
business is at virus bulletin in 2019
and if you haven't seen it i would
recommend that you watch it and the
point that harun makes is that
you know we suck at uh evaluating
security products and i think when such
a review board
you know is created it will be able to
shed light on what products actually do
work and what actually products are
actually bad to close off this topic i
think we are in a sorry state when um
eight of the 25
most exploited vulnerabilities are
actually in security gear um 30 percent
of all of the vulnerabilities across the
us government are actually in their
security software and hardware and until
we start fixing the core issues behind
this i don't think we'll actually move
forward
from a security posture perspective
the next topic is disinformation or how
the supply of information has been
twisted
over the past year with the coronavirus
and there's been a large anti-vex
movement to
undermine the rollout of the covert 19
vaccine
they often
will spread false baseless claims with
emotionally charged imagery and language
to provoke an emotional response from
the reader and research done by the
center for countering digital hate
discovered that 12 individuals
called the dirty dozen were responsible
for 65 percent of all of the
disinformation
related to the coronavirus vaccine
and these individuals have a large
following
and have routinely you know pedaled
these base baseless clam about the
coronavirus and the vaccines and in
doing so many of them have generated a
large amount of revenue by pushing
alternative unproven treatments and
cures for cover 19.
a lot of them have books and webinars
and seminars that they have as well as
pools that they then sell and this is
obviously ironic because
many people won't take the vaccine
because they say they don't know what's
in it but they'll happily take a pull
from an unregulated person
which i think is quite
ironic
well this information around the
coronavirus vaccine may pose a public
health
issue
the real challenges when this
information is has been weaponized
to spread false baseless claims for
example the theory that the u.s election
was stolen you know this led to
real-world violence on january the 6th
during the insurrection of uh trump
supporters where the u.s capital was
actually um
attacked in a an in in an attempt to
overthrow uh the election
and this obviously raises you know the
issue of how do we actually you know
address these issues there was a rather
controversial op-ed in the new york
times about the limits that free speech
should have i personally believe in free
speech
however how do you actually go about
combating this information while making
sure that you don't infringe on free
speech
rights and this is really a whole a
heart problem this is really a hard
problem to solve next up is um the apple
see sam debacle of how apple you know
portrays its values
in the past apple has proclaimed that
privacy is one of its core values and
has routinely taken shots at its
competitors such as google regarding um
privacy however in august of this year
apple announced plans to put content
scanning technology on iphones to combat
child sexual abuse material or csam as
part of this announcement they also
announced initiatives to combat nudity
in messages i'm not going to go into
that
i'm going to focus on the csam issue
so how this would work is apple would
get a list of known csun material from
the national sensor for missing and
exploit to children um they will compare
the hashes of known csun images to
images on a particular user's iphone and
if the image matches
the photo
is encrypted with a safety voucher and
then is sent to apple apple will verify
the image hashes before
sending it back to the center
during that process
and then this would be reported to law
enforcement the response from the
security community was swift and clear
that this is a bad idea
and it was really great to see the
entire community really you know agree
on this even people that i typically
disagree with
actually you know said that this was a
terrible idea
one of the first problems is the hashing
so in the past images were hashed with
shot 256 and md5 and if the image was
resized or encoded cropped or slightly
altered it would generate a new hash
apple try to fix this problem by
creating a system called neural hash
which looks at the content of the image
in order to derive the hash so even if
images are slightly different or have
slightly different color the idea is
that they regenerate the same hash apple
claims that there is a one in one
trillion chance of a hash collision but
there's no way to actually test that
because the census database only
contains a few million images the second
problem is around reporting requirements
so under title 18 section 2258
all platforms that allow user generator
content to be uploaded to a platform
must report any material that could
contain
csam
and there are harsh penalties if a
provider fails to do so
and
this leads to a situation where
providers would rather report an image
as potentially being csam rather than
take the chance and be fined
for for not reporting it and this
creates a issue in the way that apple
wants to actually use the system so as
an example let's say you have a photo of
two 18 year old teenagers
engaged in sexual activity this is a
legal image it gets uploaded to a social
media platform like facebook or twitter
facebook doesn't allow annuity but
twitter does
and the the images reported to the
social media platforms
they're not sure if it's legal so they
take it down and they
report it to the national center for
missing and exploit
to children and then this thing gets
added to the database which then
obviously updates apple's database and
if somebody was looking at this image
again a legal image the image hash would
match this would then be sent to apple
apple would do the verification they
would send it back to the center and the
center would then
notify law enforcement and the law
enforcement would then do a certain
session warrant and this is really where
one of the big challenges lies because
even though the images were legal
you know now somebody is having a
certain seizure
you know done against them and even
though they are completely innocent this
whole process has can so distrust with
neighbors and can cause severe
reputational damages even though the
person is innocent
and this is particularly problematic if
for example the media actually then goes
and reports about this investigation as
well
the second
more problematic issue is around the
fact that this content scanning
technology can be repurposed
for government surveillance and
censorship so china or russia could
actually force
apple
to actually use this technology
to center images or
for requests to bypass encryption
if we look at china these are three
images that are banned in china
obviously the
the the comparison of xi jinping to
winnie the pooh the square
incident as well as an artwork depicting
river crabs which is a play on chinese
words to mock communist rule and
what the chinese government could say as
well you know these three images you
know are illegal and anybody that have
them um you know could potentially face
legal uh repercussions as a result of
that
and many people would say well you know
these governments don't really have the
power to do so however the evidence in
the past have actually has actually
demonstrated otherwise so earlier in
this year
alexia navalny who is the main
opponent
to vladimir putin actually created an
app
for tactile
voting and
the russian government reached out
directly to the ceos of both apple and
google to have this app removed from the
app stores despite the fact that
it wasn't violating any app store policy
and russia claimed that refusing to do
so would be treated as meddling in the
preliminary election
also china has a very firm grip on apple
um
in the past they have removed a lot of
apps from the app store
the apple was forced to put the icloud
keys for china users inside of china as
well as share quite a lot of data with
the chinese government
china is a key market for apple so even
though apple
you know
even though there are human rights
issues tim cook is on record saying that
you know they have a responsibility to
do business everywhere including china
earlier the
last month there was actually
a
research paper published which
highlights a lot of these issues that
i've just spoken about and um you know
these government requests could really
be a real threat and apple can't claim
that it is impossible once they actually
release this technology in the wild
another thing to you know kind of think
about is that recently australia passed
a surveillance legislation amendment
which allows
them to force tech companies to help
them with investigations and again they
claim that
you know this is meant to help deal with
sea salmon terrorism however we've
actually heard these arguments before
as revealed by the snowden documents you
know
a lot of these governments you know
claim that all of these laws and signal
intelligence capabilities are used to
fight you know terrorism and and csam
etc however the evidence actually
opposes that in many cases
and the the
you know the community has really been
pushing back on this move by apple
apple for its part actually says that
you know this is one massive
misunderstanding and you know this is
just you know people are confused they
don't really understand what's going on
um and i don't actually you know by that
you know this is actually quite a
serious issue um one of the things that
really you know enraged the security
community was the fact that um an email
sent by the national center for missing
and exploited children after apple had
released this you know basically
congratulating and thanking them for for
doing this
you know had this infamous line uh where
they say that the days to come will be
filled with screeching voices of the
minority and this really made a lot of
people
upset including myself because you know
if we believe in privacy and civil
liberties you know are we now a
screeching voice of the um minority and
this is a classic you know if you're not
for us you're against those kind of
argument which um i think is actually a
lot of rubbish
the community also then started putting
petitions together
this was an open letter
requesting that
apple
stop
the deployment of this content
monitoring technology and that apple
issue a statement reaffirming their
commitment to end-to-end encryption um
over eight and a half thousand
individuals and thirty-four
organizations uh signed this letter the
electronic frontier foundation also
created a call to action
and 15 000 people actually signed this
petition as well as 90 organizations
co-signed this letter which was sent to
the ceo of apple
apple for its spot actually relented and
actually decided to put all of their
plans on hold
mainly due to the fact that they didn't
want this to overshadow the launch of
the new iphone 13
so they uh you know put this on pause
however what the electronic frontier
foundation did um on the day of the
launch of the iphone 13 they actually
flew a banner over apple park um you
know to kind of protest uh this move by
apple
in closing um you know we shouldn't have
to give up our civil liberties to fight
csam or terrorism we know from the past
that these things have very little
impact and once you give up your civil
liberties
you don't actually get them back so this
is no laughing matter and with that
that's the end of my presentation i
thank you very much