hello everyone my name is katie also
known as insider phd
um welcome to naham con uh
my presentation today is learn to hack
choose a target something
hack i guess get a bounty and this is
really gonna be a
whirlwind tour around a bunch of issues
in bug bounties or what i think are
issues
um and how i think that you can learn
how to do bug bounties like right now
no special requirements at all in case
you don't know who i am my name is katie
i'm also known as insider phd i run a
youtube channel
where i teach people just like you how
to learn how to get into bug bounties
and web applications hacking more
generally so
the basic recipe and this is what i tell
people um
to learn how to hack is to learn to hack
to then choose your program to hack i
guess however you do that
and then you get your bounty and it's
kind of presented in these steps
and we hack we find bugs we write report
we move on
but i don't really think it's that
simple and i don't think anybody else
thinks it's that simple either
bug bounty's changed adapt over time and
what even i may have learned last year
is not necessarily going to be relevant
for you
the people who learned five years ago
it's not necessarily relevant for you
and i think actually the landscape has
really changed um
because really we have all these other
questions we have mentorships
automation private versus public
um checklists methodologies are all the
bugs gone when do i give up how do i
take notes how to test the
vulnerabilities
how people can even find bugs when pros
find so many
and this is kind of what i'm going to
address today it's like these three
issues
and really how i think you can learn how
to do bug mounties
um this year so let's look at the first
one
learn to hack this is the fundamentals
to consider when you're learning to hack
um where should i learn from so the
first advice i always give is whatever
works best for you there is absolutely
no right answer there is no
magic spell there's no pill there's no
like course there's no money you can pay
to just become good at bug bounties um
and there is just no right answer what
will work for me won't necessarily work
for you it won't necessarily work for
your friends
but i like this idea of this learning
pyramid it's completely debunked
no scientific evidence behind it before
the idea is
to have this kind of variation you know
if you just watch something you don't
really retain a lot of the information
but if you see a demonstration if you
practice it if you teach others you then
retain more
um answering that works for me really
well is write-ups so i really like
reading write-ups i really like
digesting them
um and i really like to present them on
my videos and that's really useful for
me
because um i learn a lot by practicing
and then by teaching others
so what i think is the best thing to do
is really to get some variety like
choose a bunch of different ones
immerse yourself in hacking and that can
really be a huge
advantage keep up with the news like on
twitter via newsletters
um you know just put yourself in a
position where
you don't necessarily have to eat sleep
breathe bug bounties
just make sure you are kind of exposed
to it
regularly um and the next piece of
advice i can really give is take
effective notes as you learn
effective is going to completely depend
on you like there is no
correct way for taking notes um but you
should take notes
because when you take notes you will
remember more a hundred percent
no really don't have to be detailed just
enough so you can remember them
so you might be thinking okay if they
don't have to be detailed
what should i actually capture and i
think what you should capture is signs
um and i say this a lot so what really
separates pro bug bounty hunters from
new bug bounty hunters is that new
hackers learn one bug
and then look for that everywhere and
that really gives you a disadvantage
because you can be looking at a bug
straight in your face and completely be
unaware of it
so what i think the best way to kind of
get around this is is to learn the signs
of more than one bug
even if it's just three or four you know
versus learning one bug and learning
like four well you've
you've got your chances up by four there
so whenever you read watch listen
however you absorb your information
ask yourself questions like how they not
to look for
why did they try that um one example is
you know
every idol usually revolves around id so
now as a hacker as soon as i see an id
i'm constantly checking for eye doors if
i see reflected input i'm thinking
cross-site scripting i'm terrible at
cross-site scripting
but i would be thinking it and that's i
think what you kind of need to get out
of your notes is getting those signs
really quickly
um but then you might be thinking but i
won't know how to exploit it
so really what your note should do is
help you become familiar with a few bugs
but you still need to be able to recall
it my advice is to go broad with your
knowledge
grow broad with your notes and go deep
when you need to exploit only when you
actually find yourself needing to
exploit
so always make sure to record where the
information came from right you know
even if it's just a link to a blog post
right
notes are good for simplifying helping
you remember
if you have loads of complex technical
information in your notes they're just
not going to work for you anyway
so what should i take my notes in so i
did a poll on twitter
um and i had people face off against
different note-taking apps
but honestly whatever you like it's
completely up to you if you like a
specific method a system piece of
software
just keep it there's no point changing
it um i really like notion and i also
have a lot of handwritten notes but you
might not like notion and you might not
like handwriting your notes
and that's fine um i did my poll and
obsidian was voted
as the one people most liked um
with notion as a second with vim as the
community choice which really shows you
know
there are very broad um like categories
here there's no like
one application and you can just write
notes in a text file it really doesn't
have to be complicated you just need a
way to recall them later
so what do i think the goal is i think
the goal is what you might think is a
knowledge map
and a knowledge base a way you can kind
of go
vulnerability i s i will look for xss
and in the xss category you have
a bunch of reports on xss maybe a bunch
of blog posts bunch of different types
maybe you have it split up into
dom and reflected and stored right
maybe you have it so it's completely
separate and you can kind of search what
you want then
you want to build up a knowledge base
you want to build up something that's
unique to you that you know how to use
um and then when you hack and when you
sort of see oh yeah that's the sign of
that one bug
you can just go into your knowledge base
scroll down find
the resources that you think will be
most appropriate and try and replicate
their exploits a lot of people ask when
are you done learning like when do you
when are you done and the answer is
never the best hackers are learning all
the time
nobody ever goes yes i am the ultimate
ruler of uh
bug bounties i now know everything um
literally no hacker will tell you that
because everyone is always trying to
like learn and improve they're always
reading they're always trying to improve
their practice they're working with
others trying to understand them
but then you might be thinking so when
am i ready to move on
and the answer is right now like there
is no critical mass of knowledge you
need
to get started in bug bounties i promise
you you're good enough there is no
like doing something else is not gonna
be the thing that lets you get uh
bounties right it is just you've got it
now just
roll with it so that was my kind of
learned hack section
it's all about choosing a program and
you know how do you choose a program
when you don't really know what you're
doing
um so let's talk about bug bounty
platforms so if you're not really sure
what a bug badge platform are they're
third parties which host bug bounty
programs
so programs are things you can hack a
platform hosts them
and they kind of let you hack a
different range of companies
they do things like coordinate payments
help manage programs they may also
provide triage services invite only
um it really doesn't matter which
blockbuster platform you go to
all of them are good um you might want
to pick one
based on what we'll talk about a bit
later but there's no wrong answer there
and you might be thinking from that well
don't all the pros have all the bugs
anyway
um and like you know you can never find
a bug
and i will promise you as a beginner you
will find bugs that pros don't
not every bug can be automated or will
be automated some bugs
pros don't exploit when they find it um
because they're focused on kind of more
critical issues and
fundamentally it doesn't matter what
program or platform we choose
we can always turn the tide in our favor
so a big platform or a small platform it
really doesn't matter
um we just need to be hacking on a
program um
which we can kind of see
people have um
seen so what we want to see sounds
really weird
um what we really want to do is look at
programs which people haven't had to
look at yet
and try and get as fresh as possible um
this could be a public program
it could be a smaller um like
platform it could be a nisha platform it
could be a private program and a large
platform or just a program that has
regular updates
we really want to see new stuff we want
to see new assets you want to see things
haven't been touched before
because that will improve our chances
and i say that but bounty
is like a mixture between luck and skill
and this is how we turn the tide of luck
in our favor so public versus private if
you're really worried go for a private
program
look for programs with a low total
bounties paid which suggests in your
program
but that have a good response time
especially time to bounty because that
means it's an
active program um what industry
specifically
i always say any if you have an option
to hack an app you already
kind of know definitely hack that
because
those tend to be things where you know
them quite well already you know what
some of the functionality is
so you'll be more more an advantage
basically
but there are certain programs that are
always going to be better for low
competition bug bounty hunting
like for example mobile apps trust me
nobody touches
mobile apps it's harder it's more of a
pain to get set up
and because of that less people do it
android is popular
and easy to set up you can entire an
emulator less people do ios
overall you need an ios device unless
you have one of the new macbooks
but fundamentally um mobile apps are the
place to go if you want to learn kind of
niche skills
okay so then we've kind of covered like
programs we've covered learning to hack
how do we actually hack anyway like how
how do you how do you hack like how do
you actually do that so let's have a
chat about actually hacking something
hacking is partly luck to find a bug you
need the combination of luck and skill
now when you first start out this might
be like 80
20 skill but as you improve your skill
luck is less of a factor and what the
pros have done to kind of tilt that even
more in their favor is they have
specialities
like that's how hackers get the
consistency
um they have the consistency the
knowledge and the experience to flip
that around and make it so
um skill is far more in their favor but
when you first start out luck will
definitely be
um an aspect of whether or not you find
a bug
and that's important to recognize um and
you shouldn't
feel bad if you can't find a bug because
it is challenging
and the most difficult part of hacking
is well
hacking stuff um packing is different
for different people like learning the
way people hack is differently
um there's tweet posts that get kind of
spread around
it's like how did you find your first
bug and you know i found my first bug
like kind of randomly i found it i was
very
very fortunate and this is
when we can use it to our advantage
because we have mentorship and
collaboration
it's challenging we have a large
community like there are so many other
people and you'll see them in the chat
now literally talking
we have such a large community that we
can make those connections with each
other we have the ability
to collaborate to listen to
join together and we can meet other
hackers
use this join communities like nahomi's
right
talk to people it's fantastic for
learning because not only will you see
how different people hack
you'll also see how different people
learn and what different resources get
shared
and being part of a community is such a
big advantage especially when it comes
to
um you as a more established hacker as
you improve
you'll see oh i already have a bunch of
hacking friends i can ask if they want
to collab with me right it's not a case
of
i'm completely on my own because you're
not
now a lot of people like to use other
people's methodologies
and i think this is a difficult subject
i don't think
other people's methodologies will work
for you unless you adapt to it
some people are very recon heavy like
nahamsek he is very recon heavy and he
finds bugs with his recon
and some people don't really like recon
and you know what you'll figure out what
works for you in time it takes
experience
it takes like um learning it takes like
actually hacking something and getting
that kind of
oh actually i don't really like doing
this this is kind of boring
and on the subject of recon i think this
is a difficult subject because i think a
lot of people
think oh recon is how i get bugs
when you do recon you really need to do
it thoughtfully you need to be thinking
you know what am i trying to accomplish
and from that are you trying to
understand the whole attack surface
are you looking for hidden endpoints on
functionality are you looking for like
pure information disclosure file
disclosure
and always think about that goal like
what you're going to do next a lot of
people will run recon and then they
don't necessarily know what the next
step
is for them so really think before you
do something like recon what you
actually need it for and what you're
actually going to do with it afterwards
and how are you going to use it
um and that will really help when it
comes to actually using it effectively
you know whether that's taking
screenshots
whether that is oh i want to look for
javascript files
all of that is best done by recon but
you have to know what you want first
and on the subject automation so
automation is really trendy right now
um and i'm sure you have all heard of
nuclear at this point
um i will say that relying on automation
alone is unlikely to get you a bounty
it's more likely to get you a dupe
a lot of these tools are available for
everybody now and
what i think is important is to learn
manual testing
first and then figure out how tools fit
with your methodology
so for an example as an example i hack a
lot of apis one of my major issues
i have when hacking apis is finding
additional endpoints
so one tool that kind of solves that
problem
is um ffuf so
i use that as a fuzzer so i haven't just
used that because it's on trend right
now i use it because i had a specific
problem i needed to solve
that couldn't be solved with manual
testing
and my kind of number one piece of
advice for all hacking
is to hack what you can see focus on
functionality first
if you see a log on screen you need to
be testing for like account takeovers
can you reset the password
if you see e-commerce you should be
thinking about pricing issues
if you see a comment system you should
be thinking about xss
any kind of like deleting permissions um
creating permissions you should be
thinking about idols
hack the functionality that you can see
don't get obsessed with like
where rce's are that will come in time
when you get
more experience and you kind of
understand better what you like to hack
for the moment focus on what you can see
and how you can break what you see
and that is the best way to actually get
started
and you're probably thinking from this
how do you actually know when you found
a bug
and that seems like a really simple
question but it's kind of a complex
answer right how do we actually know if
some things are vulnerable
well what we look for is bug bounty
hunters is impact and what is impact
impact has some kind of effect on the
security of an organization
even non-technical bugs can be impactful
and complex technical bugs not impactful
at all
um for example i i know that
um my mentee mentor uh sarah she
had found a vulnerability um and it was
like
rc so you're thinking top level apart
from was a sandboxed environment
which she'd gone like the difficult
route to find a bug on
and equally you know one of my best bugs
is not something that has like
really complicated it's a very simple
idol but with a really impactful effect
and that's what makes bugs like unique
so
so we found something how do we actually
get paid how do we do that get a bounty
part
so how do you know if you've got impact
um the easiest thing to do is to ask
yourself some questions
does this affect the organization's data
or intellectual property
does it affect the users of a product is
this likely to affect the reputation of
an organization
and kind of more generally would a
malicious actor be interested in what
you found
as bug bounty hunters we play malicious
actors right
we play the scary hacker in the basement
with all the lights turned off in a
black hoodie um and what we need to do
is scare
a business into paying us money um
not to like say oh look if you don't do
this i'll hack your systems
but to say hey look this is a really
serious issue that you need to address
right now
and with impact we need to constantly
link it back up to what the business
is and what it does we want to put like
our findings into
their language so what does this mean so
let's say you find an idol an e-commerce
platform
the idol allows you to cancel an order
without being logged in
what does this mean for the organization
that you're hacking well
we can go ahead and say a malicious
actor could go ahead and cancel
everyone's orders without them knowing
this links back to what the organization
does we're not using the term
idol while we might give technical
details when we talk about
impact we kind of want to talk more
generally
um it's kind of thinking about
how would you make that case to somebody
who maybe isn't technical
linking it back to what the business
does is really vital
so why does impact matter well impact
tells you you found something
interesting and a core idea you
structure a report around
bug bounty platforms aren't actually
there to throw money at you they want to
protect their
customers reputations organizations and
data from malicious
hackers now if we look at the photo the
issue there is a plane crash right
like that is not kind of that not that
obvious
but we need to be thinking what is the
impact that that could have so
somebody could die um there could be a
fire the home could be damaged
we might see something even kind of
greater you know what if
they can't control the blaze that could
cause a forest fire
and that's how we need to be thinking
about our vulnerabilities is like okay
what could this do if left unchecked why
do they need to care about this
and that's how you get bugs triaged well
and even if you know you're not that
great at english if you just have a go
most organizations will work with you to
kind of understand that impact not
against you
so what makes a good report this is i
think the
fifth the five most important ones first
is
clear concise writing if you're not a
native speaker
try your best and get a friend to give
your writing a second look
um it could be a really good advice
because i'm dyslexic
is to to put your writing into google
translate
uh put it into english and then listen
to it and then say oh okay
um i can kind of see what sounds clunky
the other thing
is a lot of um bug bounty programs might
actually support your language
um i think microsoft has a really wide
range of languages it supports
and if it would be better to be in your
native language then
write it in that if you can write clear
and concisely that's the important part
uh second is you need to explain the
vulnerability on their terms not on your
terms how does it affect their users
and that's i think what a lot of people
get wrong is they kind of think about
vulnerabilities in a kind of a weird
kind of hacker way when actually we need
to put that into a business perspective
um three are clear pocs right making
sure those steps are really clear
making sure that you know people can
understand it follow those steps
um bonus points for things like videos
one click exploits those things that
just make a trial just
job just a little bit easier and talk
about triages
four is be polite being rude and yelling
at them won't help your bug be
triaged faster right just be
professional
um fifth is don't make assumptions like
don't make assumptions that your triager
kind of knows everything about an asset
or what it does or that they even know
every bug in existence what's great
about bug bounty hunting is actually we
can learn from each other
both triager to hacker and from hacker
to triager
and actually you might know more about
an asset than the triage
does initially um because you've been
hacking on it for five days
straight so that is the end of my
presentation
i want to thank you all very very much
for listening to me i hope this has
helped you
kind of be maybe a bit clear on some of
the steps in bug bounties
i know this is kind of a whirlwind tour
through quite a lot of these different
issues
but i really hope it's helped you um i
want to thank nahamsek for inviting me
to speak
and i want to thank you all for
listening to me um have a great rest of
the conference i hope you learn a lot
get your notes get your notebooks out
because we're taking notes from this
point onwards
thank you very much everybody and i hope
to see you all very soon
bye everyone