hi everyone um thanks for attending my
talk for naham khan
and putting your mind to it bug bounties
for 12 months with me
z shawnee i'm very honored to be able to
speak at this conference and i'm also
honored to be able to sponsor it
as bugbountyhunter.com if you haven't
heard of it definitely check us out at
bugbountyhunter.com
so what is my talk gonna be about well
i'm a strong believer that if you put
your mind to something amazing things
can happen
so this talk will be aimed at
experienced and in
inexperienced people because i'm
basically going to set you a task at the
end of this for the next 12 months for
you to go out
and hopefully you'll find some cool bugs
and earn some bounties potentially
because i'm hopefully going to ease some
of your concerns and show you that with
time effort
and patience the sky really is the limit
especially with bug mountain is because
you can sit at the comfort of your own
home and hack on so many
massive companies with so much in scope
and it honestly will keep you busy for a
long
time so for those of you who do not know
who i am
my name is z shawno my real name is sean
i'm a self-taught developer
web application hacker and mentor i
first started out developing websites
aged 11 12 13 etc
and eventually learned how to hack and
yeah
now i do mentoring on
bugbountyhunter.com which i mentioned
earlier
but the site is aimed at teaching people
how to identify vulnerabilities and web
applications but also applying this
knowledge on bug mountain programs
so in the membership section once users
find enough bugs
on the vulnerable web application that i
set up they can join what is called hack
events
and i will basically hold their hand and
show them how to
apply my methodology and identify
vulnerabilities
on public bug bounty programs
i'm a big fan of just targeting one
program and literally just going as deep
as possible finding out what what works
how it works etc and i actually managed
to achieve rank two on bug crowd when i
first started out in bug mounties
um i targeted literally one program it
took me eight nine months literally just
focusing
understanding how things work and yeah
my profile
is now deleted on bug crowd but we won't
get into that
so bug money for 12 months
think about it and i will get into
that bug bounties isn't all plain
sailing it's not
all dominant fun and games amazing there
are
some whole loop not loop sorry there are
some like holes as such and
concerns and problems but we'll get into
this so
for the moment though just sit back and
think about this right companies around
the globe will invite hackers like me
and you to legally poke at their systems
legally you cannot get in trouble they
have most of them have safe harbors and
they will say hey
you can hack and if you find anything
tell us and we'll pay you
literally you sit at the comfort of your
own home hacking at your own pace
and you can get paid big money for it so
as a hacker
bog bounties has enabled the internet to
become your oyster
so literally as it says there let's hack
the planet
so my first tip for people wanting to
succeed in bug mounties now like i say
this is aimed at experience and
inexperienced people
um if you don't understand like too much
about web application hacking and
vulnerabilities then of course
this talk might not be obvious used to
just
at the moment go away and learn from how
to find
web application vulnerabilities practice
against some challenges
um and things like that and understand
what xss is crosstalk quest forgery open
uri
open url redirects idols and things like
that because
you need to understand the common
vulnerabilities and what they are
why they actually exist so for example
with xss you chuck it some input and it
reflects it back as html you have your
xss
whereas with idol you're looking for
integer values or some sort of identify
in the request
um and if you change it to something
else you're able to either view or
modify or do something to someone else's
data
right so a lot of people will think
or they're told sorry or they advised
look for just one bug type
learn all about xss and just go look for
xss
i don't believe in my opinion that's a
good approach because you're going to
miss
so many bugs and healthy features and
things like that so understanding how it
works and then you know what to look for
so example a login flow when you're
logging into a website or you're
registering
look for o wolf sso login tokens and
things like that look for
look for what happens but not only that
once you're signed in let's say for
example you sign into google.com
go find a subdomain that you can sign in
and see when you press sign in well
first of all are you already signed in
if you're not if there is there a sign
in button that when you press sign
in maybe it doesn't really ask you for
your username and password and there's
some sort of
token exchange happen and it just logs
you in based on this a token do i mean
that token
identifies who you are that's for user
experience they don't want you to have
to re-log into every single website
owned by google
they want you to be able to visit their
website and you're in your account
you're if you're logged into google
you'd want to be able to log
in all their services right that's then
when you can use a harmless
open url redirect um to potentially leak
that for example
edit in your profile why would you think
to look for an idol and edit your
profile well
think go look at it in your profile on
some websites you'll see
your account id sent in the request
maybe it's sent in the url
maybe you a center some post data
pretentious actually sent us a header
if it's a mobile app sometimes and
believe it or not there was a bug
disclosed on a heavily tested website on
yahoo believe it or not
where they it was naffy where they found
an idol simply via the cookie value i
mean it's on one of their slides from
years and years ago
crosstalk forgery it's an easy account
takeover and not only that but i always
recommend people
go test features that should be the most
secure so
updating your account information on for
example google
should be secure right there should be
crosstalk request 4g token they
shouldn't be allowing
anyone to update anyone's information
when they visit the tag
the attackers website and things like
that so
see how how does it work what how are
they validating
and where their requests came from and
things like that and stored xss because
i mentioned earlier anytime you can
input information and it's reflected
back
you want to be testing for xss and
server side template injection and
things like that anytime it's reflected
back
you chuck that at it and see what
happens developer tools
now go on to google right now during the
talk and type in
hackerone webhook ssrf
you'll find some disclosed reports
you'll find some blog posts and things
like that
now again understand the features and
what to look for so when you visit for
example developer.paypal.com
and you can see that you can test
instant payment notifications and web
hooks
you then have to think from a hacker
perspective and
add in a bit of a developer thought
right okay
so we've got a feature here that is
intended to send a request to the
website that i
input and it's going to query it and
pull
the metadata and display it to me
so you then as a hacker need to think
well okay what's this developer done to
stop me from querying for
um internal services some metadata
things and etc i mean
and then down the rabbit hole you go
maybe they've just simply blacklisted
saying no you're not allowed to look for
localhost if localhost is inputted here
block it
but maybe some different encoding will
bypass it maybe that literally is just a
hard coded fish
i mean string to look for redirects and
things like that
and that's because these developer tools
which are made for developers for
me for users to use they're purposely
coded
with like the intention of like it's a
server-side request
because they're sending the intention of
that feature is to send a request to
this website
pull the information but then you add
the hacker mindset and you start poking
around
um and the same with mobile apps go
check and see updating your information
like literally run burp now on your
phone open a few apps that you've got
installed obviously you have the https
cert installed etc of ssl pinion
and just update your information you'll
see your id
like using a lot of apps to identify
which account to update
now with that in mind most features
on websites work the same they take user
input they handle it like they do
something with it
and then they maybe reflect it now
that's why you'll look at some hunters
and say how can you just find so many
bugs on this website it's quite tough
and that's because with years of
experience and something that hopefully
you over the next 12 months you're going
to pick up
you'll discover that like i say websites
work the same and you'll be able to
look at our website and you just know
you just see it they see a certain
request you
see a certain parameter you see
something certain reflected et cetera
and you just know
because pretty much things work the same
obviously
i mean his variety of how requests are
sent json requests
etc but again that then opens up even
more things to test for because if
every single request is sending json
data
we'll change the content type to
application xml and see if they're
passing xml
because maybe they are and you can get
xxe whereas
if you didn't see that you potentially
wouldn't think to try that would you
join me if it was just sending it as a
normal post um i seen a drink
so yeah hopefully people understand that
so
it's not a case of right i'm just gonna
look for xss all over google
it's a case of right i'm gonna
understand what this
feature is in front of me what can i do
with it
um but yeah
second tip don't spray and pray
find the right way now i'm not a fan
of just spraying payloads everywhere and
hoping for the best
using the same payloads i'm not even a
fan really of polygots because
when you're chucking quite a lot at it
and a certain part of that payload
might trigger some sort of waffle filter
and then it all might not go through and
yeah so like this is actually a bug on
parker believe it or not and if you
visit bugbountyhunter.com
there is actually a tutorial um like my
flow of looking for xss
on there and it says there start
harmless first
now like i say this bug is on barca
where if you chuck script alert
it doesn't work whereas if you give it a
h2
or some harmless html you'll see it's
reflected
so then then you start going down the
rabbit hole okay well how can i make
this malicious what is actually going on
and
down the rabbit hole of testing you go
but you've started harmless first
you've started off with something that's
probably more likely gonna reflect back
to you
and you can confirm is this vulnerable
to xss what are they actually reflecting
and very easily you can quickly test for
xss on the fly
um an example of this is a heavily
tested website i was literally just
giving it image source equals x on error
alert
didn't work anywhere um and then i was
trying
to bypass a random filter on there like
with xss where it was reflected and i
needed a single apostrophe
um and then i re when i tried it i saw
that it actually reflected my html like
it's valid html and i was like huh
so i went and revisited a bunch of xss
and discovered that
anytime i added a single apostrophe to
any of the xss payloads it worked
this is what i can assume is some
anti-sql
injection code one on their website or
whatever but yeah
that was a a weird bypass in my opinion
but don't just chuck the script alert
check various payloads at it chug verse
characters out to see
how things are being handled and what is
being reflected
and then you can work your way from
there the same applies for everything in
my opinion
um so if sql injection don't just chuck
it a random like a payload that you
found on the internet to
get the database table versions or
anything like that
because they might be filtering this
waff etc
chuck just like a single apostrophe or
some random characters that are gonna
break the sql if it's vulnerable to sql
injection if you're giving it a single
apostrophe and some other random
characters
like read up on sql injection um with
what you can test it with
if you can get it to give you the error
then you can work your way from there if
xxa
for example don't just go ahead and try
read some internal files
try just a basic doctype replace see if
it's actually gonna
execute that see what isn't working what
is
um and it says there start harmless and
then go malicious now by malicious i
don't mean become a criminal
and exploit their system and be a bad
person no
what this means is and i'll give you an
example so if you watched my stream with
ben
at ben's stream sign i joined the stream
and chat picked a target and they picked
rockstar games
now starting harmless means you give
the website what they're expecting to
make the feature work
so in this case there was a return url
on rockstar games
um so we give it rockstar games that's a
harmless payload
they're expecting that that's what they
want but then we want to start making it
malicious okay let's work out what
they're looking for here so if i tried
shawn dot rockstar games do they still
trust it okay
and you work your way through there are
they got the trailing slash for example
because if not i could try rockstar
games dot computer
um what about local relative redirects
so just forward slash test
do they instead they automatically input
for me the rockstargames.com forward
slash test
or does it just redirect to forward test
and they're trusting the browser
to handle all of that for me is there
some sort of logic going on there where
they're
forcing it to be rockstar games how does
it handle different characters
so you're starting off harmless and
you're working your way to malicious
and then you're being the best person in
the world by reporting it and hopefully
getting a bounty if you find a bug
so understanding your features and then
understanding the payloads that you're
chucking at it and what's working what's
reflected and how it's handling it
because sometimes some bugs are
vulnerable to more than one thing
you might find stored xss or some xss
but maybe it's also vulnerable to
sql injection you don't know you know
what i mean you test some things see how
things work
now this some is some advice now
this isn't a tip such as this advice
finding a program to hack on
so we've learned to not spray and pray
we've learned to
work out how features work etcetera
etcetera
now finding a program to hack on this is
something a lot of people struggle with
um newcomers they join
um they're recommended to do i mean find
some flags or be active etc and prove
you can hack and you'll
receive some invites most people tell me
that the invites they receive
aren't that good they're not that
interested not that active
like etcetera and yeah that's fair play
and that's why with bug bounties
ultimately you can take the success into
your own hands
now there is no special source
and there is no way for me to tell you
go hack here you will find bugs because
a program that i might succeed in you
might not succeed and you might find
frustrating you hate it and you're like
how do sean find bugs here
it's about what works for you what do
you enjoy on
um if you can enjoy hacking on the site
that you're hacking on
you're gonna have so much more of a good
time because when you're digging deeper
and finer things you get that
hacker dopamine rush you get that this
the
tingling senses see feelings you know
what i mean anyway it's like oh
what's going on i want to find out and
then when you actually get the bug it's
like whoa
you feel proud of it you know what i
mean whereas i have looked at some
targets where it's like
i really don't just don't enjoy the
sight
like there's not a lot to play with
there's not a lot to do as such
um that's not necessarily saying you
should walk away from that program
because there might be some bugs but
enjoying the site you're hacking on will
help you be a lot more successful in my
opinion because you're going to enjoy it
aren't you
now i've also put there do not rely on
bug mounting platforms to send you
invites
in order for you to be successful at bug
money um bug bounties
because in my opinion that's step one to
burn out now
what you define a success is up to you
um i know there's probably some people
at bug banking platform shaking their
head at that right now
but this is coming from somebody that's
had years of experience with
bug platforms and hacking and i've heard
from lots of people and things like that
again what you define as successful
is up to you that might be one bug a
month that might be just your first ever
bug that might just be your first ever
critical bug
that might be you quitting your
full-time job to become a full-time bug
bounty hunter
the reason i say don't rely on bug
making platforms to send you invites
is because well you ta
you put in your success kind of in
someone else's hand and let's say into
them like well hey come on
send me some invites do whatever whereas
you'll discover
majority of companies welcome hackers um
and you shouldn't rely on invites it's
just
i could sit here for ages talking about
this but
it's probably for another video but yeah
that's not to say by the way i'll just
go back on that
you should 100 join every single bug
making platform don't mean join every
single one
definitely and if they send you invites
check it out on whatever but don't rely
on them that's that's what i'm trying to
get across don't
think oh i'm going to join a bug money
platform get really high up in the
rankings
prove whatever and hope they send me
invites because
potentially yeah might work in some
people's cases but
ultimately no and yeah it's a lot better
to kind of take the success
in your own hands and we i will explain
a little bit more
in a bit now when you're picking a
program
and i'm going to give you some help and
let's say i'm going to do some homework
at the end of this believe it or not to
get you going so and you're not going to
have to get invited to nothing for this
don't worry
so aim to at least spend at least six
months poking at your target
bigger the scope the better um because
bigger the scope
think about different teams different
code bases perhaps a different um
language site like for example i know a
bug bounty program where
their dot com and their cn are
completely different code bases
different teams whatever
um there you go so the bugs you're
finding on.com
there's gonna be completely different
things on cn and i wonder how many
people actually go visit other different
websites
um i'm thinking not many if i'm honest
um
the reason i say bigger the scope the
better because well
percy for me i like to really dig deep
into a program lots to play with
and the bigger the scope and the more to
play with the more mistakes the more
mistakes more bounty's coming your way
now if you're not prepared to put the
time in in my opinion don't be expect to
find much don't expect to find much
sorry um or if you are just going to put
like let's say
just whatever not a lot of time run some
tools then you're probably just going to
find some dupes
now i'm not saying you need to sit there
and put
me in a full eight-hour day learning to
hack or hacking or whatever
but don't just look at a target and skip
through it so quickly
actually feel confident that the site is
secure
feel confident that you could at the end
of this test that you were giving them
say you should be proud of how secure
your website
is um and this is where your notes will
come into play because you'll be writing
lots of notes as you're going along
but yeah
like i say while everyone's waiting for
private invites
naffy just goes in the hacks on google
for a couple of months right
and fair play he has so much experience
of hacking
but there's nothing nothing stopping any
of you viewers right now watching this
to learn google for the next 12 months
and crush it
you don't need to prove that you can
hack to anyone you don't need
to hack for free on vdps to get private
invites and all this and that this
in my opinion is what a bug bounty
program vulnerability disclosure program
is
it's a company who believes they have
their defenses
in place and they are saying to the
world hey
if you can find ways around our defenses
we will pay
for vulnerabilities they've not had to
make you jump through hoops because
that's in my opinion not what a bug
bounty program and crowd source security
is it's not really
crowd source security if it's cherry
picked security is it
in my opinion so that's why i say
take the success into your own hand
because there's nothing stopping any of
you
from looking on google and other bug
money programs facebook
apple etc so
third tip sharing is caring and how you
can create a lead for yourself i
actually give this as a training session
for
um bug by hunting members um we
dissected some
um write-ups and we went against the
program and had some fun
now i'm big believe in shows caring i
try share i've shared lots of rights up
over the years uh tutorials and things
now
one big problem i ran into is companies
don't want me to disclose bugs no no no
sean sign an nda
or if i ask to disclose a bug they don't
tell me no
instead they ban me um so in all honesty
i give up asking to disclose my my
research and my findings because it's
just
a ball lake right now so this is why
it's massive motivation for me actually
making barker and bug bounty hunter
because
no one can stop me from recreating the
bugs i've found
and making a web application full of
these actual bugs john i mean
um so that is a big part of actually bob
barker and bug money hunter and the
challenges and fast food hackings it's
all the bugs i found just recreated for
you to find because
well i can't get in trouble for that can
i because i haven't named names and i
haven't disclosed stuff
and you can then also get the benefit of
learning how to find it yourself
by understanding how the web application
works
so with that said though lots of people
share
lots of epic write-ups and these
write-ups
not all write-ups have good information
because some write-ups
are just a basic summary and don't have
a lot but some write-ups are gold
so much information and they can help
you find bugs
so you just digest disclosed issues and
you can create us lead and like a
starting point for yourself you
literally can go
test to disclose bugs and place yourself
in the same place as the other hacker
find that request that they've talked
about or potentially i haven't spoke
about but they've spoke about a certain
feature go find that request
go find how it's been fixed because
potentially
you might find a way around it you might
find a bypass every hacker approaches
things differently
or it might lead on to more bugs
potentially this hacker because it
happens
it happens you get a hack a dopamine
rush you find a bug you're so excited
maybe you've been looking at it for two
hours
you feel complete so you submit it and
then you go away
potentially there are similar bugs
related to what's been disclosed
more than likely yes because developers
reuse code
and depend on what the bug is maybe it's
a site-wide issue
i'll give you an example sam curry and
everyone else who contributes that their
post on apple
is gold there are so many key areas in
that post right if you seriously read
his post in detail and understand
where they looked for those bugs right
follow their footsteps literally go
follow their footsteps
you will see yeah like i says there i'll
let you work it out
i'm not gonna yeah go have a look at
sam's post
read what they did follow their
footsteps log the request
you'll be going down the rabbit hole and
again you don't need an invite to this
program
there is so much and yeah i personally
know that people are killing it on apple
so like i say
digesting the information read it
finding the
parameters that were used endpoints used
the bug type where it was found etc etc
um so with that said everyone
your target for the next 12 months
is going to be google vrp
and so if you all want to check out
david
who's ex david who's post
on github there huge shout out to him
for contributing this and creating this
um and i want everyone to tweet over
over the next 12 months and let me know
how you're getting on i'm gonna run
through what your tasks are do not worry
so before i go through those i just
wanna real quickly
just run through very very quickly
first tip understand the features and
what you're looking for so
logins updating your information and
whatever features they offer you
developer tools
mobile apps etc second tip don't just
spray and pray
understand what it is you are testing
and what you expect it to be vulnerable
to
try various payloads try harmless
payloads that they're expecting and work
your way to malicious
and how you can create impact second of
all
yes sign up to every bug bounty program
a platform out there sorry
but don't rely on them to send you
invites in order to be successful
um again or successful is up to you
and if you're watching this thinking
well i'm probably not gonna have a lot
of time to get in the bug boundaries and
you're not actually up for spending the
good six
twelve months of this then this probably
isn't for you
um then yeah there's enough for you and
the money
and lastly the last tip let's say
creating the lead which is what we're
going to go through now with your task
everyone
so if everyone is ready let's do this so
if you can see here
i literally opened this github didn't
open any posts just had a little look at
what they were called and this what the
idol one i
i know i idols in my opinion are just as
common as xss
so i clicked onto it i read through it
and i've highlighted here in my opinion
what i think is interesting
guessing the idea here is not possible
but if the victim shared his file the id
will be visible in the path he got five
thousand dollars
um and it was vulnerable to idle
so say to me any other time you see a
similar id like this
you should try for idol because maybe
the developers had the same for
no one like maybe google developers or
whoever coded this as such didn't think
this but potentially they thought
no one's probably going to try another
value here because they're not going to
be able to work out how to get this
and do you know what i mean um how do we
also know if you try just an integer
value there what about if you try the
value just one or
100 whatever maybe it'll respond um
you never know so that was literally
from me
that that's me just looking at that post
instantly and i'll be i'd go test that
now data studio
and i'd also consider is there any of
that same code in date studio
potentially other people have found this
because it was a 2019 post admittedly
but potentially throughout data studio
there were similar bugs
the code was reused do i say developers
reuse code
trend is your friend yeah so everyone
your task
first of all digest all google vrp
write-ups that you can find
whether that's on github whether there's
this other blog posts
whether you know some friends
obviously shouldn't just don't just um
share private information and search
between me if i can give you some hints
or anything like that but yeah
so write endpoints directories and
parameters used
so where was this bug found so let's say
for example it was example.google.com
forward slash friend service forward
slash
whatever whatever go google doc for the
friend
service maybe that leads on to more api
calls and things like that
same with the parameters are these
parameters used everywhere anywhere else
what's going on
um what was the bug found was it a
simple idol
in front of literally everyone did the
xss require a special bypass
um was it a really cool chain where they
needed to
use an open redirect with the server
side request forgery to get this
and pull this do that what was required
here
and then not only that but think about
how has the developer fixed it
because not only when you're going to go
test it but how have they fixed it so
obviously with xss you can fix them
relatively easy but if it's a
complicated bug where you're sending
some sort of server aside request
forgery
server side request but that's what the
features intended to do how did the
developer stop it from being malicious
and broken what did they do
and where was it found basically um
like i said i put this test various ways
to buy test various ways to um
to bypass it and there's actually a
bypass i actually found there on a
heavily tested website recently
where they wanted it to end in jpeg.png
and if i put dot html.jpg
it and it actually saved it as just
file.html
and again write lots and lots of notes
trust me because
when you look through google you're
gonna find things that look so similar
and you're gonna be able to like say
pick up the trend as your friend and be
able to know i know what this is used
for i know where this is blah blah blah
and you'll pick it up trust me you need
to trust the process
and that's why hopefully a lot of you
are gonna follow these tasks i've said
a second task everyone
now so you're digesting all this
information as to where these bugs were
found
xss idols what was going on now your
task is to continue hunting for the next
12 months but not just go overline on
recon
just don't go just run your recon
scanners and i've got a lot of sub
domains and i'm just going to do this
um rather we're going to be focused on
web apps
ones you can interact with log upload
stuff
post stuff and things like that you want
things that has lots to play with
because there's lots of new code shipped
regularly because
even though there's posts um were
disclosed a while ago and they weren't
fixed
how did you know old code wasn't
reintroduced
so find yes we've got to do recon on
google because there's lots out there
john i mean
and there's not just one single hub
point you log into google drive
the main idea of google is the search
engine but they've got google mail
google ads etc etc
so find all google sub domains and
domains because i believe
without looking um a lot of stuff of
google is in scope
i have to check this but check their
policy of what's in scope but find all
google
sub domains that everything that's in
scope you can log in and interact with
because that's the thing you want to
understand how these things work and
break these features
and not only that but when you're doing
your recon you'll make sense of what the
recon means
you understand what this subdomain does
what you can do of it
so make sure you can edit your profile
post some content upload some stuff
etc but check is the login flowy the
same each time every single time
you're logging into the subdomain so
mail.google.com
ads.google.com etc is it the same is it
the same on mobile device
is it the same on android and iphone you
can actually get
iphone and android user agent in your
browser from an extension on either
firefox or google
uh chrome um so you don't actually need
the device to test it how does each
thing work
did they all work the same um and
another common thing
is google don't really care because it's
actually in their policy they don't care
about open redirects right
so with that in mind you're going to
probably find a lot of them out there
so what can they be used for leaking
tokens service request 4g and things
like that
um so yeah
but not only that but test and
understand how each feature
works so and this goes back to not just
trying one bug type everywhere
so for example on google ads you can
invite other users so
let's say for example you invited
another user can you set
permission and roles to this user and
are these permissions and roles working
correctly
do they work correctly is there a google
ads mobile app
has it might not be vulnerable on the on
the desktop version
what about the mobile app what about if
it's a completely different team what
about if they outsourced it a while ago
to get something developed
just to get it off the ground and
they've never really got it changed
you don't know go test and see how it's
working
and again this is why it can take a long
time to really dive deep into programs
and web applications and understand
how they work but honestly if you follow
the advice from here for the next 12
months please do
keep me if you do um try this out please
do keep me updated with how you're
getting on and
i'd love to know because i'm honestly
going to do it as well with you
um just not probably as long not as like
i said not as long but probably not as
much as you like because i don't have
the time really
um but yeah so it may be daunting at
first everyone
what do these parameters do what does
this mean what what happens
if you're completely brand new and you
don't understand anything about hacking
one hundred percent you need to go away
and unders like learn learn hacking
basically
check out pentester lab bug bank hunter
the hacking 101 and things like that and
understand learn check out videos on
youtube tutorials and understand what
hacking is etc
um but unders once you've been looking
on google
and you understand what the parameters
do and things like that
then it will kind of over time make
sense to you um
we've all been there i've been there all
the top hackers have been there
think about it it's fresh to you you're
attacking it blindly aren't you
um but like i say the more you focus on
the target everyone the more you
understand i've seen this parameter
being used i've seen this i know this is
the
crosstalk crest 4g token the more you
test it and the more you click around
and use
and make sure to write notes the more
you will begin
to see the more you'll be able again to
say oh well i actually can
do this and this happens um let's say
rather than just focus on one bug type
i believe in you all though trust me
there are bugs out there
like i say i've hacked with members on
bug bounty hunter of hack events on
a public program which people thought i
mean i'm not going to find anything on
here
and i literally showed them how step by
step we digest the information and what
to do with this and talking and leading
on to things
and they're all now finding bugs by
themselves on this program without me
you can do the same you just got to put
the time and the effort and actually
want it
and actually be like okay i want to make
a complete mind map of how
everything on google works what ones can
i log in what functionality do they have
have any old bugs been found in these
sub domains and you'll get it
good luck everyone and happy hacking i
hope you've enjoyed my talk
i hope i haven't rambled and bored you
all
and i wish you all the best of luck for
the next 12 months and please do
keep me updated and i hope you'll find
some bounties because trust me
they are out there pete