okay good morning everyone
some thinking that we're doing with in
Comcast's related to ipv4 is a service
and I'm not sure if that's a term
everyone's familiar with so I'm going to
give a real quick definition because
that'll put into context kind of the
rest of the talk kind of what we're
thinking about doing is potentially
running ipv4 as an overlay service on
top of an ipv6 underlay network and we
think there's a number of reasons for
doing that I'm going to share with you
the motivations from why you might want
to do that and then give you some
analysis that we've done in the v4 space
that kind of details how v4 is being
used in our network today and then i'm
going to i'm going to give you an
architecture that we're working on here
that would allow us to kind of you know
in run a v4 overlay on top of a v6
infrastructure and you know listening to
russ's talk earlier today it seems like
you know the thinking is kind of in
parallel to what is what Russ is saying
and that we're basically running a
control plane on top of another control
plane we think there may be some value
in terms of doing that let's see I
always had problems with these things
green one green one thank you all right
so I'm going to start off with the
really highly scientific graph here
which basically shows you know the
relationship between v4 and v6 traffic
internet work today and clearly we're
way on the left hand side of this right
where we've got significantly more view
for traffic than v6 traffic but at some
point at some point in the future you
know we will transition where we'll have
more v6 trafficked in v4 and so what
we're starting to do is you're trying to
think about you know what might our
network one what might we want our
network to look like after we've
transitioned to where there's more v6
traffic than v4 do we want it to look
the same or can we do some optimizations
can we start thinking about
optimizations today so that you know as
we ask our vendors for new features and
whatnot or less features that we're
basically setting ourselves up for where
we're going to be post that transition
so we're starting to think about you
know you know what is our network
ecosystem going to look like or you know
you know what's what's the right way to
build networks you know when there's
more v6 traffic than v4 and so kind of
you know we've gone through this before
where we've had protocols that were
deployed everywhere that have you know
basically gone away you know I've listed
a few of them here maybe see LNS should
be
included as well but you know we're kind
of going through this evolutionary you
know sequence where we've had protocols
that have been predominant over time get
subsumed or replaced by other protocols
and we think the same thing is going to
happen for v4 and I'm not suggesting v4
is going to go away completely but what
I'm saying is that we may be able to or
maybe we make sense to start thinking
about you know what our network should
work or how they should work and what
they should look like you get to the
point where there's more of you six
traffic than view 4 ok so kind of what
you know what we're thinking about is
you know building or driving towards a
v6 optimized network and so again you
the thinking here is that you know we're
not going to be you know lifting Oliver
view for traffic on top of a v6
infrastructure today but in the future
what might that look like is I'm going
to give you a couple of concepts here to
give you an idea as to how we think
we're going to baby step in that general
direction the first one is this concept
of a lean core and so you can think of
it as being a network where it's still
dual-stack but what you're doing is
you're looking to reduce the types of
features that you've got there and
you're reducing the size of the fit we
think there's a value in terms of
eliminating complexity by eliminating
features that you're using and that
there's probably some significant cost
savings if we can reduce the size of the
FIB right today we buy routers with
millions of entries for fib for v4 and
v6 I'm going to share with you some data
that basically says we're wasting a lot
of money in that space all right so kind
of we're in ish alee thinking about you
know transitioning or network to this
lean whore sort of concept now there's
another concept here and I think some
service providers are going down this
path today where they're basically
driving their infrastructure to be v6
only right so they're trying to
eliminate v4 all together and then run
before some sort of overlay on top of a
v6 only network infrastructure we're not
going to we're not trying to get there
right right now but we see value in
going not in that path and then you kind
of think of you know a lean via six
cores kind of being the combination of
the two where it's really geared towards
v6 and you're really gearing towards and
reducing the number of entries need to
care in your network and again we're
really targeting that first concept this
kind of lean core sort of concept and
again we think there's really two
primary values that are going to be had
the first is is that if we can eliminate
different types of features that we
don't really need and if we get the
vendors to kind of eliminate them from
their code train that's going to make
you know that's going to eliminate bugs
and make our networks more robust but we
again we think that you know if we can
drive towards this model of having a
thin fib having fibs you know on those
86 that are significantly smaller in
size given how we basically build
networks that will reduce the cost of
the memory for those for those a
six-level reduce the amount of power
word putting into them that will reduce
the amount of heat where we need to cool
along and whatnot so again we're think
there's a fair amount of value in terms
of moving towards this leaner sort of
architecture and that's kind of like
them to talk about here in the next few
minutes and so as you think about moving
down this path you know if we're going
to gear ourselves to try to move towards
more v6 focused and more of a thin fib
sort of architecture but nonetheless we
need to support v4 you know you know
what's the practicality of that ok so
what we did earlier this year is we
basically started doing an analysis of
her network overview for network and
basically this is just showing us about
five days back in February of the amount
of traffic load on a network the amount
of E for traffic on your network chances
are you've seen these graphs before you
may dream about them right this is the
kind of classic kind of you know diurnal
pattern of you know traffic under
networks today now I've had to scrub the
y axis the y-axis basically shows how
much load but what I can tell you is the
y-axis is in terms of terabits a second
and sometimes it's double ditch terabits
per second and that's going to be
important understanding the scale of
this as i talk about subsequent
information here but basically this is
sort of the classic profile of how much
you know happy for how much before
traffic we have in our network today now
this is really kind of probably a more
interesting slide for you what we did
was we took the NetFlow data and we
basically asked you know how much
traffic do we have for every v4 prefix
that we're carrying in afib today on the
backbone on comcast backbone today we
have about five hundred seventy five
thousand five entries so we're getting
bgp updates from all of our peers doing
passed selection whatnot in a
programming the fit and again it's about
575,000 v4 prefixes in there
you notice that this graph here which is
basically showing how many prefixes we
seeing that flow over time the maximum
value there the numbers are kind of
poorly formatted but that that upper
bound is a hundred eighty thousand so
what does what the data wasn't
immediately telling us is even though
we're basically carrying all these
routes and all these prefixes and
jamming into these fibs and asking for
millions of fib entries from the routing
vendors we only only basically send
traffic to about 160,000 prefixes today
v4 prefixes today so what that means is
about seventy two percent and based on
the study back in February two percent
of the FIB entries that we're jamming
into those asics aren't being used at
all seventy-two percent okay so that was
pretty eye opening to us right you know
that we have you know again we're asking
routers to build bigger and bigger
routers with you no more asics for more
more more entries and whatnot and for
the most part we're not using a
significant portion of them today when
you think about it you know Comcast
might be a bit of a special case in the
sense of you know were based in North
America and so getting slashed
twenty-fours from ten or twelve time
zones away maybe it's not surprising you
know that we have a significant number
of entries that we're not sending data
to but nonetheless seventy-two percent
of the entries have no measurable
traffic so it was pretty enlightening
for us so the next thing we want to do
is kind of dig in a little bit more deep
in a little bit more details as to those
160,000 prefixes those prefixes that
dean have measurable traffic what do
they look like we have like a uniform
distribution of traffic to the ones i do
have measurable traffic or is it
exponential in some way as well okay so
this is detailing just as 160,000
prefixes and basically think this is
what we effectively did think of you
know getting 160,000 prefixes where for
every prefix you have a certain amount
of load and sort them you know what you
do is you basically go to the the prefix
with the most amount of traffic and
start working your way down adding up
the amounts of load until you get the
number of prefixes that account for
ninety percent of the load okay and so
what that ninety percent point it means
and that's going to be the number about
3200 basically what that is telling us
is that on the comcast backbone to carry
ninety percent of the v4 load I only
need 3200 prefixes now that's a mix of
Comcast prefixes and internet prefixes
and so the green line basically shows
you know how much of how much that is
made up of Comcast prefixes versus
internet prefixes so in order to carry
ninety percent of my v4 load in the
underlay fit but we need about 3200
prefixes about 2300 of those who become
cows prefixes and about 900 would be
internet prefixes again think about this
you know we're buying line cards with
million of entries for fibs and a
significant portion of the traffic Sam
about a very small number of prefixes
now this is the ninety percent point so
you know if I was going to if I was
going to think about building an
overland and under layer is going to
carry ninety percent in the underlay and
ten percent in the overlay remember that
first slide I showed you that first
graph I showed you where I mentioned
double-digit terabits per second so ten
percent of double-digit terabit per
second still results in terabits per
second so maybe not quite ready to do
that yet because again part of what we
want to do here is transition this into
an overlay that's based on cloud
infrastructure that's a key part of what
we want to do here so if you look a
little bit further to the right you know
basically what we did was we identify
the 99 percent point and again it's the
list of prefixes sorted you know for
most to least and basically identifying
how many prefixes carry 99% of the load
and it turns out that you only need
about 26,000 prefixes at least from you
know the comcast view of the world you
only need about 26,000 prefixes to carry
99% of the load in the comcast network
and about six thousand of those of the
26,000 or Comcast prefixes and about
20,000 our internet prefixes okay so it
seems at least to us that this is pretty
enlightening that again we're building
you're asking these vendors for huge
amounts of memory to store huge amounts
of fib entries for v4 and we're not
using most of it and you know what
remember that very first graph which is
basically showing over time that we're
going to have more v6 traffic to v4 do
we want to continue going down this path
or can we do things more efficiently so
our thinking is you know maybe we need
to rethink how
we're doing our networks here okay so
I've kind of summarized it here again
575,000 v four five entries seventy two
seventy two percent don't carry any
traffic at all don't pull any traffic at
all and then out of the ones that are
pulling traffic you know basically
ninety-nine percent of the traffic load
is identified by about five percent of
the prefixes that we're putting into the
FIB so there's a huge amount of waste
and then kind of thinking of it the
other way we have five hundred and fifty
thousand five hundred forty nine
thousand prefixes that exist that only
carry one percent of the load yeah so
what we think is doing ipv4 as a service
is in fact practical today okay maybe
not for all v4 but we think we can make
a substantial reduction in the terms in
terms of how many entries we need to put
into the FIB by lifting a significant
portion of the v4 prefixes out of the
underlying network and into an overlay
sort of network that's built on cloud
infrastructure now that's not going to
help us today right we're ready put
reverti purchase you know routers that
can handle all these five entries and
whatnot but what it can do is allow us
to kind of validate that this approach
makes sense and that this approach
scales and it is in fact or bus all
right this is sort of again or to think
russ was hinting at is these overlays of
control clients kind of this is kind of
what we're thinking about doing as well
and you know you know so this this kind
of allows us to kind of validate this
approach so that we can go back to the
vendors and say you know what we would
really like you know a v6 focused
platform and we don't need as much
memory on those line cards because it is
practical to build an overlay today and
the other value here is that not only
does it help you send a message to the
existing vendors but maybe it also
lowers to bound for new people to get
into the space in terms of building
forwarding infrastructure as well if we
can reduce what they need to do to
become part of you know big service
provider network okay all right so
basically you know I've given you a
little bit of motivation here you know
as to why are we thinking and moving
down to v6 focus network or makes sense
I've giving you some analysis here as to
kind of halvie for you know at least
from our perspective how we see it being
used in network today and now I'm going
to talk about you know the mechanisms
for you know how we might build an ipv4
overland
work okay so many many different ways
you can do this and I'm only going to
talk about two technologies and these
are really two technologies that were of
interest to a number of folks with in
Comcast's in regard and I'm not going to
go into detail here because I believe
these these these two technologies have
been talked about both here nanigen IETF
and elsewhere in a lot of detail so I'm
going to talk to you about these from
like two distinct ways and when you
think about building an overlay an
overlay Network really consists of two
pivot points the technology the first is
how you do encapsulation so how do you
take in our case a v4 packet and map it
into a v6 packet and so there's
differences between how map map map to
you and Lisp work in that sense and so
you know the classic way you do
encapsulation and this is the way mapi
works in the way list works is we take a
v4 packet and you basically totally
encapsulate that v4 packet inside of a
v6 Packers the visa etc map t works a
little bit differently map t works in
the sense of what it does is it
basically looks at the v4 header and
synthesizes a new visa etc so basically
looks in the information the address
fields in the in the v4 header and
basically derives what this
corresponding v6 address it should be
and so what's on the wire for map t is
in fact slightly smaller than what you
would see form a p or less because it's
not doing full encapsulations basically
taking the v4 payload and it's slapping
a v6 head on top of it there's no v 4v
four header there so that's kind of that
makes it a map to approach you know
simpler than mapi or less pin the sense
it's simpler that it's smaller but
encapsulation is just one part of this
the other part of this is how do you
determine when you capsulate to pack it
how do you determine where to throw that
packet to what's the end point at which
you're going to send it to and so this
is where map the map solutions tend to
be different from lists the map
solutions tend to be more provisioning
based more set of rules that you
basically apply to the border router the
home gateway in advance which basically
give it the information it needs to know
to determine what the remote end point
to send a packet to and Lisp and I'm
going to I'm going to use a slightly
different term now classic Lisp does
something else where they've got a
control plane that's kind of based on
DNS again i'm not sure if people
familiar with kind of class
sick Lisp in the sense of you know it
proposed a mechanism much like DNS where
you do a lookup for a packet or for an
address to determine you know what the
remote endpoint was going to be for so
classic list does this kind of DNS kind
of recursive sort of look up to find you
know the remote end point in which you
should be sending the traffic to and
does some caching what not to to make
that efficient some probing to deal with
you new endpoints going way so the two
differences you know between these
technologies again encapsulation and
what the mechanism is you're using to
determine the remote end point to in our
case you know we wanted to want to go
down the list path we thought let's post
a promising path so the rest of the talk
is going to be talking about the lisp
solution but with a twist okay so we're
doing Lisp encapsulation but we weren't
yet ready or comfortable to basically
move down the path of changing ratting
routing from this push paste routing
model to kind of you know a pull based
quarry model so what we did was we took
you know our Lisp implementation that we
got from dena wherever he might be and
we basically coupled it together with
routing okay so we're thinking again as
we're using the Lisp encapsulation
mechanism but we're still going to use
our classic routing sort of paradigm
were comfortable with that and when we
think about building this overlay it
would be easier to do easier to
operationalize if we basically kept a
kind of common routing paradigm in place
and so you know our thinking is that
we're going to be doing a lisp
encapsulation but we're going to be
using classic routing as the means to
kind of program the information that
Lisp is going to be using for forwarding
information and key here is that you
know cloud and virtualization is going
to be enabler here you know we're
looking to lift this overlay into our
cloud ecosystem and this is going to be
enabled because and this is where we
have the the two the two diagrams here
you know today in the comcast footprint
you know we have cloud and
virtualization at the national data
center level and now we're starting to
bring it into the high levels of the
regional data center levels we think and
feel and this is going to happen where
we're going to be pulling cloud and
virtualization basically all the way
down into the hub site so down to where
we have the CMT s is located today and
it's the fact that we're pulling this
cloud and virtualization down you know
very much to the customer
edge that's going to be in a blur force
to basically bring or instantiate or
begin our ipv4 is a service at that
point okay so so cloud and
virtualization here is going to be key
for us and again you know what we're
trying to do is leverage open source as
much as we can and where we don't quite
have open source you know we're growing
our own code as we need to okay so this
is kind of a high level architecture I'm
going to get into some details in the
subsequent slides here but basically at
the top you know I've got you know our
other providers I've got my backbone
where I've got my peering routers and
whatnot and you know my regional
networks my hub routers and CMT s that's
kind of the classic you know under light
infrastructure that's what we have today
what we envision doing is you know
having an overlay Network where we're
going to have you know virtual machines
running on that cloud infrastructure
tied into you know our peering routers
basically at the top of our networks and
then also having two VMs performing Lisp
encapsulation that are very close to the
customers down in the hub site so unless
to enlist speak they're going to be etrs
egress tunnel routers and itrs ingress
tunnel routers kind of again mostly the
analysis that we've done here was based
on showing that a significant number of
routes that don't pull traffic or
Internet routes and so we're thinking
initially that this this list paradigm
or ipv4 is a service overlay paradigm
would basically operate in one direction
namely outbound okay that's kind of how
we're thinking about getting this going
from the beginning and so you could
imagine in regional networks we'd have a
number of ITRs pulling traffic in and a
number of ETR is basically a tower
appearing locations so this is kind of
like intended to give you a high level
of what the actual architecture is going
to look like if there's a little bit
more details on how the routing is going
to work ok so it's more or less the same
sort of paradigm if you look on the left
hand side there I've got my routes
coming in from my providers coming into
my peering router and then basically by
appearing router is going to basically
identify which of those prefixes are
really the heavy heavy hitter kind of
prefixes what are the ones that are that
have huge amounts of load to them and
we're going to allow those to flow down
through our backbone down through our
metro necks network
down into the hub sites okay so those
are those of the underlight prefixes
those are the 26,000 prefixes I've
talked to you about or 50,000 prefixes
whatever want but those are the prefixes
that have significant load on them our
peering edge router will basically take
all of the routes it's coming into it
and then basically send them over to an
ETR these egress tunnel routers and then
these egress tunnel routers will
basically you know send them to a route
reflector and dare I say maybe a
controller or something like that that
can apply business logic and again this
is sort of aura tizen and what russ was
talking about right we've got this
overlay control plane and this business
logic that sits on top of that that's
sort of embodied here though I didn't
didn't split it out specifically but you
know we've got something acting at the
control plane doing some sort of route
reflection or whatnot maybe doing
something more sophisticated than that
and then it's sending those routes down
to the ITR down into each of the hub
sites or each of the regional networks
and then what that I TR is going to do
is going to inject a default and so what
you can imagine here is that you know
I'm going to be allowing those heavy
hitter prefixes coming down and that's
where my knobs are right by the prefixes
that I'm allowing to come down in the
underlay that's going to detail or
dictate what gets flows over the
underlay or what gets pulled in over the
overlay itself ok now you know what I'm
proposing here is you know effectively
you know we want we want to build a v4
overlay on top of v6 so logically when
you think about it I want a v4 prefixed
with a v6 next top that doesn't exist
today now I know there's an internet
draft out there somewhere in some ways
some form that is basically proposing
exactly this to basically out allow you
to specify EV for prefixed with the v6
next stop as far as I know there's not
publicly available code to do that now
what so what we wanted to do and you
know this is going to die in to some of
the other thinking that we've shared
here NER noggin last couple of years is
that we think there really is value
moving control planes for new kinds of
technologies away from classic BGP bits
and bytes in tlv to instead use JSON and
so it turns out and I think it was the
Google guys not the Google guys here
before me but someone from google or set
of folks from google have written
something called XO bgp
so familiar with it it's pretty slick
what exit vgp allows you to do is to
basically speak classic BGP to see a
classic BGP component but on the other
side it can spit out bgp information in
json okay and that's basically what this
is showing us this is basically the exit
bgp code here in jason is a bgp update
you will recognize all the information
here but it's represented in JSON as
opposed to in a classic bgp unity
alvey's and the beauty of it being in
JSON is the following the beauty is that
it's very easy to extend this right it's
very easy for me to add new attributes
new information that may not be part of
classic be bgp but allows me to
experiment or test out new ideas again
back to russ's experimental sort of
concept and so what we did was we took
the exit vgp output we have an ETR
effectively that speaks classic bgp to
our peering router and then it spits out
json bgp updates you know to an entity a
piece of software we've written and what
that does is basically just add a
next-hop value a v6 next top value all
right so we've got JSON of the original
bgp update and v4 and we take that JSON
information we add a few more attributes
that indicate things like what the beat
what the v6 next top should be and we
basically push that northbound to a
route reflector and today we're doing
this via HTTP ok but you know we wanted
to show that you know the fact that it
is in BGP allows you to extend things
much more easily than you know trying to
you know shoehorn things into a classic
bgp itself ok so this is just kind of
more of a theoretical and again I've had
to have had to remove kind of the y-axis
details and maybe this is pretty
straightforward but each of those lines
there the red line indicates you know
how much load you would have on the
underlay network you know for different
fib sizes so you know I believe the
numbers are the red line is twenty
thousand five entries so if you underlay
was limited to 20 thousand five entries
this basically shows you you know how
much load we would have any underlay and
obviously as you allow the FIB sizes to
grow and more traffic to be pulled on
the underlay the curves get flat and go
down okay so kind of to wrap it up here
so what are we doing
you know we're trying to think about you
know what this futuristic network
architecture would look like again you
know as we're slowly transitioning more
traffic from v42 v6 we're thinking about
what do we want our network ecosystem
look like in the future and so we're
thinking about you know building at an
ipv4 is a service overlay Network to
kind of you know get us you know to be
more efficient in terms of our
underlying infrastructure and this we
think of this as almost as beginning the
trend the beginning of transitioning
services out of the kind of classic
underlay networking into the cloud okay
and v4 is one of the first services that
we're thinking about doing that and
there's value here again because it
gives us it empowers us as service
providers to kind of do the things that
we need to do without having to go to
the vendors and ask them to build
features for us so we find you know a
lot of value in terms of doing that and
you know you the kind of classic Sdn
paradigm do we program the network or do
we make it lean you know today I think
at least from my perspective you know
really make sense to make the underlay
Network lean fewer features a fewer fib
entries and move complexity into the
cloud where we have more ability to kind
of manage it and I just want observation
here again you know you know with Sdn
you have the network and cloud kind of
combining one of the learnings that we
had here you know is that you know
OpenStack you know evolved out of data
center space and so they're still
playing a little bit of catch-up in the
networking space so one of the things we
realized was kind of OpenStack wasn't
quite ready to kind of do all to support
some of the features that we needed to
do this ipv4 is an overlay now kilo just
came out in April and it sounds like
kilo might have the features but we
haven't got a chance to really look at
it but you know there's still some
catch-up that the OpenStack folks are
doing to kind of get us to this point to
get us to the point where you really do
network services on top of cloud
infrastructure and then just one other
slide here this is I guess the third
time have been to nanog you in June to
kind of present and I just wanted to
kind of connect the dots because I think
these things do really connect together
and again two years ago you know is here
up up on the stage here proposing and it
makes sense or we believe it makes sense
to start transitioning control planes to
kind of be more JSON and
people rented and you know again it
looks like other service providers are
going down that same path Google went
out and built you know XO bgp i don't
know if it was specifically to support
json or just as amazing doing
troubleshooting but there seems to be a
little bit more energy behind kind of
reevaluating how we do control planes
and maybe this touches again back on
what russ was talking about so we think
there is you know control plane
evolution clearly control plane
evolution that we're leveraging today
you know last year we were proposing or
talking about what we were calling this
hybrid router platform architecture the
ability within a component router to
basically add your own operator specific
code and you know we you know we propose
that we demonstrated last year writing
segment or building our own version of
segment routing and running on the box
and actually you know dropping in our
own version of Isis as well so that was
kind of like legacy or platform
evolution within the box and kind of
what we're suggesting today we think is
really kind of like an end-to-end kind
of evolution where now we're basically
refining assets of services that are
happening within the network ecosystem
and then lifting the the ones we really
need to have more agility to and putting
them into the cloud okay all right so
that's my talk thank you much for your
time
what hi Brian Allen to run from I can I
would like to make a comment in a
question than for you comment is about a
very futuristic technology that was made
in 2009 it's a in RFC 5512 and 55 65 the
talks about you can have an athena safi
in BGP 34 others families so I 12 and
done because some friends from zernich
in China had an ipv6 only backbone they
wanted to about bgp forever ipv4
universities so the first one described
the office a second one described a
framework and now this is all done our
is implemented to virus vendors I'm not
quite sure about different vendors have
done different routes that the actual
technology exists it has been
implemented where at least in China kept
very think so well the second is a
question is about a number of prefixes
how many prefixes do you foresee in an
ipv6 mostly world I've out different
comments people saying is going to be
really small people think is going to be
about the same as default there's no
difference what's your ticket so I think
the thinking is that we think it's it's
not going to be nearly as bad as before
today and maybe not as well as we would
like it to be kind of like in cherry pie
v6 space so I think it's going to be
somewhere in between but the thinking
would be you know that we're not or
hopefully not going to need to do is
much kind of we're not going to have
been going down the same evolutionary
path that we went with before you know
side or pre side or all those sorts of
issues so hopefully we'll have built you
know an addressing plan that is much
more scalable with fewer prefixes thank
you
yep Randy bush i J the 70 odd percent
reduction in fib size is gained by a
very trivial hack which one the IRT fanr
award sitcom awards etc etc called
dragon home and is essentially the the
reduction of routing entries that are
redundant and real cheap talked to your
vendor and we can all get this with out
Jason okay thank you so the hominoid
lature neighbor thanks for the data on
the prefix traffic distribution I knew
that it was uneven but they didn't knew
that it was that bad a question to you
actually do you think it would make
sense to build forwarding planes
entirely different and incorporating
memory hierarchies I mean the reason why
fibs are so expensive today is because
we are using srams in order to produce
two million fib entries and just take a
look at your laptop right there's a
hierarchy of memory there's l1 cache l2
cache drm do you think it would make
sense to build in memory hierarchies in
forwarding engines as well in order to
tackle the cost problem there yeah it
may and I think it depends you know in
terms of how we were in a tank of the
network moving forward you know how much
of you know the services do we want to
put into the cloud make sense to put
into cloud how much of it we need to
remain you know in the in the underlay
network itself so certainly it couldn't
hurt to you know continue or look at
those technologies because I'm the
locality thing I mean we have the
problem not just for before all we see
the same thing on you know certain GRE
tunnels certain mpls entries certainly
six routes also having those power law
distributions right right and you know
again it in an i don't know if you know
with rust again what he was saying you
know with the centralized controller and
what not and I'm not suggesting we go
down that path but I think there's a
desire from service providers you know
to kind of you know have more ability to
manage and what's happening in the
network and in the process can we
eliminate what's happening there and so
the parallel the paradigm when I was
thinking about this it's as if you know
even with the hierarchical stuff it's
like you know we're asking the vendors
to build like a concrete highway to
every taco bell 7 11 and Pizza Hut
that's going to be made in the entire
world and for the most part we're not
using most of those lanes because you go
to the pizza hut nearby right so we can
maybe solve this via other mechanisms
but again I question you know is that
the right paradigm or do we have do we
think about solving it differently but
I'm not saying not to investigate that
path okay right point taken thank you
Jeff Houston a painting look I was kind
of curious about your comment about fear
and I'm kind of wondering if it's the
size or the speed that is really the
issue with fear and the cross point is
to cost them right well costs number of
gates you know that sighs very speed is
something that's really hard to buy
right because at some point you just
can't go any faster right and
realistically is speed the problem here
as distinct from size so i think it's
the two the two combined together and in
v6 when in essence you're going to use
128-bit wide fit entries which is four
times the size so hopefully we've gotten
many mirror fewer you know entries in
there fed right four times fewer round
good luck thank you yes I was Phil
Rosenthal for my his prime I was
wondering if if you had given any
thought to I don't know how many people
in the room remember the SQL slammer
worm that decade ago
in the case where you have something
like that where you're now sending
packets to every single IP address on
the internet at random what happens when
you're now you know you no longer have
you know really fast SRAM for processing
you know that right now we haven't
looked at that so I'm sorry yes
pollutant speaking with my pms ECT
dotnet hot I wanted to thank you for
sharing the results of your IP before
prefixes analysis with the debate but
also from Spotify we did present
recently a similar analysis that we did
but of course from the Spotify network
so it was very interesting to see that
both from a content provider and from
eyeballs provider so let's say I would
regard calm casting eyeballs provider we
have very similar results so I was
tending to think that the very low
entries that we did see so the
ninety-nine percent was 16 k prefixes I
was thinking that's because it's a
content provider with any cast and
things like that but actually you come
up with very similar results so that is
very interesting i think there was
nothing like that public before so very
good and i have a second comment which
is you mentioned the ex ability i want
to just make the attribution right so x
a bgp is from thomas managing from AXA
networks in the UK and you're absolutely
not from google okay thank you Thanks
yeah
just one more please and then yeah a
bill Goldstein retired from AT&T but
here in my own representing only myself
first forgive up perhaps a dumb question
to a very smart presentation are there
any security schemes out there of like
deep packet inspection being run in net
well perhaps on provider networks but in
large customer networks that might
reject your encapsulated packets so the
encapsulation is purely within the
comcast footprint so we would come in
from our customers as a normal v4 packet
and then it would spit on the other side
is a normal view for packet okay all
right well I'm sorry was it dumb
question that the second question is uh
yeah I personally I like what you have
here but are there any minimum standards
or that that have to be added in the
large-scale provider networks which you
and we all depend on in order to enable
your in your encapsulation scheme in
lisp here so now I mean you know the all
the Lisp encapsulation stuff is well
documented in RFC is today zoom and
again there's a number of open source
implementations of that okay thank you
thank you very much Brian ah so