good morning good morning how's everyone
doing this morning all right okay so
we've got a look biggest nanog ever all
right so folks at the back of the room
there's still a bunch of seating up here
near the front don't be shy coming up
left and right sides still get about 20
30 seats up here so come on up I just
wanted to welcome everyone to Nana at 64
yay and we'll other presentation up
there in a sec here we go yeah went a
little too far okay nope all right good
morning my name is Dan Goulding I'm the
chairman of nanog sportive directors I
wanted to welcome everyone here to nanog
64 this is nghia Nog's largest meeting
ever and I wanted to take this
opportunity to well to welcome you as
our members as our attendees as our
sponsors and friends and also to take an
opportunity this morning to thank some
of the people who've helped to make this
nanog meeting and all of the other nanog
meetings possible so before we start out
I wanted to recognize the folks who
primarily make this meeting happen and
that is our nanog staff led by executive
director of Betty Burke so folks good
so some of the other folks who make this
thing happen and nanog is a little bit
different most of the conference's most
the eventual go to their throne by
vendors they're done by media companies
nanog is a very different kind of animal
nanog is an organization run by
volunteers and a very very small
professional staff and those volunteers
are composed of members of the community
who are elected or from volunteer for
various positions of responsibility
those include membership on our board of
directors our program committee our
communications committee in a variety of
other tasks including our technical
committee first let me talk a little bit
about the attendee demographic what
you'll notice here today is that the
folks who attend an an augur a little
bit different from the folks you see in
most conferences especially folks you've
seen a lot of conferences in the San
Francisco Bay Area we're not full of
venture capitalists you know we're not
full of people pitching ideas what we
are full of however is what we're full
of our network engineers so what we are
and what we always have been is in
operators forum for professional network
engineers the folks who run the networks
the folks around the broadband networks
the folks who are on the content
networks content delivery networks
universities nonprofits government
networks you have it and our goal is
education our goal is to raise the level
of skill our goal is to share knowledge
with each other our goals here are not
to sell things our goals here are not to
make money for people you know this is
this is sort of an old-time event that's
carried over from the first days of the
internet and its successful even more
successful today that doesn't mean nanog
isn't evolving we're evolving quite a
bit we're constantly looking and
searching to make nanog more useful and
more important for the folks who come
and attend and that's one reason I think
you'll see that our program committee
who has put together an incredibly great
program for us is really focusing on a
lot of the new technology and a lot of
the new advancements that we're all have
to learn to stay relevant and a rapidly
changing network landscape one other
thing that's special about an a
non-conference is this as a
peer-reviewed program now one thing
you're going to see this morning is a
lot of sponsors and we really appreciate
our sponsors our sponsors are your
employer's your vendors the people all
around us but one difference between an
ordinary conference and nanog is that
the sponsors don't control the program
here and I say this as someone who works
for one of the sponsors when you look at
the program that's put together by the
program committee there's no paper pay
for play here there's no control once
you get into one of these rooms
everything sponsorship related except
for a brief thank you is absolutely off
limits and I believe we're one of the
very few conferences in the country and
in the region regardless whether they
say so or not we're one of the very few
that can make that claim and it's
absolutely one hundred percent true and
I'd like to thank our program committee
who zealously guards their independence
and who guards the integrity of nanog
meetings thank
now so now exhibit has been around now
for almost 22 years and a career out of
the original NSF regional tech meetings
in the past couple years we've been
trying to do a few things differently
I'm so in addition to the three time of
year fulminated conferences we also do
what are called nanog on the road
conferences which are smaller events
held in smaller cities where we try to
get the local operator community
involved we try to bring some of this
content from the larger conferences to
smaller venues weary typically a 50 to
100 attendees I urge folks attending
this conference to come to the nanog on
the road events both to bring content to
meet prospective engineers to do a
little recruiting to socialize they're
great events nana also is a strong
commitment to supporting new operators
when Sonia Naga is a membership
organization and some of the folks here
members in some art but the board of
directors is accountable to the members
and when we listen to them what they
tell us their most significant concern
is is where do I find new network
engineers where do i find you know
people who are at least as good as the
people i have now more of them and folks
who will understand a lot of the new
technologies coming down the line so
nanog is an organization has a
commitment to supporting new operators
both new network providers and also
existing providers looking for new
sources of staff we have a couple of
programs that support that we've got the
college immersion program and do we have
any college immersion program students
in the room today you know raise your
hands your college immersion program
student so we definitely have a couple
of those folks in the room and what we
do is we work with professors in network
engineering undergraduate and graduate
programs to bring groups of their
students to nanog conferences so that
they can learn a little bit about
carrier network engineering and so they
can sort of advanced in their coursework
and we get a chance to meet them we also
have a variety of fellowships the
operator of tomorrow fellowship Diablo
we just a fellowship where we try to
take folks who are promising future
operators and fly them out to nanog all
expenses paid so that they can learn
about what we're doing
and have a chance to meet the folks here
who are attendees so the last thing I
want to do is to read it again we we
have revenger neutral on the program is
off limits that being said I do want to
take the opportunity to thank our
sponsors we have two groups of sponsors
we have our premium sponsors who sponsor
nana's you read activities and we also
have individual meeting sponsors I'd
like to thank all of them and there
you'll see their logos on various boards
around the event so what should you
expect here at nanog 64 you've got a
couple different things you've got the
general session content and that's going
to be in this room it's what we call the
plenary session and it's its content
that's of interest to we feel all the
folks coming to Nana we also have tracks
those tracks are in smaller rooms
generally they run against each other
and there are areas of interest to a
subset of folks good examples of the
peering track the data center track and
a variety of other sort of special
interest tracks we encourage everyone to
attend them and if you find one you're
not interested in your free to jump out
and jump into another track it's great
content well as have tutorials those are
primarily tomorrow this time there's
some outstanding tutorials things like
Python for netops DWDM troubleshooting
the tutorials have become one of the
crown jewels of nanog to the point where
the tutorial presentations are used as a
standard part of knock and network
engineering training at many many
carriers strongly encourage people to
attend the tutorials the content is
really great we have lunches today and
tomorrow all of our food is up on the
Betty on the 32nd floor so there is an
elevator ride to get to the food we
apologize the elevators usually work
yeah so so the elevators usually work
they're great they're very fast they do
run on windows yes so sorry Microsoft
people so we've got a social tonight the
social tonight is sponsored by our
friends and Netflix and then we have the
beer and gear tomorrow night and then we
also have a Tuesday evening social as
well so here's some of our information I
think this is up to date more or less we
have a lot of newcomers of this event
374 folks probably a little more by now
are new to nanog and we appreciate you
coming thank you very much of the folks
of our 718 nanog members 223 of them are
attending this event Thank You members
we look forward to seeing you and our
members breakfast tomorrow morning and
we thank you because those members are
not only folks who pay money to be
members there are also the folks who
make up our volunteer corps the folks
who are on our program committee our
communication committee they help with
our educational efforts the folks on our
board of directors tour members thank
you so much and finally attendees our
number so far is 1162 I don't think that
counts single day attendees do we have
an update mr. charnock it's higher than
that so it's it's some it's some insane
number of people in any event as we
reach 1200 this is our largest ever
nanog our second largest now was I'm
sorry 1170 in climbing and that beats
our last record in bellevue of 899
attendees so thanks everyone for coming
we really appreciate it here's a list of
our host connectivity premium
infrastructure sponsors these are not
all of our sponsors these are the folks
who are sponsoring either annual
sponsorships or they're helping us with
the the connectivity or they're the
meeting host thank you to all of these
folks now I'd like to introduce the host
so every nanog azhar host which is a
company that's part of our community and
they put in a tremendous amount of work
both money and time and effort into
making these events a success our host
for this nanog is Netflix I'd like to
introduce Aaron clink for a few words
Thank You Aaron
Thanks am so yeah I'm Aaron click senior
manager for Network strategy at Netflix
assume we are happy to again host here
in San Francisco with this amazing
turnouts in addition our amazing weather
which we hope you all enjoyed this
morning so as some of you have you know
may have noticed I'm not Dave Temkin I
am NOT the chairman of the board of of
nanog so surprisingly dave is not on a
plane he is not on a boat he's not on a
train and he's not in an uber he's
actually meeting with executive
management at netflix in los gatos and
and this is kind of the overall net in
netflix discussions so why are we
interested in nanna why are we
sponsoring why are we hosting this why
are we so involved it and it's because
Netflix runs on the internet and and
that kind of goes along with engineering
and ops and interconnection and
provisioning and hardware and software
and all the other related services that
are involved in our business that people
in this room and in the Nano community
represent and make happen on a daily
basis you know so when we see ass and
vine report that says Netflix is roughly
thirty seven percent of downstream
traffic for peak evening hours that's
something that resonates on a global
basis both within our org and within the
overall nanog and global internet kind
of operations and engineering community
so you know what we look at nana as a
platform for education and for sharing
best common practices and overall
driving the scale of the internet
forward so you know kind of real quick
we have a kind of medium sized presence
here we have Dave David Mara Mike Ryan
me of course Peter Cohen Jill Nina Gabe
Fabrice Brady Anina and NAT who I
haven't met yet because I think he
started on Thursday and yet he's here so
we'll find him and you know give him a
good harassing so say hi to the new guy
at Netflix if if you run into net and
and this is where these slides got so so
the windows XP embedded is what is
taking you to and from the 32nd floor
and christian Koch apparently was stuck
on the elevator for only five minutes
while it rebooted earlier coming down
from breakfast so so we got that in if
anyone else has some lovely elevator
shots later we hope you're not stuck too
long in the elevator it and finally you
know Netflix has jobs and the 14 of us
are around here to discuss if there are
openings that you're interested in
discussing or have any questions about
Netflix overall and and how you can kind
of better be involved with us an ISP or
better be involved in nanog we're happy
to play ambassador for that thanks Thank
You Aaron next I'd like to introduce
Mike Vogel with comcast comcast is one
of our to connectivity sponsors for this
event as you've noticed we have blinding
fast internet as we probably should in
an Internet engineering conference so
Mike take it away thank you and in fact
there's so many people here we had to
have to connectivity sponsors so it's
that big in terms of what we do a lot of
people know what we do from an ISP
perspective but we do a lot of other
things what we did for the connectivity
at this conference is we utilized our
comcast business group which through the
standard operating process they
provisioned fiber from the street into
the facility and we turn that up in
generally less than a month from the
local network it goes out to our main
asn 7922 where it reaches our global
network some of the other things we do a
comcast that people may be aware of may
not be aware of before content ends up
on the internet it's generally produced
via comcast wholesale my business unit
or at one of our production units like
Universal carnival films focus features
etc some of the things we've been doing
recently in the news we're rolling out
to gig residential service of the homes
starting in Atlanta moving into the Bay
Area and other metropolitan markets live
streaming to the x1 Xfinity platform in
the home some things we're doing with
the open source community with Apache
traffic server and OpenStack a lot of
things were happy to provide information
we post a lot of things on github and
we're more than happy to provide more
information to the open source community
and other thing coming out later this
year is 4k UHD set-top box connectivity
to the home some of the things with our
NBC universal group which is driving a
lot of the content on the internet fast
and furious hitting 1 billion earlier in
the year pitch perfect having a major
opening in four am a film minions films
coming out this summer my favorite Ted
to that I'm looking forward to and next
week Jurassic world opening up we are
sponsoring the break later today at two
thirty we'll be giving away a couple
gift baskets from NBC Universal as well
as having an entry where we'll be
providing Fandango gift certificates
another Comcast company to allow people
see hopefully lost world or another
universal film this summer so thank you
so this is our biggest conference ever
accordingly we have to connectivity
sponsors I'd like to introduce mr. Jack
waters chief technical officer of level
3 Jack I don't have any slides sorry
breaking ranks here yay whoo so I have a
confession to make I Dan mentioned the
first nanog was 23 years ago my last
nanog was 23 years ago and and to be a
hundred percent clear I've actually
never been doin an odd my last meeting
was a regional text meeting in boulder
colorado where i live today we're for
those that remember Martin offer and
Elise Garrick I'm not sure any of them
that's where the name nanog came from
that meeting so it has a kind and dear
part of my heart I see two people in the
room that were actually there that day
Sean Kennedy way in the back there from
XL and Bill Manning so thanks for
sticking it out guys you know it's kind
of funny the things that we worried
about back then were I was trying to
make notes you know gosh you guys think
about all these very complicated things
now and and back then we were worried
about the t3 NSFNET cider those are
remember classless routing IBM artis
remember IBM artis the routers remember
them yeah those are those are awesome
sorry IBM NSF proposal 9352 does anybody
know what that is that was the
privatization of the NSFNET which
created all this great public networking
stuff that we all are enjoying today and
those were awesome times there were 30
people in the room just to be clear back
then there are 1,200 people in the room
or registered today
so it does still feel like the same
spirit that I remember back many many
years ago same interest and and love of
the Internet I think the bar bills might
be bigger right so I've heard there's a
little drinking that still goes on here
is that right a little bit okay and so
level three I think our company started
about 18 years right right about 18
years ago I joined wonder about 10
people today we have about 13 thousand
ten thousand here in the US another
couple thousand in Latin America another
fifteen hundred or so folks in in Europe
so we're a big company now but but we
still love the internet and love to be a
part of it we're happy to be a
conductivity sponsor we would like to
thank PG&E for pulling our fiber out of
the hotel about four months ago so we
had to repo it and so thanks thanks PG&E
for that thanks to Dave chem potempkin
and everybody in netflix were we're
happy to be a great partner with netflix
and and they have a great product and
thanks to all of you for making the
other internet bigger better and safer
have a great now nanog two to the sixth
i think great thanks a lot
okay so are as i said before our
incredible agenda is put together by the
nano program committee which is composed
of nanog members where volunteers who
devoted tremendous amount of time to
this effort the person who leads that is
Tony topper is the chair of our nanog
program committee Tony thanks and so
just so people are clear that's kind of
the the end of the sponsor and paid for
part of things no no no no so you know
what that that was clearly all
promotional and and that's our
appreciation of the money and effort
that they've contributed to making the
meeting possible the folks who actually
helped review and the program
submissions from from folks who would
like to speak here are all listed here
they spend hours and hours over many
months reviewing submissions slides
working with presenters to develop their
talks and and then even working here
operationally to make the show happen
through the the presentations you know
getting the slides up and into the and
onto the web page so wanted to thank all
these folks things that have happened
since since we last talked there's a new
piece we tool that we had the first
version of at the last meeting but we
spent a lot of time now with some
contract development help courtesy of
the board funding it to to make our work
easier and smoother in to make the work
of the the folks who manage the website
and thus guidebook app to you know have
automation to integrate all that so that
it passes through without a lot of
manual effort still working through some
of the kinks so if you see some things
where you know snot all the presenters
have BIOS or the some of them are
right and and the meeting materials
aren't aren't up the timely way we're
still working through the first version
of that so please have patience with it
the grand ballroom sessions will be
webcast and archived and you should see
like a little webcasting icon on the
left hand side of the agenda slot with
those and you can click on that and look
at the webcast after the meeting you'll
they'll be a link added to a YouTube
video and we appreciate that that Google
and YouTube help to sponsor the the
archiving of the content many of the
other tracks will you know that happened
in other rooms some some tracks will
happen in this room there's a couple of
other rooms that that also contain
tracks we're trying to get as much of it
videotaped and archived as well even if
it's not webcast can't promise that
we'll have it all but you know that
that's the hope and the goal so be on
the lookout for that there's just some
other program notes so there's a
tutorial that's tomorrow there's there's
two different slots basically there's a
930 and eleven o'clock slot with a break
in between one of the tutorials runs
through both of them which is the netops
coding one so you'll see if you walk
into the second part of that you'll
maybe get the feeling that it's already
been going so that's why that is not to
say that you can't do that but just just
a heads up that if you want to learn
that part try and get there for the the
early session too and here's another
departure this time and hopefully won't
catch too many people by surprise
there's the peering track so
traditionally nanog has had the thing
called peering track it used to be
called bearing buff back in the days
that bill Norton started it and it had a
variety of different things you know
things that were special interest to
interconnection you know topics and then
how the thing called peering personals
so that that bill thought up where
people would at least I hope I'm giving
bill the right credit or not taking it
away from someone else where people
would come up and talk
about well I want to you know I'm from a
s whatever and this is where we have
presence and and and and peer with us
and so there was that part and then
there was what they called IX updates
where folks who operated in her
connection points would come and talk
about things that they've done and new
capabilities that they've had on offer
so those you know over the many years of
nanog you know the the focus of that
seemed to be kind of getting stale and
also it seemed a bit promotional where
people were coming up and you know doing
that that kind of presentation so what
we did was we went with something now
called peering personals which is going
to happen today and there's a link on
the website to submit a form which
people have done in advance we may be
kind of full up at this point but like I
said this is a this is a new thing so
we're kind of getting used to it and so
that the peering personals will happen
at 5pm today after the general session
and then the first track block and and
they'll be toward the end of the day but
before the netflix social and that is
programmed outside the purview of the
program committee so if we do expect it
to be you know essentially somewhat
promotional where people come up and
talk about their internet exchange or
they're from a s blonde they want to
connect with other folks there'll be
some refreshments there also so we'd
like you to come to that there's also
appearing track which will have non
promotional content as the goal and that
will be on wednesday afternoon in the
earlier part of the afternoon where it
had been in the later part of the
afternoon so this is this is a little
bit of a change but i want to get people
the heads-up that we're splitting those
things apart so the peering trap will be
topics related to inter connection but
but in a more traditional nanog non
promotional vein so
we've got a lot of different things I
had tried to set this up as a slide that
kind of built incremental e by the
didn't work out so you know regulatory
always popular we have some of that this
morning one of the speakers was delayed
so we'll get him Reese lauded and into
tomorrow or the next day automation
we've got several talks about automation
in addition to the the coding tutorial
that I talked about tomorrow there's a
few other things that you know that's
obviously how topic ipv6 and its
discontents you know whatever it's being
rolled out and some experience with that
new architectures and technologies
particularly on Wednesday we have a
number of talks that kind of clustered
their measurements is always a big topic
so there's that security there's a
security track but a lot of different
talks about security three-letter word
starts with s no it's not sex it's sdn
and then you know a lot of other stuff
and obviously hopefully you've all had a
chance to look at the agenda and see
what's on there just some reminders so
we've got outside the general session
breaks and it's an espresso bar that's a
sponsored thing what we would ask though
is if you go out in that session during
sorry in that area during the time that
the time we r talks are going on please
try and be quiet or move just a little
further away because the doors open and
close and we get a lot of chatter and
and noise ins very distracting so
appreciate your your consideration their
breakfast and lunch as dan also touched
on they're going to be oh it was
supposed to say not overflow but they're
on the 32nd floor so that's the elevator
that hopefully will not have any more
outages and will take you right to the
cloud so so yeah I can't believe no one
no one got that before no I know I know
but I mean I can't believe no one no one
no one hit that one okay so QA and
microphone guidelines so there's
microphones two microphones in each of
the aisles
forward and back and what we'd like to
do is toward the end of most of the
presentations we invite people to to
come and ask questions of the speaker
and have a little back and forth so soak
you up and we'll try and distribute
fairly you know pick pick the people as
they first arrive to the to the queues
and you know it fit in as many as
possible I mean we have full agenda so
we need to keep things moving so please
don't feel slighted if if we do get cut
off will hopefully give you some warning
that that's going to happen introduce
yourself with your name and affiliation
please be respectful and courteous I
think that's normal you know stay and
listen to the answer and you know make
eye contact with the with the person who
asked a question of that's that's kind
of normal stuff but maybe not everyone
gets it and be pleased be briefing to
the point not you know go on a long rant
and make a statement let's see surveys
ok so the program committee and and the
the other planning aspects of the
meeting really can benefit from your
feedback so so we have surveys and we'd
like you to take them there's I think
they're available not only on the
website but through the app the
guidebook app and to help encourage your
participation we have some giveaways
which i think is a five-hundred-dollar
amazon gift cards and there's going to
be three different giveaways right Betty
okay so that's pretty nice thing to you
know you can obviously spend it on
almost anything there or you can get
almost anything there you can spend it
on anything but so we'll do one on
Tuesday morning you know fill out
surveys on Monday after the after the
contents done and then on Tuesday
morning we'll we'll do a drawing you
have to be I think in the room to to
receive it ok and Wednesday morning for
the Tuesday surveys and likewise last
Wednesday afternoon for the at the end
of the conference so we encourage you to
stick around and also fill out all the
surveys so with that I'd like
too oh yeah one more program note before
I go on to this is that one of our
speakers was a delayed i think i
mentioned that from this morning Russ
buntrock who's going to be the speaker
after next who is slotted to be wasn't
able to make it so the good side is the
other speakers will have time to expand
a little and maybe we'll end up breaking
a few minutes early for lunch if if it
comes to that but so please we'll get
bra sorry scheduled and fit in but that
you know when you see when you look up
and say okay who's on now and it's
ross's time it won't be Ross it'll be
one of the other folks and we didn't get
a chance to update the agenda online yet
so with that I can invite the you can go
you're excused