and please welcome Chris
Luke Utilities Commission who's going to
talk a bit about the will get chris's
slides up regulators read on the open
Internet order and regulatory
proceedings so here's your clicker dingo
ok forward back thank you
good morning that's pleasure to be here
I my name is Chris Weidman I'm senior
counsel at the California Public
Utilities Commission I'd really like to
thank you for having me here and
especially thank Tony for his patients
in fielding my questions over the
weekend first the disclaimer I am NOT
here representing the California Public
Utilities Commission I'm speaking on my
own behalf and my views are my own and
should not be attributed to the Public
Utilities Commission the second caveat
is the open Internet order itself this
is a 400-page tome it has multiple parts
over 2,000 footnotes not all of which
are consistent internally consistent so
i cant pretend to have mastered it all
and may have to get back to you on some
of your questions so with that said I'm
honored to be speaking from the same
stage figuratively from which
Christopher you addressed you at your
winter meeting I have a very different
perspective than professor you but I do
agree with two things that he said at
the outset of his speech one lawyers and
policymakers need to understand the
technology a lot better and
technologists may need to understand
aspects of the policy-making world
better so I'm looking forward to
dialogue to your questions this is why
I'm here and hopefully we can close that
gap the second thing he said was the US
has adopted a different regime than the
rest of the world when it comes to
internet access for the rest of the
world broadband internet access service
is part of an existing regulatory regime
that governs all electronic
communication networks cable fiber
copper wireless and transport and all
protocols whether it be TDM IP or other
in the United States we've tried to
develop separate rules specifically
tailored to Internet access and IP
network built on the notion that access
to the Internet is itself an information
service one that you can't separate from
its transport underpinning so that that
really is the theme what I'm going to be
talking about today so blow through that
common carriage is a concept that goes
back into the common law 16th 17th
century bridges ferry boats bottleneck
facilities and its key components were
non-discrimination rule and fair and
reasonable rates in our context today
and in the context of the open Internet
order the fair and reasonable rates is
this is not about rate setting so we're
going to focus on the non-discrimination
portion of common carriage the primary
analog in the United States is the
railroad in response to widespread
public outrage about the power of the
railroads the power of railroad the
railroad barons and how they could
control the United States and California
economy and the politics it's one reason
for it by the way why the Public
Utilities Commission is in San Francisco
and not in Sacramento in response to
that on the federal level you had the
interstate commerce act of 1980 of 1887
and the founding of the California
Public Utilities Commission which was
then called the Railroad Commission
common carriage is also the foundation
of telecommunications in the United
States for the entire 20th century it
ran on the concept of this separate of
this non-discrimination principle and
this separation
between the conduit and the content and
this continued even through the early
years of the internet the FCC's computer
inquiries in the 1980s and 1990s were
very clear about a separation between
facilities on the one hand and content
on the other and in fact required at one
point the telcos to have separate
subsidiaries to run their transport
operations as opposed to any information
services they were into so this
continued until 2002 and then we have
what I refer to as the FCC's original
sin this was a and led to the us all
being cast out of the garden this was a
decision I this was a decision where the
FCC did away with this division between
conduit and content between carrier and
payload and determined that they were no
longer separable they were together
formed an inseparable information
service held together with the special
DNS saws this decision went up to the US
Supreme Court in 2005 in the brand x
decision and the Supreme Court did not
approve the FCC's logic but rather
deferred to it as a doctrine called
Chevron deference one of the dissenters
was Justice Scalia interestingly enough
who said this is just too clever by half
the famous pizza analogy clearly when
you order a pizza you can think about
the pizza delivery separate from the
pizza so years of litigation confusion
and wandering in the desert ensued I
myself was party to several night
circuit cases involving companies that
claimed
that IP transport was something entirely
different than what was contemplated in
their interconnection agreements so the
FCC attempted a number of fixes none of
which worked in 2005 they came up with
four principles that consumers are
entitled to access the lawful Internet
content of their choice they're entitled
to run applications and services of
their choice they're entitled to connect
the devices of their choice and they're
entitled to competition among carrier's
network providers application and
service providers and content providers
well this didn't it wasn't into long
until Free Press brought a complaint
based on a guy who liked barbershop
quartets and he used bittorrent to share
his barbershop quartets with his fellow
aficionados and discovered that for some
reason the transmissions were
interrupted I think he discovered that
the technical thing that was happening
was a tcp reset function Free Press
brought the case to the FCC the FCC
called out a violation and required
Comcast to change its ways Comcast was
the carrier in question Comcast appealed
it went to the DC Circuit and the DC
Circuit rejected the four principles in
a 2008 decision because the FCC really
couldn't identify the authority on which
it had propounded those four principles
I think the real problem was there were
principles they weren't rules in any
event the FCC went back to the drawing
board in 2010 they came up with an order
this time they had rules no blocking no
discrimination transparency but again
based on this concept that broadband
internet access service was a
information service and not a common
carrier tell
communication service so this case went
finally back to the DC Circuit Judge
title a blind man who is just a
phenomenal jurist i mean he he ruled
against the FCC twice but in each case
it was really well reasoned and he
ultimately wrote the decision this
decision in 2014 which agreed that that
content discrimination was a problem
approved the FCC's logic and authority
to do something about the problem but
rejected the FCC's broken model you
can't do this the court said if you call
broadband access and information service
so your problem is what you did back in
two thousand two essentially you have to
reclassify broadband as a
telecommunications transport service
well the good news for the FCC was that
the DC Circuit decision was really a
roadmap to reclassification a broadband
internet access server as service as a
common carriage service but still the
FCC didn't get it in late 2014 they
floated mid-2014 they floated proposals
that were again based on this
information service classification it
did not look good until four million
people wrote in to the FCC ninety-nine
percent of which were in favor of
reclassification as a common carriage
until John Oliver went on HBO with his
famous ran and until President Obama's
strong's it clear and I think really
knowledgeable statement about we need
title to I I listen to the guy my own
take was this he gets it he understands
the technology so the FCC reworked the
rules they reclassified broadband as a
telecom service
uh and applied the rules to wireless as
well as wireline so what are these rules
going forward well you have your three
bright line rules no blocking no
throttling no paid prioritization you
have a general conduct rule no
unreasonable interference or
unreasonable disadvantage and you have
an enhanced privacy excuse me enhance
transparency rule which is essentially a
consumer protection device you must
disclose what your networks are about so
on the no blocking no blocking of
content applications or services that's
pretty straightforward there were two
exceptions reasonable network management
we'll talk about that in a minute and
unlawful content I know that's a whole
other subject I'm not going to get into
that at all the second rule was no
throttling this again is a bright-line
rule not addressed to outright blocking
but conduct that inhibits the delivery
of particular content apps or services
or particular classes of content apps or
services again two exceptions the
reasonable network management and the
customer chosen speed tier so if you
choose the lower speed tier for a lower
amount of money that would be if you are
essentially agreeing to that it's
customer driven the FCC specifically
mentions the problem of a carrier
threading throttling the over-the-top
content that competes with the carrier's
own content throttling is the flipside
of paid prioritization so that's the
third rule no paid prioritization
paid prioritization refers to the
management of a broadband providers
network to directly or indirectly favor
some traffic over other traffic by
traffic shaping resource reservation and
other methods some of which are
mentioned in the open Internet order
this is a bright-line rule you can't
receive money or other consideration for
prioritization and you can't favor
affiliated content in other words
develop a business partnership and favor
the content of your partner paid
prioritization is a business decision
therefore reasonable network management
does not apply here it's just a
bright-line rule you can't do it so you
carriers cannot for instance prefer
Netflix traffic over Amazon or those two
over a smaller competitor safe and or no
so those are the three bright line rules
now we have the unreasonable
interference or unreasonable
disadvantage standard this is a general
conduct rule carriers conduct may not
violate one of the three bright line
rules but you a carrier's conduct may
not violate one of the three bright line
rules but may still interfere with the
consumers access to lawful content
that's really the key here the consumer
is in the center of this analysis this
rule governs conduct with edge providers
but on a case-by-case basis as we'll see
the FCC shied away from really going
deep on the peering and inter connection
issues whenever reasonableness is
involved whenever a lawyer sees the word
reasonableness they know that there's a
lot of guaranteed work out there for
and it's a multi-factor test the number
of factors I've highlighted the two most
important ones preserve end user control
and application agnostic the FCC gets
really focuses on those two and I
predict those two will be the the center
point and issue of any litigation that
grows out of this other factors they
look at does this promote competition
does it protect consumers does it
promote innovation free expression and
yours kiefer nanog is it consistent with
Network best practices and standards the
FCC defined what it was talking about
here it says standards and practiced and
erds adopted by open broadly
representative and independent internet
engineering governance and
standard-setting organizations so this
is your opening you will play an
important part going forward in the
development of these rules I take this
as a reference not only to nanog but to
groups like Aaron and I can the FCC
specifically rejected a commercially
reasonable standard that was the
standard they used in the roaming order
when they tried to expand wireless
roaming they said this is a larger
analysis this is really not just between
two carriers or what's reasonable
between two carriers this is about the
public interest and again the consumer
stands in the middle point of this
analysis to specific questions that the
FCC mentioned we're sponsored data and
data caps and they would apply they say
they are going to apply these rules to
those two questions my prediction is
that sponsored data will have a very
difficult time but the data caps
particularly wireless data caps as we've
seen will will pass muster
okay so now we get to the enhancements
to the transparency rule the
transparency rule is not a new rule they
did not prepare a new rule this this was
the only rule that survived the DC
Circuit appeal and the reason it
survived is because it's not a common
carriage rule it's really a consumer
protection rule and so the old rule says
a person engaged in the provision of
broadband internet access service shall
disclose network management practices
performance characteristics and the
commercial terms the full commercial
terms of the engagement this was
directed at two constituencies not just
consumers they talked about consumers
having enough information to make
informed choices that's language you see
in a lot of consumer protection statutes
it's in the california public utilities
code but the second constituency is was
content application service and device
providers to help them develop market
and maintain internet offerings so you
are within the protected class if you
will of the transparency rule the the
enhancements in the 2015 version of the
open Internet order our price full
monthly service charge so you can't give
a price and then add on a lot of add-ons
that are not fully disclosed in your
advertising other fees let's webs just
referring to data Cape data caps and
allowances and performance
characteristics such as speed latency
and packet loss in other consumer
protection contexts we've seen state
regulatory state and federal regulatory
agencies come up with a matrix for such
disclosures for instance the FTC's
privacy matrix might be something the
FCC will come to all right so what is
reasonable network management this will
applies to three of the four rules that
we've talked about no blocking no
throttling and no reason reasonable
disadvantage or interference now we have
the typical bureaucrat tt's definition
here a network management practice is
reasonable if it is appropriate and
tailored to achieving a legitimate
network management purpose taking into
account the particular network
architecture and technology of the
broadband internet access service are
you still awake really what it boils
down to and the FCC says this in one of
the subsidiary paragraphs is whether a
practice is primarily motivated by
technical network management
considerations or business justification
if it's about business if it's about
revenue you're going to have much
tougher sledding there's some bleed over
here between the factors that we talked
about that I talked about a minute ago
in regard to the no unreasonable
interference or disadvantage standard
does it allow for into user control is
it application agnostic so when the FCC
announced this they made a big deal of
saying that this was not going to be
standard utility style regulation they
were referring to a practice that's
called forbearance this is in the 1996
telecom act and essentially allows the
FCC to forbear to not enforce rules in
the 1996 telecom acts when it finds that
the public interest would not be harmed
so here the FCC said it would for bear
that is it would not enforce rules
relating to rate regulation Tutera fein
and to unbundling I unbundling because I
think that really is an issue that the
FCC in all honesty has just kicked down
the road
they were not going to forbear I'm very
clear about not for bearing on rules
relating to privacy pole attachments
good news for Google and other who would
come into the facilities world on
universal service new proposals on
universal service out a day or two ago
from chairman wheeler and disability
access so now comes coming to my own
backyard preemption of the state's under
the 1996 act really changed the way
regulation had been done there was a
strict divided up into that time about
between intrastate carriage and
interstate and all kinds of separation
rules and it became very difficult to
deal with so the 1996 act assured in
something that was is referred to as
cooperative federalism the feds more or
less set out the framework and we color
between the lines there are two air two
areas where the states have
traditionally been very active one is in
consumer protection billing issues and
the other is disputes between carriers
to California carriers are in a dispute
even if it concerns interstate traffic
there's still two California carriers
under the aegis or jurisdiction of the
Public Utilities Commission the open
Internet order declares that broadband
internet access service is quote/unquote
jurisdictionally interstate but this
doesn't mean obviously that it's
factually interstate what it does mean
is that the states are bound by what the
FCC says and they're bound by the FCC s
forbearance decisions so what can the
states do the key word here is nothing
inconsistent with what the feds have set
out so no new state universal service
assessments that was they were explicit
about that
uh it's not a basis for requiring cable
systems to get new telecommunications
franchises still unclear how this is
going to play out in inter connection
disputes and billing there's an
interesting issue here because one of
the things that the DC Circuit did in
the 2014 verizon vs FCC is rehabilitate
section 706 of the 96 Act which
delegated both to the FCC and to the
states equally the role of promoting
competition and removing barriers when
it came to advanced telecommunication
services Reed broadband so the states
have a role in doing that have an
independent statutory authorization to
do that and the FCC's order acknowledges
that but doesn't really parse it out
more finely so what does this mean for
you a lot of talk about FCC take over
the internet I think that's misplaced
discussion for the last 20 years we've
had in the wireless area very light
handed regulation there's been no rate
regulation virtually no entry regulation
it's all about terms and conditions and
issues like roaming so that certainly
has not impeded the growth of the
wireless industry and I do not expect
the open Internet order to impede the
growth of the broadband and internet
related industries if you work for an
edge provider or competitive carrier
this might give you some tools to
achieve more fairness and transparency
in your inner connection with incumbent
or facilities-based other facilities
based carriers there's no direct change
in the inner connection rules the FCC
acknowledges a lot of conflicts that
have been out there the level 3 Netflix
comcast conflict I was glad to see
everybody behaving themselves this
morning it says that there are competing
narratives about what happened it says
they're essentially going to wait and
see with
a rare act of regulatory humility said
we really don't understand this enough
to make rules so we're going to let you
folks try to work it out and see what
you come up with if you work for an
incumbent you probably should take a
look at your tariffs contracts rules and
policies to make sure they're
transparent and fair both fees V or end
user subscribers and competing carriers
and other commercial partners so I think
we've said enough on that the larger
picture I'll close with this I really
think the OpenNet internet order is a
watershed change in the way the FCC
views the network I'd say this is the
end of the telephone network as we know
it this has been in the works for
several years National Broadband Plan in
the 2011 transformation order but this
really hits it on the head dial tone is
replaced by broadband connectivity voice
is just an application they specifically
say that with regard to VoIP and as we
know VoIP is pretty much going to be the
voice product going forward and they
redefined the endpoints of the network
previously the nampa numbers have been
seen as the endpoints of the public
switched telephone network now the num
endpoints include IP addresses again
does this mean an FCC take over the
internet there they explicitly address
it on this count and say no this
definition will change to our
regulations in no way a search
commission jurisdiction over the
assignment or management of IP
addressing by the internet numbers
registry system so I expect that the
consensual decision-making of I can
Aaron and others will go forward so at
the end of the day I think what the what
the FCC is saying here is that broadband
is an essential service it is even if we
don't regulate it completely as a
utility it is a utility you cannot get a
job now you cannot find out about your
community
you cannot do so many things if you are
not on the internet it's like water it's
like gas and by the way in gas
regulation there's over the last 20
years there's been an unbundling that
has occurred their gas pipeline
operators are supposed to I'm not a gas
regulator so I don't know for sure but
are supposed to be separate and apart
from the gas generators in the
electricity field another essential
service there's the whole issue now of
net metering and feed-in tariffs you
have panels on your roof on what terms
and conditions are you going to be able
to feed electricity back into the
network and I think broadband shares
some of those characteristics if
broadband is going to be different than
a traditional utility what is going to
have to happen is some sort of
competition in the last mile that's the
key that's the bottleneck this can occur
through unbundling regimes something
like the functional separation that
ofcom in the United Kingdom has pursued
or perhaps carrier-neutral municipally
sponsored networks or some combination
of the three but the to the extent that
you've got a monopoly there you have a
real need for in my opinion for some
sort of neutrality or open Internet
rules so in closing we need your help
the FCC needs your help they're
developing standards I talked about the
reasonableness criteria i talked about
best practices you're on the front lines
of that we're trying to deal with known
historical problems while honoring the
uniqueness and wonder that IP technology
has brought us so with that thanks for
listening I'll try to answer your
questions you can also email me
questions at wit wi t @ CPUC
CA gov
no questions good tiny tiny question all
right yes hi my name is Chris Wood Theo
and I'm with Twitter your mention of the
fact that broadband is now being
considered an essential service brings
up some interesting implications guys we
all know telephone service was declared
an essential service and we had things
like Universal Service Fund to make sure
that rural areas have have ax had access
to toe telephone service do you see a
point where the current FCC standards
for broadband would eventually become a
baseline for some sort of universal
service requirements and you think that
would be a that will ain't necessary or
be even desirable so we were taking bets
on whether that question would come up
and if the smart money was that it would
the FCC the day two days three days ago
issued an order that goes down that road
to redefining basic service to include
broadband I don't see any way around
that I think that talking about
standalone voice even if that's all
you're using that that just does not
make sense going forward as far as I can
see and I think the FCC says that
between the lines by referring to VoIP
as a data service rather than a
transport service Thank You Houston I
painting do you think that the
regulatory system is suffering from lamp
post bias in other words you're looking
under the light of the lamp post because
that's the easiest place to look whereas
an actual fact
the intrinsic monopolies that are
forming on the internet are in different
places you've got a long history of
regulating carriage because carriage was
central to telephony in the internet
carriage is merely the sewage and that
the value is in apps and certainly it's
true right now that apps are incredibly
monopolistic the DNS is largely serviced
by a single provider even our email is
serviced by only one or two is this a
problem and if it is a problem of these
forming monopolies in applications and
services what do you see as your role as
a regulator in looking at this
upper-level world that sits well above
the traditional regulatory environment
of carriage I think that's an excellent
question there's did you bet that that
was going to be asked as it I know but
I've thought about that that's a
definitely a question I thought about
I've done some reading and research into
search bias the all of the attendant
privacy issues that the Europeans are so
exercised about there's no doubt that
companies like Facebook and Google have
tremendous market power but I go back to
a very simple principle it's the wires
stupid it really is you talk about the
protocol stack and lower level control
the people that own the wires are in a
commanding position from what I can see
these other market problems I think are
more the province province of the
Federal Trade Commission I think the PUC
the California PUC and the federal
communications commission would do well
to stick to the wires and to the market
power that attaches to those wires and
to the act of transportation of
information so in fact you're saying
it's someone else's problem but it's a
problem exactly that is exactly and I
would it's it's like the railroads the
you know you've got one rail
track into town the railroads themselves
can be a problem there and export super
competitive rates from the people that
they're serving or you can have a
Rockefeller come in and co-opt the
railroads so that's the problem you're
talking about thank you yes bill
goldstein for reference purposes i'm a
retired product manager from AT&T and
manage internet services though I'm here
on my own representing only myself first
question most large-scale exchange of
traffic between networks is done via
private peering given the transparency
and bottleneck aspects of the current
ruling what do you think is the future
of private peering and the second
question of course all this is under
some very significant legal challenge I
just wonder what your observations would
be on what you think the chances are of
this latest ruling really standing the
test of the courts going forward so let
me take the second one first I think the
DC Circuit and judge table did the FCC
and the United States a tremendous
service in setting out a roadmap and a
logically coherent roadmap at that to
what the FCC should do and the SEC
finally followed that roadmap so I my
money is on that this will be upheld in
the courts I'm not even sure if it will
reach the Supreme Court but and you will
have if it does reach the Supreme Court
you'll have judge Scalia who's looking
for a very simple clear approach to
regulation and separating out the
conduit in the way that the FCC has done
I think it's clear enough for him he's
got his transport element as a separate
element as to private peering
and chairman wheeler said in the last
month or two that peering is just a
fancy word for interconnection a $25
word for interconnection I my guess is
the FCC is going to stand back gather
data and see if you folks can work it
out among yourselves and then only
interfere or only regulate to the extent
necessary to keep a level playing field
and again with the consumer in the
middle point if data is effectively
being in information is effectively
being made more difficult for consumers
to reach I think that's the point when
the FCC will step in I don't know if
that answers your question but well you
know no one would be unfair me to
address you is to be young a substitute
for all the courts and front rulings
that was basically interesting
observations as certainly very
interested in very well informed party
to all this and I appreciate the
response sure thank you I think bill
Manning representing the 70s all right
to answer Jeff Jeff Houston's question
and a suggestion for the board if he's
interested in content men content
control invite the mpaa censorship board
to come talk next time to talk about
content control even my sarcasm
challenge mind gets that I just just
saying I have a cognitive disconnect
every time someone in the United States
says broadband I want to break out in
laughter
is there any expectation that when the
FCC talks about broadband or the Public
Utilities Commission talks about
broadband or anyone else in the United
State talks about broadband they
actually mean broadband instead of the
FCC's current definition and what do you
understand the FCC's current definition
to be I'd have to go back and look at
the stats but when I checked my Japanese
friends when they talk about broadband
they're talking about minimum 100 Meg up
down unfiltered last mile it right
that's the old you can get that out in
you know like rural Japan the new stuff
is a little faster than that and so when
I hear broadband in the United States
and I go talk to my provider in Los
Angeles and I say I'd like broadband and
they say we've got this deal for you we
can get you one and a half Meg's up and
down and it's only going to cost you a
hundred and thirty-five bucks a month
such a deal and I just I I don't I don't
think that's broadband and I don't think
that's price competitive and I just it's
really it just it makes me snicker so
can we get broadband you know do you
think broadband is going to change well
well the FCC just redefined it upward to
25 Meg's down that probably wouldn't
satisfy you but but a lot of people are
complaining that that's unrealistic and
people don't need 25 megabytes and
megabits thank you I'm showing
showing that I'm a policy guy in a tech
guy so they're there there's pushback on
on what you suggest but yes there are
people out there who say we have to go
to a Giga bit keep big of gigabyte
gigabit service and I think we're moving
in that direction it might be slower
than you'd like but I Patrick Elmer
Markley cloud services speaking
specifically actually about an answer
you gave not the presentation by the way
the presentation was awesome and kudos
to you and the pc for finding you so
thank you very much thank you talking
directly about interconnection you
mentioned during one of your answers
that if the consumer is harmed then
inter connection might be there I was
worried in this I'm just asking for a
little clarification I was worried that
the order would actually be as long as
things are agnostic or even handed
across all comers then it would be okay
no matter what the rule was what you're
saying that the FCC will actually look
at the consumer and just to give a
slight bit of context for many years for
decades actually on the internet it has
been common for a carrier that believe
either has or believes it has market
power to specifically congest its
inbound and outbound to the
quote-unquote public that the core the
default phrase on whatever you want to
call it and force people to buy access
if they want good connectivity to
whatever is behind them but that's
even-handed everyone has to do the exact
same thing is the FCC going to look at
that and go no that's not correct and
then what are they going to do are they
going to say okay here's a reasonable
price or you have to have settlement
free to the ones above a certain size or
I mean that seems like a hard problem to
me to solve well it's in a really
interesting question and I don't
completely have an answer my off the top
answer would be to go back to the no
unreasonable interference or
disadvantage and there no unreasonable
interference or disadvantage not
necessarily visa vie
other providers or competing carriers or
content providers but visa V what is
possible it just that strikes me as a
unfair business practice in and of
itself what you described and I'd
actually like to know more about that
and Susan Crawford also talks about that
artificially constrained bandwidth
forcing consumers to allowing the
company to upsell consumers so if you
could contact me afterward I'd like to
know more about that I think there are
tools there to deal with that I'm not a
hundred percent sure what the hell is
like soon I'd be happy to talk to you so
it I'm sure hundreds of people in this
room but you'll get a lot of the email
in the very near future okay please I
appreciate it Randy bush raj um I think
the second half of bills point was price
right as to how much bandwidth is good
enough you know if God had meant us to
fly in airplanes she wouldn't have given
his trains um i have three home internet
connections one is comcast for which i
pay 70 bucks a month and get about 20
meg down and thank you John if you're
here I get ipv6 which I can't even get
in this room don't turn on v4 you can't
get it your DS can't get dns over v6 the
other is time warner i pay a hundred and
three dollars a month for 15 meg down
and one and a half of and the third is
NT
I pay thirty dollars a month for a
hundred symmetric and it's going to go
to forty dollars a month when I go to
gigabit and they're apologetic and
that's what Bill means by what we say
here is broadband is BS thank you so to
move this issue in the policy world I
again I would ask you to send me the
data on that because it's very helpful
in something I'm interested in but to
move the issue in the policy world you
need studies you need comparisons the
Berkman Institute at Harvard did a study
about three or four years ago finding
that in Europe you could get much more
speed for many fewer dollars and that
study instantly became the target of
attacks that to their credit they really
didn't pull back from their conclusions
although they soften them some so and
there are other people out I won't
mention any names making on the circuit
saying that European us comparisons show
that we're doing just fine and the
market is working just fine so we do
need good comparisons and my own
thumbnail comparison I have a friend in
Hamburg who gets 427 euros voice and 10
to 15 megabytes megabits whatever that I
and I mean compare what you would pay
for that in the United States similarly
have acquaintances in London who even
less than that so I think we need good
cross-country comparisons to drive that
discussion a new sort of money I
presenting the university of colorado
boulder in the college merchant program
so i'm primarily a tech student trying
to understand the intricacies of policy
so forgive me if my question sounds
stupid so if you have CC the only body
that regulates the rulings of paint
browsers prioritization and
non-discrimination if yes then do you
think the FCC is equipped with enough
resources to detect and regulate any
infringement or in discussions that
might occur you asked two very good
questions one the Federal Trade
Commission has some jurisdiction in this
area but they do not due to a long
outdated law have jurisdiction over
common carriers and that needs to change
Commissioner wheeler is I think
dedicated to working with the Federal
Trade Commission and bringing their
expertise on board so very good question
and as to your second question the
weather the FCC has sufficient resources
I think my answer what from what I can
gather on the west coast here is no they
don't they have one administrative law
judge if they are really going to
elaborate through a series on a
case-by-case basis which is what they
say they're going to need more
administrative law judges more capacity
to do dispute resolution than they
currently have does that answer your
question yes it does thank you time
thank you very much
thanks very much Chris