first let's talk about how you make the
web faster and what go
there are a lot of things that are
involved in user perceived latency x'
all the network - you build a course but
other things an important one is the
increasing use of TLS for example now
Google and in particular YouTube is
almost all secure and so that's a big
part of a user perceived latency so what
have we done
we built a huge CDN we have one of the
vast largest CDNs in the world
we offer Google global cache to the
supona install it and get closer to the
users and we didn't only have a huge
network that we've spent a huge amount
of money building out just to make these
er experience faster thanks so we've
also made her own browser we've done
Chrome which has had many innovative
things built into it
one of which became HTTP - so we're
really trying to advance the space you
know and do anything we can to both make
the web more secure and faster but what
else what's in the middle
well there's transport traditionally TCP
and we've done a lot of work with TCP we
have some of the best and brightest
working on it already but we wonder what
else could we do so the question is what
is quick it's a reliable multiplexed
transport over UDP it's always encrypted
make reduces latency it runs in user
space so we can upgrade it quickly and
deploy it quickly and it's open source
so where's it fit on all these tasks so
it's obscene some of the things that TLS
1.2 does pretty much all of them the
handshake
as well as the cryptography add some of
the things that HTTP to do such as
multi-streaming and also does things
like congestion control from TCP and
lost recovery how do you make sure quick
works well a very important question so
for for three needs to be open otherwise
it won't work at all
UDP rate limiters are definitely bad any
other type of differential costs tends
to be bad and reasonable stateful
firewall in that timeouts so we did a
variety of experimentation and found
that 30 seconds was a very conservative
timeout value and that very very few
Nats expired in less than 30 seconds and
so that's what we've chosen but you know
we need a certain amount of time to
actually keep the connection open and we
need reasonable load balancing
so as we scale up quick you know we're
we don't want to have any issues where
suddenly we end up all on one port have
you router you know and other issues
where things are not distributed evenly
let's talk about congestion control and
reliability so quick is reliable just
like TCP incorporates all the best
practices and really builds on years and
years of learning with TCP even though
TCP hasn't really evolved very much on
the wire over time it's really evolved a
lot in terms of the techniques used to
make sure that the TCP works really
really well so incorporates cubic so
it's fair with the existing TCP
implementations fact TLP and all the
most modern RFC's as well as some that
aren't even full RFC's yet but also add
some signaling improvements that can't
be done in TCP for example
retransmissions are come with the new
sequence number so because of that you
have no disambiguate II when you're
retransmitting a packet you have very
good RTD information you know exactly
what happened on the connection
and there's a lot of code in TCP to try
to do disambiguation mix the codebase
and the kernel a lot more complicated
this is also a good time to call out the
fact that you know there are a lot of
things people would like to add to CCP
and kind of improvements that they would
like to make but probably the most
complex and most important one that's
ever been added is selective
acknowledgement or the sack option and
that's been around for about 20 years
and it's now for the last metrics I'd
looked at about 90 percent deployed so
even really really compelling
improvements to TCP take a very very
long time and they're very hard to
experiment with because of that because
you really don't know how well it
performs until you deploy it at scale so
we have a lot more other flexibility
going forward we can change how the
receiver acknowledges data for example
either to get more information or to
make the network more efficient so it's
important to talk about faster
connection or establishment this is a
core feature real quick that was
designed in from the ground up we
combine the handshake for the connection
with the handshake for security all in
one and in the best case it only takes
it takes zero round trips in the sense
that is immediately established and you
can send a request on the first flight
so with TCP it's typically one with TCP
plus TLS it's either 2 or 3 depending on
whether you can resume the connection
and in quick 75% of the time it's 0 and
25 percent of the time it's 1 so the
worst case scenario is you have to do a
full round-trip and that of course
relies on you having talked to the
server before but at least in Google's
case you know most people have talked to
google.com before
so it's always encrypted it's very
comparable to TLS and actually uses two
of the ciphers the TLS supports actually
it supports the only two that I believe
are widely considered to be the most
secure has IP spoofing protection so it
has proof of source address token even
though it's 0 RTT it does have a
fruitful source address token and it
also inspired TLS 1.30 RTT handshake so
you know already we're seeing interest
in adopting this and moving some of the
technology we've developed and quick
into other forums tend to be used for
TCP as well so how well does it work so
we spend a lot of time measuring
performance and making sure that we
really know how well it works in one
would you control the experiments we get
there client-side data we got there
server-side data we make sure they match
up you know we gather all kinds of it
error information anything that could
possibly go wrong and we also do a lot
of fine grained analysis so we almost
always do analysis by a s we also do
analysis by location like serving
location I will do analysis by operating
system anything else so anyway we can
slice and dice it we'll look at the data
and we also give you a view into it on
peering google.com so as a recent
feature we now have added a lot more
quick centric information there so how
well is it on Google properties so on
average it's 5% faster it's one second
faster for web search at the 99th
percentile
now 5% doesn't sound huge in some ways
but we do incredible things to optimize
everything we possibly can so the fact
that there's anything left on the table
is sort of amazing and also I want to
emphasize as I said before this is
making the cost of doing a secure
connection really kind of nothing from a
user latency perspective which is a
really critical improvement so also
improves YouTube quality of experience
30% fewer rebuff rays which is a huge
difference
and we have a lot more improvements to
come work only at the beginning forward
error correction bandwidth resumption
much more so 0tt
is one of the big ones in terms of where
all the improvements go over half of the
latency permits come from that one thing
at the moment it's also the feature we
sort of designed the protocol around to
work really well and we've invested a
huge amount of time we also have better
loss recovery so those of you who are
familiar with TCP usually around 30
percent of retransmits our timer based
those in juice a lot of latency to you
know from the end users perspective
quick has almost 10 times fewer time
were based retransmits than TCP in a
typical case and this really comes off
as you know much much better tail
latency and that's one of the things
that contributes to the fury buffers and
there are other smaller things had the
wine blocking because we're using UDP we
can deliver a data out of order more
efficient framing and some other minor
please so when is it deployed so it
started in 2013 in Chrome Canary 2014
was when it had chrome stable and
currently we're in the process of
ramping it up over the course of this
year and have really started around
January of this year so are we doing to
protect users and your net waste on the
client side
if UDP is blocked we just fall back it's
just like ipv6 happy eyeballs sort of
race and you know the user is never the
wiser have to Pat them to you is too
small because we currently use around a
1350 byte packet then the handshake will
fail and again you know these are will
be none the wiser and well if the client
doesn't want to use quick they have a
problem their policy doesn't matter what
the reason they can disable it in Chrome
or you can do a policy wide disable to
disable it as a site administrator
across your site
sometimes client-side protection is not
quite enough so as a last resort Google
will disable it quick on a per ASN basis
this is kind of the the least the thing
we'd like to do the least but
occasionally there are issues that we
just can't resolve on the client side
and can't detect easily on the client
side so why would we disable quick
usually we get very like lots of
indications that quality of experience
common when YouTube is hugely degraded
for that Network commonly its duty UDP
rate limiting virtually always actually
and in the worst case scenario we'd rely
on end-user reports to give us
indications of problems so quick on your
network on peering google.com so let's
quick FAQ there's some excellent
information on quick and there is also a
link to how to sign up for appearing
account so you can see all this
information so there's a traffic summary
about how much of the data flowing into
your network is quick there's a profile
of how it varies over the course of the
day and also will tell you whether your
network is one of the networks we found
is not quick friendly so is either
blocking UDP or is it highly filtering
UDP so in terms of debugging the best
tool is chrome Chrome itself has an
excellent mentor NAL's pane it's one of
the standard tabs that's even in
Chrome's table and that's where we get
the most detailed bug reports that of
any issues that we find it allows you to
see into the quick frames themselves so
you can see like what's the data
what's ignant the connection
establishment
what's all that what the all the
handshake parameters are it really gives
you a very very detailed view into the
quic protocol and if you're just curious
and wanted to take a look then you know
fire it up and and it'll be there
there's also a Wireshark plugin that'll
identify quick identified the flow
identifier called the connection ID
identify packets by sequence number so
again sequence numbers don't repeat
quick and they start at one so a little
bit different from GCV but conceptually
similar but it'll give you an idea of
how big a flow is how long it lasts for
and all of that information I also tell
you the quick version so we're currently
on actually version 25 not version 24
and you know we we've been solving down
our version iteration to fair amount but
it is relatively rapidly iterate and
compared to most transports so what's
next coming in the future many people
have asked when are we gonna do forward
error correction and the answer is well
we're experimenting with it but making
it work really really well is hard
connection mobility so you know there's
a lot of interest in migrating from cell
to Wi-Fi and back and forth and we're
starting to work on that now as well
multipath is a natural follow-on to that
particularly for mobile devices and more
improvements in congestion control
originally even quick we kind of thought
ah we're going to completely rewrite TCP
and it turns out you know doing an
entirely new transport is enough of a
project in and of itself that you might
as well keep a few things the same and I
think the choice to stick would keep it
for now was a very wise choice
open source we have a server that's in
chromium that you can play with it is
not intended to be ultra high
performance but it certainly is correct
and certainly will give you an idea of
what you you can expect that a quick
we're working to support quick and
apache traffic server no actual ETA on
that but definitely we we hope that
it'll happen sometime than a to distant
feature and we have so open source
chromium climate libraries for both
desktop and for mobile and Google Chrome
and some various Google mobile apps and
I mean people are actually used quick
but yes we are talking with other
browsers as well for the future so quick
has been presented at the IETF back in
2013 as an initial idea it's changed
quite a bit since then but the concepts
are still the same
most recently at the IETF the in Dallas
the quick crypto was presented this was
very much
you know timely because now that TLS 1.3
is kind of starting to move along there
was really a lot of people had questions
about how quick crypto related to TLS
1.3 and kind of the answer is TLS 1.3 in
many ways is going to end up subsuming
quick crypto as a profile inside of it
there's going to be an updated
presentation this summer in Prague and
we have an ongoing work as I mentioned
to kind of make sure that quick caesura
RTT handshake kind of merges with TLS
1.3 so we can eventually move directly
to TLS 1.3 for quick interview it's
reliable it's multiplexed it runs over
UDP it's always encrypted has optional
forward error correction as a rapidly
evolving implementation and it's open
source but most importantly the one
thing I skipped over a person tential it
was that is designed to be lower latency
for users it's really designed to
improve user experience make the user
experience more reliable faster and just
generally make the web work better so
how do we get to a passage of quick
basically Crete UDP like TCP open 443
don't rate limit it you know make sure
that the cost is set up reasonably as I
said reasonable firewall and that rules
and you know have your hack your traffic
distributed evenly all right and as I
mentioned before peering at Google calm
as more information about quick as well
as how you can get more information
about your s if you have one questions
Phil Rosenthal from is prime so I think
it's actually wonderful work to improve
on HDPE it's a long time coming
one of the features that you know is
very clearly core to it is always
encrypted but there is a downside to
that which I think even in the best case
scenario when you're in encrypting data
you're using say 40 percent more
computation cycles to do that and you
know there there is a cost to that right
in some cases you know that encryption
is obviously valuable you know I want my
bank to be encrypted but I may not
necessarily care that some video streams
are encrypted so if it's going to be
something for the Internet as a whole
that we encourage everyone to use is
there any thoughts to you know to
allowing at some point an unencrypted
version and if not you know what do you
say to the you know all the years of
effort towards zero copy that it seems
to be now throwing away and going the
opposite extreme no it's a reasonable
question right so one thing is at least
based on my my understanding and this is
talking to paternity folks at Google and
as well as that Netflix actually that
some reason were to make encryption
faster has really helped and so that I
think I think the forty percent number
is a little bit high
based on my experience because for
example Netflix had an option to do
whose encryption in the kernel and so
you could write a file directed to the
kernel and it would encrypt it for you
and it was extremely fast but but in
general I think at least for Google the
right choice is to always encrypt things
as much as possible for everyone else I
would encourage them to you know kind of
tend to do so as well
but it doesn't curse um CPU cost so I
guess I guess the answer is I tend to
think it's worth it but I don't know
this is Brian Rogan by the way
hi-yah I think that's definitely your
observations definitely what we found is
that in deploying crypto wide they right
so now something north of 70% of all
traffic from google by volume is
encrypted it's obviously a big priority
for us as a company we actually found
the primary CPU cost has generally been
has been copy overhead not actually
flipped alright it's quite efficient
especially symmetric ciphers on modern
processors right but but I think I think
for us and a bit a big part of quick is
kind of that he's taking that payload
and and kind of bring it back into
endedness to it right so I mean the
encryption serves a lot of purposes but
from our perspective I think it's an
important feature of the protocol yeah I
should also add to go back to the work
with speedy the feeling about speedy was
that if it wasn't encrypted that it
would never get through the network and
I think there's also a little bit of a
fear of that for for quick as well as
that if it's not encrypted that there's
gonna be a little bit more a few more
issues with tampering and other such
things so but it's definitely a concern
okay thank you
crystal come gust so some of us were
just looking at the stats for quick on
our network which is great that web page
is really pretty
I'm good job on that but the number was
something like 5% and given Chrome's
penetration that seemed a bit low to me
can you explain what some of the
discrepancy might be so I think I could
speak to the deployment right now so we
deployed quick quite widely differently
across different Google services right
and so you know it works how quick the
protocol I work on on content delivery
at Google and and how we scale that
delivery right and basically what we're
doing is scaling our different products
at different rates right so I mean the
quick rollout on our site is not not
complete right it's different farther
along for some products than others and
so we're ramping up you know some of our
biggest sources of traffic now and over
the next few months
I don't know everything it's just kind
of curious what the breakdown is in
terms of if you've had experience with
quick operating over what I'd call like
middle box heavy environments or in
mobile versus and kind of you know
standard wireline deployments do you
know how does the fallback work I mean
how often do you fall back when you're
traversing to in kind of middle box
environments sure so we found that
overall it works all right quick it's
possible to use quick something like 95
percent of the time that's pretty
similar to that I think the numbers that
the web RCTC folks have found as well
maybe there's they're a little bit
higher but and so you know in general it
almost always works we haven't found any
issues that are particular to mobile
environments at all so far the hardest
part about mobile so far is actually
even computation things like not only at
the crypto that was mentioned earlier
but just generally you know computation
is much more limited on mobile so that's
actually been a much bigger issue and
yeah hi Chris Woodfield Twitter
you mentioned there were the
recommendations for reasonable time outs
for stateful devices I think 30 seconds
is what you said for UDP yeah I think
the most common number we found was
either 60 or some number much more than
60 but we used 30 because we found
essentially new devices that seemed to
timeout before that okay my question is
is there anything in the protocol today
or plans to put the protocol the the
equivalent of a closed message the
equivalent of a TCP finner r3 set so
that a stateful device could watch for
that and clear out the session table
sooner yes there is actually discussion
of that and we yeah the currently the
close is encrypted so you can't really
watch it and I think John it might be
wanting to answer that question right
now he's very behind you he's also a
team member Jenna I googled so yes it'll
be very useful to have that actually a
pheromone
at the IETF even about having unity
based transports show sin and offended
but of course it opens up the Pandora's
box of reset attacks in various other
things
one of Mick's big strengths is that the
entire header quick header is in fact
authenticated by the receiver which
allows us to ward any sort of injection
attacks and this will open the door to
that but of course it's it's a
conversation that can be had on the face
of possible attacks you kind of have to
infer things without reading simply war
overbuilt is sent to you so the
conversation goes there from Zendesk i
have no questions about the about the
performance and how code the protocol is
my question is more about I know that
Google is proposing this as an open
standard in IETF right and do you guys
see the community in a medium long term
migrating to serve HTTP traffic by quake
or maybe all the knowledge and
experiences from from this protocol
being been brought to TCP and in a
long-term or or something like that I
think personally I see it is both
alright as much as possible we would
love to do things that bring
improvements back to TCP that's
definitely a huge win but I tend to
think that we're gonna end up wanting to
deploy quick as well fairly widely
because we are gonna be able to do
things that are just not going to be
able to be deployed in a reasonable time
frame for TCP hard to know how to layout
thank you
hi Armen Bobby Kim switch Co I've got a
question about the port 443 requirement
that you guys have for quick does that
mean that a single server listening on a
single IP address has to have the entire
all the services that it's trying to
give
all the services is trying to provide
hosted on a single port on the machine
or do you guys plan to generalize that
or relax that requirement so you talked
about in terms of serving architecture
yes so it doesn't really have to be four
four three semantics I mean you could
certainly configure it yourself and use
it on any port you want but in the
context of doing HTTP traffic the goal
is to use 443 so quickly useful web RTC
or something else than it would get to
be on a different port sort of a follow
on to with respect to quick and WebRTC
does that support it at the moment or it
is not supported there's definitely hope
to make that happen at some point but
it's who knows when that will problem
okay okay yes sorry I think you're
Spencer Dawkins for the purpose of this
conversation transport Area Director at
the IETF thank you guys for bringing the
work that you brought to the IETF so far
there are a lot of things to count quick
that I'm excited about in the both about
you know feedback to TCP and other
transport protocols and in its own case
for deployment
having said that have I seen a buff
request from you guys
I ain't got no you have not and that's
because we haven't sent it yet I look
forward to one with bated breath and
actually a couple of people from Google
of Thome one is coming which is why act
I asked but I just wanted to make sure
like I said I look forward to this with
interest
I that process I leave up to Jonah I'll
just say that that there may be a bob of
request coming up very very soon yeah do
the right thing just a good question you
said this is open source but I saw no
pointers to any place where we can look
at the source for this is this sort of
open in a theoretical sense er do you
actually have a coder
there is it is actually all in chromium
so I think if you go to the FAQ and you
go there should be a chromium link for
the chromium like explanation of kind of
this is quick and here are some detailed
design Doc's there is like a crypto doc
and a radio felt like a separate library
we can grab I have to grab a whole for
chemical so yes that is really annoying
right now I'm gonna just acknowledge
that right now there is actually an
external team idly working on trying to
library eyes it and we've talked about
like how to make it easier many times so
so currently it's it's hard but there is
a I know an ongoing effort to try to the
library as it as well thank you yeah
yeah haven't really had time to check it
because I'm just basically got it
working but um you mentioned that your
closed message is encrypted are you
working at all with the UM the SSL
session key or other plans tooth as a
method of decryption I am not familiar
with that I don't know if John there
anyone else from Google in comment I
think the answer is no but I also did
not write all the crypto stack I was
mostly Adam Langley and a few others
fair enough
thanks great thank you
you