our first presentation this morning is
by Russ white from Erickson and you'll
be discussing rethinking centralization
so if anybody see me speak before you
know how much I love podiums just
awesome thanks Tony this is your
obligatory trigger warning there are
things in this presentation that might
get you upset but that's okay I'm used
to that too did anybody bring tomatoes
okay all right good I'm pretty safe then
all right so I'm us why it worked for
Ericsson right now a old red back you
probably but no red back better than you
do Erickson desserts and even make IP
product anybody on an Eriksson router
probably not oh look somebody Oh two
people I'm astounded anyway then you
skip the next slide or their thing up
here here we go all right so first of
all note well this is an experimental
presentation which means i may change my
mind about what i'm talking about in the
middle of the presentation or look like
the dog before it's over with so that's
great all right does anybody recognize
this okay I've lived through this you
know I started in IT putting vt100
terminal cards in in little Z Nazi 100's
and then I moved up to Z 1 Z 2 48 which
is that bottom left-hand bottom one down
there and then on and on and on you know
we do mainframes then we do Oh Leslie
lotus 123 then we do minis and we do SQL
and then we play all these games we have
been doing this in the IT industry for a
very very long time Tony and I were just
talking attorney was just saying that we
do this organizationally as well and I
think we're actually doing this in the
control plane as well this presentation
is primarily about the control plane so
why don't we do this first of all we
look around and we say okay you know
this centralized stuff this polling from
the old mainframe days it's really
complected it's really slow it takes
five minutes for somebody to figure out
that that vt100 is offline it's a
that thing we need to make this faster
wouldn't it be cool if we decentralized
and we did something like ooh routing
protocol that's it is is ospf BGP we
could do that and decentralize our
control plan be really cool and then we
distribute it and we all look at it and
go oh my gosh this is really hard
routing is not a solvable problem let's
do software-defined networks and open
flow and bring it all back into the
central center again the other reason I
think we do this is because we have this
whole capex cycle that we're playing
with when you buy a data center you buy
all the links and all the fiber and
everything else and then you start using
it in 10 years later you actually use it
to full capacity and by the time you've
used it to full capacity you've already
run out of end of life for all of your
equipment so you actually have this huge
capex waste between what your business
requirements are and what you're
actually trying to do I think there's a
couple of reasons we play this game
either way I think it's a bad thing in
the end I think what we're trying to do
is we're actually trying to solve
complexity you know the whole cap
theorem anybody know what the cap
theorem is right and consistent
available and partition of all the
entire quick cheap and high quality
problem that you run into all of these
little side effects of tearing proofs
that exists in the real world that we
face on a daily basis I think part of
what we're trying to do is we're
actually trying to solve complexity and
there's no silver bullet for complexity
you know we think that distribute is too
complex so we centralize we think
centralizes too complex so we distribute
so here is what I feel like a lot of
times there is no silver bullet for
complexity but there is that stupid
pendulum on the bottom of that clock and
we keep centralizing and decentralizing
things constantly and it's driving me
mad there are several things in the IT
industry driving me mad right now if
anybody reads my blog you'll hear all
about the things that are driving me mad
so here's a radical thought has anybody
seen this video I love this video stop
it okay stop it or I'll bury you alive
in a box as he says at the very end
see somebody seen it wait stop it we are
driving ourselves nuts we are playing
lots of games with 5980 s88 types of
tunneling 4,000 different types of
control planes and overlays and all
because we're trying to solve an
unsolvable problem complexity can't be
solved you can mitigate it you can live
with it you can figure out how to work
around it but you cannot solve this okay
I had somebody tell me the other day
that the cap theorem is just an observer
theory and I thought perhaps they needed
to be under observation so where do we
go from here I feel like I'm going to MC
Escher drawing right there staircases
everywhere I can't figure out which way
is up I'm just running around doing
stuff so let's think about this how do
we solve this in other parts of the
network how do we mitigate complexity or
how do we manage complexity and
understand complexity and deal with it
in other parts of the network that's not
my dog my dog is at the very end I'll
tell you when we get there anyway right
what do we do in protocols we layer
protocols right we have this infamous
seven layer stack the seven layer model
which is so far dead and so far out of
bounds of useless that I don't even
explain it to people anymore anyway but
we do live protocols we layer protocols
because we simplify protocol design
right what we do is we look at it we say
okay I can create consistent and
understandable ap is and I can split
failure domains by layering protocols
right I can take my protocol and I can
split different things from one another
i can divide complexity from complexity
and build things between them here's a
more efficient model for understanding
learning protocols Alan Turing
everybody's Red John days book patterns
in network architecture but this is the
model he pushes through or he iterates
through this iterative model so you can
see there that if you look at what the
functions of a protocol are you have
effectively for things that you're doing
you're doing transport or marshalling as
we used to call it an SQL days right we
marshal our data
we have multiplex we have error
correction and we have flow control
those are the four things we effectively
do with a protocol those are the for
purposes of a protocol we can actually
look at this and say okay Ethernet does
transport multiplex data link does error
flow control then I pee does transport
multiplex TCP does error flow control so
if I actually look at this I can start
looking at this and saying what i've
done is i've divided my purposes or what
i'm trying to do and i figured out how
to divide them up into a way where i
have clean api's and i have clean
separation of duties and i've actually
separated hop-by-hop and into end in my
network and then when I go up to HTTP
and I transport all sorts of garbage
over HTTP and PGP and then I just keep
building these layers for no apparent
reason other than i can write so that's
basically what we do all right wheeler
topologies are I've been writing about
hierarchical network design since the
late 1990s first book I wrote advanced
IP network design was all about
hierarchical network design it's a cool
idea doesn't always work in all real
world networks but it's a cool idea but
even if you don't do pure hierarchy you
still do some sort of layering at
apologies why do we let apologies
because we simplify the problem space
right we take our data center and it has
one set of problems I have a weigh-in
and has a separate set of problems I
separate these two things out and ice
break-up the failure domains and I make
it easier to troubleshoot within each
failure domain by separating my purposes
in what I'm doing wheeler lots of other
things okay why did we first start
running bgp it was divided my customer
routes from my internal valance that's
what I cared about we do it a lot we do
a lot more stuff with bgp today does
anybody think will be soon transporting
video / bgp because we've just about
thrown everything else that you can
imagine in the protocol pretty might as
well just add video and get it over with
anyway but the original reason for using
in EGP was to keep my customer out
separate from my routes hierarchy right
again reach ability aggregation
repeatable configurations right I'm
marginalize my network so i can do
repeatable configurations I do failure
to main de management I really care
about these slings flooding remains
right why do I break up flooding remains
an OSP
is is because I'm aggregating reach
ability information and topology
information and I'm actually managing my
failure domains in a logical way layer 2
layer 3 right I have ethernet and I have
IP what did I do that because I'm
breaking up a failure domain imax is
simplifying the problem by dividing
things virtualization why do I do
overlays and data centers so I can break
up my customers from each other i can
break up failure domains it's always the
same set of answers so my real question
this morning is in my experimental
presentation is why don't we layer the
control plane we have been playing this
game for 20 years and we just munch
everything together don't we my policy
is carried in BGP and my that's my
spanning tree picture that's okay that's
a that's about how i feel about spanning
tree so anyway you know we munch our
policy into bgp using communities we
munge it into ospf using community type
things tags and things like this and
then yet we have the yet we have the
routing protocol doing fast convergence
and we have the routing protocol doing
shortest path compact calculations reach
ability so we've managed reach ability
and policy and fast convergence and all
these things into one thing and we and
unlike in the protocol world and the
network design world we always flip
these things up and we thought about the
layers logically we're just munge them
all together so here's my slightly my
slightly radical question is why don't
we just layer the control plane right we
have four things that I can think of now
again this is not a perfect model this
is all very experimental and something
that I've been playing with in my head
and you know I'm actually writing a book
on network complexity right now so I've
been thinking about this a lot is that
there are a few things that we that we
want the control plane did it first of
all we want it to handle an a handle to
implement policy we dont want it to
crash we don't want to be spanning tree
we want to calculate reach ability
shortest path and we want to be able to
react to changes in topology those are
the four basic things that I expect it
to do okay so what is policy I had a
sliding here that i took out of Bilbo
holding up
a little you know the little map going
whatever is policy but anyway so policy
comes in two pieces in my mind the first
is data plane policy which I'm not too
concerned about but I threw the slide in
here to be consistent and complete data
flame policy is anything which modifies
the handling of a packet hop-by-hop
queue depth things like this to control
jitter delay and to do things like deep
packet inspection stateful packet
inspection by the way the next time I
hear somebody say fire while I'm going
to slap them outside the head there's no
such thing as a firewall anymore there's
a bunch of services running on an
appliance that you can virtualize out
but anyway that's my pet peeves are
broad admit II so anyway deep packet
inspection filtering stay full load
balancing all these things are my data
playing policy so what is control plane
policy so here's an interesting question
what is control plane policy so I've
looked at all the control plane policy I
can think of and every one of them
shares a single thing or a single single
common thing that they do they increase
stretch they take your traffic off the
shortest path or they potentially do all
right aggregation what does aggregation
do aggregation is actually a control
plane policy it's actually removing
reach ability or topology information
out of my network so I can make my my my
control plane converge more quickly and
more consistently more predictably
that's a policy solution that's not
something that you're you know you're
breaking up your failure domains this is
something you do as a matter of policy
but what does aggregation do on the
other side it actually increases my
stretch so again or it has the potential
to increase my stretch because I have
less routing information that I did
before if i look at service chaining
traffic engineering classic examples i
am actually carrying the traffic off of
the best path in order to implement a
policy whatever that policy might be the
case of a service chain what am i doing
i'm implementing a policy by carrying
traffic through a certain set of
services that have been virtualized onto
the network but i'm taking it off the
shortest path to do it i do the same
thing when i look at traffic engineering
right i have this link over here this
less less less utilize so i'm going to
carry traffic off the shortest path and
take it on a longer path so i can
optimize my utilization of links over my
shortest path you
sation okay so in any case what I'm
doing is I'm taking things off of the
shortest path and here's a crucial point
how many of you have ever seen a stop
sign on a murd map all right we don't do
this right i mean we don't mark traffic
signals and stop signs me no you turn in
no parking on your Maps maybe you do in
some very specialized maps by and large
if I go down to rand mcnally or I go
down to the map store and I buy a map of
Raleigh where I live I don't expect it
to tell me where the stop signs are I
expect to see the stop signs when I
Drive up to the stop sign right the
policy is distributed in effect and it's
not carried as part of my reach ability
well this gives me an idea if my policy
is not the same as my reach ability why
can't I just flip them out why can't I
start treating my policy as a separate
thing than reach ability now of course
policies going to impact reach ability
that only makes sense because again
control plane policy takes things off
the shortest path so clearly there's a
relationship between these two but
they're not the same thing if I can
split these two in my head then maybe I
can actually think of a way of layering
my control plane and doing the right
thing in the right place okay so
centralized versus decentralized what
works really well centralized a handle
to implement policy is the biggest thing
i have not fail up there but that's a
little bit questionable in my mind as to
where that falls and the centralized
versus decentralized but nonetheless a
handled implement policy is definitely
something that is much easier for me to
do centralized this is the whole game
behind open flow and saw and
software-defined networking is that I
want to treat all of my reach ability as
policy and I want to implement a
centralized controller that rolls out
all of my reach ability y'all are
looking really confused this is I told
you this is very experimental
decentralize what I think worked really
well decentralized is I don't think
you'll ever be able to beat is is or
ospf or BGP in react
the topology or discovering reach
ability just don't think you can do it I
don't think centralized polling systems
will ever be decentralized routing
protocols for finding discovering and
advertising reach ability very very
quickly in a way that makes sense in the
network so here's my experimental
proposal following on de lower layer
determines my reach ability reacts to
topology change my upper layer hides
information engineers traffic and
traffic flow and then I have an
alternate layer which is my business
logic which actually interacts with my
hiding information and my control plane
policy so if I can actually think this
through this way I can actually think
about where does it make sense and by
the way you'll notice I have domain one
domain to domain three drained off
domain for and now this is again an
emulation of Ethernet does the same for
things that IP and TCP do but it does it
in a different domain Ethernet does it
hop-by-hop IP does it end to end so
here's my second kind of experimental
proposal consider each slice of the
network in terms of problem bounding and
ap is the right solution might very end
to end right in my data center it might
make sense too because my data center
probably across my fabric particularly
in the overlay is probably very very
centered on policy and service training
so really I might want to conflate my
policy with my reach ability in the data
center in favor of policy at the peering
a/s edge where I'm actually talking ebgp
to up here I'm actually going to be the
opposite way I don't have any
centralized controller that I can use to
push policy across a s boundaries so I'm
probably going to carry my policy within
my routing protocol within the core I
could actually think about splitting my
policy in my reach ability since this is
kind of a strange proposal but I
actually think it makes sense that once
you look at how you can put these things
together and think through what the
control planes actually responsible for
and what it's doing you might be able to
divide these functions up and do the
right thing in the right place so
whether by the
Tony I'm really really early but that's
okay now he doesn't care good all right
so weather here is the first thing first
of all we got to learn to ask hard
questions we're network engineers and
engineers ask hard questions and figure
out hard solutions or figure out how to
manage the solutions in a way that makes
sense first of all would we really be
better off troubleshooting an API than
in distributed protocol this is actually
something that we need to ask them
whenever we centralize anything is where
does it make sense to have an API to the
network and where does it make sense to
have a protocol they're different things
and we're thinking in terms of coders
are so good that they've solved all the
world's problems and they can slice
bread so we'll just make it all an API
I'm really sure that really works so in
polling ever outrun reaction to local
events my answer to that is no I've been
doing this for a long time 20 years now
25 years perhaps I have never seen
polling outrun local reaction to an
event topology change reach ability
whatever it is polling does not beat
local reaction in the world of
philosophy we call this the subsidiary
principle but that's basically what you
run into should policy always or ever be
expressed in terms of forwarding well
clearly there is some interaction
between forwarding and policy but is
there a way to separate these two things
in a way that makes sense so that i can
stop thinking about munging them all
together is there a way for me to
overlay these things that that makes it
easier is a unified view of the network
actually possible that's pretty hard
question a lot of people don't want to
hear about it are we to the point that
with large-scale networks that we need
to stop thinking that we're going to be
able to understand the network all the
time every corner of it in every area I
think we might be getting there we might
be getting to the point of using
heuristics instead of algorithms it just
may be the way where we are with this
world and what should we do about
failure domains look you know stn is a
great thing perhaps and by the way you
know I do like sdn for some solution
what I'm proposing here is that we think
about where to use sdn and where to use
distributed control planes in a way that
makes sense but if you start thinking
about failure domains when I've
connected an entire data center through
a single or a pair of controllers I've
just built myself a single failure
domain for 20 years I have spent doing
network design and architecture and
doing coding you know working in BGP and
working in all these other areas and a
rule of thumb is always been split
complexity for complexity don't build
huge failure domains this is spanning
tree right failure domains large failure
domains large interconnected failure
domains or a bad thing so are we really
ready to throw away 20 years of
experience in building distributed
protocols breaking up failure domains
and learning how to manage the stuff in
order to simply go all the way to
centralization my answer is no to that
but these are hard questions we need to
ask ok weather should we go community
action what can we do as network
engineers to think through this and
think about how we could logically take
these building blocks like Legos and
build something useful out of them I
always say you know vendors are in the
rope business you can either build a
hangman's noose or you can build a
signal tower it's entirely up to you
rope is rope so how do we take the rope
that we've been given and build a signal
tower rather than a hangman's noose so I
think the idea is if we need to think
through in our own networks since I
don't know a network that means you I
guess but anyway think through policy
what do we mean by policy what are we
doing with policy can we separate policy
from reach ability does this kind of a
model make sense and then we need to
push back on the vendors and say look we
need to we need to think about how to
compliment how these things complement
each other rather than just assuming
that we're all going to go one direction
ok so these things might be supporting
yangon net comp ok I've said the bad
words and our yang is the favorite thing
of everybody to hate right now and
that's fine I to RS but think about
Stanton ways of pushing look the reason
if yang fails to unify the user
interface or the interface in a
programmatic way across a large number
of devices The Fault doesn't lie with
the vendors as much as we might all like
to yell at the vendors about it it lies
with everybody sitting in this room and
every other nog in the world it's
because we're not pushing the vendors
and I say that as a vendor by the way
we're not pushing the vendors enough to
say look it's important to have a
programmatic interface that allows me to
overlay into my network and do the right
thing you know so anyway that's why one
of my other pet peeves for this morning
think about existing protocols for
southbound could you use pc EP we're
talking a lot about pc EP at ericsson
and about how we could use pc pc EP not
just as a traffic engineering thing but
as a way to do label stacking for things
like service chaining it's an
interesting idea what are the gaps what
needs to be done and how does all this
fit into open source right these are
questions we need to think about and we
need to answer I mean for me from my
perspective like I said I've been doing
this for 20 years I've lived through
this revolution of centralized
decentralized three or four times I'm
getting kind of tired of it and I really
think we need to think through how we
manage or understand the problems we're
trying to address in a better way that
actually makes sense questions and
thoughts that's my dog looking for the
squirrel and you can download the slides
off the off the website and those are
all the places that I write and places
you can get in contact contact with me
if you want to has my email address my
twitter handle alright for ipj all sorts
of places anyway lots of ways to get in
touch with me if you have feedback or
ideas or thoughts or if you want to
throw Rotten Tomatoes off offline any
questions
thanks a lot Russ next up we have oh we
up question
hey Russ sorry sir Dave Meyer brocade
you go um I guess as you know I've been
doing a lot of work in this area over
the last couple of decades and they have
you been an inspiration to me for that
by the way thank you thank you um one of
the things i wanted to mention here is
um the way you talked about complexity
is the way that we always talk about it
as if it's a bad thing and we've really
worked on um trying to tease that apart
a little bit and we've got to this idea
where so the bottom line here is if you
want to have robustness which we all
want which you are talking about in the
latter part of your time you have to
have complexity to achieve that yep it's
the gratuitous complexity that you don't
want right so complexity itself is not
inherently bad in fact it's how you
build it's it's a consequence of trying
to build robustness in these systems
it's thicker to it as part of it that
you don't want yeah completely agree and
that's what I think if we if we think
about what we're actually trying to
solve and divide it into pieces we might
actually be able to figure out a way to
to be complete the right level of
complexity and not too much and not to
them yeah so you know we've tried to
quantify that a little bit in that and
where it sits today is that you try to
understand what complexity is adding
robustness and what what isn't right and
that's that's a hard problem and I think
you're pointing that out the other thing
I wanted to mention was um the
discussion we had about layering was
really pretty pretty on target I'm
actually layering is actually one of the
ways that you build the good kind of
complexity right yeah and because you
can you can separate an abstract right
it's a wasp place model of IP from
original right right that's right thank
you go ahead Tony Tony's going to throw
tomatoes i don't know i was just going
to encourage you to also think about dns
and and traffic steering and people sort
of moving things you know to where they
have the control so you know if if
somebody wants to build I don't know if
you
heard the top from Facebook the other
day or it remarks about how they built a
shim layer to my mom you know to put
control you know have a better control
user experience I think that's going to
be discussed coming up but you know it
it's not just complexity it's also
control you know when some part you can
control versus what somebody else
controls or what's beyond your control
so this really comes down to policy
dispersion right do you want your policy
dispersed throughout your network or do
you want to control your policy
centrally and try to centralize the
policy right and then then you get into
policy surrogates and that's another
entire craziness yep but I great good
point now they come rushing to the mics
no no okay I we're done cool thank you
very much Ross