all right good morning everyone
team at Google you're gonna see my
colleague Annie shake from network
architecture in just a second so we're
going to talk to you guys today about
three things the whole vein of the talk
is really around manageability and magic
ility at scale and how that is sort of
being driven by some of the concepts
that we're looking at in terms of
programmability api's we'll get into
some more detail so let's go ahead and
just jump right into it so what's
driving this talk this kind of will be
the ground the ground floor for us for
some of the motivations so in in our
network environment today some of the
challenges that we're dealing with
we have 20-plus network device roles
half a dozen vendors multiple platforms
multiple generations of those platforms
and service currently we have around 4
million lines of configuration currently
trending around 30,000 changes per month
into the configuration depots every five
minutes we collect around 8 million SNMP
IDEs and store them and around 20,000
CLI commands are issued every five
minutes across the fleet and that data
is also parsed and stored naturally this
lends we have many tools multiple
generations of software multiple
generations of network software to
interact with so there's a there's a
significant challenge here and that you
know we want to be focused on accessing
these devices efficiently storing this
data efficiently parsing and efficiently
but the divergence and hardware and
software that you know the the operator
community has to deal with is is causing
you know a lot of dilution and the
software focus that we have so
continuing on just to kind of reiterate
effects I think everyone here is
probably experiencing this as well op X
is becoming a dominating cost factor in
in network infrastructure today it is it
is growing it is growing with every sort
of new tool you put online with every
new platform you put online every new
version of software you put online the
the optics to manage that is going to go
up unless
there are some opportunities to to sort
of curb that I think that's one of the
core motivations for what we're talking
to you about today so just again keep
setting the stage the management plane
has some challenges in how we're dealing
with these devices today some some
points we'll just throw out there you
know see lies that you interact with our
proprietary in most cases that leads to
a lot of scripts that are generally
written to focus on one COI or another
configuration is often imperative so
that you basically have difficulty in
telling a device the in state you want
it to be in if you want to move an
interface around you actually have to
sequence those steps to the device
yourself you have to tell it do this
then do that then do that sort of a
workflow that you design on your own
rather than just saying I want the end
state to be X there's a significant lack
of abstractions I think you guys have
seen several talks so far during this
conference about sort of better ways to
wrap and abstract some of the the
primitives that exists on their own
today this is actually a big problem for
us as we mentioned just a minute ago a
lot of data that we collect is not
available via things like SNMP which is
an even more difficult problem to deal
with in that we need the data we have to
have it somehow so we wind up having
scripts that go and execute CLI commands
bring that back we use reg X's to parse
it and then determine what data to store
after that and then a little bit of the
preview for the next set of discussion
is going to be around SNMP it's not
always simple and we've actually found
that the scale challenges of SNMP are
growing to be debilitating so we want to
propose a framework that sort of focus
is on data on the device so we're
calling it model driven network
management and there's sort of three
blocks that we're going to throw out
there we'll talk about two in detail
today and the third one we can always
have an offline conversation or in the
conference if you're interested
those three blocks
go ahead and just throw them out there
topology configuration and telemetry so
topology obviously sort of
self-explanatory we're not really going
to focus on that but it's a it's
valuable to have a way to model the
actual connectivity in sort of a graph
fashion of your network devices but what
we will focus on in depth today
configuration telemetry I'm going to
speak mostly about telemetry and my
colleague anis is going to talk you guys
about configuration these these two
ideas are what we want to focus on
because we think that there's a lot of
value if we can sort of address these in
a fashion where we eliminate the
divergence between different versions of
software different vendor
implementations so on and so forth if
there's a standard way to read data from
a device the device can represented in a
structured way and there's also a vendor
independent way for us to send data down
to the device that's sort of the
configuration part of that you guys have
probably seen there's a lot of model
work going on the ITF yang seems to be a
very very hot hot topic on on these
fronts today but we're actually going to
be able to discuss sort of a common
modeling language but then the data
encoding is actually something that is
going to be fairly flexible and that can
be you know at the at the whim of the
operator so to speak telemetry we're
gonna hopefully get into some a little
bit more detail but we're looking to say
that telemetry is also a something
subject to modeling and that you can
actually model the operational data on
the device in a structured way and then
you can deliver that back to something
that doesn't actually have to go through
a very difficult parsing cycle or
something custom it's actually as self
describing as you can make it so again
we're gonna focus mainly on
configuration telemetry telemetry will
be next and I will say this if anyone in
here really really loves us an MP this
could be graphic you may want to leave
we are we are agnostic but we want to
kind of present as much as we can sort
of an objective picture of some of the
the challenges we see with SNMP and then
hopefully some of the solutions that
we're we're hoping to get your input as
the operator community
so just fair warning so telemetry
solutions today obviously SNMP is the
default choice you turn a device up 99%
of the time people be managing it with
SNMP I think you saw Shelly's talk from
Cisco yesterday mentioning some of the
history of SNMP it is it is a relatively
old protocol if you actually go back and
read some of the original protocol specs
some of the core design choices were
actually made to deal with the very
limited processing capability of network
elements at the time and also the
limited bandwidth available to those
network devices to send data upstream to
their telemetry endpoints it's expensive
to discover things with SNMP you
basically put in a new line card you
actually have to ReWalk the device in
order to figure out hey there's a new
piece of hardware so you wind up in a
bunch of challenges about either
overloading the device with discovery
cycles or not even actually knowing when
to run the cycle maybe you do it every
30 minutes you may have a blind spot
about something new coming online that
you want to pick up on there is no
capability advertised on with SNMP it if
the myth says it's there you often have
to test to make sure that the oeid is
actually supported and that doesn't lead
the protocol to actually telling you
what it's capable of providing you from
a telemetry standpoint rigid structure I
don't know anyone in here I'll raise my
hand have actually written an SNMP mode
it is something that isn't really fun to
do and it's sort of archaic so there's a
there's a very limited number of people
who are out there extending the the
datasets that are offered by SNMP and
then often proprietary data really
focusing on the the multiple mappings
required often you pull SNMP you get a
bunch of indices from different tables
it's now on you as the operator to tie
these indices together to give you a
complete picture of what's going on
think about QoS stats on an interface
you may have traffic statute may have
QoS stats you will have to line those up
somehow and that's extra processing and
cognitive overhead that you're
responsible for rather than offloading
that to a network element itself and
this one this I realize that sounds a
little bit
but it is true that there is a large
surface area of open-source work going
on right now in terms of transports RPC
frameworks data encoding mechanisms that
SNMP just is not taking advantage of
sort of the telemetry itself out there
is not really taking advantage of that
so these are some of the things that
we're hoping to kind of address with a
new way to look at telemetry so just
some of the challenges just doing a
little bit of reiteration but with a
little bit more numerical data around it
object collection is growing with each
platform generation I think you guys can
see from some of the demos at gear and
geared the the actual platform density
is growing significantly from the the
vendor community hundred thousand
objects on current platforms our
projections are that that grows you know
three times over the next two
generations and those are conservative
numbers without factoring any new
software features or things that may
require monitoring as well object
collection frequency is also important
to talk about and will actually speak
about this and the bullet coming just in
a second but the trend is continuing
there's no there's no you know real
surprise there but there's scale
limitations at the data acquisition at a
high frequency so if you have an
extremely large device you want to get
data off very very frequently it's it's
a challenge we have not been
successfully able to do that with the
newest platforms that we're deploying in
our infrastructure and it's proven to be
you know a lack of visibility is a lack
of data to operations which is you know
a serious blind spot that can cause us
problems
but the crux of this is the need to
acquire this data is being driven by a
lot of these talks that you guys have
heard you know whatever buzzword you
want to throw in here Sdn and at v--
blah blah blah it is basically that
these technologies all depend on
operational data to be able to arrive at
an optimal solution so garbage in
garbage out if you want tight control
loops if you want software systems that
are steering traffic on your network you
want to be able to feed those systems
with the most accurate data and the most
fresh data that you can possibly give it
so this is putting another sort of
if it is on telemetry to grow in
addition to just the native growth of
the platform over time so this is just
kind of reiterating all we're talking
about so again we don't really like SNMP
that's true but in terms of having a
constructive dialogue there is something
that we're wanting to propose mainly to
to everyone here the operator community
to try to get some specific feedback on
and more importantly to try to get your
involvement in because this is something
that is still coming together that we'd
like to get as many people that sort of
sit in the chair that feel the pain that
actually have a need for those as
possible so what are we thinking so
again you probably saw a preview
yesterday but reversing the flow of
telemetry where instead of going out and
pulling the device going out and saying
give me these things that I think you
have kind of reversing that flow and
putting the onus on the actual network
element to stream that data upstream to
you based on a subscription and a and a
sort of publish/subscribe model so also
observing network state through a time
series data stream is something that you
can actually construct an offline model
of your network in such a way that if
you're getting data frequently enough
that model can be used to sort of have
you know think of it as a network arcing
like you can rsync your network over to
an offline system if you have fresh
enough data play with it there and
actually kind of observe how the network
is reacting in sort of an offline
fashion so anis is actually going to get
far more in detail to the the data model
but a data model is actually really
important here in that if the model
exists on the device in a standard way
and as many of the things are
represented in terms of a yang model or
whatever the flavor does your is that
allows a lot of flexibility and sending
structured data upstream to you in ways
that you don't have to do really
creative ways of parse and you can have
it be self describing and then a really
important part is also in the use of
sort of transport and encoding protocols
that exist today that are secure and
that are focused on efficiency and that
are not necessarily you know
twenty-year-old protocols that haven't
really been
today so going into so just some of the
requirements that we're putting forward
on RN and this is again something we'd
like to collaborate with you guys on
specifically a push model upstream
devices will stream their data to a
network collector that data is actually
populated on the device in data model
that is vendor neutral whenever possible
so an interface traffic StatCounter on a
jennifer device is an interface traffic
StatCounter on a Cisco device Arista so
on and so forth whenever possible to be
standard and then when that has to
deviate you know Anissa is going to talk
in more detail about how the models can
actually deviate and be augmented to
have been there specific knobs and
features in them a Polish subscribed
model using an API where you actually
tell the device what you're interested
in at what frequency you'd like to have
it and where it should send it set it
and forget it you know at that point the
device is now given its you know it's
marching orders and it will send that
data upstream to you based on what
you've told it to do we're looking to
make sure that we have something that
can scale organically with platform
growth as well as have very high data
freshness high data freshness to us is
somewhere in the neighborhood of one to
ten seconds for every individual sensor
or counter on the device and actually in
this discussion I think we're seeing
that other protocols are doing load
management by actually distributing
functions to Hardware telemetry is
another option for that to happen as
well and that's one of the things we're
encouraging people to look at is how can
you actually move the telemetry load out
into the device as far as possible to
make sure that the the load is
maintained without being on a central
point of a failure and/or congestion
again using modern transport mechanisms
with the development community that's
active people are actually you know
putting a pull request out on github
they're developing you know it is
something that you know people coming
out of college will actually be able to
make use of it is not an archaic
protocol that you have to find specially
trained people to do it there are some
examples here we actually have just open
sourced and our piece
framework called G RPC if you're
interested I would encourage everyone to
take a look at it it's available at g RP
cio and there are some backup slides
that have more detail in it and this
deck thrift has been around for a little
bit it's also something to take a look
at or if you wanted to take a very
simple approach just transporting
protocol buffers over UDP
fire-and-forget as long as you have a
way to detect data loss is another
option so just to kind of you know
translate this into the way we're
thinking about how we would configure
this kind of system there are a couple
of steps to the process so in this case
the network element is actually going to
come online and actually advertise a
capability set of hey I have these
sensors on my platform I have these
capabilities and I have this inventory
you know something important if you
don't have SNMP you know you still have
to have a way for the device to describe
its inventory so advice comes online it
actually pushes us upstream to your
network management system the red end
points here are gr FEC endpoints or
whatever RPC API framework you guys
would like but once these these
inventory capabilities are sent upstream
you will have rules which you can define
I'm interested in interface statistics
on Ethernet interfaces every two seconds
and whatever your operations staff may
may want to have for an override I'm
debugging something let me let me put
that in as well network management
system will coalesce this together it'll
generate a model and generate a
monitoring configuration and then
publish that to the network element and
at that point the network element is now
configured with the monitoring it needs
to it needs to send it knows where to
send it how frequently and you're off
and running the flip side of that is the
data flow off the device to your
collection system you can send sistex
every X number of seconds to your
collector whatever it may be can be a
workstation running under someone's desk
it can be an actual you know large
cloud-based service you also want to be
able to a synchronously report events
you know LSP has gone up or down
interface has gone up or down those are
also very important in the concept of
like SNMP traps you
overlook that data and then also this is
an important part is sort of operator
requests or ad hoc data this is someone
logging in to device issuing Ashoka man
hey show me all the blah blah blah on
the device if you're doing this via
telemetry channel in a structured way
your CL eyes can actually become much
more powerful your CL eyes can actually
understand semantically what the data is
coming back to you it can actually flag
things that are important think about a
large show interfaces output that
actually highlights error counters or
highlights other things that maybe you
know of interest to people as long as
you're doing this in a structured way
with a model that is as vendor
independent as possible that sort of
automation is relatively easy to do but
just to recap the three types of data
that we're attempting to cover in this
system or bulk data you just you know
raw time series data
you know blasts it away event-driven
things and then serve the operator
requests in response which we already
covered so practical realization this is
where I'm wrapping up and just trying to
say this isn't necessarily a pipe dream
this isn't something that is intangible
in that you saw a talk yesterday from a
vendor on a streaming telemetry
discussion you're going to see one I
think after our talk here these things
are actually being developed right now
but it's not a final product we're
experimenting we're trying to find a
system that actually is usable but it is
completely for naught
if it is not a larger discussion the
operator community so this is mainly a
call to action for you guys if your
monitoring is fine
then you know that's cool everyone's
happy however if you are concerned about
your monitoring over time or you want to
make your monitoring better or you just
want to explore these ideas now is the
time you know now is the time to get
involved to try to get your input into
these systems before they sort of close
down because the systems really are
geared to make your lives easier in the
operator community so there are vendor
implementations available now for
experimentation this is where I say you
can see who gave these talks at this
presentation go talk to them and go talk
to
your your account teams and just let
them know you're interested and you know
you can kind of see where where things
are in the community so anyway that's
just sort of reiterating you know now is
the time to get involved if you're
interested anis and I are here for the
rest of the conference there's an open
config website in the deck that has
contact information for us if you'd like
to sort of reach out we'd love to
continue a discussion with you at that
point I'm gonna hand over to anis who's
going to talk about the config side of
the puzzle thanks Josh okay um so open
configure we don't have a lot of time
left but in the short time we have I
wanted to essentially give an overview
of what the working group is open config
is a collaboration an informal one an
industry collaboration among network
operators and it's motivated primarily
by all the challenges you saw Josh
described at the beginning the lack of
abstractions the lack of program ability
that results in the lack of API so the
network the fact that we have so many
different tools that have to manage the
heterogeneity and complexity of having
multiple platforms multiple generations
every time we qualify a new platform we
have to qualify all of the tools that
talk to that new platform or the new
generation of that platform so there's a
series of challenges that arise from a
lack of a common way to access
configuration on network devices so this
is just the executive summary of what
open config is as I mentioned it's a
collaboration among operators so it's
informal in the sense that all the
operators involved haven't signed a
single piece of paper there were no
lawyers used in the effort of putting
this thing together it's just a bunch of
network engineers from different
operators who share the same needs and
vision and goals working together to get
some work done
you might also wonder why this is a
collaboration why did why didn't just
proceed on its own it's really to get
the force multiplying effect so it turns
out that there's a large number of
operators who we've spoken to that share
similar sets of goals and challenges and
when we approach our vendors to actually
implement support for some of the models
that we're talking about it makes a big
difference when
more than just one customer coming to
them right so the idea here is to
consolidate the requirements across a
set of customers hopefully a set of
important customers to the key vendors
that we care about and then approach
them that way our focus as Josh
mentioned is on taking this model driven
approach so one of the first things that
we're doing is developing these vendor
neutral data models for both modeling
configuration on network devices as well
as operational state and I'll say a bit
more about both of those things the key
distinction between what we're doing and
what I think the rest of the community
has been doing around data modeling is
that we're taking a pretty purist view
as far as reflecting real operations and
real usage so by involving operators in
defining the models we ensure that the
models don't degenerate into sort of
lowest common denominator and they also
don't try to represent every last
feature on the devices right so we're
not trying to be exhaustive we're trying
to focus the models on what is
operationally useful and important and
what people actually use in their
networks we have adopted yang as the
data modeling language there's a lot of
momentum around yang vendors are
supporting yang based stacks on their
devices if you're not familiar with yang
it's an ITF defined data modeling
language standard it's an RFC 6020 so
who's involved when we started this we
essentially approached AT&T and asked
them if they would be interested we had
some other discussions with them they
were interested and through the ITF we
got connected with a couple of other
operators and it sort of grew and grew
after that so we're up to essentially a
list of 10 or 11 operators you can see
them here all if not most of them are
quite active in the group we have a
meeting every week and we do our work
offline and we essentially use github as
a repository for our the output of our
work so we the main output today is
primarily model code which we publish in
a by open source in a public github repo
that occasionally gets that periodically
gets refreshed and the link is there in
the slides
you might ask what this has to do with
other efforts in modeling whether it's
an ITF or in the onf or in open source
projects like
open daylight or Ono's from owen labs we
do interact with all of those
organizations in addition to our vendors
of course which is our primary
interaction that we do publish our
models as well as other design documents
in the ITF just to inject the operator
perspective into those communities so
just to make this a little bit more
concrete where did these vendor-neutral
models fit into the configuration
pipeline so we start with this notion of
having a relatively high level abstract
intent API right that operator might
want to drain a peering link for example
that usually translates into some change
in topology so there's maybe a link that
needs to be taken down in order to
affect that intent the result of that
topology change then results in a set of
configuration changes right so the
configuration changes have to be
generated based on that update to the
topology now here is where in the
current set of tools that we have you
have this big branch right if it's a
Juniper device I've got to issue this
set of commands if it's an Aristo device
I've got to issue that set of commands
or I've got to get that vendor specific
template or issue this particular API
call so that's the stuff that we want to
do away with I mean the onus has been on
the operators thus far we're trying to
push that further down to the devices so
here's where the vendor-neutral models
come in the configuration data that gets
produced at this step is actually vendor
neutral so you produce configuration
data that will work against any device
that supports the models and that can be
validated so yang itself has some
constructs in it that allows some basic
syntactic validation checking for ranges
defaults pattern matches things like
that simple things and then of course
you'd have some business logic that do
it would do your own validation and
checking of the config and then you can
push it down to devices directly so
there's no translation to a vendor
specific language or configuration style
you essentially push it to devices that
support it and here is where we're
working with some key vendors to
actually support the models directly and
natively so each of the vendors devices
will have to do some sort of translation
to their native schema issue those
configuration commands and of course
when you read back configuration either
through the telemetry channel as Josh
discussed or through some show command
you want to see the data also in the
same schema that you sent to
right so you don't get the data back in
the native schema so this is sort of the
antenna flow that we're envisioning and
we're building a stack now at Google and
testing it that actually follows these
steps pretty closely using some of the
yang models that have come out of open
config so far so one of the first
questions that comes up when we talk
about this is that well this base vendor
neutral model sounds great but what
about devices that don't quite support
it or need to support some additional
things so it turns out that there is a
relatively natural way to do this this
is one of the one of the key features of
yang that that we actually appreciate it
for it has a lot of other rough edges
I'll admit so the idea is that you have
this base model again it's not a it's
not a least common denominator model
it's an operational useful comprehensive
model that reflects all the use cases of
the operators that were involved in in
developing it but then there's also a
opportunity to extend the model so for
example vendors might propose
modifications that add specific
configuration nodes for some feature
that they support uniquely right that
aren't that isn't supported on other
devices or platforms they may also not
support the entirety of the base model
so there might be a deviation from the
model that they issue the nice thing in
yang is that you can create these
augmentations and deviations
programmatically right so they're
another they're just another yang module
that when overlaid with the base module
gives you a resulting model that
represents what's actually supported on
the device now we're pushing our vendors
to support the base model in its
entirety but in the near term it's
obviously going to be the case that not
every bit of the of the model can be
fully supported so we fully expect to
deal with deviations and augmentations
at least for some time and then of
course there are other modifications
that might be local to an operators
usage so an operator might have specific
data that only they need to consume you
can similarly extend the model with
those those data act nodes so that you
know your management stack can
understand and use them so where are we
an open config we've been working at
this for probably close to a year now
maybe just a month shy from when we
officially sort of kicked this off in
that time we've produced some fairly
complex data models so we spent actually
a number of months focusing initially on
BGP and routing policies so we've
published a pretty comprehensive vgp
model also a generic routing policy
model that also supports BGP specifics
there's details about both of the models
on our website and also in the ITF
drafts we've published the good news is
that there's actually multiple vendors
who are now starting to support the
model so we've had demos in labs across
the open config operators that actually
support the consumption of these models
directly on those devices we've also
done a fair bit of work on an MPLS and
traffic engineering model and this is
sort of a consolidated model again the
approach is really operation centric
it's really the model is not protocol
centric is it RSVP is that LDP is it sr
it is really about ok what kind of LSP
am I trying to create what are the
different items that I need to configure
some of them are protocol specific but
we're trying to create a framework
that's natural for operators to use and
I think that can only arise when you
have operators involved in defining the
models so our initial focus of this
model has been on the rsvp-te portions
and also the segment routing portions
and again those models are published in
the public repo that we have we've also
in addition to the models themselves try
to move the conversation forward in the
yang and net conf and net mod
communities by offering up design
patterns for how you should model things
like operational state which has been
relatively sort of unaddressed in the
current work that's gone on and also the
need for actually putting models
together I'll say a little bit more
about that in one more minute and the
other thing that's come out of open
config are now some tools for
translating yang models into actual
usable code artifacts that you can use
in your management systems so I'll just
mention one of them this is PN vine from
Rob shakir at BT who's an active member
in open config this will create Python
classes for an open config yang model
that then you can use to populate with
real config data and then we have a
number of other models in progress I'll
just mention a couple we're revisiting
the interfaces and systems model to make
them more comprehensive and useful
operationally we've also just started
talking about it
after of an optical transport model and
they'll be more models coming so I'll
just mention two more points before
wrapping up one is that a lot of the
work that's gone on in this modeling
space has been very focused on defining
a model all right the problem with that
is that I can't set up a service or even
a device with n interfaces model or a
bgp model i need a set of models that
work together in a coherent fashion so
model composition to create an overall
device model or an overall network model
is crucial but it's really been a
missing piece of the modeling work
that's gone on we've actually proposed a
way to compose models at least at the
device level how the different
individual models should be fit together
to create something that's more
comprehensive and useful the second is
about modeling operational State yang
has thus far been really focused on
modeling configuration but we're really
trying to you know explore how to use it
also for modeling operational State this
includes the state that's reflected by a
fluid derived or negotiated values think
of you like a negotiated BGP whole time
the state that you might normally think
of as counters or statistics and also
state that represents the intended
configuration so oftentimes you have
systems where the configuration that you
push down is not necessarily the actual
configuration right away there's some
time that it takes for that
configuration to be actually committed
so by treating configuration of state
you can actually see this mismatch
directly and also get a sense of how
long it takes for that config to
propagate so we see clear benefits in
using yang for modeling both styles of
data and there's a bunch of conventions
and design patterns that we've proposed
and we're discussing with the ITF net
mod community so finally just to wrap up
you know Josh opened the talk by you
know mentioning that a lot of the work
that's gone on is you know been related
to control of the network right we're
applying all these new paradigms and
techniques to basically to the control
space but relatively little attention
still being paid to the management space
right so really we're looking for a way
to make the management plain more
programmable more API driven handling
abstractions all the things that we
mentioned through the talk so there's
three core principles that I think we've
we're
sort of pushing here one is this idea of
model driven management that we talked
about earlier the second is you know
really changing the way telemetry and
monitoring is done to more of a
streaming style that really improves the
scale and also the freshness and
accuracy of the data the third is really
pushing for a vendor-neutral way to
configure api's we don't buy different
platforms because they have different CL
is we have considerations whether its
density robustness price whatever it is
but the fact that I have to use a
completely different CLI to configure
BGP on every different device this
doesn't make any sense and there's no
real reason for it that we can see so
this is a core principle that we're
driving so two examples of this the
architecture and the reference to
emerging vendor implementations of the
multimode streaming telemetry type
solutions you've seen examples yesterday
you'll see another one today shortly and
then also we've talked about open config
which is a collaborative effort by
network operators to develop these
vendor neutral models for api's to the
management plane and then finally the
last thing is you know we just urge
other operators to get involved if you
share these goals and this vision you'll
get involved in open config you know be
an active participant either in sharing
your requirements so that the models
reflect the things that you need and
also pushing your own vendors to support
both the vendor neutral models as well
as the telemetry solutions that were
outlined before so this is happening now
in the industry we have multiple vendors
as I mentioned involved in these
implementations and we'd really like to
get more operators involved in providing
the input thank you very much
hi a quick question
why why isn't the industry embracing
what's happened with server management
you know puppet chef these other tools
that we're using to manage our other
devices why don't we just integrate the
same why don't we use JSON all these
message queuing buses things that
they're well established maybe I'm from
San Francisco have been do it too many
web startups but these are these are the
same problem sets in my mind different
devices why don't we use the same
technology so you know I think some of
the technologies you mentioned are
certainly potentially viable you know I
think our own view on this is that the
tools that we use for server management
yes they've been applied to things like
white box data center switches I'm not
convinced that they apply across the
board to much more complex pieces of
networking gear that are you know
various have very specific network
functionality but that said it is
feasible although you know just because
I have a JSON based encoding doesn't
mean I have a data schema right the
models are still key so having a model
that represents the actual schema and a
vendor neutral way could still be used
with a puppet style configuration system
or use JSON encoding right so we're
really focused on the models and less so
on the transport and the data encoding
we consider those sort of secondary hi
so I add hi Josh I meant so I guess I
have a quick question which is basically
you why push this in this way right
there there's a number of different
repositories at this point for various
yang configuration modules there's also
opendaylight stuff which is primarily
yang based there's i2 RS and ITF and I
guess you guys are positing that this is
fundamentally different in some way
from it from a technological perspective
it's not just not clear to me why we
need all of these separate efforts so I
guess I'm wondering just specifically
what's different about this and then you
know two or three others that are going
on right now again I don't know that I
would say they're fundamentally
different because at the end of the day
they're all producing yang models and in
fact we're publishing the models in the
some of the same repositories that you
mentioned and as far as the working
groups whether as I said we interact
closely with ITF and we're trying to
leverage the work that's going on there
but I think what is unique about this is
that it really is an operator driven
perspective it is the consumers view of
what the data models ought to look like
as opposed to the backend view which is
currently how most of the models are
being defined meaning that you know
vendor implementation vendor driven
models tend to reflect implementations
and I think it's the perspective on the
models has been different
are you are you positing that IETF is
not an effective forum for large network
providers to drive these sorts of models
well I think that ITF has its challenges
I wouldn't go so far as saying that it's
completely ineffective I mean you saw
that if you saw the presentation at the
last minute from Chris Brendam and I
think he points out some of the issues
that operators have in in ITF I don't
get into that here but we are trying
hard to work with ITF it hasn't been
easy I will say though LG Walker
barefoot I'm sure it's been considered
but it's not obvious how if you go back
to that slide where you had the two
trees the base model the extended model
you don't have to actually put it there
but I had horrible flashbacks of all the
vendor specific oh I D myth kind of
catastrophe and in a former life being
somewhat responsible for that expansion
I'm interested in how kind of
organizational way you're going to keep
people from doing the same thing and
growing us all again
so LD it's a great point and it is
definitely a risk in this approach right
I think one advantage we have here is
that we have a multitude of operators
all asking for the same thing we're
pushing our vendors to not support some
you know their own version of the model
there's a base model that we're
expecting and pushing all of them to
support
we're just recognizing the reality that
at least in the near term there will be
deviations from the model and vendors
should be free to add their own specific
special knobs because they have
customers that may depend on them now
the point here though is that you can do
this extension a bit more
programmatically than we could do in the
past the hope is that that will make it
a bit easier to deal with but I fully
agree that there is a risk of that
happening would be when dealing with
vendors you would probably be well
served to be more rather than less
strict and how are you present that
because otherwise I think if you I think
if you give them an inch they will take
a country mile thanks yeah I fully agree
I think we are being as strict as you
can that's why we have people like Igor
helping us for example an LJ just to
just kind of reiterating that point like
the base model itself is trying to be as
complete as it possibly can so this is
this is kind of flipping that that's
sort of dynamic around where it's on the
vendor to come up with everything where
it's actually on the operator community
to come up with the 80% solution and
then if there are things that need to be
tacked on to that or modified then you
know there's there's a framework to do
that as possible it's not necessarily
the default choice on the same note to
answer Ed's question in a not as polite
way because the guy needs was trying to
be nice
ITF is a pain in the ass to work with
they move very slow sorry I've heard
I've heard that yes you should remember
that as being a working group chair the
other major thing is the way IT have a
structured into very different
hierarchies one of the things that was
very interesting for me about open
config
that it kind of creates one guidance for
every different hierarchy of how we want
things structured so we don't have MPLS
that's looking one way BGP that looks
completely different because one is
routing one is transport area and they
don't talk to each other very much in
idea so this is kind of a top level
guidance of make everything look the
same because guess what your Ola router
and that's one of huge advantages of
open config and oh by the way all of
this has been fed back into ITF sort of
via a set of informational traps yeah
but which has a way to feed badger name
sure now but I guess I guess the
question was mostly around just like why
why not do this tonight or else and I
guess the answer is you think it's
moving too slowly which I think it is -
I mean all of it is being said that the
informational drafts which at some point
if ITF wants to pick it up will become
standards and if we the operators tell
vendors that this informational draft we
require implementation of and you know
that's how we get it done we have had
some luck by the way and with pushing
some from informational to standard the
BGP model for example looks like it's
making progress in the idea or working
group that way well that's good thanks a
lot Josh and it needs