hi everyone thank you for coming I come
from University of Southern California
information Sciences Institute and i'll
be talking to you about the research
system we've developed for distributed
attack defense this is joint work with
minh lam you and abdul allah girl
trouble USC and in jhang from HP labs my
primary reason for being here this is my
first 90 days to get community feedback
about the system if it seems deployable
I don't know if there's a some I
fearsome macro they my tooth to closer
is it fine ok so we would like to know
if the system seems deployable if we've
overlooked anything if our assumptions
are realistic and if anyone is
interested in pilot this we will have a
prototype zones we would like to like to
talk to you so start with the motivation
and insights we had we looked at
distributed attacks on the internet I've
worked myself in denial of service area
for 15 years and we just have ongoing
trend of the attacks getting more
frequent and stronger and we have very
few solutions for them so this is the
slide showing the trend in denial of
service area it's borrowed from the
arbor Network annual report for 2014
where two-thirds of the networks say
they've been hit by a DDoS attack and
the volume of the attacks has hiked
skyrocketed in the prefix hijacking area
of the radishes corporation publishes an
annual report showing the frequency of
the attacks and in 2013 15 hundred
prefixes have been hijacked in 150
cities you can see that these are
distributed all over the world and the
attacks have lasted sometimes for 60
days so imagine losing your traffic for
60 days the traffic for major companies
and governments and ISPs has been
affected by this and so the attack
various that we wanted to focus on in
our work are indeed us field direct
floods reflect
attacks and crossfire and in btp pubic
skyjacking origin and closeness attacks
with black holing or interceptions so
I'll go quickly over these just as a
refresher the yellow dot is representing
the victim and the red dots are the
attackers in these pictures and during
the direct floods the attackers send
high volume traffic to the victim that
overwhelms its network in reflector
attacks the attackers spoofed the
victims addresses in service requests
for example DNS requests they send them
to public servers usually open resolvers
and these servers reply these are
usually much larger replies than the
requests were and this traffic over
rounds the victim the crossfire attack
is something that has been proposed in
the academic community I don't think
we've seen it in the wild some people
tell me that this would not be really
problem in the operational world but
this is something that academics have
been looked looked at the crossfire
attack has the attackers and traffic
from many sources too many destinations
but the destinations are smartly
selected so that the traffic converges
on a single link in some given ISP this
happens to be the link that the
legitimate traffic crosses from clients
to the victim and that's where the
congestion occurs that's where the
traffic gets dropped this is far from
the victim the victim does not see
congestion it just sees that it's loses
its losing traffic the is pcs congestion
but cannot diagnose why it happens
because there are many sources
communicating too many destinations in
the traffic in which IP prefix hijacking
we look at the origin and closeness
attacks in a region attacks the attacker
announces the prefix of the victim and
does attracts the traffic in the
closeness attacks the attacker claims to
be close to the victim so if he claims
the short a spot and that's how he
attracts the victims traffic and once he
attracts it he can drop it this is the
black falling attack or he can modify it
or sniff it and forward onto the victim
that's the interception attack so
looking at all these attacks we ask what
is the thing they have in common and the
thing they have in common is that they
are really hard to mitigate and diagnose
from the victim's perspective because
the victim needs to
observed traffic and routes in remote
networks to diagnose the attack
sometimes and to mitigate it it needs
help of the remote networks for the
mitigation indeed us case to drop the
traffic in a bgp prefix hijacking case
to fix the routes that have been
polluted and especially in the bgp
prefix hijacking case i'd like to point
out that the routes that are polluted
are usually polluted in the networks
that are far from the victim these are
in the networks that will adopt the
attackers route because it will be the
shortest one so our insight was that we
need help of remote eyes piece for
attack diagnosis and mitigation and we
came up with the idea of sense this is
the framework the system that would be
deployed by ISPs that the victim could
talk to on demand when it's under attack
and it would enable the victim to
observe its own traffic we define on
traffic as traffic going to the victims
prefixes or carrying the source IP from
the victims prefixes it could control
its traffic you can think of senses
enabling a distributed firewall where
the victim can filter or allow traffic
to its prefixes but these rules are
installed in remote networks it could
observe its own routes throughout to its
own prefixes from remote networks and it
could control these routes by demoting
some routes that have the attacker
segment or asking for the route to be
corrected in a by replacing some
segments of the a spot with a different
segment so now tell you more details
about how sense works i speedrun sence
servers and victims talk to these
servers when they are under the attack
they could discover the existence of
these servers through some public
directory for example through dns and
they when the victim is under attack it
would select which is peace to talk to
it would send a query it either about
traffic or about routes receive
responses figure out where to act on the
traffic to filter traffic or where to
correct routes and then send control
messages
that would then be implemented by ISPs
of course all this requires very well
thought and foolproof security layer
because we don't want people affecting
anybody's traffic or routes except their
own and we have mechanisms to ensure
that and every ISP when they received
the request would actually authenticate
the request verify the ownership of the
prefix and then act on that we also
envisioned that ISPs could charge for
this service so this could be an add-on
service they wouldn't just do it for
free although I guess we don't quite
understand how the operational world
looks like maybe people would do it for
free that's that's what I'd like
feedback on too so we made two key
design decisions first was that we
wanted is to be implementable today in
today's ISP infrastructure so we have
very simple actions in ISPs that can be
done with today's infrastructure and all
intelligence resides at the victim so
the victim collects this information
decides what to do and then implement a
score control actions of the ISPs this
also has the benefit that the victim
decides about its own traffic it routes
so it aligns the ownership of traffic
and routes with the control over these
and this is good because victim there
are many trade-offs indeed us and prefix
hijacking it's usually not clear-cut
what to drop it's usually not clear-cut
which route to fix and how and so the
victim that the precaution of
precautions of having the bad decision
means that some legitimate traffic might
get dropped victim is the one that has
enough insight to make these decisions
it understands the priorities of its
operation it can understand what the
what the consequences would be if
certain types of traffic get dropped we
also made the second design decision to
support direct victim remote ISP
communication and what this enables us
to do is in a very sparse deployment if
this if the sense is deployed in key
points in the internet then everyone can
benefit whether they appear directly
with the sense ESP
or not so this is a quick comparison
with the state of the art I tried to
focus only on the either solutions that
are currently deployed in the
operational world or those that could be
easily deployed there is much more
related work that I'm not showing here
and I won't go in detail through this
except to point out that our goal was to
handle a large variety of attacks
because the techs are relatively
frequent in the internet but they are
rare for any given victim so if the ISP
is to market this service to its
customers it better be able to handle
many different attacks so that the
customers may use it relatively
frequently we handled all the attacks
that have listed on the motivation
slides direct floods reflector attached
sand crossfire and then like hauling
interception prefix hijacking with
origin and closeness variants the other
solutions in this space only handle a
few of these attacks and I would like to
focus on two solutions that are relevant
to to us the commercial d-does
differences such as CloudFlare and
Prolexic and secure BGP so cloudflare
Prolexic and many similar did those
defenses work by diverting the customer
traffic through a CDN like structure
they avoid presence on the internet and
then so that helps sustain the attack
and they also have proprietary
algorithms and deep packet inspection
they try to scrub the traffic they try
to figure out what's the attack and
remove it and let just a legitimate
traffic through in some cases this
solution will actually be more accurate
than what sense can do because sense
works at the header level not at the
content level and we made this decision
on purpose because as I said we wanted
it to be deployable in today's network
infrastructure however the DDoS
mitigation solutions that exist today
concentrate traffic in this city and
like structure and this can lead to
other problems
attackers can go after links that appear
with the DDoS defense provider or goal
after the defense providers
infrastructure itself that was the case
during spamhaus attacks where they
couldn't bring Spamhaus down because it
was using CloudFlare but they went after
CloudFlare and they went after certain
peering links that CloudFlare had and
for some limited amount of time this
created problems for bystanders for
traffic that was just traversing this
infrastructure going to other places and
so we believe that sense is a better
solution because it could have either
reach it does not divert traffic it just
works with the current routes that the
traffic tricks takes and if does if
there is an ISP deploying sense on this
route it can have a great benefit to the
victim insecure BGP direction the secure
BGP can mitigate all the prefix
hijacking attacks by doing heavy crypto
both on the it validates both the origin
of the route and every hop in das pot
however to fully secure the part you
need full deployment from the source to
the destination that's hard to ensure in
today's Internet nothing will ever be
fully deployed everywhere we believe
that we need something that works in
sparse deployment and has actually good
performance inspires deployments people
feel motivated to use it and we believe
that sense is this solution it uses rpki
for a region authentication but then the
AAS path is not authenticated we just
detect when there are texts that Miss
USA has part the closeness attacks and
then we can correct for those so these
are the sense API satires piece I won't
go through each of them except to point
out that you can ask about your traffic
or routes if you ask about traffic what
you get back from the ISP is the
distribution of traffic over the
neighbors of the TSP you can tell which
neighbor sense which traffic what volume
of traffic to your prefixes using this
is P
you can identify a Stas links and the
volume of traffic they carried to you in
the route query you asked about the best
route and you get the response when
controlling traffic you can ask for
traffic to be filtered or allowed you
can we originally proposed that you can
also ask for bandwidth guarantees
listening to the FCC talk I learned that
this is actually not in line with the
net neutrality so we'll we'll be looking
how to fix that but this is just a small
part of sense and it's really not
critical we can actually drop that and
then in the route control you can ask
for routes to be demoted if they have a
certain segment or you can correct that
segment you can ask to be replaced for a
different segment the envision that
sense would be deployed the ties piece
is a web service and we made this
decision because there are a lot of
functionalities that web service
currently has that we can leverage for a
botanist we can leverage your
application solutions to to web services
for security we can leverage HTTPS and
for if I speeds were to charge for this
we can leverage e-commerce solutions so
people can sign up on demand and start
using sense now talk about security
security is very important we don't want
people controlling anybody's traffic or
out but their own and so we propose rpk
use of rpki to verify ownership you can
only when you send requests for sense
services you attach the RPK our
certificate the ISPs validated and only
if it's valid they will take actions so
you can only affect traffic for your
prefixes and routes for your prefixes
also to address attacks in the middle we
use TLS that's a common for
communication security further victim
might be so over around with the attack
that it cannot communicate not even with
sense maybe it's prefixes are hijacked
so it cannot receive replies from sense
and that's bad because victim needs to
observe in order to learn what to do
with
traffic and routes or it may be solver
around with the DDoS attack that it
cannot receive replies again from san
servers what victim can do easily with
sense is offload the victim
functionality to say a cloud in a
different network if the victim prepared
a proxy or several proxies in several
different networks in advance and gave
them the prefix ownership through router
is a shin through our pki that these
proxies can act on behalf of the victim
when the victim is disabled so now
briefly introduce how we could use sense
to diagnose and mitigate attacks and I'd
like to point out that these are just
examples since api's are very simple so
you can combine them the customer can
combine them in any way they see fit in
case of direct floods the if there is a
tcp/ip signature the handling is simple
the victim would choose the ISPs to
communicate wit and just ask them to
drop the traffic this is similar to flow
spec use today except that it works with
remote ISPs and it adds layer of
security that does not currently exist
in flows pack if there is no tcp/ip
signature traffic is coming from
everywhere it's hard to separate
legitimate from the attack the victim
can use sense to identify links between
the neighbors of the cells deploying ISP
and that is P so it identifies dasdas
links that carried little traffic prior
to the attack to the victim and now
carry a lot and these links are prime
candidates for filtering because they
are likely to carry most of the attack I
will illustrate this with an example
this is a simple example of a data
attack prior to the attack the blood
traffic flows to the victim imagine that
only the grey nodes are the nose
deploying sense so adgjm the victim
periodically queries them about the
volume of traffic they received from
their neighbors and it learns that link
a B carries most of the track
to it during regular operation when
there is an attack it queries again it
now learns that link ls2 carries a lot
of traffic whereas it did not do so
before link JK carries a lot of traffic
whereas previously it carried just a
little and so these are the links that
are prime candidates for filtering the
next step would be for the victim to ask
for filters in L and potentially in j2
to filter the attack we have a solution
for reflector attacks that we believe
would be able to surgically remove the
attack traffic reflector attacks are
mostly unhandled today what we propose
is that the victim could net all
outgoing traffic to the service that is
affected that is misused in the attack
for example if the attacker is making a
lot of DNS requests then port 53
requests would be perfectly three
traffic would be netted at the victim
and the victim would choose a range of
source ports that is secret known only
to the victim this range is a to b and
then it would send to control messages
to isps asking them to let only replies
to the net i pianned to range of ports a
to b from the port 53 and drop all the
other replies and of course if the there
are only six hundred 65,536 ports so the
attacker can probe and figure out which
ports range the victim is using and then
focus it spoofing on that but the victim
can dynamically keep changing this range
because sense is fully automated in the
interception attack this is the attack
where the victim victims prefix is
hijacked by the attacker if the attacker
annouce is the prefix rpki takes care of
that so we don't have to do anything
special with sense however if the
attacker announced is short part to the
prefix this is the attack that is very
hard to diagnose and to mitigate today
using sense the victim can ask the
deploying guys fees for their control
plate
XO it asks about routes and it forms
this control plane pad set CPPs it also
can ask about the data plane pet about
where traffic is coming and going when
it's going to the victims prefixes which
which neighbors of the ISP send and
receive this traffic and from that it
forms the data plane pad now looking at
the intersection of these two if there
are segments a FAS pad the terrain the
control plane but not in data plane
these are prime candidates for having
the being the fake segment the fake
parts of the segment of the route
announcement that the attacker made and
these are the segments that can be
corrected either by demoting this route
or by correcting the segment's so I'll
illustrate this quickly in this picture
H is the attacker it announces part hgv
to the victim so it's doing the
closeness attack and this attracts the
traffic from the ases that are close to
it again only grey ones are deploying
sense victim can ask the tray that the
sense deploying guys piece for their
control part and it learns from G&L that
their control part is going through h
and then g and 2v but then through
asking about the data pet it learns that
g receives traffic from age but sends it
to f and victim notes from its own
observations that it receives traffic
from e so it assembles the data pet that
is different from the control pad
looking at these two there is GV segment
that appears in the data pad but not in
the cern in the control pad but not in
data pad so the victim can ask for any
route that has a GV segment to be
demoted I'll talk briefly about the
evaluation I was cautioned not to
mention well word simulation in this
meeting but unfortunately we we are at
the University and we have to work with
simulations however we also wanted to
answer the question how this would do in
sparse deployment because that's what we
care about if this doesn't do well
with first few adopters then no one will
ever ever deploy this so we constructed
a nice level topology from route views
we looked at several partial deployment
scenarios what if only a small ISPs
deployed this or what if a mix of small
ISPs and tier 2 and tier ones reply this
and in these mixes seventy percent would
be small ISPs twenty-five to thirty
percent tier tools and five percent
there one and we went up to 200 de esas
which is half of the percent of the
current AAS population and it's 15 times
fewer 15 times smaller deployment and
current deployment of rpki for some of
these simulations we needed to assume
some things about the tiger distribution
and legitimate traffic distribution and
we used both realistic traces from
EdgeCast for legitimate traffic and from
bars group at CMU and UCSD for attacks
and we also looked at just random
choices of attackers and legitimate
clients and all these simulations had
the similar conclusions I'll just show
you a few of those in case of the dots
reflection and direct flood with
signature I'm showing you the benefits
that under different deployments the
benefits that would be experienced by
direct customers of the sense deploying
ISP these are the red and the yellow
bars the yellow bar is for multihomed
customers and the red bar is for single
home and then the brown bar is for
everyone else so what if someone
anywhere in the internet wants to use
sense and you can see the direct
customers have huge benefits that's
given because they work directly with
their isp they know what to filter and
the ISP just filters it however when we
have tier 2 deployment or tier 1
deployment the benefits become huge not
just for the direct customers but for
everyone else because there is high
probability of attack traffic hitting
one of the sense deploying ISPs and
again because the signature is so
specific it can filter the attack in
case when there is the dose flood
without signature
this is the case when we have to
identify these AAS links that did not
carry much traffic before but now do and
are likely carrying attack in small ISP
deployment we don't have good
performance mostly because you really
need white performance to catch the
attack if the attack is not traversing
your deployment point you cannot do
anything with it however when you do
have deployment in tier two and Tier one
is peace and this is again very small
deployment it goes from 20 deployment
points to 200 and only twenty-five
percent of those are tier two and five
percenter dear ones we have huge benefit
for both direct customers again direct
customers have more benefit than remote
ones but everyone else experiences
benefit similarly for interception
attacks we need deployment in tier 2 and
tier ones too to have benefit when these
deployment points correct their routes
then the corrected route propagates to
their neighbors even if they are not
deploying sense it propagates just by
using btp so talk briefly about
deployment considerations the biggest
feedback we've got from operational
world is that there are concerns about
privacy and policy the tires peace have
and we understand that this is a big
change in the culture opening your eyes
p for anyone to to insert control and
observation messages in it we believe
that the structure we've imposed on
these api's helps understand the risk
and we believe that the risk is very
small to non-existent so routing
information is already public traffic
information there is sensitivity a nice
piece about load balancing and if asking
about traffic would reveal load
balancing decisions however the neighbor
information and the volume in the
replies when you're asking about traffic
and you're getting this replied that
tells you about distribution of traffic
over other the neighbors of the sense
deploying I speed this information can
be anonymised or aggregated and sense
can still work well but you're
preserving the privacy
finally the ISP can always refuse to
take any action that goes against its
policies so this is just a service that
is offered the customer asks for service
the ISP can refuse for example if the
customer is asking too many questions or
asking to demote routes that are
especially desirable for the ISP and
have been around for a while the ISP can
refuse talking about charging we would
really like your feedback we envision
that you I space could charge fixed
price or on demand and we believe that
on demand makes more sense because
victims are infrequently affected by
these attacks and disproportionately and
it would be nice for them to sign up
when they are under attack to sign up in
an automated fashion and to reap the
benefits and pay only when they are
using the service we looked very closely
into misbehaving ISPs and what would
happen if someone is lying or someone is
underperforming and the good news is
because this of the sense design where
the all intelligence resides of the
victim and victim is only asking about
the particular ISPs view of the world
lying cannot really affect us it only
increases the cost of the of the victim
because the victim pays for services
that are not rendered and it may delay
the correct decision at the victim but
the victim will not make a wrong
decision because of it will not filter
legitimate traffic or correct Allah or
out that does not need to be corrected
so to conclude our we believe the
distributed attacks are not handled well
today the focus today is on sustaining
the attacks but the real fix is dropping
attack traffic and fixing routes that
have been a hijacked and so we believe
that sense can help in this regard that
it can help detect and mitigate
distributed the text it has good
performance inspires deployment and it's
simple to deploy with current
infrastructure so we believe that this
is these are good news and we hope to
motivate my deployment
ultimately review sense as a first step
towards future infrastructure for isp
collaboration with these simple api's we
can handle not just current attacks but
future attacks and we also believe that
there are many cases that are not
security related for example there are
natural catastrophes that affect routing
in some part of the internet and sense
could be used to detect that and to
enter mitigate it so thank you for
coming please reach out to us if you're
interested to learn more if you're
interested to deploy this will have a
prototype maybe by the end of the summer
these are pictures and our names and our
project web page and my email address
and specifically we would like feedback
from both eyes peas and customers if we
overlooked anything again we're coming
from academic world where newbies to
this or if there are any other attacks
that we should look at how likely it
would be to deploy this how would you
charge anything that you can give me
would be appreciated thank
Randy Bush IJ and Dragon labs um first
of all hot stuff thank you very much um
I just one pedantic comment our pki is a
database it doesn't check anything or
validate anything you are specifically
using rpki based origin validation thank
you yes ok there is also in prototype
and test rpki based path validation
which will help address future issues
there but I just wish everybody here
would be careful with the term rpki it's
just a pki it's how you choose to use it
right thank you any other questions
comments don't be shy
one question bcp 38 and our TBH I've
been around a long time and one of the
things could be said for them one of the
reasons that they're widely utilized is
because they are standards-based in any
of your work is there anything being
done to incorporate this in the current
standards which these other principals
or engineering tools that already exists
our are thus given the necessary
respectability to enable widespread use
you're referring to the ingress
filtering busy p38 again what you what
you presented here is you know seems
like in some ways of you know a
follow-on and hopefully an improvement
for certain you know mitigation tools
that are already used right and the
mitigation tools that are already used
our standards based so my question is is
a part of the process to propagate the
use of of sense is is to make it anyway
standards-based or is that discussion
not relevant to sense frankly we have
not thought about this yet it would be
great direction to think about Thanks
okay thank you