so next up we have a NYX lab coat from
juniper
source routing two point oh why now why
again
good morning everybody so we start with
a question how many made it yesterday to
the Facebook netops coding tutorial yay
Wow seems like most people I enjoyed it
a lot too what a great job by Facebook
to tell us about their f bar system that
allows them to pretty much render their
network without a knock I think they
said like one guys on call what an
awesome job by David Swofford for
keeping about 500 LS on track for three
hours writing Python code at the end
even I wrote something and now I get to
wear a t-shirt with with some piping
stuff on it so seriously though what
Facebook did is they took a fairly old
technology I have to look it up last
night Python has been around since 1989
I think that's the the year when the
Berlin Wall fell so they've taken a
fairly old technology they've added some
new insights to it some pixie dust shall
we say and have developed something
that's pretty cutting edge I'll say the
n vehicle of meaning so I looked at the
age of of Python then I thought few
technologies out there are as all this
Python and source routing is one of them
so we'll talk about source routing today
again from a perspective of some new
ideas some new insights that people have
added to it in order to do cool things
and where we're going to do that is I'm
going to go through a little bit of
history of source routing level said
everybody on what that is but the real
reason for talking about source routing
today is the resurgence of or the
emergence of this segment routing
technology which uses the concepts of
source routing so this is not going to
be a segment routing tutorial by all
means
there are better ones out there all I'm
going to do is just kind of mention a
few major concepts just so that we all
understand the insights that came out of
it and got implemented by some people
calling spring inspirations by the way
so first a little bit of a level set
I'll use these three terms fairly
extensively in this talk source routing
is a very generic tremens been there
forever and it basically covers all
these technologies that allow you to put
a prescriptive header in the packet and
send that packet in the network and
every router acts on that prescriptive
header with regard to its forwarding
segment routing on the other hand is a
specific incarnation of source routing
it's kind of the technology de jour
shall we say it kind of does the same
thing in a particular way spring is the
simply the name of the ITF group charter
with standardizing these source routing
technologies I will use the spring term
and the seminar during term pretty sort
of interchangeably in this presentation
and most people do that anyway and it's
okay so the main idea in back to source
routing the kind of the generic thing
the main idea there is let's prescribe
the path of the packet in the header of
the packet itself and then launch that
packet into the network and each router
acts on that header and and that header
tells them how to forward that packet a
nice side effect of that is that you get
to avoid loops and loops in the network
quite easily by just describing where
packets go and eliminating the hub by
hub decision from routers another nice
side effect is that you get to reduce
the forwarding state in the network
which is always a good thing a few
historical examples if you guys come
from you know high-performance computer
environment there's all these exotic
interconnects their space wire
at they'll use source routing technology
in their forwarding those of you that
are of certain age will probably
remember token ring and appn and all
these other technologies that also use
source routing in their core but for
most of you source routing probably
means putting source router subscribe
with headers in the IP packet and v4 and
v6 both have definitions for that
unfortunately all of those definitions
have been you know kind of deprecated
that simply didn't work out and you
would think that v6 will get it right
but it really didn't leading to you know
RFC 5095 pretty much banning routing
headers from the packets tunneling on
the other hand if you're on the in a
service provider edge and if you take a
packet and put it in a tunnel and then
source throughout that tunnel packet
that tends to be treated with better
respect and consider more secure in fact
all of these mpls networks today that's
what they do you know if you're familiar
with RSVP it uses ER OS and euros and
northing nothing more than source routed
you know statements
so why now are we talking about source
routing again it is because of the
industry interest in spring or seven
routing technology again the key in
spring is to tunnel packets from the
source to the destination by describing
the path of the packet in a header with
a sequence of segments what that's what
what segment routing is calling it and
there's certain good flexibility there
you can describe more or less in the
header depending on how much you care
about the specific path the packet needs
take the other reason why this new
interest in source routing is has come
around is the resurgence of the interest
in centralized controllers and they are
not a not a new idea by themselves but
with all the interest in SDM of course
every Sdn has one of these so or more
their job is generally to do path
calculation and also paths in position
at the ingress of the traffic and the
ingress could be their host or a router
but the kind of the confluence of those
two factors has started people thinking
again about hey what can I do with
source routing these days so I'll go
through a few slides only again just a
couple of concepts around spring nothing
inclusive really there's there's much
more extensive tutorials out there there
are two main concepts around spring one
is or segment routing one is that every
router is going to assign a label to all
of its interfaces as a matter of fact to
sloop loopback address as well and it's
going to flood these labels into the igp
and with that knowledge every router now
can craft the packet by creating a label
stack and putting on top of that packet
and that label stack pretty much
describes the sequence of links in the
network of how that package should be
forwarded so that's pretty clear pretty
sort of conceptually nice
spring defines two major types of
segments or labels the first one is this
adjacency level and it's it's again
pretty simple concept every every router
assigns a label to each of its
adjacencies or its it its neighbors
basically and the interest the
interesting labels here I have them in
red so if a paper router say r1 wanted
to send the packet to r5 all it needs to
do is craft a header for that packet
that kind of looks like this with label
two or three on top and that label two
or three was announced by the next hop
router router to and that label meant
hey if I get a packet with that label
I'm going to forward it I'm going to pop
it first and then I'm going to forward
it to router three and then router three
is going to receive a top label of 307
and do the same thing our server is
going to do the same thing until the
packet header dwindles and the payload
of that packet ends up in router five so
we just source routed that packet couple
of observations around this the certain
goodness that comes with this kind of
source routing the packet you're
reducing the state in the network you no
longer have to have end-to-end LSPs
instead each ingress can simply describe
the path that I'm that one wants to take
and doesn't have to actually refer to an
LSP for that path then again if you are
relying on things that rely on / LSP
state and networks such as bandwidth
accounting such as traffic engineering
you may lose some functionality if you
just do that this type of forwarding
there observe the other observation I
have is that it's a trivial method of
forwarding in a way that you need to
expend quite a few labels in the packet
in order to describe the path of the
packet so that doesn't come for free
either on merchant silicon or custom
silicon you know there's some costs
associated with pushing these kinds of
deep labels tab
and the third thing is that you almost
never really care to describe the packet
with this level of specificity so enter
node segment or node Sid or node label
all the same thing pretty fundamental
and quite powerful concept in spring
which calls for each router announcing
itself let's say the loopback address
it's it's on loopback address with a
label that is globally known to
everybody in the segment routing domain
this is very cool because everybody now
should use label 107 in order to send
packets to Robert 7 it's cool because I
know what that label is and that's
useful for troubleshooting if I want to
integrate a controller or whatever now
there's the only problem with that is it
breaks interoperability and it breaks it
in at least two major ways so one of
them is that if some router from this
network was actually connected to
another you know labeled domain say RSVP
or LDP it may have already allocated
that label 107 for that protocol for
that other protocol so it may not be
able to comply with the demand here to
use label 107 to reach router 7 so that
would break the other thing is that it's
it breaks interoperability between
vendors because if this was a
multi-vendor network you would need to
get all the vendors to agree that label
107 is dedicated for this purpose well
someone some some labels managers may
have chosen to already allocate that
label to some other purpose so you can't
assume these things you know if you
wanted to achieve interoperability so
time doesn't permit me to actually go
through the workaround and the solution
for this problem I do have a backup
slide at the end of this deck that you
can kind of walk through and it
describes how spring solves this
this problem in terms of implementation
but the concept is there still that you
have a globally unique address that you
can use for your for your destinations
last thing I want to mention is the
spring has the notion of a label stack
compression and that's basically the
combined use of adjacency labels and
note labels in order to achieve
reduction in that overall size of the
label stack again we kind of established
that that was a good thing so by the top
example shows you simply using adjacency
labels and you're going to need for
labels in that stack and then if you
combine it with an old label in the
bottom example you can reduce the label
stack size by at least one late okay of
seriously last thing on segment routing
you this is just mostly for for
completeness you will probably encounter
a bunch of other segment types which
fundamentally are really similar to the
first two that I mentioned the adjacency
and node but they're used for different
use cases so there's peer not peer
Jason's you know that you also probably
discover discussion about mapping
servers which help in achieving
interoperability with ldp you'll also
probably discover discussion about Sid
tlv mapping which is helpful for
achieving interoperability with RSVP and
lastly you'll probably discover a
discussion about incorporating segment
routing into BGP which is the sort of
the de facto protocol for most large
data centers okay getting to the main
kind of the main points that I'm trying
to make here first the the main the two
main insights that come out of this
whole spring discussion that I wanted to
bring out where
where this there's certain goodness in
having predictable label values
especially for your destinations well
that's what the destination IP does is
how the predictable label value except
if we're tunneling the packet there's
also value in the tunnel packet itself
having a predictable destination which
is the label value it's good for
troubleshooting it's also good if you
wanted to incorporate a controller in
your network or if you wanted to source
these packets from hosts that don't
speak network routing protocols or label
distribution protocol so for all those
reasons there's goodness in predictable
label values so we want to achieve that
even in environments that are not spring
or segment routing environments and then
the second sort of idea is the notion of
this note said there's there's certain
elegance in being able to to address a
node with one simple instruction from
the ingress all the way to the egress
and not have to care about how to route
the packet throw network the notes it
basically allows for the packet to get
to the egress over whatever ecmp path is
available to that egress so again people
have looked at can we do these things
without actually having to upgrade our
network to spring you know which is
fairly large exercise you know that a
minimum it's a software upgrade it also
involves a completely different way of
forwarding so your operational staff
needs to needs to understand that who
knows it might even include some new
bugs so this is a fairly a commonly
referenced use case for segment routing
for spring and there's a special draft
that describes it and kind of in essence
the idea is that if i wanted to exercise
every path in a network with OEM probes
I can just craft these OEM probes and
use
adjacency segments or combination of
adjacency EndNote segments to steer the
packet every which way I want seminar in
lends itself really well to that sort of
thing there are some enhancements to it
toward that you know at the bottom i
have this aggregated bundle ethernet
bundle i could assign segments to the
bundle itself but I could also assign
segments to the constituent links or the
child links in that bundle and exercise
predictably those links which is kind of
cool idea too so the segment routing
approach to this would be I craft a
packet like this and this packet says
hey Traverse that ring in a clockwise
direction and in this particular you
know stack of segments I don't care
about which link of the bundle I
exercise just go ahead and use the
vendors load balancing algorithm and and
the packet gets to them now if you do
care about the witch which link you
exercise predictably then you can make a
slight modification to that stack and
the label next-to-last here is now 4011
I think or 4031 which causes this this
packet to be steered through the you
know the top link in the bundle and
exercise that one predictably and then
lastly using that concept of stack
compression if you don't care about all
these specifics and if you want it to
just exercise a link you can say things
like hey get me to get that packet to
router for and then just exercise the
top linker than in that bundle and then
get it back to the path management
server so lots of flexibility there
turns out you can do these things in
other ways and people have done them in
other ways my first example comes from
Google who presented this a couple of
nannaogsigurd unissued pls peas and they
have injected pro packets into into
those LSPs and then they've collected
those pro packets and
analyze them and made sense of them
which links of aliens and so forth now
the only drawback with that solution is
that in doing so they've also created a
full additional RSVP mesh which creates
a lot of extra state and then their
network so other operators have picked
up that idea and kind of move move moved
it on borrowing a couple of more
concepts of segment routing except they
have done it also without Simon routing
they've done it but static LSPs the
beauty of doing it with static LSPs is
that you don't have to install any kind
of control control state and in their
little boy LSP state in their hours so
these are kind of config snippets and
examples of how this would work if you
were to craft a packet like like this
one in the bottom and inject that packet
into into r1 r1 is going to act on the
stop label of 1 million and two and that
top label based on the configuration
there says pop the pop the label and
then send that packet to the next top of
11 12 which happens to be router to
router to has a similar configuration
that would act on the next label in the
stack million and three and then it's
going to look that send that packet to
our three hour 3 is going to act on the
next level send it back to r1 and r1 is
going to look at the payload and send it
to the to the path management server so
this is kind of easily done with sort of
current means now the second example I
want to bring up as a bit of a
controversy so and it's a controversy
because I'm used I'm going to use the
words mpls in the data center okay I get
it but I'm not telling you to do mpls in
the data center unless you want to but i
am telling you that there are a couple
of good reasons for for doing so and
and some of them are discussed in this
presentation that Yandex did some time
ago but if you did want to do mpls in
the data center you're likely to want to
to create a packet or craft packets out
of your servers that kind of look like
this there's a 33 MPLS label stack with
a depth of three labels and the top
label the orange one is the one we use
to address the egress top-of-rack switch
the next green label is one that we used
that that we used to address the actual
server or port out of that top-of-rack
switch and then the third label if you
have VMs that would be the label that
would address a particular vm in that in
that server so by doing an overlay like
this you can you can actually achieve
overlays pretty cheaply you hesitant to
say that you don't need a controller but
you could actually do it without a
controller so the bottom two labels are
not really concerned for this talk of
they usually will get you know they'll
usually actually get assigned by a
controller or an Orchestrator and in the
data center but the top label is the one
we use to do forwarding on so how do we
make the left router the ingress store
switch rather how do we make that
ingress store act on that label if we
want to inject that that packet from the
server how do we make the server know
that label those are all good questions
and there they have pretty much three
conceivable answers one is this segment
routing concept of a note note SID it
lends itself quite nicely to this all
the egress store needs to do is simply
announce a note set for itself and then
everybody can use that node Sid and we
have predictable way of addressing tour
three two or three is the notes it for
two or three
okay the only problem with that is you
gotta upgrade your data center just to
spring to segment routing data type of
technology you could go the traditional
way and simply create an RSVP LSP mesh
in your data center you will achieve
reach ability you will not achieve
predictable label values because every
you know that they're going to be
dependent on what RSVP assigned for you
which brings us to the third approach
which is let's use static LSPs with some
pixie dust to to make to achieve this
label forwarding you have a very
predictable label values for the
destination so what we do also is we
enable some sort of a label protocol
within the data center but we don't do a
full mesh out of it between all of our
egress stores instead we do hop-by-hop
you know label allocations so for in
this example the egress store uses bgp
labeled unique ass to announce its
loopback address to to its upstream
switch then it uses bgp level you guys
to announce that that loopback address
to everybody else that's a neighbor of
his so eventually the ingress store gets
a label allocation for that 3333 address
which is nice but we can't know what
that label is it's not predictable it's
up to bgp label unicast to announce it
we haven't achieved our kind of main
goal here to have predictable label
allocations so the way we do that is by
by having an extra extra configuration
with a static LSP that says so this
configuration pretty much says hey if
you should get a packet with a label of
a million and three for that package to
this node 3333 that's the egress store
so for our packet there and stitch it to
whatever label path is available
to you to forward it in this case the
label Pat that's available to me came
from bgp labeled unicast and it has a
label of something there which I don't
really care about because this config
call caused the this forwarding state to
get installed in top of rac1 with this
forwarding state pretty much says
incoming label a million and three gets
swapped to label 299 something something
which came from BTW playe of all you
niggas now once i do that i have a way
of addressing this egress top-of-rack
switch by crafting a packet just like
this one the top label of the packet is
a million and three and every ingress
store in this data center can just
generate that one packet every every
server router can generate that packet I
know that label million and three will
get me to aggress tour three and I don't
have to care what the underlying label
distribution protocol assignments were
so in the eyes of a server this now
looks a lot like a note said it's
predictable and it's allowing you to
reach the egress store with whatever
path is available to you by the way
these terms spring explorations I got to
credit my friends to you or it was
somewhere in the audience there if you
guys like the term tell me if you hate
it tell him so the last thing I want to
talk about this last example is this
case for egress pure engineering that's
the last spring exploration and it's not
Aspen inspiration at all it has been
around for years years before spring was
was conceived in fact the first
reference I could find for it is from
five years ago coming out of this
form Tom and and Richard kind of
explained that sort of the initial
concepts around the sink respir
engineering which are hey let's bypass
the the forwarding decision the
forwarding decision made in our clearing
routers and the way we the reason we
want to do that is because we want to
override the BGP best path selection
with something that we think is better
so the way springwood do that and again
that's kind of described in details in
this purpose-built draft spring with a
sign well spring in this kind of
solution you have three main components
the peering router the controller and
the ingress so most of the
functionalities in the peering Robert
the peering router would use spring to
allocate segments to these piers there's
going to be individual unique segments
to each pier those things are going to
get announced to the controller the
controller is going to make its best
path selection and it's going to impose
that best path selection on the ingress
of the traffic either host or ingress
router and the end result of that whole
thing is going to be that I can create
this steering policy that in this
example allows me to split that prefix
8a / 8 for example in 22 / 16s and send
them different ways and also you know
dictate where B / 24 is going to go and
c / 20 is going to go same thing can be
done and has been done with bgp label
unicast the same concept remains just
the protocol changes bgp label unicast
along with an igp perhaps is used to
announce these unique labels pointing to
peers and the controller basically gets
the same amount of information that
allows it to impose the same type of
policy on the ingress of the traffic
except this time the policy looks a
little differently instead of a note
segment on the top you'll have an LSP
label in fact the interest in this use
case from Spring has been made has
resulted in a lot of enhancements that
we got asked as by customers mainly in
two areas you know one is to
auto-generate these bgp le routes
representing peers and the other one is
to provide protection for that traffic
that is now labeled so that we don't
have to wait for the controller to
notice any failures and and you know
react to them so this is just a config
snippet of how you do these things
Spring has sparks people of spark
people's imagination around ideas of an
old technology source routing it has
given them some insights that allowed
them to you know just take a second look
at existing problems and solve them with
some present existing solutions without
having to upgrade their network to
spring capable you know code and routers
so I kind of covered three of those
hopefully they were kind of meaningful
to you and useful and if you guys want
to talk about them I'll be happy to
discuss in the break do we have for time
for question or done with that
sick