very impressive we're we're almost there
almost in the end and i see almost no
casualties from last night we are
avengers great great determination
i found myself thinking how cool it is
to have a cyber conference in estonia it
is the final minutes of the conference
and we still are having a former
president in the audience uh this this
is uh
very very good for this conference and
it made me think i need to tell a bit of
script and talk about the roots of
estonian digital story all the estonians
know it we know the tiger leap
perhaps the
visitors don't know it
now in the early 90s estonia had just
broken free from soviet union
economy was devastated from 50 years of
occupation
um
everybody was screaming at the
government we need for funding you know
for retirees pensions for child support
everybody wanted something everybody was
discussing how can we catch up with the
rest of the world how can we catch up
and then we had a group of three
visionaries
who decided that catching up is the
wrong question to ask how can we get
ahead
and they pushed for a program
that became known as the tiger's leap
and the government
signed on to it and we financed
computerizing schools started teaching
coding in schools
probably that's why we're having this
conference
probably that's why estonia is a
digitally advanced nation
without tiger's leap
perhaps estonia right now might be known
for its
potatoes
i just make it up so
tilda thanks so much for the service for
our nation and for your continued
support to our center thanks so much
[Applause]
now sometimes the final speaker is
expected to sum up the conference uh
entire conference uh impossible here at
cycon
four days of workshops keynotes uh
panels
on cyber technology
strategy
law
that's why we give it a book so you have
the book in your bag uh go go read it uh
impressive i'm gonna be reflecting uh
for a couple of weeks of the impact of
what was said here
there are so many people i need to thank
for this event uh amazing it's it was so
great to have a live conference again
after three years break uh some of our
organizing team actually more than half
of our organizing team had not seen a
live cycon so we were slightly nervous
is it gonna flow can we can we create
the cycon vibe again but no the second
vibe is carried by you the audience so
i'm gonna thank you first uh thank you
without you cycon would be just another
cyber conference
thank you
[Applause]
our keynotes and panelists absolute
world class
as you know cycomp panelists must submit
the scholarly paper chosen in our double
blind review
bruce has written 14 books so
no no fluffy cybertainers on this stage
except for me
audiovisual audiovisual production our
trusted rgb thank you so much
great work uh
our dozen of volunteers uh the people in
white shirts yellow yellow bands you've
seen them they've been helping you to
check in
answer all your questions our small
staff couldn't do all this without
without the help of volunteers thank you
[Applause]
i hope tanya has a chance to be here
she's not busy
this year's program director uh tanya
yanchakova there she is
[Applause]
god
what what a job thank you so much
it's been very stressful for you i
apologize for that you've done excellent
job
hotel we've had a long relationship with
swiss hotel
great great venue thank you now
as a tradition we now announce the next
year's cycom theme uh we had a
debate uh in the center we we came up
with a unanimous winner um
soon the call for papers will will
follow so get your pencils ready get
ready for next year's cycle and the
theme for cyclone 2023 is
meeting reality
we i i yeah uh i it scares me a bit too
just like you know last year uh
keep moving we
we had we had no idea how the world will
change the paradigm shift uh
i'm hoping that next year's reality will
be that
ukraine is
in
their restored 1994 law for borders the
war is over and we're analyzing the
aftermath of the war where cyber played
a big part
a mobik
so let's let's
yeah all hope and help ukraine to
achieve that
and now the very last thing uh
it has been an absolute honor to
be the director of ccdcoe uh for the
last four years time has flown by uh
suddenly i'm the oldest serving director
in 14 years of history of ccdcoe it's
time to pass the torch
you met dr mark norma
on the first day on wednesday
so uh he had to depart
at noon today
at least that's what he's told unless
marty's here
no he's not here so yeah he has he has
gone he's the citizen of tartu
university town so he had the important
engagements there but uh
there he is as a reminder
so uh next year uh mart
with the same awesome team that i've had
privilege to work with uh we'll deliver
you cycon
our official endor ceremony will be
first of august
so uh as a first of august mark will be
the director of ccdc
without further ado this is it enjoy the
lunch have a safe trip back home cycon
2022 is over
[Applause]