thank you henrik thank you lisa uh
mr president mr assistant secretary
general general naxona uh journals
admirals excellencies uh dear faithful
fans of saigon
uh it is an honor and privilege to
welcome you to the 14th annual cycon
conference here in thailand
the last time we met here physically was
three long years ago in 2019
and while we made the most out of the
pandemic era online events
i trust that most of you came to a quick
realization last night that the
icebreaker event that
the cycon vibe does not travel the
internet
we after all we are human beings
we like to be close to other human
beings
yes even the nordic introvert types like
myself
so we're we're thrilled we're thrilled
to be back live
we're tremendously glad that you the
faithful cycon all crowd psychon
audience is back with us we are sold out
again
there are enough cyber conferences
globally that one could leave home after
new year's and first of january travel
from conference to conference and come
back home from christmas
uh we the nato cooperative cyber defence
center of excellence we are very much
aware of the level of competition out
there so we truly appreciate that you
have trusted with us the most important
resource that you have
your time
you come from 50 countries and four
continents amazing
this year's cyclone program committee
was led by tatyana yanchakova
so everything that you enjoy at this
year's cycon
is thanks to tanya and her team
and everything you dislike is my fault
please address it to me
we tremendously appreciate the
commitment of our world-class speakers
we do not have a budget to pay speaker
fees so all the outstanding experts that
you will see as our keynotes and
panelists
they do it for economy class tickets to
telling and your applause
so while we are being cheap please you
the audience don't
to prove that we're not completely
stingy
i would like to now reveal this year's
speaker gift
as a tradition it is an estonian
handcrafted item
and it this time it is a wooden case for
your
eyeglasses
most cyber people are equipped with them
and those that are not i'm sure you own
at least one pair of sunglasses for the
both of those sunny days that we have in
estonia each year
we could not deliver you cycon without
the help and partnership of our
sponsors
being a governmental non-commercial
organization our budget is multiple
times lower than you would guess trust
me i know
this year our diamond level sponsors are
fortinet meta and microsoft
thank you for your partnership and
support
our sponsors have the option of fielding
a booth
in the coffee break area so please do
visit and thank them and learn thing or
two about their vision
our conference agenda as always is
packed with high-level insightful
keynotes and expert panels divided into
three areas
technology policy and law
the beauty of cyclone crowd you
is your diverse background and interest
i know that you have already picked out
your must-go sessions but please allow
me to
pick a few to highlight them i will
start from the last day counting back
towards today's special events on friday
right before the closing remarks
we have a keynote session on this stage
by bruce schneier from the harvard
kennedy school
bruce is a multiple time psychon
guest he's mostly known for his thoughts
and works on cryptography
and this time he will talk on the
looming topic the coming ai hackers
tomorrow on thursday
we will have a very special panel 11
o'clock main stage here
one year ago when we picked the theme
keep moving for this year's conference
we really could not have possibly known
how different the world would be
we first saw the world changing in the
post-pandemic world uh so we we thought
you know you better keep moving in a
changing world
but we did not foresee the cataclysmic
paradigm shift in the global security
environment brought by
russia acting on this 21st century
just like the soviet union did back in
1939 launching a brutal war of expansion
against the european neighbor
so when i visited kiev in january this
year i asked the military members who i
met there on their opinion of the
threat of war
and i was overwhelmed by the bravery in
their response they they said that
we the ukrainian soldiers we have been
fighting a war against russia for the
last eight years with one hand tied
behind our backs if you now get to have
a fair fight bring it on
if we
and and as we know
ukraine's heroic defense of their
country has been anything short of
amazing both in physical space and in
cyberspace
they are moving
and we're proud to host a panel on the
cyber dimension of the war in ukraine
where three panelists are with the
frontline experience in the ongoing
cyber war
and also as you are well aware our
center steering committee unanimously
approved
the accession of ukraine so in other
words ukraine is on the path becoming
the
fully committed contributing partnership
partner nation in the nato's dco is soon
and we're honored to have
uh ukrainian deputy minister of defense
mr alejayduk in the audience thank you
sir for being with us
now coming to today
before introducing the
three important keynotes right after me
there is a slight schedule change um uh
jona rutkowska could not make it to the
health reasons
and with less than 48 hour notice our
future director dr mark norma yes on the
first of august i will hand over the
command but so our future director dr
mark norma is stepping in on a short
notice to the second stage
he has a very exciting background in
space and
physics he's a professor in a tart
university long-time professor for the
last five years he's been uh working
with the development uh in an exciting
estonian startup on
autonomous ground vehicles so we'll tell
about cyber security of the autonomous
ground vehicles so all you need to do to
meet the next director of ccdcoe is to
come back after coffee break
now
today's special events today i will have
the opportunity to introduce you have
the opportunity to listen to the three
very special keynotes
first one of them
in estonia we have a non-written
tradition that the president does not
come from the ranks of career
politicians
thus we have once again privileged to be
a to
we we are once again privileged to have
a president who is technology savvy and
enjoy sharing his thoughts with an
educated audience like yourselves
uh mr allarkaris has been the president
of estonia since october last year he
has a very accomplished background in
science with his latest research
research in the fields of molecular
genetics and developmental biology
he's a long time professor and from 2007
2012 served as director of university of
tartu mr president saikon is yours