welcome and thank you for being here i'm
gabor vishki technology technology
researcher at nato cooperative cyber
defense center of excellence with a
focus on the cyber security of
ships modern ships i'm a phd student at
tall tech regarding cycon i'm the
co-chair of the conference and the
manager of technology track
today i'm going to moderate this panel
in which with or distinguished speakers
we will focus on cyber security in
maritime
noida is the importance of the shipping
industry for modern society is
constantly growing
more than 90 percent of the goods across
the world are being transported by the
sea
the need
to reduce the operational costs and the
delivery times has led the industry to
seeking technological technological
solutions
along with the growing reliance on
automation
the risk of external interference and
disruption of key systems is greatly
increased
malicious actors can interfere interfere
with different control systems of the
ship
and can cut off external communication
or obtain confidential data
western cyber security is recently
gaining momentum
as a result of fair of few
recent attacks
to western sc but i'm sure there is a
lot more to know
in our panel today or first speaker
professor katsikas
will introduce the actual situation and
the cyber challenges in the maritime
sector
then we will dig deeper
dr michael thomas will share
his uh results in his research and
discuss the land-based attack scenarios
and possible consequences against ships
finally
retired colonel uh isidoros monoedes
will offer us possible mitigation for
cyber threats in a maritime sector
unfortunately enough he was not able to
join us in person he will be
here remotely
dear audience i would like you to
address your questions in between the
presentations and at the end of them
now it's my great pleasure to introduce
our first speaker professor sokratis
katsikas who is the director of the
norwegian center for cyber security in
critical sectors
and professor at the department of
information security and communication
technology at anti-annual norwegian
university of science and technology
he has authored or co-authored more than
300 journal papers book chapters
conference papers
he is serving on the editorial board of
several scientific journals has
contributed 46 books and chaired the
technical program committee of more than
800 international scientific conferences
he chairs and steering com
the cheating steering committee of
srx conferences
and he is the editor in chief
of the international journal of
information security
professor the floor is yours
thank you very much gilbert
good afternoon ladies and gentlemen
thank you very much gabor for both the
invitation and the the warm uh
introduction
okay so
shall we
start the the slides
okay good
so uh
that's just the the first one and
it's supposed to serve as an
introduction to the discussion that we
will have uh uh later with uh with
michael and uh isidoros hopefully so
just to start with a few words about the
norwegian center for cyber security and
critical sectors which i'm the director
of
it's a
research-based innovation center
which is actually a public-private
partnership between
research
institutions and universities in norway
and several industries in different
sectors critical sectors all of them
actually are critical infrastructures
even though we call them we call them
critical sectors
and the the idea
uh behind its development is that we
create a bridge between our research
groups in cyber security that exists in
ntnu and in our research partners and
what i call the the real world
of industry on the other side of course
to non-norwegians these
logos may not mean much
but those that can identify
loggers will see that these are partners
from the process industry the defense
industry the
power industry the oil and gas industry
healthcare and the police and so on as
well as the security industry and then
there are a number of international
collaborators around the world
from
asia europe uh and north america
collaborating with us we started about
almost two years ago
and the lifetime of the center is
supposed to be
eight years after that it's supposed to
be self-sustainable
so
one of the the sectors that we do
research in and remember it's a
research-based innovation center so it's
applied research
uh is of course the the time maritime
sector even though this is not
represented among our industry partners
so
there is a lot of
research going on and
you might wonder why all this fuss about
cyber security in the in the maritime
sector uh lately well
unfortunately we may like it or not but
usually it's money behind everything i
hate to say that but as an academic but
unfortunately this is this is the way it
usually is
so uh just as an example gabriel already
gave you an indication that 90 of the
goods worldwide are transported by ship
right i hope that i was true yeah yeah
absolutely yeah and of course this gives
you an indication of the magnitude the
economic magnitude of the industry so
this is just you know a small portion of
that
in in europe and i would just draw your
attention to the fact that the overall
contribution of the shipping industry
not the maritime the the shipping alone
uh to the european gdp is
149 i think a billion
euros
i if i'm not mistaken the european gdp
is something around 17
trillion
so you can do the math and say that this
is a substantial percentage actually of
the overall european gdp
so this is one of the reasons why
interest in the cyber security of the
the shipping industry has grown
lately and by lately
i mean
almost 10 years really
the one of the first reports if not the
first report that i came across
regarding the security of the
maritime sector came from media those of
you not familiar with anisa it's the
european network and information
security agency that's the european uh
european union
agency
mandated with supporting cybersecurity
activities in
member states so they came up with this
report back in november 2011
and the
summary or the conclusions of the report
was that the the maritime sector
at least time
had these challenges with regards to
cyber security of course
so low awareness and focus on
the on the field on the cyber security
the complexity
of the ict environment
fragmented maritime governance context
inadequate consideration of cyber
security in maritime regulation
no holistic approach to maritime cyber
risks and over overall lack of direct
economic incentives to implement good
cyber security in the maritime sector
question to you how many of these
challenges have we really addressed in
the past 11 years
how good do you think we are doing
are we doing
well are we doing can we do better are
we doing terribly
well no volunteers i understand this is
just after lunch so i'll give you a hint
okay
well
this is how the
the shipping industry itself perceives
how they are doing and this comes
actually you don't see the answers here
you only see the questions
i was
i missed a slight gap or when i sent you
the slides and then it was too late for
me to introduce the answers as well but
i have i have a piece of paper so i'll
tell you the answers so this was a
survey done by lloyd's list
on how the shipping industry themselves
perceive how they're doing cyber
security so
do we have more attacks
the answer is yes we do have more
attacks we know that right but what is
the severity of attacks
mind you the perceived severity of
attacks well
only 10 percent are perceived to be
severe
are supposed to be significant
52 percent supposed to be or perceived
to be minor and and this is the most
alarming to me
seven percent responded unsure
not certain
do you agree that this is the most
alarming fact because if you know that
you have sustained an attack
and you're not able to assess the impact
that the attack had
alias its severity that's too bad really
because it seems it means that you don't
really know how good you're doing with
cyber security or not right
okay
are we doing enough
well
57 of them say that they could do better
we could do better
and only 26 percent are satisfied
i don't know the correlation between
this 26 percent and the 7
that we're unsure about the severity of
attacks but it would it would have been
interesting to know
coming to training because of course it
is a well-known fact that
one of the crucial factors in improving
the cybersecurity statute of any
organization
regardless of the
of the sector is to improve the training
right well 54
of the shipping
of the ship owners responded that they
do provide cyber security training which
is not bad
but it can be it can be better
and then the question whether there are
measures in place in the event of an
attack
63 said yes
of course the question was not specific
enough because yes of course the
shipping industry has measures in case
of an incident
but do they have measures
against cyber attacks in particular
michael i think this is something you
will pick up
perhaps
and then no measures at all 16
and again
unsure
so they don't know
do we have measures
sorry don't know
and finally of course insurance
great 69 are satisfied sure
then what is the economic
incentive to do something about cyber
security if you think if you believe
that you're insured against almost
everything that's great then you don't
have to invest in cyber security right
okay
now
what's the situation uh today
uh this
in this uh two slides this one and the
next maybe three i'm not sure i'm
following a report uh that has been
issued by norma cyber
norma is the norwegian maritime cyber
resilience center it is a center which
has been established by ownership of
many major shipping companies in norway
and their issuing annual report so the
annual threat assessment for 2022 will
give us a good
a good picture of the landscape as it
stands today
and among the the threat actors that we
identify and this does not only apply to
norway that's why i'm just using this as
a guide right
uh of course nation states
we have
cyber criminals
and we have activists as well in fact
i don't think that we have any recorded
incident of hacktivism in the maritime
sector but everyone agrees that it's a
question of time rather than if
something like that will will happen
eventually but of course these days what
is on on stage are nation states
and
cyber criminals
with
the the goal of monetization of an
attack
and what kind of threats
are identified as relevant
again i followed the structure of the of
the threat report and that means that
i've followed also the order in which
the threats appear this is not
any hierarchical order here meaning that
the first one is more important than the
the last one
but it somehow reflects
the uh perception of the importance of
such attacks and it was quite a surprise
to me that the first one on top uh was
the espionage
threat
yeah i mean it was a surprise because i
had never thought
of espionage in the in the maritime
sector
as one
really very
strong threat
but it appears to be that we do have
evidence that there have been incidents
like that
more uh
possibly well known among them an
incident with a soviet ship
a research ship
i think the name was academic lazariff
that was caught following the
pipelines the oil pipelines between
norway and the uk
because i mean the ais truck of the of
the ship was uh analyzed and it was
found that it was following the the
pipelines and of course anyone can think
why this this was happening obviously it
was not part of an exercise to see
whether they can navigate
well enough to be able to follow the
pipelines
then we have of course the supply chain
attacks the usual ones not anything
specific to the maritime sector but
there have been incidents because of the
supply to the well-known supply chain
attacks in the maritime sector
exploitation of well-known
vulnerabilities as well
then malware delivery is is common as
the first step in the
cyber kill chain of any of any
attack and unfortunately because of the
poor training
not only of of cruz but also of the
staff in the
land basis of the maritime sector is is
quite poor in terms of cyber security uh
this
method of malware delivery
by
uh social engineering techniques seems
to be quite quite successful
then of course credential harvesting
after the the malware delivery is is
happening and therefore that means that
attackers have the uh the opportunity to
get into the into the uh the systems of
the of the attacked
whether
it's known or not there have been
incidents even though we have not been
able to attribute them
uh of fishing through in massachusetts
communications and in fact
this was actually related to credential
harvesting so there have been attacks
phishing attacks uh someone or some
someone's are trying to
map
crew credentials and ship credentials
through
the communications through in
massachusetts
particularly through the the pandemic
when of course this communication was
was more useful for
delivering news and so on and in fact
the cyber security of the satellite
infrastructure is something that we have
not paid enough attention to i think but
it's coming up as one of the issues that
need to be looked upon not necessarily
in the maritime sector itself but in a
more generic context and then of course
we have fraud mostly through
business
business emails
fake emails
and financial fraud and then of course
the well-known ransomware
cases now
i'm usually very bad at keeping time so
please shout gabor
i will help you there's the time good
but i think this is my last one so i'm
not so bad not so terrible eventually
so
um
if i go back to the first slide then i
mean to the slide with the challenges
identified by iniza 11 years ago i would
say yeah okay there is some progress but
there is still way to go before we can
say that we've met those challenges but
unfortunately or fortunately for us
security experts there are more
challenges coming up
and some of them
first of all they derive because of more
digitalization right nowadays we're
speaking of shipping 4.0
the equivalent of industry 4.0
initiative in in the shipping area right
and
one important aspect of this process is
the integration of it and ot
not the convergence as many people say
because convergence has happened at
least 15 years ago when ot started using
i.t but now
we have an integration of that and the
situation with this is very similar to
what had happened more than 20 years ago
when information technologies and
communication technologies were
integrated and we were forced to change
the paradigm that we were using for
cyber security
moving from closed systems that we had
to protect against the bad guys
to open systems that would be accessible
to everyone and then we had to change
our mindset into transformation to trust
rather than
lists of people that could access the
closed systems so something like that is
happening again
but i think it's even more difficult
because
information
technology people
were always aware of communication
technology and vice versa but
unfortunately
those that are
very good in i.t and iit security are
usually
quite unknowledgeable about ot and again
vice versa we simply don't speak the
same languages there are very few
that can understand both worlds this is
a very major challenge
another one is of course autonomous
vessels
we are already seeing several of those
in several applications and they do
carry their own
cybersecurity challenges far more
enhanced and advanced than those of
conventional vessels and of course
another variation of autonomous vessels
as the remotely operated vessels and
again this is an area where we need to
do uh to do more
the final one i've just used one word
underwater
there is so much going on underwater now
and there is so little that we are doing
to secure what we call the internet of
underwater things that this is a vast
area that
we need to pay attention to and this is
really very very
challenging area of research
for us there is a lot to do and
hopefully we will be able to do that
before any major incident happens i'm
not only saying that underwater but the
maritime sector
in general
i'm usually optimistic so i'm not saying
that an incident will happen
but it may
so thank you very much
[Applause]
thank you very much professor for your
very nice presentation i we agreed
before the panel we will not dance
around but still we can't change any
time well
we are ready for your questions
if you do have any
yes please gentlemen
john
sir
please erwin
i have a question
uh nuclear
airport carrier um schooling people from
on the sea
fishing ship uh container ship that has
fielded here
from
yeah yeah
you're right of course uh i should have
mentioned that this uh well being a list
a survey by lloyd's list it is about of
course
uh merchant money time sector so
no
warshipping involved and i'm sure that
the perception is is very much uh very
much different between the civilian and
the military
sector uh sector there i wouldn't have
any any data any hard data on the the
military
sector but of course
i would definitely expect it to be much
much higher
than what it is in the civilian
sector yep
thank you
okay then i will address a question that
i'm
really curious about so we are at
advancing with the autonomy so the
weakest point the people is out of the
out of the loop more or less but the
automation is heavily growing more and
more itn auto systems are installed on
the autonomous ships
how do you how do you predict the
shifting of the uh cyber issues
do you think that uh we will have more
and more uh
incidents in the
in the area of autonomous shipping or
where we have less because the
autonomous ships are designed by
being secured
uh yeah that's a that's a very good
question actually gabor thanks
and maybe we should we should discuss
this not
uh in the narrow context of the maritime
sector but i think that whatever i will
say as an answer will apply to more
general industry but let's keep it to
the maritime sector right
to answer this concretely
i would say that what we need to know is
what percentage of the incidents
are due
to human error
right
and of course the uh the reasoning that
if we exclude
if the percentage of incidents that are
due to human error is quite high and
then if we do exclude the human factor
from the loop
then that would automatically mean that
we should expect less incidents but is
this reasoning really correct
what i would think
and again no hard data right this is
just a
an intuition um
yes these kinds of incidents would be
reduced
but then there is an additional question
that needs to be asked would there be
any additional incidents that would not
have occurred if we had a human in the
loop
and would occur because we don't have a
human in the loop
let me give you a very naive example
right
imagine one of the well-known
cyber security attacks against
navigation
actually the two most known attacks are
gnss spoofing jamming right
and
ais
tampering with
data and in fact you did showcase
an attack with ais in the workshop on on
tuesday right so
let's take the scenario that you have an
autonomous ferry
no human involved right and suddenly
someone launches an attack
with a few hundred fake
ais trails in the trondheim fjord
right
great scenario what would the system do
with today's technology right or if
the ais was proved so that it showed
the location of the vessel on the shore
rather than in the sea right with
today's technology
not much of course we are working
towards that right so that we can use ai
techniques and so on to
recognize that something is wrong but we
couldn't be able to do much it's the
human operator
on board the ship that knows that this
cannot be correct right
so
to recap
i think we would be having less
incidents that are due to the human
factor naturally but we would be having
different incidents that we don't have
today now
quantitatively whether the latter would
be more or more severe than the the
former i can't know but
i don't think that this is something
that should stop us or
slower the pace of automation because
there are so many advantages
thank you
well i've been considering that going to
to an autonomous ship with my with my uh
motorboat and with fake ais messages uh
stealing it
but uh this attack would be
from this c
but uh our next speaker
dr michael thomas
brought scenarios the in which the
attacks are
addressed from the land
so
let's uh thank you very much professor
for the problems
and let's dig deeper
our next speaker is dr michael thomas
who is a retired colonel
and currently assigned to maxwell air
force base alabama as a professor of
cyber cyber air force studies previously
he was served at naval
information warfare center
as an ice
c4 isr system engineer in communication
and network division and was responsible
for design implementation and
fielding of major systems engineering
project for us navy
he served in several offices like at the
pentagon at the joint special operations
command and at the air force institution
of technology
mike the floor is yours please
introduce your results thank you goodbye
you for the nice introduction and
thank you for attending
the
topic is going to float between
both the military and the civilian
sector
because a lot of them have things in
common just as there are things in
common between
platform technology and the air force
and platform technology in the navy
the current navy ship building has had
some issues
ship classes have been cut
vessels retired early
many are waiting years for
repairs
the lcs the littoral combat ship
has been an example of the adoption of
tech and tech failing
the zumwalt class stealth destroyer is
being cut back
from plan 32
to only three
and the implementation of a rail gun on
board has been abandoned
ford class carriers have got
all sorts of issues with catapults
radars elevators
cost overruns
shipbuilding capacity has been minimized
there is
a quality to quantity and right now the
people's republic of china is out
building us and us i say the u.s
historically a nation's rise and decline
has been directly linked to the power of
its navy
the current world order
was established at the end of world war
ii
with the united states guaranteeing the
freedom of the seas
and encouraging
britain the france
not to rebuild their navies and begin
another arms race in the maritime sector
that we would guarantee
freedom of the seas for them and they
could do their
uh
world trade under our banner
the um
the issue of the size of the navy has
has been discussed in the past at the
end of world war ii we had six thousand
ships in the navy
reagan bankrupted
uh or convinced the soviet union that
they could never outspend just by only
wanting 600 ships in the navy
right now we've got about 350 ships and
the proposal has been
uh to increase that to 450 ships
what kind of platforms are we talking
about stated earlier 90 percent of the
world's traffic in commercial traffic is
done at sea
90 to 95 depending on the statistic
of the internet
international internet is under the sea
so the sea is very important to the
current information environment
there's a major study in
19 in 2019
that talked
about almost 60 open source incidents
involving only the components of the
integrated bridge system that ip based
network on the bridge that has
both data and connectivity
to the outside world
uh examples of this
uh has been by either disabling and
spoofing ais
by russia iran and north korea
due to masking movements
there was an article in the in the news
feeds this morning about the shipping of
oil and the russians using the same
techniques as the north koreans to turn
their
ais and gps off
running dark to trans transport
ship oil
sanctioned oil from a russian vessel to
a non-russian vessel
even for sale in the u.s
nga has provided
maritime charts to the u.s navy and to
the commercial sector but not all the
charts are of the same quality
and in fact the electronic charting
system on board
using bad
uh data
has shown some vulnerabilities
both to html html injects
our
outmoded
operating systems on board
jamming gps is not difficult to do
and in fact the
uh power of a gps signal is said to be
about that of a 25 watt bulb
the
sensitivity of the receiver is what's
important uh
data indexed at gps
using poorly secured satcom terminals on
board
that might be linked to
uh the gps enabled
autopilot onboard the ship
has created problems
the uss guardian
in naval history had inaccurate
uh nga data loaded on their electronic
charts and caused it to run aground
uh the uss john mccain
faulty nav
poor sailoring poor manning and poor
equipment implementation as well finally
the uss donald cook
had their gps jammed by a russian
aircraft
so it happens
let's take a look real quick
yeah we'll watch the first minute and a
half of this do i have sound on this
no
there there is a
an audio track to this as well
maybe you need to be out of presentation
mode for it to play
no it'll it'll
it'll play in the presentation mode okay
there's a there's a uh
if you go down to the bottom of the
screen there's a toolbar on the far left
and it should appear
all right go go out of presentation mode
for a second
do we have
audio
i think we do have but
i
think we have to check the details
no there's a there's an audio there's a
video embedded in the slide
and if you click on the body of the
slide it'll begin playing
it's only
you see it's a picture
and we have to deal with huge shifts so
okay sorry that's a challenge i expected
the audience to anyway the the audio is
a story that was on cnbc go back to the
presentation end of that slide and i'll
continue
that showed the
nsa was training college students to
um
[Music]
hack
integrated bridge system technology and
one of the young students reflected on
uh how much damage in the economy they
could do to a country
all right what does the attack surface
in the ship look like
navigation data can be in the cloud
you've got port infrastructure
mainland computer systems at the
companies
all sorts routes procedures and
personnel
who are the bad actors
as my colleague earlier mentioned
nation states rival companies
criminals pirates
are
independent freelance hackers
and then of course insiders as well
a little bit of history
um
typically
the uh
if we look at the top the cyber
interacts industry 3.0 and industry 4.0
was when we started seeing
uh automated systems introduced first to
scada then as
it linked to scada
this is another
video
i would love to see these dots moving
but apparently they're not going to do
it each dot being a ship
and each ship
having
uh different systems on board
in different sets of systems
the bridge system being composed of
course of ais
the charting gps gyrocompass radar and
weather
tampering with any of those can have
very deleterious effects
on the outcome
the problem also happens to be when you
cross the navigation
into the marine systems or the
propulsion and steering
cyber attacks on board a vessel often
occur because those systems are no
longer segregated
companies wanting minimal manning and
wanting to check and check the
status of where ship is and how it's
performing
will often
go through the ip based network
across the bus into the control systems
to look at fuel consumption
uh performance if they're monitoring the
ballast properly and create a create an
issue
gps simulators can be uh
purchased for very little money and used
as a platform to inject an ascii
character 12 to 18
ascii characters
through the satcom
until there's a ship that would normally
be ready to turn left for example you
change the l to an r and it turns right
it's been demonstrated on a container
ship back in 1918 pentest partners
showed that access into
the steering
steering and throttle was possible
using such an approach
again the volume of global tonnage we
can believe
back in march 2021 when the ever given
was jammed inside the suez canal the
disruption on global trade that was felt
and for a short time
the impact
was known and was being paid attention
to
um
there was another
attack on a merchant vessel in june of
cyber attack they're not sure if it was
targeted by hackers or if one of the
crew
entertainment uh
i.t based products had malware injected
uh accidentally or intentionally by the
crew
but it was a deep dress vessel bound for
new york and it was totally debilitated
by malware they had to fly a white team
crew out and actually
basically reboot the reboot the ship
we published data
online
depending on the size of the ship a ship
may have to ping every five four five
seconds its location and heading
and speed and that's
broadcast on an open network
for the world to see so the information
is there target selection is a
possibility
what the ever given provided was the
idea
that block ships could come back in
vogue a block ship being something that
was
uh blocking a channel
uh the russian navy did this as early as
2014 as recently as 2014
when they
sunk a derelict vessel
at the bay in crimea and basically
trapped most of the ukrainian navy
taking possession of it
um
if we look at the red circle
uh april 1 2021
uh we see what is called a navy task
force heading towards the suez canal
this is immediately after
the ever kevin has been refloated
as we start to move it by april 8th it
is through the canal
and on its mission on the way to its
mission further in the persian gulf and
then finally by the 15th it's on station
uh just outside the persian gulf
for counter piracy maneuvers
this is a view from the uss monterey
part of the eisenhower strike group
that was displayed on the charts
imagine
being stuck
in the canal with a block ship and then
being targeted
by
people with floating bombs
uh
it would totally
eliminate the success of this mission
uh that occurred in may where they
grabbed a lot of russian-made anti-tank
weapons
uh and route for somewhere
but but basically what would happen is
that you could establish three separate
kill zones
north in the great bitter lake and then
south
with traffic backed up
and in fact this is exactly what
happened to the uss coal back in 12
october a small
uh
floating
floating bomb got close enough to take
out a piece of it
the ship was able to be recovered taken
back and rebuilt and is still in service
but a determined enemy
uh using this vector of attack could
disable either
military or civilian shipping
one scenario protection of pipelines and
subsidy cables has been proposed
um
people have to know where the subsea
cables are we advertise where they are
because we don't want ships running into
them running over them fishermen
dropping their anchors on top of them
disrupts the internet
but in fact
not too long ago
there was an occurrence of
a ship
subsidy cable being cut
between the northern coast of norway
and svalbard
that disrupted internet traffic
interesting it took out one but didn't
take out the other one
another scenario
cyber attacks against shipping and
shore-based infrastructure
some of this has been occurring in the
run-up to the ukraine war where lng
tankers in the u.s were actually
targeted
and disrupted
an lng tanker again
a floating vessel with high pressure
tanks
lots of
kinetic energy potential energy stored
in that compressed gas
the concerns of
lng tanker accidents in the boston
channel has been documented over and
over again in the last 50 years
um
with the current technology if a an lng
tanker were jammed or taking control
in a populated area you could
potentially have nuclear effects without
having a weapon of mass destruction
boston channel again
shows some of the
affected areas that would be in there
cyber-enabled underwater weapons
targets abound examples are
pipelines coming from north africa
supplying
hydrocarbons to
southern europe
in real life
again
russia has been
attributed to having had something to do
with the subsidy cable
cut
and it's not just russia france has in
fact
uh created a strategy for underwater
warfare and is prepared
uh to move forward with this capability
in the coming decade
shooting and blocking dangerous
exercises again
once
a ship is under control of some
uh
negative party
how are they gonna handle it what are
they going to do with it
a control zone outside one of the
islands in open water again
uh the graphic didn't come through
either
beijing has got lots of
uh
encroachments into other areas of the
south china sea
um so some tactical advice for maritime
cyber security we'll look at tactical
operational and strategic
um
make sure your i your ais uh
is secured your satcom is secured your
ip based network uh is secured
um
crew and the wi-fi are and business
networks are logically separated there's
no need to have your crew email system
connected to the rest of the bridge
usb ports secure this is all basic stuff
check on board for the wi-fi networks
don't over rely on technology
that was part of the problem with the
mccain the bridge crew thought they were
where they weren't
and ended up running into a container
ship
teach your crew about cyber security
that's going to be a difficult one with
the number of people
on the vessels and the crew rotations
that occur
technology suppliers
have to prove to you that they are
secure uh you shouldn't have to be doing
it all by yourself
there are companies out there that will
do
a cyber security audit for you this is
something before you allow a vessel into
your waters legislation can
be introduced
so that it is safe it can it has to
prove that it's safe to be in those
waters
operational advice has been put out by
bimco
uh
you know a cyber risk management
approach
in
in a
multi-stage environment
but again
developed the philosophy for the vessel
design
designed for robustness and then of
course system resilience
operational advice again
you've got to look at the entire
package in a system of systems approach
so
the atlantic council came out with
strategic advice for the implementation
of policy legislation
large scale measures that should be
adopted globally
and more
more strategic advice eventually we're
going to a more remote control
environment for floating vessels it's
going to be a problem the navies of the
world as well as the commercial sectors
have adopted this as a means of keeping
the number of floating platforms up to
have increased capability
um
in fact the navy just introduced
a
new uh
float a new sub command
uh to be held in uh navworm
in dahlgren
that will
in fact be in charge of uh floating
floating vessels automated vessels uh
one test result a year ago from darpa
they sailed a 50-foot vessel from san
diego to honolulu in back with no one on
board
so
the technology both in warships and in
commercial shipping is
on the on the rise
so
dunn and kruger always like it we
started at the peak amount stupid
halfway through maybe we started having
some hope
all the way through the slides
we've become a little bit more
enlightened
but sometime in the future driven by
mission requirements we're going to have
to have some way
and definition of what a sustainment for
these new automated
platforms are going to be
and if no one has got questions
that's the end of my material
thank you very much uh for your
excellent uh presentation and the brief
overview
i'm not scared i knew about it but uh i
think that uh our audience might wish to
address some questions please
in the back
i thought i saw a hand up
okay
uh
two questions pop up in my mind
how do you estimate uh
how
confident the sector is and how clever
the sector is right now
on the
tunneling club graph
in which stage we are
oh um
we're in the nation's stages
of implementation and security
uh it's largely been ignored
because most
people just want to go to the beach they
don't want to think about
the industrial controls and the ip based
controls
necessary to have safe
a safe maritime working environment um
if you think of
uh the number of incidents in private
homes and in businesses
um
there's still a market for
people wanting to create havoc so it's
an extension of that into a moving
environment at sea
regarding the please in maritime as i i
i'm observing that the current trend is
to train maritime personnel and people
working in maritime teach them cyber
security
and there still is a lack of as i have
witnessed lack of
skillful people in cyber security in the
american domain how can we or is it
possible or is it feasible to do the
other way which is teaching maritime
affairs and
concepts and the aspects of the maritime
industry
to be able in cyber security there's a
lot of people knowing it knowing ot
security but they have no idea about
maritime and what is needed to secure
martian system
would this be something
useful or how can it be
um let me let me tell a story and then
tell another story
last august at def con
they have a hack to see
competition
uh the the the goal is to win the black
coveted black badge
um
a team
with only land-based skills
uh was able to plug in and take control
of both the the
integrated bridge simulator as well as
steering
and throttle within it within a few
hours
it doesn't take a lot for clever people
to look at systems and see what they do
particularly systems that
maybe 15 20 years old weren't designed
with security in and i'm talking
that lower section of the integrated
controls that would be called scada or
ics on land
um
the second um
there's a guy named joe weissman
he's an expert
in cyber security marine maritime cyber
security uh did a talk for us on our
virtual cyber seminar series
uh and said that
the internet of things that helped run a
ship
uh the pumps
uh
the
motors and whatnot uh
are not built
with any type of cyber security built
into them at all and the people that
designed them
don't know the language of cyber
security so some of it can be very very
easy some of it can be very very
difficult
other questions
i think that you have a better overview
on the on the sector
so that's always a good excuse okay our
technology is old we cannot introduce
any cyber security measure at the same
time international magnum organization
uh made compulsory the cyber assessment
for ships uh
how do you see in your country is are
these recommendations followed or just
omitted and told that okay the
technology is old
there are some um
some good steps being taken and
recommendations being made
but even um
uh off the east coast of africa you've
got
legitimate commercial haulers turning
off their ais
so that somali pirates won't
won't be able to identify them
for target selection
uh
the russians uh turn theirs off for the
sake of sanctions avoidance the north
koreans turn theirs off and the
um
for the sake of uh
sanctions avoidance we know they're out
there
uh reports are thousand page reports are
generated every year by the united
nations uh the question becomes
what incentivizes
the rest of the industry to do something
about it
and i don't have the answer to that
you mentioned russia several times uh
how can the sector attribute the attacks
well it you know it's interesting using
uh
geoint and satellite-based technology
most
freighters of a certain length and a
certain
width
have
something the equivalent of a figure of
a fingerprint
in the way the deck is configured
antennas where the bridge is
uh
where hard structures are placed so a
ship can be identified relatively
accurately and then can be tracked from
space
so an integration of uh
uh geoint and a geo enabled tracking
uh for that
uh as well as
uh keeping track of the ship uh when it
when it meets up with another vessel
does the cross
platform transfer the sanctioned goods
and then tracking where it where it goes
either to north korea or uh even some to
the united states
i see but in the land case attacks it
would be a
more challenging task right yeah well
there's a smuggling smuggling is what
we're talking about high-tech
smuggling yeah excellent thank you very
much i hope and believe you preserved
some questions for the uh very end and
let's keep moving uh honest speaker is a
isidorius
monoyudis who is a retired coroner from
the greek armed forces with more than 20
years experience in critical
infrastructure and cyber security
before his retirement he was the head of
cyber defense operations in the greek
military of defense involved in several
projects for incident response security
assessment red teaming
cyber defense exercises and many more
after his retirement
he worked for the uk-based security
vendor as a cyber
security architect focused on the threat
intelligence and its integration with
other
security
solutions since july 2021 he works as a
project officer for european defense
agency managing research projects
for information technologies and cyber
defense
easy dorius welcome you you are online
we can see you i hope and believe that
we can hear you please introduce your
opinion
how to solve the problem that was uh
figured out right now
uh thank you very much for the
invitation first of all apologies for
not being there physically
before moving on please confirm that you
can hear me well
yes yes yes perfect okay perfect
so um again thank you for the invitation
uh it's
a really very er it's an honor to
participate in the conference
several years ago i was attending uh as
a participant
even from the first desi icon back in
february 10 or 12 years ago and
anyway before moving on please allow me
to share my screen first
first of all to do this myself i was at
the you mentioned i'm retired journal
and
currently
involved in the european defense agency
managing research and technology
innovation projects in cyber and
information technology
before that
i had the opportunity to work also in
the private sector that gave me also the
opportunity to get involved in projects
related to maritime cyber security
with
the experience that i can share with you
in my presentation that will try to
address to identify what we can do what
are the medication
measures
for addressing the challenges that have
been identified so far
so let me share
my presentation let's hope technology
will help us
okay can you please confirm that you can
see my slide in full
yes please please
okay we can see your slide
perfect
so mitigating the cyber threat in
maritime sector what are the key
principles
for
cyber security for medication threats
initially just to say that i will not
try to use any
known already worked and applied in the
land of the traditional let's say cyber
security area so what we need actually
in the maritime sector is to tailor to
customize technology and processes to be
applicable in the specific environment
of maritime sector
so what are the key principles is to
identify the threat which is something
that my colleagues already the previous
speakers have already addressed that it
was part of
the panel
risk management detect and protect
respondent recover secure architecture
user awareness and training and security
compliance
let's move on one by one so by risk
management which is actually includes uh
the identification of threads uh
we can see that
those are the four key
elements that
consist the risk management first of all
and especially for maritime we need an
asset inventory and a sufficient ascent
management
system
why because uh one of the biggest
problems in maritime sector in the
recipient industry is to know
our to know their assets
many times
failures or incidents come from
devices that are
forgotten the thermistor not something
new to the cyber security domain as we
all know but in the shipping industry
combined the land the shore the port and
the
vessels technology
there are assets that are forgotten also
more
specifically and more importantly in the
ot
area operational technology assets also
need to be
monitored and managed continuously
because of their sensitivity and their
impact in case of any security incident
gap analysis we need to identify the
technology and administrative gaps
every shipping
industry in the maritime sector need to
know what are the gaps they need to know
where the threat comes from either for
their offices or
from the ship and the vessels
themselves
then we need to assess there is to
identify the risk and accessories many
times
we can see that there is a poor risk
assessment in
the maritime sector
i have seen risk assessment that just
consists of a five to six
major global let's say transparent
risks that do not actually apply to the
specific environment so a risk
identification is something that
requires a lot of effort and
focus for each shipping
industry
it's time risk treatment not only
identify the risks but also to define
security controls that will mitigate its
identified risk
again as i told you just something new
but what i have seen
from my previous experience in the
private sector it is something that does
not
performed well it does not perform
sufficiently meaning that at the end
shipping owners and management
at the management level do not know why
they need to invest on cyber security
technology and people
detect and protect again we are
following the guidelines from mist okay
the overall principles in cyber security
in order to
be able to protect our systems we need
to detect the threat
some key points for detect and
protection are the following endpoint
detection technology currently
we can see that technology offers
advanced endpoint detection response
solutions
agent-based technology that can be
installed and applied to every iit
system both
offshore and on-board
that can give a sufficient protection
and
explain in terms of detection and
response to the i.t systems
and also to some of the ot
that means that
in maritime sector shipping industry can
rely on that advanced technology because
it offers advanced automation and much
more much more sufficient protection for
from cyber threats vulnerability
management again some a critical
issue
that requires continuous assessment and
medication prioritization including
operational technology
i have
the opportunity to see some
new
technology solutions in terms of
in the context of vulnerability
management and vulnerability assessment
solutions and software that include
operational technology assets and that
and which also
based on some specific recommended
architecture can also work on board
for vessels that even
during
shipping during sailing can provide
sufficient vulnerability detection
management they use cloud technology and
they have the also the capacity and the
technology to er to work in the isolated
in an isolated environment like a vessel
either way we all understand how
important it is to detect
vulnerabilities early enough to mitigate
the potential threats the real time is
just an awareness again something really
critical that involves collection
process and analysis of digital asset
security information what's security
information we are talking about logs we
are talking about everything that could
provide the cyber hygiene of every
digital asset especially on board and
this is something critical because
management usually takes place from the
headquarter so the id and security team
need to know for every visa
the security
status
but
in real time
of course it's not easy however now
technology and current internet bad
reference solutions offer that kind of
solution that kind of capacity to
collect
send data
to
a management central management console
that could efficiently
process and analyze the data providing
to
the security team
the right picture threat intelligence
this is something
really important in global
because that will drive uh how we can
detect and respond to cyber attacks uh
maritime and based on the what we have
seen lately we can see that there is an
increased number of cyber efforts in
cyber attacks successful cyber attacks
so we need to communicate how these have
been
successfully performed what are the
medication measures and what we can do
to share information
for successfully mitigating the threats
path management really important and
really difficult prioritization and
patching the vulnerable systems it is
not really straightforward even in the
traditional i.t
area
we can understand that there are a lot
of old systems in the
shipping sector in the maritime sector
that makes any patching process really
hard and really difficult especially for
systems that are on business that are on
board and we cannot properly test them
and to make the right process so it is
something that is really a headache in
the maritime sector but still needs to
be addressed properly
respond and recover
something really important in
the
domain this in the security domain that
involves a incident management plan and
this response capabilities and here it
is where
cpic industry in maritime state needs to
identify how they can
deliver
those capabilities
most likely and
it is something well realized it's not a
capacity that can be developed in-house
uh
maritime center and many and more and
more shipping companies in our days uh
put that in an outsourced approach
mainly using a security operation center
as a service that includes incident
response capabilities and capacity of
course and the previous uh approach and
the previous principle the detecting and
respond and detected
and responded also involves
the engagement of a security operation
center mainly outsourced either way what
we need to communicate what you need to
understand is that it is a priority it
is important to have a 24 7 coverage
that will provide to the cipic industry
the right
capacity and capabilities to respond to
cyber attacks because
it's not a
protection and proactive productive
measures will not sufficiently
prevent
cyber attacks from being happen
disaster recovery and business
continuity plans are
plans that have their own maturity level
in the maritime sector in terms of
physical security
we know that there are plans that
provide the right measures
even against piracy and so on
so we need also to tailor those backup
plans
to
perform a
proper backup and restore the systems
and to make sure that shipping
operations can be restored
when they are impacted when they have an
impact by a cyber attack
we need to know how the it and ot work
properly and how they can be restored
because the major concern in the
maritime industry in maritime sector is
the impact in the ot assets
since
any disruption there could mean
quite significant damage
other aspects in terms of mitigation the
cyber threats
are the following that include secured
architecture
with the key
principle the network segmentation we
have seen in the past
that there are systems
especially on board on bezels where i t
and ot systems are not separated not
physically separated meaning that they
can provide a vulnerable path for cyber
attacks to be
performed
so starting from that from the network
segmentation a secure architecture need
to be applied involving also other
subnetting principles that will make
sure that
access is being granted only to those
who have the right permissions in the
right authorization
strong identity and access management
something really important in every er
globally in the security domain
so even more in the maritime sector we
need the stroke authentication process
for every digital asset we have seen
many
incidents
especially on board from
different audits where passwords
were just on a stick
and
passwords with a common accounts with a
common password and other very poor of
education systems and that's why in a
recent guideline from
us coast guard
the first
let's say a guide instruction was to use
a password for each account i know it
sounds really trivial but
in 2021 because it was last year's
accommodation you can imagine
how
often this was identified in the real
world audits
secure configuration every system must
be configured properly to minimize the
attack surface something really common
really
not something new but again a lot of
attacks come from poor configuration
from default admin consoles from default
username and passwords that make
uh from unnecessary services that are
open to
the rest of
the network that make the attack surface
bigger and more vulnerable to cyber
attacks
user awareness and training
it has been mentioned before we need to
train the users which are the weakest
link
with multiple awareness activities i
know from
my experience with
private maritime sectors that one of the
biggest concerns is how they can train
the users that are on board on vessels
uh given uh most of the times the poor
background in handling i.t equipment
it is something that requires a lot of
effort and we need the multiple
awareness activities those just trivial
videos
and
instructions of how to use the digital
assets
we need facing pains we need many more
to train the users
to identify potential threat also what
has been also identified is not only the
size the maritime sector that is
suffering from that the entire security
community offer suffers
from the lack of cyber secure expertise
even more in maritime sector there is a
misconception that
security is part of the overall i.t
management
so it is very often uh
that we find
a security cybersecurity in maritime as
a part of it which is something actually
that used to happen
in
other
areas
as well in the past however we need also
to
explicitly address
that and
shipping companies would start involving
and hiring cyber security experts that
will
fill and address the
security gaps
last but not least is
what we call the security compliance and
regulations
uh
you referred briefly before
how imo and
regulations can help
imo has started in 2017 with the
guidelines of maritime cyber risk
management
bimcore released the guidelines on cyber
security on board ships both guidelines
and imo used and still use as a
reference the iso
27001 standard in the nist framework
and
the main
concept and the main recommendation back
then was for the shipping company the
civic industry receiving owners to
develop a cyber security plan
that actually drove to a situation that
they can share with you at least for the
last two years
that most of the times part of the audit
and part of what can be could be
considered as a successful cyber risk
management
approach was for each vessel to have a
cyber security manual
a manual that included
the guidelines that imo offered
a cyber
risk assessment the risk treatment plan
some recommendations security controls
but only them only those were on the
manual nothing was implemented in real
time and until recently those
this was a
conceived considered by the auditing
authorities as something sufficient for
a vessel to be cyber security compliance
so my point is that yes regulations need
to be there
shipping interest in maritime sector is
very sensitive to regulations this is
what has been
seen in the past for other areas however
compliance doesn't mean security we need
to be compliant with the instructions
regulations are there but we have to
realize that needs that those need to be
more than a cyber security manual need
to be implemented
and applied security controls that will
really make sense on
mitigating the cyber threats
and the impact
from
in the maritime
community
and that actually concludes my
presentation
i hope that
you helped me well despite the distance
thank you very much uh for your
excellent presentation
is doros uh i would like to ask
or
audience if there is any question
yes there is please
thank you
my name is luke helleborg and first of
all i was very astonished surprised
that
i saw the anissa study for 2011. i was
doing the study with deloitte at that
time and i'm so surprised that still
those
points are not all addressed yet so
thank you michael for bringing them up
now my question to eda is the next it's
about user awareness and training
i hear a lot we need and we should do
and sometimes in mankind we always need
a very big
catastrophe if something really needs to
start moving on on the terrain
so my question was about this
training of people
is there an existing
training maritime center already exists
ongoing or planned
where people could go on the operational
level and tactical level to really train
hands-on
how to secure
maritime cyber
in a very practical way we heard today
technology is there
processes are there we have capabilities
so my question is is it existing and if
not
if we should propose from industry
a maritime tactical training capability
yeah for europe would european defense
agencies support us thank you very much
thank you for the question
i know that uh for nato exists that
that's a maritime specific training
center and actually it is increased in
greece
but the european union as far as i know
and the focus on defense there's not
something similar to that
eda of course can support such
initiatives and
based on how we work in terms of
facilitating and enabling
research and technology innovation
activity is bringing to their networking
and the acting as an interface between
industry academia rto and ministries of
defence
it is always there's always an
opportunity and room for
further improvements and invest that so
yes it
can support that
i know that there's not any european
union defense for maritime sector a
specific training center and
you are more than welcome to provide
recommendations from the ideas on that
thank you
thank you very much
any other question
not yet
well uh
i was just considering uh
recommendations recommendations
recommendations that's nice but uh i
don't know uh if the if the industry
follows it or not most probably yes it
does
but
is there a
participant in the industry who offers
a platform or a framework
that can be used by any participant of
the industry to join the forces and
fight together against the cyberattacks
is the question for me yes
yeah
as far as i know uh
no there's not such a kind of
of a platform that can be used for
everyone of course commercial solutions
are there
we know that big
companies uh i don't want to name one or
two i don't know what to be considered
as a promoting specific private sector
but there are solutions that actually
integrate uh the
let's say traditional cybersecurity uh
solutions into a more tailored
environment that could
function and work in vessels we have
seen solutions that try to do that
however there's not something that can
be used as the golden should learn and
confirm that yes
we need to do that or we need that
platform that is applicable
and certified at some point for use in
the septic industry
for visuals and for part-time
assets
make sense
i think so
thank
you
the the question of education uh popped
up uh several times uh
professor katsika sir i think that
norway is
very advanced in the in the topic how do
you feel how could we introduce an um
education system for seafarers
uh related to the cyber
issues we i don't think that we can
teach
hundred thousands of of uh
guys
for everything
no that that would not that would not be
feasible and i don't think it is needed
anyway because this is the kind of
well let me take it from another angle
you know when you speak about human
cognition
usually we identify three uh three
levels in the knowledge continuum you
start with awareness right
of being which means being able to
answer questions like what is this about
right
then
you go on with training
and when you're trained you're able to
answer questions of the type how do you
do this
and then the third level in the
knowledge continuum is education
uh after which when you're educated
you're supposed to be able to answer
questions of the type why
now we don't need really
so many thousands or hundred thousands
of people that are
educated in maritime cybersecurity but
we do need
trained personnel and we most of all
need aware
personnel now how can this uh how can
this be done well one way is
by
inviting
the industry because this is not really
only a state responsibility to build up
training
and awareness
it's mostly training centers for their
staff in the maritime industry
uh isidoro's already mentioned one such
which i believe is of military
orientation
in crete actually
but
such initiatives would be welcomed from
industry and in fact
i do remember an initiative
back in 2017
so it was the beginning for the cyber
security
issues in maritime when such a training
center was announced as a joint
initiative between the tacos lines in
greece
and
a major norwegian
industry
actually with presence in many nations i
will not name them of course but you
might guess what it is
that they would start a training
center for cyber security but
unfortunately this didn't didn't didn't
fly but this is one way of doing it now
if you move a bit
in the knowledge continuum and you go up
to education well i guess the the way to
do it
is to introduce
cybersecurity
course or courses
to those studying marine technology or
marine operations so in the
ntnu
setting
we would have to
somehow introduce courses uh of cyber
security into our the curricula taught
in our olasund campus where the maritime
maritime industry is
that would be one way to do it and of
course to a lesser extent
in size i mean
inform the curriculum uh in my own
department which is on information
security
on
matters of cyber security in maritime
but that would have to be
on on a different scale and much less
because obviously they would have to be
exposed not only to the maritime
industry but also to transportation
industry and to
power industry and to any type of of
industry
you could imagine but i think
well i don't think i know at least in
norway
there is a great demand
for master's programs
that will
produce people that are knowledgeable in
both i.t and ot cyber security
and
yeah that's something i believe
that
us as educators will have to pay
attention to is
thank you very much mike is the
curriculum in the states for seafarers
contains some cyber related education
there
are a couple of ways to approach this
from the
from the military aspect of course
you've got the naval academy navy rotc
uh programs
officer training contained within public
universities
and the naval and the coast guard
academy
merchant marine academy as well
how we go back and
recapture
the people that already have
um
the creds that are working in the
industry to get them spun up uh that
that's a great question and i'm not i'm
not sure how we would approach that or
even how we would incentivize it
so
see thank you uh i think uh
do you have any questions for the
question
so thank you very much
for
our speakers for the contribution
i think
we see the problems we saw uh
several possible
scenarios that can happen
in the case of uh
in a case and we
saw that
there are
a way how to solve the problems
and i hope and believe that uh
we
it was not an accident that we ended up
at the education
i think
i'm sure that the weakest link always
the
personal
and we can harden this weakest link with
education for sure
i don't know you might not not might all
of you from the maritime sector and the
there was a slight sma smile
when the password management was
mentioned let me comment with this short
story i was dealing with uh with the
simulator and obviously who tortured the
estonian keyboard um on the workshop
they can feel my pain so i i mistyped
the password obviously so i contacted
the vendor
that the password doesn't what is the
password
and they wrote it is in the users manual
page 57
page 57 password is there cool
remark
please
don't change this password
because in the case of need or experts
will not be able to help you
good
so i tried to finish my job but i failed
so i sent a letter
to the vendor hey the password is wrong
okay try this one
super admin password
opens everything so i think
it was a it was a good case study to
show that uh
there is a
nice room for improvement
gentlemen thank you for your
contribution derivatives thank you for
your time uh please uh i've got uh i
reserved 51 second to hand over a teeny
tiny present for
uh
presenters thank you very much it was
excellent
thank you very much
thank you thank you gabor thank you very
much
thank you very much i hope and believe
that uh enjoyed our panel please uh
uh
join us
today to the dinner
and see you around tomorrow thank you
goodbye
[Applause]