good afternoon everyone
i am very happy to see that so many of
you have survived the morning and the
afternoon i've decided to stay on for
this uh late afternoon session with this
panel
uh
my name is ingrid winter i am the
norwegian special envoy at the center
here and i have the great pleasure of
happening through this afternoon panel
with our three distinguished speakers
first out is professor italy biki who
holds the kaiser chair of security
studies at the u.s naval academy
very nice
in addition to teaching he carries out
research in cyber war and the general
impact of information technology on
domestic and national security
his prior employment is extensive and
includes 12 years at the national
defense university three years on the
navy staff
and three years at the u.s government
accountability office
next to him is dr lonergan
she's an assistant professor at the army
cyber institute at west point
[Laughter]
[Applause]
here we have some
competitive cadets very good
um she also she's also a research
scholar at columbia university
no one from columbia okay
[Laughter]
she previously held positions as a
senior fellow at the carnegie endowment
for international peace and the atlantic
council
and she has served as senior director at
the u.s cyberspace stellarium commission
at the far end of the stage for me is mr
butler
he is a researcher at the institute of
law and
technology at masadak university in
bruno
and a security consultant in the private
sector and this is me practicing my
check so
uh thank you for your patience
and his research he focuses on threat
doctors especially ransomware groups
which is also what he will be talking to
us about today
michael previously worked at
the czech ministry of defense and he has
been both a visiting scholar here at
nato ccdcoe and at the natos.com coe in
riga so we're very excited to have him
here
but first out martin the floor is yours
okay thank you
uh
okay
we got that right okay that's who i am
that's where i work that's what i'm
gonna be talking about
these are my caveats
okay don't have to put them up for very
long
and uh because the conference theme is
keep moving we'll go to slide number
three
okay so what motivates this discussion
we have what i would call standard
deterrence
and standard deterrence essentially
rests on three things one
you make some indication or declaration
of what you don't want the other side to
do
number two
if the other side does it
you have the responsibility of
determining
whether it crossed your red lines who
did it
and number three if you're going to
instantiate a deterrence policy as
opposed to just have it then you have to
meet out punishment
okay
standard deterrence one-on-one
does it work
and this is a big question but i'm gonna
say it doesn't seem to be working well
enough
the best example of coercion
in the service of improving cyberspace
was the agreement signed by presidents g
and obama in 2015 in which the chinese
agreed not to carry out certain forms of
cyber espionage
but the linchpin of that agreement
was not wonderful and good feelings
between the two presidents but the
implicit and not always implicit threat
that the united states would put
sanctions on chinese companies that
disobeyed
well the life span of that threat was
roughly equivalent to the remaining
lifespan of the obama administration
and a large reason in my humble opinion
not everybody agrees for that
was because the turns has an assurance
component it's not only if you do this
i'm going to do that to you but it's
also if you don't do this i'm not going
to do that to you and you had an
administration that had a much broader
set of complaints against china at which
point chinese said
damned if we do and damned if we don't
so we might as well go ahead and do okay
the other instance i would point out is
there was a specific warning from
president biden to president putin not
to go around hacking our infrastructure
and it's too soon to tell whether that
in fact reduced the amount of hacking
one of the things we know about
deterrence
is we always know when we can tell when
it fails but we can never tell when it
succeeds okay
part of the problem with standard
deterrence as we practice it where
attribution is an important element in
the game
is that it puts the burden of proof on
defenders
okay it forces us it forces those who
would deter
to
detect the the cyber attack characterize
it as a cyber attack
somehow make the argument that it
crossed the red line although u.s red
lines are not particularly precise and
then do attribution and then you have
the other side basically going what us
we are a law-abiding country what he
wouldn't even think of doing that and
that's sort of where it lands okay but
still the burden of proof is on the
defender
meanwhile if you were actually level
your punishment you can't go around
saying not us
that indictment of your hackers that
wasn't our country yeah like you know
okay it wasn't pennsylvania
okay now there are some people who make
the argument that the reason deterrence
has been disappointing is because we
haven't pressed hard enough
okay and if you look at the two forms of
punishment that have been used
since
roughly 2014 and going forward it's been
sanctions and it's been indictments
indictments could very well be
dissuasive word not for the small fact
that when we indict state actors they
almost never see the inside of a u.s
courtroom
as for sanctions are concerned
there is a a zero-sum game in sanctions
we cannot for instance
credibly threaten
not to trade with north korea because we
don't trade with them we can't do that
for iran because we don't trade with
them right and we're getting to the
point with russia that we can't credibly
sanction
russians for cyber attacks because we
are credibly sanctioning them for a lot
of other misbehavior that we like even
worse than their cyber attacks okay and
there's a final point is that we have
found that novelty
the fact that cyber attacks are often a
surprise not in how they got in
but why anyone would want to do
something else like that at all are
characteristics of a lot of cyber
attacks if you put together a bunch of
smart folks in 2015
as i was honored to be among those
you know me plus a bunch of smart folks
right and you try to list all the things
that were red lines for the united
states
nobody would have come up with it with a
hack on the dnc
okay if you're trying to explain
yourself why it is
that the
the solar winds attack somehow crossed
the red line you can tie yourself in
knots because cyber espionage is in fact
accepted state practice within certain
limits if you look at colonial pipeline
right is a problem that was a ransomware
attack it was a problem that colonial
pipeline decided to respond to an attack
on their business systems by closing
their operating their operating pipeline
okay so you have issues
so what i'm going to entertain
oops oh sorry
okay is something i call obnoxious
deterrence the word obnoxious is so you
can associate me with any particular
term here at the conference
okay and it works as follows
it starts off with one side carrying out
behavior you don't like
okay
uh
so you carry out cyberspace operations
which are seriously annoying and i'll
get to why it has to be seriously
annoying but short of armed conflict for
very obvious reasons okay and i've given
two examples
but that's because somebody asked me for
examples it's actually harder to give
out examples and defend them than it
looks like okay so we now start being
annoying to the other side because we
believe that they are doing things that
we find annoying
okay the other side
suitably annoyed starts asking for
negotiations whether they're public
informal private and informal tacit used
through signaling
is is it is a different matter but
anyhow there is some sort of give and
take
in which ultimately you end up with an
agreement be it formal be it tacit
because a lot of agreements from the
cold war for instance were tacit they
were never written down in which
both sides refrain from the behavior
that the other side finds particularly
annoying
okay and then we come for the last part
what if the other side sheets
right what if they go back and engage in
behavior that they don't like
well the solution is we engage in
behavior that they didn't like
right which is has a certain first of
all we don't necessarily have to explain
ourselves
and second of all
um
we don't necessarily have to force them
to predict what's coming because
inherent in the nature of that agreement
is a notion of what's coming
okay
now
at this point i'd like to thank cycon
for allowing me to introduce the concept
and now i'm going to spend the next two
slides shooting at it
let's prevent you folks from doing the
same okay
um sorry i'm a little behind on the
clicker
okay um
okay there's obnoxious deterrence the
obnoxious deterrence raises whoops
okay
let's go back
compared to standard deterrence
obnoxious
deter oh
okay i was right the first time okay
obnoxious deterrence raises some issues
of its own
the first thing is it helps for it to be
a cyberspace operation now notice
that the u.s approach
to other people's cyberspace operations
we don't like involves something outside
of cyberspace
why should obnoxious deterrence involve
something inside cyberspace
okay
that depends on the kind of agreement
that you want to conclude
if what your agreement is i won't do x
if you don't do y
right that's an asymmetric agreement if
x and y are not the same
but there's an expectation in fact that
what you're basically saying is i won't
do x and y
and you don't do x and y
it's our x that you find annoying it's
your why that you that we find annoying
right and we put it together in a
package once you cross domains your
negotiations become a lot more difficult
because
the advantage of staying in the
cyberspace domains is it gets rid of a
lot of extraneous issues
once you cross domains you're into these
extraneous issues your negotiations
become far more difficult okay so that's
the first constraint number two
it needs to work
now
this is so obvious that i'm going to
have to explain why it's not obvious
right
if you do deterrence
and you threaten somebody with something
you've never done before
they have to believe that what you're
going to threaten with is in fact going
to work
so for instance
a nuclear deterrence policy
we are threatening people
heaven for fan with essentially
missiles that we haven't used in combat
right
there's a high degree of faith on the
other side that they're going to work
with obnoxious deterrence however you're
starting off with the behavior that's
the punishment
which means if you're going to be at all
impressive
the thing actually has to function and
in cyberspace that's not a guarantee
right it's one thing to say if you mess
with our electric grid we'll take down
yours it's quite another thing to be
able to do so with a high degree of
reliance with obnoxious deterrence
before you even have any deterrence
you've proven yourself capable of doing
a certain category of annoying things
okay
now number three and this one is
particular for cyberspace
and that is
it has to be
working as defenses arise
the cybers the medium of cyberspace is
one in which measure and counter measure
are continually competing against one
another
okay so you can expect that the other
side's first reaction is not going to be
to go to negotiation table but to use
internal measures
to cost effectively reduce the annoyance
level of your cyber operations so if
you're going to be effective you need a
set of cyber operations that don't
counter measure that easily okay
number four that's actually is obvious
enough i don't have to explain it it
needs to be annoying enough
it needs to be annoying enough
that countries start negotiating or at
least raising the issue at the state
level
okay a lot of things that we see in
cyberspace are annoying but not annoying
enough so there's a certain threshold of
annoyance that you have to meet
okay
number five
is
you have to
get enough out of it or at least appear
sufficiently committed that your form of
obnoxious deterrence is not going to go
away on its own
right you have to be invested in it you
have to credibly
convey the notion that you're going to
keep going on as long as the other side
keeps going on
okay
now then we get to the converse
if the results excuse me if the results
of obnoxious deterrence
are too attractive
then the other side figures you're not
going to give it up
right
for instance we carry out carry out a
lot of cyber espionage as do other
countries we find the results useful
otherwise we wouldn't do them
in fact i may even go out on a limb to
say that we find the results so useful
that we would be very loath to give them
up
to the point where the other side
probably doesn't believe that they can
negotiate us
away from doing that sort of stuff
okay so there's a model here if it's
painful enough to you you won't keep at
it if it's beneficial enough to you you
won't give it up so you have to find a
sweet spot in the middle
okay
you also have to have the technical
characteristics where if you promise to
give it up the other side can detect
that you're promising to give it up
right
if the other side does not have any
confidence in their ability to monitor
your behavior
if you give it up
you don't have the verify part of the
trust but verify okay and then finally
um you should be able to come out ahead
if the other side does likewise
and it should be this sort of operation
that doesn't have an obvious escalation
path
now that doesn't mean escalation won't
occur
but it does mean that in escalating
somebody has to do something radically
different and there's an inhibition
against that
okay
having given you all of these criteria
what have i ended up concluding
that it's a wonderful idea in practice
okay but is there any actual form of
cyber operation that can meet all these
criteria
and i can't guarantee that there is
and you know you're going to end up
pitching a lot of things that might seem
superficially attractive but not
necessarily fit this criteria okay
added issues come from one-on-one
bargaining for instance the united
states has a great number of allies
clearly nato in the pacific etc
to what extent will u.s negotiations on
behavior in cyberspace reflect the
interests of these allies or to what
extent should negotiations proceed
through alliance structures okay now in
europe obviously alliance structure in
asia not so obvious an alliance
structure where the united states has a
set of bilaterals so that's a question
will it necessarily lead to norms
building
and this is this is a question of
narrative okay our current narrative is
responsible countries don't do
irresponsible things in cyberspace and
once we declare an action to be
irresponsible
it's incumbent on us not to do it
right because of our argument on norms
is you're doing something bad
you're really not in a position to
actually go ahead and do it
with obnoxious deterrence you've
abandoned that notion everything sort of
becomes reason of state almost up to the
million dialogue level okay
we don't like what you're doing we're
going to do what you don't like and then
we can come to an agreement not that one
is right or one is wrong or there's a
standard of responsible behavior there
isn't is in many ways morally neutral
and this notion of moral neutrality
doesn't really sit well with some people
which includes me about half the time
okay um
lastly because the united states has at
least two major adversaries to minor
adversaries in cyberspace there's a lot
of negotiations would one side see what
the other side has managed to negotiate
as a floor or a ceiling
okay
so where are we we are
i can sort of end here i can go to the
next slide which is a set of
okay
okay here's here's the conclusion right
tempting idea in theory practice maybe
not so much
and then here's here's what i say
questions but i decide to leave out the
word
okay are we good here we go thank you
passing the totem pole excellent okay uh
thank you martin for challenging our
conceptions of the returns and the same
breath shooting it down in classical
style excellent before erica sets off if
you don't mind i'm going to very quickly
abuse my power up here and all of you
i'm sure will have lots of questions and
you will be allowed when they're all
done i have one question because i want
to pull this back to the
keynote speaker from our australian
colleague this morning she talked about
how
negotiations have only gotten harder
that
china and russia are harder to negotiate
with you've talked about how they pay
service to rules-based order
and
do you think
and again you've shot it down well done
but do you think what would you
think about the feasibility of civilian
rules-based negotiations given
obnoxious deterrence
well if i had a great deal of trust that
you could not only craft a norm's regime
but keep people to it
i probably would have selected another
candidate topic for this form
okay the fact of the matter is she's
right
right our relations with russia took a
strong downturn after 2014 our relations
with china have
faded considerably notably after 2017
when we started raising a lot of trade
issues with china okay they're not
the optimism that we could have felt
about norms 10 years ago does not exist
today
um
with russia
we'd have to go through a lot of changes
to get back to there with china
it's not going to be obvious it's pos
it's more possible than with russia but
i wouldn't give it a 100 guarantee okay
now
when you start talking about norms
you end up having to talk about
punishment it's fairly clear that
wagging our finger at russia and china
doesn't really work that well
so the question then becomes what is the
form of punishment and and can you do
this in a bilateral negotiation you have
the advantage
and and i i'm thinking in terms of the
nuclear various nuclear treaties we had
with the soviet union or that nato had
with the warsaw pact right and it's like
if we don't like your be if we think
you're cheating we'll just leave simple
straightforward you know what the
consequences were
okay
[Music]
but when you have a norms-based approach
particularly it's a multilateral
norms-based approach it doesn't work
right because what are the consequences
if you leave the norms you're going to
misbehave no because you're very
promised you're not going to do bad
things and you've just marked this out
as bad so you don't have that kind of
leverage so you're forced to go cross
domain
and when you go across domain
at a risk of exaggeration um
nobody asked me are you exaggerating yes
i am at the risk of exaggeration you
either have counter measures that are
weaker than the original effect or
stronger than the original effect and
the stronger ones the weakness ones tend
towards irrelevance and the stronger
ones tend sword escalation
thank you for a very bleak summary of uh
future negotiations
uh
speaking of punishment uh erica um floor
is yours thank you so much oh okay um
all right hi everyone i'm erica lonergan
i'm really excited to be here um i'm
presenting
a paper that i co-authored with admiral
mark montgomery who um could not be here
today to present with me unfortunately
but i'm really excited to share sort of
our thoughts and ideas with you and i'll
just caveat this by saying that
we sort of see this project
as a conversation starter as the
beginning of a conversation
um we don't have so the the topic is the
promise and perils of allied offensive
cyber operations we're really focusing
on nato in this paper um and we sort of
have some ideas that we're curious to
get feedback on and so really excited to
present this here to get your feedback
and have some hopefully simulating
discussion about this topic and i have
the similar caveat as professor lovicky
my views are my own and they don't
reflect as well as my co-author's views
are also his own and don't reflect any
us government
entity or organization that we are or
have been affiliated with so
with that um i i thought it would be
useful
to give you sort of some background in
terms of how we started working on this
research project about offensive cyber
operations in an alliance context more
specifically in a nato context and it
really came from our work together on
the cyberspace delirium commission um
admiral montgomery was the executive
director of the commission i was a
senior director on the commission and
just by way of some very brief
background because i could spend the
next 20 minutes just talking about the
commission which which i won't um
congress created this bipartisan
uh commission in the 2019
national defense authorization act with
the idea that the us government needed
kind of a comprehensive and independent
but sort of multi-governmental take on
what you know do we have the right
strategic approach for cyberspace to
deter cyber attacks and what are the set
of policy recommendations both from an
executive branch perspective and a
legislative perspective that would help
improve our overall deterrence posture
and i'm just i'm just mentioning this
because you know so so we worked on this
commission for about a year and a half
came out with this report in march of
2020 right before everything shut down
and the the report is from a strategic
perspective is anchored in this idea of
layered cyber deterrence um i i don't
mean to put out yet another deterrent
concept for for you all to sort of to
chew on but um but there
the basic idea of layered cyber
deterrence is that you know we need to
take cyber deterrence out of its silo
and um think about how deterrence might
apply differently and look different
across sort of
the conflict continuum right
the closer you get uh to the left side
you're sort of at lower levels of
competition and as you get further to
the right you you get toward crisis and
conflict um again the point of this
presentation is not to talk about
layered cyber deterrence but i wanted to
highlight a few insights from this work
that informed how we sort of started
thinking about
offensive cyber operations in a nato
context and there are three insights in
particular that i think are relevant to
give you some context
the first is that
well the title of this panel our group
together is um is i think it's is
offense the best defense in cyber space
right is that something like that behind
you yes our offensive operation is the
best defense and so despite the fact
that i'm talking about offensive cyber
operations and deterrence this afternoon
with you all i actually don't think that
offense is the best defense in
cyberspace um and that was a really
important insight from the commission's
work and this idea of layered cyber
deterrence having the credible
capability for effective cost imposition
to include cyber and non-cyber means is
of course an important element of
deterrence right but
alone it is insufficient to address sort
of the full scope of the types and the
magnitude
and the various actors
that threats that we face in cyberspace
so that's sort of the first caveat um if
i had to answer that question it would
be no um the second is that
and this is really where our paper kind
of um the jumping off point for our
paper is that when we think about cost
and position
sort of early thinking on cyber
deterrence and in particular early
strategy and policy in the united states
as well as in um
allied and partner governments has
really focused on costs and position
above the threshold of armed conflict
right
and what
layered cyber deterrence try to do and
what other approaches have done as well
is is kind of extend that um
left side of the curve
below the threshold of arm conflict um
with the recognition like professor
libiki mentioned just a few minutes ago
that um there even when you're sort of
in a context of competition um for
deterrence to be effective there has to
be some type of um punishment that's
imposed um and then the third insight
which is uh relevant for the us
government but also highly relevant even
i would say more relevant for an
alliance is that um there are inordinate
hurdles in terms of
interoperability and coordination within
the federal government um not to mention
between the federal government and state
and local actors and between the federal
government and the private sector and
these kind of
coordination and cooperation challenges
were something that we really struggled
with during the commission and i think
it's also something that is really
important to take into account when we
think about how an alliance um
should should think about sort of a
an approach for for cyber operations so
that's just giving you some
context um and then the other
sort of more more obvious
source of this project was um was was
really thinking about the threat
environment and um
there was a typo in there it should say
the primary cyber threat to nato um
i guess i could have made it a guessing
game to see who could improve
what i'm referring to here but um but so
you know did this work on the commission
on layered cyber deterrence at the same
time we're seeing the sort of continuing
evolution of the threat environment i
think what's really fascinating to me is
that on the one hand
you have an alliance like nato that has
really matured over time in terms of its
thinking and its organization for
cyber deterrence and defense
and that focus has really been on sort
of the high-end conflict but what we've
seen from an empirical perspective
is that
much of the threat stems from sort of
the range of malicious cyber activity
that takes place
below that threshold
rather than sort of the high-end
decisive cyber attack and i think what's
really interesting and this is probably
a controversial statement and i'm sure
there are many in this audience who will
disagree with me but i'll put it out
there to see what you all think um i
think that there's been a lot of debate
about what are the sort of lessons
learned from um from ukraine um
ongoing lessons being learned for cyber
first sight with the nature of cyber
conflict and there's a panel i think
happening tomorrow that will get into
these questions far more deeply than i
will today but i think that you know
the debate has been framed in this very
binary way
you know with one camp thing cyber isn't
you know is is not important it's not
happening in ukraine in another camp
saying it is it's just confirmation that
you know cyber war will take place and
is taking place i think the evidence is
a lot more mixed and i think that what
at least what's been publicly released
so far whether you look at the microsoft
report or other reports that are coming
out
as well as statements from senior
government officials that it's actually
far more
nuanced and complicated and challenging
to
coordinate cyber effects with kinetic
effects on the battlefield in a way
that's decisive
and the level of coordination that we're
seeing doesn't seem to be perhaps as
as high as we might have expected which
is why there have been all these debates
that have been prompted about well how
come you know where where is all the
cyber war in ukraine there's a lot of
cyber activity um but sort of walking
the line from cyber activity to sort of
meaningful decisive impact is a lot more
complicated and contested um and so and
this confirms research by a lot of great
academics um like nadia koschuk and yuri
zukov who've done have done work on the
role of cyber operations in the
battlefield in the past um and so i
think that this is all pointing us to
having a conversation about how an
alliance like nato should think about
the cyber threat not just for the
high-end you know
conflict but also below the level of
armed conflict right because we know
that's how nato adversaries are
operating
okay
so we try to sort of lay out a bunch of
research questions in this paper and
again these are questions that we have
some initial thoughts on answers to
you know this is sort of the opening
salvo so to speak of a research agenda
so the first question is should there be
a role for offensive cyber operations in
a you know the context of nato
deterrence um sort of below the level of
armed conflict not just in integrated
with conventional
military operations above that threshold
and if so
what are the potential challenges and
impediments to
doing something like this which i'll say
off the bat are significant
but something that i think is important
to start thinking through and having
those conversations about
which brings me to my last question
which we kind of put out in the research
paper which is what you know what
initial steps could the alliance start
to start to take
to improve coordination around offensive
cyber
okay so
you know
i think it's helpful to kind of lay out
how
um the alliance has evolved both from a
sort of organizational and capability
perspective and also from a strategy and
policy perspective since 2008 because
there really has been a lot of
evolution and maturity of thought and of
organization um but i i think there's
still some sort of unresolved
tensions and mismatches that um that
we're seeing kind of bubble to the
surface over the past few years and so
you know as i said um how nato has
organized itself for cyber has evolved a
lot since bucharest in 2008 um these are
all things that you all know right um
there have been a number of
organizations stood up within nato
mostly focused on the defensive aspects
of cyber security whether it's incident
response and rapid reaction teams um
communications the 2016 cyber defense
pledge where allies pledge to increase
their spending and investment in
you know all these types of defensive
measures training and education and
information and so on and so forth and
that's all great
there's also been
growing but sort of limited organization
on offensive cyber focus on sort of the
integrating cyber into conventional
military operations uh in 2008 nato set
up the cyber operations center um and
created this sort of voluntary process
for individual nations to provide cyber
effects it reached initial operational
capability in 2020 2021 so again very
sort of new um emergent organizational
uh organizational capability at the same
time there's also been
really important evolution in nato
strategic thinking
and nato policy around around cyber
around cyber deterrence and again i'm
sort of reiterating what a lot of people
in this room already know but i think
it's helpful to kind of see
um how the evolution has taken place
over time right so in 2014
um the alliance
agreed that article 5 the beating heart
of the alliance
the all for one and one for all applies
to cyberspace and
in 2016 nato recognized cyberspace as an
operational domain similar to you know
air land at sea
um i think what's really interesting is
what happened
um the result of the 2021 summit in
brussels where um of course the alliance
reaffirms that article 5 applies to
cyberspace but the language was sort of
different from in the past in particular
um
you know
the language of the communique stated
that the impact of significant malicious
cumulative cyber activities might in
some circumstances be considered as
amounting to an armed attack and
therefore could potentially be
justification for
invoking article 5 which would obviously
happen only on a consensus basis but i
think it's the language is really
interesting because i think it reflects
um
it reflects
a maturation of thinking about the
nature of offensive cyber
and the nature of the threat environment
because you know
we haven't seen the sort of singular
decisive
cyber attack that has major cataclysmic
consequences
instead
what threat actors have done is sort of
conducted
cyber campaigns that in their
accumulation could in some circumstances
rise to
significant events and so but this gets
that this kind of
challenge and ambiguity about where
exactly the threshold lies for thinking
about an appropriate
um
retaliatory response in support of a
deterrence objective because it's not
quite as
bright and like not quite as a red line
in practice as um
as perhaps we would like it to be in
theory and so i think that this
evolution and thinking is is really
important um
on the other hand this sort of lingering
ambiguity
is um i think presenting some challenges
for how we think about the effectiveness
of a cyber deterrence posture for nato
um and and those ambiguities are
reflected in um secretary general
stoltenberg's press conference and other
public statements that have been made um
with respect to the ukraine war in terms
of the application of article 5 with the
fear that russia might perhaps
respond against a nido
nato member in cyberspace as a
retaliation for the inordinate economic
sanctions regimes nato has been impo
nato members have imposed on russia
right so he says that
um yes we've stated that cyber attacks
can trigger article five but we've never
gone into we've never really said right
we've retained strategic ambiguity about
when and how and the conditions under
which a particular event might trigger
article five and yet when you look at
that um in you know as a follow-on to
the brussels communique where you have
this kind of um
sort of loosening of
what type of incident would constitute
um
a an event that would rise to
that type of threshold
i think there are a number of unanswered
questions and so hopefully
um hopefully we start to address them
right and i i think that you know
yes it's a it's a positive development
that there has been all this maturation
from an organizational perspective from
a strategy and policy perspective but um
you know there's sort of these
unresolved
tensions or these kind of mismatches
between
how um you know between strategy policy
organization and the nature of the
threat environment and i think that
starting to have those conversations
about
how salient and important are these
tensions what are the implications for
the credibility of cyber deterrence um
how should the alliance think about
addressing them are um are sort of what
we're trying to get in this paper and so
the first the first sort of mismatch or
tension that really kind of anchors the
whole piece is on the one hand you know
the current
nato approach has been focused on how
you know how to integrate offensive
cyber operations into
conventional sort of kinetic campaign
plans for you know forearmed conflict uh
which again is a is a important uh
important investment in in resources but
you know it's mismatched to the nature
of the threat environment where what
we're seeing the types of threats that
nato is confronting in cyberspace um
have not
really risen to that threshold um
instead they're they're below that
threshold um and so
does this tension produce any sort of
credibility or problematic issues for
for its cyber deterrence posture
um the second is that you know on the
one hand we have it's it's politically
convenient to draw this bright
demarcation between
um you know between the level of armed
conflict and
above and below that threshold when in
reality we know that governments can't
even agree on what that threshold what
constitutes that threshold and so the
ambiguity is sort of politically
convenient but perhaps not strategically
useful
and when you apply that to
planning and developing capabilities
around cyber operations um
it might be sort of nice to try to
contain that to things that apply to to
wartime but the reality that we all know
is that there are things that you have
to do
in peace time and in competition
to prepare for
crisis and conflict and some of those
things involve
uh sort of tricky and potentially
problematic operations right to conduct
intelligence uh preparation to gain
access to strategic targets and so on
and so forth and so while it might be
nice to kind of segment okay you know
we're focused on offensive cyber during
wartime you know and we we don't really
want to talk about it you know during
during peace simon competition
there are things that need to be done
for
the employment of those capabilities to
be actually effective and useful during
wartime right so again the they're these
sort of tensions um but the same is true
for offense and defense right
for you know
nato um again strategy and policy has
been mostly focused on sort of defensive
cyber um and mostly organized around
defensive cyber but um
you know in in sort of uh
they're well while some activities are
obviously defensive and some are
obviously offensive there's a whole
range of things that um that are far
more ambiguous and so again the bright
lines are not quite as bright in
practice
and then you know there's the reality
that there are nato members who have
already articulated
strategic concepts that take into
account um countering adversary threats
below the level of armed conflict the
united states is an obvious example
right 2008 was a watershed year for u.s
cyber strategy and policy with the
release of the 2018 department of
defense cyber strategy which articulated
this concept of defend forward
which kind of reflected a
shift in how
you know and how the department of
defense conceived of when and where
its capabilities would be employed below
the level of dharma conflict the same is
true of the united kingdom right which
has become even more and more public
over time in acknowledging cyber
operations often conducted in in tandem
or in collaboration with the united
states to impose costs on threat actors
again like below the level around
conflict so i think all of these kind of
um
tensions and ambiguity suggest that
a conversation should be started about
how we think about um
offensive cyber below the level of armed
conflict
and so
you know
in in offering that
i'll start by sort of undermining my own
case
i guess and um and note that there
are a whole host of challenges um
that
sort of immediately bubble up to the
surface when we start to think about um
how to even have how to even have this
conversation and think about its
implementation at the political level
right um you know
and i'm totally i'm going to butcher the
quote here but um you know when the uh
when the conflict in ukraine first
started
president biden um i think he's repeated
this line more than once
but definitely do not quote me on it but
he is um because i'll bungle the exact
phrase but he's emphasized over and over
the importance of the unity of the
alliance right and how that is um that
has been critical to it the
effectiveness of its of its response to
russian aggression um when it comes to
offensive cyber
there isn't there isn't a lot of unity
there isn't political consensus around
these issues and that's because there
still are these sort of persistent
disagreements about basic um basic
concepts and definitions when it comes
to sort of variations in how sovereignty
is defined and what constitutes a
violation of sovereignty in cyberspace
variation in terms of you know what
types of cyber incidents would sort of
cross a threshold
into armed attack or even disagreements
about the difference between use of
force and armed attack right um
disagreements about the acceptability of
cyber operations to gain access to
maneuver through within um networks
owned by owned by one's allies right um
and so there are a whole host of
political challenges that make this a
difficult conversation um
even more so there are a whole host of
sort of operational and tech and
tactical challenges in terms of thinking
about um implementation and i just have
you know highlighted a few up here and
there are only just a few but um
but i think it illustrates some of the
some of the hurdles here um one is sort
of the relationship between intelligence
collection requirements and military
operations both in terms of the fact
that um you know a given state has to
make definitions about um intelligence
gain loss right and whether they're
willing to compromise
access that enables intelligence
collection and supports intelligence
requirements for the conduct of military
cyber operation those are only
compounded when you think about
aggregating those decisions in alliance
context particularly given that nato
rests on consensus
the other reality is that um you know
intelligence collection requirements are
set at a national governmental level or
from a nato perspective decisions about
military operations aren't an alliance
level right and so you may have um may
have significant tension there
cyber operations rests on intelligence
um and states have been
you know very circumspect for obvious
reasons about sharing exquisite
intelligence that enables
the type of access that's required for
conducting
meaningful strategic cyber operations
the reality that even allies spy on one
another right because
with the exception of certain
certain alliances um
you know because espionage is accepted
accepted state practice um and so uh you
know
that poses some challenges and then
obviously concerns about just you know
sensitive information that's being
shared that may that may end up in
places it's not supposed to um there
also significant variation in
capabilities across the alliance um
there are also concerns about escalation
risk although i have that as a question
mark because in general i'm skeptical
that um cyber operations create
meaningful escalation risks i'm happy to
talk about that in q a if that's of
interest um i have no idea how i'm doing
on time i can have a 30 more seconds 30
more seconds okay
so um so i think that from in terms of
in terms of next steps um
i guess this is as i said sort of an
opening to a conversation i think it
would be
really useful to start having those
conversations about how an alliance like
nato might start to think about
offensive cyber operations not just for
armed conflict but sort of below that
level and what that might look like i
think that interoperability is a bridge
too far but starting to think about
improving coordination
whether it's improving intelligence
sharing which is sort of an obvious
recommendation but also you know
assessing whether you know particular
alliance members may have a comparative
advantage in let's say access for
instance because of geographic proximity
or capability or what have you whether
you know you can sort of divide and
conquer a cyber a cyber campaign um
particularly for developing access and
capabilities against you know really
strategic difficult targets
but anyway um
as i said initial conversation looking
forward to your thoughts and questions
and i think that was 30 seconds
okay thank you
thank you erica very much for
introducing conversation with a healthy
academic attitude of immediately red
teaming your own point well done both of
you um again i'm going to take advantage
of being up here
and i have a thought on the
ancient uh um
tactic of war death by a thousand gods
well not so much war as a torture method
death by a thousand cuts um the low
sophistication operations that you're
constantly seeing against
various targets frankly all over the
world but very often against western
democracies do you think this proverbial
cyber war would it be fair to say that
the target at the end of the day is the
core foundation of what builds these
states namely namely this
liberal democratic world order
rules based order that is a big so so
just so i understand your question
correctly so you're asking whether the
sort of death by a thousand cuts in
cyberspace over time will erode
what we understand is the foundations of
the liberal world order correct okay no
okay very cool i can elaborate
you may get a chance later but first
okay uh we're going to move over to uh
michael and hear a bit about the
non-state actors that
are involved in other operations
yeah
thank you to to erica and martin for
great presentations and thank you all
for being here so uh our research topic
with my colleague yakupuri sitting there
is
about non-state actors and specifically
bransonburg groups and but it is uh
possible and feasible for us to try to
counter the activities through offensive
cyber operations
so before we start the usual disclaimers
that uh
we all like to use uh i would like to
also mention the the second one and that
is that we used only uh open source and
public information
which is also one of the limits of our
research so before i get to the topic of
the offensive operations let's maybe try
to create some shared understanding of
where we currently are with the
ransomware issue and how we got there
so
on one side you have numbers and volumes
and data about how it is how it uh is
going
to uh how it uh over the last few years
got a bit worse
and
on on the other side quite literally you
have to the stories and the
the other uh considerations behind that
so we've seen uh events like uh the
colonial pipeline attack the jbs and
cassaya we have seen
attacks on healthcare and
education systems during the hate of the
global pandemic
and we have also seen
conti one of the major groups pledging
support to to russian government and
threatening
retaliation to anybody else
who would who would try to to attack
russia in the in the events in ukraine
and what we haven't seen are the
countless attacks on on uh small and
media business businesses causing
economic damages that we simply do not
uh know about
uh because of under reporting
so
how did we actually get there
we have currently something that we call
as a vancouver as a service which is um
no longer a bunch of hackers hiding in a
basement and launching cyberattacks but
rather a thriving business environment
with you know dedicated roles
management people
budgets rented offices
vacation plans and even office politics
so we have different people that
specialize in in doing things they're
good at be that
the the initial access the hacking be
that encrypting the networks handling
customers payments and infrastructure
and we also highlighted several
factors that we think are contributing
or are important to that helped create
this this ecosystem and that is the
network effect or the the availability
to share and buy and sell the initial
accesses tools knowledge to recruit and
market their own brands in the in the um
system of underground forum and
microplaces
obviously the ransomware business
couldn't really be conducted at the
scale without cryptocurrencies which
allowed to uh the transfers of millions
of euros or dollars whatever you prefer
without the traditional oversight of
banking industry and governments
and we have also the geopolitical
considerations that limit our law
enforcement activities and especially
non-cooperative jurisdictions that
harbor
their cyber criminals in exchange that
they don't target their own people
so
to tackle these challenges
over the past few years many experts and
indeed
public military and intelligence
officials sounded the
the notion that you know this is maybe a
national security issue that should be
handled
also with the use of offensive cyber
operations and especially by military
and intelligence agencies
so that is a starting point of a point
of our paper
to
try to approach it from
a data-driven way or the the empiric way
we try to select and and find out as
much case studies as we could on
the broadest sense of what could be
considered as
an offensive cyber operation against
ransomware group
and
the broadest sense is in in our research
basically the any unauthorized use of
systems and and data that these
these groups are using
and
we also try to leverage the the
information we have on other operations
against uh against non-state actors be
that the operation glowing symphony by
jdf aries
uh against isis or the the multinational
european-led uh
europa league disruption of emote.net
that also had an offensive cyber
component by by netherlands police
so
with this approach there are obviously
some challenges and limitations that
mainly stem from uh from the the lack of
data and observability
and
but i start with the first one and that
is how do you differ
the the impact of offensive cyber
operations versus other factors be that
political pressure economic and social
developments or even the the traditional
law enforcement activities
the second challenge is
how do you actually measure impact in a
in a next system that is rapidly
changing and involving almost every day
or every week due to how the groups and
the variants rise
disband rebrand under pressure and what
is essentially partially obscured to us
because we don't have the visibility
there
and the first third one is
about how do you account for events and
information that is not available in the
public public sphere so
those are obviously a big challenges to
to our research and that is
also why we don't
presume to
present results but uh
we are already trying to to make some
initial observations that will hopefully
be before the developers as our
understanding and the data set grows
so um
for the the observations themselves we
try to divide them into two logical
groups and that is impact on the whole
ecosystem level and on the individual
act level
um however the
uh
the division or the declassification is
really an artificial one and they often
overlap and
influence each other
the so the first one that we have seen
on the x system level is is exclusion
from the broader
uh
cyber crime ecosystem
and that was noticeable especially after
the colonial pipeline attacks and
subsequent events
that
uh the ransomware operators and variants
and
affiliates were
ostracized by the the rest of the the
underground ecosystem because of the the
pressure and the visibility that was
uh against them that impacted other
people's operation
um
we have also seen the the influence and
that is this is really hard to discern
from the other uh from the other factors
that that come into play here
regarding targeting be that from the
industry or the geographic
consideration
and we have also seen some shifts in the
operating models so in the in the public
operating model the it's really the
brand of the
and the the the malware that gets
presented to the affiliates which are
free to use them with for a fee
but uh some groups especially after the
pressure uh converted a bit more into
the private model where they can
carefully select their affiliates so the
people who do the actual hacking and
also their upstream and downstream uh
business partners and try to vet them
and try to keep the the operation and
the reps
which also limits their profits and
scalability
so
in especially in connection with the
first
first individual level uh
factor
is the
uh shifts in
the most popular strains so the strains
that have been compromised or were known
to be compromised had a
harder time to to attract uh new
affiliates to recruit to sell their uh
you know programs and that led up to
some shifts in in what was the the most
popular the the hype at the moment
the
brands and reputation are really at the
the core of of ransomware stuff
apart from the prophets which i'll talk
about in a moment
um they
impact how they can attract developers
pen testers and the low levels
uh low-level staff which we don't often
hear about
but it has also some kind of
consideration on the victim's side and
that is
to have the reputation on the one hand
to
be able to follow up on threats to be
able to actually keep the
the data encrypted and to be able to
with the the technique of double
extortion to have them uh available to
the public so the confidential
confidential data of of companies and
organizations
so the second potential impact
or the the impact we have seen is uh
obviously on the core of the
run software business and that is profit
margins and bottom lines
and it's
noticeable from
especially from the the county case the
county was
one of the largest organizations until
very recently
and after
their own compromises and also
compromises of their
close business partners they often
burned down and rebuild their whole
infrastructure
they often dismissed and then rehearsed
a lot of their stuff
excluding for a several feet that they
knew
let's say uh in the real world or
had
a long
long
relationship with
they were rebuilding identities changing
nicknames and emails and accesses
and they also
which is kind of ironic uh had to
increase their security spending
on solutions that uh
were helping them to monitor their
administrators and also they were buying
tools like endpoint detection and
response
we can't also discount the psychological
effects which were mostly seen on the on
the arrival case
so in a
very simplistic way what we can say
about the case
about the the group is that after the
compromise of a single server
and subsequent actions on objectives
that were
as far as we know uh
uh
focused on under identifying members of
the group they're scrambled
and it's also uh it's of course the the
um
influence of
other factors and other
other
uh events but uh that that is the the
short version
and
one thing that
is sometimes overlooked in
focusing on the the most impactful
and the leadership and the
the pen testers or the hackers is that
there is
a lot of low-level support staff
handling operations that's
laundering money without administrating
servers and
botnets and what so
uh that
are usually low
uh low-level poorly paid
and they they sometimes resent what they
are doing
and
by
uh making their half uh
their lives harder we can influence the
the burnout and their motivation to
continue to do so
of course there are some other
intervening factors that both allow us
with some options and uh considerable
challenges for this topic
and that is
uh
as as for us
the criminals also have hard time doing
a lot of basic stuff like securing their
infrastructure and keeping their
anonymity on over time
and trust on the internet is hard and
it's especially hard with
the underground's forums and lack of
real identities
what
is challenging for us
is many things in that this respect
first of all balancing
legality and proportionality
and not over militarizing
the issue
spillovers and accidents are always a
concern for a predominantly civilian
infrastructure
and
allocation of resources actually means
two things here so that is of course
balancing
uh
the focus on cyber criminals with what
other
threats and threat actors we have and
there are many
but it's also
to be able to define what is important
to us
and to not get into the trap of a
tactical weka mole of trying to do
everything or trying to just you know
suppress everything that is that is
there
so to conclude
um
from the data and from the cases we have
seen the
this uh approach of offensive cyber
operations against transomburg groups is
maybe best perceived as an important
soul in the whole of government approach
but
providing that we have some basic
some basic
prerequisites like cooperation inside
and outside of the public sector deep
understanding of the environment and
maybe most important of all
reasonable
goals and definitions of success of what
we want to and what we can achieve in
that space
and that is why this is not the silver
bullet
but rather
the part of the whole tool set
and with that i thank you for your
attention and i'm happy to receive your
questions
thank you michael for
highlighting the unforgiving nature of
this domain where both your
proverbial good guys and bad guys face
rather similar challenges
i am going to stop abusing my power as
moderator and i won't bug you anymore
but i'm going to try to summarize you
know because this panel has a question
as its title i think we can say that
erica does not believe that offensive
operations are the best defenses
martin thinks that obnoxious behavior
can compel actors to behave
and michael
maybe
and michael's observations uh indicate
that disruption is effective but
certainly no silver bullet so that's a
yes no one a maybe yeah
excellent
i think you all want to take credit for
the maybe right so i'll turn the floor
over to our wonderful audience thank you
all for your patience um before we get
started i will remind you to please
introduce yourself name affiliation
whatever else you want to share about
yourself but very quickly getting to an
actual question we have about 22 minutes
left and out of respect for your fellow
audience members try to keep it brief uh
also if possible i prefer if you can
direct your questions at a specific
panel member instead of
an answer from the entire panel because
then well we're not going to get through
a lot of questions we have two very
eager ones in the front row so i think
we'll start with uh youtube
and then i promise to look to the far
back as well so you won't be ignored
all right thank you so much for the
wonderful presentations my name is
aleidar amirsid i'm from kazakhstan i
represent the private company so not a
nato allied nation
so i have a question to dr libiki and dr
lonergan about how does the
state-sponsored hacktivism
fit into the consideration of obnoxious
deterrence
because and in terms of
offensive cyber operation short war in
the sense that
in the last couple of years and
specifically with this situation in
ukraine uh what we have seen is that the
um great
increase in uh
activist group being active and hacking
governmental servers government websites
with defacements and
uh personal data leaks which happened to
the numerous uh private companies so in
a way uh what i'm trying to say in in
case of dr labiki
uh state sponsored hacktivism offers
this kind of uh plausible in my opinion
offers this kind of plausible
deniability for the state in order to
uh denying their obnoxious behavior in a
cyberspace and at the same time
state sponsor hacktivism in certain
cases can be considered as an cyber
operation short of war and in this case
who should be responsible for it and
what should be done about those type of
situations
thank you hopefully i was brief okay let
me redefine your question of course as
an academic
the question is
what about non-state actors acting under
the color of state but not obviously
under the state right yes uh how do we
prove they're acting as part of the
state and that's part of the attractive
feature of obnoxious deterrence we don't
have to prove anything
we just go back to our behavior now if
it turns out
that we react to their behavior and they
didn't do it
their motivation to stay in the deal
goes correspondingly down
so we still have to maintain that
incentive by being roughly right and the
more correct we are
the more we preserve their incentive to
be part of the deal okay
the problem with standard deterrence is
exactly the one you point out you know
the russians say hey it's not sorry i
don't want to pick on them except i do
you know it's uh
we're not responsible for these guys
right and then we have to start making
the case
forget about it and we think you're
responsible and this is how we're
reacting
erica would you like to get those um
i
i think it's a great question i won't
rephrase the question but i think that
you know i don't
i think when we talk about sort of proxy
actors in cyberspace it's often held up
as this thing that challenges deterrence
or something that is particularly
problematic and um i i guess i don't
find as problematic as maybe some others
do and i think that's because um
you know i'll steal a phrase from from
jay healey and you know he talks about
the spectrum of state responsibility
right
um so we can think about different um
you know the the extent to which a
particular sort of target of a cyber
operation believes that a government
rather than sort of a lone wolf you know
hacker or organization is responsible
for that for that activity and so and
it's a spectrum right at the end of the
day these are political decisions less
than they are sort of um sort of
technical ones right um and so and so
that's why i think it's useful to think
about responsibility along a spectrum
rather than as this binary you know did
the state sponsor it or did they not
sponsor it i think what's really
interesting when you bring up the
example of ukraine is that
what i find most fascinating about the
cyber dynamics
in that context are is sort of the
decision on the part of the
government
in ukraine to sort of throw away
plausible deniability probably because
it's not so important during an actual
conflict although russia still maintains
you know denies responsibility for cyber
attacks in the context of ukraine even
though we all know that to be ludicrous
right but um
you know the uh ukraine has taken the
opposite approach and and and sort of
very publicly said okay we are we are
calling on an i.t army um and you know
we are going to give this army
directives through a telegram channel
and actually provide a targeting list
and say okay go right that's the most um
you know straightforward example of
state directed cyber activity and then
you have all the way at the other end of
the spectrum states like russia that
completely deny these types of things so
i think about along a spectrum
i don't think it's that problematic i
think decisions about response are
ultimately political but i do think
that's why when we think about sort of
um
rapid responses short of war
getting at a reasonable level of rapid
attribution is really important for
western democratic states to be able to
justify taking a response and things
that improve
our ability to rapidly attribute
particularly to share information that
others may have about that would enable
more rapid attribution i think i think
is a really important thing and by
attribution i don't necessarily mean
public attribution right um i think
um their
sort of internal confidence might be
sufficient to be able to respond in a
rapid way
i will uh dive into this and add just to
shamelessly plug a recent ccdcoe
publication
for a legal analysis of your question
there was recently a paper published by
the by the center i could highlight
recommend so you get the political
expertise here and uh legal ones on our
website
please
thank you um
it's a peak northern europe but when you
raise your hand you are labeled a very
eager one
saint sacco is my name i am a stone an
ambassador to
to helsinki
they um and
dr labiki the question is is this to you
if i
understood you correctly
you said that
in
meeting out retribution it's good to
keep in the same domain
uh not
you know do it cross domain or outside
of the same domain was that some
something would have said could you
unpack it in a way because i mean it
seems to me
probably the opposite because um
uh
you can have a better dictatory policy
saying if you do this i'll do that in
you know in some other domain uh also
you can
dial it up or down better because as you
said in the cyber domain you cannot be
that certain of a intended effect
happening on the other side
uh and so what basically when you when
you have done your attribution your
retribution is actually
let's say
and it would be also more obnoxious just
not to limit yourself to do whatever you
want wouldn't that be a peak obnoxious
yes thank you
all right
um let me go to two reasons
first reason is
the usefulness of putting your obnoxious
behavior in the cyber domain is that
when you come to negotiations it limits
the scope of the negotiations and the
more the negotiations are down scoped
the fewer extraneous matters there are
to derail it okay then i expressed
another opinion
which was
that there was a tendency for things
weaker than cyber to be ineffective and
things stronger than cyber to be highly
risky and you want some sort of risk
risk effectiveness trade-off
but i want to bring up a point which i
i didn't maybe i should have
one of the problems with sanctions
particularly the way the united states
has applied them is that it's not a
hundred percent clear why we've
introduced the sanctions on particular
particular parties
okay in the criminal justice system
when
you go in front of the court it's for a
particular crime and that's what you're
sentenced for
okay or not sentence force depending on
the outcome and when you start wandering
off that crime
you've changed the nature
of the question you want the person that
you're punishing
to understand that they are punished for
what they do
you don't want them to get the
impression that they are punished for
who they are
right because if you punish them for
what they do you have a chance of being
able to modify their behavior so they
don't do what you don't want them to do
but if you're punishing them for who
they are or more specifically if they
start believing that they are punished
for who they are you cannot change their
behavior
because they're not going to stop being
who they are and a lot of what we've
seen in the rhetoric and this is beyond
cyberspace but it's also within
cyberspace is the united states is doing
is to me not because of what i've done
they just don't like me right
at that point your deterrence policy is
essentially over
because that's the attitude from the
other guy it's one of the paradoxes of
deterrence policy
but of course after 10 seconds of
continuous thought you realize yeah
that's true that it depends entirely on
what goes on between the ears of your
adversary
and if they haven't bought into your
line you don't have deterrence
see
we're going to go all the way to the
back
john i do believe
has his hand up
oh sorry sorry go ahead you go ahead you
already have a mic i promise to go to
the back and john promised to be
annoying so it's a good combination good
afternoon
i'm a dutch cyber diplomat in brussels
both at the eu as well as nato i have a
question to both erica martin but first
a comment um and i hope that you will be
there friday at the eu nato strategic
outlook panel where i'll be more
going in-depth on what the eu has done
but i just want to mention that when you
use the examples eric about imposing
costs and you mentioned us in the uk
since 2019 the u.s done um a lot as well
i'll go more in detail to that on friday
but i had a question on the strategic
ambiguity when it comes to article five
i didn't create quite get whether you
were
advising us to be more precise or where
you are agreeing that there is some sort
of deterrent effect of not being precise
on what article 5 would trigger and i
would be interested to hear martin's
perspective on this as well thank you
yeah
absolutely so i i i
i think that strategic ambiguity
um is not as effective i think strategic
ambiguity is not as effective in this
context as perhaps it is in others um
although it's a you know preferred
approach by
the united states and by nato and by
others and i guess my concern is that um
i'm a bit of a cyber skeptic in general
right and so i think that
my concern is that given that there is
ambiguity about the application of
article 5 in cyberspace and a lack of
consensus about the conditions under
which a particular incident would
potentially rise to a threshold of
article 5. and given that there's been
sort of a revision of you know nato's
statement around how article 5 applies
to cyberspace which could include sort
of the cumulative malicious cyber
attacks rather than a single decisive
cyber attack
my concern is that um
it holds at risk the credibility of
article the credibility of article 5 in
cyberspace is is
contested and that this could have sort
of
secondary effects on the broader
credibility of article 5 which is where
i think it actually matters and i know
we're at a cyber conference and so i
imagine many will disagree with me but
at the end of the day what i care about
um and what i think is important from
sort of a more of a political science
international relations perspective
unless a cyber security perspective is
actually deterring an attack a real
attack on nato um whether it comes
conventionally or god forbid nuclear
weapons right like that's where it
really matters and
and i i think that there are you know
certain types of cyber attacks could
rise to that threshold but i think
they're very few and the likelihood that
they're going to happen um there
probably will be other things that would
already um in conjunction with or in
tandem with a cyber incident that would
you know that would make it obvious that
we're in sort of a
article 5 situation and i think the
problem is that with this lingering
ambiguity um there are all these things
we could point to that well you know is
this a cumulative malicious cyber
incident or not what does this mean for
you know for article 5 and nato and um
and i worry about sort of the the follow
the sort of broader implications for for
article 5 which is the beating heart of
nato which is um sort of the the most
essential important part of the alliance
and which you know absolutely
must be preserved right and so i guess
that's where my
concern is and so even though i
understand that we like to have
strategic ambiguity and respond at a
time place a manner of our choosing i
think it is helpful to have more clarity
about um how article 5 applies to
cyberspace because there is so much
cyber activity right
there is already you know a whole host
of militia cyber activity that
traditional nato adverse adversaries
conduct against nato members and to
undermine the cohesion of the alliance
right so
that ambiguity is not um
i think it's not useful in this
particular context
but perhaps you disagree i think martin
wanted to add something to this okay you
see that you see the bottom bullet here
this is from your briefing yes i want to
creatively reread it
february 20
february 2022 the chief of police said
we have stated that speeding can trigger
a traffic ticket but we have never
gotten to the position where we give the
potential adversary the privilege of
defining our speed limits
that's exactly that
[Applause]
well some well summarized point well
summarize point
you should have just answered the
question i took way too long that was
much better
john did you still have a question for
us i i promised you did threatened
rather that that was a great response by
the way john solomon fsi sack
when you go after a non-state baddie as
um sorry michael was was pointing out
you know trick bots or or conti the
worst thing that can realistically
happen is that they go underground they
regroup and they resurface and you have
to do it all over again it's part of
life
when you go after a state actor
offensively they're not going to
retaliate most likely it's a hardened
military c4 infrastructure they're going
to go after something soft and squishy
like a hospital infrastructure so how do
you as a state actor
on the good guys doing the offensive
cyber cyber operations i assume we're
the good guys in here how do you
understand what potential collateral
damage for you know subject to
retaliatory action is and how do you go
about protecting that and yes i am
obviously saying this as a as a
representative of the private sector
here
you know you're you're you're small to
medium enterprises your your less mature
sectors are going to be very very
vulnerable to state affiliated state
sponsored or even state military cyber
attacks how do you work with them how do
you protect them
was this directed at a specific panelist
or you want something anybody who'd like
to respond does anyone want to jump on
this
michael any thoughts ahead
um
so yeah i have thought that this
question was not originally for me but
uh yeah at least
let's try
that's a good question of course
but um
the
i i think i don't have really a good
response so maybe i'm happy yes
i thought yeah go ahead erica um
so okay not to like plug layered cyber
deterrence again but what i like about
that uh that graphic that i showed um
illustrating sort of the the the role
but also the limits of sort of a cost
and position approach i think that's
where um better coordination between the
government and the private sector is
important right um
you know there are all these debates
about you know
who's responsible for securing what
parts of sort of the the broad uh you
know
the landscape of cyberspace right but um
you know
from a u.s government perspective right
there are sort of roles and
responsibilities that reside within the
federal government and roles and
private sector i think sort of radically
reshaping that architecture is not a
good idea but i do think that you know
this
underscores the importance of improved
you know i don't want to say information
sharing because it's you know a phrase
that we repeat ad nauseam but like
meaningful collaboration between the
government and the private sector
particularly the owners and operators of
critical infrastructure which i realize
leaves out this um small to medium-sized
firms most of the time that you
reference um but i think that you know
we've seen
from a u.s perspective the federal
government do a better job at sort of
recognizing that challenge and
recognizing that actions taken in and
through cyberspace by the military for
instance are not going to be perceived
by the private sector and yet the
private sector could suffer the
consequences potentially or the response
um because it's sort of the soft
underbelly of of the united states and
so doing a better job at sharing
indicators and warnings at um improving
collaboration um
at um you know
the department of homeland security cesa
the cybersecurity infrastructure
security agency within dhs has tried to
sort of stand up these entities right
now we have the joint cyber defense
collat collaborative that's meant to be
kind of a hub of collaboration to be
able to sort of pass um in some
instances um information that's gathered
by entities within the government
outside of cisa like
the dod or the intelligence community to
the private sector to enable them to
sort of improve their own defense
posture and resilience and so i think
we're getting there but it is it is a
concern and that's why it's tired to
talk about the multi-stakeholder model
and for information
sharing and collaboration but i you know
it's manifestly important to improve
those things it's hard
um it's hard to do within the united
states it's even harder to do when we
think about uh the reality that um the
private sector is not bounded by a
particular uh national or geographic uh
geographic uh
area uh but yeah i think the point
you're raising is exactly right and i
think that's why there has been um
greater and greater attempts to improve
collaboration i do think the challenge
though is with the small to medium end
size
firms less the sort of the big players
who are you know already kind of
participating in these government
government collaborative programs
we have time for one last question
question and we have an intensely eager
one on the front row again with a very
discreet knowledge thank you uh dr
bloomberg from certainly
i'm going to be practically annoying
with the question so i'm going to
paraphrase the question of the session
is
not if the offensive operation is best
defense but do we actually have the
capability to conduct the offensive
operations as a union or as a or as an
alliance now
we already know that the uh we have like
cyber defensive initiatives such as from
the european union we have the nato
rapid response team we have the united
states defend and uh hunt forward but
actually how do we harness this how do
we harness this capability and is this
actually when someone calls for help
how do we call for help and will the
nations who participate actually be able
to contribute to active cyber defense
not even talking about the offensive
operations or they will say increase of
crisis we're going to hold on to these
capabilities i'm i'm talking about the
current situation when any of the
alliance neighbors
allies can reach out to someone else and
request this capability and this is the
question to all of the panel i know this
is
not direct to any anyone particular
thank you
well we don't really have any
representatives from the alliance here
today but if
any one of you academics
from the us
or
academic researcher
feels compelled to answer this question
i'm
welcome to just share your thoughts
without clearly binding any countries to
anything
yeah let me just take a gander at this
and i'll start with nuclear policy
because why not right
um
in 1962 robert mcnamara secretary of
defense tried to interest the soviets
in separating counter force which is to
go after their
nuclear weapons from counter value
uh
in other words basically if the war
starts we're going to go after your
missiles we're not going to go after
your cities this way you don't go after
our cities because you realize what's
going to happen and we can settle the
nuclear war with a lot fewer people
being dead
two problems one the soviets didn't buy
it but the other problem was that the
french philosophy of nuclear weapon they
did not have enough nuclear weapons to
do counter force they could only do
counter value
so it turns out that even though in
conventional capability nato acted as
one in terms of nuclear capability they
all had separate policies and
establishments
same problem in cyber
right we talk as if
we're you know all for one and one for
all and we all collaborate but you're
talking as my colleague here observed
about that part of the defense
establishment that is most secret from
other folks
right and one of the ironies is that the
alliance that is strongest with the
united states in cyberspace is not nato
it's the five eyes
and two of those members are not in nato
okay
so
you have a problem in one part one part
of the party going off doing operations
that the other parts
other members of nato are not aware of
may not have approved of may raise
escalation issues
that they're sort of being taken along
for a ride for and being understandably
upset and it works the other way if
you're trying to modulate your cyber
offensive cyber war activities in order
to present a sort of consistent position
for the purpose of escalation control
and somebody from the alliance decides
to carry out a cyber attack that seems
to go beyond that
can you count on the other side saying
oh yeah this isn't the big country this
is just one of the small countries that
did it or will they have a tendency to
say
i can't tell the difference between them
and frankly
if i could it doesn't matter because
they're all one alliance i'm going to
respond to the worst cyber attack as
having set the level of escalation in
the conflict
which is the question i don't know how
to answer
which is a good point a way that that is
an excellent way to end a little bit
grim and a little bit a little bit uh
unclear
at this point i worry slightly about
keeping you guys all from the joys of
talon we're also glad you could make the
trip but first please join me in
thanking our panelists
you