good morning everyone
i hope you enjoyed the hospitality of
the cyclone yesterday night and you were
not crazy enough to drive to riga for an
iron maiden concert and get back so with
this those who were actually at the at
the cyclone dinner you already
experienced part of the session that
we're going to tackle so this is
bringing a historical events into the
virtual reality or addressing the
digital twin technology in the current
era so with this we keep moving and this
session is virtualized environment and
the available complexity with me i have
the panelists joe sid and ibars who will
going to
introduce their topics and explain their
field of research
before we start there are few house
rules
each
presenter has 20 minutes and after which
we're going to have 10 minutes of q a
within the q a everyone here present is
encouraged to ask questions as so as
well the other panelists are encouraged
to engage in the discussion with the
rest
without a further due
let's
keep moving
joe
is going to be the first one and he is a
phd student at the university of
plymouth and his work is focused on
exploring the digital twin technology
towards increasing dockyard's efficiency
thank you very much the crowd is yours
so to begin with i'm going to look at
the background of the site that i'm
working on which is hmnb devonport
that's her majesty's naval base
devonport which is in plymouth which is
in the south west of england
it's the largest naval base in western
europe
it has over 650 acres of land and four
miles of waterfront and employs over two
and a half thousand service personnel
and civilians
it's the largest energy consumer in the
area and possibly the entirety of the
city and it's one of three raw navy
dockyards in the uk
one of the main challenges for
digitization for this site is that it
was built in the 17th century which
means much of the infrastructure
has not been designed for digitization
it is home to the royal navy's
amphibious ships survey ships and half
of her frigates it has 15 dry docks
25 turtle basins and five basins for for
maintenance of those vessels
and also it has training facilities for
flag office sea training and also
submarine training
barracks that includes medical dental
facilities for those living on site and
also recreational facilities and
accommodation
so it's quite a large complex site to to
try and to optimize
so digital twin this is what i'm i'm
researching at the moment
and my understanding of digital twin is
that it's a virtual representation of a
physical entity now if you ask lots of
people what a digital twin is you'll
probably get lots of different answers
so let's name a few ibm say that it
accurately reflects a physical object
nvidia says it has to be a true to
reality simulation of physics and
materials
which has to be continuously updated
and then forbes has a similar
description to what i have given but
they all have the underlying
definition of that it is a virtual
representation of a physical entity
now what are we going to be doing we're
going to be
modeling the entirety of the dockyard
as a digital twin and that is going to
be for it for a number of purposes to be
able to understand what the current
limitations of the dockyard is and how
they can be improved
why are we doing it well that's twofold
first of all
the royal navy wants to know what they
can do better so we've got a an old
dockyard that can be improved we know it
can be improved by building a digital
twin we'll be able to find out specific
ways in which that can happen
and secondly due to the scale of the
site and complexity of the site
academically it's an interesting topic
because we're looking at a digital twin
of a large
large area with a completely different
goal to other twins because as the the
royal navy dot card is military as
opposed to commercial the goals of the
site are also completely different we're
not looking at trying to make as much
money as possible
we're trying to make sure that our
military assets are available as often
as we can
so what do we hope to achieve by the end
of this project we hope to have a
proof of concept
for how digital twins can benefit a
royal navy dockyard
which should then provide results as to
how
much
the the output the results of the
optimization of that twin
if implemented can actually save the doc
guard either money reduce carbon
emissions or improve develop
availability of vessels
so the digital twin specifically has
three key domains
first of all is the infrastructure which
looks at the buildings roads and
pathways and critical port
infrastructure on the site all of that
needs to be modeled
then we have utilities domain which
looks at communications
energy and water
and then the operational domain which is
asset tracking people and teams and
workload so each of those domains
contain a number of layers as i've just
just uh talked through and those layers
will all be individual models however
what makes this a digital twin is that
all of those separate models will be
based upon data from other
layers so we'll all be interconnected so
make a change in one layer that change
the effects of that change will be
visible in other layers
so all of that will be modeled together
to then give accurate results
so here's an example of how this could
be used if we simulate a power cut
that will be on the power layer of the
utilities domain
that will then be visible on the
infrastructure domain in the buildings
layer so one building may lose power now
one building that could have a few teams
working within that that would then
identify within the twin which teams
have lost their ability to to do what
they need to do on site
that will show the impact of that power
cut
additionally the people within that
building may be able to work elsewhere
however there may be critical network
infrastructure for example a an active
network switch in that building if that
goes offline then the communications
layer will show you where
people on site may lose connectivity and
then again other people may not be able
to do their day job so you'll be able to
simulate
outages
around the site from from maybe one
small outage
so the stages of development start from
modeling that's making sure that all of
the models we create are accurate to the
site
with the right level of abstraction of
data
then we need to analyze the site in its
current state looking at what the
potential limitations are
and also looking at um
where we can improve
and then finally we have optimization
which is finding solutions to those
problems and also problems that maybe
individual people on the site have
themselves they'll be able to input
those problems to find a solution
through optimization
so modeling what are the challenges of
modeling well first we have the data
collection being a 17th century site
some of the data
may be difficult to find or difficult to
gather so that is a really key problem
that needs to be overcome early on uh to
make sure we have data so i've started
with the communications layer because
that is a layer that has as much data as
i need at the moment but as i go forward
i'll need to find ways to collect data
that may not be as easy to gather
then we need to make sure that the
the data is accurate and relevant but
also that the model that's created is
accurate and relevant to the site there
is
a really key point with digital twins
that if the model isn't accurate the
results you get out will also
effectively be invalid because it's not
going to show you what the true state of
things are
so from this stage on its own it will be
beneficial to users on the naval base
because they will have access to
visualization of the current state of
all of those layers so if you're working
in in one key area you'll be able to use
the digital twin to find a visualized
way of representing that data so they
can complete their day-to-day job
slightly easier than current
next is analysis
so analysis is looking at identifying
vulnerabilities
specifically through single points of
failure that's the first area that i'm
looking at for identifying
vulnerabilities so that is looking at a
single point on the site that if that
point was removed has the greatest
impact over the sites there'll be
so many uh points within the site that
if you remove will have an effect almost
all of them but which one has the
greatest effect will be found out
through analysis and that'll look at
each layer and also look at the impact
across other layers
so across the priorities of the naval
base which are
primarily to improve availability of
vessels but then also we do want to
reduce
our expenditure and reduce our carbon
emissions
we will have a fitness score through the
analysis for each of those topics
initially that will just be an arbitrary
number but every change that is made
either through optimization or through a
manual change
those three
fitness areas will be scored so then we
can assess as to whether the solution is
better or worse for those we only want
to pursue solutions which have an
improvement on the priority for that
work
so the user with this stage will be able
to make minor changes to the data
monitor the impact on the fitness scores
and the purpose of that would be to aid
decision making if it's better then they
can go with that
but then finally we have optimization
which uses genetic programming
so using single objective optimization
just to solve the problem you've got a
key problem that needs to be solved
regardless of anything else
we can run an optimization algorithm to
find the best solution for that problem
which is
really good however that may have very
expensive costs for
other priorities of the naval base
so that is why the digital twin will
also look into multi-objective
optimization to then look at all of
those priorities together
where the main one is to solve the
problem we're trying to solve but also
if we can do that in a way that reduces
environmental impact and reduces the
total expenditure of the site then that
is a
bonus as well and that will produce a
selection of possible solutions
so the decision makers can consider
everything because sometimes it is
worthwhile to spend a bit more or have a
bit more carbon emissions if the end
result is going to be better but this
should give them all of the data they
should need to be able to make those
decisions
best for the for the decision that he's
making
so where am i now within the development
i'm right at the beginning
so i've modeled the communications layer
of the site
and
that is that is where i'm at at the
moment starting the analysis stage next
i have lots more data to collect uh to
be able to model the remainder of the
site to make it a digital twin at its
current state is just a it's just a
computer model it's not a digital twin
yet but that is where i'm going
to be able to run optimization
algorithms on on the site
other challenges i have being a military
site
is that uh all of the data that i'm
collecting for for the site is
confidential and can't be published
so that is a big
drawback from my phd research is that i
can't publish what i'm doing
so to go around that i've tried to
create artificial data that represents
something similar to to the site however
that has proved doing that uh
autonomously has proved quite difficult
because
automated data to design a network looks
nothing like a network
so what i've done
is i've created a set of data
which is much smaller than the dockyard
which allows it to look almost like a
network which has worked i do have that
data and i can publish that data however
it doesn't accurately reflect a real
life scenario so that is
not not ideal for this type of research
so i've been speaking around with other
ports
and i've found a third party that is
happy
to
to provide me all of the data that they
have and allow me to publish all the
data on their airport that is a
commercial port in the uk
they've asked to remain anonymous at
this point
but that will allow me to go forward
publishing all of the data from that
board while by while designing the same
digital twin for the raw navy which
remains confidential
so looking at what i've done so far
the image on the screen shows you a
a diagram of that network this is
artificial data it does not reflect a
real site
each of the the points is a node that
would be a building because at the
moment the communications layer is
building specific
and each point the size of the point is
how many neighbors come off that how
many
buildings that is connected to uh it's
not geographic so there's no no
coordinates there it's just based on
trying to make the image with as few
cross lines as possible
interacting with that you if you go to
one of the nodes you can see all of the
neighbors that are connected so for a
for the view of an individual user
trying to interact with their day-to-day
job
rather than trawling through a long
excel spreadsheet to try and find which
nodes are connected to to which
buildings
this would make it a lot more graphic
and being able to overlay this with a
physical satellite representation of the
site which would then
move the diagram to the correct
coordinates would then allow much easier
interaction from those end users
being able to see the neighbors uh
that's not all we need because often
there are many connections going between
the same two buildings if you look at
the edge you can see the actual id which
is affiliated to that final
uh that connection which will massively
help the end users using that
so that's very similar with
the other
utilities layers
so with power and water
they will be designed in a very similar
way
however looking back to the uh the
different layers that we'll be modeling
there'll be certain things that won't be
able to be modeled in this way so
buildings will be derived from the the
satellite imagery all the utilities will
be derived in this way but then looking
at the right hand side which was
operational
that is something that's going to be
very unique for each layer so first of
all we have asset tracking which is
arguably one of the easiest ways or best
ways that we can
actually derive results from this
digital twin because that will track all
of our infrastructure
and at
the end level it would be everything
from small items of
use all the way up to all the cranes and
port infrastructure
asset tracking will monitor everything
that that item is doing it will look at
when the engine's running when it's
actually in operation
the statistical analysis all of that of
all of that data should identify where
where where we're going wrong so if an
item is hired for two weeks but it's
only used for three of those days so
therefore an external item has to be
hired in and that is only going to be
that's also hide in for two weeks but
it's only used for a different set of
days
that is that is a waste of time
we could just use that same crane or it
could potentially be that another job
has to be put on hold because that item
is uh
is being used elsewhere it's hired but
it's not actually in use to be able to
look at that data will give us
information as to what is being used
and how we can improve prove things then
looking at people and teams that's going
to look specifically at where people
need to be working so some jobs
office-based jobs
can be done across the site or
potentially even remotely so they will
be they will be modelled but they will
have a clause that they can work
elsewhere so that is not a vital
failure if if that if they can't work in
their building
however other work has to be done in
that location
so if if one of those buildings go down
that will then identify that work cannot
be taken and it will not be going
forward
uh so i'm afraid i've finished a couple
of minutes early i hope that's not a
problem uh but i'd be happy to take any
questions if you have them
thank you take your seat and then we're
going to dive into the discussion
session
now when i read uh joe's paper initially
i felt he's trying to recreate a 90s
game transfer tycoon
we all loved playing back back then
however the level of complexity that
you're trying to bring in um
is fascinating currently at this stage
you're more playing with the digital
doppelganger versus digital twin uh and
you are trying to facilitate the
decision making process uh to make the
dockyard working more efficient now if
we look at the layers you're currently
working with the implementation of the
communication layer
uh a communication layer what components
have you already considered for
implementation and how how's it been
going with this one
so the communication there is looking
specifically at
where where the
buildings are in how they're
interconnected so it's looking at their
neighbors um to create that map
it does have other data included which
is uh sort of how many cables and
connections there are within each cable
and how many cables are going in the
same direction that's data that i can
use in the in the future but the the
implementation of that in the model is
uh is it's very much an analysis of
where how nodes are connected together
and it is a it's just a plain script
which i've written myself it's not
nothing uh
no no framework right when you're going
to
carry on with implementation further
implementation of the communication
layer and also other layers
how granular do you think you're going
if you're saying that you're going for
the buildings first the physical layer
buildings if you're going to target
physics rain everything that can
actually impact have a significant
impact on the dockyard functionality if
it's icy can the can the employees get
to the
to their work in the can the uh
cars drive within the
campus and if you're looking at the data
connectivity layer would you go and try
to emulate some network protocols that
are there as well or that is totally out
of the out of the decision-making
process uh it's definitely not out of
the decision-making process um
the idea of the digital twin that
finally if they implement this on the
site
as much as can be modelled with modeled
but within the scope of my project um
what i've done for the
for the communications layer at the
moment i'm going to leave that as it is
so that i can add much more
into the total digital twin which will
then allow me to to model everything as
a whole which will allow me to get the
results to monitor the impact before i
go back and add layers of abstraction
i understand i would like to take also
the questions from the uh from the
audience
i know it's early morning but uh
and the first bird is gabor
mike i got mike
so uh a question how do you plan the the
model quality assessment or the model
quality analysis if you are restricted
in the source data
so
i'm i'm within a team at the dockyard at
the moment uh the cis team
and
so all of the information and data i get
from the dockyard
i get through that team so i've got
those points of contact so any results i
derive initially i don't expect once i
first model something uh for it to be
fully accurate so that is going to be an
iterative approach with that team
to to work through the data that i get
to then to monitor the effectiveness and
then i can tweak the model until i get
something that they all think is is
relevant and then i'll see if there's
other
industry specialists on the site that i
can do final checks with oh excellent
thanks thank you
following the gabor's question so
are you going to collect also historic
data meaning that i mean you can't maybe
you can still collect these prehistoric
data
before starting before your uh research
or
you're going just to start at this point
collecting the data related to how the
dockyard operates what's the also the
the the traffic intensity how the
operations work there what's the network
load uh and so forth how are you going
to collect and what are the methods that
you're considering for the data
collection because you need to have a
decent model there yeah yeah absolutely
so
lots of the doc card as it currently
stands collects lots of data
as it is but it doesn't do much with
much with it at the moment they're all
all kept separate so i've got lots of
contacts that i'm looking to exploit to
collect that data and build into the
model
the future of the digital twin would be
to have that data collection automated
through iot sensors spread around the
site um because that's always going to
make it as accurate as it can be have it
having real-time data um but for the
initial model it will be based on static
data as it is now so
in my current stage any data i can get
my hands on will go into the model
where as and when i can get updated
versions then obviously i'll update but
at my initial stages of development i
just need to get as much data as i can
together
um any other panelists do you have a
question sid go ahead go ahead i have a
question um so with the recent
events which have happened in
like global shipyard industry and the
docking industry especially in the
united states and we have seen the
impact of what can happen when
when a critical infrastructure like that
gets choked so
how do you plan to extend this work or
make it transferable enough to be
applied to dockyards which do not
conform to the model that you are
focused on
how flexible will this trend be that's
that's a really good question so i think
because
i'm in the unique position now that i'm
developing the
the digital twin for the dockyard but
also for a commercial port
there is going to be inherent
flexibility within that because i want
one singular
model to be able to take in either data
data set so it's going to have
it's going to be built in with the
priorities for for certain things that
will relate to commercial and also
military
within the same model because i don't
want to develop two completely separate
digital twins for the same project
so that flexibility that will be built
in there will allow it to be
transferable between
certain things
however that is is all going to be
specific to the maritime environment in
this state
so it's going to be ports or
or dockyard right thanks right
one of the questions that we have is
also would this model be applicable so
something beyond just the dockyards can
you apply it to anything else and with
yes that what would be
yeah absolutely so the digital twin
technology is absolutely applicable to
to almost anything um the model that i'm
creating the digital twin i'm creating
is specifically for
uh
the naval base down at devonport
but also my third party port so it's
going to have a bit of flexibility built
in there
but additionally the technology that
that that is based upon um would would
absolutely be able to use for other
other sort of uh
places of a similar scale so an airport
for example either military or or
commercial uh would be another
application for this technology are you
going for a very complex
complex issues here
we have we have a question look
actually i had several questions but you
asked many of them
so i'm left with only two and um the
first one then is for you bb did you
really drive to riga last night for a
rock concert
i did yes there's a couple of people in
this conference that are i imagine them
like terminators like machine that just
keep going non-stop and people is one of
them okay so the question is for you
joseph congratulations great research
are you going to publish this model
are you going to make it available
do you believe that other people can
contribute to it to enrich the semantics
of it yeah absolutely um so
due to the model being um
the model specifically for the port
the third party port all of that
including the data i plan to publish
obviously with their permission from the
data from results side
i plan to publish everything and make
make the actual model the code for the
model open source i was speaking to
someone at one of the events earlier
this week and they've offered me some
access to one of their github their
company's github repositories for some
some modeling system uh so i absolutely
want to
sort of return that back to the open
source world
and i promised to the the panel that
you're not going to be the only one in
the hot seat here uh dodging all the
questions so um i have a question to the
rest of the panelists as well well i'll
start with the eye bars and the uh the
same question will go to the sid uh and
this is purely theoretical you don't
have to provide me already the working
details how would you tackle
this issue if you would come up with an
idea of
virtualizing or recreating a digital
twin for a naval dockyard or an airport
how would you approach this
[Applause]
actually this is a difficult question
for me why because i am not interested
in the shipyard however i
many of times i
entered to shipyard because i was a
safer and during this period i saw that
the one of the most important
issue is the human factor
and
you need to simulate also a human factor
in the shipyard as well and you can see
that
many incidents
is caused by the human factor and in the
digital timing maybe you can also
mention about the human factor right
thank you so do you have any take on
this yeah i'll pick off from where i was
left so the human factor is one of the
most interconnected and interdependent
pieces of any complex system like a
shipyard so modeling that modeling how
trade unions work modeling how the
shipyard
labor unions work that has a huge impact
on how the trans how the load gets
transferred through the ship through the
docks so that would be definitely one
thing which needs to be modeled and the
second thing is i would look at how much
fidelity do i want to go into the twin
with so
it so digital twin when people say it's
a digital twin it's either referring to
a digital model
which means it's approximating some part
of that physical process or it's a
digital shadow which means it's getting
inputs from a physical actual
operational system and then trying to
model the future states or it's a
completely bi-directional digital twin
which talks uh to and from this physical
process so
so that's so these are the three popular
like ways of differentiating between how
how accurate do people want to get with
these technologies so maybe we can start
with a very simple approximation like
game simulators or shipyard tycoon or
something like that that can be the
first step but as we move to like much
more real-world use cases you will need
to have this to and fro communication
between the twin and the physical
ships right thank you and i think joe
already mentioned that he would like to
extend this with the with the sensor
technology we have a question here from
the audience please yes hi uh verenika i
will not stand up yesterday night was a
bit uh much
um
so question to the three of you
potentially rather to the two of you is
how would that look like if you would
apply it to a mobile
uh station let's say so speaking about
satellites um how would you
what would be your way let's say to what
would be the best approach is to model
um the links with the satellite let's
say
and then speaking about security
concerns obviously you can
use the digital twin probably quite well
to do some pen testing to do you know uh
to find out where security gaps would
lie
um
so yeah write a general question what is
your take on that how could you best
implement uh digital twin on a satellite
we'll start with eye bars please if you
haven't if you have any take on this of
course uh yes this is
for
for example autonomous ship for the
autonomous ship the the security cyber
security is one of the most important
concerns and for the digital tv this is
like a digital twin uh and nowadays
there are some technology
systems are developing for example with
us technology and so through the with us
technology there are some encryptions
will be possible most probably
and
of course
not only during the attack after the
attack we should be carried by the uh
researchers this is another story
actually i mean uh cyber incident
handling
and
still ongoing process actually now as i
remember the third version of the gps
for example was started to be
tested and
against some
cyber attacks like jamming or spfing's
will be more resilience
but probably for the digital times it
will be also useful
right
sid i will save you because you will be
our next speaker but
before you are in the hot seat i wanted
to ask a
transition question to you joe
we're going to talk about the exercises
cyber exercises would you say
and briefly would you say that your
model could be integrated in one way or
another into these cyber exercises
well i'm by by no means an expert in in
cyber exercises but i i can see
the use case for for digital twin
technology with
those you those uh exercises having a
real life asset uh or environment being
modeled and then having that model
visualized for for the white hat for the
white team um i i can see the benefit
then i definitely think with with some
yes editing it would be right be useful
right thank you with this
you can start relaxing now and start
preparing for the questions to the rest
of the of the panelists with this i
would like to welcome on the stage sid
he's a researcher at the itra center for
research in cyber security at the
singapore university of technology and
design his work is focusing on cyber
physical systems and exercises related
to those
the crowd is yours sure and i will
answer that question about satellites in
my talk because it's extremely related
to everything that we go uh we go into
with cyber physical systems so as you
can see on the slide the theme of this
conference and the theme of like living
a long healthy life is to keep moving
and the way people have represented that
in the digital sphere is this um
cellular automat automaton which is
called the conveys game of life so it
follows very simple rules
and that those simple rules let it just
glide through the cyberspace and this
the reason i bring that up is because
this became the hacker emblem for
cypherpunks in the early 90s which is
where the whole field of cyber security
began and now we are at a state where
hackers
or problem solvers in general are not
just people who are underground but
people like you and me who work with the
governments every day and try to protect
our countries so with the spirit of
hacking and problem solving we'll start
the talk which is about the design of
cyber physical exercises and
i am a researcher at itrest as bb just
described
and
for more context i've been advised by
professor aditya mathur since 2016 so
that's the last six years of my life
and i've gotten the freedom to explore
like the whole broad range of emerging
technologies and that's what we will get
into in this particular talk
and that comes from like uh like a
background in different fields so i was
i've interned at the indian space
research organization designed things at
the mit media lab worked with financial
infrastructures at goldman sachs and
more importantly for this talk two
experiences with the google summer of
code where i worked on simulating a
martian rover like a mars rover and the
human factors involved in communication
with astronauts and rovers as well as
organizing complexity weekend which is
an event we do twice a year with the
best complexity applied complexity
scientists across the world this has
really led me to think how to best think
about cyber physical systems which are a
much more complex system than just cyber
systems so
if you look at the book that you
received with the
cycon package you'll find our paper on
page 347
but you do not need to read the paper to
attend this talk i assume no background
and yeah it will be a very gentle
introduction to everything so
so yeah
this has been repeated this message has
been repeated throughout this
event in which we started on the
workshop day with a very relevant
like talk and preparation by
members in ccdcoe so this
talk was about trust in cyber exercises
and the future vision for nato as they
go forward and this talk uh especially
focused on
the importance of cultural communication
the importance of
like interoperability between countries
the importance of collaboration over
competition or cooperation and concepts
like that so it was a really good look
at that from both a strategy point of
view and then it was followed by another
excellent talk which some of you might
have attended by
by dr max meads and that was an analysis
of the lock shields exercise and this
paper is the first paper in the book
that you received so this is the role of
military cyber exercises and the case
study for lock shields and this was
particularly very exciting for me
because this went into the history of
locked shields and how exercises evolve
we just assume that people
like gabor and the team they just come
gather gather around and organize an
event like this
but the history that has gone into
events like this predates like a decade
back so an exercise like lock shield
started
like soon after there were cyber attacks
on estonia in 2007 and the first event
that was conducted was the baltic cyber
shield and 2012 onwards
it's been called the log shields and we
at singapore have followed like a very
similar path which is very serendipitous
because these two
series of events happened independently
and now they are in a sort of
interdependence with each other so
after doing and conducting all these
exercises
there's one thing we have realized that
the role of cyber exercises in
increasing our resilience
is extremely clear but it's certainly
not enough and i'll get into why
this is because traditional cyber
security is no longer enough you see on
your screen that there's a whole
a range of attacks which are purely
cyber attacks then there's a whole bunch
of attacks which are purely physical
attacks
which which the world is very
good at planning and strategizing and
thinking about since the last century
or even the last thousand plus years now
we are at a space where cyber and
physical are no longer like independent
things are systems around us like from
the smart watch that i'm wearing to the
phones that you have in your hands they
are no longer just cyber or just
physical they are completely a new thing
of their own and when people say the
real world they usually mean the
physical world which is also no longer
true most of our lives are spent in the
digital world most of the decisions that
countries take happen in the digital
world and any manipulation with that
digital world has physical world
consequences so when i mention real
world in the talk i refer to the cyber
physical and not just the physical
so you see some examples of cyber
physical systems and just like the
question you asked about satellites they
are also very
cyber physical systems they have some
capability to maneuver through space
they have sensors and actuators on board
they have
network links which can be compromised
or hacked so anything from pacemakers
which people have in their hearts which
can be controlled by bluetooth and can
be hacked and you can essentially
like
like kill someone as a result if
if the pacemaker has an anomaly or if
the pacemaker has been compromised by
malicious actors
two like large-scale country scale water
treatment systems
everything is driven by these
communications which happen between
sensors controllers actuators computers
and this has large consequences in the
future and this has been very clear in
the attacks that we have seen in the
last decade and more so in the last
couple of years with the florida water
treatment attack and the colonial
pipeline attack these attacks may have
origin may have their origins in the
cybersphere but they had large
consequences in the physical sphere
so this became very clear in 2016 when
nato recognized cyberspace as one of the
domain of operations
and
this is because we had the four domains
of warfare sea space air and land and
then
cyber was introduced by a lot of
countries in that area and then here you
see like weaponized social media and
cultural engagement now this is
something where memes play a huge role
and things which we have seen play a
huge impact in global elections as well
as day-to-day dialogue now what happens
is that cyber physical warfare is the
next step so cyber physical defense and
cyber physical exercises are obviously
the next step for us to think about
and this is why it's important to frame
or define this term first
so when the attack has its origin in the
cyber domain in the information domain
it's purely a cyber attack if the impact
is also felt in the cyber domain so this
can be something like just getting
someone's passwords or just messing with
your friend and changing their password
on their phone
but if the attack is purely in the
physical domain and also has an impact
in the physical domain such as me just
drilling a hole in a tank in a water
tank that's a purely physical attack now
when we go to
origin in the cyber domain and an impact
in the physical domain that's when it
becomes a cyber physical attack so
this can be me just blowing a satellite
up in space or attacking a remote water
plant sitting here in estonia and
causing a flood in my water test bed in
singapore this is a cyber physical
attack and this is the most popular
style of attack that is going on today
which we are not yet prepared but we
have begun to think about and lastly
there's this very under appreciated uh
under explored area called the physical
cyber attacks which we won't get into
but it's important to mention so these
attacks can have their origin in their
physical domain like me just
coming with a hammer and blowing the
servers apart
so this uh this has an impact in the
cyber domain that the disks might get
damaged my processors may not work as
expected or i cause like changes in the
voltage and that causes impact on the
computer
infrastructure of this of the entire
facility
or a very popular example is signal
jamming i can just jam the signals off
like all the communication devices here
and that has an origin in the physical
domain but an impact on the cyber domain
so these are
things which we can use to explore the
whole range of cyber physical attacks so
it's just important to explore what a
cyber physical system really is and very
simply it's anything with a sensor with
an actuator and with some controllers
which help to understand the physical
world around us
and then manipulate that world
based on the logic that we have just
come up with so that
that manipulation is decided by
controllers or computers so these can be
very simple things like arduino
microprocessors which kids use to
program simple things to like
even very advanced things like
controlling nuclear plants or water
plants so all of this is done by a
supervisory controller which takes in
inputs from all these
smaller controllers and that's why it's
called the supervisor and popularly it's
known as the scada or the supervisory
control and data acquisition unit so the
abbreviations in this field are scada
plc which is the programmable logic
controllers these two are the only ones
you need to be aware of for this talk
and the reason the attack surface or the
points of attack increase is because
each of these things exists both in the
physical realm as well as the
cybersphere and all the letters small
letters that you see here are points of
attack these can be some things like
supply chain attacks which start with
anomalies in the micro chips itself
which we may not be prepared for right
up to like man in the middle attacks and
all different sorts of network attacks
so
these things which can be at the scale
of sensors or actuators or at the
broader scale of control devices or
utility devices these have broad
consequences and this is why it's
important to understand the difference
between information technology i.t
versus ot operational technology which
is what industrial control systems and
cyber physical systems are all about
and this is why ccdcoe has been on top
of this since the last many years and
most of you would have seen this if you
have
attended cr14 or the cyber ranges
in lock shields anytime
so
for what does it mean for all of you as
people representing different countries
these are our critical infrastructures
and all of them are
essentially controlled by these cyber
physical systems increasingly
to take an example closer to home these
are singapore's critical information
infrastructures and
to counter that to protect these systems
there is a whole of society defense
approach which is called total defense
and digital defense was one of the
categories which was added in the recent
years but since society is this
interdependent complex being between
technology economics culture and policy
it's important to essentially understand
the interplay between all of these
things and come up with strategies to
protect cyber attacks and cyber physical
attacks
so this talk is mostly about keeping
calm and cyber exercising and
introducing that as like a cultural
practice among all critical
infrastructures and countries around the
world and
the paper will go into like six years of
cyber physical exercises and the
exercises included are these ones so
there's one exercise which we conduct
every year at itrest in singapore and
that's called the critical
infrastructure security showdown or ciss
then we take uh and transfer our
learnings from locked shields which is
an exercise conducted by ccdcoe and it's
a blue team defensive uh exercise and we
have been taking part we we were in the
log shields 2020 planning
events and we have taken part in 2021
and 2022 which just concluded a couple
months back and crossroads in which uh
we met bb for the first time and that
was like an eye-opening experience for
training red teams and the importance of
these two exercises independently and
as a whole was very enlightening for us
and
also for the organizers of the exercise
because they
introduced a water system which is a
special system for these exercises for
the first time so
so yeah all of this was built on more
theoretical foundations which started in
2015 where we had the same uh like test
beds open at a much larger scale um in
the future years so that was called
sci-fi systems week or
special systems
or
cyber physical systems special systems
week so
yeah this is the tv wall of ccdcoe which
is used in lock shields and different
exercises and you see our human machine
interface or 24 blue teams here 24
countries essentially or teams of
countries
trying to defend a water treatment
system and the reason they are trying to
do this is because attackers usually
think in terms of networks and graphs
and the relationship that different
components have how is my tank connected
to a wall how is my
network link connected to a satellite
how is my um shipyard connected to like
the human who will be uh using who will
be driving uh and using the truck to
transport
the
the load so defenders instead have been
traditionally thinking in terms of lists
can i install a firewall with a list of
rules and try to protect this link this
link this link whereas attackers will
always think uh in terms of like
networks and graphs and they will be
always be one step ahead because they
have like a different view of the entire
system so if we want to be good
defenders we have to think about how
things are related and we do that um at
itrest with examples like this so this
is essentially any cyberphysical system
and the red devil emoji is essentially
points of attack which can be
network attacks between links
and
that's why it's important for us to
monitor each of these points
so the broader thesis of that is we have
to monitor all the attack points as a
good defender and then visualize these
the security and operations and safety
conditions in a very uh accessible
interface not just for technical
operators but also strategists and
policy makers so
this is what we have been doing at swot
which is secure water treatment testbed
at itrest and we
have a whole bunch of sensors such as
this flow meter which measures the flow
of water and an actuator and these
things look um like this when
when seen from a like computer graphical
user interface and uh the reason these
things look like something straight from
the 90s is because there has been no
major innovation in like design and user
experience in this field so what we have
done is we have come up with like
modifications to these
hmis or human machine interfaces and
added detectors and
more technologies to make it more
obvious for operators to understand if
there's an anomaly or an attack going on
and we have been doing that not just for
water treatment but
different test beds such as water
distribution
internet of things and an electric power
test bed all of these which will be used
in exercises and have been used
so this started with
an event back in 2015 called the sci-fi
week or the secure cyber physical
systems week and we wrapped up last year
with ciss 2021 where we collected 85
hours of data
which was which is not
it does not seem like a lot but that was
multiple red teams attacking throughout
the week and we had one more than a
terabyte of data in the form of packets
collected and
0.32 gb of operational technology data
and we have opened up these data sets
for anyone to access once you request
from the itres website and the
distribution for that has been something
that you see on the screen so it's a
very balanced red teaming blue teaming
exercise with a few judges and technical
staff from the green team and lock
shields has a very similar model and it
has been interesting to observe the
similarities and differences between the
way exercises can be conducted and the
reason we do
we have such a balanced
way of approaching this is because we
want to capture all the
aspects of the nist framework or the
nist framework which essentially helps
us describe the security posture of any
critical infrastructure so it's
important to not just identify assets
but also protect them detect against any
anomalies or attacks respond to these
attacks and then recover from these
attacks to ensure that the security
safety and service of your
infrastructure as well as the people and
the operations is preserved
so we do that with a whole bunch of
technologies which we won't get into in
this paper but you can definitely come
to our booth after the talk to learn
more about it but the idea is that you
need a holistic set of tools and
technologies and procedures
to essentially counter that because
attackers are getting smart at every
step of this skill chain so if some of
you are familiar with the miter attack
framework
this is an easier representation of that
which is
like a very recent pyramid called the
techniques tactics techniques and
procedures pyramid which goes into
increasing levels of detail like what
command was launched to what strategy
did the attacker have more broadly and
this leads us into more of a purple
teaming mindset which is something
that's inspired from both the red team
as well as the blue teams in which you
act both as a blue team and the red team
depending on
what area needs more attention and once
you do all these things once you
understand the state of
the system through not just attack but
also defense you lead to a more secure
design and this
help leads us into the mitre playbook in
which you identify and hold an ipc or an
initial planning conference then a main
planning conference then you conduct the
exercise through something like partners
run in lock shields and then the final
exercise itself
for us it has looked something like this
so if this is your first time conducting
a exercise you can read more about it in
the paper so it's steps which are
mentioned here such as communicate and
coordinate implement green team systems
implement it and ot protocols create a
digital twin if you need to provide a
database then design the human machine
interfaces design and develop attacks
for red teams implement anomaly
detection and create test plans and
update the code so
this has helped us understand the
increased importance of these techniques
tactics and procedures not just across
twins the importance of digital twins
but also user experience detectors and
the need for protectors or safety
instrumentation systems so you might
have seen just four names on the paper
but none of this would be possible with
an entire village of people who have
supported us
in this journey including people here at
ccdcoe so so your thanks to all of you
and this all started in 2019 when uh
ccdcoe also visited dietris for one of
our exercises uh in
before before covid so this was cis 2019
and it was a very proud moment for us
when our blue team systems the hmi
are were represented in lock shields for
the first time and one last thing before
i wrap up the talk ciss 22 is happening
later this year and this will be the
first time in which we'll have three
systems not just one but three systems
interconnected for red teams and blue
teams to
play against so yeah that's the talk if
you want to know more about
the work at itrest or me you can just
take a picture of that and reach out or
talk to us at the booth outside or after
the talk that's right thank you thank
you sid
you got a very condensed and archived
version of the information he has a lot
of things to uh to tell so make sure you
visit his uh booth and talk to him and
also the rest of the i trust crowd
uh when looking at the crowd during your
presentation i've been on the other side
as well this is just
gabor invited me to sit in this chair
but i saw a lot of people taking
pictures of your slides meaning that
they do have some importance in in there
so
although the water is a common theme in
this
in this session this panel although you
might not know about it we have
shipyards we have water what are the
purification distribution systems and
eyebrows will talk about the water as
well
however i want to just to slightly dive
deeper you mentioned the concept of the
digital twin and digital shadow in your
specifically this came from you
and how is digital twin or digital
shadow understood specifically in your
uh exercises that you do
yeah that's a great question so
when we started thinking about um like
how do you even implement a complex
system like a six stage water treatment
plant the first step was not to like
model every physical process itself but
to take readings from an actual
operational water plant which which is
the physical test bed that we built and
then input that into like a visualizer
like a virtual reality uh kind of a 3d
visualization which people can just
understand and remotely
observe and operate remotely if they
want to so that's more of a digital
shadow in which we take inputs from
from an operational system and it's
essentially just shadowing the actions
of the of the physical system then
professor aditya matru who is in the
audience here he started work on
implementing the digital twin in which
what happens when you want to provide
your test bed or infrastructure to not
just one team one blue team but 24 blue
teams you cannot provide one physical
test bed to 24 blue teams to attack at
the same time or defend it at the same
time because there will be conflicts um
like there will be priority conflicts as
well as many other operational issues
with that so for that we need a digital
uh version of the plant or the test bed
or a purely um like replicable um purely
extendable
virtualizable instance of the plant
which i can deploy not just on my own
computer but on the cloud for any
educational institution to use for any
government to use or for
an exercise like lock shields where 24
blue teams play together so
so yeah that's why it was important in
the last couple of years to develop not
just
the shadow but as well as
like model those physical process like
how does the formula for flow which
takes into account gravity and all these
concepts from physics apply to this
to this digital world and then also
model the network traffic and accurately
represent um industrial protocols like
opc ua which is used popularly
increasingly being used in all critical
infrastructures so how do we re how do
we make it such that attackers or
defenders cannot tell the difference
between the actual operational real
physical thing um or the real cyber
physical thing which is the digital twin
right so yeah right thank you i'm going
to take also the questions from the
audience if there is anyone
look look oh i was pointing pointing at
you but it's actually luke
so yeah okay first of all
uh
sorry go ahead
okay so uh this uh
this panel is recorded and just to bite
some click
for us i've been taking part in log
shoots for four times five times and uh
as a green teamer
i have never defended any system never
attacked any system
and i always have the question how to
how to defend the system against
red teams i do not know but now i have a
chance to ask how to defend your digital
twin in
in lock shields against the red teams
because
this is the this is the aim i think that
we have to to serve
thanks yeah firstly that's an excellent
question because we always approach
things with the
mindset of an attacker which is great
like offensive security is how you find
weaknesses or holes in any system but
the next step is how do you harden these
systems how do you plug these holes and
essentially stop future attacks from
happening so most of the practices that
people have learned in the cyber space
which is information security they still
apply because the points of entry of
most of these attacks are still
like cyber security strategies that
attackers use so these can be simple
things
like hardening your firewalls
understanding that there's no
like ports open which shouldn't be open
and things like that and then
understanding is there any operational
or process based weakness in the system
like is is it possible that if i just
overflow a tank in stage one it will
have cascading consequences in stage
four now this is something new which
operational technology defenders have to
learn
what is the process like so when a blue
team blue team participant approaches an
it system they have a very standard
playbook
in which they have like these six steps
to follow is the firewall okay is the
port working fine are the services
configured correctly and things like
that but when they approach
an operational test bed it's a different
like bag of tricks for every operational
system or at least like different
classes of tricks because every fluid
based system is different like water oil
all these systems they have similar
behavior because they are all liquids
essentially but when you are defending
an electric uh grid or power system you
cannot be that relaxed with your defense
strategy because any attack happens in a
millisecond and you need to have
different
strategies to counter against that so we
are still in that phase in this whole
community in which we have to come up
with like a better playbook for blue
team systems and there's already efforts
in that direction in red team it's
called the mitre framework in which
that's a very very easy to understand
approach to approach red teaming for
blue teaming we have to come up with
something
that can be like a theme for a futures
icon right thank you for the answer yeah
luke yeah uh my question is about the
the physics of things so uh we also
include uh plcs in in our exercises and
uh i think it was four years ago we did
the gas pipeline and we ended up uh
mimicking several sort of pipelines and
valves and sensors and the attack was
against the uh the plc and we ended up
uh realizing that we have to essentially
model the physics so pv equals nrt and
all this stuff but even more complex
because if we started to shut the valve
here how fast would the pressure drop
over there over 40 kilometers say so all
of this you and if you want to do the
simulation correctly then you've got to
model the physics yeah and and then
you're in an exercise you want to run a
test run of it you want to make sure the
physics are good so but you don't want
to wait two days for for events to
happen so how do you deal with uh
collectively building up the physical
model of reality to allow the use of a
digital twin uh in an exercise
firstly that's an excellent question
that is an extension of what bb asked me
like why do we need a digital twin we
need it because we can't wait
a day to replicate the actions that
actually take a day in a digital twin
you can
essentially simulate uh an ear of plant
behavior in a day or you can just speed
the digital twin hundred times um and
just essentially see what uh actions
take place in a plant throughout the day
so this uh can be modeled not just by
physics but also like chemistry like in
our water
system we have ph sensors conductivity
sensors and all the chemical processes
which need to be modeled by chemical
equations so these physical systems are
mostly dependent on time and because we
have the like privilege to play with
time in the digital space which we do
not in the physical space digital twins
become this very exciting area where we
can essentially forecast which what will
happen if these initial conditions are
configured and i'm setting the twin to
run at 100 times the speed it's like
watching a movie at 1.5 x 2 x if you are
short on time so that really helps in
not just reconnaissance after an attack
takes place but also um like forecasting
what will happen in the future and
predicting the consequences yes so this
is very good but uh what about the
framework to do this are you aware
because i mean you you're so much to be
modeled is there some kind of standard
was that your question
are there standards in here is there a
plug-in play where i can just come in
with an equation or something and then
model some part of it yeah definitely so
yeah professor aditya can describe that
in a lot more detail so you can meet him
after after the talk but i'll give you
the tldr short version of that which is
uh that when we were building this test
bed we knew how the
reactions and equations uh were modeled
because we had to build the physical
thing
like as a whole and all these
programmable logic controllers they take
into account these equations when they
have to decide on the logic like if the
water is low if the pump is off if the
valve is closed these things have to uh
happen so when deci designing any such
physical test bed all these equations
are considered so it's the same
equations which are then converted in a
programmable
like logical form and represented that
way so the framework comes from like
systems design which is used for
constructing these test beds as well
and it varies from plant to plant right
i will as a moderator i'll have to put
an end to this unfortunately this is a
good discussion but we have to honor the
time when we have to move onwards
however please do
visit them at the itrest booth and
torture them more
347 exactly
unfortunately and now
and now for some something completely
different still staying on the water
theme i welcome on stage i bars he is a
phd student and a research fellow at
norwegian university of science and
technology
oh he has a very long experience uh
working with the
in even in the ship
engine room and also on the shore so
please the crowd is yours
thank you for the introduction bibi
marhaba
hello thank you for joining us today
i will start my presentation immediately
i will talk about our
papers published a couple of months ago
by the journal of marine science
engineering
and
we were i am not alone for this paper we
wrote this paper together with
associate professor vasilisky carlos and
also professor socrates casicas
the title of our paper is towards a
cyber physical range for the integrated
navigation system
what is the purpose of this paper we try
to understand the requirements of a
testbed for the integrated navigation
system what's that in circuits of
navigation system
it is a system and combines the
information receiving from
different components such as as gps
actors and others
to improve the safe navigation for
conventional vessels
and it includes six tasks these are
detailedly
described by the international maritime
organization
with some circulars
and the requirements for the collision
avoidance and route monitoring is
totally mandatory for an ins some of the
requirements of the navigation control
data and alert managements are
mandatory again
and root planning and navigation
citations and data display these
requirements for such tasks are optional
our research consists of two parts in
the first part we investigated the
integrated navigation systems in
different aspects such as components
sub-components services communication
protocols interfaces dependencies and
connections data and data flow
we find a basement for this resort
because each manufacturer has different
viewpoints some class requirements has
different uh requirements
that's why we selected the imo
requirements because it is the
gut of the maritime
and to access the rules current rules
and regulations we use the imo vega
database offered by the international
maritime organization and dnv
in the second part of our research
we look at the bridge testbeds in the
literature in different dimensions such
as capabilities and functionalities
hardware components monitoring and
management tools simulation and
emulation tools architectural models
research analysis comparison of test
band and potentiality for cyber security
of attachments and we made a
systematic literature review to reach
out to relevant
publications in the literature
and finally we found 16 publications in
the literature between the 2014 and
2020. before the 2014 there were no
publications
regarding the british test paths and
finally we combined our extracted
knowledge with the paper off towards a
cyber physical range for the integrated
navigation system however in this
presentation you will take more than
this paper
firstly we look at the components
however international maritime
organization doesn't have a component
list for an ins because there are
several factors such as the size of the
vessel as a volume or as a lens or a
navigation zone that's why we look at
the relevant circulars relevant
conventions and we try to find the
components as many as possible and
finally we find 25 components developed
by developed for different proposals
such as positioning such as to receive
methodological information
or heading information
and then we look at the sub components
imo defines only the performance
criterias actually they don't interested
in how it works typically and for
example actors act as an electronical
chart and we divide into two groups as a
hardware and software and hardware
monitoring it processor in it and
controlling it
software electronical chart active
software and operating system of course
you can go deep
more deep however
for us it was adequate
and services service means functions and
we look at the
imr requirements again to define each
component for one of them is ecosander
is to measure and
give the reliable information
about the depth of the water under the
kill under the westerly amine
communication protocols vessels are
communicate uh with other vessels and
sure through the different
uh protocols through the satellite for
example or to do some antennas and
another story is actually how the
companies communicate with each other
interfaces there is no any interface
list for
in terms of the international maritime
organization that's why we look at the
manufacturer brochures and we found some
interfaces such as ethernet port or usb
port or some ports for the serial
communication
dependencies we reviewed all performance
criterias performance standards of the
ima for each components
and
for example for the radar we found that
it is depends on gyro compass or
transmission heading device ais epfs is
this electronic position fixing system
actually it is uh
like gnss system or aileron system
and speed and distance measuring
equipment
and finally we reach out that
seven components depends on different
components
produced data everybody knows that gps
uh give us a position information
however for the international maritime
organization it is not adequate
according to the international maritime
organization gps must provide also time
information
cpt information speed our grant or
course information course over grant
and finally we made a model for an ins
and in this model you can see different
uh locations for example monkey island
it is the roof of the vessel actually
or the bridge
is the center bridge and with wings and
what about under kill there are some
transducers also we try to show some
communication protocols between the
terrestrial system between the satellite
system we would like to show the
communication protocols between the
vessels vessel to vessel
and we would like to show the position
of some components for example some
antenna units or
magnetic compass are in the
monkey island but there's some
microphones is the starboard side for
side wall side and the outside
then
we look at the bridge test in the
literature and we found that two bridge
test beds are available in the
literature uh
they are developing for performance
tests of the components to develop new
technologies and to make a risk
assessment and one of which is
recognized by the ilr i will mention
about what
it is
the testbeds are mobile designed as a
mobile or fix it
real components or mimi compo mimic
sensor data can be used
and some tools for the monitoring or 3d
creations
it is also possible
ayala ayala is the one of the most
important maritime organizations in the
world and it is recognized by the
international maritime organization it
is granted with consultative societies
and emer bridge has pat emery time
integrated reference platform developed
by oldenburg universe in germany
recognized by
the iola however it is not used for the
cyber security studies
they have a fixed platform it's a really
large container with some antenna units
there is another container what's
smaller one however it is it offers
again the mobility for example in this
photo you can see that this container is
are
on deck and service
also they can move their test beds
with some aluminium bags
another test patch is developed by the
hyundai
when i
uh use the real components
on vessels in service
what is the drawbacks for our
researchers to find a vessel
because
maritime sector is a conservative sector
and they they are not open for the
research or for uh
collaboration cooperations
collaborations and however for hyundai
it was not difficult because
they
construct ships and also they operate
ships and also they develop some
technologies and for a technology
developed by them
they use a real vessels
and here you can see their
schematic diagram their test environment
as you can see there are some real
components on board ships such as ais
radar gps and other real marine
components
of course you can use also some
simulations in your test beds for
different proposals one of them is
environment what is the environment
firstly
you can
you can need a geographical position
geographical map and also you need
weather conditions you can create some c
conditions you can make some scenarios
with them
and traffic simulations you need to
create some you need to put some vessels
which kind of vessels tankers containers
dry cargo vessels which one
and embedded simulator it is regarding
the movement of the vessel it is like
through the starboard side port side or
to both side or outside like this
you can stimulate the behavior of the
vessel with anybody simulator and sensor
simulations of course sensor simulations
means iis simulation gps simulations
anamator simulations and others
you can create some virtual components
of what is for example for the main
propulsion system or thruster system
some steering system what is the benefit
of the virtual
controls
you can carry it easy
also maybe you can use a tesla one and
you can occupy this song with several
components such as a system some cameras
some
weather sensors and you can transmit the
collected data through a
router to your net to your lap
we tested the bridge command is an open
source software actually it was first
time used by the email bridge
and
we found that
it is it acts like a real ship network
of course it is too limited however
it can be usable somehow and also you
can combine it with
some
chip controller units as well
and another software we tested
nba simulator it is
it actually broadcasts more
ship network
however visualization is limited or
limited to compared to bridge comment
opencpn is an electronic chart is used
by the amateur cifers
and also some
ship pilots
however you can connect your real
components or you can use some ma
simulator or bridge comment to this
software and you can
take the nba messages you can collect
the enemy messages you can see the
reaction of the
simulators in the open cpn
another one during your research during
your study you can need data set and one
of them of course the ais dataset and
norwegian coastal administration uh
offers their aes data free of charge
through an ip address and port number
use of present letter
as i remember the first time mentioned
about mentioned by the plymouth
universities and researchers in the
plymouth university they also mention
about the drawbacks and advantages what
is the
drawbacks for example
the maritime departments are
used the bristol letters for training
purposes
and if you damage their simulators their
trainings will be delayed and also these
are costly equipments
uh it is really hard to touch the
simulators in terms of i mean coding
however it is a ready system
and that's why you don't need active
software for example radar software it
is ready to use
general university has a huge project
actually and one of them regarding the
cyber security studies they're also
planning to combine their
full mission bridge simulator and cyber
range
as i know still an ongoing project
taltec
taltec also use a build simulator
for their
cyber security studies
and now
they have another test environment they
are planning to make some research for
the maritime cyber security studies
maybe
during the cafe time they can give us
more information about their test paths
as well
and uh anthony
our university marine department
purchased a simulator for the cyber
security studies uh in particular
around six months ago
and we started to work on it i would
like to share
our initial findings with you firstly
it is possible to connect with real
bridge components
like
gps a real components you can combine
and we review the network traffic and it
is compliance with the standards
then another one
we found
in the front side
15 different kind of components however
when we look at the network traffic it
is less than sin for example heading
information is provided by the gyro
compass on a real ship
however and in the front side we can see
we see the gyrocompass
however when we look at the network
traffic this data is produced by the gps
message
messages
we are trying to
uh
understand how we can create a remote
connection opportunity this are one of
the problem because the marine
department is different city in the
difference
than us and maybe
a remote connection could be also better
for us maybe also better for
our stakeholders
then another one these potential
scenarios
how can we create some scenarios using a
simulator this is our next question
actually
and
we are trying to understand the
combination of the simulator with
some tools some cyber security tools or
some
data sets how can we combine them this
is our next question
thank you for listening me if you have
any questions maybe
okay
then maybe you can ask during the cafe
right um before i open the floor to the
questions so thank you take the seat
as uh
okay maybe here you don't need a warm-up
but every
big rock band needs a warm-up questions
so there you go i'll start with the with
the question that
i have prepared i have multiple
questions for every one of you so thank
you so much um
so you are
looking at the concept of that the
simulators who are designed primarily to
train the crew on the operating the
vessel and now trying to look how those
simulators can be adjusted uh to train
cybersecurity of the vessel right
at least that's the in the nutshell what
i understood and you say nodding so it
means okay so i understood right
the first question i have how close the
those replicas are to the actual systems
and
if there are already test beds and the
individual components exist why would
you need to struggle and create testbed
with with the full equipment yeah
firstly with the full equipment you can
create different scenarios i would like
to explain one scenario
for example gps supporting it is one of
the well-known attacks or one of the
well-known vulnerabilities for the gps
gps is connected to the active
electronic map and connected to the
track control system
for instance during the gps proofing
attack track control stand what is that
it is called like uh autopilot actually
if you
uh
[Music]
in case of a gps proofing attack it is
possible theoretical is my idea only
a
misdirect vessel because track control
system is depends on the actors activist
depends on the gps and the starting
initial point is the gps and for this
reason i think it is possible to
misdirect to vessel
you can if you have a full system if you
have more components
you can create more scenarios this is
the one issue
the another one if you have a system
yes this is this testbed for cyber
security
but if you have a system
you can also make some research for the
operational site
for example
for the awareness of the seafarers
because at the end of the day
for the conventional vessel at least we
need seafarers and today many people
mention about that the weakest point is
the seafarers it is open to discussion
because also the strongest point from my
point of view
because at the sea we need this sea
first
uh
yes is it good for you right perfect
i will take the question from
the audience please go ahead
okay i will actually stand up now um
thanks
you're all for your for your
presentation super interesting uh so for
me coming from the cyber threat
intelligence sector
um
one question is
really emerging here so all are
gathering quite a lot of data
and especially if you look at the
maritime sector and if you look at gps
and ais regarding the messages you mean
in my massage protocol
one second one second um
for example sid was talking about uh
that they had gathered over a terabyte
of data in their exercises you're
speaking about all the tools you're
working with uh for for monitoring the
ais the gps and so on
and i just quickly looked it up again uh
the ais spoofing is not a new thing
right so this happened in 2017 to at
least i think 20 nato vessels so it has
happened and it has happened in the
alliance um so from a cti point of sand
uh stand point of view um could you give
some examples to
which tools you use to analyze these
massive amounts of data and to find like
some real time and actionable threat
intelligence uh on the cyber
vulnerability so which cves have been
exploited how can you react up on that
how can you immediately patch and update
and all of that actually we didn't do
that however another project
it was done
as i remember for example secureas they
you know as data actually includes
uh
three kinds four types of messages
scientific messages dynamic messages
word related messages and safety
messages and
real time they collect this kind of data
and compare for example
if we are
started to get some data from the ais
regarding the ship type
however
the cargo is different than ship type is
not comprised with the ship type
it gives an alarm
we didn't do but it was done in another
project they compared the aes data with
another as data
this is a
option
actually we had uh
we published a papers with ahmed is my
office uh
friends and
uh also my close friends
we checked the nba messages you know any
messages
and
we try to establish the enemy messages
different fields i mean
and main messages maybe some people
doesn't know any messages consist of
several fields and we compared this
field with another messages in our
papers
for example
if
a message regarding the rpm revolution
per minute
running
i mean there is a data for the rpm for
example
60 rpm
instead of these messages
there is no any movement of the vessel
we can understand that there is an
anomaly this anomaly could be relevant
with the cyber attack or maybe sense or
failure
all right
yeah i will before i and gabor have you
been introduced does anyone know that
you are a phd student and you are also
doing research in naval systems
gabor my friend you have a question
yeah
this is why this spawner is here because
they are supporting my phd
estonia is a very open-minded country
and if i tell my my boss that i do not
know the answer they usually
accept this answer
the last answer
the last question was that is it
possible to
to integrate maritime
components to our cyber exercise lock
shirts
so i transferred the the question to you
guys either as a digital twin either the
virtualized test that would it be
possible
my bars for sure that's corresponds all
with the questions that i have could you
could you tell me again your question
please
yeah
i can respect it uh
how could we integrate a
virtual ship or uh digital twin of a
ship tour exercise do you think that it
is feasible possible will you do it for
us
i uh i i think it is possible and today
it is trying to
conduct trying to succeed
some
researchers to do that and
of course there are some difficulties i
know because
manufacturers also use the different
v points different
protocols there are some difficulties
and there are some i remember some
projects i don't want to mention here
but it was unsuccessful
however if also the manufacturer maybe
could be open for the discussion
it could be possibility that's my
viewpoint all right
but there's an unsuccessful
project we may learn sorry for we may
learn we may learn from the unsuccessful
project the best things that we learn is
from our own mistakes even though
someone told you not to do so
with this i would like to also wrap up
quickly the panel so digital twin is
something we understood is a ambiguous
term we see that
joe my friend here is trying to
replicate an evil dockyard and bringing
it as a as a model as a virtual model
said is using a digital shadow uh
technology where it's interlinked
already with the physical system with
the with the one in the virtual space to
speed up as you would quickly watch a
movie or listen to an audio book which
is really awesome approach
and eye bars you're taking already a
miniature version of hardware that is
representing a huge vessel right and
you're trying to play around with it so
there are different approaches that we
we can take on this i would like to
thank each one of you and specifically
you as the audience for being awake and
asking questions really engaging
questions a round of applause for
everyone thank you