really Joseph on the first year here in
the death the hell so far off the rocks
and to a good start
so that's possible I never I always
encourage people to start conferences
because I think one of the the best
strengths besides sharing information is
building community and how they talked a
bit today about community but you'll see
that underneath on with all the problems
they see it's pretty much people
problems
I mean people build technology so I
guess everything's a people problem but
you'll see that where I think we're
heading the community is a country
people and I'm hoping there will be some
people in this room because I can tell
you there's a big shortage of included
people participating in the process so
the more people can get involved the
better and so let me just tell you my
expectancy for today's talk this is my
talk by the way sorry conversation tell
you where I'm coming from some of the
big thoughts that I've had and then I'm
hoping toward the end you can push
and tell me what your thoughts are on it
and where you think I might be wrong
because I think you know there is no
answer so I come from for a long time I
come from the Hector community and I
live in the effect and there's a
difference and I've been trying to call
out the difference recently I think I
think happy and acting conferences are
more interested in like sort of the joy
of discovery but I did totally trashed
your machine and I think in folks life
is much more focused on producing skills
advancing careers producing tangible
results that help a company or you
financially and they're not necessarily
the same thing but if you pretend
they're the same thing you'll go a
little crazy I I look a little crazy and
my solution conference I have a full
second conference black and so I would
just suggest to you at some point make
time for your record so and keep that
family separated from your info so so
and you'll find you'll get strength and
inspiration for maybe the exercise
because I can tell you you're never
gonna convince your boss the learning to
happy of scores final fear company's
engine but it might be mildly you know
so fulfilling
so the other thing I think you have to
be really definitely breaks failure all
right
we go failure it turns out that this
failure as unique to our industry
and it's pretty unique to Western
civilization
so Valley in particular if you ever in
say China or Asia culturally admitting
failure is a very self-limiting maneuver
in the West so compactly you'll say man
I just had to start up it and fail
everybody else will buy you a drink
they'll say great what did you learn I
tell me about your mistakes so I don't
have to make doesn't happen to very many
other industries so it breaks that don't
fire them necessarily government
involved it's no longer our playpen it's
no longer ours it is a phenomena and
governments have their say frankly and
so because of this we're seeing more and
more sort of policy encroachments into
what we would consider our domains you
can push back or you can embrace it and
personally I have been embracing it
because I think you can't help affect
change you're not involved and so my
personal trajectory that have been
unfortunately less spectable but
fortunately I get some more political
more policy and I'm realizing now we're
right at the beginning of it right
meaning in the last couple of years or
five years it's going to be another
that kiddies until they even have some
of this stuff figured out so don't feel
like you're late to the party
all right we're still setting up those
tools bringing in the case so you can
actually have a really large material
impact and because the there's a lot of
who here wants to admit that here with
military or people how many do you think
those people in line it's more than four
here I'm I've been told there's more
than four here so I'll try to convince
some of my thoughts more maybe in a US
and a military perspective the national
security perspective but you can see
where it's the researchers were really
were effective about two years ago three
years ago how many people follow the
Wassenaar arrangement sort of debates
arms control so this was an area where
some decisions have been made and
researchers never trying to didn't even
know we need to chime in and completely
give to us the Wassenaar arrangement
procedures and next thing you know some
researchers in the red team II offensive
security side looked at it and heard
about it said wait a minute
this means my business is illegal now or
it could be illegal right
actually notes finders
reverse engineers started writing
articles about it next thing you know
semantics
and Microsoft and Apple China said oh if
I have a foreigner sitting next to a US
citizen and one has some information
they can't tell my foreign engineer
about that information does that mean
considered that doesn't make sense so
all of a sudden we've got corporate
America and researchers involved in the
Wassenaar arrangement in policy and
since then we've had some really
positive interactions I think that was
our watershed moment that's woken us all
up that says number one you don't have
to be a policy ninja to make impact you
just have to be aware and then when the
Department of Commerce did it called for
feedback from the community on how these
rules the effective it was the most
amount of feedback the Department
Congress that haven't had any issue ever
so exciting that we're not shy that's
well pointy enough problems and other
people's policies so when I'm thinking
about where this is taking us and when
I'm thinking about what the future hold
I think it's really going to be the
United States and China this is not the
most some people don't like that and I
don't like that necessarily but I don't
see any other possible future let me
explain that a little unpacked a little
bit who's signing internet standards who
is sending people to IETF meetings who
has a giant economy that produces
technology like
there's a tiny amount of Russian router
Brazilian cell phones you know a
Canadian PlayStation right it doesn't
happen almost all the products he finds
a silver made in I know we're designed
in a manner and do you see that changing
it into the next point here I don't
okay so so two products we buy and the
standards that are set are coming mostly
in China
what well your community there's huge
okay your communion
I'll give them a close third but with
the GE PR and some other policies
they're exploring like this trying to
filter knighted for intellectual
property protection they're claiming to
fall on their length their hampering
themselves and I think that's gonna make
their economy and short hours in front
less competitive which means they're
gonna be taking a big figuring out what
they're up to
so so I'll keep looking over my shoulder
is you European Union is doing you know
maybe they'll help set some standards
and we can import for our own privacy
protections for various reasons animal I
don't see America stopping like games
and I'll explain for a couple reasons
one is what in the future I think data
Rd is key
big data it is the battleground in which
were fighting who has the data it's
Canada and the data brands have the data
for this Google Amazon Facebook
Microsoft right it's Huawei 10-7 I do
have the data so if you need the data to
run you gentle machine learning
algorithms we've been trained your
systems
I think they naturally happen
competitive I don't think Russia
naturally have some competitive
advantage in this area or many other
countries and then when people bring up
Russia it's like they're antastic
spoiler I think it in a trench any party
I think it took over any birthday cake
they can you know make things a mess but
obviously I'll be buying anything from
them today you can count really in the
Internet or are they just there
eventually exploited things for us and I
don't get things their way and so I keep
my eye on the thing that fundamentally
is going to move the needle from our
countries do you just can't get around
and therefore any solution to an
Internet problems gonna have to have a
global solution that means because
they're making all this stuff so he can
get China to make their own team
products
all that means the entire planet has
that much more secure IOT products and
so it's to our advantage to push them to
produce better products so I think
that's why there's a certain
international component to this and the
only people who can really apply
international pressure are Chinese
companies and difference and if you
think what China has been saying lately
it seems like we're also paying for
showdown
a contest between models we've got
America the American Western democratic
system with its values and then a new
emerging Chinese and the Chinese are
really feeling compliment right now
government over there it basically goes
like hey we've had some great successes
we have very depending the economy big
countries that were involved with we
don't seem to be suffering from all the
internal stripes that you're suffering
over there in the West we don't have
these problems with fake news we think
we have a winning model so it will be
almost impossible for you to convince us
that we need to switch to your model
because we currently think about models
well that's the mindset to try out here
you're jujitsu monomethyl jujitsu but
they didn't really think that they've
got a winner so what does that matter
involved well they've got you know they
do deals unilaterally and multilaterally
just like the United States but unlike
United States
I really I mean there won't be a meeting
like this we're sitting around talking
about how we're going to lobby the
government how we're going to get
involved in the Oise my arrangement
I doesn't happen there so they don't
have that feedback mechanism of the
civil society or the multi-stakeholder
model though that's alien in that arena
but it gives them a certain strength
right they have single voice they have
long-term vision they can pick a target
they can pick an objective and they can
pursue for a very long time is that the
inside track we're in the Western moment
we get sidetracked and it slows us down
I would say though the strength of
having all these extra voices in the
room is it gives us legitimacy our model
government actually represents all the
people and so what our government does
speak it's legitimately speaking for the
vast majority of the people and so I
think that's how you do strength
it's just takes forever to get there we
will talk about our marketplace of ideas
and it seems like the Despoiler who are
aggressive they can optimize their
attacks to come after
is deep faves I think you're gonna be
just I'm like I'm attracted I'm up all
the same time you know it's like look
into the car wreck on the side of the
road they call me I got somebody got
hurt but I got a look it's the same
thing happening with this whole deep
fake technology it's like oh my gosh
they look so real you know when you see
the videos of Obama and I don't know Kid
Rock or something and they're making the
same movements and they're sounding the
same and then you hear what they can do
with 15 seconds of your age they could
make you say anything and then you see
the advancements on automated
robocalling
and they can interact with you like an
IVR system and you can have a
conversation with a robot that sounds
like anybody and you can extrapolate
this is known about and it's just very
well you will be able to trust video you
will be able to trust you you won't be
able to trust almost any kind of but how
do you get how do we get past this and
it looks like they're adversaries you
know they fix the problem they zoom
right in on us and you can see the
argument between information security
and sort of data security Russia and
China
control the information flows very
strictly and trying to prevent these
problems anybody speaking out against us
we can't let anything go and that's
being tested right now that we tested us
and we the people designing the systems
to detect it will mean the people trying
to create the countries
we the people that experts trying to say
tell them what do we do giving you the
heads up it's coming down the road it's
going to lead all kinds of your
cognitive visited the Russians have some
tractor this morning's like an info shop
they call it you know they try to create
a post truth or a fake news environment
and then I believe it's gonna lead us in
this industry to have a certain amount
of cognitive dissonance where we believe
what we believe but not sure why right
or we end up distrusting too much okay
that's kind of like that was maybe a
little too much on German systems but it
leads me to this next point which is the
people who the offense the people in in
government and read claims the people
who know how to attack professional day
after day information operations and
those who know different University how
far the to give you some examples during
the Cold War before and there's a
build-up for the missile gap and
countries were trying to figure out how
did you into their weapons eventually
after about 40 or 50 years ended up with
the mutually assured destruction model
we didn't get in there overnight that
wasn't like five years or ten years it
took a long time and the people involved
in that debate that helped create that
nor were academics beginning think tanks
policymakers researchers it was the sort
of civil society response to how are we
going to deal with this
people in the department of war or
Department of Defense but we have today
though as we have super super
specialized people doing super
specialized offense in super-classified
environments that never talked about
none of that ever gets out and then you
have people on the hill and people
newspapers policy makers and people
ranking movies that just sort of invent
in their mind how offense must be
occurring and then that informs the
public and then that informs our
representatives and nexon you know how
often really happens and how a real
thinks it happens they're diverging and
this really crystallized for me when I
was in a I was at a conference about
those at NATO saikhan conference in
Estonia and there was an academic up on
stage he was telling us all about
offense in cyber and it hurt this can
hang it was next to me that does this
for living
it's like right we're gonna have our
policymakers everybody off off to the
races thinking that they're designing
policies within reality effects is a
completely different there's a big
disconnect there and that's not so bad
for our adversaries there's a big
disconnect in our policymakers take more
power to the bank in it but it is a
problem for our governance model when we
know how informative population rather
than foreign policy in this great little
society all speakers everybody and so I
see going forward is how are we going to
be able to sort of bridge that gap a
little bit more without giving away the
secret sauce without compromising
operations it's almost like we need to
educate people on it's not a
quarter-pounder people working big
effects for years that's not how people
think it's tough this is disconnect is
only gonna get worse
the other thing is we have a great
saying ones and I'll paraphrase it
because I'm not sure if I remember it
correctly but essentially it is there
are those who operate at scale and then
there's everybody knows are you either
operate at scale or you don't
and that is a big second just like those
are those who understand in my own
there's no you you're consuming big data
and operated scale for you so what is
that well let's see my original point
comes an operating escape Apple Google
said I do who's not operating at Skate
Canada France Germany I mean really it's
a weird bipolar world where there the
internet was supposed to connect us all
and empower us all and if you believe
the trends what's happening we're
creating these attracted what I call
attractive nuisances the economies of
scale are forcing us to centralize and
as we centralized we're creating like if
you had a blog in the olden days if
every 900 significant walking platform
your the blog today right market forces
are consolidating so what does that mean
you've never been well if the government
had to regulate one of 200 logs not to
be difficult but if the government has
to regulate Facebook that's a really
convenient and when you talk to
politicians in the European Union they
love it because now they can go after
YouTube Google or Facebook they're not
going after 500 American companies
they're going after to write an American
regulators want to regulate something
thank you after four or five right it's
really convenient and if you look at the
future the future of big data this means
this consolidation will probably
continue so while there might be five
billion connected devices on the planet
there's gonna be
what's the implication of that those
companies are gonna be hugely
consequential in our life they're gonna
be targeted regulation if I was a
military I was trying to take down some
B's infrastructure I don't have to bomb
500 blog sites digitally father but I
have to go after - well I have to do
bigger research in compromise - sites
it's much easier than trying to give 500
insiders and 500 locations so there's a
lot of consequences as well it was
interesting I was talking to the chief
knowledge officer at IBM and he had this
great being IBM you have a slide that in
this great slide deck and then pointed
to the riot and amount of data that's
being stored and the speed of bandwidth
over the clinic in the Pacific this
point was that it's so expensive to move
the data to where you're computing you
have to compute where the data is at you
know you can't move that much data over
a little straw and then compute on it
here you get it so that means that's not
geological you know module located
anchor they can't move and then
everybody's gonna cluster a rabbit
trying to get at it with high-speed
computing so that means geography is
really important again
in these bottles and we're those welds
that located are going to be really
important and so I'd like say Singapore
that have rule of law and great
connectivity that can become very
important in the global order addictive
is you're not going to stick your data
center in Malaysia Singapore right move
up roll up what do you pick up you're
out there you're a big so the other
consequences of this is that
everything's going to be multi tenant
everything is going to be shared
well how do you differentiate for
targeting if everything is you're going
to spend so much time trying to figure
out the impacts the second is there's
over impact of taking down one server
here an attacker because everything is
going to have a consequence and I always
wonder what would I think it's announced
that say CIA is by Amazon I always
wonder is that just like a different
graph or is that a lot of ability is a
bill that has a big target on the roof
because I wouldn't want legitimate
target mixed in if I commercial probably
I separate that if you can and so with
that name is sort of like designated
servers
that's it native data centers and you
can see it's tonyia being so small after
the attack Estonia had Russia
there their foreign ministry has done to
ignition
they have sovereign servers that that
particular metacommunity sovereign
servers posted outside of Estonia and
they have a complete backup of the whole
country's infrastructure and citizens
data outside of Estonia ready to reboot
in case the country is wiped out by a
biome or something I summon server
administrator
that just sounds cool how probably means
you're gonna have to be really careful
if you're targeting these things
another thing that finding fascinating
is that machine learning seems favored
attack seems to favor of offense right
then so that's five to ten years if I'm
writing the net battle system I can
either can try to build something to
save the world like say the cyber grand
challenge did or I don't have the
resources I'm just trying to be a better
editor about secret attack and why is
that it's the cycle the loops are pastor
did I get in there did I not get pretty
easy to tell fun writing a defense
system it's like well did I recall an
attack or not how legitimate network
traffic and they try to find out what's
not legitimate good luck with that I've
been doing that for 20 30 years but tell
them whether you probably shuttle or not
you can probably internet that be easily
and so the offensive cycle will
accelerate it is accelerating I've
talked to somebody who understand
research but he said there's databases
available for a small fee where bad guys
have met sort of it's like the entire
they know every version of everything
that's running and for small fee you can
create a database so for example if I
add a new jhula exploit I could go there
and I can put in the jeweler version and
it'll give me the IP addresses of every
machine in the world can import that
database and I can hit go and I can hit
information
and collective defense and call up your
money of the sir it's like one minute
you're safe
thanks make it up right and so if you
look at the rule right it's kind of so
tight that basically the decisions are
not that it's our do I attack or not and
once you decide to attack what you know
the target is vulnerable or highly
confident that they're vulnerable
because almost then not so on defense
and so we end up with this disparity
where attack is it it's predominantly a
technical exercise defense is highly
political well what do we protect what's
worth protecting
how much money would be better protected
well Wadena County pay for will Susan in
hor improving right it turns into big
person problem we have to get together
and decide how to protect America policy
where the legal requirements so has its
duty and it's very technical defense
very very political you have to talk to
third-party vendors your helpers
providers it's very slow and then
leadership if you don't have good
leadership leadership is going to
provide the direction they're gonna
provide the priorities here's what's
worth protecting here's what's worth
noting when did you give the snacks and
we have to be aware of this can we
operate you are gonna operate across all
three boundaries you might be an attack
attacking our company
example but you have to be aware of how
defense works and what the political
reality is because otherwise you can't
provide any about any but and your
employers going to be like yes we know
we're both will be needed and will
provide and of course they do ship it
someone's going to call you up and say
like what just happened what does this
mean my daughter's there and defensive
sort of like out marketing how many
people have been unfortunate or
fortunate enough to work in a marketing
organization right like the saying is I
don't have to my budget is wasted I just
don't know which happened it's the same
in defense because it's an offense is
now such a secret arcane art the vendors
don't have a lot of really good
monitoring models to work out but that's
they stopped working in offenders just
keep inventing new new features new
defenses that they are may have a
contagion to do impacts the defense and
all are compact the Eldar who networks
at google project zero and so one of
those jobs is he travels around a cool
art medicine and helps them become
better defenders and he always tells me
stories about these defenders who were
so proud to show off the latest
destruction but how they're going to
prevent any future except
well can you go back in time and point
the three bugs if this would have
stopped like okay you've added four
hundred lines of code and so what's
happening is absence this knowledge of
how real offense works the defenders are
making our systems more complicated
they're doing it with a tinkerer right
but they might not be doing what's best
in a long time and you have to be aware
of that the two are somewhat
disconnected so I have two big advocate
of training how many machines have not
teaching anybody they don't already know
and so when I talk about we're not
trying to steal money the Rings have
printing presses they make their own
money so they're generally after secrets
organized criminals don't have pretty
impressive probably not so interested
that maybe fungible things that they
could monetize quickly their effort
money and if you look at the difference
between those two right they both need
the internet to work to steal secrets or
steal money all the players need the
Internet to function and hackers
academic security researchers meeting
generally we want to know how things
work you want to tear things apart to
get it to quote unquote the truth the
ground truth how does a technology
really work and companies by criminals
I don't wanna make money but the
criminals I'm going to tell you how
they're breaking they tell you how
they're breaking in company is not going
to tell you the problems security
problems in their products who does that
leave
it's us it's hackers and the security
researchers we are one of the only
sources of ground truth knowledge coming
out if you look at cars locks smart
vehicles voting machines implantable
medical devices whatever it it's coming
from our community because there's sort
of a market filling the other
communities are not providing that
information so that puts us in a really
weird position we knew the only person
in the room talking about because we
don't quite realize that the whole world
listening to what we say because there's
other people
like these things it's not in their
interests and when I go through these
groups I always wondered is there a
group I'm missing and I've gotten that
before but I'm wondering these four
groups all need the internet to function
is there a fifth group out there that
definitely the Internet to function like
it wouldn't be the end of their business
models over that stopped working
and I haven't even really been able to
come up with a model but I just know the
Internet is insecure rickety as it is
now when all the players need to work I
just imagine if there's a group out
there they didn't necessarily mean the
amount to work and they just okay then
we're in trouble and now I'm into real
come so in this world that is getting a
little bit more fragile it's not quite
informed by information operations and
depends we have the internet architects
we have internet engineer we have the
people building to maintaining the core
of the Internet and they're doing
whatever they can do they're sticking
don't we take one things are wrapping
them with bacon wire in Louisville we're
making the whole entire more friendly
we're making the whole internet whole
thing in the name of security greater
flexibility for the name of security you
can see this happening across
so when I started with the Internet
you could sort of travel around the
whole world
and people would source route funny
messages to themselves up by driving
through a city in Australia Oh what
would a rat look through Africa right
they could send use an ICP redirects and
then get a packet and they just keep
redirected Chinese are public oh cool
that took 30 seconds for Toronto the
world to the minute 1/2 do we allow ICMP
redirects anymore we've outsourced loser
streaks or anymore not really
we have EVP filters everywhere all right
so BGP Friday is having to get locked
down because people keep misusing we
have DNS SEC now where if you screw up
one little certificate you don't have
made a circus anymore nobody can find
your company but we have to do that
because people are lying about DNS
responses we're moving to a future of
security TV you screw up one certificate
now you don't read but we're having to
give this because of our environment all
right we want to go to SMTP TLS always
HSTs always all right bye everything
about running a web server mail servers
just hideously complicated now you make
one mistake I always talk somebody you
can probably cause more chaos as a bad
guy
by getting into somebody's DNS server
and just updating some HS
yes records are H keep paying
certificates to non-existent
certificates
everything would stop nobody could get
to your site I knew have the famous clue
what just went wrong because everything
is don't running that's our future
wonder if that's the future that we want
I know it's all my intention I know the
engineers are doing their best but then
some of the doesn't this become a policy
decision like we decide we're gonna
trade off for this much security and get
this much flexibility or resilience you
know at some point we're gonna be okay
with everything that's all addicted in
five data centers but in return we get
you know three movies we aren't having
these discussions partially because
people aren't informed with them
that's a problem so I'm questioning like
in the future who makes these policies
will end up in China who's gonna make
the policy for the government because
there's nobody else to be involved in
our system are we going to be involved
in making this are we gonna have to join
the idea for the item eat are we going
to do
there's a big world out there where huge
tectonic shifts are happening and if
you're not involved there you're not
aware you're just gonna wake up one day
and it's you know big data's gonna be
done to you it's the new being involved
and so the debate surrounding norms are
happening right now
they started years ago - the norms to be
what are the acceptable norms of
behavior nationally internationally and
you might not realize that's begin part
even part of this debate new Marty
concepts or norms things that
coordinated only really did this closure
is a good thing
I see me be participating in that that
it used to be the norm
it used to be responsible disclosure
which was a terrible idea it was great
for companies is they could decide who
is responsible about but it wasn't so
good for anybody else and we managed to
get past that - thanks to someone in the
trip we have all these inequities
program that is now becoming the
department a lot of countries right
governments are now expected to behave
in a certain way and then they know we
use these norms just wanting to identify
the spot okay this is about actor who's
not who's been in a little bit strangely
with tensions it gives us a way of sort
of figuring out who's outside who's not
you might not realize it right your
Terms of Service acceptable use policies
in the routing world we have period
agreements and if you're pissed off
enough of your peers you
here you don't get to rap anymore that
didn't involve law enforcement in a
politician that was a community response
to deciding that you're no good or
withdrawing our routes there's no legal
requirement that they have to provide I
mean to you and so we have ongoing the
base in these areas right the watchtower
arrangement on effects of tools you I
keep saying this in a random way but I
want you to get involved I want you to
help identify these problems I want you
to find the bad actors and I want you to
recognize that at the heart of it it's
us it's a hacker info centers community
and we're going to be called on to
participate more of these or policy
so people saying is great how do I do
that
and it's really easy it's as much or as
little effort as you want to put into it
so for example all the time if there's a
request for comments go to you read
about of the global and you say that's a
great idea that's a terrible is why it
takes five minutes or you can spend it
in ten hours doing the research back you
know you're staying with data and having
been the chief security officer not
again
I can tell you absolutely at least like
you've read every comment on different
proposals we took everything very
seriously partially because like in
Department of Commerce we got so few
comments I'm not kidding it's a planet
of billions of connected people and we
would get 20 comments on an important
policy funny any one of those comments
could sway the whole decision so don't
think that you're one of the 50,000
people in common
anything you're not you're like one of
the 50 so if you're interested in an
area lost are you you come in at the
Department of Commerce but you can
provide your feedback and people
actually listen just it's mind-boggling
there was one guy I can know who he was
nobody ever taught we assumed it's a key
exhibit the name we don't even know what
country is it but he commented in
English commented on his proposal for
the last ten years there was never a
proposal was one person never come in a
tie and never can go we need that we
never met this person in real life but
it was really weird because you be
reviewing feedback and people would
inevitably say well what did that guy
say it's he's so involved and so too
hidden both sort of like counted more
than other people's because he was so
involved in the process he cared so I
call it story just to say to you I could
be any one of you you don't have to get
on an airplane and fly to the mic I'm
wondering if any one of those points
ever get spent
instead Cochise free money pool the
whole thing collapses and I'm wondering
if it's to the point like how close is
it that we can pre-compute a single coin
she's cool and if somebody could do that
that person has the power to wreck the
whole Bitcoin all they have to do is buy
that one point they can trash a little
party for everybody they just say that I
try not to okay so that's generally my
big picture which is that the we're in
this era where we're technology is
critically important you can see that
with AML big data but at the same time
the equal side of it is becoming I would
say more important what you also see
finally is company if you're in the
military or the government and
somebody's messing with you who do you
call you have a State Department you
have a military if you're a company and
somebody's messing with you who do you
call not the State Department not the
military intelligence agency do you call
your lawyers right my lawyers are like
my Intelligence Agency my diplomatic
military they're everything all of
that's my my lawyers so lawyers like the
middle well I just like to find things
to do to be useful so you see more and
more lawyers involved in this area and
they're going to do nothing to get more
involved so when we lawyers ask me where
do you think you should I should get
involved with what's the future I think
it should be suing people should sue as
many people as you can but you should
sue them in other countries because
what's happening is we're really good at
each other within America
country they just keep spamming like you
know soon that other country like well
that's up at work there's no
jurisdiction ago so that doesn't matter
just start swinging and create
presidents create force lawyers none of
the country top five team forest judges
on that other country to make decisions
out lab right that will start the
dialogue you're not going to solve the
problem but you're gonna start a backlog
where you're forcing other people to act
and one of the first companies that
would do this so the guys up there
giving us the burger saying haha three
years later a new treaty with Canada the
judgment applies right so you never know
what the future will hold
so I guess other people right lawyers
are gonna get involved if I was a lawyer
man I would be because we need is we
need norms we don't need just
governments talking to governments
figuring this out that's interesting but
who owns and operates the internet civil
society so civil society would have to
figure out our solutions and they'll be
in the framework the legal framework
provided by a government but I'm telling
ya military's not going to come in and
say
the different labs I recommend say I see
if I come in and say here we worked at a
company right it's on you and your
lawyers do now so I have like maybe five
or six minutes I'd love to talk to you
because honestly I find the question
more interesting hopefully 10 Tim
berners-lee is terrible proposal about
DRM or is proposal about the ubiquitous
everybody run by the server at home yeah
yeah isn't that essentially everybody
want to pack to your home and then post
other people's key porn by accident and
now we're pretty viable for deals of
data that was a glib answer but I'm all
distributed systems but I'm kind of more
of the crypto privacy anarchist like
what was his name
left or not I do he what's in the
distributed data store freedoms right
more of a free net solution where
everything is encrypted you don't know
what you're posting I almost feel like
that's tins Mel Koopa for for allowing
DRM into the
and which tells that are forgiven for so
follow on that I think though the part
of that distributed systems that's the
only way around would be a
centralization right this trend of
centralization we're seeing that we
don't like that the future our only
other future is distribution
distribution systems and so I donate my
age people who are developing this is
done these things like that will give us
an alternative because right now there's
only one thing on the menu of its I
don't like where that's going
and it's chicken every day I want
another option
No yeah you don't need to be policy
affects this none at all but you need to
be aware that policy is happening and it
can happen to you just like the security
researchers woke up one day and lost our
bathroom to them a year before they
didn't even realize that they lost the
race they didn't even know there was one
right right so in that arena I think
that the happy byproduct of wasps are is
that everybody's more tuned to it so now
there's a policy mailing lists there's
websites there's a lot of the security
blocks cover this stuff that we're dark
birth wasn't covered so I think it
awareness they're raising awareness
there's a there's a community problem
it's still on my phone it's good with
like every other Thursday a bunch of the
companies from Watchtower Microsoft and
so on they all have together pool their
money hired a law firm in DC that law
firm is sort of directing the
community's responses in DC and they
have an open phone call every other week
to update anybody who cares to call on
the call participate review their
documents whatever and so it is reading
that case kind of created this mechanism
for everybody to provide feedback five
minutes five minutes
[Music]
right
right right we're in this great period
we're having to submit a button legally
legitimately
that there's no and there's all these
other problems too like some of the
bounty programs Hector what requires a
real name but what if I don't want to
give you my real name I don't want to
get paid so I give you a lady I just
want you to know about the button some
of these bounty programs don't have that
option because they assume everybody
wants to get paid so we're working on
waiting through these systems where you
know probably not a problem five ten
years from now but it's a real problem
right now so anything you could do just
be that so for example like I was about
a year ago security is not txt you know
that on your website in the well-known
folder the problem was how do I even
know who to contact on that comes up
with a standard Google put a file called
security dot txt in the well-known
directory and hit oldest could contact
how to PT PT so on and so forth that was
one person it's now accepted so there's
ways to you know there's ways to try to
screw these bumps over and I'm always
you can always google school this dump
it on full disclosure might not be the
most responsible thing to do but you
think answer I think there's a problem
now than the theater and it's so hyper
connected you might think that the
problem is insignificant the manufacture
might think the problem
but there might be a wallpaper using
that technology in a different way we're
turns out no it's a punctual it's just
other people disagree but unless you get
information either let people make their
own decisions like I don't want to make
it so he decided for me what I like in
the research and I can look at the whole
for me that's really important
I call it the vodka I think the term is
confusing that means different things to
different people so you can't really
agree to what net neutrality and I I
think that traffic Rd rounded there's
already quality of service depending
upon what route to pay for what you're
pairing arrangements are you get traffic
is not neutral rated to weighted
immensely and when a system is under
attack the administrators absolutely
provide filtering and different levels
of priority based on what's being
attacked so with the net neutrality laws
that I can never filter under attack and
I can't filter so it's highly nuanced
and I don't hear anything they want to
the debate so I avoid those debates
until hopefully go throw up a little bit
okay
that is it I'll be around for a while
I'll see you outside
[Applause]
you