so welcome to my talk thank you all for
coming and choosing me over whatever is
on the other track so the title of my
talk is a quick look at mark o/s
thumbnails so this is basically a very
high-level overview of centralized
thumbnail caches and mccoys so first of
all let's say a couple of words about
who I am so I'm a fourth-year student of
cyber security and forensics at Napier
and research that I'm showing today is
actually my dissertation project so it's
due in a week I'm very happy to be here
it may be a couple of words of how I got
here so a couple of years ago I attended
a jungle girls event
I made the blog I was very excited about
making something that works and then I
started mentoring at other jungle girl's
events I started organizing some other
jungle girls events I got involved in
the Python community then for some
reason I don't remember why I applied
for I didn't run a pair to study
cybersecurity and I quickly joined in
your psyche where I started just going
to all the meetups that are you know
around Scotland all the conferences and
then last summer I interned at lone
hooks and now I'm here and I will help
people hopefully graduate soon in May I
think let's let's keep our fingers
crossed for that okay so what our family
is probably most of you know homeless
are just the miniature little images of
fight that represent the files made by
your operating systems they are there to
help you navigate your files because if
you were just supposed to remember what
your files are but just by the family as
we all know that we just call everything
f DF DF D so like you need fabulous
right so what's interesting from those
and as far as I'm concerned most
mainstream operating systems right now
they are not only made for for image
files as you
but for many other files like
called text-editor files PDFs images
videos obviously and a lot a lot of
different ones so in Mac OS specifically
the technology that the mechanism of
making these thumbnails is called quick
look and it's also responsible for that
cool feature that you can just select a
file and then press the space stop and
then you can get a full preview of for
example if it's a PDF of a couple of
pages you can scroll through these pages
you can read it it's completely fine but
it's not actually opening the file it's
just a quick look at the file so just
before we continue this talk is only
about Mac OS so if you are interested in
Windows and Linux for comparison or just
to just to learn something new you can
scan this QR code if you have an iPhone
just open your camera and and pointed at
this and it should take you to a link
where I put up some resources and so if
you are interested in with the cinetic
go do that but today I'm only talking
about Mac OS so what are hotmail caches
they are basically directories and you
will have a separate directory for each
user so that's important because it
turns out that the when you're root when
you're admin you can access all the
other standard accounts caches from your
account so that will be useful later
which I'll get to that anyway how where
where is this cache so you go to bar
folders then you go there there will be
a random two letter string a a from
directory name then there will be a
random long string and then there will
be a C directory and come up
quicklook/thumbnail.jpg jfif @exif aynd
that just just use the five command
being and
and of our folders so yeah I'm not sure
how visible that is but it's just a
directory with in many other different
caches there and within that directory
we have from three to seven files
because there are some additional file
SQLite files being created so you can
see the ones that we are interested in
the most is the s key index dot SQLite
database and another one that's
important it's pump it's companyís dot
data so index dot SQLite is a a database
which has all the metadata about files
that thumbnails are created for and
about from players and funders the data
is just raw data the the thumbnails
themselves just in a big data blob and
it's really it would be really difficult
to to parse from knows the data without
having the index dot SQLite because all
of these images are in PNG format but
they are stripped from from file
signatures so you can't really carve it
out easily
that's why you need that index dot
SQLite where you have the offsets and
then you can you can easily find where
your thumbnails are so let's take a look
at index dot SQLite so again there's
five tables inside that database file
spending secure delete buffer
preferences reserved buffer and firmness
and again we are most interested in
files and thumbnails so let's look at
both of them what's what's the structure
of these and first the files table gives
us some juicy data so we can see the
path so it also often includes volume
name so the path to the original file so
in there in the files table we see
information about the file so by the
file I mean the original file that the
family was made for not just the phone
now so then family file name obviously
and then FS ID which includes
volume ID and then
. and then a file ID within that volume
so i will show you examples in in a bit
where you will be able to see that in
practice let's say and then in the
firmness table there's a lot a lot
fields a lot of this is is used to be
able to locate and locate where the
funnel is within the data block but the
ones that we are interested in from
forensic point of view is the number of
times the five thumbnail was accessed so
that's the hit code and last time the
family was accessed so last hit date
so obviously that can give us some
insight in what was done on the machine
so let's let's think of like how does
the thumbnail end up in the cache so
like we go into the crash with you the
database and we see some files but how
did it get there what do you have to do
to make a to make a file like make a
thumbnail for itself so basically every
time you you see a file yourself so
whether it's on desktop or it is in a
folder and you open it and find there
every time you actually see that file
and you see the funder for it it will be
it will be created and also if you open
a folder which for example has 300
images then the thumbnails will be made
for all of them even though you'll
probably see maybe 10 only because of
your of your window size so actually but
all my experiments were done on a very
very not powerful VM so if I open the
file sometimes it would take a couple of
seconds for you know the thumbnail to be
created so for example I haven't had a
picture and there was only like this
this white page let's say thumbnail
place place horrid placeholder so it
would take a while for the thumbnail to
actually get produced and if I was quick
and just collected the cash before it
then it wouldn't it it would nothing
would be there yet so basically when you
CFM though it means that it it got
caster so let's look for a cup at a
couple of examples so for example here I
have a very very easy scenario I have
two folders and both of these folders
are on the same machine so it's it has
nothing to do with networking or
anything
there is a folder code files and there
are two files in them to copy and to
move I'm taking the to move file and
moving it dragging it to new folder and
then I'm collecting the cash and looking
at the index dot SQLite so when you look
inside index dot SQLite you can actually
see three records and you remember we
only had we only had two files so in the
fandom we can see that there are two two
entries for to move one is in when you
look at the folder part one is in files
one is in new folder so there are two
separate entries even though it's the
same file that we have moved but when we
look at the file ID and FS ID where we
have the volume ID and the file ID these
are the same numbers so you can easily
link link them together and see that
this is the same file just have has been
moved somewhere else so example number
two is when you have an external device
and you are moving a a five from from
the external device to your machine so
here I have USB storage just a USB stick
there's a very important secret image
called hacking jpg on it and I'm just
dragging it on the desktop and then
looking at the cache so here's still the
file I have to two entries and in the in
the cache and both of these obviously
the file name is the same but you know
the thumbnail can be the same for two as
always but you can see that the file IDs
are different both the volume ID and the
file ID is different because it has been
moved from an external device so it
wasn't just an operation on our machine
and for exact little example renaming a
file we changed the file that we changed
the name of the file I literally took a
screenshot if you haven't much you know
it just gets saved with this weird name
format with the live the date and the
time when it was taken and then you then
I changed the name to name changed
again two entries and you can see that
the file ID volume ID and the file ID
are the same here that's an interesting
one what happens when you delete a file
so here I just created two txt files
because based on my research they also
produce thumbnails the the I only put
test string in it so you can't see it
but if you zoomed in really really
precisely you would see that actually
the layout of the document is reflected
by the thumbnails so you can kind of see
if I had the word document with the huge
pictures and you could see it in the
front nail so it does give you some
information about what's inside so I
have two text files or a test string in
them then I put them in trash and then I
click on the trash open the trash and
click empty trash so that it's super
deleted right so then I go to the cache
and what it actually did was create yet
another entry in in the cache for each
of the files where you can see that the
folder bit says that it's desktop first
and then trash so if you want to be
extra careful and you'll go into the
trash and delete their contents it only
increases the footprint of that file in
the cache because it creates yet another
from them so don't do that if you if you
don't want to be exposed okay so why do
we care about this at all why why are we
looking at at the cache so first of all
in its quick be and fast to copy because
it's quite small in my on my environment
my test environment that I have prepared
which isn't very powerful it was only
growing up to 500 megabytes and when it
reached 500 megabytes it will just reset
back to the start so it was just I know
it's weird I almost I also thought that
maybe it would intelligently switch
things around but no it just deletes
itself and starts at zero megabyte
second so anyway that's just half half a
gigabyte it's quick quick to copy when
you especially when you when you
appreciate like how much inside you it
can give you into what the user has done
on the
that's what digital forensics is by the
way it gives you a very very useful
insight and what the user has has been
doing on the machine
so obviously it's much better than if
you have a huge a huge machine with a
huge amount of data then it's much much
faster to just go through the cache
first even if it's just for triage you
can still do it much faster than try to
check every file especially when you're
interested in what was done recently on
the computer and also a regular user
probably wouldn't think to delete it so
you would first like a regulars and
would first just try to delete things
you know just put them in the trash and
then empty the trash maybe if they are
super smart but they probably wouldn't
think to to go and delete the cache so
obviously it's no no it's not very
surprising that that people started
researching and and thinking what what
can be done with this so this is very
important addition to this slide so in
2000 and 2018 a security researcher
called Wojtek Inagua has published a
blog post about how the cache can leak
information from your encrypted and
encrypted drives so this is another QR
code to that blog post if you if you
wanna take a look at it so he basically
realized that when you plug in a an
encrypted password-protected drive to
your computer and then view the contents
of it and then eject it and take it away
the the thumbnails will still persist in
the cache even after it's ejected so
obviously that's a huge huge high
security concern so obviously a lot of
people weren't interested in it and the
the guys just died like a master student
as my master student in Poland but it's
got a huge coverage and different like
hacking news and tech reader all these
security blocks you can see there's a
lot and also security forums so
obviously there was a lot of a lot of
pressure on Apple to do something with
it and fix it somehow in the next next
operating system version which was
Mojave so what did they do they just
included
they just included the thumbnail cache
under their system integrity protection
so it means that basically you cannot do
anything with that file so you go into
the cache and you have different caches
and some of them including now thumbnail
caches it's just an accessible to you it
you cannot copy it you cannot delete it
you cannot move it you cannot run file
on it to see what it is like you can't
just you have no permissions to do
anything so there is a way to to kind of
bypass it great because the system
integrity protection can be turned off
you can just put it into safe mode and
disable it from the terminal there so
then you you just have access to the
cache and you can analyze it as I have
shown before and even though they have
fixed the the encrypted drive owner
ability so now when something's equipted
you you plug it in your view the stuff
it doesn't get saved in the cache still
if you plug a USB stick in and you plug
it out which isn't password protected
not encrypted then it persists still if
you are sharing a a folder within your
network then it still gets gets saved
and persists there so deleted files
still stay there so it's only this one
thing that they thought of but nothing
else so hence this like so you may think
ok so how is that useful because I just
told you that that they have made this
system integrity protection on this on
this directory so you are not able to
access it in any way well you need what
you really need is the root password
because after after you boot into safe
mode you need to reboot and oh and then
and then access obviously the the root
account again so there is a number of
scenarios where you actually do have
access to to the root account for
example when it's your machine so if you
are an employee
and or for example a new University
anytime it's your machine and you can
still you can do all of these things as
long as you have the main control of it
another thing you could also think about
it in a way that you can trick a person
to use your computer and then be able to
to reconstruct their behavior based on
the cache so I have a couple of -
actually - real-life examples of of this
working so I have read many many
different court cases while working on
my dissertation to look for something
that would kind of touch upon this this
topic so what I found is that their
approaches to the funnel caches and also
in general to digital evidence but
thumbnail caches in in particular they
differ greatly because of lack of kind
of standardized and well researched
knowledge about how they work so instead
of instead of treating the you know the
the fact that there is something in the
cache as evidence that for example you
have viewed or the you know whoever is
being charged you'd something indecent
for example on their computer they
treated us possession or making of this
indecent contents so for example if
there there's what first case I'm going
to talk about is the Regina versus
Porter so there's a case number on there
you can take a picture and and google it
later if you want
so basically in both cases that I'm
going to talk about these are men who
got charged already with with possession
of of indecent images and in this case
the guy had over 3,000 the over 3,000
companies were recovered from his from
his computer showing some indecent
indecent content and he then appealed to
around two twenty-seven twenty-seven
hundred of them where we're recovered
using a special software which were
which was kind of lent to to the UK by
the US government so he appealed the
charge and said that because you needed
this special software it like the the
contents were not available to him
because he wouldn't be able to see this
twenty seven hundred photos because they
were only available when you cuz
obviously he deleted them at some point
before they were only available using
them using the specialized software and
he he actually did he did actually get
like his appeal was granted and he was
found not guilty he was found guilty of
possessing other ones that were easily
accessible but this one but you know
it's like it seems funny but when you
when you think about the difference if
he had like eight hundred or you know
over three thousand three wasn't
indecent photos then it's a different
kind of magnitude of a crime right so he
actually want that little bit and they
did say okay it wasn't accessible to you
because you would need that special
software on the other hand though there
was another case regina versus
Christopher Brown where the guy was
found he appealed his charge as well and
he said that the the fact that the
thumbnails were on his computer were
because because he has downloaded them
and he he just he said that he did not
view the pictures at all so this is
again if there was standardized and well
researched knowledge about how the
family caches work then obviously that
that could be proven untrue like basing
it on whatever operating system he was
using because you need to view the the
file for in order to for the family to
be made so he did not he did not have
have his appeal granted because the jury
and the judge has found
that the firm nails were big enough for
him to be able to enjoy the content
anyway so he was found guilty but you
can see these two cases are very similar
but still you know still there were two
very different approaches and I just
find that it's it's really weird that no
one is actually treating thumbnails as
evidence which is basically what it is
more than actual positions of wealth you
know illegal content okay so that's
that's the end of my talk thank you very
much I won't be question taking
questions here but if you have any
questions please tweet me or ask me in
the pub later and all the resources and
the slides later will be published at on
my blog and this is a QR code for it so
thank you very much