oh hello everybody and welcome to the
highway 19 it's very evident that a lot
of people like to set the back but it's
very evident that people then like happy
at registration and the facts for coming
no I don't prepare laughs I was out till
one o'clock this one so and I've just
got my grandma Lee open here so he still
gets it correct so that's just stood
exit george watsons college yes a venue
same the first litter the hike not ran
at an EP or however fun fact all the had
to be on the same street and just a
coincidence and therefore many of this
will be the first time we're back in our
school quite a while so you maybe get
like PTSD flashbacks I'll be in at
school don't worry
hopefully no billion here him however
who gets up and this is a father to the
hug 17 they started 70 and dividuals
competing our CTF over a weekend in the
classroom he probably passed I became
incontinent then last year we had a
hundred and fifty attendees coming to do
a workshop then our CTF and then this
year we've get this which we saw a bit
230 packets and so therefore I go and
bear are growing every year so moving
that confidence say we try to do
something completely different like
which I do change it to cater to what we
wanted to do until the educational ethos
we wanted to make sure people down and
took something away from the weekend and
I think we can do that with the staple
of em like the venue in the or donor
agenda and special with the two tracks
and couldn't one day to get to the
students along with our master crafted
team you key member charlie CTF tomorrow
and and but we can't do that's obviously
event you the size and the event that's
big refer all of our sponsors as you can
see in the screen so
start at the bottom roller for stock of
illegal jacks get cracking enter beneath
University when we suddenly get hub
SecureWorks eliminate technologies hack
the box and lloyd's some of them are in
the back corner here I would recommend
will speak to them they've got swag they
bit stackers and they have most
importantly jobs if you're looking for
placements and turn chips our am a
graduate rule I go speak to them they've
got nice weather here but here I talk to
you they're looking for enthusiastic
students but shoes are because you came
to us event a half eight in the morning
and haven't listened to me speak him
sorry but up and so when your age did
you get your swag bike and among it you
got an array of stackers but also if you
inferred your t-shirt you got that split
clip this Pickler has everything so as
they run order for the day so you know
what talks to go to and it's also got
the just got the Wi-Fi passwords at the
back along with social links and QR
codes to both I worked what are which
were doing updates throughout the day
and also cyber Scotland connects and
slack which one Gavin updates for a day
so going back to the speaking there is
hawks royalty from people set in the
front row
people going here yet but and the only
thing I have to see is the talks have
been recorded and they will be good on I
managed to have that video from Cooper's
worries and kipper stuffs that's we've
seen many Cooper on the camera right
here and then we will the owner hang
guys was only one talk that's not yet
recorded and that's dunks Carson spoon
freakin top so therefore he he can't you
want to see that you can't mess it here
because it's going to be not recorded
pelea and so just to move on finally and
go on to the code of conduct
so as of any English take event the call
to conduct as a barrel and code of
conduct and this and the booklet as well
but it basically boils down to don't be
at that and not to be taking jest all we
do take any code of conduct violations
seriously and if you have our critical
violation you need
one speaks someone in the black branded
t-shirts with the kamati badges that
says em the people who are responsible
for getting all sorted we will take
things very seriously and our goal left
that system in teen was super hard to be
an educational event less and
accommodate an environment to foster a
learning experience and that's what this
event is all about talking about
learning experiences passed over and Max
is going to pass on his Leonard was
doing ok thanks Jamie yeah so I get I
get I get all the good stuff so I you
can see around there there are fire
exits here so like all throughout the
day the fire X is really clearly marked
if you're in this building or track 2
which is kind of upstairs then an
assembly point is out the front so when
we go over to track 1 which is out the
back here then I will tell you at the
beginning of the day like where where
the muster point is and stuff like that
toilets if you need them out the front
and sort of to the right there very
clearly marked with with big posters one
with a woman not it's not like that but
like with a woman and and one with a man
and wear your lanyard all the time
please if like we've been told that if
if you're seen without a lanyard then
people will kick you off the site
because you might just be like an
interloper or something yeah yeah
so photos and stuff were fine but if you
see somebody wearing wearing a blue
lanyard please try to avoid taking
taking a photograph of them not because
they're spies or anything like that but
just because they'd rather not be
photographed and phones on silent
obviously um what was the other one
smoking right so because this is a
school even though there are students
here today it's yeah so it's a school so
if you're going to smoke you need to
smoke off off campus so that's out by
there out by the road yeah don't get
caught
hey um anything else
okay so track 1 is going to be with me
all day and so that's if you come out of
here you'll see there's a sign there
that says track 1
you're gonna walk along after afters
choose giving us talk then anybody
that's going to want to come over to
track 1 I'll walk you over there
together it's just sort of out the back
and then across says like music music
halts quite sort of obvious says Music
Hall in big big letters a track to is
gonna be up the stairs it's it's clearly
signposted who's running track - where's
mark
mark and charlie probably up in track 2
right oh there is that guy you can see
waving his hand wave your hand for
everyone mark yeah there's mark so
Mark's going to be running track 2 so
he'll take you over after after Stu's
talk right so that's it that's it for me
welcome to Latoya hack 19 I hope you
have an awesome day I'm gonna kick
things off here with stupor thank you
very much
[Applause]