why have one and I am ashamed over Chen
can we talk about them you called it
proceed apparently they to ownership or
what we find is we kind of kind of
probably moved closer to back to usage
use of that data oxy oceans not that
long and also what we thought is having
talks here today - seems to be quite
technical both kind of change of pace
then the more overdue said types like
score beach water situation yeah explore
some of the so who are we
yeah so doctors if I'm recently done a
and Emma since I'm scusi but my
background in intelligence all right
guys how about let's say quite a while
after my MSC time think I'm doing the
soft warfare and Trump status due to
that nicely
fugly lot more research pops loose it is
how follow the law society loses their
social in life outside society and of
course man - I - thanks edition so yeah
I'm Stefan so actually I'm all kind of
industry so you know over the last
number of years I've worked
calcio worked in software but finance
systems and more recently can
I'm working a lot with the spread of
publishing associations want to get that
message their content out that global
audience and yeah we're a technology
partner we partner with those sample
relations global poses so also ghupat
work through the UK EBI so dissolved
from identification so just more on a
process of post more so kind of like
methodology but on incidence after
hospitality so similar to mission and
you know master cybersecurity I found
that for me that was just a great thing
to do she sewed up a lot my industrial
kind of experience sectors and subsidies
at work that covers many different
things and for me just was was a great
leader to even at this point in my life
let's say so you know education is the
number two tools to start that game so
you know most a few things you know
articles and journals this book come out
as well jaymund you know clear the
trials and transparency of that data
similar fell over RSA and MIT so yeah
which is here really just to kind of
just give that allude to the beginning
that idea about cross everywhere really
promising transparency of pay your
ownership survive having pregnant is
shown the weekend you can dump we're
going to talk about going to my data it
rips eBay but they understand pain kind
of read the whole PowerPoint and talk
about packs a while way to go that's the
sort of
[Music]
I'm looking at the breakdown their usual
suspect services just media some of the
elders really what's interesting about a
lot of these agencies how is it going to
be used what maybe explore today just to
kind of think about how data is being
used as opposed so we can't talk about
data and how it's being used without
pushing upon the industry 4.0 as well
again some more I'm sure you're all
familiar with we talked about well if
you think about industry three or the
third revolution of industry digital
revolution I guess for point no is more
geared around automation and integration
of automation around processes
everything from the set of things sub
physical systems robotics nanotech
quantum computing how how everything is
effectively gonna change or we're seeing
already a lot of this stuff is happening
now a lot of it is due to come like 5g
autonomous vehicles it's a really
society and I guess the way we do things
is changing our usage of data
I suppose data is perhaps changing the
way society operates as opposed to
society changing the way we generate
data so moving on from industry 4.0 we
then look at what is data ownership
so again data ownership a bit obvious
really but if you look at it
legislatively I suppose if you're the
owner of data you're gonna have more
ideally you want to have complete
control and legal rights over the back
piece of specific piece of data and
that's what it comes to cyllage
legislatively I should say that also
means that you can create you know edit
modify restrict that access or that
particular data so you give permissions
to whichever organization it is that
you're given that data to at the same
time they're just listed lis
usually you you know you can surrender
these rights or share these rights with
terms and conditions or you know use
accept you know you accept the
permissions to use a particular platform
you usually give them rights to use your
data again there's something all aware
of and again so I didn't trying to
identify data Rona's again that's in it
that's a big kind of thing right now
because with this big mishmash of
sharing rights giving permissions who
actually owns data that's being
generated is easy to say well I am doing
X Y Zed function therefore the data
that's generated off of that is mine but
is it actually mine and if it goes for
platform does the platform own it or do
they just use it and if they share it
you know what where where is the
permission coming from and is there an
implied permission to that land it
becomes like quite a quite complicated
legislative kind of conundrum really
talking about well I monopolies one of
the things that's all well with
monopolies I've put not the game there
meaning if we took if we taught my dated
data generation data ownership and if I
use an example of Google and you know
whether it's your gmail account or your
Google search history or whatever it
might be and if you think of alphabet
Inc that own Google but then all of the
other kind of subsidiaries under
alphabet Inc so straight away if
alphabet Inc have quite a few I guess
different facets or different kind of
tunnels that you're generating data and
giving data to will say about this as an
organization that become very powerful
cuz suddenly they've got a lot of data
that they can be doing or some of the
things that were going to be talking
about shortly so yeah monopolies really
data is becoming the the gold might or
not the goldmine but the kind of the
currency the new oil I guess of the of
the cyber world I had a video here to
show you about a project anything's
gonna over we'll see
sidewalk labs I'm not sure if anyone's
aware of the work that Sidewalk labs are
doing in Toronto I'm seeing lots of
blank faces so I'm assuming not sidewalk
labs right there essentially they're a
startup that were bought by alphabet Inc
Google their idea was to create or they
are creating a neighborhood within
Toronto that's going to be effectively a
smart neighborhood monitoring everything
facial recognition using web basically
with five gene all the other networks
and things using biometric tracking
behavior analytics all sorts of stuff so
when you're in this neighborhood their
idea is that by tracking you and your
data that you're generating everything
that you're doing they can provide a
better service and provide targeted
infrastructure and whatnot obviously
there's a massive privacy kind of
connotation to that and perhaps even an
ethical an ethical kind of thing that
will that we can talk about I had but I
had a video that was the you know one of
these glossy promotional video we're
doing see if a place I put on speak
around
this or is this like this but yeah yeah
like they I mean essentially if you look
up sidewalk labs it's quite interesting
they're using these you know free Wi-Fi
you know for everyone you know by all
means free Wi-Fi do what you want on the
Wi-Fi and whilst we kind of mine your
data obviously they're looking at it
from a very kind of utopian point of
view I look at things from a data
profiling
I guess side I guess as security experts
we kind of have to be quite critical
quite skeptical about these sorts of
things I'll skip along if there's no
sound again it's it's not
mission-critical it was just it's just
an interesting concept as to what's
what's going on and on the advert that's
what I guess on the other side of the
spectrum to sidewalk labs in Toronto
obviously there's the work that's going
on in Shenzhen at the minute in China
with them facial recognition and
automatic essentially in Shenzhen I'm
not sure if anyone's been to Shenzhen in
China and you guys know the offense of
jaywalking don't you if you cross the
road on a red man say if you've got you
got two pedestrian crossing red man
green man so you cross the road or you
wait until the traffic light changes if
it's red and you cross the road facial
recognition identifies you you know to
cross the road they get your details
from WeChat and they automatically
billed you and find you and you get your
criminal record everything in it notify
via your phone but by the time you've
crossed the road it's all about and so
that's trying to but like I said it's
it's you know it's kind of the dark side
of looking at that kind of data
inflection so yes I mean it's definite
to it I probably missed it on the first
slide but when we're talking about data
again data collection points so I'm
trying to keep I keep throwing out
talking about the data that we're
generating but when we think about data
collection points and talking about
talking about s attendees throwing me
off place collection place we talk about
what were you know things that your
phone generates so location history your
search history you know IOT devices
listening devices
that kind of thing right so these are
the sorts of
I mean your I can stand here and give
you a one-hour lecture on data
collection points it's gonna be really
boring so I'm not going to do it big big
data again yes I mean big data now I
mean it's it's metadata right it's it's
all sorts of things that we are
generating in terms of our listening
habits our driving habits our
consumption habits what we buy food
where we buy food what times we buy food
what time we leave the house what time
we go to work who's in our household
you know medical conditions medical data
everything you can think of biometrics
how we do things has some interesting
research on biometrics one particular
one that I was looking at recently was
them by tracking on your computer so if
you're sitting in an office space and
you're doing your work and you've got
your Word document up and you don't want
your boss to see what you're doing
because you're actually playing
something else using the camera they can
monitor your eye tracking movements
actually correlate that with what's on
your screen so are you actually reading
the document that's on your screen or
are you doing something else I mean
that's just a very very kind of
breezeway throughout or looking at I
guess if you're if your manager leaves
the office and suddenly everyone's
walking to a particular area all you're
going to see a particular person
somewhere else in the office that you
might not necessarily be dealing with in
your everyday kind of operations why are
you going to see that person I mean you
can look at it from an insider threat
kind of point of view so you know
behavioral analytics again but again
it's a sort of tracking units and sort
of stuff that now is being looked at
it's the data state that's already been
collected but now it's they're finding
uses for it really social data or social
media data misuse you know rhetoric
Cambridge analytic and stuff which
Stefan will talk about later and again
then we go on about key key logging
third part third-party keyboards is an
interesting one I mean anyone who's got
a Google phone like a pixel and you've
got your what they call the G board if
you go into a Google account you can
actually look up all of the words that
you've added in your dictionary in lock
words you've actually typed within G
board so it's quite worrying really that
to think that actually everything you
ever type is being stored somewhere just
food for thought see ya which leads onto
what do you devices know about you so
yeah
a place you've ever visited a thing
you've ever told someone obviously we've
got Siri goggle that kind of thing
ought to be a standard kind of things
that you think of but when you really
kind of start deep-diving and thinking
about what do I actually have on my
phone whether it's my credit card
information or you know my emails my
text messages my whatsapp's my usage
very much traffic data when I'm going
you know what when I'm traveling here
from where I live and I'm looking on my
Google Maps or I'm using my Virgin
Trains information or once I get here
and I use my uber to get to the hotel or
trying to walk here and whatever right
to do so all sorts of kind of profiling
data building that white up data kind of
picture about someone so when we move on
from that we kind of enter the realm of
data profiling which is kind of where
I'm or one of my hats I suppose where
again so you start thinking about data
points and metadata this is the stuff
that we're kind of generating and as a
data profiler if I want to profile a
particular individual I want to know
what makes them think what are they
doing obviously I know I you know it
depends on why I'm profiling the buyer
need to know what they think what
they're doing what what their likes and
dislikes oh I can kind of get a
psychrometric profile from them to
analyze them for particular reasonable
way so now you have a treasure trove of
things we've got social media activity
yeah your likes and your shares on
Facebook straight or or any social media
I know straight away what sort of things
you like what sort of things you don't
like I mean that could be political it
could be just general kind of events it
could be your favorite movies or your
favorite music or whatever it might be
your status updates what are you
thinking about what are you doing your
check-ins where are you I mean Strava I
mean you everyone knows Strava the
fitness app right and then knew about
that issue last year about the actual
mapping of military bases through Fitbit
so don't need to go into that again
internet search history that's a scary
one
well I won't go too much in tax peanut
are self-explanatory YouTube twitch
again what videos you watch who you
watch you know what what is it about
those particular videos that you you
like to watch pornhub search history I
don't know what pornhub is May
be someone like explained to Alda to
have no knowledge of quanta whatsoever
but I hear that you know based on
people's pornhub history I mean can you
imagine looking at pornography without
going too much into detail it's a very
private thing why'd you do it at home
behind closed doors can you imagine what
someone can do with the information if
they knew your pornographic likes or
dislikes in terms of thinking of um a
psychrometric point of view right very
very scary when you think read it that
way and then couple that with your
Amazon search history you're gaming like
something I'll say so we're not just
talking about whether someone is you
know your basic kind of psychometric
stuff now we're really kind of getting
those really valuable deep dark kind of
indicators those data metrics about an
individual that become really depending
again on which way you look at it
whether you really want to investigate
them heavily or socially engineer them
for a particular reason I mean obviously
if you're looking it from a law
enforcement or an intelligence point of
view if you want to get an individual
more information on that individual pop
G I mean I put pub G up there
everyone knows play on the ground
battlegrounds right you know they're
like the cod online but the Battle
Royale type thing
that's an interesting platform actually
it's a it's an intelligence Trevor
treasure trove I'll just put it that way
in terms of people's conversations
within those servers and stuff I might
go into the sorts of stuff that goes on
in there and the sorts of things that
discussion that I discussed on there but
we're talking about dark web
transactions terrorism cancer yeah that
kind of stuff is quite it's quite scary
what people are saying on there and what
you know and who's listening
same with fortnight you'll be surprised
that the sorts of people that go on for
my on what they talk about that's what
I'm gonna say about that one free use
platforms I think one of the other talks
mentioned this before are they actually
free well oh yeah I mean therefore
they're free but you know you're you're
free because you're giving them your
data otherwise what's the point so from
there you would spoken about all these
data sets and their sources so building
psychometric profiles and I put Spotify
me there well Spotify got me is then
unaware of Spotify dot me probably not
of one good
of course is for you but yeah
so if I put that up so we all know what
Spotify is right yeah I'm a heavy user
of Spotify and I can't leave this
invisible wall here because of the
camera but then I've got on these
magical pen secondly so this was as of
January so again your daily mix is a bit
obvious you think yeah I listen to music
and what if I learns the source of music
that I like and I listen to and it
builds a profile and it kind of says oh
you know your daily mix one two three
four depending on your mood so lots of
things there from Dean Martin and Bing
Crosby all the way to some movie
soundtracks to Max Richter and you know
kind of showing different facets of my
personality right as to what I like what
I dislike and yeah that's helpful for me
because I want to just click on a daily
mix that I know I'm going to listen to
that kind of music and fantastic great
so why don't we do a bit of a deeper
dive though so I've got Spotify which is
your music streaming service which is
free yes it is free but you get ads or
you pay for your premium service and
then there's Spotify for brands which is
essentially what spots
what Spotify are doing with that data
that they're collecting you know sending
it to brands effectively I won't say
what brands and I won't say who is
buying that data but it's not just
advertisers I'll put it that way so if
you go on Spotify dot me it's actually
essentially like a I guess a I say
public but a user kind of front so that
you can potentially access or you can
access your more limited amounts of your
Spotify profile to actually see what
sort of data and psychometric profile
that they've actually gained off of you
or gain from your listening habits so I
kind of did that to myself you just have
a look so it came up with based on the
music that I like is really hard to read
so I'll have a look curious the stage
he'll according to your streams it looks
like you're into coffee house rather
than house all you need is a guitar mic
and maybe a latte so I'm assured
individual based on my music I mean I
know I like to think I've come across is
a chilled individual maybe it's not
coming across right now but then looking
again it says keeping at 100 here so
damn you like a lot of any
based on your listening we guess you
lose music through soundtrack your
workout and party moments so to two
slightly different sides of me there but
I would say to be honest that's that's
quite accurate because I like to live as
you saw from the daily mixer I listen to
lots of music depending on my mood and
being one that this is just a very very
scratching the surface of the sorts of
things that they're getting and then we
go on to the time of day that I listen
to music straightaway you think oh okay
I listen to music more at 7 p.m. and
maybe midday but there you've got a
little spike between 4:00 and 5:00 a.m.
and this was taken January 28th well
this was clay turd on January 28th so I
can probably tell you now that around
that time I was doing some work in the
middle of the light and I was polishing
work in the middle of the night and
coming home so interesting that that's
on there really and there there is a
little I'm not sure if you can really
see it there so but there's a little
location thing there so you can see your
timings based on other locations so
again looking at thinking well I listen
to music at what time you know those
sorts of times why is that interesting
but then again like I said I can gain
all sorts of information that coupled
with other things so if you're listening
to music at certain time base at a
certain location is that where you work
is that where your are you coming home
at certain time that builds a picture of
your your working habits or your daily
habits your daily routine what sort of
music do you listen to a certain times
maybe when your significant other leaves
the house you blast out you know thrash
metal and go crazy
but then when your partners in you keep
income whatever you know again so
building psychometric profiles is
there's quite worrying really like last
I said this is a very very kind of
surface scratch as to the source of
information and the source of profiling
that Spotify using one of the things I
will say with Spotify for brands is that
they're using this information to give
to insurance companies so for argument's
sake if you're driving your car and you
let's say I'll give you I'll give you a
hypothetical scenario you you are
driving you cut your car and you have an
accident
you crash into someone no one's hurt but
damage only whatever it might be
wouldn't it be interesting if the
insurance company could review this kind
of data and suggest well adapt
kela time you were listening to music
that had an average speed of 145 beats
per minute
therefore your heart rate was increased
therefore you're sinking perhaps or if
it was like a thrash metal or whatever
it was that indicates that you're
thinking at the time my you know might
be in line with the certain psychometric
profile therefore you may have taken
more risks so actually you may be more
liable for the accident therefore we're
going to void your insurance stand
silence or just maybe I'm losing people
I don't move on again like I said this
is just food for for here it's kind of
thinking about a lot of things that
there that's another you know all the
things that are kind of going on now so
we move on to listening devices you know
fantastic AI assistants I asked my
Google assistant all sorts of things all
the time about what weather is and you
know random questions and it usually
gives me the wrong answer because it
never understands my voice but yeah I
mean same thing I mean if again if
you've got if you've got a Google
listening device to Google home you can
go onto Google account and actually look
through your entire history and see and
go through the recordings of everything
that you've ever asked it you can play
back the recording which they say it's
useful their you know their voice
algorithms and all the rest of it but it
makes you wonder if you play back fat
and the whole passive listening thing
you know what else are they recording
what they listening to yes they might
kind of assure you with data proof seein
gdpr and and whatnot that you know
they're only recording and they're only
keeping some snippets but again there
are plenty of examples that you can find
online through Amazon and extra and
software in where conversations have
been recorded and sent on to employers
inadvertently or there's been actual
police investigations using things that
have been recorded through smart TV
devices and that was hypothetically yeah
hypothetically I will say a group of
individuals that were planning something
in a particular country something not so
nice and they were discussing it in
front of their Samsung TV and it was all
recorded on their smart listening to on
the smart TV and the authorities were
alerted I mean obviously that was a lot
of other kind of stuff going on there
but I'm not suggesting that
you guys are scheming horrible things at
home but it's just that now everyone has
a set of ears in their house so um I put
speech analysis there purely because of
we've all heard that line when we call
them you know if we call up I know fast
co-op's guy and I'm wanting to change my
package and you hear the whole this call
will be Mont you know recorded for
monitoring and marketing purposes or
whatever it might be
well actually doing now is using speech
analysis to again profile you determine
you know if you're in a bad mood not you
I find if I'm waiting on hold
I might just kind of talk calmly and I
actually get an operator who is licensed
to me it sounds a bit strange but if you
if you're on hold and you're there
cursing and all for goodness sake um
whatever more than likely the person
when they pick up the phone is going to
be quite standoffish with you because
they've been alerted that this but yeah
this is not happy also if you're calling
up about your insurance policies and
that kind of thing again they'll be
profiling you based on your
conversations and how you're interacting
and and that kind of thing so I mean
there's a lot of again there's a massive
deep dive that we can go into that which
we won't because we just don't have time
in household routines again knowing what
you're doing in a house and who you're
doing it with and what you're doing at
certain times and that kinda thing so
see this is all scary anything you know
now we're at this point we're thinking
everything I do is being monitored and
used against me I can't say anything
anywhere without some what you know a
phone or some device picking it up what
am I gonna do I'm gonna put my tinfoil
hat on and map myself up you know in
Faraday material and you know hopefully
you know I'm affect me so I mean I don't
need to talk about VPNs because we all
know if it VPNs are so I can kind of
skip college just skip that slide and
obviously women to talk about VPNs
that's just securing you know the track
you know the data transfer right it's
not actually you know we're talking
about what the company is at where the
data is going as opposed to it being
intercepted in transit so again so we've
talked about how come more how companies
storing data metadata for profiling
that's the big one profiling and
metadata everything we generate is not
you know everything in that you can
think of when you're buying your
supermarket shopping you're using a
Tesco Clubcard there a reason that
you've got loyalty cup club cards is to
profile what you're buying
where you're buying them and you know
selling that information to advertisers
you're browsing in you're purchasing
data again online for advertisers I'm
sure I mean it goes from the basic thing
on Amazon where you buy a book and it
says other users bought this based on
that or it might be I'm not sure of some
of you have noticed it but I notice
sometimes if I'm talking about a
particular subject when I'm at home or
somewhere else
the next time I go on my Amazon app
strangely enough it's suggesting that
you know there's this particular book or
there's this particular item that I
might be interested in and I just so
happened that I was talking about it a
couple of days ago that's really
worrying me
but again and then you kind of go into
the conversation of well are they
actually helping me and suggesting
things that I want or are they kind of
almost grooming me to want certain
things and there's an interesting TED
talk about that about the chapel's using
those sorts of techniques in advertising
where they're actually grooming people
to buy instead of suggesting to you that
you want a pair of these shoes or these
shoes are really nice and you might like
them it's almost as though these are the
shoes that you need they're creating the
demand for the shoe as opposed to
following you know the month of the shoe
if that makes sense
I mean they use the shoe as an example
so yeah so we're going into data misuse
does anyone know about ubers God view no
it's not really a pub is always not a
publicly accessible thing essentially
with good with with uber internally I
suppose they're their employees can
access that the uber tracking systems
they can see all of their overdrive
drivers and all of the users and where
they are and there was a bit of a misuse
issue when a reporter was due to be
meeting with an uber executive and was
late for the meeting so an employee
access assistant to see where they were
Buber slates and claimed that they only
use it for legitimate purposes and
whatnot but the fact that that is
accessible is a bit of a concern because
again anyone that has the uber app can
be tracked google deepmind and the wall
free they'll know about that kind of
misuse of data showing no okay the wall
free hospital in London obviously lots
and lots of medical records and patient
data they decided that there were
work with google deepmind and share 1.6
million patient records with the
deepmind
for as google say legitimate research
and kind of analytical purposes but
there was an assumes consent though
their patients weren't asked would you
like us to share your data with whoever
I'm not sure many patients probably
would have agree but the fact it was
just there was an assumption of well
it's our data more handover I'm still a
bit of a boo-boo there kami jamming it
occur everyone knows about that so when
you talk about that third I put
third-party permissions in frienemies
there that's an interesting concept
third party permissions we all know a
big one with Facebook they used to have
the and when we talk about data
ownership right and transferring
ownership to other parties you know
through consent to whatever and with
third party permissions if you think of
anyone on Facebook if you ever had one
of those quizzes that says find out what
your Lord of the Rings character is or
you know what what what day of the week
are you and then you go oh yeah I want
to find out you know if I'm Gandalf or
if I'm Frodo and you and you click on it
and the first thing it pops up is do you
give whatever access you know to see
your profile and did it do the most of
the time you just click you know might
whatever cuz I want to find out but I'm
Gandalf so you click on that and they
get access to your contacts or your your
profile and you do your quiz and you
find out that I'll know your Sam you're
not Gandalf that's a bit sad and you
forget about it and then you move on but
and then you forget that that permission
is still there and you you can deep dive
in your Facebook settings and actually
see all of the permissions for all of
these historic apps and even recently
like Farmville was one that haunted me a
long long time ago but yeah but that's
the sort of stuff that the general
they're creating these kinds of quizzes
and things to get access to your
facebook details I know a lot people now
are a bit more savvy to it so perhaps
it's not as big of a thing and I've put
frenemies there purely because an
interesting sort of again I've got to be
careful with how I've saying this book
is being recorded
in an open it wasn't OSINT earlier open
source intelligence and let's just say
hypothetically that's gonna be my magic
words per se when i say hypothetically
because it might not actually happen but
who knows maybe I'm telling the truth
but then hypothetically back in the day
of you know early Facebook days where
everyone was rushing to get you know how
many friends can I get meeting engine
time mate so um yeah how many friends
could people how many friends could
people have and they're kind of
accepting everyone and this and the
other so that let's just say that
potentially there could have been active
measures by certain law enforcement
agencies that say that would generate
kind of profiles based on new injury
individual let's say that Stewart there
on the front row has you know a total or
unlike for a particular type of
individual but I've found out about
based on his pornhub search history and
so I doctor this profile with a
particular profile picture and some
interesting details that students can
look at and go yeah actually yeah oh
yeah do I like do I know them oh I don't
know because you know I like that
picture so I'm gonna like them and
straightaway you've got access to
Facebook page somewhere argue that's not
open source it's a bit of a debate am I
going to I am we've covered Spotify so
I'm gonna start flying now because I've
been waffling and TLDR we all know what
that is right too long didn't read yeah
we all know that when you kind of
install itunes and then you've got to
accept the 76 page terms and conditions
and you actually read any of that
usually that's where they just stuff all
of this kind of thing so it's quite
interesting when you've got the time and
if you're that way inclined perhaps you
should take a look at the terms and
conditions but without further ado I'll
hand over to my colleague because
otherwise we're not gonna have any time
sure thanks Nick shame tell us X and
actually so benefits of station before
we do that I mean are you guys like just
out of interest cuz generations then
that most you guys are in that area I
think or the era of younger generation
are you worried about all this beta
stuff you know I mean before people say
oh I don't care but I mean now it's like
becoming kind of rapport I mean now you
don't know if you knew all this stuff I
mean you know we're we're research into
a lot of this with a lot of errors we're
looking into it but it the more you look
into it the more scary it gets to be
honest with you and you start to think
actually I don't wanna share
but we have to look at this this is you
know the the benefits of of you know
data sharing in a good way as well I
mean it means you want to look at its
medical why because you know we can all
put so many examples into this as you
know basically your longer to know
medical history everything from day one
right till now which could be a huge
benefit if you're in control of it
meaning you know if I go to India next
week I have an accident you know as long
as I'm conscious I can actually say to
him guys don't bother with all these
x-rays and everything you look I busted
my ACL some time ago be careful there
here's all my Asian history here at his
access to it without running every test
or whatever medical condition you've got
but you need to be in control of it you
need to know that's the ownership word
right interrupts ability I mean you know
all the silos of day I mean we came from
physical records which the only problem
with physical records is if someone
actually breaks in and steals and more
building burns down but now it's went to
electronic records which is great but
they're still held in silos still no
good to everyone because no one sharing
data so the interoperability is a key
one between many organizations many
hospitals many you know in the whole
ecosystem of medical care unless you
equation written repeats of data that's
obvious streamlining infrastructure
again that's obvious because that's all
commercially beneficial and I would say
end-to-end supply chain transparency
wallets commercially beneficial you got
to look at also it's actually beneficial
to us because think about drug that
custody the chain of custody for drugs
right I mean I'm talking about legal
ones yeah and basically you know
everything from is sauce where it's
manufactured right through to supply if
it's not tracked how do we know it's not
counterfeit we know that there's like I
can't even remember the exact stats ten
twenty percent of all drugs out there
are counterfeit you know legally so so
that's a key thing and then if you look
at the individual centric or patient
centric approach I was talking about
making that person responsible
themselves to actually who's accessing
are there as long as they can actually
see that sort of chain of custody
smart infrastructure we told you about
that so on a project where they're going
to be many projects like that and that's
what I'm talking about that data
explosion
you've got no choice in that and that's
going to interact with you when you
enter that zone it knows you're there in
fact you came here last week why don't
you hire that chair over there in cafe
Nero and have that clatter you usually
have how it's all going to interact you
that way so whether you like it or not
law enforcement there obviously for
safety of you know where we are what our
daily lives that says that's obvious
there it's a slightly advancement and
advertising we'll skip through that so
yeah smart wearable day are really so I
mean there's gonna be billions of
devices right I mean that's without a
fact Internet of Things is running that
kind of like ways forwards I would say
and this is 27 24/7 data collection
process so you know everything that you
know no longer we need to talk to a
patient basically we can put device on
them and capture everything in the cloud
and everything's seamlessly reported so
basically what's the danger that is is
well again I don't have the ownership of
it the institution has ownership that's
fine but I don't have any access to and
I don't have any control over it smart
cities many third part is accessing this
data and you know I'd want to cross to
much wonder show instead but that's kind
of what we're talking about there but
that flexible approach I'm talking about
if we could have some control then
actually you could decide if you want to
donate this data say like if I'm a
diabetic and actually I want to really
want to do something about that I'm fed
up of that condition maybe if I donate
something to pharmaceuticals in terms of
my data I don't even want to premium a
premium could be offered back to me but
I don't I'm prepared to donate globally
as a service part one of the things I
want back is maybe some something back
in terms of knowledge I'll get a report
from a pharmacy I'll get a report on
conditions and globally in the world and
the trends and what they're doing so I'm
not left in a dark that I think would be
significant yeah so I don't know how
many of you know aware of like the
digital twin kind of methodology right
so this is essentially what's happening
right now and it's it's going to explode
up because many reasons obviously one in
terms of efficiencies and terms of like
improve
all sorts of things but it's a
connection between the physical and
digital world and you know really
essentially using Internet of Things so
you know NASA was the first to develop
this technology in terms of simulation
what would he be like on Mars and all
that sort of stuff so that could
actually preempt everything in advance
you can you know create this virtual
product process facility and all sorts
as I say a massive demand you know look
16 billion as a market in 2023 Garner's
prediction 21 billion connected sensors
an input so you know it's huge benefits
are there it's real-time simulation
particularly if we model it on a person
we could actually I would say do
something on individually developing the
drug specific to them right so there are
those sorts of benefits you're talking
about but if we look at what the ethical
and privacy issues are whether there's a
lot there actually because it might be
actually a way of discriminating or
leter segmentation some it might not be
accessible for they may make decisions
say well there's no point giving this to
you because we've already assessed this
all artificially you know how far do we
go in terms of biohacking
to improve ourselves and you know this
therapy and human enhancement we're
talking about personalized medicines and
so on
so I'll just skip through cuz I know I'm
short on time so data threat factors I
don't think need to go up that much you
guys have seen some presentations today
you know who these kind of attackers are
what they do you know the individuals
are hari mal was a service
state-sponsored attacks and and so on
and the common methods right I mean
those are just a brand and bunch of
methods but they tend to be their most
popular ones and phishing still hugely
successful if you look at how they took
down a critical national infrastructure
in Ukraine in 2011 through a phishing
attack coordinating over many months of
course because once you're in you've got
to find out all the passwords before you
shut a power grid down so that's their
power of a state-sponsored attack and
cyber tech now hit quickly I mean you
know obviously that the main one that's
getting hit is healthcare primarily
because it's premium data why because
identity theft right
one a cry was an obvious attack you guys
all know about we live in the UK and
it's was a disaster that weekend and the
power grid stuff and of course you know
what's the main combination with dissing
correlation and some analysis in various
sectors but the main thing is malicious
Outsiders for the purpose of identity
theft right so they're really targeting
for identity theft so if everything's
held in trusted third parties well you
know the problem is it's like Swiss
cheese and some some operations
including health care particularly which
is why that gets hit a lot so what we're
saying is what we could do about well
there are some things like block
chaining me I'm not advocating block
change the thing there could be
something else that comes along that is
much better than that but at the moment
it gives you that kind of like
mutability or durability you know gives
you that increased security obviously
transparency protects that privacy and
so on how we do it well there's a number
of ways and my kind of models are
looking for industry it's more in the
permissioned and where data is held off
the chain so that we can just have it as
I think an authentication mechanism so
actually pretty much that date is still
held in cloud and data lakes but the
only way to access is through it is
through the blockchain and that's just a
moment one of the real quick model we
looking at I mean we've talked about
healthcare records you know we've talked
about those benefits so for patients and
so on and obviously commercially in all
that side of it all the way through to
using blockchain but in clinical trials
if you look at that then this is a huge
area where it really transparency if
they are ownership and all the issues of
privacy are all kind of having to have a
lot of problems and everything from
inform setting up a trial to inform
consent all the way to outcomes
everything seems to be selectively
reporting a lot of bias you end up with
drugs in the market that could have
problems as podu farmer who are back in
the newspapers again 26 billion they've
made and 200,000 people dead in the u.s.
because of opioid abuse so you know that
that is a major issue and identity then
so what does identity oh that's just a
Latin thing there which means I think
therefore I am
kognito ogle some but basically it's a
sum of attributes obviously what you are
about
person you know characteristics possible
numbers and so on of how we do it there
are a number of different ways and
basically how we're doing this at the
moment is how do we interact with our
identity we'd give it everywhere because
we have two insurance home insurance car
insurance whatever think about that you
have to give your details first as a
quote to get a quote rather before you
can actually buy a service maybe I don't
want these companies I just did it
recently myself because my wife's forced
me to do life insurance and I was
running out of time and unfortunately I
didn't think too much into and I put
this data right there now I've got all
sorts of phone calls all sorts of emails
and that's the disaster so so basically
a lot of people falsify their
information now I mean I do on sites
that you don't need where it's not on
official right because what's the point
of giving you a real name and date of
birth
so basically another way of this current
way of doing is it's what some guys
another presentation have said obviously
is through Google or Facebook log in
universal login
that sounds great it's ease of access
and all that kind of side of it but then
you've got the problems of obviously
giving permissions to all the third
party the trackers add trackers and so
on that now have access to all your data
you know your um oops yeah sorry that's
it yeah just me with pivoting around
access to your name you know your
birthday and all that sort of
information we've talked about Cambridge
at only America and that's exactly what
happened on that one so the future could
be that I mean it could be a self
sovereign I mean basically what we're
saying there is is you don't need to
rely on these third parties you have a
virtual you have a real identity of a
digital identity I'm in a virtual
identity a number of virtual identities
actually and this is a concept that's
been thought of out there there are a
number of companies looking at that it
is interesting so taken for example a
bank if you want to set up a bank count
I've been Banking with Berkeley since I
mean 14 years old why would I need to
give all my details again to Lloyds for
example you know I uncredible the rules
and so on right I'm just you know so
just an example of a bank name not to
say those to a particular but but if you
could give your virtual identity then
that would suffice it because as far as
that other bank the new banks concern is
they know that you're a bona fide you
person you're credible and have the
worthiness because
you're a virtual identity has been
obviously sanity checked in a sense of
whoever's and whoever could be looking
after this it could be something like
the future all of a bank so these are
some of the things that have been
thought about so in summary because you
can see there's any questions you can't
stop that experience your growth data
growth there's no way gonna stop that
that's happening there are many benefits
associate have talked about the
interment believe they are interchange
data sharing of course with our fish and
television machine learning it's all
gonna get better instruction because 80%
of the world's data is unstructured at
the moment so the more that can we can
help curate their data the more
intelligent will become however there's
a greater exposure as you've seen to
your privacy of data you know the less
transparency of how they or what use is
they're going to do with the day at this
data collection and this dilution of
ownership has already happened it's
already out there your name is already
you know reused so many times and your
details are reused so many times so if
we can't stop it then perhaps we could
have better control mechanisms was my
thought as a personal you know kind of
view on this presentation you know we
need to look at the legal
infrastructures and frameworks that's
something that government and and you
know organizations need to do but there
could be some things like blockchain or
digital identities and something we can
all do ourselves to have that
situational awareness of where and what
we do with our data as I gave you the
bad example of what I did a month ago
with my life insurance business you know
trying to get a quote which was just cuz
I was in a hurry so that it's kind of
like where we're at as the end of the
presentation and I just you know to kind
of like really pull it pull us along to
any questions or any thoughts you've got
any comments please Scott it and only
final thoughts emissions and say I mean
really but I think the whole point of
this presentation and think of the other
presentations that have been going on
today
like with Becker's one earlier about why
users are exploitive at security I think
we're really talking about we had
previously by design and security by
design obviously privacy by design is
the gdpr thing but you know ethical by
design really we're trying to not just
look at it from a mechanism point of
view or you know put all the onus on
companies and we're
science or whatever to make sure that
their things are secure and that they do
things in a particular way but almost
using that privacy or security by design
concept in the way that we think and the
way that we do things and being aware of
what's actually happening with our
nature and how it's being used and you
know we might be happy to be giving
certain sets of data you know in certain
instances but just being bit more a
little bit I suppose really but yeah so
that was a kind of a yeah flying field
Wars yeah yeah people make so much money
about why did we see companies getting
poor because they're selling some
devices they're not they're getting good
for the day that's it so do you have any
questions yes yes essentially you're
saying different companies are creating
or building these data to all these
profiles based on your data so whether
it's in silo from Facebook or Google or
Amazon or whoever forever and by
themselves that's fine because you give
them certain data but you're asking so
who is it that's actually looking at the
whole overview government agencies I
suppose well I don't suppose oh yeah so
I think that's the thing so like out
alphabet Inc for example who own a lot
of companies so even though these
particular companies have certain
snippets or certain kind of slices of
your data pie as it were
yeah these larger kind of umbrella
companies will then hold larger chunks
and then if I'm talking from a profiling
point of view
so if you're thinking of law enforcement
where you start kind of taking these
sections and building this data profile
and obviously in if we're talking about
kind of how I phrase this Western
democracies let's say where you trust
the government 10 perhaps that's fine
because everything's toward but perhaps
you're kind of if you then think of a
more dystopian future or government's
where if they've got access to this kind
of data again I mentioned Shenzhen in
China purely because they're actually
profiling people and seeing how they
rank according to the Communist ideal
that's very dangerous right hmm yeah
yeah no exactly and nothing but and
exactly and and that's what and that's
where the that's where the ethical bar
design kind of concept comes in about
you know ensuring you know and we talk
about democracy in everything that the
powers at play you know making sure that
you know they're governed appropriately
so that if they're handling our data
that they're doing it perfectly right
but obviously but we need to be aware
about what's actually happening so then
we can actually govern you know how it's
being treated because otherwise if we
don't know then it just gets abused and
abused I suppose yeah sorry I know yeah
yeah I mean yeah yeah it's fine I mean
yeah I mean sorry guys I mean I know I
waffled on a lot I mean it is an issuing
subject but