thanks guys thank you so as you can see
I'm gonna be talking about the good the
bad and the ugly of coordinated
disclosure and I'll get into a bit of
that later on
so first up Docs to myself Who am I I am
NOT a big fan of these lights but we'll
say is I've had a really good year and
if you're interested in anything that
I've done and saw more about my
background you can head over to my blog
and you can always hit me up on Twitter
with any questions or anything at all
and what I'd like to speak about today
is more about the background and the
stuff that people don't hear me talking
about because I can't most of the time
and so it's more of the circumstances
around disclosure and my personal
experiences and if you can take
something from that that'd be brilliant
so disclaimer back in my head at the
moment I'm thinking this is a really
terrible idea but at the same
time you know I'm not a lawyer or a
vulnerability disclosure expert please
take anything you feel when you see
today and you know make some good use of
it a lot of you here will be students
and you'll be learning some bits and
pieces that I didn't when I first got
into it please don't go out and hack
systems that you have no authorize
reason to do so and you know don't use
any of the stuff that I have here today
with regards to justification for doing
that it's first up a history lesson this
is Alfred Charles Hobbes I would call
him a bit of a old school hacker now
what he did back in 1853 was pick locks
and what he would do here we go around
finding the best locks of that day and
time and he would set himself challenges
and breaking those locks and he would
he'd actually get into them and you know
it caused a bit of fuss was doing it now
at the Great Exhibition in Crystal
Palace in 1853 he was set a challenge to
break one of the locks it was a bronze
lock
and the manufacturers gave him a set of
blank keys and a lock and said you have
30 days in which to break this lock now
Alfred here he's pretty good at what
does and he managed to do it in 24 days
of course there was a big fan for her
about it but what did the manufacturers
do they took it negatively and they
actually turned around and said well the
lock was broken there was something
wrong with it they didn't believe for a
minute that they were at fault now this
caused a lot of controversy and Alfred
wasn't shy of controversy at all he then
went on to publish a paper that detailed
all the different problems with the
locks of those days the vulnerabilities
and also detailed about safes he felt in
his mind that people needed to know
about him and you can see here rogues
are very keen in their profession and
know already much more than we can teach
them so he's basically saying the bad
guys know this stuff so what we should
do is like the public know about it so
they can best protect themselves so how
do you let people know about the
problems now there are a couple of
different ways of disclosure first one
is non-disclosure and this can be a case
of where you're working for a company
and they've been told to do some
research or a security test on a vendor
like a product or something like that
and you'll sign a contract it'll be you
cannot talk about those problems also in
addition to this you have people
researchers who will find out about
problems and they will keep it to
themselves you'll have government
organizations find out about these
problems and they will stockpile them
for their own good you also have people
who will possibly get into a NDA with a
zero-day organisation who buy these
vulnerabilities
but basically the point is you keep
mouth shut
which brings us on to our next one
coordinated disclosure so when I started
doing my slides and I was talking to
people on Twitter one of the guys that I
was talking with he said oh actually I
called it responsible discussion he said
well actually some of the people want to
call it coordinated me explain why and
some of the reasons were is that
responsible disclosure might send the
wrong signal some people prefer it but
coordinated with something that
Microsoft kind of pushed for when one of
their own actually published a report
some years back on the whole subject of
full disclosure
so now industry's adopted coordinated
which shows pretty much everyone's
working all together on something so the
purpose of this is when you'll find
something you're reported to the vendor
and you'll go through a process it's a
two-way thing and there could be other
parties involved
you could have bug bounty programs or
maybe some external agency like the FBI
now there are some problems with
coordinated disclosure we have pretty
much a waiting game us as researchers
have to disclose our vulnerabilities and
then we wait now Google zero they have
theirs as 90 days and then they'll
release but as you can see from here
that timeline can extend so you know it
could be in a think up to eight eight
months there some of mine are nine
months nearly enough a year and that
shows in its sense that you have to have
some level patience but if you don't
want to have patience and you just want
to get out there
here comes full disclosure
so I have it's in full disclosure it is
a case of yeah dropping it like it's hot
you will see this where guys will go on
to Twitter
they'll have blog post and they'll
release and it's released for the most
public exposure possible now their
motives may be one of their own exposure
for credibility within the industry for
their own ego or it could be because
they actually want to let the public
know about this to better protect
themselves going back to our Fred's
point but this can get you into some
bother and a lot of trouble
understandably vendors don't always like
here when you go full disclosure on them
and this isn't something that's new so
here's pizza psycho ok Lodge much from
the loft and he's actually part of the
loft hacker collective and the cult of
the dead cow I'm just going to play this
video as get run out on any city that's
crimes as a group the cult of the dead
cow gained worldwide attention for
releasing hacking tools that let users
take control of Windows software forcing
Microsoft to confront security problems
with its programs I've released several
security advisories on various pieces of
commercial software which have prompted
vendor patches which means they improved
the software after we pointed it out to
them unfortunately many times they would
not improve the software until we
actually went public with the findings
companies do indeed want to ignore
problems as long as possible it's
cheaper for them wait
oops sorry my bad
go back a slide not be like I'm a new
virilis stuff okay let's see is it on
fullscreen though it's not is it it was
okay let's go back then right
I'll just leave like that for the moment
um so basically what we have there we
have him saying 20 years ago mind you
that the only way you get things to
change was to go full disclosure and as
you if you were at the bear farmers
talked earlier on you would have seen
some incidents where people have come
out about issues and we're still having
it this day and age you know researchers
are either getting frustrated or feel
the need to go full disclosure in public
and the problem is as well we have laws
that are being used from the 80s and
they don't give us any kind of
protection either so what will happen is
we will then end up in a lawsuit to be
fair and part of this problem is
sometimes it's really hard to navigate
not only do we have the laws to think
about we have standards and then the
vendors will implement their own Terms
of Service you look at a product and
Katie's even helped the bug bounty
community really really like a lot and
there are now bug bounty programs that
help researchers who want to explore and
have a look at things but admit she had
a look into things as she saw the Terms
of Service in one of the vendors
products for bidded someone from being
able to investigate
now that's within a bug bounty program
that's somewhere we're supposed to be
allowed to have a play but yet the Terms
of Service contradict it so what we need
ourselves we need a lot more safe
harbors places
we're free to research and have a look
we need a clearer understanding of the
term service all the end-user license
agreements the laws and we need some
guidance for it and here I've got
emitters alazhari I've also got mischeif
who Saskia and she's in the UK and she's
been looking at standards and laws and
she's really good kind of like putting
big red circles around wording and you
know pointed out and she's helping us in
that regard and also Katie at the end
there so what do we do we have this thin
line that we could cross anytime we have
laws that say to us so you can or you
can and this is how you go about it and
there is not much guidance at all but
then we also have this issue where we've
been going through something with a
vendor and we may face problems they may
drive us crazy we may get very
frustrated and it then Bulls down to a
moral compass of that person I've I know
friends who are really good researchers
and stuff and they've had to drop stuff
and you know make it public and or
they've had to sell how many now no guys
have turn around to me said yeah
security research is doing really well
you know they do talks and everything
else but I've never known one person not
to do badly by selling zero-days you
know if it's less problems why wouldn't
you but then it's a moral guidance and I
love this word anonyme it's the
condition in which society provides
little moral guidance from individuals
and I think we have some of that within
our industry and we need guidance from
our peers and our the people above us to
help us know what to do in certain
circumstances now if you don't want any
of those problems sometimes you head
over to the bug bounty programs and it's
very good you can go and enter and work
with a vendor and they'll have a triage
process and everything will go quite
well and then you may get a pop payout
but then you may also get a dupe or a
big class or something like in
information it's not relevant you get
nothing so
you spent maybe you know nights or weeks
even on something for nothing but some
people in recognition and that's fine
and some people want payouts and the
financial problems though the finance
with it
I think the bug bounty programs
themselves have actually led to possibly
and expected expectation of like having
money and that can lead to extortion now
one of the problems that we've had to
come up it's quite an interesting case
was uber uber had a bug bounty program
and their payout was ten thousand now
that's fantastic you find a problem with
uber you get 10 grand these kids found a
problem with uber they then proceeded to
download 50 million users details they
then approached uber and said 10k I
don't think so I want more and they got
away with it
uber caved in and I needed to behave in
they also got into other like legal
problems because they hid the fact they
happen um but they actually caved in so
these guys thought you know he's
brilliant I'm now gonna go ahead and do
it to someone else just what exactly
what they did and then they got arrested
for extortion you know but the president
was set they thought they could get away
with it and do it what we have today is
standard so we have the ISO 29 147 and
the ISO 3166 and there are really valid
valuable documents to actually look at
and read so you can actually get the
tooth
14 version for free Katie made sure that
people could get hold of this
unfortunately it wasn't long before the
2018 version came I've got all three
versions I compared the 2014 version to
the 2018 with a different tool and there
was extensive changes not just the page
count but you had the scope that was
different the terminology that was
different
mention of stakeholders reading through
it it's a brilliant document but reading
through it didn't feel like he was
written for us it feels like it was
written for the vendors and the
companies and fair enough there is no
standards that's who they should be
written for but the same time what do we
have but if you're gonna get into bug
Bannion programs or you're gonna get
into vulnerability disclosure please go
and read these because it will help so
the one on the iso twenty nine one four
seven on this side
that's how vendors would deal with a
external vulnerability disclosure to
them and the 3111 works with that in a
sense and it it deals with the internal
processes and I've had to watch talks
and I've had to read different papers
and around that see kind of understand
what these documents do because half the
time when you read in terms of service
and legal stuff and ISO standards if
you're not from like you just don't
understand it you can read it however
there are some really good people like I
said before you have Katie and you have
Amit and they're actually lowering the
entry of being able to understand this
stuff with some of the talks that
they've done that's one of the diagrams
from one of the standards that diagram
appears in both standards and it shows
the flow of what happens in in
circumstances of whether it's external
or whether it comes in internally and it
shows them how to deal with it because
some of the times we will report a
vulnerability to a company and they
won't have a vulnerability management
program at all in fact they won't even
know what to do with it at all
at that a lot so yeah please check out
their talks they're really good and
these girls brilliant they're so spot
the difference this is the cirque guide
very similar document it's not an iso
standard it's a guide more of a report
but it shows the flow from the finder
who would be us security researchers and
then you've also got the finder on the
iso standard also so there are some
differences between them that one there
looks more complex but there's also
something that's the same can anyone
tell me what might be the same no before
Andy if you have a look if you have a
look at the finder you'll see that the
arrows are one way the communication
doesn't never go back to the finder so
we have vendors who actually reading
these documents looking at the diagrams
to make sense of this stuff and they're
getting the wrong visual cues it yeah
exactly
it doesn't make sense and Saskia
originally brought this up in her talk
and I looked at it and I thought right
okay she's worried hundred percent and I
had looked at sir and they were the same
however sir a very receptive of
amendments and changes now Allen reached
out to me on Twitter when he knew I was
doing my talk and I'll tell you one
thing yeah being able to speak to
someone who's actually an author of one
of these documents firsthand when I know
the the loopholes that you have to jump
through to even get any changes or speak
to people with regards to the ISO
standards I find out the ISO standards
people the other day and they said right
you need to speak to the BSA I find up
the BSI this is right you need to write
us an email we'll forward it through to
the right people because it's the people
who like Cisco Microsoft all these big
companies who are dealing with it
you don't get that one-to-one
communication as a researchers be like
I've got an idea will you do something
these guys broke to me on Twitter I told
him I said can you look at the arrows
sure yeah all the arrows are pointing
away from the finder nothing goes back
it's like sure no problem next revision
gonna get changed so small wins right
it's also very readable it's realistic
and it feels like it's being actually
written for our security researchers the
first time I've read something I've been
like I totally agree with this unless it
does feel less bureaucratic overall I
sat down with a bunch of guys online and
we had a look and their mixture of hats
and for the first time had a bunch of
hackers talking about Lauren
legalization and standards and they
loved it you know they said yeah a
hundred percent they agree with the
stuff that was in there and they were
really happy that standards and stuff
are moving forwards to help them so
please go and download it it's free so
you don't have to pay for it to 121
pages and it's a really good read really
good read so I need a drink of water
before I start this part I need a
whiskey as well so as you know this talk
is about the good the bad and the ugly
and because I wanted to end up on a high
I started with the ugly first I didn't
want to depress anyone so we're gonna
start with the ugly and the first one up
is who is calm so it's my first ever bug
yeah go me I had no idea what I was
doing at all and I found it pretty much
by accident I was sat online one night I
had my VPN on I was doing some awesome
work and I had a check it was checking
out some details basically I put a
website into who is and for some reason
all the details are showing
annealer to be true with some American
sites and stuff like that but post GDP
are you shouldn't be able to put a UK
site in and get details right that's not
right at all so I was like okay I'm
stupid I've done something wrong so when
and I did another domain name and that
one all the details were redacted hang
on a minute I went back to the other one
and the details were redacted was I seen
things no I checked through the code and
I could see what they were doing so
basically what they were doing was when
you did a request they were actually
sending through and pulling another page
called requests PHP now that this
request PHP page would then update the
the website page with all the details
and since gdpr what it's been doing is
refreshed in the database so then it
just shows all as redacted but because I
was on a shitty VPN and the connection
was so slow by the time it got to me it
hasn't got through so I was like okay I
found something possibly and it dawned
on me holy like this is post UDP oh
we've got all these people status I know
there were there previously but
afterwards this is kind of like a bit of
a breach so I sat down and I wrote some
code that would go through who is calm
and their entire database and grab all
of the domain names and all of the
details as well just as a proof of
concept
not for nothing nefarious at all and I
issued an email to them I tried to get
hold of the right people I was having no
luck I spoke to one of the chat agents
and he wanted me to give everything to
him over the like the plane and I'm like
no not happening can you put me through
to someone I literally I was it was it
was a bit bull like to prepare so what
did I do
newbee started how I went through to a
disclosure Assistance Program and it was
an experience in itself
barony - cited this in July 2018 and I'm
still emailing people now I'm going to
show you the actual a video of it
happening see as you can see here and
pull in the details you've got the name
address postcode all the registration
states I did it once twice three times
for luck just to prove that I could do
it and I was saving these details to a
little file and as you can see I've
actually called it domain protect
because what I was trying to do then was
figure out a way of how I could protect
these details if who is calm will let in
anyone be able to do this and I surely
wasn't probably the only person doing
this how could I figure out a way to
code in a protection mechanism so it
pulled the details so what happens now
is I go to the same domain do my search
yeah I've got she ain't that right and
see it's showing the details but what
you'll see up in the top corner it says
updated three hundred and forty days ago
and that's the little indicator just
tell me that I was actually having a
successful find so if we go back just to
show you and I'll try and bring that up
[Music]
if you look again on the top hand corner
you'll see a little round dis thing it's
got cop dated three hundred forty days
ago and that's how I knew that it was
actually working well because that was
all part and parcel tied into the strip
the there refresh PHP so there I go
again I've pulled it again oh so when I
do my bad
Co the registering contact details are
there I run my script pulls the details
again I go back to the site I let it run
through and then all the details
disappear because it's been updated I've
run the code and it can't pull any
details awesome
so who is dot-com if I was who is and I
had someone telling me about I'd be
really interested I possibly breach but
it's been a matter of delayed responses
it's been broken down just like nine
months so I break it down the first
three months I was waiting on anything
to actually get done and for the right
people to be informed so then that was
July time - by September 6 hacker one
got in touch with them disclosed a
report they have a system where they
send them an email and they'll let them
know about everything happening and
they'll have a link to click on and I
didn't know any of this stuff was going
on in the background
completely unaware because what actually
happened with my ticket was my ticket
got put into a category
where it's non-responsive vendors so I
was like literally sending loads of
messages loads of messages to Hakka Wan
to anyone like we would listen and it
was like screaming into the void
because no one was getting back to me
because when you're in that category
they don't get notifications which is
wrong
finally I bumped into one of the guys a
conference and I asked him about it and
he gave me his telephone number and I
spoke to him and he was really helpful
really helpful and then from there it
got changed and then it was back into
the right category again which then we
proceeded to look at the emails and the
communication between hacker 1 and who
is so who has sent an email that claimed
it was not an issue they literally wrote
an email where they detailed the problem
extensively and said oh it's not an
issue but what she happened was they got
told 6 September the 6th and then
between September the 7th and September
the 10th the code got changed anyway how
do I know this because of the wayback
machine it's a brilliant thing and then
I was trying to draw my process of
trying to find out what was going on and
I was getting no reply back from hacker
1 I was reaching out - who is - and
there was a complete communication shut
down they just would not talk to me they
said no go and speak to hack 1 we've
spoken to them and I've reached out as
well and told them about doing a talk
today and no response I mean as you can
see and it's very very light you can
read it
hello Cristina yes they reached out to
us regarding the supposed funder ability
sorry I've got of like a video of it
working quite well and and we have
responded to their email with the
explanation that it wasn't the case you
may reach out to hack 1 to obtain
information about our response to their
email the case is now being closed so
for that it got fixed and end of case
yeah but what could I have done in that
circumstance I could have found that and
I could just dropped it on Twitter then
every single hacker would have
gone out and scraped all the details of
any one that they could and I know there
are companies that have already got the
database details but I didn't because my
moral compass at that time was telling
me to do the right thing they comment so
basically it really is unacceptable and
what I've done I'm pursuing it I know
there's very little that hacker one can
do I know there's communication shutdown
with who is and I don't know if I'm
gonna get any for saying about it
but basically I did do all the right
things but what I did do is I wrote a
two-page report to hacker one to see
taylean all the timeline and any
questions I had about it and then room
for improvement because obviously I want
other researchers to do well if they
don't have anywhere to go the disclosure
assistance programs there to help them
and I want them to have the best
experience I don't want anyone been nine
months down the line and still like
having issues so yes so I've written a
report to hopefully that will help okay
the bad I guess Bell Microsoft Office
365 here's Gary
Gary's assist admin and he's adopted
office 365 to improve productivity in
the workplace in fact he's got half his
users now using mobile phones and
they're sharing documents and it's
really good
and here's Kevin Kevin's a happy hacker
he has cool stickers but very bad
intentions and he's been trying for
months to get into Gary's Network and to
get to his users but because Gary is a
really good admin he's got two-factor
authentication on his user accounts so I
can't get in yet so gonna give you a
crash course on Microsoft Office 365
subscriptions just in case you don't
know about them so we have different
types of accounts we have admin accounts
normally global admin accounts and then
they vary between like billion
administrator and these kind of things
but essentially you have the keys to the
kingdom if you have Wellings then you
have a subscribed user account
now these subscribed user accounts they
normally come in with different packages
so I know it's not very good you can't
really see it that well but you have
either a monthly subscription base and
that's the way that office 365 is pretty
much moved towards or you can have like
a one-off for home users and it's
one-off fee but the difference is
between them is the stuff that you can
access so if we have a look here this
office 365 is the business one 7-pound
90 month and you get your outlook you
can get Excel Word onedrive but you
don't get SharePoint so what you'd need
to do you'd have to buy it as an extra
button which would cost like three pound
80 per month then you also have the
other packages up the way which also
include SharePoint these ones this one
here doesn't but the rest of them do so
these users can only access the products
that they're paying for and then
anything else that they want basically
they just have to upgrade their
subscription everyone understand that
cool right so we have the online
versions of Office Word Excel PowerPoint
SharePoint et cetera and Microsoft has a
really good business model in fact
they've got 155 million active users
with a growing growth of 3 million per
month that's a lot of money you know
even if you've got the very basic
account so to get a lot of raise our
hands right so say if you're a admin and
do you think you'll be able to access
everything all these different products
packages anyone do you think you would
yep yep how about a subscriber user
who's got a let's make it more precise
so safe we've got the SharePoint and
we've got the the business one that we
had there
shows as no sharepoint you think they
could get sharepoint if they wanted they
tried what happens here and is part of
the problem is that microsoft have made
it a free-for-all shock not only can the
admin account get into sharepoint
standard if you're a subscribed user you
can get into sharepoint standard if you
have a shared mailbox account you can
also access sharepoint if you have an
unlicensed account you can access
sharepoint and how do I know this
because I like around on my
computer just pretending to be user and
seen what I can get away with and that's
how I found it just going through a
normal process of just testing things
and seeing what works and what doesn't
it's not a groundbreaking discovery nor
is it a zero-day but is bad and it's
putting people at risk yep so that's
Gary and Kevin so what is the problem
here shared mailboxes can access
sharepoint and so can unlicensed so
Gary's a really good admin as we said
he's got two-factor authentication on
all of his user accounts but Gary
doesn't know you need to put two-factor
authentication on a shared mailbox user
because why would you generally speaking
they don't have passwords but what's
actually happened recently is that
Microsoft has allowed people to be able
to assign a password through a shared
mailbox and this is because they can
then get on their phone because when it
comes to mobile phone support with
Outlook Microsoft is a little bit
lacking on anything notes the shared
mailbox room so now that shared mailbox
has a password it doesn't have two
factor authentication
Kevin can now get into the accounts also
with an unlicensed exactly the same
situation now an unlicensed subscription
it would probably be someone who's left
the company and what they've done is
they've handed in their phone so there'd
be no two factor authentication really
if it's to be fair I don't think
everyone out there does put two-factor
authentication on them up Microsoft
Office 365 accounts I mean the average
score is something like 39 if you go by
the secure score on the tenants and that
can be improved by it by adding stuff
like that what's worse is with the share
bot the shared mailbox accounts the
monitoring is turned off by default
within the audit logs you have to
specifically do a PowerShell command for
it then - showing up how do I know this
because I found it and then I had to do
this because I was like where's all the
details of who's been logging in and
everything else with these accounts then
but small business user who just gets
office 365 to help them to be more
productive they're not going to
necessarily know about this stuff and
why because Microsoft do not document it
at all
now they know about where they've
actually got when I spoke to them
they've got a flag that should be turned
on for the tenant and basically what
happens is that restricts anyone getting
into SharePoint until so what can you do
when you get into SharePoint you can
view everything you can actually export
rate data you can then edit create and
remove groups he can then upgrade his
own account to add additional services
like flow or outlook and this causes a
problem because what he can then do he
can then send Gary a link or someone
else from another department and say hey
there's a new SharePoint site and then
they'll click onto that and then he
could be hosting all sorts of malicious
links everything that he wants and this
is the audit log and didn't show
anything
in fact it's not even turned on by
standards so you have to even go through
the house off that you can get
information gathering by having a look
at the search so you don't even need to
touch the sites themselves so you can go
through to the search part and if you go
into the classic search it's really
handy because it actually shows you a
visual representation of the site itself
so then all you need to do then is clone
that site you can clone that site and
then send a link to somebody else to
your own site where you're hosting the
malicious links and the admin would not
even know so here's an example of data
exfiltration so what I did is I got a
shared and unlicensed and I upgraded
this the subscription to add flow now
flow is a way of automation within
Microsoft and what I did is I I copied
every father was being uploaded from one
SharePoint site to another and this
other site the admin didn't have any
idea about can see it and the only way
that he could do it wasn't even showing
on his frequent sites because he'd never
been there and someone's gonna end up
getting hacked I mean it's not known
about
I mean Microsoft were really good about
this whole situation but and I'm a
Microsoft Research security team were
really good about this situation the
problem is I had is that they took the
report and said it was valid was going
to be added to the Microsoft Hall of
Fame and then he went slowly south the
SharePoint engineering team didn't agree
they said it was a licensing issue and
not a security issue I'm very sorry
I've tried fighting for this and he did
and my heart goes out to him because his
head's probably banging off a desk every
day if this is what's happening with
something I found I don't know what's
going on but I'm sure there's a reason
and that reason was with them we can't
read it from here it caused friction
with SharePoint adaption so basically
when they started releasing SharePoint
they had all these licenses but
none of the people will activating the
licenses so they just made it a
free-for-all sit all right then we'll
just turn it on for everyone and then if
they's at leas if they don't they don't
they allowed everyone basically into the
tenancy and see the SharePoint it's no
like I said but it's not documented and
the way that I can actually do it is by
just going on a link all I need to know
if I'm a hacker is this link here and
this is the main SharePoint page so I'm
on my admin account right now and I'm
now on a ship so I'm gonna shared cells
at victim account all I need to do is
put in the link and I've got access to
the all the sites there but there's
nothing much on there at the moment it's
just a development one I've not accessed
instincts I haven't gotten the frequent
sites but what I'd mean Gary is standing
is a really helpful guy he's put a list
of all the frequent sites for his team
members I can see all this so there's a
team group and that's private and the
settings are made as private and that's
brilliant it's a team group for an
organization now bearing in mind you go
and get a Microsoft Office 365
subscription and you pay for SharePoint
for anyone that you want in your
organization to see SharePoint anyone
else you would assume that they're not
going to be able to see any of this
stuff so you make it for the
organization but then the little hacker
man here he can go in god this Internet
and I tell you another thing that you
can do you can create a site and you can
create news posts do what you want you
can add news you can add links you can
get to the documents do everything that
you want it's pretty sure to prefer
I have not had a look at too much in
detail on this or staff is specifically
around this and if you want to work on
something every good yes so what can you
do about it so I've had a look at this
thing so I mean like I'm no expert but
this is the sort of stuff that I've
figured out so far you can review the
SharePoint default configuration
settings you can review the logs and set
alerts specifically for your shared
mailboxes and your unlicensed users you
can restrict down a lock down where
possible now there are configuration
files in the back and the SharePoint
where you can do it you can also ask
Microsoft for that flag and I tell you
if you can and ask them about it maybe
something might actually be done about
this please delete all unused accounts
because they're just sat there waiting
to be used by someone else
activate share but shared mailbox
monitoring and what will happen is it
will actually show up in the audit log
so where I've been messing around there
let's see now this isn't turned on by
default let's see if it's shown anything
nothing so so to complain to Microsoft
and update the documents because all the
documentation don't show it was working
right okay so I've literally not got
very much time and I've got more
exploits to show you that I found so
this was some secure application I can't
name for legal reasons reason being they
wanted me to sign in NDA
this was a blind XSS fire an embedded
widget on the victims site so the main
thing for me to point out here a
customer would embed the widget on their
site this would then provide a
communications channel say like a
comments box or a message ice box or
thing this would then feed into a
platform that the admin of that site
would log in to what it was possible to
do is
just put a load of xs/s into there so as
soon as the admin opened up the admin
panel on the portal they would then see
this message and get attacked you get
hacked that's what happens okay I
remember the little Cloe from earlier on
slide sometimes feel like this because I
found this issue through due diligence I
do because of my company that I work
with I try and check any apps that we're
taking on board and I was like what
you're actually supposed to be a secure
application yeah I could do this and
then literally took five minutes today I
asked them when I put through the report
to them for a secure Channel and they
told me to send it through the same
means and it just fell off so they
didn't know about bug bounty programs at
all and as soon as I talked about maybe
a reward and I was more interested in
the library that they would use him
because it wasn't the reward I wanted to
get off them it was perhaps a third
party library that they were using in
which case it would be more valuable for
me to know however their devs were kind
of off and so were they so what I did is
I created my own NDA and I signed it and
I sent it and their detailed report with
videos were submitted now I've just eat
held my points of view on this no
systems are harmed I'll produce a report
and it's done with the mind of the
researchers protection and the rights
and the confidentiality I state that
I'll keep it confidential for 90 days
after fix and I was very willing to work
with them as much as possible for this
to be a positive thing I then got an
email back where they basically said yep
sure no problem they've signed it but
then there's CEO has actually detailed
here the nature of any such agreement
will be at the sole discretion of the
platform as it deems appropriate to the
impact of the finance on its key
business objectives I found XSS in
multiple places of their system and
they're a secure site
I would have thought that that would
have impacted their business models
significantly so they patched it
arranged a few pen tests and further
support is all done
they assist it is not severe basically
these developers that I kind of felt a
bit off about previously have ty Rena
said oh no no no no that was an issue at
all it wasn't a problem and downplayed
it so even if you're speaking to a
company maybe the developers are working
with might have other ideas and what can
you do in that sort of situation
the CEO asked for the extent of the
vulnerability so I did another rapport
and another video and I said to him look
this is serious is this an exercice you
know I can do this showed them different
attacks and as part of this the
developers have actually said that they
had measures in the background that
would prevent this clearly not I did it
so this is going over a long period of
time then I got an offer a 75-pound this
is a company that's actually had
investment funding for the security of
the platform and I'm not money driven at
oh I can't care but what frustrated me
was the fact that the developers or the
client because of the developers were
perhaps saying something different would
just not get in the severity of
everything what else they tried to do
try to say yeah we'll give you 75 pounds
and you can have a free subscription for
three months on our program but we want
you to sign up to 12 months with our
system and also their NDA was indefinite
meaning I could not talk about it ever
which I felt was unfair I said 90 days
so basically they gave me 10 days to
reply and I was too busy doing other
stuff so I didn't bother sometimes you
just need to know it's worth drawing a
line and walking away because they're
not going to listen good so the blue
infall upload vulnerability I don't know
if any of you guys have heard about
before basically it's one of the largest
github repos out there with like 8,000
Forks and 30,000 stars I didn't find it
but my friend Larry did I reached out to
Larry said I was really interested in
this could I have a look at things and
he was brilliant I spent a whole weekend
working with him writing one of my first
official reports and it felt brilliant
having that kind of support and I think
that's one of the things as security
researchers you grow that little
community around you to help you and it
helps massively so the problem with this
was you had the ability to upload any
file type due to lack of checks you have
the ability to upload to the service
route due to miss configuration issue
you also had a problem where the
developer had put in security mechanisms
but because a patch he'd updated its own
configuration files it then superseded
the protections that the developer put
in place so that was another area of
problems so the good things a bit I
found that a platform had in being using
the file upload library and then they
were then passing distributing their own
platform it's quite popular so they
actually responded to things and managed
to get it resolved within 48 hours
it was patched within their own platform
it was brilliant and they were really
good about it also the developer of
Bloom was really good he's actually
written some security documentation how
to configure everything properly and
that was a really positive experience
the report that I wrote Larry then
distributed to the Akamai's security
research research team and his managers
and then he also gave me a shout-out on
the echo my blog and let me just go back
to that one and I guess from this one
here the point is when I did this I
looked into it and I wanted to send out
vulnerability reports to other people
who might be using this because there
are 20,000 other sites that could
possibly be affected by this and even
though when I did it no one got back to
me I still feel that it was a good end
to something I was working on because of
the support
because worked with different people
including CD nsj so they host all the
JavaScript right to make it quicker for
web developers and what we wanted to do
we wanted to cut the head of the snake
and possibly use a redirection technique
where anyone who was using the old
versions of the blue imp library would
then be forwarded to the new and we had
the discussion now obviously with that
you could actually probably brick sites
so we didn't go ahead with it but was
still very positive discussion and
something where researchers should look
into in the future so a nun named C
called for paper platform this is
something that's going on at the moment
it allowed for other people to see data
about another person by entering their
email address so that was the
information disclosure
you also had XSS and you could attack
anyone because of the way that the data
was being passed through the system you
could actually attack the reviewing
committee now bearing in mind some of
these people who are on the reviewing
committees for call for papers are very
important people these are people within
our own industry this was a platform
within information security
so why was it happened in people didn't
know the the developers and the platform
had a feature enabled and they didn't
know about it but as soon as they did
they turned it off they said it was a
feature not a bug and I can't go into
too much details because it's still
being waiting to be cleared by legal but
they were fantastic they acted on
reports immediately
I was up till four o'clock in the
morning right in the report and then the
next morning send it through and over
the weekend period they'd fixed
everything which was fantastic and there
was communication there's communication
backwards and forwards between me and
them and I think that speaks for itself
when you have that level of
communication it really does help I
didn't go on to Twitter and drop this
and be like oh there's all this bad
stuff going on in information security
and look look what they're doing you
know that what they're supposed to be
the security professionals I didn't do
that I
of work through and it's because you
have to make the right choice when doing
this but I think also during the process
what happens impacts on what you do so
really grateful and we're going through
a range in a rewards but to be fair I'm
not too fussed about that it's just the
fact that my fellow information security
peers are going to be ok that unhappy
and I literally I felt like that so
awesome people shout out to my mans if
none of this what I've done ever ever
see name-dropper and so yeah it's been
my first year and I hope that you might
have learned a bit from some of the
things I've discovered and I didn't know
what I was doing and hopefully that
during this talk I might made some
points about things that you can take
away with you but one of the people that
I did reach out to was there for fish
and he gave me a bug bounty template
that I use now even still and it really
helped me because it put everything that
I needed to put down and give to a
vendor in a really nice way so have a
look at is github also some shout outs
to some other amazing people like you
need support from the community when you
go through this even if it's just like
you need an agony on other end of a
voice call so the mini-hats Club they
have a really good research community
and they're fantastic and when you're
pulling your hair out you can speak to
other researchers about it and it really
does help you have cybersex - he's been
a great person to speak to also ghostie
who who looked at some of the stuff that
I've done with regards to this
presentation and reviewed parts of it
obviously Zef he's also got a book by
the way if you didn't know by the book
and Rico so on Tony I'm trying to give
back a little myself what I've done is
I've provided a template
the blue file upload report which how
she does go down into detail and I was
running out of time so I've had to bash
straight through it but what you can do
you can go onto my website you can go to
the Google link there get the report and
you can start sending these run ability
reports out through other websites are
out there there's a lot of companies
smaller companies especially that I've
run a brawl and they need our help to do
it so I've given you all the tools that
you need to get started all I ask you
let us know how you get on and I think
we can actually probably make a little
difference doing that so if you're new
to all this and you want to get started
have a look at that because everything's
there for you
further help so know your rights know
your Terms of Service when you're
working on a product software understand
the iso's know the laws in which you
need to abide by and have a look at the
end-user license agreements get a decent
template together I have one now
thankfully and work on explaining
frequent problems with diagrams and
videos to help then you won't get the
to-and-fro we don't understand the
problem so can you expand so what I
found was analogies and examples really
do work I also and have a AWS server
that I've set up to demonstrate proof of
concept and what I've done with my XSS
reports is I've done a redirection
attack and then that redirection attack
then leads to a page where you have a
key logger that's embedded into the site
so it's a very nice visual
representation for that person they see
somebody else's credentials being stolen
because you've cloned their site they're
put in the details in and they can see
that it's actually been stolen life form
friendships and get the researcher
community behind you and seek advice
because you never know when you might
need it take a break and get clear heads
whenever you can and mainly don't be a
dick as well and buboes actually got a
little Santa's list and what he does now
Uber's one of my friends and he's
actually got this list he's the guy who
had the problem with a tree and he's the
who got hit now he's now got a website
and he's got a Santa's naughty list
oh nice list and he lists down all the
people that's working with and what the
status is with those people and if
they've been idiots or not so that you
know I'm not saying you should do it but
yeah that's it so final thoughts we do
not live in an ideal world go and have a
look at the guide really nice clothes in
part that he's got with conclusion and I
don't think we even got time for
questions that way no no thank you