hi everyone
i'm alicia your mc for today's workshop
in this workshop
zero to hero ish your journey to car
hacking begins
division zero's class security quarter
core team alina tan
edmond lim tan paisle and javier young
will cover both theoretical vehicular
knowledge and practical hands-on
activities
please welcome them hi everyone
we are the cast ready quarter so today
i'll be presenting
from zero to heberish your journey to
cartoon begins
so my name is alina uh beside me is jbl
bottom left is pacer
and bottom right is edmund so let's
begin our presentation
okay so for today's agenda we'll be
talking about uh
theoretical vehicular knowledge so i'll
be going through the introduction to
nuclear architecture and technology
uh the overview of basically hearing
network protocols
and the introduction to regular threat
landscape and
international vehicular standards and
then followed by
jv and pc will go through the cambus
protocol cam free
introduction to currently tools and also
the practical aspects
for the session itself and
edmund will be going through the rest of
it isotp protocol
uds mostly factory and automotive
yeah so uh this portion as well uh
you'll be going through by
travia and pc okay
so basically uh you can't see our faces
now but here's photo of us and top right
hand corner
so uh um basically i
i'm earlier you know my teammates are
placed at managerial so
um csp itself we have a total of 20
class members
uh we are also part of the wider
subsequent community here in singapore
called division zero
uh and csp also powers uh the automotive
security research group
based in stuttgart uh the singapore
chapter asrg sim
yeah so if you would like to join us
feel free to give us a shout out and
our twitter handlers are right beside
our names
okay so basically the goals of class
quality quarter is to facilitate and
promote to multi-subsecurity awareness
to the
community here in singapore we see that
there is a lack of
automotive knowledge about the community
here hence
we wanted to empower like-minded
security enthusiasts in gaming cancer
experiences
and ultimately want to contribute to the
automotive security industry
through our research community
engagement and building of our test
benches
okay so let's get started this is an
overall
vehicle architecture of a modern vehicle
where you have a central gateway being
linked to the center device
that's actually the majority of the
components such as the
ecu infotainment obd2 port and
telematics
so as you can see the boxes marked in
raid are actually your aftermarket
devices that can be connected to your
obd2 port or your central gateway
your cell phones are also an external
device that can be connected to make a
phone call
to your telematics itself so a majority
of the architecture actually runs on
canvas and bus
however in some vehicles it will be a
mixture of motive ethernet and can bus
or even bars and other protocols but
we'll go through uh
that more afterwards
okay so uh i will first start off with
uh
the definition of traditional vehicles
so basically traditional beakers are
also known as mechanical horses
that gets you from point a to point b
however um you know vehicles are
essentially computers from wheels
uh that have actually multiple embedded
devices known as ecu's electronic
control units they actually control
different functionalities of the vehicle
so uh i would like to bring our
attention over to the bottom
right hand side of the box highlighted
in
raid itself so the first ecu was
actually created by bmw in 1939
and uh the canvas is actually
which is one of the most important
protocols
commonly used commonly used by leaders
now
called the controller area network was
created by robert bosch
group in 1983 and the first
connected car to feature you know
connected functionalities was actually
brought in by general motors in 1996.
okay so as we progress further uh from
our traditional vehicles we have our
next generation of vehicles known as
connected vehicles
so uh we actually commonly see connected
leakers on the road right now
so essentially connected vehicles
actually allow communication with
external devices and have the capability
of connecting over wireless networks
so some of these features are cellular
connectivity which allow manufacturers
to push
software of the inspire over the air
channel unfortunately these features not
currently available in singapore
yet but it's coming in the future and
then next we have the
adas which is known as the advanced
driver assistance systems
which is actually designed to reduce
human fatalities and reduce correlations
and something similar to like collision
avoidance and cruise control
they actually can be found in the
adaptive features itself
then finally you have your in-vehicle
information systems that actually allow
a driver to make a phone call
from their vehicle via their cell phone
voice control and
actually allow them to text messages or
even check on the legal help fire the
diagnostic systems
okay so as we progress further with
technology we have the future
which is known as the autonomous
vehicles so
an autonomous vehicle which is short
form for av
so it actually operates via sensors
actuators and algorithms
so ideally we should actually operate it
without any human involvement
there is also six levels of driving
automation divided by defined by the sae
which is level zero from fully manual to
level five
fully autonomous so avs have the phone
features
so basically you have radars uh they
actually monitors the position of nearby
vehicles
video cameras they actually allow a
detection of traffic light and road
signs
uh lidar sensor that utilizes light to
measure distances and load ages
and then ultrasonic sensors to detect
curves and other vehicles during parking
and then we have the fms which is the
fleet management system to actually
control the fleet which you don't see
here
and of course the software to actually
process all these sensory inputs to
control acceleration breaking and
scaring
okay so having mentioned on the
evolution of vehicles we now come to the
communication protocols within the
vehicle itself
so these are the common uh computation
for the course
uh within a vehicle we have to actually
secure it without
uh it may proof as a potential attack
vector for attackers
so firstly we have the can bus as i
mentioned
on my first few slides so it's actually
a message page protocol that actually
allows my
controllers and devices to communicate
between false and vehicular networks
uh unfortunately the cab bus itself is
very short it's eight bytes
so manufacturers have an improved
version called the cambus fd
uh which is known as the cambus flexible
database
it's an extension to original canvas
protocol actually provides accurate
real-time data
as well and then we have the limbus
which is known as local interconnect
network
it's mainly used in killer systems and
you know other connectivity buses
uh my admin will actually
talk about it more later and then we
have flex rate bus
so factoring is usually used for uh
critical systems such as brick by wire
because it's high speed and um i know
it's very expensive so
usually you actually see it in higher
end vehicles
and then we have the most protocol which
is known as the media oriented systems
transport protocol
which is commonly used in vehicle
infotainment systems
uh unfortunately the most protocol will
be phased out uh soon enough
but we still see some of the vehicles uh
using the most protocol
then lastly we have the automotive
ethernet which actually provides
interconnectivity between vehicles uh
it's much lighter and faster the canvas
again amber will be discussing more
about this later in
the presentation
okay so and then we have the uh several
serial communications between the ecu
which is just in standard of
j1708 then j1850
is uh is basically used for diagnostics
and data sharing application using pulse
rate modulation
and then we have the sae j1939 which
defines the communication between nodes
and used for b for dynamics as well
and then we have the keyword protocol
2000 which is known as
short form kwp2000 which is used for uh
obd2 and uh covers the application
essentially
the osi layer model and finally the
isotp protocol
which actually allows sending of more
than eight bytes of data packets over
canvas
and it can uh allow the ability to
actually change the message into
multiple phrase
uh which actually allows a maximum
payload of capacity of four thousand
zero nine
five parts a bit more even more than
they can fd itself
so um after going through all the
commonly used particular protocols if
they are not secured correctly
it will actually result in an increase
in the amount of potential attack
surfaces which i'm going to briefly
touch on over here
so firstly we have the ota updates so
attackers may be able to actually
intercept traffic
from the cellular channel and push
militias over in the leader system
as for the ecu's over on the right hand
side they can actually include critical
control units such as your pcm which is
known as your powertrain control module
your ecm engine control module and the
attackers are able to actually access
through this opt2 port to obtain
information to the vehicle's internet
network
uh attackers are also able to do a
manual mirror to obtain campus data to
control the legal
if let's say the obd2 ports actually
block
so as for remote hijacking uber on the
bottom
right hand side of the vehicular tab
itself
attackers are able to pull key fobs by
skipping the signal sent by the remote
and clone the frequency or perform a
road gem attack which
actually involves jamming the frequency
and capturing the unlock key
to unlock illegal so for ransomware
uh over here in slightly in the middle
the attackers may be able to compromise
the vehicle by asking for some more
money to unlock the vehicle to drive
or even considering attacking the supply
chain by installing vendor on the
manufacturers and
kilmer suppliers all right attackers may
be able to actually control the fleet
management on the vehicle systems to
actually attack the vehicle and control
them
making them like portnets and use it for
distributed denial of service attacks
there should there are also actually
different potential attack factors such
as
spoofing attacks on lidar sensors camera
sensor attacks and spoofing
rivers can reverse parking sensors over
on the left hand side
of the slide
okay so after touching on all the vagus
potential attack vectors here are the
research types that we're using on
connected
vehicles so for example in august 2020
during a blackhead
security conference the security
researchers from the 360
group sky goal team based in china have
actually uncovered some security bugs
that can liberally control some fleet of
universities ben's vehicles for example
like starting off the engine
so uh in 2019 during uh
you know the blackhead conference
tencent team labs security researchers
also based in china
have discovered about eight
vulnerabilities uh zero days
uh bmw directory allowed attackers to
remotely attack the number of bmw models
through various means like infotainment
systems and bmw ports
and over here in december 2019 bmw and
gta have allegedly been attacked by
an apt group known as ocean lotus or
apg-32
so a um apg-22 have infiltrated
these corporate networks of these two
manufacturers supposedly to steal trade
secrets and intellectual
design for a start-up company or owned
by the state union
so earlier on i actually mentioned some
of the supply chain attacks
so one example is over here so in july
2020 the uk call center utilized by
several car makers have actually
suffered data breach and over 500 000
customers were actually affected
so similarly in 2019 1 million customer
records were stolen into the dust hack
which was
allegedly conducted by apg-1022 as well
so although there hasn't really been a
major cyber attack on this vehicles it
could potentially happen to our votes
here in singapore
and these are the attacks that we have
been seeing for the past few years
the most famous one being the chief
trophy attacks by the two security
researchers uh
chris bellassai and charlie nina and
they were able to literally control the
steering and kill the engine at high
speed
there were also zero day vulnerabilities
that allow attackers to tamper with the
vehicle through bmw portal
and through these unpatched flaws in
2016.
so in 2018 tesla's keyless entry was
really vulnerable to sporting attack
security researchers were able to clone
the keyport by just walking past the
owner
however this can be resolved by adding
the machine to the key fob itself
and then in 2019 tesla's compiler was
compromised by kidnaps researchers
by using train stickers by tricking the
autopilot technology
and steered the vehicle into oncoming
traffic
so earlier on i actually mentioned the
six levels of automation ranging from se
zero
node automation basically and to sae
levels one and two which
features the ada's and driver assistance
systems
and also sae level three and four which
features conditional automation for high
automation
for safety driver facility level 4 and
sc level 5 for full automation for fully
automated vehicles
so um level 4 itself you still have run
on geofencing
so um as of now we are currently at the
state of sae level 102
i understand that there are actually
talks of releasing vehicles in the near
future
years on sae level three however as we
progress
um towards autonomous speakers that's
how we unavoidably introduce new
sub-physical risks
so for example um long distance remote
attacks
compromising the field management
systems that governs the
car updates uh car code updates and
attacking the vehicle to allow complete
cellular
complete vehicular control and also for
short distance remote types one example
could be attacked against the tire
pressure monitoring system
which is known as the tpms a wi-fi cross
module
and then lastly for the uh access
physical access attacks
planting a device that will inject
arbitrary data messages into the
net network
okay so to address all these threats
that
we see globally different countries have
favors
subsequently best practices and
standards for the optometric industry
so for in singapore we have the tr-68
which is known as technical reference 68
which addresses specifically autonomous
vehicles
specifically on which focuses on the
subsecurity principles and assessment
framework
as for the eu region we have the ace
principles of
automobile cybersecurity and any sales
publication on subsecurity and
resilience
of smart cars and as for iso standards
we have the upcoming iso 21434
vote vehicles subsequently engineering
and u.n stake on the harmonization of
vehicular regulations on wp-29
and in the uk the government published
the guidelines on
the key principles of the subsecurity
for connected automated vehicles
and in the u.s we have the national
highway traffic
safety administration that came up with
the automated speakers for safety
article
and the document of the fmvss which is
known as the federal motor vehicle
safety standards
considerations for vehicles with
automated driving systems
although it doesn't really touch fully
on cyber security
it actually touches on the research
findings in terms of
options regarding technical translations
of the
fmvss and evaluates the regulatory text
and test procedures aig briefly takes
some security assessment into
consideration
so and also in the u.s itself the auto
isaac is also formed and they launched
the subsecurity best practices and
guidelines document
so if you are interested you can go to
this website to check out
more of these regulations
okay so after briefly touching on the
global best practices and standards
let's dive into the international
standards and regulations
so for wp29 uh it's actually created by
the uae
inland transport community and it
provides legal framework to allow
contracting parties to establish
regulatory instruments concerning
water vehicles and equipment and as for
the isotope for 34 it's a standard entry
addresses the management of service
really for goods and vehicles
he actually set the minimum criteria for
vehicular
subsecurity engineering and establishes
guidelines on cerabros without a safety
operator
and as for tr-68 is specifically for av
systems here in singapore
and it establishes the subsequent
principles and assessment framework to
support
the development and management for avs
so the assessment framework actually
acts as a guideline for avs prior to
actual deployment itself
so next up we have the saj3061 it's
actually a subsequently guardboard for
several physical vehicle systems
and establishes high level guiding
principles for physical
nuclear security however the e3761 will
be superseded by iso 1.34 once it's
completed
so currently the iso 21434 is in uh
i think it's in draft stage yeah
and then lastly for iso 26262 although
it's not standard focusing on some
security
it actually addresses the functional
safety of the entire life cycle of the
four beaker
subsystem uh for the um
the whole yeah subsystem on the vehicles
itself
okay so um next i'll be present uh
passing all my presentations
over to jbl and lisa will be talking to
you more about
the canvas protocol and the critical
aspects
so i hope you guys are not asleep yet
okay uh thank you alina for uh
so now i'll talk about the 10.4
so the cat protocol um consists of two
portions
so one is can hand kendo uh kenhun
operates at
3.5 volts and kendo operates at 1.5
volts
uh ken high injury operates at pin six
and the camera g operates at pin 14 of
the obd2 port
on the actual vehicle so in this
particle you won't really be seeing this
portion but if you don't try it out on
an actual vehicle this is
what you should be looking up for the
canvas carries eight bytes of
data and kenneth is actually technically
just an extension of
the camera core itself so it carries 64
bytes of data
there's a differential signaling for hot
tolerance so
for ken hi and kendo they will actually
broadcast one block higher all over
simultaneously
as uh compared to like the resting
voltage of
2.5 volts it dominates after
a 120 ohms and supported board rates
are one two five 250
500 and 1 mbps but usually it's 500 kps
and this is actually how a cam frame
looks like
so to break it down there's a style
frame
identifier remote transmission request
data link code there are a few stuffing
beats and crc but what we really want to
focus on is actually a data field so
we'll show you on the next slide
um the data field is the data to be
transmitted
it's usually a maximum of eight bytes
long
so let me just go to the next slide so
if you can see in this actual can
free you see that the other phase
actually uh
eight bytes long and you can actually
see the interface and the ken
arbitration
id so this particular interface is
can utils it's a live capture stream and
this is actually what you'll be
interacting with uh later on
during the practical itself so slk 0 is
the interface
and for the vertical you actually see it
to be
v can 0 and state consistent virtual 10
and then the second arbitration id
and the data field
so let's talk about the car hacking
tools that
are commonly used here the list of tools
that you can use for
uh can bus analysis
so we'll we're really using this time
around is canutils
and these are all the links towards for
the
different tools that you can actually
use
and for simulation two steps udl that's
udsm and icc
so kudus is just a software can use the
space
application that has multiple
functionalities um essentially what you
really want to do with it is that you
can
generate can data it can replay
the message that will send it can send
messages
display cam traffic and yeah you've
actually experienced it for yourself
later on there's also canva studios
which is
similar to tiny deals just as announcing
analyzing canvas traffic
there's also carrying caribou septican
socket candy
and uds sim and later i'll also be using
is i
season so iccin is an instrument cluster
simulator for success
and it works together with candidates
so introduction to candidates so the
main functionalities of candytales is
canda which is display
filtering and logging can data to a file
that is specified
kent layer is replaying can log files
that you've recorded using tandem
can say just sending a single frame of
of data and then ken gen is
randomly generating can traffic so this
is actually really good for
fuzzing and you get you actually
it's much more useful when you want to
fast like actual
like live traffic from car uh ken
sniffer is displaying can data content
differences
so when you lay down the practical
actually you get to see like what
what you can do with it and what you'll
be able to view with it
so now it's time for the practical
so let's see i see sim is a software
utility designed by open garages to
produce a few
key can signals to simulate an actual
environment in the car and that's the
link where you can download icsun from
and it allows you to practice canvas
reversing
in a very safe environment so you won't
be breaking any cars of your own
anything that happens is completely fine
and you can also change the difficulty
levels
by adding so you actually add more
background noise which
makes reversing much harder to perform
as you go along
and as in i also have icy sim which is
the instrument cluster simulator for
socket cam
that works together with key tools
so this is the installation so
for all of you that's following the
practical still
uh so what you want to do is that you
want to update kali linux first or any
debian
or ubuntu vms that you have or actual
computer
but you do by doing sudo apt-get update
or if you're using ubuntu just
do the equivalent of the set of the
commands over here
so you need to install link sdl to dev
and the
sdl to the image that libraries with the
following command
and after you install those libraries
you need to install the can utilities
by sudo apt-get install candy tools
then you need so usually install ic sim
so
just get clone uh the github repository
and then it automatically be cloned over
to your home directory
and make sure that you root um this
won't actually be able to run
without pseudo permissions so just
sitting into the
dark tree and you should be able to see
the contents of ice system if you just
run ls
so we're just gonna give you five
minutes for installation over here uh
make sure you get everything up and if
you can't get things up
you can feel free to message any one of
us to
help help you out with the installation
thank you for the campus introduction so
now we're talking about
the practical power icc and how to
manipulate the cameras packets
so firstly uh we need what we need to do
is to prepare the virtual
care network run by system software so
as mentioned by this default we
need to re-chrome the icc directory from
the internet so
after you decline you share the icc
folder in your
linux machine so if you go inside there
should be a
bench clip called setup weekend.
so what this flash cube does is
basically create a
virtual cam network called we can zero
and
um this virtually can never basically
help us simulate the can network and
also help us run the instrument faster
so if we go to our ubuntu
i mean our last machine we can verify
that
the v10 level is indeed stopped by
running
and then the v10 level should be
here on our device so
we will move on to the next step which
will be capturing the can bus traffic
from p10
so the what is
what this like something else basically
we need to
start our fcc and
which is our cluster and then we also
need to start our
controls which will basically
send the manipulator package over
and then we also open test network to
sniff out the traffic
okay so we can do this on our
computer by running the binaries located
in icc
directory so the first thing is to run
our instrument cluster
which is in the binary icc v10
icg i'm sorry and then with the argument
we can 0
as our network
so after we run we should see this um
dashboard which has the speedometer and
blinkers
then the next step
we should the next step to do is run the
controls
which will send the
packets to our instrument cluster
so this is the controls
binary and how it should look like along
with our
along with our cluster so the last step
is to run cancer on our device to
support the never packets so cancer is
already pre-installed
so we don't need to go to any direct
path
so if we run test network on
computer it should run out like this
so i'll stop cat sniffer and move on to
the next slide first
okay so the next slide will
cover basically the various different
controls that we can
use on our uh that we can use to send to
our cluster so that to manipulate the
various car functions okay so
the first step to do is to come on
uh perform can down which basically
listens
to the network traffic but stories
stores in a file
in a current directory and then
on the right is basically the different
functions and the different keys mapped
to it so i for example accelerate this
up arrow on your computer
but do remember that you need to click
the joystick
window and press the keys first if not
it won't work
so i will move to the
machine and see how it plays out
so first we run kendam
[Music]
and then we'll listen on weekend zero
so if you take note uh this
this uh what kendam does is basically
save
the can traffic to the file name which
is
on the terminal and then um if you click
on the joystick window
and then you press like for example up
key
you can see like the speedometer
increases
so likewise if you follow the slide
the left left arrow is for left left
hand signal
and then a right arrow is for right turn
signal so on and so forth
so you can try this out on your
device and then see how it goes
so moving on
moving on we have a camp layer which
basically
reads the can down file so that you can
view what like you can view
uh what the cambus traffic captured
earlier and see
like it replicates whatever you whatever
data you need to win
or outputs out on the cluster so
uh it should basically replay the same
thing as what you did earlier
yeah so if we go to our ubuntu machine
okay so on the linux side
uh what we need to do is to run cam
player
and you you you need to add a dashboard
the flag so that all the cat data gets
printed
at the same time so when you run camp
layer
like on the right you can see like all
the candidates that was transmitted just
now
by a candle and then we actually need to
wait for a while to see the changes
uh we played on the ic simulator because
i actually started the can down a bit
too early
so if you wait for a while and look at
the ic simulator you should see the
changes
as you can see now the speedometer
increases
and then followed by the girl
and then
so yeah so that's
that's template essentially is basically
just
replaying what uh what did
what you and then
yeah and then we'll move on to the next
slide
okay so moving on we'll be talking about
reverse engineering the can id from
weekend zero
so essentially what reverse
what we are trying to do here is uh
analyzing the can traffic by
using test default and then see what are
the changes
that are made to the traffic when we are
using the
controls to manipulate the
data so uh
if we go to the machine and run can
sniffer
as shown here
you can see that the this is the can
traffic current display so
so as mentioned just now like for
example if you press up
see it's the speedometer is right
the because you're supposed to
uh look and analyze the test equation
here on the right to see what changes
so i think speedometer is a bit hard to
see so we'll do the left blinker for
example
so if you press left angle
you can see that uh i think one
hit it is changing from zero to one
oops yeah one a is changing from zero
zero to zero one on the first
byte so that's how we see
the changes in the can traffic yeah
so bring on to the next slide
okay so now you'll be tasked
to do three analysis of
how to reverse the can id so
the first one will be acceleration and
deceleration
second one will be the open call lock
and then the last one will be
right turn and left and blinker okay
so we will give you five minutes
for you to try this out and if you have
any
questions can ask us okay
we'll leave it over here so that you are
able to see what we
wanted you guys to do so yeah see you in
five minutes
so welcome back guys so now we'll be
going through the
answers for the reversing can ids
question just now so for the first one
acceleration and declaration it's a can
id 244
so if you look at the ubuntu screen
yeah so if you look at the screen if i
press
the acceleration button and then you
look at the
can i need to perform it increases
increase
increments by one bit
[Music]
okay so uh next is the
right and the left and signal which is
canadian one eight
so what it is if you look at the weapon
then if you look at the right side uh
it changes from zero to one for the left
blinker
and then for right changes to from zero
and two two so and then lastly
for the dollar and dollar
so currently right now the door is
locked and if you want to unlock it you
shift
it for left front laptop
so if i press shift it
the it changes from zero f to zero
e and then if i lock it again it's
zero f again so yeah that's
so essentially like reversing can ids
because
like for you to analyze the cancer
cancer differentiate
in order to pick up the various
canadians for the different functions of
the cars
so now we'll be moving on to the next
part of the practical which
is
spoofing the canvas effect from weekend
so previously we have already
covered how to reverse engineer the can
ids
so now we will try to spoof the cam
traffic directly using the cam
set tool so
can send requires you to input the
network
and also the canid and along with the
data
so we can try to
edit the speed by sending
the one f6 data to the canid 244
so if you go to the ubuntu machine
and try to send that
okay so this if let's say
the the cancer data is not replicated on
the ic
simulator we can try to include a volume
so that
it's sending the data continuously so
so after after creating the while loop
bash
command you can see that the speed
actually maintains at
60 and then yeah that's how
that's how you basically like send like
you spoke the can traffic and then
send the data to the various can ids
okay so next we have
another level of exercise for you to try
out so
we have uh come up with different uh
different parts of it different
functions of the car for you to
attempt and spoof so first here i
increase the speedometer up to 60
horsepower
and secondly will be to bypass the speed
we need
so that will be increasing the
speedometer to 220
miles per hour thirdly is to keep
both right and left turns at the same
time
fourth keep the right turn signal up
fifth is to keep the left hand single up
and then the last two will be to unlock
all those and to
lock all those yep
so we will be giving you
around 10 minutes for you to try these
various exercises and then we'll come
back and discuss how to decorate
each of them
okay so welcome hey guys so now we'll be
talking about we will be going through
the
questions about spoofing the can traffic
so um
the first one will be accelerating to 16
horsepower
so we can do that uh
using canson and then for 16 months for
all the data
the can id is 244 and then the data is
2 3 f6 so if we look if we
input that command into the hotel
machine you look something like this
[Music]
okay so after
okay so after uh you input the command
you
also added the volume so it's more
obvious so if
the so if you go to the ac simulator the
speedometer
will be at 60 miles per hour and then
be i'll stop this process and then we'll
move on to the
next one which is bypassing the speed
limit to 230 mass per hour
so for this the can id is the same 244
because
it's regarding the speedometer and but
for data it's uh
[Music]
9 000. so you'll change your last four
digits to 9000 and then you can see that
the speedometer
changes to 220. okay so
next okay next we'll be going through
how to how to send the data for
the signals and also for the draws okay
so see
[Music]
signals uh which is for
signals is 188 that's a can id
and then if you want to keep both
signals up this
the canon data is 0 3 so
if we go back to the ubuntu and try so
i'll edit the command
okay so after inputting that command you
can see that both signals are now
so next question will be right turn
signal so right turn signal
uh we change the canada remains the same
at 188 but we changed the can data from
zero three now to zero two so
after inputting that you can see now
that the right signal is turned
on okay lastly for signals we have the
left-hand signal which
which we will change from zero to zero
okay so that concludes for signals so
lastly we will be doing the first unlock
can message so for those are not the can
id
but then we'll change the zero f data to
zero
to zero zero so if we input this
yeah you can see that on the bottom
right the dots are actually locked
so that concludes the vertical portion
for icc
simulator and then now i'll be passing
my time to edmond
we will talk about more about the
various
another protocol
thank you javier for going through the
lab work on the ic sim
so now i'll be going through the
different protocols present in the
vehicles and the first up will have the
iso tp protocol
and it's covering the layer 3 and 4 of
the osi model
it is the international standard used to
send data packets over the can bus
so previously pacer has colored some
canvas frames and it contains 8 bytes of
payload
with the isotp it can extend the limited
payload to a data size of
4095 bytes and the most common usage
of iso tp is for the transfer of the
install dynastic messages
with the obd2
so the structure of isotp protocol
mainly defines four frame types
the single frame first frame consecutive
frame
and flow control frame and they are
denoted by the different codes
in the first byte of the ktp header
so packets containing up to seven bytes
of data
identifies as single frame and anything
more than seven bytes of data
will go to the first frame consider
frame and flow for two frames
so how the communication of isotp
protocol works is
the sender will send the first frame to
the receiver
and the receiver will respond with a
full control frame
and then the sender will consecutively
send
frames based on the flow control frame
block size and the separation type
so soccer can has actually some basic
functionalities to use
isotp tools mainly isotp send sotp
sniffer sotp dom and many other
functionalities
so this is an example of how isotp
protocol can be used using
socket can and uds so the first one
denotes the requested
dynamic session code and then like the
can send we have the interface which is
0 and with the dash s and d
flags we can denote the sender and the
receiver of
the response and transmit
okay
so moving on to the uds which is unified
agnostic services communication
ds uses the iso tp protocol to send
larger data outputs over the canvas
so the uds is actually to provide a
read-only view to display
information to mechanics and however
troubleshooting the vehicles such as
sending a request to unlock doors can
also be done
using uts so
uds capable modules such as seos are
able to respond to the isotp messages
examples are
your instrument clusters and they
provide the following functionality such
as the dtcs
diagnostic trouble codes upload normal
capabilities for software reprogramming
remote routine activation to start
routine memory
and also write read write capabilities
to rewrite
any eeprom values
so the uds has a specific method to
receive
response data and like the canvas it has
the arbitration id
a positive and a negative response so
at the bottom right you can see an
example of a negative response whereby
a response is sending a 7f
and for the positive response it will be
adding a 0
4 hex into what you set up
and the structure of the uds is as
the example picture we have the
interface the sl can 0
the sender and receiver arbitration ids
number of bytes and also the payload
so that was the uds and sotp protocol
next we'll be moving on to the effects
way protocol
so in the flex-ray protocol it is
designed to be faster and more reliable
than the can bus
and it's commonly used for braking
systems or drive-by-wire systems
it allows clock synchronization and the
common applications and
critical safety components are high
performance for train
electric cruise control drive by wire
and active suspension so the downside of
flex rate protocol points actually the
price
is very expensive to use so we don't
really
you see it in normal vehicles and
usually on the higher end vehicle models
so the structure of the flagship
protocol can be broken down into
the header payload and trailer
the header is 40 bits long and it
contains information such as
such as the status bits the frame id
payload length header crc
and cybercow the payload is 254 bytes
long
and contains the data to be transferred
by the frame
the trailer contains three bits of crc
used for error detection
so the lean protocol is actually the
opposite of the flex tray
it's a slower protocol compared to the
can bus
and there's a low cost serial protocol
designed to interconnect other
components
and it's meant to complement the network
within the vehicle
so it has a master enslave network
topology and similar to the can bus
it's using a broadcast network and
utilizes the iso 1797
216. the common applications for the
lean
protocol is example the steering wheel
door
seats and air conditioning so anything
that
is not critical or dependent on the
speed of transfer
yeah you will be using lean protocol
some of the hardware
being used to decode the waveform of
limb bus can contain
example logic analyzers and bus
analyzers
so the structure of the limb protocol
since lin
is using the master slave architecture
the master node is looping through the
snake loads pulling for information
and transmitting the header of the link
bus and the slave responds with
8 data bytes so the header consists of
the following
information the sync break field which
indicates the start frame to all in
nodes
the sync bit which allows the lean nodes
to determine the baud rate
used by the mastermind identifier which
identifies the lead message to be sent
and the parity bits which determines the
validity of the id field
in the response we have the data field
and a checksum
so the data field transmits two four or
eight bytes of data
when the lin slave is pulled by the
master and a check
sum ensures the validity of the link
frame
so in this table we can see a short
breakdown of the limb bus
can bus and flex rate so the difference
in the voltage
lane bus is using 12 volts and can bus
is 5 volts while flex rate uses
up to 3.5 volts wires
limb bus is using a single wire can bus
using twisted pair and flex tray is
using
a twisted pair or four wires in the
speed
you can see the lane bus is only 20
kilobits per second
can bust up to one megabit per second
and flexway
10 times of that of can bus so the cost
for
lean bus is cheap and can bus
is moderate but flex rate is very
expensive
that's why we don't see much use of
x-ray
so now i'll be talking about the most
protocol so most is
media oriented systems transport and
it's actually used for multimedia to
transmit
audio video via the plastic fiber of the
cable
most ring daisy chain allows high speed
networking subsystems to be connected
together on a multiple
multimedia network optimized for
multimedia and infotainment applications
for most protocol it supports up to
maximum of 64 devices in the network
and is used in almost every vehicle that
requires multimedia
so the design of the mohs protocol there
are few masters that exist in the most
network
the timing master network master
connection master
and power master that serves different
purposes
within the network most protocol has
three
communication channels namely the
control channel
asynchronous channel and synchronous
channel
there are three different types of data
frames for most
most 25 most 50 and most 150
the difference between them is actually
just about rate so most 25
is using 23 megabyte system
and most 50 is 2 times the speed of most
25 and most 150 is 6 times the speed of
almost 25
most devices follow osi model
with layer 1 handling the physical
optical interface
layer 2 which acts as a mohs transceiver
most network interface controller the
nic
layers 3 to 7 acts as a network
interface and serves as a communication
block
for the application
for the communication of the most
protocol the most device
consists of physical network and
function blocks
network service consists of the nic
the function blocks on layer 7
application has a master and slave
function
the function blocks uses functions in
slaves called controller
and the controller send commands to the
slaves to receive data from the slaves
controllers are connected to the hmi
which interfaces
to the user to issue commands to the
safe
so the physical properties of the move
scale they are using
[Music]
photodiode emitting red lights
with a wavelength of 650 nanometers
the transmitter uses the ld and receiver
uses a pin photodiode
the physical medium uses the plastic
optic fiber
so this is true for most 25
so this is consistent with our findings
in our bench tool
so from the pictures below on the left
you can see
at the end of the orange cable it's
emitting a red light
like the mouse cable that uses the
red photo diode and then on the right
picture
when we talk about our infotainment
system
we located the plastic fiber which is
black in color
lastly we have the automotive ethernet
so similar to the normal internet
automotive ethernet is designed to
replace or complement can bus
due to the rising demands for bandwidth
so the increase in usage of a multimedia
and upcoming b2x
the demands are more bandwidth than the
can bus
so automotive ethernet comes in two
forms the 100 base and 1000 base
and like the flex tray protocol it
allows for clock synchronization based
on
ieee 1588
it supports a bandwidth of up to 1000
megabytes per second
and it's a bi-directional traffic flow
common implications for automotive
internet includes the body and comfort
systems
safety systems infotainment powertrain
and ada systems
so instead of using dynastics over can
for automotive internet will be using
dynamostics
over ip which uses iso13400 for
automotive fitness
so in the breakdown on the table on the
right we can see that
under the osi layer only layers 1 to 4
changes in comparison with the
traditional canvas
layers 1 and 2 changes to
100 base and the internet instead of can
bus
and layers 3 and 4 changes to ip
and tcp respectively instead of the
isotp protocols
for the physical properties of the
automotive internet
single twisted pair wire allows the data
to transmit and receive at the same time
and it is designed to reduce the weight
of the vehicle
so from the table below you can see the
differences
between the standard internet and
automotive internet
the length of a standard internet is up
to 100 meters
and automotive ethernet is 15 meters and
the connector for standard internet is
rj45 whereas
for automotive internet it can be
specified by
each oem variant by model
for standard internet the cable is
two-twisted pair
and in single direction while the
automotive ethernet
is one twisted path bi-directional
next i'll pass to elena to talk a bit
about the ctf guidelines
so thank you edmund i hope everybody is
still alive after
uh our workshop and hope you guys
picked up something or learned something
from the basics
for the basics of car hacking so next up
we are going to move on to the ctf
guidelines
so the class ready ctr will start from 3
pm to 8 pm on the 2nd of january
and 10 am to 3 pm on the 3rd of january
so for the registration create an
account on ctf.comwater.org
and you will receive an email with
joining instructions for downloading and
joining the cotr vpn networks
so next create a twitch account to join
the queue
on twitch and join the discord channel
of sincon and go to the car security
kampong channel
and once the teams have registered an
account on ctf.com.org
uh and join a specific vpn network um
kindly approach our team on synchron's
discord channel with the following
details to authenticate yourself into
the network
so uh let the discord emmy know the
specific network name they were drawing
your team name the number of players in
the team
so maximum number of uh three players
per team
and your player handlers your players
device address as shown in the zero tier
network
and your twitch account name associated
with the team only one account is
needed per team
okay so next up once you've placed these
details into the discord channel
the csq crew will actually inform you to
kill in the twitch
and your q number so please only queue
for one bench at a time
so to join the twitch queue create an
account in twitch
and inform your team's username plus
your
tier network details plus the bench you
would like to play to our csu crew in
the
sync cons discord channel um
car security and uh go to the specific
stream that you are queuing for
under the video section of our website
then type exclamation
mark drawing in the stream channel to
join the queue and play
so once it's your turn the csq crew were
jpg on squad to draw in
uh and standby for the bench
playing session so we have 30 minutes to
play for each bench and we killing is
actually allowed so your
csv crew will inform you on the discord
when you have three minutes left
there will also be a countdown timer on
the twitch stream itself
so um the difference between the
previous ctf and the cdf is that all the
questions will be
different so hope to see you guys in the
csgo ctf and we'll be around to assist
you if you need any help
so thank you very much everybody
and do let us know if you need anything
from us
thank you