so I'm gonna talk about security burnout
so I know I'm standing between you and
the beer gardens right now I thought
this picture so you know I'm out and I'm
sure you're burned out from today from
all the information you've been exposed
it's just been really great topics so
this should be an easy topic that's not
that technical I guess I don't have the
think that's okay okay no I'm fine it's
okay like I do have a disclaimer up here
just to let you know these are my
opinions not the opinions of the
companies or organizations I have worked
for I don't need to thank you
so is it job burnout it's really just a
buildup if when you're tired of your job
from an emotional and physical state and
we can really replace job with security
burnout because it's the same concept in
definition but why are we there security
is hard if we look at the evolution of
security we started off as firewall guys
right and then we started off as ids/ips
individuals and then our positions have
increased compounded over the years
because all the risks is unfolded
throughout the years and security in our
industry so these are just some topics
if you think about our role we wear
multiple hats unless you're in a
organization where you're only doing pen
testing or some specific rules so just
audited but if you look at most
organizations that are customer facing
and you have a security team you're
wearing multiple hats I can tell you
when I was assistant well stir health
systems we had about 14,000 employees
five hospitals about 200 physician
practices and had seven people on my
team running managing an information
security program for the whole
organization so we are wearing multiple
hats in multiple roles you know from a
business perspective to a technicals
perspective so and if we think about our
workload every day its new threats and
vulnerabilities there's new tools shiny
tools we can work with we've gotta learn
there's new and old risks to reviews
those vendors and customers we have to
deal with all the time and I feel like
I'm ignoring you guys on this side
please Connor I heard you don't like
moving around a lot so I'll try it okay
there's like the audience to conduct and
and honestly we have that every day
security hygiene right we have to
consistently do we have to patch all the
time we have to you know look at
vulnerability scans we have to look at
our pen test results we're gonna update
our policies we've got a security
awareness training listen list just goes
on and on right let me know I do talk
really fast I could slow down so these
are some topics of why security is hard
in our industry and why we can't get
burned out so easily so how can we
recognize that somebody or yourself can
is easily burned out so obviously
there's gonna be the emotional you know
this job scuse my language you know
I'm tired you know I'm just gonna go in
and do what I have to do and leave for
the day I don't care anymore I've had
employees come to me and I've heard
throughout the other colleagues a minute
you know what
I hope my company has a data breach cuz
you know why if we have a data breach we
get more money we can hire more people
we get more tools you know I have
definitely heard that in my industry
we're going my colleagues and stuff and
then you know there's thing you're doing
the same thing over and over and over
but you're not making a difference in
your organization I think that what
burns most of us out especially if
you're a company where you're providing
security of security program for your
organization you just feel like you're
doing the same thing but you're not
achieving your program is not actually
maturing in itself anonymously there's a
physical stress you know you can't sleep
at night and then your managers it's are
any of you managers in here do you have
people that report up to you should be
looking for these signs and your
employees to to make sure they're not
being burned out because you obviously
you don't want to quit because we don't
have enough people to hire right we
don't have enough people in the industry
that has a security skill set and
obviously if we have people that are
burned out this pose a business risk a
security risk and potentially a
compliance risk because if you can't
meet the demands of compliance then
you're not secure either any questions
so far okay yeah
and you can ask questions I know
something you tend to forget your
questions in the end yeah so I want to
come back to this I wish I had my
company have a security breach so when
the company doesn't care maybe this
company just doesn't need any security
it's a compliance check at that point
companies are yeah so why do we care
more than the company which should want
it when it doesn't I'm gonna talk about
that why do we care more because we have
passion for security we want to make a
change right and I will talk about that
in our next slide good you can go ahead
and continue out sir I'm cut you up but
I'll talk about it yeah so how did we
end up here first off usually it's a
lack of support right from leadership
and the company and the organization
itself so we feel like we're doing the
same job over and over feeding ourselves
you know but we're not getting anywhere
in our company because we're really just
a compliance check at the end of the day
right we're doing our audits is the
compliance check even though we have all
these security issues it's just a
compliance check we're in a reactive
State not a proactive State we want to
get out of that we want to have
automation and organization right we
want to be able to be proactive a lack
of security maturity I've been in my
company for years I'm not made of
different and why do I keep on repeating
myself I know we see these things over
and over security awareness trainer
we're saying these same things over a
number it's amazing to me I've been in
this industry for 10 years and we're
still talking about phishing you know we
shouldn't have to do that and we cannot
keep up with new and as its technologies
vulnerabilities and threats there's just
too many out there and there's not
enough else that's out there and there's
no input into the organizational
strategy I think that's very important
where we tend to fail we can have an
information security program is that
word we don't have any input to the
strategy at all because that tells you
that they don't really care about
security they just care about that
compliance check again so what do we
need to do we need to evaluate ourselves
so the first thing I always tell my
people
so why did you join information security
a passion right why did you guys join
information security hopefully not for
the money we need to talk then all right
yeah it's good money but it shouldn't be
the main choice so to make a difference
in information security we want to help
protect organizations data and then we'd
like to learn new shiny things and any
others so you want to evaluate yourself
and if you feel like you are starting to
get burned out you need to go to your
manager yes I can use a mic if you want
yeah okay so you know talking about
valuating yourself sometimes you need to
think about you know also what is your
communication style like why are you
effectively communicating to your peers
in your organization to your leadership
that we need to do better in our
security program am i reporting the
correct data when I tend to fine and and
when I took over the CISO job the syste
before me what he was reporting he was
reporting very technical information to
the board and to the compliance
committee so sometimes you need to
change that because you need to change
it into a financial this is very great
pictures right you need to turn into a
financial gain right because if you
think about security security is really
just looked at as a cost center to an
organization or not looked at as an
added value to the organization money to
them
oh you're my jacket too so I am a mom of
two boys and I and then the mom of a
husband I guess you could say that so
know how to multitask very well yeah so
going back to the day that were
reporting alright there we go we have to
report the right metrics and the right
statuses in a manner that's the owners
of the organization the board the people
that organization's going to understand
I was talking to Jenna earlier working
in health care she asked me he says how
did you change you know the minds of the
people at your organization to get them
to effectively learn that security is
important to them what I did was I had
my team go out to the nurses and the
physicians and actually sit down with
them and say hey I know you want to get
this application and it looks like it'll
bring value to the organization and your
department but we want to learn why so
we can better adjust ourselves to figure
out what's the best security controls
for that application so it's really
about your communication style how do
you communicate effectively and you have
to learn how to communicate to different
audiences you definitely have to change
that because I had a daughter line two
IT and we had a love-hate relationship
so I had to go to them and talk the tech
talk but I also could bring down the
compliance bat sometimes because they
weren't doing their jobs are you
following through and are you talking to
the right people in the organization
that's the key if you're not talking to
the right people you need to figure that
out who that is in your organization
support so talk with management
obviously and managers you need to do
your job you now have your one-on-ones
with them you know what I did was I had
tea time every Wednesday with my team
and then the employees I work with now
we have one-on-ones every week we almost
every day it seems find support at the
organization reach out to your
information security community Yeah
right like us your chapters your
professional organizations
and even from your MIT appears and and
don't looked and when I also say is if
you want to look to your peers look for
a peer that's not a pen tester that
works just like you and you're saying
division you know but maybe go outside
of that inquire help from a consulting
firm so I can tell you most
organizations they will not believe you
but they will believe a consulting firm
which is interesting you're saying the
same thing repeating yourself because
they had the shiny report from a
consulting firm oh yeah we should do
that here's the money for it you know so
that always helps and that what's great
about consulting firm says they're
becoming a really specialized so you can
find a consulting firm that understands
your industry in the past it wasn't
always like that it was very generic
take a break you know go on holiday
somewhere enjoy your time off maybe
pursue a different role and even a
different organization I gave myself a
goal as a SISO that and within three
years if I didn't make a decision it's
gonna be time for me to go because I
know they don't believe in the security
program and they don't believe what I'm
doing and then managers and then we
already talked about that anyway okay
keep on going all right information
security is not hard I know I said it
was hard in the beginning it's chaos but
that chaos is exciting and invigorating
and it keeps you going that's why we
love our job so we want to continue to
do it you have a unique skill set which
is very valuable because look at our
industry we have so many jobs that are
open out there so you can get a job
anywhere that's why I always say you can
go look for a job in another
organization and you got into this
industry for a reason and we the
information security community are here
for you so what I want you to do this is
the end of my presentation turn to your
neighbor and say I'm here for you buddy
yeah okay I thought you I could talk
fast
yes comment complaints questions because
I write somebody always as a complaint
thank you for your talking thank you for
the great presentation despite all the
problems that are I actually I'm just
gonna go ahead I have the first question
because I'm not gonna name any one but I
have someone that I can think of who I'm
who might be close to to a Burnout what
do you think I could do as a friend to
help that person well I mean you
obviously need to sit down with them
take them out for a beer take him take
him
is that someone you work with or just a
friend okay
okay good sorry cuz I was gonna say if
it's somebody you work with taken
outside your company you know go
off-site somewhere and take him for a
beer or coffee and have that talk with
them and then actually you know start
making them think well why did you
really joined in this industry what do
you really want to do because I tend to
find that we were so exhausted that we
have to know so much but maybe we need
to focus on one particular area and I
did that I was a security engineer and
then I switched over to compliance which
I loved a lot better I'm sorry and I'm
happier in that role and I think that's
what it is is we get burned out because
we're so there's such demand on us but
we're not focused on what we really want
to do and need to do and being able to
coach that person to help answer
questions okay thank you other questions
yeah I'll get my microphone yeah I'm
sorry like what I like my original
question I don't think it worked so I
have to okay ask again I just think that
in our society right now nobody is
passion so much about security as we are
and they have right not to be there are
people who just don't care about
security and that's fine
I mean if they think that this ayah Tito
we'll speak not only to their
grandchildren but also to all over the
world right with the same word that's
fine that's what they really want and I
think there are organizations who just
need a compliance chair yeah so this
this is a explicit decision of
management of such companies that's what
they want that's in which market they
are so I I kind of think it's on our
place like understanding that when you
take in such a job which is like a Czech
job which doesn't I mean be passionate
help building the Monaro wallet right in
hardware or change the job where the
security is essential for the business
I'm a little bit like that's not very
very wise to get burned out because you
don't have impact in an organization
which doesn't need this impact so yeah
like I don't know maybe some crypto
currency exchange security for them is
essential for staying there but I mean
some kind of library they just don't
care right so just that's like the way
where to change the job I guess well I
think in the end what needs to happen is
the company needs to get burned out
right
unfortunately it needs to happen you
know if they're not gonna care and it's
a compliance check the company needs to
get burned out they need to learn from
their lesson and incident needs to
happen I know this has been recorded but
it's it's accurate you know you're gonna
have people and board members and
executives it's just not gonna care and
they but they're gonna have to learn
from the lesson eventually realize it's
a financial risk to the organization I
think you also need to consider that you
might be working at a company that you
really like working it you like the
company and you think that they need the
security but the management board
disagrees and then you're sort up and
across rooms but that's just and you
know and it could also be maybe the
managers just reporting security is not
reported it in a manner it should be so
sometimes that person needs to be weeded
out I would like to react also on him
for his reaction because I think that
people don't there is lot of
misunderstand
in a company because there is no
communication yes as I told in the
healthcare we think okay I T Department
I say IT department not security IT
department do their job so they protect
us so if they are allowed to do
something it's safe but this
misunderstanding because we don't know
when people hear and understand what is
really going on I think they will react
a different way but she said that she
just did as I talk talk to the nurses
talk to the doctors explain them work
with them then you will get moving from
inside and because we want to work safe
but sorry it's not my way it's not my
work that I like to think about that and
they see the problem that's another
thing but nurses and doctors don't need
to take care about security that is job
from we think IT but what she said is
communication and I priced it very good
we need to talk to each other and with
each other not not go to burnout yeah
but to talk with everyone and then you
can get a result I think yep it's just
like regulations we take regs right they
come out with a new regulation but they
don't really enforce regulations right
until 10 years later that's the same
problem so we know as companies we knew
gdpr was coming around right it was here
two years three years four years ago
right we knew is coming you know and
they finally stamped that date May 25th
right 20 seconds living like that now
everybody's scrambling right now we
got to get our GED for our program
together when you show already really
have a security program in place you
just got to modify it any more questions
I know it's a very intense topic I'm an
intense person if you want to stress out
need a minute manager I'm here no I'm
just get an LFO Oracle so I saw someone
pointing but I didn't see your hand
don't be scared any questions over here
I'm gonna look for questions now
going once Melo questions you guys can
always connect with me on LinkedIn I
have my email address on the PowerPoint
so if you have a private question we can
talk well thank you very much for your
presentation
[Applause]