all right so I will be talking to you
about social engineering so first let's
get a few things out of the way what is
it well imagine you have a castle to
protect some sort of data hacking in the
traditional sense would be going around
poking of the walls to see which brick
is loosest or where to add an extra
bricks of the whole wall crumbles
meanwhile social engineering is just
simply walking up to the front gate and
tricking the guy operating it to open up
and this is why social engineering is so
dangerous I mean you can build thicker
walls or you can dig a deeper moat but
the human element can still be
compromised also the castle analogy
still holds true in the literal sense as
social engineering is very often used in
the physical world to gain access to
secure locations now first I will go
over the current social engineering
tactics and here in this list I have
loosely organized them from tactics that
are exclusive to the digital world to
those that are exclusively physical so
let's start with the first tactic
phishing or as I like it call it the
Nigerian prince one so phishing is very
much a shotgun approach meaning that
fire as many shots as possible and well
one of them has to hit the target and
because of this fishing has very low
success rates around 3% of all phishing
attacks are successful and but because
it can target such a wide range of
people it is by far the most popular
online scam method I mean I'm sure
everyone here has received some sort of
spam email at some point asking me to
reset their eBay password or something
along those lines also because it's so
broad it kind of requires a bit of
naivety to fall for a phishing attack
that's why the overwhelming majority of
people who lose money to phishing
attacks are seniors about 60 years old
additionally as just said phishing is
mainly used to exploit financial data
and although a three percent success
rate doesn't sound like much since
phishing targets so many people
percent of a large number is still a lot
of damage for example 91 million dollars
were lost last year in Australia alone
according to the Australian Centre for
Commerce and two other seas I can't
remember now onto spear fishing spear
fishing and fishing are principally the
same with one key difference being that
spear fishing is far more targeted than
regular fishing therefore it also
requires some extra research by the
attacker for example where the targets
were their gender their age etc and
because of that they are far more
effective than regular fishing emails
spear phishing emails are 25 times more
likely to be open than regular fishing
ones and because of this they can also
be used for a larger variety of purposes
because instead of targeting a large
group of people with the standard your
PayPal customer please reset your
password it can be tailored to sum or
maybe even all employees of a specific
company to disclose their network
credentials additionally both spear
phishing and phishing attacks are almost
exclusively administered over email
this is firstly because the style of
emails of large companies can very
easily be replicated
additionally they can be sent to a
massive people would listen to no cost
almost instantly and finally there are
tools out there that very easily
exploits flaws in the email system for
example there are online services right
now that yet let you send an email from
any fake email address to any real one
now on to quid pro quo which means
something for something in lab and quid
pro quo is a method of essentially
finding the easiest point of entry into
a system for example if an attacker were
to call a company's employees offering
tech support I'm sure a lot of the
employees will turn him down but
eventually one who actually needs tech
support would gladly talk to them and
likely disclose their network
credentials but it doesn't necessarily
require active involvement by the
attacker for example they can set up a
website that
tests the security of your password and
all you have to do is enter it or what
I've seen is a website that checks if
your credit card details have been
stolen and all you have to do is enter
your credit card number and security pin
and it'll do the rest
and essentially quid pro quo is driving
the target or offering a service in
exchange for information by the target
now all the next weirdly water-related
one water holy so water-holding is a way
of exporting targets trusts especially
specifically the trust in services or
websites they commonly use for example
early infections of their warned acquire
ransomware or administered through a
combination of both waterhole and
phishing attacks and it also targets a
specific group of people who use a
website where service CCleaner for
example which is a popular PC space ring
tool was exploited for as over a month
last year the official ccleaner download
contained malware and why this is so
powerful because if the same malware
were on some random email or link on the
Internet the user would likely be far
more wary of clicking it meanwhile if
it's on a trusted most trusted source
such as a software they commonly use or
an update therefore therefore more like
far more likely to fall to earth however
the one key downside of water-holding
that it actually requires website
exports to function attackers usually
use zero-day exploits such as once again
want to cry use the eternal blue exploit
in older Windows operating systems to
function and because of that
water-holding somewhat blurs the line
between hacking and social engineering
but due to this element of trust water
cooling can be very effective for
example in 2014 chinese attackers use
exports in flash to infect users of
forbes.com which ultimately led them to
gain access to US defense systems
now I'll do pretexting pretexting is
quite simply pretending someone you're
not or in the situation you aren't and
it can come in many different forms for
example being contacted by an authorized
Microsoft IT helper to divulge access to
your personal computer or from your
system administrator to do the same
additionally since an individual it
pretexting relies can also rely on an
individual's trust of authority and
since humans are taught to respect
authority this can be very powerful
for example a group of Australians
decided to put this to the test
a while ago simply by buying high
visibility vests and seeing what kind of
places they kick it into which
ultimately ended up with them getting
into an Australian Cokely concert not
only for free but also standing which
remixed the stage now finally onto
painting
baking is essentially a physical Trojan
horse and usually comes in the form of
leading physical traps such as a USB
stick lying around labelled in an
interesting manner of course was some
sort of malware on it and this very much
relies of human curiosity curiosity
because I'm sure a lot of us if they
were to see a USB stick on the floor
labeled confidential or top-secret what
probably plugged with their computer
just to see what's on it and because of
this in 2016 your researchers dropped
almost 300 USB drives around the campus
of the University of Illinois with a
simple script on it that phoned home
once it was plugged into a computer and
ultimately 45% of the deployed USB
sticks were inserted and less detectable
by the researchers so now that we've
looked at the current tactics let let's
look at what's to come or specifically
the ability of future social engineers
to perfectly impersonate anyone they
wish granting them immense capabilities
so first let's talk about the first
aspect in perfect impersonation speech
and specifically let's look at Adobe
Project Boco
project boku allows the modification of
a flip of spoken audio specifically in
to use a simple text-to-speech to allow
visual editing of the spoken spoken text
and because of this it was aptly dubbed
by Adobe themselves the Photoshop of
voice and however it has some
limitations firstly it operates
exclusively inside that clip of audio
meaning that it is quite easy to
rearrange words and maybe replace one or
two or add a few however it doesn't
really have the capability to add extra
phrases or even do this live therefore
for an impersonation standpoint it isn't
really Bible however there are still
enough nefarious applications for this
that Adobe actually never released VOC
go to the public let's elevate this one
level though and look at Lyrebird
Lyrebird is an AI startup that uses a
five-minute recording of someone's
speech combined with neural network
speech analysis to create a model of
someone's speaking patterns allowing for
full speech synthesis and contrary to
boku this allows for full flexibility ie
you could have someone read a book in
you could read a book in someone's voice
however because of this it also requires
more effort and material than boku since
voco only requires one clip of audio
lyle bird requires at least five minutes
of recording to produce a halfway decent
result but also liebert can be live so
translate your voice into someone else's
on the fly and so let's look at an
example of this first let's listen to a
recording of the Axl Donald Trump and
then let's listen to the fully AI speech
synthesized version we call on every
nation including giant and Russia to
fully implement UN Security Council
resolutions downgrade diplomatic
relations with the regime and sever all
ties in trade and Technology so that was
the actual Donald Trump and now let's
look at the AI version the United States
is consumed in addition
although there it isn't quite perfect
and I mean there are still some telltale
signs such as the weird metallic
garbling in the background sometimes
it's pretty good especially considering
some of the enunciation and speech
patterns that are clearly traceable back
to Trump and so as this tech develops
this voice will become more and more
convincing and maybe even at some point
indistinguishable from the actual person
so now that we've got the speech part
covered let's look at the visual aspects
of impersonation firstly let's look at
the fake out fake app similar to
Lyrebird is an AI powered application
but instead of doing voice synthesis it
does face logging additionally it is
very time intensive as it takes long
rendering and it has long rendering and
learning times to produce an adequate
result additionally hours of footage
have to be used of both the subject and
the target to produce a convincing
result however once you meet those
requirements it produces excellent
outcomes and since the software is free
and has been easily compiled with a
graphic user interface the Internet has
had its fun with it specifically they
put Nick Cage in anything they could
find such as in this clip uploaded by a
Reddit user from the new Superman movie
as you can see the result is in your
perfect I mean it looks almost like a
real Amy Adams in the cage mashup thing
and however fake app has been used for
some slightly less fun and less water
related purposes mainly black male
criminals have been putting people's
faces in situations they weren't in
mostly usually erotic and then wanted
money for not releasing the video as a
result of this all fake app outputs in
our watermark but also since fake up
isn't live
it doesn't really
for much from an impersonation
standpoint so let's look at something
more applicable that being face to face
face to face is also AI based but
instead of doing face swapping it's
simply swamps facial expression meaning
that it takes an RGB video of a source
actor and analyzes their facial
expression and then plays that onto a
simple video of the target actor so
let's look an example let's look at an
example that's working oops there we go
so contrary to face a face app it's
relatively inexpensive because while
face app needs a face that needs a
relatively powerful computer on lots of
time this only requires a webcam and an
RGB video of the target additionally it
is live as you can see the source act of
facial expression is being mapped off
the target actors video in real time yet
face to face is also somewhat limited
being that it is it operates exclusively
in the video clip of the target actor
seeing as only facial expressions are
being mapped for example if the source
actor were to move his head for example
that would not translate onto the
real-time reenactment but let's look at
one last solution that could solve all
these problems that beam Unreal Engine
so a few weeks ago Epic Games the maker
of Unreal Engine put out a tech demo of
what they called a digital human showing
me of photorealistic results in a real
time in real time rendering of an
actress and a motion capture suit in the
room next door
and it looks something like this and as
you can see the result is still a bit in
the uncanny valley but seeing that this
is rendered live it is an incredibly
impressive result however there are also
some drawbacks of this method firstly it
requires very expensive tracking
equipment as the actress of this source
actors for this was actually rigged up
like this
additionally it requires very powerful
computers to Ron as remember this is all
done in real time
however computer power is getting
cheaper year-over-year and additionally
Unreal Engine offers full flexibility of
lighting environment clothing and most
importantly the person being displayed
yet this comes with one drawback being
that it would require a 3d model of the
target yet imagine a default character
model with a few tweetable features such
as in present in most video games today
well as such as is present in most video
games with a character creator today
coupled with a few pictures of the
targets face can most likely create a
very convincing look especially imagine
if it's over a Skype connection for
example and now back to the tracking
aspect that is the most expensive part
of the social set up however cheaper
technology exists right now and I'm
holding it in my hand
so this Taiwanese visual effects artist
actually demonstrates this demonstrates
the tracking capabilities of the iPhone
X by mapping his facial expressions onto
a 3d mesh and while some may argue this
isn't practically viable yet for the
fidelity used in the Unreal Engine
example some game developers such as
next games are actually already using
this exact technology to animate digital
characters in their games so as you can
see here all they're set up is is an
iPhone eggs and a custom built app to
animate 3d characters in real time using
the facial tracking of the phone so this
of course begs the question would a
future version of an AI synthesis
coupled with a rendering engine allow
you to impersonate anyone well at the
moment it's not really viable for anyone
to do this however in the future with a
handful of newer developments this could
become very possible for anyone to do so
imagine in the near future
getting a Skype call from someone who
talks like your boss and looks like your
boss or anyone else imaginable why
you believe what they say now this of
course raises a simple question how can
I protect myself well this question
doesn't have a simple answer and not
only because the technology isn't fully
developed yet but there are a few steps
that don't only apply to future social
engineering but also current firstly
common-sense and critical thinking this
definitely isn't a mist in any setting
but especially important in the internet
on the internet and in a social nearing
standpoint so just ask is this email
from eBay really valid or is this
completely random and is trying to get
my information thirdly a two-factor
confirmation system for everything would
not would go a long ways ie confirming
every order you get and just making sure
it's correct and additionally there
might be another option being that you
don't have to protect yourself because
technology advances in all directions so
if there's an AI system faking someone's
voice on the phone they're similarly
might be one detecting it so in
conclusion social engineering will only
become more prevalent as digital systems
become more and more secure and as the
common matter goes a chain is only as
strong as its weakest link and this
certainly applies to all digital systems
and increasingly the human element is
the weakest link and with emerging
technologies such as the previously
mentioned AI voice synthesis this human
element will come under attack more and
more making digital awareness as
important as ever thank you
thank you so much that was very
entertaining any questions yes God thank
you for a great presentation it's really
exciting so I should like to add a
personal story so you shout the picture
of the concept in the West and in the
early 1980s I was a clear little loopy
emergency service is a warranty and a
friend of mine asked me well let's take
the orange ticket and our heart and then
don't go to the Rolling Stones and uber
trust we entered and there was a border
for for the area which was not for the
public and there were some policemen and
we did not watch to cross that border
but the policeman asked us well we can
help you and so it was not our intention
so we just wanted to attend the concert
and finally we ended up below the stage
and we saw other people pushing against
there for us and we just watched it and
so it really works so as this story
that's incredible yes yeah like secret
phrases or something yeah so the
question was for a protection would like
a secret exchange phrase to validate the
person's identity be a good way of
protection and sure definitely I mean if
you can construct such a system that
probably be a very good way of mustering
out all the potential social engineers
yeah the question was about biometrics
on the web and I think it's very
possible I think when the iPhone 5s came
out a few researchers were actually able
to I think get fingerprints off a photo
and I think I make that mistake myself
because although I think it's really
cool
my background is actually my fingerprint
so that might not be too great but yeah
I'm sure the possibility especially with
face ID now on the newer iPhones
I'm sure the possibility exists to get a
adequate 3d model of someone's face from
a few pictures yeah I use the face it's
fine yeah the question was about AI
specifically asking about the AI
solutions I mentioned and I think there
are already a few companies that employ
AI for cybersecurity I think one is dark
Trace and one was I can't remember the
name was recently bought by sofas the
antivirus software and they employ that
already yes
[Music]
yeah the question was about I think like
two-factor authentication
essentially for phone calls of the
future and I think I'm sure it's a
possibility because especially if these
technologies get used more frequently I
mean the market will exist for something
that makes phone calls more secure and
especially over the Internet and so I
mean this could already be valid outside
of a social engineering standpoint if
for example government officials want to
communicate securely this could
definitely be used to validate someone's
identity oh thank you
[Applause]