hello and thank you for joining me after
the lunch break to talk called the ACA's
guide to perception so I've been
introduced already my name is Stephan
Hagar I work for a company called dot if
in Germany if you're not from Germany
it's completely normal that you have
never heard about that company we are
doing software for text consultants
mainly and this is saying that 80% of
the literature on Texas is in German so
we're a big company with a turnover of
nearly a billion euro and 7,000
employees I'm part of the internet
security team and we are looking at the
security of our company from the outside
and that's where some of those ideas
come from this is not a hugely technical
talk it's not a talk about zero-days
exploits patching whatever it's a talk
that more or less tries to get you in in
touch with your perception how we
perceive things and what might be good
or wrong about that
this also means since it's not technical
that some of the information in this
talk might seem relevant to you and some
might not so please just take away what
you can and if you want the slides are
going to be online afterwards please
share freely in case you want or need to
leave early the things I'm talking about
are that I think you are shaping a big
part of your reality and thus can change
it if you don't like it and that if you
leave your brain running on autopilot
that it will severely limit your choices
and that a little bit of creativity in
whatever you're doing is always an asset
and let's try whether we get there but
one of the questions that I want to
answer at the beginning is why do I feel
the need for this talk because talking
about the brain about perception about
your handle things about all that stuff
is usually not the content of a
technical conference so how does it
apply to hackers um I hope it does
and I think personally that what we see
now industry with egos InfoSec Rockstar
superstars egomaniacs behavioral
patterns and not just with the InfoSec
people but with the regular users
behavioral changes are actually
something that I would love to see so I
think it's a topic that concerns us an
info security because we very often for
quite and forget the human element and
sometimes that human element seems to be
ourselves so part one your brain is
lying to you and if I say your brain is
lying to you I might be exaggerating a
little your brain is not lying to you
all the time but your brain is never
giving you the full picture and I'm not
just saying that and leave you with that
statement I'm going to try to illustrate
what I mean our brains and nervous
systems have a bandwidth problem if you
moved recently or in the last 10 years
and needed a new internet provider you
probably all know these advertisements
saying this internet line will give you
up to X and bit per second power
bandwidth whatever and a few years ago
it was a running joke that you would
never reach that number and I think with
our brains it's quite the same let's
have a look at the senses and the input
that our senses get our brain gets from
our senses this the eyes usually deliver
the most input to our brain with about
10 million bits per second down to the
tongue and taste with about a thousand
bits per second and if you add that all
up then you get a number that says
something like ten point seven and bit
per second it really depends whether I
am able to do my math correctly but with
all the numbers I'm talking about right
here they are orders of magnitude it
doesn't matter whether it's exactly ten
point seven or eleven or twenty or maybe
even
because as you will see a study from the
MIT said that the brain doesn't process
data faster than about 60 bits per
second if you compare 60 bits per second
to 11.10 point 7 n bit per second it
really doesn't matter its orders of
magnitude the question is what are we
going to do with an information it is
something like up to indeed so what we
can take away from that is that our
senses deliver lot more information than
our brain our conscious brain can
actually handle and the interesting
thing for me is somebody interested in
hacking and everything is what faculty
in my body actually chooses what kind of
information gets forwarded because there
are other studies saying that about 3
percent of the information that is that
you get bombarded with every moment is
being forwarded and again it's not
really a matter of the correct number
it's just a real fraction of what it's
what is going on that leaves me to a few
models that I think might be useful in
looking at this problem our brains can
be seen as having two distinct halves
everybody knows that but I'm not talking
about the left and right hemisphere I'm
talking about a model by a doctor or and
this model has been expanded by somebody
called Robert Anton Wilson whom you
might or might not know as the author of
Illuminatus and other interesting books
and they said the brain basically has a
thinker and approver so the thinker can
think about anything you think I can
think he's standing on a planet that is
flat or spherical or inside a spherical
planet the thing I can think that the
planet revolves around the Sun or that
the Sun revolves around the planet the
thing basically can think itself
healthy or even sick and the Provost
chop is so much easier the Provost job
is just to prove that the thing is right
the prove approves what the thinker
thinks that is the basic thing in that
which means if we have biases then these
biases get reaffirmed on a daily basis
let's not call it biases we have a
certain kind of worldview and usually
most humans are comfortable if that
worldview is affirmed again and again
for example I can walk through Munich
without getting a knife in my back it's
a very comforting thought
and each time I walk through Munich and
don't get a knife in my back this is
reaffirmed I like being reaffirmed in my
thoughts
most people are the other thing is I
could talk I could probably fill all the
45 minutes with talking about biases and
it's not just the confirmation bias that
you probably have heard about it's
really about everything we think about
could be biased it's not a bad thing
it's just something we should bear in
mind when making decisions and things
like that and since not all information
is getting forwarded to our brain
something is with health so let's
consider this street scene somewhere in
Asia I'm a completely ignorant Westerner
so I can't really read the signs and
everything but let's assume I have to go
to the toilet and it doesn't matter
whether it's in an Asian city or
somewhere else it's just if I need to go
to the toilet somewhere my brain will
automatically pick up signs and try to
give me a good direction maybe pick out
a hotel sign in that case maybe pick up
the sign saying tourist information now
if I was hungry for example my brain
probably would ignore the tourist
information because they don't sell food
but maybe my smell or my eyes would be
distracted by the by the food carts and
by the people
I'm close to the close to the vegetables
and the fruit so I probably would go
there it really depends on what I'm
focusing on which kind of information is
being forwarded there's one thing that
always takes precedence in our lives and
that is if something is being perceived
as being dangerous I apologize to that
guy with a mobile phone I don't think
he's dangerous I just picked him out at
random if we perceive something as
dangerous everything else goes to - the
background starts a background process
and I am completely aware and tried to
deal with the dangerous situation
whatever it might be and then of course
this the thing that we are able to
glitch reality we you probably all know
about optical illusions some of them are
a little bit funny some of them have a
little bit more impact if you have seen
this I apologize because you will know
the effect but just touching from that
picture who are few things that a and B
are a different color just from what you
see all right
so the squares to the left of the slide
are the same color si I hope we can
agree on that and I probably shouldn't
say that in a Microsoft Building but I
use PowerPoint to demonstrate that
because it's horrendous ly difficult to
get PowerPoint to cheat on that or to
work with it so if we just move them
here you will see the following just to
do it once again because the effect is
interesting even when it moves there the
thing about optical illusions is some of
them are funny but what you should know
is that your brain does calculations for
you your brain knows there's a green
cylinder that cylinders throwing a
shadow whatever moves into the shadow
thus has to have a lighter color then
what appears in the shadow so your brain
is filling out that gap
for you so if you never questioned that
or if you never questioned that input
that your brain gives you then of course
a and B are of a different color but
really they are not to illustrate this
further and don't worry I'm not going to
bore you with just optical illusions all
the talk although that might be funny
for me but I won't I never am sure how
that comes out on projectors but this
should be a uniform gray bar it is in my
presentation if I change the background
you will see that the left hand of the
bar seems to be a much lighter color
than the right hand right and it's still
the same bar so especially when it comes
to colors and things like that our brain
does a lot of lot for us it's not
restricted to optical illusions though
there are auditory illusions as well I
picked out one at random which is
mineral beats I don't know whether
you're aware of them it's a kind of sine
wave for each year and if you listen to
them with headphones the sine waves will
create an interference pattern which
taps out a rhythm or something like that
it's an interesting effect it's very
often used in meditation and things like
that and it is completely lost as soon
as you play the music while loudspeakers
because it really just needs your brain
to create that interference pattern
between the years more illusions or
factory illusions which means smell that
basically isn't there so the thing with
demonstrating something like that smell
that is very difficult because basically
you need a chemical laboratory setup and
and try to prove that there's a smell
that smells not there I only have one
example for an olfactory illusion from
personal experience I was driving the
Gipper River Road in Australia and this
is in the outback there's nobody for
miles and miles and miles
and I was refilling the gas tank of the
car and all of a sudden the diesel the
petrol smelled like the most delicious
onions and bacon funny thing I I was
living my fingers yes umm it's now video
I'm sniffing my fingers but they smelt
of onions and bacon not of petrol and I
was fascinated because I knew I was the
only person around for miles
so those happen if you are suffering
from tactile illusions then re don't
envy you each of us probably knows the
feeling that we set somewhere in the
summer in a nice shady place and all of
a sudden we feel an insect crawling on
our skin touching this hair and the
other and just moving and when we looked
nothing was there people who are
actually suffering from tactile
illusions don't have that feeling with
one insect but with thousands or ten
thousands so these illusions exist as
well so not only do our nerves not
deliver all the info to our conscious
brain because they can't they are also
wrong every now and then the last
example here our gustatory illusions has
anybody of you ever had a miracle fruit
or wonder berry if you haven't this is
still a very street legal thing to do it
is called miracle fruit I think and you
can find you can find that online
everything and the interesting thing is
it goes to the sour receptors of your
tongue and numbs them so usually if you
eat a lemon your tongue and all your
senses will deliver to your brain this
is sour because this is the overpowering
thing that the lemon does the
overpowering taste now if you pluck out
the receptors on your tongue that say
this is sour you will find new tastes in
stuff that you have been eating for
years like pineapples strawberries
everything that has a sour touch to it
will taste completely different because
you actually taste the aspect of the
fruit that you have never tasted before
because your brain was just saying sour
sour sour all in all it leads me to the
conclusion to say that brains are
slightly random filters with dynamic
rules
aka firewalls something like that when
it comes to the information that is
going to your consciousness which i
think is quite cool the problem is you
don't have an audit trail so usually at
no point when you are not really aware
of what's happening can you say what
kind of filters or what kind of senses
delivered the stuff to your brain and
why you don't have an audit trail and
there's only one relatively simple
solution to that and that is you have to
use yourself to observe yourself in
order to change yourself all the time
and some recursion involved of course
because usually when we watch ourselves
very closely and we humans are
thankfully that meter that we can
observe ourselves very often we react
differently but that is the whole point
because we are not running on automatic
anymore and as soon as I observe what
I'm doing and I'm running into some
pattern or knee-jerk reaction that I
wanted to do anyway as soon as I
observed myself I can hopefully at some
point choose to react differently so now
comes apart that you probably won't
appreciate Jen I'm sorry for that
because we have defense mechanisms in
our brain as well and in order to
overcome them we have to keep in very
open mind and with that I'd like to ask
you to keep a very open mind and imagine
a guy riding a hard steel and after
that I would like that you think about a
very open-minded Darth Vader
so and while your brain was probably
preparing you for an extreme graphic
image in the first example or something
at least somehow sexual and try to
prepare you for that your brain might
not have been prepared for the dark
waiter from a much sexier universe and
even innocent things like spongebob
could be abused and we all know where
this probably is headed and what's going
on there
and I'm sure InfoSec conference is
because it allows me to bring stuff like
magazines and show it around
this is magazine and magazine for
cats by cats and the thing is our brains
love to be surprised in a good way we
don't like bad surprises but our
consciousness deals with the same kind
of situations every now and then and
whenever something happens that doesn't
fit the preconception it might be funny
it might be scary as well but our brain
likes to be entertained as well so and
apart from there's also pitch
magazines for the Dhokla of dog lovers
so and whoever wants to have a look at
my magazine afterwards so I'll
consider so basically there are some
similarities to all the defense
mechanisms that we employ in info
security and that we have in our brain
as every comparison it might be a little
bit crude but I think it helps to
illustrate that our brains are doing a
lot more than we usually give them
credit for in info security we have
anti-ddos stuff so whenever somebody is
trying to get one of our servers down
and bombarded with lots and lots and
lots of traffic
the anti-ddos thing chumps comes comes
into play and filters out the bad
traffic and just leaves the good traffic
our mind has lots and lots and lots of
ideas all the time and probably
thankfully only a handful is led through
and the rest is just discarded
you can drive it out for yourself if you
catch yourself being in a very creative
face and having idea of the right year
just wait ten minutes and try which ones
you remember and which ones you don't
so always write down your good ideas we
have mechanisms like ids/ips
and to some extent antivirus in info
security mechanisms that look for known
patterns and know that these patterns
are either good or bad
and then we either drop them or forward
them which basically is what i PS we'll
do ideas just reports on them within our
mind we have something similar and that
is behavioral patterns scripted
reactions if you think about it there
might be something in your life some
situation that you try to avoid but if
you run into the situation you tend to
react the same every time and be angry
about it afterwards if there's something
like that in your life then you've just
found a behavioral pattern and can work
on that concrete another big thing in
info security at the moment or at least
the last year was user behavioral
analysis where basically a machine I'm
not going to say an AI but a machine
learning algorithm is trying to classify
users and user behavior cluster that and
try to compare it to regular behavior so
for example if you have a group of
accountants they might come into the
office between 8 and 10 they might work
until 6 or 8 and probably access one or
two servers and have X or other programs
they heavily work with if you compare
this group of people to somebody from
from the sysadmin z-- then this it's
completely different because the
sysadmin will log on any time of the day
they will work from home they will log
onto a lot of machines they will
probably not use Excel if they can help
it but will SSH a lot and things like
that and the UBS try to
get that information in for example if
Tom the accountant exhibits a behavior
like a sysadmin than this Verizon alarm
this is something that is relatively
difficult to implement in at least I
think it is because the definition of
normal is something that is quite
difficult to do if the network is
complex enough the good thing we as
humans have is we have evolved to detect
anomalies so that's really easy for us
so we get that point
another thing we like to do is if we
found some kind of threat or malware or
anything that we think is malicious we
put it in a sandbox we let it run we
have a look at it we see what it does
which kind of registry keys it wants to
access
which kind of values it wants to change
what it wants to do generally so
sandboxing is the thing I'm deliberately
again not going into sandboxing evasion
methods because they are there but for
the sake of this example this is
sandboxing and we do much of the same
whenever we have a big decision to make
be it say buying a house or talking to a
girl we like or really doing anything
that is a little bit more than eating
the next chocolate bar we like to
daydream we have that situation in our
heads we play it out we played out in
many many myriads of ways just to get a
feeling for it whether this is something
we would really like or not so basically
humans are doing sandboxing as well and
one last example there already briefly
touched upon within modern and the price
networks we have firewalls everywhere at
least most of the companies have that we
segmented networks we have firewalls and
every time a packet goes through a
network it will pass at least one
firewall and thing is with the thing and
the prover if our mind doesn't think
that this special thought this special
information is worthwhile it's going to
be dropped by the internal firewall so
these are a lot of comparisons between
info security methods and between the
human mind what I want to illustrate
next is that although they serve as an
example and they serve for us to
actually see what our brain does with
our thoughts and everything analog
versus digital is still a thing that you
can't really compare if you get an email
or let's say a text just saying I'm
happy to see you
all those 23 bytes or something like
that um don't know then in a digital
format this will be all the information
you get in a interpersonal communication
there's the nonverbal communication but
I'm not talking about that
this pronunciation for example so if I
say I am happy to see you then the
problem means I'm happy to see you but
he's not or if I say I'm happy to see
you then I'm happy to see you but not
your mother-in-law and stuff like that
so in analog communications there's a
much more going on than in digital world
and now you remember the 60 bit of
consciousness that each of us seems to
have let's try and put it to the test I
give you guys and myself much more
credit and saying let's say we have 48
bytes of consciousness okay instead of
60 48 bytes it seems good so there is
this movie that I hopefully can start
some how does it start
no yes yeah please see what you can take
which kind of watch what information you
can take from that movie and again I
said 48 bytes because I thought you know
if you take one of the squares as a
really really big pixel it would be 48
bytes any takers how many colors were
there in total
any takers we're all the slides unique
so just have a look at it again it's
going to illustrate a point because I
don't think or I think that a lot of
people here in the room could write a
small program to analyze the video and
tell me the exact answers because it's
easy to analyze but it's easy to analyze
for a computer so just for the curious
among you tiles 2 & 7 where it's
identical and tile slide 15 was slide 30
interest rotated by 90 degrees doesn't
really matter because our brains are not
really optimized for that kind of
information have a look at that movie
then which contains a lot more than 48
bytes it's the exact same length as the
previous one but after watching that I'm
pretty sure most of you could answer a
lot of these questions if you have a
look at these questions these are much
more specialized than in the video
before so the whole point I'm trying to
make is that brains are definitely not
general-purpose as computers are we are
highly specialized sometimes you need a
demonstration for that there is a quote
by the great toerner trama who said that
precisely because we can be aware of our
shoes that are too small at one point
and the spanning universe in the next
moment this because of that our brains
are seen as having this limitless
capacity but they don't because if you
try to remember something at any given
moment or see what you're conscious
about at that given moment it's very
often not much
but let's continue so how does it
benefit your work how does it benefit
your cyber why should you bother to
think about your own defensive
mechanisms and your own perception so
the first thing is if you're recruiting
for cyber then very often if you look at
the Edwards and B monster thing or
whatever
it seems that recruiters have that very
fixed picture of an IT guy in mind and
try to recruit absolutely for the Hat
and the difference between blue and red
team seems to be a beard and it's
exaggerated of course but what I'm
saying is the next example for that is a
good in a very bad example in two ways
but I'm getting to that
if you are recruiting for cyber and
maybe you have the picture in mind and
it's not a bad picture of a person who
does a really good job if you are just
recruiting and try to clone that person
you might end up with a fellowship of
the ring looking like in the cage
there was another Anna Cage talk in the
rookie dragon very happy
the thing is in the cage might be a good
actor but probably the success of the
movies would have been slightly less if
he had been the only actor in the
Fellowship of the Ring and I completely
agree that this is a fictional novel the
success of the team was based on the
different things everybody brought to
the to the whole if they all had the
same skill they wouldn't have succeeded
so we need variety and we need creative
people we need a lot more variety in
when we are recruiting for cyber and in
the industry as a whole I think and I
said it's also very bad example because
yes
the Fellowship of the Rings they are all
male aren't they so there's no woman
there and I apologize it was the only
Nic Cage related picture I could find
that would illustrate my point if you
are in social engineering if you're
working with that if you're working as a
social engineer I don't
really have to tell you that if you
understand how your brain works and how
you can influence your own brain that
this of course is a skill that can
easily be transferred to your work
because other people's brains work the
same one other thing is that as soon as
you start trying to see why the
information you get at any given moment
is exactly the information you get at
that moment is you start to understand
yourself better I had that example of
knee-jerk reactions where you just
stumble into a situation and you react
on autopilot you do something you
usually don't like to do like getting
angry or making a sassy remark or
something like that and as soon as you
start observing yourself you understand
that of what you're doing and you can
actually change the way you react it's
not an autopilot anymore and that's the
whole thing about doing things actually
differently this is something doing
things differently
it doesn't always lead to success so
just because you are using IP addresses
that are not RFC in 1918 in your network
I've seen something like that a customer
who'd just had for example building two
third floor
first off his first computer would be
two point three point one point one this
is doing things differently but this is
not necessarily better but if you for
example think back to the time where you
counted on fingers whether it has been
40 years or three days it doesn't matter
usually we count to ten on our fingers
but we are all confident with binary so
if you actually take every digit as a
two to the power of something you can
actually count to 1023
on your fingers still look silly is
doing things differently but it's also
thinking about things differently it's
some kind of tool that you already have
and that you can already use
and if you don't like that example I've
got a real-world example for you I'm not
a war buff I really don't like Wars but
in the Second World War
there was the ghost army that was a
division of the United States the 30
23rd headquarter special troops and yes
23rd for those of us counting numbers
and these guys in the picture are not
exceptionally strong super soldiers they
just have an inflatable tank because the
ghost army recruited heavily from people
who were creative painters artists
whatever just not military guys and the
chop of the 23rd was to confuse the
chairman's basically and they succeeded
very well the thing is all the chop was
deception they would move into somewhere
at night they had sound installations
where the sound was played from a
division moving in like 20 30 thousand
people moving in tanks moving in lorries
moving in and they had all the sounds
recorded back at their home base where
it was safe and just replayed during
night somewhere close to the border not
close enough for the Germans to just
send somebody and look what happened and
they would also have those inflatable
tanks and a few real tanks because when
the chance then went weii air to see
what happened there they would see a
massive amount of tanks but if there
hadn't been any tank tracks that would
have been suspicious so they had a few
real thanks to lay the tracks and they
have that inflatable things and sound
installations and with that kind of
deception they managed to close a gap
that had opened from Germany to Paris
after Paris had been retaken and about
2,000 people in the ghost army simulated
70,000 people and so the Germans didn't
push through so deception and doing
things differently and thinking about
stuff does have a few real implications
the next slide
of course why should you think that not
um you're losing weight doesn't happen
for me or maybe I don't think a lot but
your brain takes about 20 percent of
your calories and burns those so
whenever you're thinking you're doing
your body a favor
this is causes with a with a smile
alright so if I have managed to get you
into the whole thing of thinking about
yourself in perception
you might ask for tools there are few
tools and you need to work out what
works for you the one thing that always
works or that is the beginning beginning
of everything is to be more conscious of
how you react what you do how you deal
with certain situations and if you
observe yourself I'd like to ask you to
not judge yourself at that moment
because that happens later anyway but
just see in that situations that you
don't like see what happens and then try
to figure out why it happens in the
aftermath and one thing that really
works for me is if you have some strong
concepts about anything and just go on a
holiday and pick a country where you
have no cultural reference point at all
so for me that would probably be
something in either have maybe Africa
Asia somewhere and see what what is
important to the people there and see
that the stuff that is important to you
for example that you have fingernail
color matches your clothes is something
that is of total non importance to them
and find out what actually am how you
can overcome your own and preconceptions
of what culture is or what you are what
what you have to be just by diving into
a different kind of culture and seeing
that most of it is nonsense and then
there's the thing whenever you do
something like that
whenever you try to get to the bottom of
your reactions your perceptions
yourself there will come the point where
you offend yourself probably read
appends on your character but if you
have strong beliefs in something and you
start a question then then it's going to
be uncomfortable for for you probably so
as long as it's yourself and you're
dealing with please don't be afraid to
offend yourself because what are you
going to do sue yourself but on the
other hand if somebody holds the same
belief and then just try to offer not to
offend them because they have their own
issues and everything just be kind to
yourself and others I guess and before I
come to the end
a few pitfalls and conclusions that go
along with that this is a definition of
being scientific that whenever you're
doing an experiment there might be some
results and facts which are
counterintuitive but if you repeat the
experiment often enough and the result
is always the same then the result must
be true even if it's counterintuitive
can you agree to the definition
hopefully now if you're going into the
whole mind hacker mindset mind to
mindset then it gets a little bit more
vague like my personal perception leads
me to a different assumption therefore
that aspect of the model seems wrong to
me see there's nothing hard in there
because I can't say I believe the earth
is cubic because I believe it I mean I
can say that but it doesn't make it true
but with any kind of observation you
make about yourself I think this is
completely true because the kind of
experience you have with your perception
of or as a human being it's different
from everybody else and you might have
some points where you connect but the
thing is it's still your individual
reality and stuff like that flat
earthers and I hope I don't offend any
you if you're flat earthers but I really
really don't think anybody's here and a
flat earther it's a thin line and to
begin completely honest the one thing I
think most hackers can can stand behind
is that we're doing that for freedom
because most of us really like freedom I
don't like the thought that there are
automatic reactions and behavioral
patterns that were imprinted on me or
that I imprinted upon myself when I was
younger and everything reacting to
situations I actually like to analyze
them and be free in my decisions because
it gives me freedom of choice and that
this is probably the main reason why I'm
doing that and as always I try to stay
on the scientific side on that on the
side that I can be proven and so on and
so forth but from - OSIS - homeopathy or
any other things there are so many other
things our brain does or can do when
it's convinced that this is the thing to
do that the rabbit hole I'm talking
about goes a lot deeper than that
I'm always too happy to discuss those
things so if you're interested um hit me
up on Twitter or email or whatever or in
the coffee break because I love talking
about that stuff
I also like to thank all those nice
websites that gave me stock pictures
because their way I could stay more or
less legal when doing a presentation and
actually that's it for me for me are
there any questions
[Music]
thank you are there any questions for
Stefan so that means you're all going to
go home and reflect upon how you
perceived his presentation today now I
guess it means that I didn't do a good
job in waking them up after lunch sorry
guys
see he's already observing what has just
occurred and he's judging now what did
we learn from this presentation today um
that's a quote I would like to say from
JR Bob tops which says I don't act as I
preach because I'm not the person I'm
preaching to you yeah well that's that's
a joke of course
do as I say and not as I do okay no um I
won't be happy if you think about that
and if you found it a worthwhile talk
here at besides Munich thank you again
for having me and again if you have
questions I'm I'm there all day thank
you Stefan
[Applause]