so for me I design cyber security in all
lots of technology problems they are
people from they are fit into the core
of how businesses are on surveillance
relative aspects like any field even is
executive who happen to be not gold they
don't want anyone would be there like
your slot come up
testing the rifle was intense but as
much information as they can happen when
we go to that and the biosecurity
exposed to say oh we've got this kind of
beat off the time and that's like two
feet off the back the I will be over and
now we can happen like living in the
face of the lips of one to ten
cumulative 14c of the night and
everything is new and every combination
you have is the executive piece is about
those dancing what percentage of that
happens when and delays small they
confident they clear compensate