Ohio goes a mass had in the past and
very nice
fascia Candice Karen he or she gonna
guess you mad nice to meet you all
I'm so excited to be
you'll hear today it's my
second time in Tokyo and every time i
visit
I find there is incredible technology
innovation and people in Japan
so as much as I'm looking forward
to talk with you today I'm also looking
forward
to learn from you this morning as you
heard
my name is ken as I think what I would
like to
speak to you about are some of the
biggest problem
that the world faces right now
in the field of cyber security bad
apart from the problems I would also
like to suggest
some solutions and I would like to tell
you
why I think it is the hackers and the
security professionals
that might save the world someday
so let's get started showing
if I ask you right now
what was the single worst security
problem
or breach experience
in the past year in 2014
you might each have different ideas
because the past here has been dramatic
when it comes to cyber security maybe
you're thinking about
what happened at target and Home Depot
in the retail market in America when
where millions of credit card numbers
were stolen perhaps you're thinking
about something else
what about the game over variant
above the popular source middleware
which
took it to peer to peer levels maybe you
have in mind
all the problems discovered in
fundamental encryption technology
like SSL heart bleed
or their shell shock bash bug
or the for their buck have been so many
problems
or perhaps what you have in mind our
now the attacks on the once secure
Apple I O S ecosystem or maybe you are
thinking about a kak
on critical infrastructure like energy
generation
& Electric Power's perhaps you are more
concerned
with privacy and the invasions to
privacy that we have learned about in
the past year or so
indeed there is no doubt to the past
year has been
very dramatic indeed probably
in December what everyone is thinking
about though
is what happened took sony Pictures in
the United States
and the massive attack launched by
hackers
calling themselves the guardians of
peace
it is now rumored that
the attack on Sony was so hard to
recover from
the company's actually considering
to delay the publishing all
their movie about north korea which
perhaps was the reason behind this
attack so
a very dramatic year a year for us
security professionals to look at the
world
that we're trying to secure and realize
that
the problems are everywhere and I'm sure
you've heard this saying before
but I have many friends pool are in the
security business
and they like to joke they say
the only two types organizations out
there
though that have been hacked and does
but don't know it
already that mean almost every
organization
is kicking time bomb
with a massive attack waiting to happen
I just waiting to be discovered
the lesson here is that
on of everyone can be attacked and
if there are people that know how to get
everywhere
attackers they can find access into
any system any computer any environment
this is a lesson
I learned myself almost twenty years ago
I was a bit young and it was the year
1995 and I learned this lesson
from this lady maybe someone you
recognize her
it is the hollywood actress Angelina
Jolie
in the year 1995 she starred in the film
card hackers when I saw that movie
now was about 14 at the time I realized
that
Packers are people with incredible power
right in their hands they can get
everywhere
they can do almost anything they want
and sometimes
they can also be the heroes this is the
lesson I learned from Angelina Jolie
since then I've spent almost 20 years
in the security community and the
security industry
I've worked with organizations like
technology providers defense contractors
telecom companies consulting
organization
really all across the board and I
gether different perspectives from
working with different companies also
worked with the Israeli military
as you might know in israel women serve
in the army
next to the man and I worked with an
information security department
all the Israeli military I turned my
CISSP
diploma in 2007 in the past two years
most of my work is in the academic field
working with Singularity University
in California and Tel Aviv University in
this rat
other than that I am in industry analyst
working with GigaOM from California as a
academic researcher as an analyst what
they do is look
at the trends and look at the phenomena
that is happening
in the cybersecurity world and I try to
find a story
try to find the trend to understand what
is going on
as a storyteller I often
seeks to take a different perspective
think and today I'd like to offer you
my perspective if we look at the past
here
if we look at all of these attacks and
if we take a look
at the future what we will learn
what we will learn is that
behind the corner technologies waiting
for us
but we don't yet know how it will it
affect
our lives we don't know what are going
to be the biggest security problems
in 2015 because technology is changing
very rapidly but
one prediction that we can already reach
is that we will have big security
problems
so now is the time to start looking at
them maybe even
working together to solve those problems
and I reached the conclusion that we can
work together to solve those problems
earlier this year
when I was invited to speak asked
the thirtieth and one TED Conference
attend event is
quite unique it's a massive media
event that also fanned all the talk and
then they are
accessed online by millions of people
in my talk at TED I claimed
that one on the way to solve the
security challenges
in the years ahead is to take advantage
I'll the hacker community to work
together with the hacker community and
look at hackers as the immune system
for the information age if you think
about it
hackers work separately but together
they are different individual like
organisms yourself but they are reach
a similar go or be fine security
problems and whether the report on the
problem disclose the problem
or try to exploit it we all learn about
it
and then we get better this is
part of how the evolution of technology
works in fact
so today I'd like to think about this
immune system analogy and
suggest that actually we can all be part
on this immune system we can all work
together
hackers and security professionals and
industry vendors
but that's not enough we have
to act now now is the time
to move forward and the reason for that
is because the security challenges I
waiting to happen
the right around the corner and some of
them have been devastating
in the past few or no so
really can't take the risk of letting
more
security breaches like that happen in
the next few years
and not do anything about it so
today I'm offering to you a choice
between
doing something about it and not doing
something about
and in order to convince you
to make the choice to act now
i weird talk about 5 above the biggest
security problems but also find all the
things that we can all do
as security professionals to save the
world now I'd like to start with what is
perhaps
the biggest problem of the mall and that
is
that they are not just talking about
securing
the world Wide Web for not just talking
about securing
the intern
I like to talk about securing cyberspace
now that sounds like a big name right
I'm sure you are familiar with the term
cyber
you've heard it before some security
professionals
even say that cyber is a a
marketing word or that it is
a stinging for the Internet I'd like to
suggest that cyberspace
is even greater than that and let's go
back in history and understand
where fiber comes from this gentleman
is an American math professor
or at least he was his name is Norbert
Wiener
and in 1948 professor Norbert Wiener
invented a new scientific discipline he
was looking at how technology is
changing
how remote command and communication
technologies
are transforming the well henny
was looking for a name to
give this new authentic discipline
describing
the transformative nature of new
technologies
like remote command in controller
so in order to come up with a name yeah
actually borrowed from someone else and
I will show you
from forming a in a minute this is his
book from 1948
cybernetics control and communication in
the animal in the machine
it it was published more than sixty
years ago
but they think it's more than relevant
today in the 21st century
when we actually have a mold
command control communications
everywhere when Norbert Wiener was
looking for a name
for this discipline cybernetics he
actually got his inspiration
from this guy this is the captain
the manhole runs the boat and the
ancient Greeks who were a
empire in their 50
city state Empire in the Mediterranean
Sea had a very powerful
Armada and its each ship
had a captain the captain of the ship
is the guy who says where when how fast
and in which direction
will be shipped today this man is called
in Greek key bill met and from the Greek
keep let us professor winner invented
cybernetics but I don't think
that he realized quite how relevant
remote
command and controller communication
technologies
are going to be I don't know if
professor winner if
even imagine that one day humanity
will have robot on mars
running around communicating back to
earth
and even writing on Twitter about it
so today we have
these types of technologies everywhere
and
cyberspace is also on March
by the way can you guess
what is the most popular language in the
galaxy
any ideas last week I
gave a speech in Belgium and one of the
suggestions was
cling on but actually
the language the popular most popular
language in the galaxy is not cling on
it is in fact job
yes it's true there are billions
all devices that I running Java
including
the mars rover the robot
running around on March and these are
devices
not just computers all web servers
our databases this can be anything from
eckhard to ATM's
to smart watches now I think
today in this conference we will learn
about how
some of these devices like smart homes
and cars
are going to be hacked in the near
future
so in the past
25 here this has been the story
of cybersecurity these are the top 10
computing and software environment in
which most
vulnerabilities were found in the past
25 years
but if we look at the future
this is going to be the story of
cybersecurity
it is going to be remote command and
communication technologies
it's going to be satellites and radio
frequency
and location information GPS
and fifth innings for running
airplanes in the sky and ships in the
ocean all this stuff
is going to be part of cybersecurity so
the same technologies that lol a group
of hackers from
the University of Texas to
transmit a farce location filming at
force
GPS signal to a superyacht
and make it go of course this is part of
cybersecurity
and standing radio signals
to embedded insulin pump that save the
lives of
that big patient but can also hack
their body
and transmit too much in Swat inserting
into the blood this is also part of
cybersecurity
and hacking into satellite part of
cyberspace
a problem for cybersecurity and
something local perhaps hacking into a
Real Talk enable toilet yes
it's also problem for cybersecurity so
how can we face this big problem
it's not just about the Internet it's
not just the what about the World Wide
Web
cyberspace is a lot bigger than that
it's all the different technologies
any solutions maybe we can join
the Amish which is a a group or
religious and Christians in the united
states that do not believe in the use of
technology
I heard last summer that they already
have smart phones
so maybe that's not the best solution as
well
we have to secure
all of the things all these different
things
and these are so many different
technology environment
and I haven't even mentioned the new
when Giants the companies that are going
to probably have some of the most fun
abilities
for the next 25 years so perhaps
the first step the first big problem
but also the first step is to realize
that cybersecurity
is about all of these
different environments all these
together
it's the technology that we used in the
past 25 years and the technology that we
will use in the next 25 years
it is the web giants that have all our
information and I'll web services
but also the fundamental technologies
like
open SSL and passion and then
infrastructure that we all use every day
all this together
is part of the problem
for cyberspace so if it's all one big
ecosystem and by the way this isn't
image of the Internet and connected
devices
from a few years ago right now it's even
more
complex and more connected so if it's
all connected
then we can all be part of the pinion
50m we can all work together
to solve problems so that was
problem number one cyberspace complex
but it's all connected
and we can work to solve those problems
that
problem number two this space
the cyberspace is fitted with very
creative
penny very innovative in very
collaborative
bad guys criminals
spies malicious attackers
they are very smart
and a don't mind working together they
share information
the share attack techniques and they
keep inventing
new things every day every day there is
a new
exploit or in your problem and to do
whatever they want
to get what they want if it's your money
or your document
or stopping the publication of annual
Sony Pictures movie them do anything in
the past year we've seen
tremendous innovation in the cyber
criminal underground
one example is the peer to peer variant
I'll the source matter where if you can
raise your hand and tell me
who here has heard about Zeus it's
probably the most popular
matter where in the planet right and it
has many variants
fence its source code was published a
few years ago
many other criminals have taken the
source code
and created better new versions of it
so they're not afraid to collaborate and
share tours between them and another big
problem we've seen in the past year
are crypto lockers crypto lockers are
or new types of malware perhaps ordered
new types of malware get encrypt
the hard drive all the computers the in
fact
and then request money around some
to release the five this is also called
ran some software around somewhere and
arising problem in the criminal
underworld
another innovative technique that
criminals use to get
your money or to infect your PC is Matt
advertising
now advertising is the combination I'll
malicious and advertising and there are
so many
ads and banners like this on the
internet that masquerade as legitimate
add sometimes they can if
appear on the front page of the New York
Times or the Yahoo homepage
but once you click them the matter where
gets
dropped downloaded to your machine and
your device is infected
in fact in a recent survey
Cisco claimed that people are
110 82 times more
likely to get infected by clicking
on one of these militia sad then by
visiting and
adult content website so it's very
dangerous to surf online
even in a very innocent website like
Yahoo homepage organ work time
and there is a new problem as well
fake anti-virus program
you know not just add these are adds
that make
the users think they need to install
this
anti-virus program which then actually
installers virus
these are just a few examples of how
innovative companies have
have become using the security industry
against it of course we are now learning
about
malicious software for smartphones there
are many variants of that as well
and one of the newest to additions to
the past year 2014
point-of-sale matter where matter where
which
620 back the point of state saying the
cash registers
at places like target or Home Depot
or other popular retail locations and
grab the credit card numbers
directly from there what all these
examples show up
is that the bad guys no the name of the
game
in the name of the game is to innovate
and
automate and create new technique in new
growth
revenue engine all the time they are not
resting
maybe they have conferences like this to
learn from each other
but they're not taking a day off from
working hard
to steel our money so
this is the second problem what could be
the solution
one approach could be to keep calm
and carry on and some security vendors
have suggested
that cybercrime is parts of the world in
which would accept it
I don't agree and maybe we can do
something different
maybe we can do the same thing that the
criminals are doing
share collaborate and innovate
work together to learn
about these new techniques and figure
out new wave
to protect against them collaboration
and information sharing programs
already showing great promise all over
the world
I heard that there are some initial
information sharing programs
in Japan as well I'm a big fan all
the practice on sharing details I'll the
attacks
the intelligence that together and I
think
it's time to share it's time to open up
in
tell everyone what has happened even
though many organizations
are embarrassed to say that they were
attacked
the reality of 2014
as we've seen is that almost any
organization can be a target
so really there's not much to be ashamed
about is there
any one one saying is that
sharing is carrying and by sharing
information you're caring for
the ecosystem that you share with your
friends
but I I hear from any security
professionals in many organizations
that they don't care about other ppl
they would just like to protect their
own environment
their own enterprise their own computing
systems their own laser
piece of heaven as it were and make sure
that they're safe
and it doesn't matter what happens to
everyone that so
wiring should you care why should
anyone care this brings me to the
third big problem it's not just about
cybercriminals anymore in the past year
we've learned that they are massive
resources human resources hard at work
actually making the world honorable
keeping the world
fun about making it less safe for
everyone else it's not just the federal
criminal in the past year
we've learned that certain government
agencies
have spent millions of dollars on
finding new
software vulnerabilities but not so they
can fix the vulnerabilities
but rather sort they can exploit them
we've heard about and weak
crypto algorithm that was deliberately
kept week for ten years and them
varying well known company refused vast
amount of money
to keep this algorithm everywhere
although it was weak or
the heart bleed open if the Fed about
when
everyone learned about heart bleed
buggin open SSL
in April
this year it was considered a massive
problem
but the reality is that a certain
government agency
had known about it for years and
everybody uses SSL every country every
organization uses SSL
so this organization this agency
chose to keep it fun about instead of
fixing it for the whole world but
there is something that really makes my
heart believe
at work and these are front page
articles like this
published in time magazine earlier this
year
this article record World War zero talks
about a new trade
in software vulnerabilities they are
private companies that
develop new all software vulnerabilities
also known as
zero-day vulnerabilities and the weapon
knife them
they create working exploit and then
seldom to the highest bidder so that
means there is a
small group I'll individuals and
companies making
lot of money by making everyone else fun
and this is part all the big
problems that we have to face there are
massive resources
at work to make companies like that and
government agency like I mentioned
keep finding new vulnerabilities in your
problems
and they're doing their job that's what
they want to do
that means we all have to work
much harder so I'd like to suggest the
solution to that
or one solution to that and my solution
would be
don't keep your bugs to herself very
simple
the more unknown software
vulnerabilities
are kept silent and secret everyone else
remains
in secure if you are a security
researcher
or malware researcher or even a security
professional in Oregon
nation and you find the problem you find
a bug you find the viability
I think that the best approach
is to make it public and no I think
there is a saying from a supreme
court judge in the United States me said
this about a hundred years ago
he claimed that there is no better
these infect and then the light of day
and
I think this also holds true for when it
comes to
software vulnerabilities next like these
on the Japanese version
thank you
perfect the light of day
so by making
the bugs and vulnerability that we find
known to the public we can make
companies fix their technology and we
can all become more secure
think about the immune system
analogy if we keep a lot of viruses
secret how can we develop a solution how
can the immune system becomes stronger
and protect against it we have to
publish
security vulnerabilities and bug one
from tastic way to get more bugs found
our bug bounty program I heard that
bug bounty programs are starting to
come up in Japan you might have one or
two like this but they're still not very
popular
I think the bug bounty programs are
fantastic ways
to get more security vulnerabilities
found one popular program is the
Facebook
bug bounty program these programs are
away for a company like Facebook to pay
independent hackers and security
researchers
rewards for disclosing vulnerabilities
in their cold and it's not just Facebook
was doing it
in fact there are more than a hundred
companies
in Silicon Valley that now have
published
bug bounty program and they've paid more
than million
millions of dollars for security
researchers from all over the world
Facebook say that they've paid about to
to three million dollars just in their
own bug bounty program
it's a fantastic way to get more
vulnerabilities found
harness the power of the builder hacker
community
and reward them for their findings
another great bounty program is the
internet
by the bounty plan this was started by a
company called
hacker want and their idea was that some
technologies
like PHP and Perl and open SSL
our technology that we all rely on you
but there's nobody working to secure
them
and find the problem so by coming up
with a budget
for a reward program a bug bounty
program for these technologies
they are making cyberspace safer for
everyone
and this is a and
image from Japanese publication and I'm
not sure I got the joke of it but I
understand that bug bounty programs are
beginning
and their way in Japan in the past year
and
I'm very positive about it but I think
there is great promise but
saying you don't find bugs let's say
you're not going to security research
and you don't discovered by the by
yourself okay what about
exploits maybe you found in you exploit
one thing to do about it is to
uploaded could be exploit that the base
and if your company or an organization
that develops technology
I would suggest you take a look at the
extra database
you might be surprised to find some
exploit against
your own technology there this would
happen to me many times
where I go to consult or speak with big
software companies and ask them okay
what the situation with exploiting
vulnerabilities
in your cold and they say oh we're
secure we don't have any exploits
in the wild
north and abilities but if you go online
to a database like this or the
open-source fun ability database
and you type in the company name or the
technology product name
the software suite you find many bugs
are still
being exploited after technology and
they didn't even know about
so one way is to look in these databases
exploit database and the open source
community database
and you might find your technology or
software that you use
is already listed there but
let's say you don't find security
vulnerabilities or exploit okay
what about no matter where what about
you
fun that you discovered on your system
and you suspect that it might be
malicious what do you do that
probably you try to research it yourself
for youth and it will allow
but another approach could be too
uploaded
tocqueville start out how many have you
here are familiar with this
cell website we also got over here
view not fantastic many many viewers
now in use this product by the way it's
a service offered
for free sense Google acquired
the website and they are running it and
in this website you can upload
suspected 5 and have it tested
with more than 50 different anti-matter
engines
but even if it is not discovered that
suspicious file
it is then sent on words to other
security vendors
to start developing the signatures for
it
to start identifying it so again think
about an immune system
we all shared information and
we can create new signatures again new
manner at the score some love you all
are perhaps not on the bottom or not
exploitable
in the world Taylor Swift well actually
they should not be popular American
finger
Taylor Swift bats day
Twitter parody account called swift on
security
and the reason I mention this is because
again
even at this stage there are some
organizations and some companies to
think
we're not a problem we are secure there
are no vulnerabilities in our product
we are safe well that brings me
24 big problem we are all
as mine about as our weakest link
no organization or person
in the 21st century is an island
we are relying on services technology
solutions
partners we have customers we have
calling
we work with other technology systems
were part of an ecosystem
nobody is isolated and that means that
even if for instance you are a massive
american company like Target
even if you're a company that invests
very heavily
in cybersecurity target had them
budget for security more than one
million dollars some of the most
innovative new technologies a place yet
it was still hack how is this possible
well the reason
is because this organization was hacked
first
this organization is called Fuzzy 0
Mechanical Services
and I wouldn't be surprised if you've
never heard about them
because this is a small company from
pennsylvania
that hander refrigerator
macon and this was the
refrigerator maintenance Supplier for
target the massive American retailer
and while target invests very heavily
in cybersecurity fazio Mechanical
Services
do not and fun so did not even have
basic antivirus in place so the
attackers who wanted to get into target
first act Fazil an easy target
and as a supplier of target Fazil had
axis
to the target supplier portal from there
the hackers were able to get into the
Active Directory
inside target and that was there
first pointing to the organization from
there they were able to
getting to the point of sale systems and
stealing millions of credit card
but it all started with one refrigerator
company
in pennsylvania that doesn't even have a
basic anti-virus
we are all as weak as our weakest
partner even a massive
defense company like Lockheed Martin
who creates the next generation fighter
jet
the F 35 bomber fighter
even they are as weak as their
weakest partner and in this case one of
the reasons
1-under suggested reasons that Lockheed
Martin
was hacked and 2011 was because their
security provider
in this case our essay what hack
lockheed-martin used the ISA
secure ID one-time password token which
meant they have
pretty strong authentication so the
attackers
first got into arce to get the secret
information and the algorithm
the generated this one-time password
token now who is behind this attack
there are many rumors but I think
one image is worth a thousand words this
is data
J 22 mother from Chengdu China I think
you'll find it looks quite similar
to the f35 mother made by Lockheed
Martin
so
like I said we are all on me as week as
our
weakest part and sometimes even if
our partner is a multi-billion-dollar
security company
we will still get hacked so it might be
a matter of time even if your
organization has not been attacked
it might be your partner your customers
your employees getting attacked at home
and the second
part of this problem is we have
an illusion we think our borders are
being defended
by fierce cyber warriors but the reality
is
there are no borders in cyberspace
everybody is on the front line
member well-connected so we don't really
have these
fears cyber warriors defending us its
each and every one of us who is or needs
to be
that warrior on the front line we are
connected
this image is up
from the Gulf click also known as DNS
Changer
not or infection a few years ago
now this was a a Trojan used
mostly for clickjacking and other types
of
cybercrime however this image all
almost four million infected devices
shows a very clear picture the attackers
didn't care where the computers the
infected war
they didn't care if it was a security
organization
or a smaller company even after
the American space agency had infected
divisive
what this means is that
if your machine is infected than you are
part of the problem you're spreading the
infection onward
think about the immune system analogy so
if you are not part of the solution
if you're not part of the immune system
you are probably going to be part of the
problem
so another suggestion of another
suggestion on the way
to solve it there are many people out
there
are very happy the massive people that
use their computer or their smartphone
everyday
and they're not concerned with
cybersecurity
they don't realize that they are a part
of the problem
so we have to empower them
we have to help them become part of the
solution
in a way I think we would like all those
happy people to be more like us like
security professionals
always thinking about the next thread
always thinking about security
challenges
always trying to stay one head all the
attacker one
step ahead of the attacker 11 to do this
is a called crypto parties these are
very popular event in Europe
and a crypto party is a voluntary event
informal
like a party where security
professionals
teach basic security scares
to everyday people they teach them about
photography
about staying safe and private online
and they make them
a little bit more powerful there is
another way to empower the masses
and their actually there is someone in
the audience
who has participated in one of these in
the past this is called a
red cyber team and this is in no way an
experiment
started by a good friend of mine was
actually sitting here in the front row
and he will speak to you later
his name using bomb so a group of
security professionals from tel aviv
came together as volunteers
to perform voluntary
red King security testing
for an organization that did not
that could not afford it
and did not really have security in mind
in bar is it okay if I say that type of
organization
the type yes but nothing okay so this
is a medical environment hospital
in central Israel and didn't have any
security budget in place
but after the Red team came with their
quite happy and performed very basic
and free security assessment showing the
hospital manager
exactly what they could do that growth
security
to the top of them I'm it brought
cybersecurity
into the agenda for that organization so
as security professionals
that's another way you can help the
masses
help them empower them make them safer
work like an immune system
volunteer to perform assessments like
that
for organizations that are not from a Dr
with cyber security or that don't invest
in it in other ways by organizing
what is sometimes called a cyber
fire engine this is like and
earthquake parent nest test or fire
drill
where you make everyone in the
organization get ready
for dealing with an attack scenario how
do you know that something went wrong
what are the first indicators what is
the first response
how to deal with an emergency situation
in cyberspace I learned
left week that the fiftieth San Diego in
the United States is performing cyber
drills and exercises
for businesses in California as a joint
voluntary venture with the naval
Postgraduate School which is the
University belonging to the American
Navy
so I by this point I told you about four
big problems before we move on to that
last big problem
I want to give you an idea or suggestion
opportunity
to get some bonus points
in our attempt to saw all the problems
according to a recent survey Cisco they
are
one million security professionals
needed
in the world right now that means that
we need
1 million more security professionals
and so
for us as hackers a security researchers
is
security professionals that means we
have two
start creating more security
professionals
we have to reach out to score the
University
to be mentors or start under
internship programs for new security
professionals
why should we care about this
weekend we can just you know
move on as we were and not think about
creating more security professionals
the market which still demand 1,000,000
security professionals
so everybody can become a security
professional
but they won't have the kid and the
knowledge
and the quantification that Tweedy would
like them to have
so that should be a good reason to start
thinking about
making more security professionals right
now
and now I'd like to move on to their
fifth and final problem 15 find a big
problem
as it were for cybersecurity and I call
this problem
the gap not because of the clothing
store
but because of the gap between their
security industry us here in this room
security professionals and hackers
and the rest of the world and
until the real Taylor Swift
suggest that we start talking about
information security
we were still have a gap a gap between
the popular opinion about cybersecurity
and what we as professionals
no is the reality of it so the first
way to deal with this problem is of
course
to mind the gap to understand
there is this difference between how we
see security issues
and how the public sees security issues
and how the media
talks about them many times that when I
speak to media
our when I a consultant or do speaking
engagements
this is the a beer that the public as
you know cyberattacks there are millions
of cyberattacks
everybody is under millions of
cyberattacks
each day and I liked last them millions
of what
what are you counting millions all
port scans millions all new
malware variants millions of infected
PCs
it's very important to bring the
conversation
to the level of reality and one way to
do it is by asking
questions like that and again remember
the immune system analogy
if we're talking about bacteria
and viruses it's very easy to counts one
million
organisms and bacteria that may be
living everywhere
yet not everyone gets sick all the time
so keep this in mind when you're told
there are millions of cyberattacks
bring the conversation to reality mind
the gap between
what we know is happening and what the
attacks are
and what the public thinks about it and
there is also a gap between I for
security professionals
and the top management the executive
leading organizations that we're working
with and we want to make them invest
more in cybersecurity
but we don't know how well here's
one way to do it you can ask the
question
very simple question how much does the
organization
spend on coffee each year if you're
spending more on coffee
then on cybersecurity you're going to
have a problem
now this was a suggestion by Richard
Clark
who was a their former White House
chief cyber security officer for
the a bush government Bush
administration ten years ago
but it's still true there are some
organizations
and some management executives that are
more concerned with the coffee budget
then with making sure the organization
is secure so
we have to mind that gap and we have to
start closing that gap
now as I up
reflect on the think that and cordial
let's give it a moment to look at these
big problems some of these are very
serious major problems but here are the
good news
all these that these issues these things
I think that we can all
change we can do something about
right now some people in their
organization or environment
what did they say I would love to change
the world
but they don't give me access to the
source called
well here is the thing when it comes to
these problems and solving them for the
future I talked about buying things
that we can order the right now and we
don't need access to the source code on
the world
we can start making these changes happen
in our organizations
so let's summarize number one
think about securing cyberspace
not just the internet or
the World Wide Web cyberspace is complex
and it has many different technologies
in it
number two the bad guys are
collaborative
so we should be as collaborative share
information
innovating our defense techniques and
work together
number three don't keep your bike
yourself there is no better disinfectant
then the light of day
reports on vulnerabilities
disclose exploits start about the bounty
program
in your organization or contribute to
another program
this is all things that you can do
number four
they are amassed masses out there happy
shiny people
that don't think they are part of the
problem we have to make them powerful
we have to help them defend themselves
bring them
into our world the cybersecurity world
problem number five
there is a gap the gap between
the security industry and the general
public and the gap between
ass and our managers and by
finding this gap identifying it and
trying to bridge
across it weekend make cyberspace
safer so with that
I'd like to give you one last message
the future is already here 2015 is
around the corner
new attacks no wonder abilities new
technologies and your problems
will be discovered the question is
how will you shows to protect it
thank you
carnahan do we have a time for one
question yes
okay if you have any questions believe
stand up there's a question over here
thank you you can ask the question in
Japanese and I would have a translated
to me
if that's better for you thank you for
does a view of the thinking about a
question or maybe are shy
plane do not hesitate to contact me on
my own personal
a.m. website on
yes you have it over there
and you have it right here my website
and my Twitter
so you can contact me there yesterday's
are ya today on my question is are
regarding yes right
saying there 1 million secured ex parte
is required
yes and do you think they are are the
requirement can be
it appeared by having the mom 100 them
by have a hundred me on our people
to spent a cybersecurity
are with out there are
one part and doctor brought forth and
time the other thing
so repeat the question just to make sure
I understood that the question was
if we need one million
more security professionals perhaps one
way to achieve that is by asking
or getting $100 million people from the
general task force
to focus on security and get one percent
on that
to make them into security professionals
yes it is so
I think that's a great approach that's a
great way to think about it
really if you have a big workforce which
has
hundreds of the hundreds of millions of
people all you need is that one percent
to become concerned about security the
other
part of that is there is a
responsibility for us
for us as people that are already in the
business
of cybersecurity to make sure good we r
actively creating more security people
by becoming mentors or by opening up
and internship program I've been in the
security industry
the for quite some time and in the early
days
I found it to be closed club
exclusive club right and maybe that was
cool in the nineties
but now I think in order to
face the challenges that we have ahead
we have to open up the club to more
people thank you for the question
I think and I totally agree with that
dumb security people
have to ok the crap yet gone
thank you and I think only have one
question here
up front pay
help how he's disclosing all the books
a solution when there is a fundamental
economic problem
which is a price movements became what
the bad guys
are offering and what but my aunties are
offering
minute because again say okay it's
working
the but my desire giving results but
a my opinion you are just getting that
top of that ice word
and you are not going to reach there
bottom of the iceberg where the real
stuff is that okay
few days that will compromise or
organization will come from thats
and
from that area so it's the problem okay
so let me repeat the question the
question was
what is the logic or the viability
all solving the problem of security
vulnerabilities by
disclosing all the bugs and by creating
about the program
where in fact the the person is claiming
the real problems and refund abilities
are the ones
probably coming from deeper underground
the ones that the criminals are paying a
bigger amount of money for if I
understand your question correctly
so again I think there is a question all
large numbers here if we can get more
and more and more vulnerabilities found
and discovered
and Saul it would make the life all
those people that are trying to find a
10 days in Feb for a lot of money
it will make their life harder and they
will have to work
harder to find a favorability this is
to you that energy it is a big swap
right and we can't drain it all but we
can start
making it a little bit more shallow we
can make the problem space
smaller so that they have to work harder
if they're if the criminals or the
vulnerability researchers are going to
make
200 thousand dollars for selling one bug
they better work hard for it that's not
make their life
easy and again it's a big problem but
one-way
I think to start solving a problem is by
getting more and more
and more vulnerability disclosed thanks
further questions very
relevant I think that's all we have time
for I
am
in
any more questions last question okay so
I repeat again
if you'd like to ask me a question in
private please don't hesitate to reach
me through my website
or my Twitter account very accessible
and I'd like to thank you again
oh yeah