all right good afternoon everyone
welcome to the dirty tooth talk in
addition to the published author
Gemma Alonso right here we have a
special so please welcome both of them
to the tour see how the community is
growing and I was in in the valley this
week my I didn't want to show to give
many information about the topic in the
end probably all of you have been
reading the description of the top and
it's quite a pity because the magic is
is when you don't know what is what you
are going to see the real the talk is is
this it's only rock and roll but I like
it because it's a talk about music how
many of you like music okay so let's see
how many of you are brave enough to
prove that your music is the better the
best so we have a present if you will
connect to our device too and whoever
wins by playing their favorite song well
get one of my lock-picking business
cards so yeah one of these and you just
you need to have an iPhone
no Androids we don't have any come here
please a big April the device is
Bluetooth speaker how many of you any
time in your life have connected to a
Bluetooth speaker
and select some music well is it
connected
okay so selects music I got play your
favorite song
double check the connection try to
connect again yeah 32 up on hers Kilburn
there are too many speakers here let's
see I show it on mine but you know you
don't want to hear any of my music
what's not connected there just turn it
off and on any other volunteer with our
real life phone gosh so April I met her
in Jason Street in Beijing last week and
I don't know if he she purchased her
iPhone from Shenzhen because then it's
not really an iPhone so maybe bluetooth
is messed up so we'll see anybody else
by the way I have an iPhone connect to
the kill barn
who's gonna connect the kill burn can
you see it
should you see the device
well I think he just dropped my no you
know you don't want to pair it no you
turn it off I have to reconnect to it
okay we're gonna turn it off and on yeah
it's strange right now where do you see
Kilburn try connecting maybe it's
showing up in my devices because i was
connected to it in the past
do you see a bluetooth device kilburn
connect to kill run in play music it's
quite simple I got one
Brereton is forbidden you can play any
music but reggaeton does it show that
you connected to it music and it's weird
because I'm not seeing the device either
because I forgot the device and he
associated okay okay connect
I already connect lots of people really
connect and that's you know but the good
point is that we wanted to listen the
music so we connect to the PI if you
want which is doing exactly the same is
duty to the speaker if you can put the
audio front from the out and someone and
someone connect to do it I'm going to
connect to the I got exactly the same is
an iPhone nothing special and I'm going
to connect to to the pipe that's a dirty
to the speaker if you see that on your
Bluetooth list
but already connected yeah this is
interesting so I try to connect it you
might have to well it sucks when a demo
doesn't work straight off the bat but
well let's see how many of you have been
connected the problem is the audio no
they're not the connection but let me
explain what had been happening behind
the scenes because it's quite quite
interesting so one of the good things
with iPhone is a device that is supposed
to be very secure it has a lot of
protection it has cosine in it has
approval from Apple to install new apps
it has a very good encryption algorithms
to a store data into the hard drive etc
the problem with devices like like
iPhone is that once that you connect the
device to any channel you are exposing
the security that's that's very easy to
understand I mean iPhone there are a lot
of tricks to to take information from it
or to to hack the device you can do a
lot of things with sorry if you are used
inside a with the lock screen you can
hack the full iPhone from the Windows
machine or I know always machine if it's
already / we've seen in the past a lot
of malware that was was using the
pairing connection with a Windows
machine to jailbreak the iPhone an
installed malware if you are making a
backup in the iCloud you are going to
have exactly the same problem if you
don't have secure mechanism to protect
iCloud that we've seen a lot of
celebrities having troubles with the
picture that had been stolen stolen from
the iCloud when you connect to a
telecommunication network like the same
etc you can be hacked using fake BTS we
seen in the past a lot of a lot of
attacks using jammers against the threee
of four year connection to get at
to the connection and the same with
Wi-Fi Bluetooth Epica application etc
one of the things that the iPhone has is
the Bluetooth connection and the
implementation that we got in iOS with
the Bluetooth is quite special it it is
full of usability features that you can
use in your advantage if you want to
extract information from from a target
so first thing is that the Bluetooth
stack that iPhone so it took a few times
of rebooting it but we finally got it
that's just enough
[Music]
all right so we tested 20 times what do
you want stage it fails of course in the
case of iPhone
we got one implementation of the stack
which is the 2.1 that means that one
specific feature that was added to the
Bluetooth stack in 2007 that was the
first version of iPhone mm what's in
there which is the possibility of do a
Bluetooth connection with any device
with a pairing token which is good for
usability because you don't need to to
type any token or you don't need to
check a number in other devices click on
it and you are connected that is exactly
what you've been doing a lot of time in
Bluetooth speaker look for the Bluetooth
speaker click on it and that's all which
is good for you stability but one one
problem with this is that when you get a
Bluetooth connection you are not having
always the same Bluetooth connection and
when to when when two devices are
connected over bluetooth what's really
critical here is the profile because the
profile whoops essentially gives
permissions of what that connection is
allowed to do so it's kind of like
meeting a girl you're right it might be
having the friendship profile and then
all of a sudden maybe it could switch to
the friends with benefits profile you
may or may not know about it but then if
it switches to the marriage profile you
can be in big trouble
or maybe not I don't know but the types
of profiles there up here I don't know
if you could see them clearly but it's
much easier over here we could stream
audio we can control audio-visual
devices everyone knows about the headset
profile connect the headsets and free
for your cars what's it going to be
important later on in the presentation
is this profile here the phonebook
access profile and a profile I'd love
this to work with but doesn't
unfortunately and chema we'll get into
is the map profile where we can actually
get access to text messages so the idea
is that when we are reading that iPhone
supporting Bluetooth in fact we are
reading is that iPhone is supporting our
set of Bluetooth profiles in the case of
iPhone or iPad
we have different profiles that are
implemented from the iPhone 4 and later
we have hands-free profile phonebook
access profile advanced audio
distribution profile audio video etc
personally an Edward Humes device and
messaging audio profiles messaging
access profile all of them are available
from iPhone Quattro 4 to the iPhone that
we have today and depending on the
profile that you connect to any device
that device is going to be able to do a
set of things on iPhone so first thing
that we got with this usability feature
right so what's interesting with the
iPhone over here is when you get a list
of potential Bluetooth Bluetooth devices
to connect to it doesn't give you much
information in contrast with the Android
we get a little bit more information
with the icon it's not so much more
important but it's interesting that the
Android gives you a little bit more
information second point is that when
you connect to one device if that device
wants to have a secure connection it's
going to require a temporary failing
token appear in token that pretty token
is quite interesting if you are able to
read only a name in the Bluetooth list
about the device you are connecting to
you don't have you are not 100% sure
that you are connected to connecting to
the right device so if someone
impersonate the name or the device that
you are using every day in your bathroom
or in your kitchen you are going to
connect exactly
- the same name Pearlie is not going to
be automatic because there is our
protection with the physical address but
people can connect to to it on the other
hand when you have device that requires
a painting token you are forced to look
to that device and be sure that you are
connecting to to the right one and
normally at least with iOS not only does
Apple have to approve access to the
application because they must sign it
before you can install it on your phone
but you must give explicit access to the
apps for example to access your phone
book or your contacts here later so when
you connect to you install an app and
that app try to get access to your
content links you need you have an
explicit permission on the other hand
when you connect to one device a
Bluetooth device that wants to access to
your contact list the answer by default
is yes that means that without any
parent token any any alert or any
special permission any device if that
device has the right Bluetooth profile
can get access to your contact list
right so if you do this with an Android
device Android actually pops up a
message warning you that a profile has
been changed unfortunately it's in I'm
not it's in Spanish right because I
guess Spanish is well here we are a
small video about what is the behavior
in Android if one Bluetooth device is
trying to get access to your contact
list so here we are opening the
configuration area it's in Spanish
because the Spanish is better so right
now it's looking look is the new version
is is the P so as you can see there is
on a speaker with a headset and you
connect to it
it's supposed to be able to speak
but at some time in the future that
device this a decided to change the
profile why not you are connected to one
device and you select the profile you
want to use in the example as you can
see Android
so at warning messages saying okay
something happening but that device that
wanted to be your friends with benefits
now want to get married with you okay so
over here when when you're looking at
the when during the connection process
when it's doing the connection there is
like no warning here but when it
switches the profile it actually gives
an option whether or not to share the
contacts but typically what's what
happens is nobody is actually staying on
this particular screen on the phone
they've already switched to something
else so they don't actually see what's
happening in the background so once they
connect it's really nothing else matters
yeah so this is the video of exactly the
same that we've seen in Android but in
iPhone you can see is in a perfect
Spanish and now we are connecting to one
device that is supposed to be a
Bluetooth speaker you don't have any
information just the name so he's the
speaker to connect to it that's it you
are already connected everything is
perfect no extra information on the
configuration options so we go to switch
the profile and later by default is
sharing your contact leads if you are
there when it changes you can watch it
if not you cannot so okay so basically
just the steps here
I am the Bluetooth speaker it goes
through the pairing process with no you
don't need a pairing pin you're paired
and then after a few seconds then we
switch the profile and then we get
access we switch it from the advanced
audio distribution profile to the
phonebook profile then we're able to
basically think your phonebook your call
log what's your call log this calls
receive calls calls phone numbers you
call to we're able to sync that we're
able to store the data and then
exfiltrated that we can actually switch
back to the speaker profile so it's a
few seconds the data stolen it switch
back the victim doesn't know any better
so on this the Marshall speaker what we
have here is that with the original
speaker we have a Bluetooth board this
Bluetooth module actually has to be
switched out no because the to access
this module users proprietor proprietary
their proprietary software so we
actually have to switch it out to a
spark fund Bluetooth module so this is
kind of the diagram but the whole thing
so basically in this particular speaker
the Bluetooth module is switched out we
put a teensy in obviously programming
with the Arduino framework we have an SD
connector because once the information
is stolen from the device we store it on
the mini I mean the micro SD card then
we have we have a GSM module that were
able to exfiltrate the data and what
we're going to show you in a moment is
we have this debug module that lets us
use screen to basically to be able to
connect to the device so we can
essentially like get a shell on the
device and control it that way so over
here we'll get into this in a second but
in on the device itself we have main
book DCF and what that is that's
actually the contact list of the victim
that we've stolen from the device and
then we have incoming calls the outgoing
calls the miss calls it's stored in the
devices directory and this is a CRC
crc32 of the MAC address so basically
for each device it's going to be a
different directory it's created and
then it's going
or the status the means of incoming
outgoing and miss calls what's
interesting is how this is set up if an
iOS device connects then we're gonna
switch the profile not an on iOS device
connected we could tell by the Oh UI
right from Apple if an on iOS device
connects we just play music
we don't actually switch to the
phonebook profile so let's see reconnect
to it unfortunately she already has one
sorry now I'm going to cut connect to
the debug module in the Marshall speaker
so we're just waiting takes a second for
it to come up there we go now you're
gonna see the the pin please don't
connect yeah unfortunately i hack work
and you already connect no no stop
messing with it I was going to turn off
the mirroring to connect to the pin but
I trust you guys to let us do the demo
now I don't know if I'm making a mistake
by trusting an audience of hackers but
we'll see
no turn it off and on don't mess with
her come on cuz then I can't show you or
how the information is stored and you
just stop the demo it doesn't make much
sense it's not the right pin is it one
let me try this didn't fail seven one
zero no you tried turning it off and on
again
Mac OS now someone's messing with her
from the audience as he's looking up the
pin so so basically once we connect
using the debug module obviously you
have to put a sim card in the device so
instad is a command where we can
actually make sure before actually doing
the attack that we have connection to
the mobile operator okay how you connect
to the debug module is simply using
screen there you know you just got look
on your Mac OS you look in the dev
directory for the actual device and then
the baud rate is 115 200 et stat lets
you look at the status of Bluetooth and
pista you can see the devices that
actually connected in the past
7:01 so let's try to get one more shot
filled 7:01 9 is there the operating
system was working over there so I don't
know let's see you want try pairing it
from yours ok ok very good
I'll try it from yours well in this case
we did with this specific Bluetooth
speaker and one important thing is that
it when you want to replace the
Bluetooth stack from one speaker to put
your round stack do you need to connect
the new Bluetooth stack to the mainboard
and in this case it runs preparatory
code and we needed to do reverse or
designers that were using the original
blue to the stack and we needed to build
up this small interface to connect the
the teensy with the Arduino and the rest
of the other things and in the end what
is happening how it works is exactly
like this video which is the plan see if
the demo was failing which is like this
on the left side we got on the left side
we got the iPhone and we are connecting
to the speaker and right now we play
music that's all good news
[Music]
on the right side you can see the the
panel is a web panel we are copying all
the contact list the miss calls etc and
we are uploading this to the to a panel
in a website and you are as you can see
we are retrieving all the information in
the end this information is in the
format in which Apple is a store in your
contact list we see which is BC cards
and this is the format in which we are
retrieving the the information is a
basica is version 2.1 if you are
familiar with this format we are now in
version 3 are trying to figure out how
to do all the character sets with his
keyboard I wasn't listening what he said
did you cover UID 0 ok so on what school
with the V cards what we look for first
is UID 0 why because that's the owner of
the device right so if they store their
own card we now know who the owner is
and we have their specific information
which might be email address and
whatever any other details they could
put in the connect to know where it came
in so one important thing is that right
now we are in version 3 and with the
phone book access profile which is the
profile that we are using in this hack
you are supposed to be able to write VC
cards into the device in this case we
try it but Apple doesn't doesn't allow
us to to do it but we tested only with
the phone book access access profile and
in the new version which is BC 3 do
which is the new the new standard that
Apple is using for the new operating
system
you got more information like picture
like notes like URL so information
private information that you are adding
to your contact list that if is storing
the in the basic format so the idea is
that we retrieve all contact lists to
the to the back end with your phone
number your name your email whatever and
once that you got the data in back-end
we do open source intelligence
enrichment so with the phone number we
look for the Facebook profiles for the
link in a car etc zoo so in the end you
can create a very nice map of the social
life of one target and this is the video
with what is happening behind the scenes
when someone connect to to this speaker
the first part is exactly the same but
there are two iPhone screen in one of
them we are going to to maintain the
screen in the options of the Bluetooth
device so right now we are connecting
and then on the right side we look for
the option as you can see at the
beginning there is nothing
[Music]
and then it changed so that's the whole
story
do you connect to any Bluetooth devices
clicking on that and that device can be
stolen your your data any time so in
order to do it easy to implement not to
be using doing reverse engineering to
the to the hardware we created something
very easy which is a distribution for
the for the Raspberry Pi the idea is
quite simple there is a debian package
that you install in your in your
Raspberry Pi and the Raspberry Pi
becomes our fro Bluetooth speaker and
it's very easy to manage this console we
are installing the package then we are
going to run it one minute video so then
we run the service and it's working and
right now it's like a normal Bluetooth
speaker the only thing that you need to
do is to put a real speaker in the audio
jack and the rest is exactly the same
you connect to the to the speaker and at
some point Raspberry Pi is going to to
change the profile to play music we're
going to play the video that we've been
seeing so before and
[Music]
quite simple let's do okay this is mine
that's my girlfriend's number back there
[Laughter]
so now she has to change the number yeah
so that's the call log information let
me see the contact list here contact
list is what's cooler though is once you
get it stored onto the PI is on the PI 3
up Wi-Fi then using Wi-Fi you send it
over to some panel and I'll show Tina
moment so that's so it's dot phonebook I
see
yeah so here we have great my phone list
so let's go to the panel let me refresh
there we go we got three devices
I know sure which one second one are you
sure I think I first one slow internet
because we're tethered to Spain SIM card
so telephone because some cars it's kind
of slow it works that's not mine for
sure
yeah that's not mine either not to show
the whole number but we still have you
know do know this is your prize for sure
your data it's like a Facebook you got
our free account but you get to share
your data
you know his girlfriend's name a number
[Laughter]
well this is the idea it's just a lot of
a small usability feature that you can
put together to create something like
this it's only rock and roll but I like
it
things that you can do with this well
hug works with any other profile so you
can be changing profiles as you wish an
iPhone is going to tell you nothing
depending on the kind of things that you
can do with the Bluetooth profile you
can do more or less thing on the device
we are not maybe next version of iOS so
turn on the map profile by default
profile but by default is not sinking
which is bad for us but it's good for
for users with this profile with for a
phone book access profile it's forbidden
to for them to write the big car which
is you can imagine what social
engineering setups you could do if he
could write somebody's contact list and
change phone numbers for their existing
contacts that'd be very interesting and
then you couple that with SMS spoofing
right so you can imagine you could
probably get a compliance and you could
use that for some really good pretexting
and the rest you know it you are
connecting to one device that someone
gave to you in a conference or as a gift
and it's a big device that right now is
only a bluetooth that will replace but
you can add a lot of crazy stuff inside
the box and you can create whatever
whatever you wanted if you want to learn
more about that we wrote a small paper
explaining all that usability fit
features that we are using in the end
with we believe that this is a hack and
not about but probably
could be good for you sir you receive an
alert when one device is already
connected change their profile but it's
an idea who knows and that's all if you
got you want to make any question we are
Albany
[Applause]
the question is in Android when you can
connect to one device that is requiring
an access operating token or not but if
you connect to one device that is not
requiring and parent token and database
changed the profile you receive an alert
so there is like a permission that you
need to get access from a Bluetooth
device to the contact list in an android
that's it
well I didn't listen you very well but
it's hard to hear you speak up a little
bit the profile switches yeah well we
were thinking about that and let's
imagine that the default option for iOS
is not to sync contactless how many
users are going to call the call center
saying okay I cannot connect to my car
with my iPhone so I my belief is that
they decide to do this just a usability
feature to not having calls to the call
center with with a bad experience that's
my belief but in the end they are
sacrificing security okay the last demo
okay so right now because we're having
some issues with the sim card here right
now it's trying to upload exfiltrate
remember how the data is first stored on
the micro sd card right now right now
it's trying to exfiltrate it but it
can't to the cloud because we're having
a problem with the GSM module in here
the sim card cannot connect to the
mobile opera the local mobile operator
is having an issue with the roaming so
[Laughter]
right now it's kind of stuck trying to
upload the data it's trying to read the
file and send it but as soon as in a
moment I'll be able to actually talk to
the actual debug module in here and show
you what we have show you that we have
the same data okay finally alright so
I'm just doing a directory there's a
device's directory
so here are the different devices and
this is again over here was a pointer oh
so we put this up here so over here
these are the devices that connect this
is the C crc32 of the actual MAC address
of the device make this bigger great so
now we're gonna look and see what's
stored in the directory 6 4 4 1 it will
look at the directory and we'll have the
contact list as main book by vfc let's
take a look
might be somebody that knows that they
don't want to get share that information
so this is easier to do it
and main book now it's doing that crappy
okay main book VCF so here's the
somebody's anybody recognize Chris
geyser Tom gets whose phone is this
anybody recognizes what your friends new
front somebody the audience how to
connect right and then we're able to now
store the phonebook right essentially
the contact list call logs and then what
happens is every what is a couple
minutes here this is trying to connect
to the mobile operator right now the sim
isn't registered here locally so I can't
actual trace the data but if we had a
prepaid if we have a SIM card here that
was locally in the US it would actually
work unfortunately this is not
connecting to the local network okay
that's all thank you very much for being
here
[Applause]
oh I have a I brought about a hundred of
my business cards which are lockpick
sets if anyone would like one just come
up and I'll be happy to give you one and
after you get your business card just
FYI we will have a snack break out in
the foyer out there so please step
outside and make sure not to miss that
it's sponsored by Qualcomm Thank You
Qualcomm