all right good morning and welcome
everyone whoo yeah that's what I like to
hear we're gonna get started here with
our keynote I've got the pleasure of
introducing a longtime friend of ours a
friend of mine the hacker with the
perfect pitch
we've got Lance James launching us off
today so please give them a warm welcome
to the stage boot good morning everyone
usually I have to do the whole like good
evening but you guys are pretty freaking
cool so maybe it's not evening so I am
okay so I've been I'm gonna brag but
it's not about bragging I've been
speaking around the world doing keynotes
everything like this this is the first
keynote I'm actually really nervous
about in a good way because this is uh
this is a big thing so a little bit
about me I'm late these buttons I guess
I'm Lance James currently I am the chief
scientist over flashpoint oh so we run a
company like almost every other hacker
does too just so that they can do pen
tests and fun stuff prior to that I was
head of cyber intelligence at Deloitte I
turned them around and made them from
bean counters to actually understanding
what cyber means and I was also the
original founder of ITP which actually
in many ways I'll explain what's
inspired by torque on and by the way I
know we have a bunch of parties but if
you guys sneak away from any of them
when I go karaoke tonight I'm not I will
go with you I will go with you okay so
this also they don't like you know my
company wants me to do biopics I I was
like all right cool here's a lifelike
drawing of me so I you know here we go
I'm actually was thinking about this and
I wanted it you know like I've been at
torque on almost since the beginning and
I'll go into that in a second and I
wanted to kind of bragging like do all
the huge lists and he's the only reason
it wasn't about me it was the fact that
I could give a lot of credit to how many
things we've done in this industry how
many things we've gone along in the last
19 years
honestly to work on in that way so it
wasn't like hey lookit I did it was more
like look what inspired me look like
what did torque on do for me so anyways
I'm gonna start with patient zero days
which is nineteen nine in a world in
1999 before a Skynet fell alright so
basically what we have is a fifteen or
sixteen year old boy with his mom
driving him everywhere around I found
that out today from hell over here
trying to basically start up this
conference called torque on and route
backwards I think we all know that so we
have this guy Ben I don't know if I ever
met Ben but I'm gonna give him credit
cuz he seems like obviously Conan has a
very cool like pseudonym so Benin's uh
score over here here's a very young
picture of Hikari I know it's weird
Ellis cuz I'm getting old man does he
look the same so he's bastards so David
was probably about fifteen or sixteen
years old probably on the costumes
when's your birthday you're like when is
your birthday yeah okay so you know he's
probably planning it at fifteen taking
over the world by sixteen I actually
moved to San Diego 1998 myself right and
so I met them in about 2001 now let me
tell you what is important about that in
1998 I got moved here because someone
actually heard me sing yes that actually
happened someone flew me on a plane Dada
and I thought I was gonna be doing music
right and you know there's two sides of
it when you grow up you're like I was
trained musician all this stuff and then
I was like by eight I was on a computer
too and I couldn't I suppose to be
practicing but I was I was having this
hard time this line is fine line with me
was getting on me I was really important
is that when you become an adult as a
hacker and someone who's like kind of
like done it now I'll tell you I got a
little bit of skiffs when I was a
teenager with this stuff learning
learning the ropes and pissing people
off but what was really important to me
was the fact that I was trying to find a
place to belong and I didn't have
anybody who understood in my world yet
so to them I was just this magician and
scared the out of them and they
didn't understand that I'm sure a lot of
you have had that feeling when we were
younger and so I moved in late 1998
worked through some stuff had some fun
got some jobs blah blah blah and I'm
living in this place called the loft it
literally is called the loft yes it was
a cult I wasn't in part of it I just
basically was assisted
for basically living because I needed
money and I needed a place to live it
was embarrassing there was a guy named
Merced he had this long beard man when
he ate all his food was in his white
beard so I think he's probably arrested
by now anyways the point is I see these
two guys his name one of them name is
Tim and one of them I name is David and
actually I furlong this time probably
thought your real name was Hikari which
was kind of cool and I haven't really
gotten over calling you that so you know
I saw them looking around the typewriter
fonts awesome for this kind of
conference by the way I totally broke
the Flashpoint rules of PR like type
fonts but who cares and I'm looking at
it and the reason why I know this answer
right here I'm like okay these guys are
hackers or at least one of them was yeah
I don't know about Tim yet he looks like
the business guy but so basically and
the reason why I knew this is because
part Hikari had his briefcase one of
these and this briefcase the minute I
saw it I'm like okay there's either one
of two things in there either
this because that's what I would have in
there or something like this which of
course will scare the out of
anybody that if you're walking near a
military building so so I of course
approached them because I am not exactly
shy you can tell I think not sure and so
we talked and he was looking for a space
and we met him and of course I think we
hung out from there on and like I was
excited and I'm I'm probably this
overwhelming like 18 19 year old just
running to these dudes that are really
kind of introverted and quiet and I'm
like hahaha
and it's like mommy right that's that's
basically the feeling I had in my head
because I'm like holy crap I'm not by
myself anymore this is awesome right and
you hear about 2600 and back then you
hear about DEFCON but that's the
legendary it's scary to someone like
that's not even like stepped into a
community yet right or or 2600 that's
like stuff you add you know you're like
oh my gosh what is that that's like you
know then you find out 26 and there's a
bunch of 40 year olds living in their
mom's basement still but anyways so so
basically by 2000 I think one I came to
torque on Ryan it was September I
believe we still had it back
very different shifting time I think
September 11th just happened which was
interesting obviously and you know
security all that stuff it kind of
played into like obviously some of the
climate that was already starting to
shift right um but what what torque onto
a yachting hacker like me was when I
walked in that room the first year 2001
for me it was a safety net first time I
could feel as humans I think and as
especially importantly as hackers and a
counterculture we all want to feel
accepted validated heard you know how
many times we yell and say you're stupid
and vulnerable blah blah blah and it's
not really that we think they're stupid
we just want to be heard we have some
cool stuff we're working on and I am in
it I walk in there I find this safety
net if people just like me most of them
a lot much quieter than I am but you
know still I'm like I and actually as
much as I talked I listened a lot and it
was really awesome right
another thing it was my first start it
was to young hacker 19 20 years old it's
a first start it was like and you know
the cool things thing is the car was
introducing me as like a crypto axe but
I looked okay I'm just starting to play
around with it but he respected the work
I was doing and he introduced me to
others and and that was a really cool
thing as like I I you know in my head in
your mind your fears like oh my gosh I
I'm probably not that smart
you know the imposter syndrome we all
have and we're like yeah I probably just
a fake and they're you know all these
hackers has gotta be really an you know
they're gonna be like oh my gosh what a
joke and and we all had that feeling I
know we do we have to humiliate
ourselves at least once to get over it
right but that's the feeling that I
didn't get because someone like David
came around and introduced me to people
and he would take a highlight of
something I'm doing and he would
introduce me to the highlight of
something else they're doing as if it
was equal planes you know and they
became my friends many times I've had
you in the house Tim drunk his house on
a bed that on a sofa that my ex-wife
doesn't really want anybody touching and
that really that was fun a big
explanation there sorry honey it's cool
he's just really sick but that's that's
that that's the no touch sofa well
that's why I'm divorced anyways yeah not
the life I wanted to live but either way
I friends
you know the cool thing is I got I got
the privilege and honor to help with
some of the workshop seminar build outs
because I was running a business at the
time later and I was you know getting
pretty I was kind of hacking business I
was learning how that worked too and so
it was like really cool so I I look back
and I get to see like the success of
like sounds like a whole week now
practically and it's really really cool
and I see so many people learning and
sharing information but they were my
friends
you know they've been through that
divorce I mentioned they've been there
you know it isn't just a community of
like my technical skills but you know
you get to really have an underlying of
who we are and how we're accepted and
through all of those things they were
there too
and they were my community right they
are they were what I know kind of an
extended family like you all are in a
way even if I don't know you like I
can't wait to meet this guy with his
head shaking like this yeah right but I
don't know him yet but I know I'm gonna
talk to him later right
so and that's the cool thing we all
share something and bond like you know
some people in church they all share one
belief but we have something we share as
a community right and then it's my home
and today I feel back home that's why
I'm nervous but I feel back home and
this is the biggest donor I could ever
have so that's that's that's to work on
to a young hacker and I and I found a
home right so 1999-2001 the hacker
climate so our favorite movies I think
most of these are right I was guessing
with most of the audience I didn't get
us time to do a survey did I miss any
what was that kind of it which one wait
oh no no no no no no wait wait for it
wait for it okay wait for it that's
their favorite movie to make fun of
that's different
jeez okay so we got war games we got
sneakers I think we all love sneakers it
was kind of like I want that job and you
know the funniest part is when they like
give him it's like paycheck and then
she's like not a very good living
because he goes it's a living and she
goes not a given I'm like yeah yeah you
talk now huh so so you know real genius
how many people really loved real genius
so I was doing an interview for mr.
robot we had Jeff Moss on they had a few
different things the thing about like
what hackers feel about mr. robot shell
secret I didn't watch past five episodes
I had a friend Tom
all the cool technical things and stuff
I just didn't have time and - I think
some of its hard to get through
especially on the drug references I was
you know get past two episodes of that I
got that he's just drunk it's good
moving on but basically by the time I
got there and stuff it was kind of funny
they were wanting the war games best
movie right and like I was gonna go to
cliche I'm like nah real genius man
that's like some prank ass man and
it's kind of like the way the world is
today right it's like look you know
academics really secretly just doing
stuff for the military hey you know so
real genius you know give some votes at
least all right cool all right you know
Val Kilmer you know all right
blue boxes when we were in this time
we're legendary but kind of like we
couldn't really execute them anymore
they didn't do anything but the TGI
Fridays down the street here you guys
familiar with that TGI Fridays anybody
go to it while they stopped here yet if
not you know maybe go to it in back then
Red Box ipil it was really awesome and
so you know when you had your red box
you like check it out and I remember a
guy a phone freak friend of mine named
Lucky who'd be here I think I met him or
here we go and you're like check it out
it's actually a coke we can
actually you know red box this thing was
kind of cool cuz you know to see that in
action at that time is fun but in the
hacker climate who were we were mostly
introverts mostly we were Nick Matt ik -
a lot of people helpful I think
underneath this has always been like we
just want to help others you know even
if it means that we got on the wrong
side of the law for a little bit of that
and I don't think we're like haha I'm
evil I think it literally was like
whoops whoops my impulse got to me again
whoo whoops you know bit mischievious
we'd like to prank people it's fun
genius and we were a little bit feared
you know 9/11 happens I know that's
extreme but now so everything is
security national security you know it
was like literally like you know and it
and we just had this fear it was like
the rest of us was like oh crap did you
read the Patriot Act did you read the
Patriot Act right like so but internally
our climate was to have certain goals
and I think we can all share these
improve security
you know we literally for some reason
find security is it I was told by
psychologists once we all loved security
cuz we're insecure which I actually kind
of believed in a little bit but
we want to improve security whether its
internal or external um we want to learn
and that was the thing that I loved
about to work on I just came here like
haha
right I mean just learned so much and we
want to share and you'd think it was the
Iike most egotistical day of your your
view of your weekend was that oh man I
really talked a lot about myself but you
realize you're just excited about
sharing what you've been working on and
then you go back home and you're quiet
again and you know back to your normal
life and back to being an introvert and
no one understands me for until next
year you know I can't wait till next
year I'll get understood again right and
the conference's we had obviously were
just DEFCON and 2600 cert or con played
a different role and I think that's
actually important but how many people
had this toy back then in 1999 and
they're there they're cool if they were
cool they had this right the M 100 or
101 right they actually kept a schedule
what hacker keeps scheduled seriously
sleep scheduled daytime right you know
ah this was IOT a quote on anybody
recognize this little device over here
you know what this talks really about
we're old anyways and then I've
got a game for you guys today all right
since we most of us are more in I age
group are higher and stuff how many
newbies any first-time comers to to work
on this year we got one over here got
there we got over there okay we got a
good crowd over here this is great how
do you guys feel
Yap thumbs up use sign language I don't
I don't know what no actually I I do
have an idea though so when you go to
the parties tonight or tomorrow you're
gonna realize your voice is going to
want run out
I suggest next year you do everybody
learning sign language and a group so
that you can communicate and talk to
each other well there's hardcore music
going on because really you're gonna
want to talk even though there's music
going on that's what happens for like
the next two weeks so I say we do that
plus there's a good side effect we can
talk to deaf people and they're not
upset about it so okay game time name
that terminal all right I'll give you a
freebie one so you guys ready which
terminal does this computer match come
on
thank you whoo who said that what's your
name
todd todd wins the trash eighty kidding
I don't didn't bring those with me yes
that would be fun though I'm like I'll
send you a trash eighty buddy
all right so what I actually okay I
actually had someone sent me their
Commodore 64 I was like really stuck
speaking of I think you guys know this
one and it's hard to see but which one
is this yeah it does say that doesn't it
I was like I could just cross it off but
you know what okay someone describe it
for me what's it look like it looks like
that thing basically big-ass computer
you find your own monitor thank you okay
and my favorite one this worked hold on
okay wait that's what yes this one yeah
I love this you know why I don't know
why but this is the one I grew up on
this was cool except mine was a color
monitor I'll show you in just a second
so how many had the Apple 2e for two
okay how many had the trash eighty
probably in schools most people didn't
buy them they're in their school you're
like hey it's in school the red button
remember little red button how many had
the Commodore I think take you like an
even round here you know it was really
the Battle of the computers back then
right so all right how many had none of
them how many had none of them you
youngers look at Co first timers all
right so the cool thing about that
though terminal stuff was the fact that
when you he wanted to know a computer
back then you have to learn how to
program that was the user manual the
programmers manual today it's like let
me watch let's watch the show impressive
button we got Connor over here he's
gonna learn programming later probably
but not because he has to so all right
so I got a cool thing I'm gonna go back
a little nostalgia my mom has her
awesome moments not all the time at all
but my mom has her awesome moments I
have two things that I love I love music
and I love computers and my mom sent me
actually recently all my classical music
and stuff cuz I'm gonna pick up my
violin again and do some stuff but she
sent me my Apple 2e from a childhood
this is really really really cool
and guess what school it's not it they
took very good care of it they give me
all the floppies for some reason all the
games I had was pirated I don't know
about my parents right now but I don't
have an original game except for who is
worried in the world is Carmen Sandiego
because you had to buy that one because
they didn't know how to do some DRM so
but basically what I've got here is this
is my first computer program I was like
that mattered to me that I wrote when I
was 8 story is I read the computer
programmer manual and I learned about
X&Y plotting and basic Apple basic which
is moving the mouse and the joystick and
I had the square little joystick and so
I as a kid was probably destined for
security because I played games in my
head is such a spy and I wanted to
protect people likely because I'm
adopted at 2 and it has some kind of
weird psychological syndrome that goes
with protecting people but the point is
for my head I'm the kid that's like I'm
gonna be an FBI agent and I'm gonna make
sure everybody's safe crap right now
not the FBI agent that you hate I meant
just as a kid okay so I work for e FF
it's a badge everybody we're effin here
ok no so basically in my head I always
wanted to protect people right and that
was my thing as a kid so I protected my
games even to run hello mode he's got a
thing going on with this one alright so
here is actually a startup I found my
first big program and it's really cool
it might be hard to see but I'm gonna
explain it so I start this thing up yes
the floppy disks actually work I enter a
security code this uses get car which
means it doesn't show any like stars or
anything
the only vulnerability is that you could
technically it has no enter either so if
you get the password right it just opens
up now this number right here is me
taking my joystick and using it as a
combination lock so basically what it
does is you have to know the actual
number in the position and the joystick
that you actually have to put in there
to open up and get to the welcome to the
president's own back door I just made
up when I was a kid I'm gonna say I
have to actually review the code so that
I knew what the numbers were in the
password sorry I was like ok I
don't remember so so and then I can't
see what that is but it's something
probably just as you know kid like you
know blah blah blah blah blah blah so
basically I have to turn it one
why turn the combination the other way
and then I having a lock code I don't
know why I chose Jamaica but for some
reason I chose Jamaica
maybe geography class I don't know maybe
a cool word to spell and then boom I'm
in so my joystick was a combination lock
it's like dance dance authentication but
different right so right so basically I
could then start that I actually edited
me running Dig Dug on YouTube because it
is a pirated copy of dick duck because
of my parents I don't know what the heck
that's about anyways that was my first
hackathon and eight years old writing
some code and I still have it I'm really
stoked about that
so anyways all right we're gonna go back
to normal stuff now but I you know hey
does anybody have all that what do they
remember their first hack their first
feeling of this how many people still
remember that I know we're old and
they're getting senile but all right
cool how many haven't even done their
first hack yet and they're hearing
they're going okay I got to do it manage
I'm gonna do it I'm a step in there I'm
gonna go I was just gonna get over it
man I'm gonna pop that cherry so no how
many enemy enemy all right Oh people
shut the up
he's still waiting for his first hack
people just don't acknowledge it yet
okay mainstream view 1999-2001
games are over let's stop playing games
guys okay there's your movie
there's your movie alright the
movie messaging of what we were was
basically 1999 2001 we like sneakers the
rest of the world thought of us as these
hackers and they try Sony really did try
to make us look like we're like we're
hacking the system man it's cool man
this is how we talk to hack the planet
all day long that's how we do it and you
know we use the most amazing gooeys you
know they're really just everything we
do do that got off they just you know it
was like wrong and I get it it's hard to
do like good computer interesting stuff
but sneakers did a pretty good job I
honestly like the whole potable rule
everything's unencrypted and guess
what's cool it's the actual crypto scene
and that was written by Rivals so when
he was talking about number field serves
they weren't bullshitting it was kind of
cool so so hackers was our freakin movie
that everybody goes oh you're not gonna
hack my computer are you when you fix my
email
no but that's like saying you know
you're not gonna steal my car when I
hand you my keys of l.a dick
anyways so swordfish remember that one I
think it was 400 and I think it was 412
bit encryption or something that you had
to break with your gun at your head and
I'm like I don't think anybody did the
numbers by 412 there was a 448 that was
one time that was Blowfish okay but 412
good luck I don't know if they were
truncating for a reason but if it is
definitely a symmetric encryption it's
already broken anyway so you just go get
the tool anti-trust another one of those
this is this is the movies that the
mainstream saw and this is what
represented us I wish we were that
good-looking
anyways culture hmm by this time we were
100% feared we were still trying to
figure out if we can get jobs even in
the dot-com bubble right we were you
know we were probably Sisson mins and
stuff kind of secretly gone mad I could
take this place out open but we were
assistant mins but we didn't get the job
he loved we wanted to work in security
we you know some of us may be lucky but
most of us had to figure out let's just
start a boutique you know let's just
start my own thing
let's start a thing torque on right
you know we're feared we must break the
law even if you know we've never broken
the law all of us must break it you know
that whole like 80/20 rule 20% of people
did it and so 80% of it's like that
whole like I'm gonna ban gloves because
you know a few people killed people with
gloves but you know I use it to keep my
hands warm in New York so and then you
know you have like you know obviously
you did have stories of laws broken
Robert Morris all the other stuff was
going on and most of the time I'm gonna
joke about Sammy later don't worry about
it
but you know most of the time it wasn't
like I'm a bad guy it was like literally
oops
my coat is wrong right I mean so
but we got the don't hack me bro don't
hack me bro please don't hack me right
and and we were associated mostly when
we think hackers with viruses you know
because we hacked the Gibson with those
ironic part is later how you getting
most systems is with a driver you know
so so the intercom impact to San Diego
how I looked at it was it was a voice
now it's very different this is
definitely not torque on work so much
better no no but basically this is
definitely not to work on it's like
programs like the big party right this
is like you know this is mostly
representative San Diego but also a lot
of people come around and come here one
for the weather and then to I don't know
if this time the weather but to you know
this is a conference that actually had
streamlined had focus had like things
that we wanted to do and there wasn't
this um let's say like I always try to
say legally leave your ego at the login
prompt I have never been to this
conference feeling like someone had an
ego which was really really nice now I'm
sure we all do I definitely have one
once in a while you know ebbs and flows
things like that like I said security
insecurity but in the general sense you
can go to DEFCON and within two minutes
you're just like oh I do not want
to talk to you so you know and that's
like that's kind of happens here I I
haven't really had that problem and when
I have upset people they're just
straight with me
alright but you could share you could
share it to work on you could you you
there was an inspiration in the air
there was there was things that got me
excited now I'm obviously easily
excitable I'm dramatic I get that I
can't wait til I get old so I can you
know fall and get attention but so
basically you know but uh I stole that
joke but but anyways basically - room
wasn't Def Con or 2600 it wasn't about
if you didn't need validation that's not
what you were trying to do here in that
way you were trying to prove yourself in
this like like messed up you know
mentally ill way of like hey you look at
me and I'm cool and like that it was
more like well you there you go and
we're coming in like at first but then
like we've got some cool things hey do
you want to solder I'll teach you you
know what I still have never sought her
20 years later I'm gonna learn to solder
this weekend I am going to I'm going to
solder
you know this this year actually for me
is like 20 years as an adult in this
industry yes I'm old shut up
no but so I actually went and got I was
in Hawaii I actually saw David and Tim
in Hawaiian and evelle and I ended up
getting myself a tattoo and the tattoo
actually specifically and this is why
this is important to me is is the tattoo
was an inspiration of everybody's like
at this point Oh Lance James you're an
expert editor da which not by even a
closest while but here it says beginner
so today I come back to to work on and I
feel like this impact is still with me I
was listening to the reception last
night and the world around us has
definitely changed in the culture of
hackers and stuff but what I did have
was I still listen and I still learned
last night I still heard and things that
I've never heard before and I and I saw
the same excitement I saw the first time
I got here I saw him being just as cool
as he always has I don't know you know
he's also just looking young just like
he always has but you know we had a good
vibe there's SoCal right
Hikari definitely represents that you
know hey so but it's really about
disruption and innovation i sat on the
floor with I think and Hunter ager back
my first one like learning about VPNs
IPSec I said camp and he let me just
dive into code with him and I I'm
totally insecure about this and not even
sure I can do it or but he didn't
question that he just you know he
believed in me the minute I got there
David believed in the minute I got there
I believed in others the minute they got
there you were accepted your ego was not
here it was like it was there was an ego
boost you felt good you didn't want to
leave that was for sure maybe it was my
marriage I'm not sure no I'm just
kidding no you didn't want to leave you
know but you know and then we got took
on 2001 to 2003 for me I found my
pattern check this out okay so I
attended September 2001 right and this
is for me I'm feeling accepted and
feeling inspired excited it's 2001
September October I started an open
source project now called ITP but back
then called IIP my language of choice at
the time was C so basically I left
torque on excited and wanted to do
something so I could speak at Oracle on
2002 right and literally I just felt
like not just about the speaking but
obviously I just felt really inspired
and left there going okay this is how it
works
we do something cool so now my first
panel was I think utilizing invisibility
and anonymity to protect security was my
first time talking anywhere and yes even
though I'm next to Virtanen seems
natural holy you know that was yeah
anyways um so but basically after that I
did that talk in 2003 after that's that
that that to work on I said I'm gonna do
more I'm gonna start a San Diego
security firm right and every year I
would go this is like this was my spot I
didn't go to DEFCON four actually until
2004 five right this was my thing right
here you know and so when I looked at
what torque on did for me as much as it
seems like I'm confident and extroverted
now there's there's levels of that
there's a lot of stupid things as an
extrovert you can do and stuff and put
your foot in your mouth 100 percent half
the time all the time and so but when I
look at it now and I go and look at the
things that I have been able to do and
have for myself and I look at everybody
else and where they've gone and all
these things I see that tor kind has
offered confidence it made it it said
you know risks are to be taken there
wasn't that fear built into this room it
was make your voice known I'm gonna do a
talk next year right and it got you past
the first one where you humiliate
yourself on purpose which I think
everybody just needs to get past and
then that fear kind of goes away and
you're just like okay well they're not
gonna kill me right you know and I also
said do what you believe in because you
know when I started I a pi2 P thing
Hikari next years like yeah Lance is
doing this really cool thing right and
then I get introduced to other people
that are doing cool things in crypto or
you know and he would Network us all
together Ryan and it built you know a
bigger dev force and it built you know
people I could talk to and learn things
I also remember when I accidentally did
an RM dash RF on akari's box by ones I
don't know why I did that it was
literally an impulsive extroverted
problem it was not passive
aggressiveness I swear to god it was
just me being completely stupid anyways
so there's also mistakes that happened
you know what he goes it's cool it's
cool but it changed the game and one of
the biggest things that taught me was to
give back right met whether it's forward
or not right and so that that's that now
I know that Trump doesn't believe in
climate change but there is some Packer
climate change 1999-2002 security
warnings galore you know we're in that
mode of like guys listen to us and of
course we're not mean listen to yet we
might get a couple of media hits here
and there but a lot everybody's like you
know but we're just tinker's hackers and
what what people are afraid of was us
not the actual like problems we were
talking about that wasn't going to be us
doing them and they didn't get that they
all they saw is should I be suing you
right now we're putting you in jail
because you told me something that I
don't want to listen to and that's what
that's what our climate was at that time
I I would go try to talk to banks and
say here's this going on and I find out
banks they're like ordered do not talk
to Lance you know literally I find this
out many years later don't talk to Lance
he's got some stuff you don't want to
hear about right and I did it in a very
professional way everything like it
wasn't like you know publicized anything
like this but this is this was the
climate back then we don't want to know
about that stuff right and we were
always talking about what could be the
scale and mass hacking attacks things
like that and I'm not talking the stupid
Pearl Harbor crap but just imagine an
onslaught of I don't know people just
hacking into your systems and your
getting preached all year and all these
things are happening and oh my gosh the
OPM and all these things other things
that could happen but you know they
wouldn't or anything 2003 I think
reality sets in emerging I think the
term became cybercrime right we got
targeted foreign attacks not even just
targeted attacks guess who the 8th the
guys who should be feared are not us it
was you know you know hello mr. hacker
I've got some pests in my election can
you help me you know so so basically a
reality set in cybercrime gets cooked
you know like a big hit
you know we've got foreign attacks
there's a thing called phishing that
we've heard about since at least 1996 or
more but you know suddenly this is like
now a thing that someone's got to write
a book on and tell the rest of the
people of the world about right so we
got malware malicious software what we
used to call viruses but now we've got
targeted malware it's not like it just
came on the scene it's just now
everybody knew about it so we had kind
of this whole big I told you freaking so
moment but we didn't get to ever say
yet so so we set the stage now it's good
versus evil because everybody's got to
have a bad guy right you know hackers
need to you know fight the wars for
everybody else right so we got you know
we suddenly have jobs for hacker
communities mostly blue team stuff but
it's a start right we got you know the
invention of you know this reactivity
causes this explosive industry growth
that starts hitting from 2003 in a
belong the invention of what's called
threat intelligence right and we have
all of this stuff and we have these
disruptive effects because of this
explosion such as things like tor and
free net we're already kind of moving
but now it's like privacy and anonymity
is even a bigger issue right and these
things kind of continue ahead so what we
termed as hacktivism back then was
someone like me I actually wrote
software for privacy reasons now we it's
a bunch of dicks with computers that
DDoS people because they want to play a
video game or not play a video game I
don't know and then we know the cool
thing is that I to Pete or all those
things they started getting government
interest you know as much as AFF
interest fna so you know when we look at
that you know peer-to-peer was a kind of
a thing it was starting to really kind
of kick out now obviously we look at it
today and so but you know we also had
the file-sharing Wars at that time that
was a fun one right anybody ever get
like a letter I got a letter twice
there's three times I think it was what
movie was a secret window that one was
one you know how I got out of that
though yeah I run a security firm and I
have a honey net set up at my house and
we didn't know that distribution was on
sorry cool all right thanks bye-bye
all right don't you can only do that
move once though just say it just saying
I learned real quick so we had DRM which
was basically fear versus innovation and
of course I think we all know the basic
gist of the story is Apple iTunes kind
of changed the game and made the vehicle
if you want to get into detail or debate
of who did that really but basically you
know we went through all of these things
right so and that we have these things
called a PTI or advanced persistent
marketing I mean advanced persistent
threat it's a human oriented targeting
concept aka it spies learned how to use
computers right and it's a shift in
thinking it's this
like look at us as castles and guess
what's happened is the invention of
gunpowder just came out and all our
castles are falling right
and so hackers and intelligence
community suddenly become closer yes I
became friends with some of the FBI guys
cuz they just were helpless and I felt
bad I actually did I was like I could
make money here okay you could you could
you can you can all help you so and our
new competition arrives a lot of people
want to call them adversaries I called
them competition right one the reason
why I also wanted to help wasn't really
just about the money it was like oh hell
no you're not gonna make it out like all
hackers are bad guys we are not gonna
give them a bad name I am gonna go after
these son of a bitches right now so
basically here is the new business that
gets on the market which is no different
than a structure of normal business
because what it is this is a full-on
operation malware operation swift
operation any of those heists that you
see this is that system this is crime
where as a service you know so we got
this new shift 2003 to now how did it
get so exponential well forums right and
then you've got like some kingpin or
Enterprise guy that doesn't even know
how to code and he goes you know I got a
really cool idea let's rob some banks
right let's do American ones cuz you
know we don't like them because you know
hey cold war and all so then basically
what happens they'll recruit developers
within a forum they'll develop that
they'll produce a product for the
enterprise do recruiter there and then
realize I don't have an NDA I think I'll
just switch my handle I'm gonna make a
new product and taught and then that
person basically goes in the same cycle
makes a product for himself becomes an
enterprise gets rich and then pays other
people to do the same thing and this
whole thing has become an exponential
problem the division of labour lowers
and basically it's not even like the
skills we have it's that these tools are
just out there now right and I think we
all know that and it's like it really
makes a bad name for us right so and so
now suddenly the defense isn't firewalls
it's different it's information sharing
right now we've talked about there's
more like information sharing what are
you talking about right but now the view
has been that because we have this new
unorthodox community that's formed which
includes industry hackers law
enforcement and intelligence communities
we're starting to learn this new
tradecraft about information sharing so
when I was in 2000
three I would talk to ISPs and say you
got some can I get your hard drive
I'll give you a free report and I would
learn about phishing and these Russians
and all these cool fun takes and
literally was about this whole like
communication of like this because
criminals they share this information we
don't have any days to protect you know
they just do it and so we were like
exponentially just going okay this is
gonna have to be a thing we're gonna
have to share information which is still
by the way a very difficult problem for
some reason even though we're here to
work on and always share information
this thing all right so we were kind of
used to that so now it's like InfoSec
and this is how it goes it meets the
tradecraft of intelligence right and
then we get this whole thing where it's
like now we have to like learn these
things by the way if half the time we're
faking we're just like right let me go
look that stuff up real quick okay I was
kind of gonna just do some exploits but
fine I'll learn about the CIA model and
the Lockheed chanter cut you know all
this stuff so basically the whole thing
now is InfoSec defense is we have to
learn their adversaries their
operational framework it goes back to
the human again it's not bits and bytes
people aren't gonna actually be chasing
that we can patch all day everything
like that obviously we know that right
and so now it's all these like let's
find some predictive insights and
detection and so we have this mix now
and guess what Kate even Soros I think
nailed it but you know wargames
was a neat thing because you know when
we looked at that that's what caused
Regan to actually react and create the
anti fraud and abuse Act Title 18 1030
so that you know we can be afraid now
then today we've got articles such as
not all hackers are evil by Katie my
source which is awesome by the way she's
awesome by the way she changed the game
by making us friendly by building bug
bounty concepts so that we'd have asked
grow systems to get along you remember
when the companies would just furious if
we are you got a vulnerability sorry
you're under arrest sir right did happen
to me once right okay and so basically
and and she changed that and built this
escrow concept of saying here's
cooperative game theory we're gonna make
it so that you get the problem that you
once solve and your risks are lowered
and the hackers will stay away from you
but they'll also hack you it's gonna be
great and it is and that's what's really
really cool is it took some creativity
to for us to adapt in this new world
this is where everybody's still afraid
you know our job is to hunt hackers
fight your wars for you you know things
like that
you know get those Russians out of
people's elections you know stuff like
that like that's our job these days
right to hunt Packers so we have to hunt
other hackers good news you're all here
just kidding that was easy and then
there's this thing called attribution
and so people have gotten used to we're
used to ip's hashes jaws or you know
domains things like this and then
there's this new art form that then we
have to suddenly go this is what we're
looking for motivation objective
timeliness resources risk tolerance so
we now have to study and learn human
psychology all these other things that
go with our play which I think we
already knew that psychology was a big
play into security anyways but this is
that but yet you we don't really call it
that this is our target but what they
call attribution is like North
korea-china you know when it at first
you don't succeed just blame China that
kind of thing right so I stole that joke
- that's my curtain but basically you
know what happened what was different
what's going on here so yesterday's
youth we had how many people had a 300
baud I don't know if we wow you guys are
really old cool so okay how about a 14-4
who started up 14 fours
all right 1200 anybody starting on a
1200 all right we have 500 we have about
43 633 6 everybody
all right so 33 6 I started I think on a
1200 at one point and then I got over 2
because I didn't have a modem on my
Apple 2e bastards but you know hey
but anyways remember when we had to wait
for every little bit and byte and every
bit was cherished literally like okay
I'm waiting for this BBS to start you
know we don't have that anymore right
there's this long game incentive we're
like crap we have a we have to write
code to get this thing to work you know
I wrote code just to dial on my modem
right like it's like you really
and then today tomorrow's youth you know
access is what it is in a good way right
except that there's a lot of not
understanding they think Ruby's a good
idea so you know and then there's the
barrier to entry to anyone which would
you love for instance there's a lot more
women here and I really thankful and
happy of the diversity here and that is
awesome because it wasn't like we were
pushing anybody out I was just you know
we were just kind of a bunch of dudes
like trying to figure stuff out but
we're seeing those barriers to entry
everybody has access to the same
information even if you're almost broke
you can get a smartphone for 20 bucks
and get on the internet learn some stuff
right and you can so there's not this
this the depletion of class systems
anymore to succeed in that way it is
kind of causing an equilibrium is also
probably causing what all the weird
shitty or come our world is today but so
what you know take out the middleman see
how it goes
and but but we're driven by short-term
driven incentives when you see a hacker
today it's about internet fame and in
ego and if I can you know SWAT you or
you know DDoS you and I'm cool and you
really just don't appreciate you know I
dare you to write that code anyways so
we got security media then and now back
then torque on one was needed no one was
listening when hackers yelled you know
we're kinda like a movement but didn't
know it yet grey hat approach look what
I found
you're stupid you're vulnerable how many
people know this one I did this I had a
whole Twitter thing of this yeah yeah
look at you you're dumb ah you know and
I'm slightly famous for it and that's a
reality for us is we got our ego trip we
found our vulnerability we tried to let
him know because we felt like they
weren't listening and it was true that
was kind of the vibe and then today you
know the media shifts there's a PT one
report comes out and makes a billion
dollars you know they swear it was for
the good of the country but you know
then cyber goes mainstream you know
right you know that was originally a
design firm refers to sex right hey you
want a cyber right so ASL baby you know
and then the security research and
marketing find they become friends
sometimes you're like I think I sold my
soul to marketing right how many people
feel like that sometimes we definitely
do it we're like I think I sold my soul
to marketing but but we did find a home
together they know how to push what
we're doing in our security research
which is powerful because that's their
area they it's PR for us but it actually
has helped I don't agree with the ap2
one report in the sense of like the
approach because that was like boom
crash and you know whatever but it
shifted for us and in a way it's kind of
like alright now we all have jobs we all
have ways to do this heck you can't hire
enough security people there's a gap now
because of the fact that not enough
people know what we know and then we
look at the evolution of target
attacks which is basically I started and
I was wrong in my first book I wrote a
phishing exposed book and I was like mr.
phishing guy expert dude and I was wrong
I was like I Allura didn't think
spearfishing was gonna be a big deal and
so I look back and I'm like okay don't
read that line so uh but basically you
know we go from serial campaigns which
is like you know you guys remember the
PayPal the ones that just come in your
box all the time in the back the Bank of
America
I swear I'm I'm swear of Bank of America
I swear it just login go ahead right and
so they would hit all the customers in
serial mass which is tiring even if you
have to just press buttons to do it but
like it's tiring your finger gets tired
and you're just like okay I gotta do
this in two weeks and run another
campaign no do that but what change was
then they also realize wait we can hop
over the fence and we'll just target
inside the targets of the world
literally target target that's a hard
one
and we get target we get all that and
everything changed how many people have
a chip now in your wallet with all the
the thing right almost every single
person who doesn't have a chip in here
get the no so thank you crabs for
putting that out there I know that you
know basically but basically the target
hack kind of changed the game and find
us finally got us caught up with the UK
and have a chip even though they've been
doing it for almost 10 15 years so
basically organized crime in all of this
stuff when we heard about like back then
I could actually track organized crime I
could tell the difference between a
nation-state I could do that now I can't
write nation states always did the
precise hit them on the other side
that's why I was like spearfishing ain't
gonna be a big thing it's gonna be a few
people it's gonna be governments and
they're gonna do their thing and you're
not gonna hear about it well obviously
we did but you know an advanced
persistent marketing threat is you know
any of these things today right so you
can't tell really the difference they're
all using the same tools right so the
evolution is different now and we've
gone from back orifice let me please
tell me you remember that one how many
people like mess with people like did
the whole like Darth Vader Plus cd-rom
opening at the same time thing where
it's like and it's like every time it
goes out the sounds making a Darth Vader
thing I really want I love doing that to
people just scan the internet and is do
you know it was just like you know it
was great
so from back office everybody you know
you you have to admit some of us you
scan and you just mess with people's
computers come on come on we all did it
you know it's almost impossible not to
so Bo comes out right scares the crap
out of people greatest name in the world
is Cal to the dead cow right and now we
have basically DVRs it's like it's like
we have Mirai you guys took Kenny to you
at the seminars yesterday sir up ting
Mirai things like that okay so we are
gonna I'm gonna brag flashpoint was the
one who got the name and figured out who
that was but it was really not even
flash my name is Allison Dixon she's
kind of awesome so but you know I
remember the news and it was like
everybody's like is it Russia is it
China all right I'm like it's not China
I know and so it was like that it was
basically it's not Russia hold on that's
right hold on
teenagers with your TV in Vietnam mostly
basically but basically it's a bunch of
2004 DVRs that have gonna love this
telnet telling it's open its defaults
and if you actually even reboot the
router after you've changed the password
guess what happens it goes back to
default and you're sitting there going
fix this but apparently now we have
problems like we think about like recall
issues or like oh well what if a
manufacturer just decides to do it their
own way and now we have to worry about
those problems but isn't it funny that
you know we can talk about 1999 tour
com1 let me talk about today and this
vulnerability would have been foolish
it's this is a torque on one
vulnerability people so the only thing
is is that the Internet is a lot more
has more targets so we're literally half
the Internet when I say that it really
means just half your TV shows that you
wanted to watch when offline you know so
basically this is that's what happened
it's basically telnet scan the world of
telnet machines infect them drop
something in there until it reboots and
basically you can DDoS the world and we
thought it was Russia and it's teenagers
with like super super you know like
high-speed DDoS which is kind of cool
and the reason they did it was they were
upset about a video game seriously they
were trying to target a video game
company it didn't work so they went
after freaking the the we got the DNS
provider boom whoops
right and I'm sure it was a whoops
so so testing one two three
microphone is now on we're here night to
work on 19 right and I'm probably gonna
go over by like two minutes but don't
hate me so
but microphone it's your fault anyways
you guys really know hackers are now
Hollywood man mr. robot all that fun
stuff I've gotten to be on the news a
lot it's like cool and I don't feel
afraid I mean they still get the jokes
like we're just gonna call you the brain
on blah blah blah I'm saying alright
don't hack my computer right you know
that kind of stuff I love I love I still
get those I'm you know certainly trying
to do talks on like hey you know stop
saying that it's really annoying the
question is are we responsible now that
the microphone is on this is a son you
know we still do a lot of stunt work you
know I hacked your car phone TV and I
think that's fine I'm not saying I'm
judging anybody or anything like Charlie
Miller is actually really talented dude
that is awesome to know about but doing
that you know I I mentor a lot of kids
now and they're like dude I just like
got it where I played the speaker on
someone's hotel room next door cool do
you know how to fix that would you know
how to actually fix that if you were the
hotel manager and the CEO of the company
and you know no right right so so it's
cold we can do all those stunt works
there's tools there's things like that
but the question is is it solving
problems are we actually solving the
solutions in a long road we can point
out the vulnerabilities that's fine I
think we got that that that clue real
quick it we're vulnerable now we don't
need anybody tell us that OPM target JP
Morgan I mean I think everybody's got
that now we're like from the castles you
know the gunpowder days and now we're
trying to go okay it's gonna be painful
for us adjusting to all this gunpowder
right and it's wearing that painful time
we're in that painful time there's also
issues with ethical disclosure I just
remember the concept of ethical
disclosure right you know 30 days 60
days 90 days and it was like big topics
but most people at least adhere to 30
days you know and and and now companies
don't adhere to that they just want to
get the content out because it's King
it's money it's bacon data is bacon you
know new bacon you know and and then
that's a thingummy content truly is
currency today and for sneakers
information is it's all about the
information while though he wasn't lying
you know and we see these secured by
marketing approaches you know thanks I'm
I really love that padlock thanks I made
it out of clay
um you know seen a few of those and then
politics in hacking dice roll dice
function rule basically political
attribution North Korea and we want a
rush to it like you know we know that
North Korea hacked Sony even though 23
people in the last two years hacked Sony
and just like the village bicycle and
everybody gets a ride on Sony but like
my point is is how do you actually even
know which hacker was what to what and
you ever would have false flag concepts
like you know you can suppose me the
military deciding this right so it's
really really funny because it's now
just become this political tool I'm
literally watching a debate between who
hacks Swift on two different regions on
different sides of the west coast
between two different agencies I'm like
they're literally fighting over like
this person and I'm like I've watched
this and I'm just like okay this is all
politics it's all pressure this is just
reactive pressure you know and
attribution to me is not a country it's
a person you know hey who actually put
their fingers on that keyboard right so
so these are our things are we are we
being responsible are we keeping you
know what are we gonna do about those
pesky Russians last but not least mainly
because I promise Jeremiah Grossman I
would get him back by putting him in a
in a in a talk of mine and so this is
also stolen from my current this is
awesome
Romney how many people watch mister
robot how many gay people liked it keep
your hands up if you did more people
liked it then watched it great anyways
so I just thought this was funny
Robbie acts like a hacker you know it
was actually he's pretty good accurate
except for the first scene on the tour
exit nodes where he's like you know
you're running a child porn thing on
this like you know on the tour but he's
actually not and you can't run your own
service and go through Exeter notes it
doesn't work that way but you know I'm
not gonna correct you guys but like it's
fun but you know and this is Jeremiah
Grossman we do think there's a slight
resemblance but you know more smiles
from him you know but this show has also
played a big influence but I think
what's more important is the special
thanks goes out to torque on because we
talk about influence and for me too
you know I want to just put out a big
thanks Dave Tim geo carlos matrix DJing
tonight that was new to me actually
beetle you know I love you bro uh
Riverside Sammy you're still my hero
still still still my hero I uh I watch
his work he's the cool cat and the crew
he's like the cool guy he's always
pushing that uh his mom she's literally
been here from the first hour please
stand up actually you know what she's
been oh you got to do it come on come on
she is literally supported as a mom
that's a mom right there right okay and
so many others and you guys you guys
make this obviously happen I just wanted
to thank though you guys for to work on
especially for it's a start for many
including the new people it's an
inspiration to Lil I think all of us in
anyways we always try to see what we can
come back with next year it's a safe
community but I really just wanted to
thank you for offering your home and
that's I think what it is for all of us
is a home and that's my speech I don't
think I have to ask four questions which
is kind of cool so thank you so much
appreciate it