all right welcome to our next talk we've
actually got a presentation here in
attacking medical devices by a presenter
that's soul eat he actually has it in
his name
please welcome rob privily to the torque
on stage so yeah talk is on attacking
medical devices my name is Robert Lee
I'm the director of red team services at
silence prior to that I was met secondly
I found stone yada yada favorite things
include breaking embedded systems did
some wireless research and of course red
teaming so we do a fair amount of
medical device assessments for both
providers that being you know hospitals
etc and for medical device vendors so I
figured this would be a good topic for a
talk as you know we've we've done some
interesting testing and we've found you
know a number of interesting
vulnerabilities over time a lot of stuff
I guess what you could consider a
systemic right and we'll talk about
those later in the talk but I figured it
would be good to do a talk on this to
kind of you know get it out there that
you know there's a lot of issues with
medical devices as there are with all
embedded systems or either most embedded
systems and you know kind of get some of
the techniques out there that we've been
using to assess these so that other
folks you know either if you work for a
provider or a vendor or you're just
doing this on your own time that can
kind of move the ball forward everybody
hear me all right cool all right I've
never been accused of being too quiet um
so anyway we're gonna do it you know
quick intro to medical devices talk a
little bit about some of the tools that
you can use for assessing them then
we'll talk about some attack techniques
that we use how we basically conduct an
assessment some of the vulnerabilities
that we've found and you know some
recommendations for you know for fixing
that right all right so you know one of
the interesting things about medical
devices is that they take so many
different forms
you know what you consider can consider
as a medical device most people might
just think of an embedded system but it
is those and it could be everything up
to everything from you know what we have
there like a an implanted cardioverter
right small embedded device probably
uses an RTOS or similar or a medical
telemetry device it's a wearable it
transmits wirelessly right also
generally like an RTS a small embedded
device but then you have you know large
devices like mobile x-ray systems that
would use a full-featured Linux OS
sometimes a custom Linux OS developed by
the by the vendor all the way up to
basically what you'd consider just a
Windows PC or some sort of Windows PC on
a cart that you generally see with like
exercise or stress testing systems right
also considered medical devices are
things like web applications those as
well as developed by by vendors right so
it means many different things and they
take many different forms and also
communicate in many different ways so we
have a lot of different interfaces right
and this is you know just a change from
a number of years ago where you know
most like for instance infusion pumps
would just have like rs-232 serial right
and I just looked at a bunch recently
that were devices you know in existence
already that I've been out for a while
and you know that's primarily what you
saw was you know rs-232 serial
interfaces if anything right so there's
not a ton of internal external attack
service there but over the last number
of years that's branched out
significantly and this is mostly due to
a demand for functionality right and as
as functionality increases so does
attack surface right so you have you
know Ethernet Wi-Fi Bluetooth and
bluetooth LE different kinds of cellular
RFID and in terms of magnetic induction
and of course you know ZigBee USB
obviously and also wireless usb we've
seen and then of course there is all the
proprietary stuff proprietary wireless
protocols and implementations are very
common
in various medical devices such as
implant the balls wearables or body worn
devices and also patient telemetry
devices we'll talk a little bit about
that so kind of the challenge there one
of the the fun parts about it though is
that there's so many different types of
interfaces and protocols technologies in
use that the you know the attack
techniques are so varied right you get
to do a lot of different stuff on one
engagement but it also makes it
challenging so medical device
connectivity real quick these are two of
the more common protocols that you run
into
hl7 is very common it's a standard for
communicating between disparate and
varied medical systems the most common
versions of that you'll probably
encounter are V 2 and V 3 V 2 is very
very recognizable when you see it all
the fields are delimited with different
like pipes or carrots at various symbols
when you see it it's very recognizable
v3 is more XML based both do not have
built-in encryption where it's can it's
I guess you could say incumbent around
you to secure in some other fashion as a
vendor right like wrapping it in TLS or
some other protective tunnel DICOM is a
standard for storing transmitting and
storing medical images generally between
like some kind of imaging device and
Capac server or PACs database it does
have built-in encryption and other
security measures however you don't see
them implemented as much as you would
hope and we'll talk a little bit about
that later as well okay so medical bands
as defined by the FCC two main ones here
we have double UMTS or Wireless medical
telemetry service right that is for
devices telemetry devices worn on the
body by a patient that would transmit
vitals data wirelessly and that is in
two main bands there the
of the vc3 the the second of the two are
considered what we you consider the 1.4
gigahertz band the the other is mid
radio and the first their mid radio is
for body-worn devices but also
implantables the the two below that are
what you call purpose specific bands the
medical body area networks is for
implantable devices only and the mm ends
or medical micro power networks are
actually for wireless devices used for
bringing mobility or helping to bring
mobility to paralyzed limbs and that's
its specific purpose those specific
bands these are defined by the FCC has
carved out airwaves space but the
protocols there are no standard for
protocols to be used in them that is
vendor specific and you see all kinds of
different proprietary implementations in
terms of protocols alright it's a little
bit about tool sets so on the network
side I recommend a good portable switch
with a span port that do will come
switch is about $170 it's a little
pricey for a portable switch but I've
had really good luck with it I'd never
give me any problems this is really
useful for when you want to monitor
Ethernet communication between two
systems you know a patient monitor or
infusion pump and the system is sending
and receiving data from so very useful
their software-defined radio so as I
just mentioned right you have these
defined you know W MTS and med radio
bands but your protocol communications
in there could be anything defender
defines and you see all kinds of
interesting stuff in there so in that
case your your best bet is to use SDR I
use the US RP be 200 and that it's very
effective for that also if you have to
deal with for instance GSM that's useful
as well if you're going to use it with
GSM you also need a GPS do clock dough
clock tamer chip which is about
additional $600 or so
because of gsm s clock sensitivity but I
digress
wellgood wireless card I use the AWS 51
NH you know whatever you like as long as
it can do monitor mode and injection
golden the ABR Raven says for ZigBee so
if you encounter or assessing a device
that utilizes ZigBee I recommend these
devices they work best with the killer
II framework I would recommend to one
for doing injection and then the other
for monitoring while you're doing
injection and those sort of attacks
they're cheap the only bummer about them
is you're gonna have to flash the
firmware onto them there's a couple
different techniques for doing that the
cheapest one is to use an atmel AVR
dragon which is like 40 bucks and a few
different adapters step up and step down
adapters to make it work but that's like
the cheapest route to go so you don't
have to buy like one hundred and seventy
dollar programmer uber tooth one for
Bluetooth Bluetooth le awesome passive
monitoring best tool for that and
definitely essential for doing any kind
of Bluetooth work and then I recommend a
good class one Bluetooth adapter class
one's the strongest Bluetooth adapter
class it's usually on paper good 400 I
believe 100 yards in practice maybe not
quite that but you know you want a
powerful adapter I recommend the Cena
Pirani I've been using that for years
the latest revision of it sports both
Bluetooth and bluetooth LE so that would
be what I would go with again your
mileage may vary hardware so on the
hardware side of assessment is obviously
we're gonna be end up spending the most
money or having the most devices
Hardware tends to multiply devices like
rabbits some sort of all-purpose bus and
a debug interface device I like to check
run you are the bus pirate is also good
but I found the rare to be a bit better
just do JTAG spi uart may i2c a
universal IC programmer is great only
because the number of chips that they
support if you're trying to dump the
firmware or contents of a flash chip you
don't have to mess around
with with different tooling you know
this thing does like the the Zeltiq the
super Pro is 610 does like 30,000
different kinds of chips it's like 600
bucks so it's expensive relatively
speaking but it gets the job done a
logic analyzer the Salley a stuff is
great the logic 16 I recommend because
it's very fast and as a big buffer space
for doing captures off of you know as
like spi and etc you could probably get
away with the logic for the logic eight
which are cheaper not quite as fast the
powerful is full-featured but they get
that you know all their all their stuff
is actually really good
I also recommend some kind of dedicated
or professional JTAG or in this serial
wire debug a probe like a Segar only
because again you know when you're doing
hardware stuff and things are not
working you would like to have something
that you know is is definitely you know
is rock-solid so you're not doing so
much guesswork you can get the student
version of this for about sixty bucks
it's definitely good to have on hand
jtagulator good for one purpose only and
it's awesome at that and that is pinning
out JTAG and UART and a high rate of
speed it does an awesome job for that so
if you're trying to pin out your JTAG or
you out ports when you're doing a
hardware assessment awesome for that
particularly good when for instance you
can't do it with a multimeter because
the chips in question are a ball grid
array or what have you
you can't real steep pitch pins you
can't reach it a good multimeter
invaluable for pinning stuff out if
you're like me and your eyes are crap a
good bench magnifier or USB microscope
at least a bench magnifier so that you
can see the hardware that you're working
on you can read chip markings you can
look at pins and look stuff up without
guessing at it or messing things up
particularly also really invaluable if
you're like me and you have fat fingers
soldering station is awesome for you
know attaching headers and other stuff
in the medical device space of your
assessing for providers they may not
want you soldering stuff on to it you
know em making hardware modifications is
somewhat frowned upon for vendors less
because they have stuff in the lab so
they don't really care so much
but the hakko stuff is always awesome
and that one I believe is like under
$100 and then various jumper wires
resistor step up step down resistor kits
headers test clips and this stuff will
multiply on you really quickly okay so
assessing and attacking I was looking at
the time a little bit alright so some
testing considerations real quick if
you're assessing for a provider not
being a hospital right the device should
be a test test device in a lab a
dedicated test device it should not go
back into you should never test number
one in production number two it should
never go back into production after it's
been tested on because you've done all
kinds of horrible stuff to it nobody you
should you know it it's a safety
critical system it should not be used
relied upon for you know patient safety
after what you've Haribo things you've
done to it the device when you're
testing it should be configured for
normal operation that being that it has
all its supporting systems Mapei tient
vitals generator or some other demo to
to basically generate normal traffic and
operation between the device and its
supporting systems if you're assessing
for a provider right they have SMEs that
can help you with this stuff you know
make sure everything's set up and
working as it should be right because
assessing a device in a vacuum won't get
you interesting things assessing a
device communicating as normal with the
rest of its ecosystem right and it's
supporting systems will and that's where
you're going you're gonna you're gonna
affect value you're gonna get you're
gonna get cool stuff of course all the
supporting systems should be in scope
we'll talk about that in a minute and
the main focus of your testing should be
will be two things number one anything
that impacts patient safety okay
anything that will affect the the safety
of the patient or the integrity of the
data being transferred as it relates to
the patient's safety
or the the availability of the device as
it you know applies to the patient
safety and then of course anything that
exposes pH I or PII because there's
going to be a big concern for any
providers under HIPPA right so the
confidentiality of the patient data as
it's stored or transferred by the device
is of course going to be a big concern
and those would be in that order patient
safety first pH IPA I second and then
anything else would be tertiary so kind
of a really bad tree here cuz I'm no
good at creating these things of like
the attack surfaces how we look at it
right look at the device attack surface
okay they will look at the hardware
attacks as part of that so that would be
the internal device surface right so
external device surface all interfaces
all ports protocols services or any
other way that you're going to be able
to get data into the device in some
fashion data that you control Hardware
attacks that being internal stuff debug
interface is the ability to dump
chipsets through like SBI alright you
see or anything like that
protocol reverse engineering split into
two parts wireless stuff and wired
alright it's a wireless protocols and
wired protocols all supporting systems
this could be vendor-supplied servers
workstations monitoring systems
vendor-supplied
applications both thick apps binaries
right etc and web applications or api is
or web services right any of that stuff
so those would come off as part of
supporting systems so basically you know
any supporting systems or applications
supplied by the vendor as well you know
again this is one big ecosystem and
generally when vendors provide devices
often in the case of let's just say
patient monitoring right
they provide almost the whole ecosystem
there'll be the patient monitors a
central monitoring workstation a
back-end database and some kind of
gateway there they're actually maybe it
should be a firewall included in that to
segment it from the provider network and
there's a reason for that because
anything that hits these devices knocks
them over and then probably also like
some sort of double UMTS or Wireless
medical telemetry
with its wireless APs and everything
feeding back into that so the whole
thing is like one ecosystem and it you
know overseer to really test the whole
thing as such because that's what the
attacker will do so okay device
discovery right first thing you want to
do is take a look at the model number of
the device look up everything you can on
it pull down all the service
documentation there's a couple different
sites like med wrench and Frank's
Hospital workshop that are centered
around medical device repair and they
store all kinds of data sheets and info
good place to go for that stuff all
right so you want to find everything you
can there every device that's that is
sold in the US that has any kind of
wireless communication will have an FCC
ID on it it'll be a sticker on the
device take that number go to FCC ID dot
IO I believe it is the f-statistic
Google FCC ID lookup and what you can do
is you can look at up there it's a the
first three to five characters will be
the grantee code and the rest will be
the product code so the grantee code is
actually the vendor every device if you
just search that every device they've
ever made will come up if you put in the
grantee code as well or the product code
it will show that device only what
you're looking for there is when you
have a device tested by the by the FCC
which you must write they have a bunch
of documentation that will tell you the
frequencies the device transmits on the
nature of the transmissions you get
stuff like internal photos of the device
external photos which are useful if you
want to learn more about the device but
you're not allowed to take it apart
manuals other kind of mundane stuff but
if you're fortunate and they didn't make
a request for kind of confidentiality
the FCC you'll get stuff like block
diagrams of the circuitry schematics and
then really good stuff like operating
description descriptions which is
basically their engineering Docs so
you'll get really good stuff there if
they were not careful if you don't see
it for the most current device go back a
little ways and see if they dropped it
for something previously before they got
smart and then never had it removed cuz
you've seen that before to determine any
proprietary protocols that it's
utilizing and search for that stuff
look you know the vendor
probably won't have a lot of dock on it
but if you go to like Google patents
there may be a fair bit of info about it
there if they filed a patent on it and
you may be able to find info elsewhere
the other thing you can do is go out and
look for parsing tools that have already
been written that are out on github or
elsewhere that the medical community has
medical device community has already
created right so don't reinvent the
wheel
so let's see what else obviously look
for any prior vulns any prior work
security work that's been done around
the device right enumerate all the
device interfaces and then look for
external debug interface on the debug
functionality on the device some devices
all devices gently of a service mode and
you can find those hard-coded
credentials in the service manage
manuals but some will also have like
actual debug functionality like I've saw
a patient monitor once that would
actually not only give you debug output
on the monitor but it would also also
give you stack dump snack traces memory
dumps all kinds of really cool stuff so
get an idea of what you can do what you
have to work with there and again hard
by the way hard core differentials
everywhere everywhere everywhere and
medical devices and you can find them
exceptionally easy what you one time was
kind of funny we we went and reversed
the binary to get some hard-coded creds
and then we realized it was in the
manual on Frank's Hospital workshop
oopsy yeah I was gonna dumb couldn't
even write that up in the report is like
us being cool because it was like it's
in the manual you know dummy
okay so supporting systems I'm just
gonna gave you guys the spiel on this
right it don't often come with with
medical Venice applied servers and if
not they'll be vendor-supplied
applications both a thick and thin right
look through first go in that directory
look through the config files there'll
be a wealth of all kinds of interesting
stuff in there sometimes just plain text
creds or encrypted creds where the key
is stored in the binary the binary is
more often than not or dotnet you find a
lot of dotnet stuff so if you just use
something like DN spy DN spy which is my
you can decompile them real quick and
it's real easy to look through so I mean
you know done all this stuff like
database database connection strings all
kinds of interesting stuff and once you
go through the config files any ini
files CFG text anything txt go through
it then look at the binaries if they're
dotnet take them apart immediately
search for the same thing look for
anything that says you know key cert
password username you know you look you
will find you will find lots of you'll
find more than you could imagine the
other thing that's useful about
reversing the server-side binaries is
it's generally less resource intensive
than pulling apart firmware especially
if it's not net stuff so if you're gonna
be doing any proprietary protocol
reversing right much easier to pull it
apart on that side and way faster right
you know generally we only have like a
week a week or two to do one of these
devices like a couple weeks if it's
hardware so you know time is important
in the in the in the scope of the
engagement right so you want to take the
path that you know that yields the most
in the least amount of time yeah all
right so a protocol reversing I guess
there's every vendor in in medical
device world seems to have their own
proprietary protocol that they like to
use there are as I said parsers for a
number of them up on github or elsewhere
so you will find a fair bit of parsers
or partial parsers that you might have
to add so you'll have some stuff you
might have to add to it as you go it may
you know decode certain kinds of packets
but not others
right but anyway it's a starting point
right there often udp-based you see this
a lot in patient monitors right so
they're gonna be unencrypted their UDP
base their streaming protocols they're
real easy to to to pull apart right and
it makes for a lot of like
man-in-the-middle attacks replay attacks
things of that nature it also makes it
pretty easy to identify any pH I or PII
being sent across them so the other
thing that we'll talk about a minute is
really crappy a roll your own encryption
being used in that as well and devices
identifying each other through like UDP
broadcasts with no mutes you don't see
anything in the way of like mutual
authentication between devices so anyone
saying right
okay so wireless protocols right why
it's a little bit more difficult the
first thing to do is go through the FCC
ID lookup process that I was talking
about right
find out what frequency it's utilizing
you can get an idea of what it is more
or less there and then another helpful
thing to do if you can take the device
device apart take a look at the wireless
chipset figure out what that look at the
markings download the data sheets look
through that if you can pull the
firmware pull that that'll be helpful as
well in ascertaining exactly what it is
that they're doing if it's easier to
pull the firmware from what it's
communicating with like if it's a
telemetry device it's gonna communicate
with a wireless telemetry ap it might be
easier or like well the device might not
have a JTAG interface the AP might right
so check out both and what you have
there easy easier which one of the of
them is easier to pull apart because
they're both gonna use the same thing to
communicate pull that one apart save
yourself time in terms of the actual
capture identify the frequency use a
u.s. RP with like GQ rx 2 to ascertain
where it is transmitting if you control
the input on the device which you should
generate some transmission input so that
you can identify and I you can take a
look at how it is transmitting you can
use a tool like Azam comm FFT to take a
capture of it once you've captured it
you can use this tool Clemente spectrum
that's really awesome for this that
allows you to do a graphical analysis of
the the captured signal and by doing so
you can identify like what kind of
keying is it using what kind of
modulation rather you know is it
amplitude shift keying frequency shift
keying on/off keying right that should
be pretty visually obvious due to their
distinctions and then the the hard part
is using something like a new canoe
radio companion which is a fairly steep
learning curve too
demodulate decode and bring the bring it
back to binary that we can work with
right there's a new tool out there
relatively new tool that I haven't had a
chance to use yet but I actually looks
really cool for this it's called a
universal radio hacker which seems to me
look - look it's aim is to make a lot of
this affair a bit easier so I'm actually
looking forward to trying that on an
engagement but this is a fairly you know
this is a very fun but time-consuming
process
unless you're like Michael Osman then it
takes two seconds so hardware discovery
carefully opened the device look for any
kind of tamper prevention stuff or
tamper detection
I don't really run into anything very
exotic largely just Springs different
kinds of shields that are attached to
the case that if it's broke the
connection is broken the device won't
function those are really easy to bypass
you can just short between the two
or you can suppress the spring or in one
case we found that it was a it wasn't a
medical device is a cheaper device
because I think our medical device
clients would have been happy about this
one but the shield didn't cover all of
the case in fact right over the flash
chip I was trying to dump was no shield
so I took a dremel and just cut a hole
in it but again you know medical device
is a little more expensive they don't
like when you do that kind of thing use
the bench magnifier or your eye or your
phone camera works good for this stuff
to figure out look at the the chip
markings write them down right down the
markings and look up all the the chip
the data sheets for each chips
particularly like the microcontroller
the wireless sock or chip set any flash
chips SPI flash nor NAND flash whatever
any kind of memory chip you want that as
well those are the most important areas
of it look at those data sheets and then
see what they support do they support
what kind of bus protocols they support
SPI I to see does the microcontroller
support different kind of debug
interfaces JTAG you our background debug
mode serial wire debug right and then
look at the board and look for debug
interfaces
right so look for any kind of again JTAG
you are etc any test points any any pins
headers that are already in place
pads etc right so that's what we want to
look for this is just some of the stuff
that you get out of out of data sheets
right the one on the left I think is a
free scale the one in the middle there
is at mal MCU and you can just see there
the different JTAG pins TMS CIT do and
that the free scale where you will
usually see background debug mode is in
free scale processors but anyway this is
the stuff that you'll get out of the
data sheets different debug interfaces
right JTAG has five pins sometimes six
test data and tested out test mode
select test clock and ground sometimes
test reset serial wire debug actually
will generally right on top of that
interface on your twenty twenty pin
standard ant arm JTAG here you can see
that the three serial wire debug pins
actually dual purpose with some of the
JTAG pins and then you arts just three
pins transmit receive and and ground
connecting the UART you can do this with
a shakoora bus pirate nef the FTDI
friend or any kind of FTDI adapter three
pins any serial terminal will do so many
comms screen what-have-you all you have
to do is specify the device and the
speed so things you'll get out of you
are right depending on the what how that
the vendor is done know their
implementation or what they're sending
out of it rather it can give you a full
route shell I could give you like a less
privileged shell like some kind of
manufactured menu type shell where
you'll have to look for an escape or
look to subvert like the the bootloader
to get yourself more privileged access
or just shooting debug output which is
very common it'll send debug output
which is actually really useful because
on startup when the device starts up
it'll give you the full hardware list of
everything and where everything's
mounted and everything else all the
addresses so that's actually really
valuable it's also really good like when
you're working with cheat JTAG and you
have like you're using open OCD and
you're trying to set a reset or whatever
you can watch the the output to make
sure the device is actually bouncing
when you
or freezing sorry I want to get to the
watching my time here I get to be I get
tend to be a little overly verbose
alright so some of the ways that you can
dump firmware right dumping flash over
SPI
this is a SPI flash win bond chip which
is call an 8-pin so ik here this we can
use as a shipper or bus pirate right we
hook up the mozzie mise au s clock slave
selecting ground pins and then we can
use a tool called flash ROM flash ROM is
a great open source tool for for dumping
or programming flash chips as long as
the chip in question is supported by
flash ROM you can dump it out to a file
and then use a tool like bin wok to pull
it apart and that'll pull out all the
different sections of the file hopefully
and then you'll have a little additional
reversing to do from there another way
to do this is dumping flash via JTAG
this is kind of a weird way we did it
here but it was cool we used the jailing
probe we found that had a JTAG a JTAG
interface and what we used was Segur
provides free tool toolkit oh you can
download from their site part of that is
the J flash tool and the J flash tool
will let you write or read to any
internal or externally supported flash
that it supports and that's what we did
here was we use that to dump out the
contents of this SD micro flash if you
see here this is actually a this is an
or flash it's not an SPI enabled flash
it doesn't just use one one pin for
transmitting and receiving data over the
bus it uses multiple and they're quite
fast so the technique we use previously
there would not work for this right so
in this case you know using JTAG here we
were able to dump the contents of the of
that flash chip alright cool so cool so
bones yeah all right so some of the this
is some of the stuff that we found on
engagements not naming any vendors or
or any particular device is the old the
purpose here is not to name and shame
these were all found on engagements for
providers not for vendors themselves and
any rate so a lot of unauthenticated
interfaces ok lack of mutual
authentication no message integrity
protection lacks a lack of replay
protection so this is all protocol
related stuff as well as remote denial
of service we found that you can knock
devices over with a stiff breeze on
either unencrypted protocols or really
weak encryption schemes and a lot of
hard-coded credentials and keys and what
I'm going to do here is give you an
example of quite a few of these not just
read this slide so I talked earlier
about DICOM alright so DICOM is used for
transferring images between an imaging
device and a back-end database server
like a pack server right which is a
picture archiving and communications
server
I believe medical world loves their long
really long acronyms so anyway part of
what DICOM has on the server side is
what's a cute call to QR SCP service
consider this kind of like a SCP or an
FTP if you will right it's an interface
that allows you to let's Express it's an
interface that allows you to query the
database and it is not necessarily
authenticated generally all you require
is a a a an application and 2d title so
this is a specific think of it like an
SNMP community name if you know this
word or this you know this this string
you can connect up and access and make
queries against the database and all you
need to know is what you're querying for
again as I said daikon does have
security profiles they are not often
implemented and vendors will publish
what they call a DICOM conformance
statement basically what it shows is its
devices what what daikon features it
device it's their device supports and
it's it's published for the purpose of
interoperability between that device and
other devices that talk aids that speak
DICOM all right but it will tell you the
list of their default AET titles
alright it'll have a big list of those
it'll tell what what classes are
supported if it supports any security
profiles and in case of one vendor it's
it's specifically that we do not support
any I'm paraphrasing we don't support
any any DICOM security profiles it is up
to the provider to secure to place the
device in a secure environment basically
it's not our problem
so what we're able to do there was we
found the open DICOM as QR SCP port we
used pine net DICOM to connect to it
which is a Python library for
communicating over DICOM over the
network and then there's also pi DICOM
for viewing what you've gotten what
you've retrieved we went and downloaded
the from the US census data a list of
like you know the top 1000 most common
surnames or last names right then we
basically ran those to a for-loop and
dumped thousands and thousands of
records out of the database by doing
that because as long as you know what
you're querying for you can pull it out
right so we just queried for all common
last names and pulled out thousands and
thousands of records of patient records
out of the database proprietary protocol
manipulation
so they said write proprietary protocols
very common this is in the case of a
patient monitoring system and it was
simple UDP based protocol what we did
was we generated known values on the
patient monitor and watched it
communicate with the central monitoring
system we modified those values and
observed that again identified what how
it was encoding them and where they were
in the data packets and then we just
wrote a simple at a cap filter to modify
those so for instance you know you'd
change a t 2 3 1 3 3 7 or what have you
and we were able to reliably change
every value that was displayed on the
central monitoring workstation from
these patient monitors the result of it
of course being that we could you know
make the nurse was watching the central
monitoring station think whatever we
thought about you know so regular normal
values while we're you know killing the
patient or assassinating the patient or
what-have-you right you know a little
little Hollywood there but you see my
point the other thing we found in that
same protocol and in others other
vendors was that device impersonation
was possible and what we found was that
in the one case the devices would use
the the patient monitors woods or they
would and the the central monitoring
station would send out a UDP broadcast
saying Here I am you know is anybody out
there well as long as you respond with
the properly formatted
UDP response the device will talk to you
and it will actually respond to you with
a if you spoof the central monitoring
system it will respond to you with the
patient a data packet containing all the
patient's information before it will
start sending you the vitals data right
this is encrypted very poorly and we'll
talk about this in a second but
basically it's a very simple key on both
devices we were able to do is decrypt it
by just reverse engineering we reverse
engineered the binaries on the central
monitoring workstation to identify how
the protocol worked and those actually
shipped with debugging symbols so that
was really much easier and then to get
the key because we were lazy we there
was a hl7 Gateway system that had dotnet
binaries on it that had the the key for
this as well for that that that
basically had that that array that we'll
talk about in a minute I'm so we're able
to pull that out of there so both ways
worked but the end result was we were
able to become a device trusted device
and have the patient data sent to us so
remote denial of service this is that
kind of goes without saying a lot of the
devices that we've assessed will fall
over from a stiff breeze you don't have
to do any kind of elaborate fuzzing if
you end map them they will fall over
which is by the way why you know in
terms of like port or vulnerability
scanning medical devices in a lie
a clinical environment I strongly advise
against it when we do pen tests for
providers you know Network pen test I
always ask them you know what segments
are your medical device is on because
you know we do not want to do any
scanning on there because they do not
they don't like it they don't handle it
well just some examples there right one
if you sent greater than 361 K through
the open UDP port it would fall over
immediately
and reboot constantly we that was
actually the one that had the debug
functionality on the monitor that I was
talking about I thought that would be so
awesome to debug this thing out and find
out we get remote code execution but we
couldn't get it to not reboot as soon as
we sent the thing to it
so another WMA mts system you could just
hold it offline by catting devil you
random into internet cat and sending it
to an open UDP port I could hold offline
indefinitely old all the systems every
one of them the central monitoring
system from one vendor if we replay in
any of the any of the traffic it had
previously seen from the patient monitor
it would fall off line for indeterminate
amount of time and then we found a null
pointer dereference in a stress testing
system it was actually in a another QRS
CP DICOM port it was a third-party DICOM
library and we found that if we sent
this particular string here I think it's
actually the first couple bites of that
that really do it I think it opens some
logic tree in there it's all wants to
accept data and then Falls it was a
third-party DICOM library we downloaded
the trial the sdk version of the DICOM
library and you know our eat it and
debug just because this was actually in
like a windows-based system and we found
it to be a null pointer to reference we
didn't in the time allotted to us we're
unable to actually find any kind of RCA
or you know actually be able to control
or or structured move the input where we
want it to be but we were able to
reliably kill the device all right so
crypto weak crypto weird crypto our home
home rolled crypto schemes are really
common what we find is that instead of
using standard crypto and
Asians multiple vendors are just doing
all kinds of weird stuff this is the one
I just talked about with the patient
info packet when we were doing device
impersonation right basically there's a
256 byte array on the sending and
receiving system right I can't do that
on the sending and receiving system and
then the decimal value of each byte in
the packet so that decimal value is the
the the the offset in the array to look
for the unencrypted value and that's
really all it is so it's just a simple
key K look at this point in this number
and retrieve and then there was a bit of
a byte reordering that you can see there
as well but that was the sum total of
the encryption being used so this one
was being used to encrypt credentials
stored in an in a config file those
credentials actually granted admin
access to a database server with all
kinds of pH I and PII on it
so for each ASCII character in that was
that made up the encrypted value picture
and ASCII table so you have the ASCII
value and you have its corresponding
decimal value all right ASCII value
decimal value if the decimal value is
less than 31 add 224 to it if it's
greater than 251 subtract to 24 from it
so you're moving through the array all
right and then if the decimal value of
the ASCII value is trying to remember if
it was even decrement it by 4 if it's
odd add four all right and then you have
the value so that's it and that is a you
know hard-coded system if you will on
all of those devices so basically once
you you know it you can do it with a
pencil and paper right which would then
allow you to walk into you know any
Hospital in the world that has the
particular device and know and be able
to decrypt those stored credentials that
will then grant you access not to the
system that they're on but to the
back-end database system that has that
and way other interesting stuff on it
much more interesting stuff yes I can
talk plaintext protocols this kind of
goes without saying you got stuff all
over the place you know DICOM an hl7
snmpv2 and XML based HTTP over over
plaintext a cheapy also slip which is
the first time I'd seen slip in many
many years if you guys remember slip is
the predecessor to PPP yeah we're going
back a ways also I guess it should be
mentioned that the the what you find
quite often with the vendor-supplied
servers is that they're also vulnerable
to traditional net pens stuff like LM
and r and b TNS poisoning so you can
pull creds off the network by using
those techniques so another interesting
thing here was we had a thick client
that from a vendor that communicated
with a pack server back-end pack servers
this is like a thick client it would
switch to when you want when you put in
your credentials authenticate it would
switch to HTTPS that's great right
unfortunately immediately afterwards it
would switch to http so the session
cookies going back and forth back and
forth you know it's going out each time
in plaintext right so what's the what's
the freaking point the other thing
interesting thing about that session
cookie is we couldn't kill that thing
we logged out properly you know we stole
it we're a login yeh we logged out
properly still work we tried it a month
later at the end of the engagement just
for giggles because clients like thinks
the works yep still work probably still
working to these day I don't know we
didn't bounce the server that would have
been the only one if it's the worked
after the server bounced that would have
been something but so anyway you know
the case of the cookie it wouldn't die
all right so these last two are not
medical devices it's a full disclosure I
just want to throw these in because
they're kind of cool examples of what
hard coding stuff will get you this was
on a network pen test like two years ago
I was doing a pen test it was an open
network share I found a bunch of these
XML files and in them was a
bunch of it was clearly encrypted
credentials you had the username and
then you got an encrypted password value
and you had the domain name and there's
like thirty of these and I'm like man
interesting so based on the name of the
file I googled it and I found what
software it was pulled down the trial
version of the software reversed the
software a lightly obfuscated hard-coded
key and we found it was using Triple DES
to do the encryption extracted the K
wrote some code to decrypt them and in
actually in giving credit where credit's
to my colleague Brian Wallace worked
with this on me and at any rate
decrypted the credentials we got like a
bunch of sets of credentials not all of
them were still good but one of them was
a DEA account not only was it a DEA
account it was a DEA account that never
expired
there other DEA accounts required you to
log in from from specific systems
although you could just move the host
name and get around that this one didn't
require that so it was like the god
account right and yeah they were they
were surprised about that one so that's
you know hard coding your crypto key not
a good idea another example of what
hard-coded creds will get you so this
was a telematics device I assess about a
year ago when it communicated over 3G
over GSM so it communicated so we used
bus pirate and flash ROM to dump the
wind bond SPI flash it was a SOIC flash
8 pin dump that out used Ben walk to
extract it and there's an XML file in it
again XML files for the win so I noticed
that in there there was a set of
credentials
there was an ftp server IP address and
then there was an APN name now an APN
name an access point name I was
unfamiliar up to that point of what that
was exactly but it is a gateway between
a cellular network and an other computer
network commonly the internet but not
always in this case it was the gateway
we found basically what we did was we
used WV dial and in a wireless card we
hooked up we put in the APN name and we
found that this was a gateway between
the cell providers that
work and the vendors privately addressed
RFC 1918 private network so now we're in
they're on their private network and
there's a whole mess of systems in there
and we have credentials to this FTP
server so let's go to the FTP server go
to the FTP server login in it is all the
versions of software for that particular
for that device and there was config
files in there with a whole mess of
creds for other servers other databases
everything else now we were assessing
this for third parties we didn't go any
further from there because you know I
didn't want to get in trouble but that
server was the server that the device is
and this is a live device in the field
so this wasn't the only one it was the
server that it used for it's
over-the-air update so and the firmware
wasn't signed either so we could have
replaced any of the firmware on that
server every one of those devices would
have now pulled our firmware installed
it and we would have backdoor on every
one of these devices so that's what
hard-coding stuffing in your flash chips
gets you alright I'm almost on time
here's some quick recommendations some
recommendations for providers server
hospitals right firstly dude inventory
your medical devices and assess their
attack surface know what you have and
know what they're speaking over what
their interfaces are I found that a lot
of providers they don't even they asked
just to come in to help them identify
what met what the inventory of their
devices are they don't even know what
they have let alone what their exposure
is disable any unneeded functionality if
they're not communicating if you're not
using the wireless functionality disable
it right same thing with any other
interfaces segregate medical devices
from the general clinical network or the
general hospital network all right as
much as possible disable any unused
ports right that would physical ports
Ethernet ports that will allow access to
those networks right a hospital is
pretty much a public area you know
you're you can't really McKey people
from being in a patient room and
connecting into something unless the
port's disabled monitor for attack
traffic and report your findings from
your assessments either internally or
from third party to the device vendors
right and if you were a larger
organization or even not put pressure on
those vendors you know politely to you
know remediate this stuff because enough
of that will make a difference our
recommendations for vendors assume that
attackers will will buy your device off
eBay or wherever and reverse-engineer it
a lot of oh well you know these are
attacks that they'd have to be in the
hospital they'd have to be on the
network how long would it take them to
attack the hardware of that in a room in
a hospital
take it home they're gonna buy it
they're gonna take their time learn
they're to learn the vulnerabilities
devise their attacks and divide and and
create something that can be done in
short order like plugging in a USB or an
SD card that your device uses for its
firmware update and then backdoor the
firmware because that's common mechanism
for doing that um use standard crypto
algorithms with secure key storage all
right and use a TPM a trusted platform
module to do key storage all right store
your keys securely and use standard
crypto algorithms do not roll your own
all right cryptography is not easy don't
run your at your applications on the
server side on their admin or root
privileges okay
run them on the only thing obviously
this is you know best security practice
stuff mutual authentication between
devices all right have devices I chain
that each other are who they think they
are right mutual auth is is critical in
that sort of ecosystem and finally as we
seen don't encrypt credentials or write
hash them or use the built-in othman
isms
and that's all I got so questions
questions yeah
honestly no so okay so most of the stuff
that we've done we either do it for four
four vendors in house or we do it for
providers in the case of providers it is
the providers as basically up to their
prerogative as to if they want to report
it what they want to do we can't
circumvent that process but the short
answer really is no I have not
yes
neither built-in DICOM actually does
have built in I think DICOM has the
built-in ability to use TLS hl7 does not
but can be implemented in in the
implementation can be wrapped wrapped in
like a TLS tunnel or use an IP so use
IPSec to wrap it or some other tunnel to
carry it through in the difference there
is that DICOM it's actually built into
the into the standard itself and I
believe it specifies the ability it has
the ability to use TLS so it's built in
as like as a security profile but I
don't often see that implemented sadly
generally it seems like the the vendors
leave it up to the provider that the
hospital to actually install all
components so you're thinking about you
know it's not just the backend server
right doing the communications but the
device itself
that's the imaging device sending images
over to icon to it we both need to be in
a secure Network you know a secure VLAN
etc right
so HIPPA I'm not an expert on HIPPA I'm
more of you know yeah thank you sir yeah
I'm more of a hands-on guy than a policy
guy as anybody I work with he'll tell
you but yeah wasn't to my knowledge
either you know I mean you have to look
at this the device itself and then be
the the rest of the ecosystem right I
think that you need to limit you know
the what those devices are able to do
I'm just off the top of my head right
you know try to lock them down as much
as possible so that you don't have you
know like the same problem that you have
in like with ICS systems like HVAC right
where you know the the maintenance guys
are surfing bad places on the machine
that that control the hmm of the the HMI
machine for for the HVAC system right
and then you wonder why they're full of
all kinds of interesting stuff so the
same thing right you don't want them if
it's if it's a ipad for instance used to
interface with one of these systems all
right you don't want them to be able to
access the internet on it do other
functionality functionality no honestly
if you think about it probably the
security model of the ipad is probably a
fair bit ahead of that of most medical
devices right or other yeah so yeah it's
a strange world we live in
back there Oh time
Oh in terms of the actual the actual
os's you to see actually vendors that
have their own Linux OS I could say one
like GE has Healy OS which is a I guess
you could say a fork of scientific Linux
that would be one example you see a lot
of like Windows XP embedded windows CA
you know other Linux variants it's
basically all over the place because
like such a wide disparate ecosystem of
devices right and then you have like the
RTOS stuff right but yeah it varies
quite a bit
yeah yeah obviously you see you bit a
lot yeah I mean so you see stuff like
u-boat in busybox and you know
everything that you you know a lot of
the stuff that you'd see how you'd see
you know just in in I mean it's not a
huge leap between that and the rest of
the you know IOT embedded device world
right it's really just more the the
purpose that it's put to and some other
considerations cool all right guys I
think I have to get out of here before I
get booted off the stage so thank you
[Applause]