mmm pues la vida the initial and
ninotchka about the informatics workshop
Edina brush as Brad all suits tag heuer
agua de las casas de barajas castle
salve workshop 18 Alexander Madras feel
Guinea region las Casas prohibition
kabhi ignorant ear and marco de tratar
de casa started unos nationalist sing
pop a super-busy Jeremy brown yeah good
luck h-hello Moscow great to be here
actually don't know if we're gonna study
any story but it's a little hard to get
here and I'm definitely glad that say
worked out because what an awesome
conference to present what a what a
great place but today I'm going to be
talking to you about hacking virtual
appliances and well actually if right
now I'm you're talking to you about that
and two hours and we're talking to you
about browser fuzzing so come back for
that right now talking to you about
hacking virtual appliances and this is
an area that's really interesting to me
and I kind of got into it because I
didn't see anyone doing security around
these things and when i first started
looking them i found a lot of really
interesting bugs a lot of remote a lot
of remote root bugs so they became
really valuable so I just had to do more
and more research and again I didn't see
many people looking in this area and
some of these bugs are very specific to
virtual appliances if you know what
virtual appliances mean that's fine I'm
going to go through all that and
hopefully you show you something new
today so if next works all right quick
run through the agenda look at the
introduction just kind of talk about
what virtual appliances are where they
are you know why this stuff's important
at all always good to know motivation to
do further research look it's the image
analysis and how I actually went about
looking and finding these
vulnerabilities and virtual appliances
and they look into the vulnerabilities
themselves there's a ton and a few
different categories I kind of group
them together in the miscellaneous at
the end because there's so many
different kinds of bugs you can find in
them and some are very specific to
you know the kind of virtual appliance
area like password glitter this pretty
specific there's some other areas it
gets into two and then go with the
conclusion and you know where to go from
here and how vendors can actually start
making these much more secure than they
are right now so you know my name
independent researcher consultant at the
moment used to work for Microsoft worked
on Windows Phone Xbox security also
works in malware protection Center for a
while and before that worked at tenable
and probably a few of you have used
nessus before I wrote a few nessus
plugins files there did some reverse
engineering things like that so fun
times so to be clear what I'm not
talking about in this area in the in the
VA area relatively non critical issues
let me talk about much denial service
cross that scripting again these can be
critical in other areas but virtual
appliances it's not a huge deal and also
not decrypting the VM images school
because that's sometimes necessary as
well in order to even start doing a
static analysis of the images you need
to you know have the keys and decrypt
them and there's no a lot of tools that
will let you do that today so all that's
pretty buck hunting stuff this talk is
very focused on vulnerabilities and so
we're going to be mostly talking about
remote shells if you're a fan of remote
shells command injection backdoor counts
and then once we get the shell we're
going to be looking at how to escalate
privileges to of course route because
most assistance we look at just at all
of them that looked at our linux-based
systems so keep that in mind as well and
other interesting bugs there's a for
mastering bug in here some kind of
misconfigured services that allow us to
to gain a little bit of ground and again
the one of my favorite bugs is specific
to this area is you know password litter
and I'll show you more about that so
what is the virtual appliance you guys
are probably pretty smart you can figure
it out physical appliance virtual
appliance so physical box and then you
have a disk image that you enter into a
hypervisor with all kinds of configure
and run in a data center or run at home
where you wish use VMware all those
different kinds of hypervisors and again
the the kind of thing the vendors are
saying here okay we have a physical
appliance you know we can ship that to
you just give them basically a little
tiny computer with a bunch of networking
ports or we can just take all that
whatever is in on that flash memory
whatever is on that hard drive dump it
on to a virtualized disk in an ISO or a
vhd or something like that and just ship
it to the customers with their data
center wherever they want to install it
so one interesting article I found and
this is from a VMware article that is
another reason that a lot of vendors are
doing virtual appliances is physical
appliances no longer need to be shipped
across national borders I never really
thought about that before I never really
thought that would be a reason but it is
interesting when you look at how you you
know how do you deliver a customer a
device you know you have to go through
customs you have to go through import
next Ford and all that with a physical
device not so much when you have a
virtual device that you can either send
them or drop somewhere or they can
download things like that so that's
definitely something that's going to
make virtual appliances take off even
more than four physical appliances you
know once we get the computer computing
power down an important distinction here
the bugs that are on virtual appliances
aren't specific to an environment there
it's kind of like the the one bug rules
all thing where this is not some
specific configuration you got to have
or make any modifications to the
appliance for it to be vulnerable once
the bug is shipped in this there's not a
ton of different versions that you need
to diff and things like that one bug is
going to take care of all of them so
that's an important distinction to make
between that and just user regular user
LAN programs or things you install on
windows and linux virtual appliances are
a little bit different so a lot of
popular vendors pretty much all the
major vendors have virtual appliances
probably not so much knock yourself for
example because they don't ship a lot of
Windows virtual appliances maybe a
couple but most major companies IBM some
antik being more cisco has a ton of
virtual appliances VMware has a pretty
good lot as well I could really look at
sa peas oral appliances because they
have cloud only trials so I can't
actually download it and you know do my
analysis on it if you're only hosting in
a web page for me that I have to log in
and do all this stuff so thanks a lot
for that got some free security work but
well so some of the pros and cons for
buck hunting the biggest thing here they
share pretty much the same amount of
code I mean everything from the physical
device and the virtual it's pretty much
they just dump everything on the on a
disk image and ship to customers so bugs
you find there of course are going to be
probably vulnerable on virtual and
fiscal and the common mindset that
creates a lot of these bugs is customers
don't have root that that's a huge thing
we're okay you know either they don't
have root or they don't have a shell so
there's all these debug interfaces all
these just sensitive information bash
history things like that they're just
left on the system and then when you
start looking at when you start
statically analyzing it even if you
don't have root dynamically when you
install and start running it if you look
at statically you can find all these
things they they left on there and they
can lead to some pretty serious
vulnerabilities so why go up these
appliances at all now you know what they
are they're definitely you know
prevalence is one factor as I said
they're becoming more and more popular
we'll look at entertainment there's a
few slides I have they're just funny
things that happen with they're not
really bugs per se but just really
things that kind of go I should take
another look at this because there's
probably some more serious things going
on and value of course enterprises or
using systems so they are the bugs here
are valuable and you can know
interesting from there so here's one it
basically looks like somebody just said
oh here's an image of my work pc it's a
virtual appliance change password if you
want to don't you just left the bass
history on here and they left the vim
history they left the diocese H known
hosts file so you can you can kind of
see where this is going where there
sleeping things are said okay maybe they
don't have root they don't have whatever
privilege uh Steven look at these files
so we don't need to worry about removing
them this is one where you know they
left just plain text passwords and
figuration file the default passwords
secure all this one you know this was a
bug where they're like okay we can't
leave plaintext passwords in a
configuration file so let's hash them
the only thing here they forgot to salt
the hash so any rainbow table is going
to pick this up no matter even if it's a
pretty complex password and they're
still going to pick it up as cluster
password this one where they left the
the password and any local user can just
you know log into the database using the
password this on the local system and
you know do whatever they want from
there again not really bug just just
kind of warming up to show you the
things and the kind of information is
left on these systems that you can
further use to to actually exploit
vulnerabilities and this one this is
probably from a abney own virtual
appliance because they're you know
they're SFTP and into internal IBM
systems and downloading looks like a
image file and it's even funnier here
they try to remove the bash history and
this is the bash history so I didn't
really do a very good job at removing it
right so entertainment factor one more
this one they sued rooted the ID binary
why would you ever sued root the ID
binary like there had to be some bug
where they're like we need to sing when
it when it executes psyd we need to make
sure it thinks its root so we're just
going to leave it like that totally
useless you can't really use it for if
anyone knows how to exploit a foodie
binary let me know but it's just just a
strange thing that occurs so value again
a lot of these virtual finds that I'll
be talking about our used in enterprise
and the most important thing here
customers really want these bugs fixed
because if they're going to trust that a
virtual appliances you know just as
secure as the physical appliance and you
start shipping all these things you
start giving people free trials and
download them find these vulnerabilities
and and then don't
even maybe pay attention to them then
that's really not good for customers
they definitely want these bugs fixed
because they're putting money into it
just as if it was a physical appliance
it's the same to them so while security
so bad again is the at this point the
vendors are just saying hey here's an
image of a computer it's a virtual
appliance you know we don't have all
this QA that we normally have on fiscal
appliances it's really easy just go set
it up you know here's the default
password the default user has to do
privileges I mean all these things so
it's just not really then aren't really
taking it seriously at this point i get
i know it's recurring theme and just
about every in a new new wave of
vulnerabilities but uh yeah that's
what's happening here as well so this is
a vendor's dog apparently sitting down
having a cup of coffee enjoying the
income so so you might be asking at this
point well how do i get a virtual
appliance to look at well I'll tell you
how at least how I did it so vendor
websites are a good source of these of
course you can look for free trial
request valuation all these Google dorks
you got to watch out some of them are
like a mix trial demo stuff you wanna
look out for that you can make a
purchase so you can make an investment
you know especially if you perhaps make
a make a living selling bugs or things
like that you can make an investment
acquire the virtual appliance and then
find bugs and go from there and then
sometimes they're just not available I
ran into a couple cases where you needed
a support contract you needed to be a
company it need to be a company company
purchase or have some existing support
there before you could even acquire one
even if you're willing to pay for it so
you're in these strange situations like
that when you start degan so you guys
have to be fully aware of what virtual
appliances are so image analysis how did
I go about looking at them so virtual
'pliance azhar distributed like a lot of
you know different systems in this way
digitally that ova containers they
usually brought a disk image and
like some kind of metadata files to tell
you how to set the configuration they
may just come as a vhd may just kind of
a hard drive you plug into the
hypervisor so a couple different ways i
mentioned before dynamic and static so
dynamic boot up the system basically
what you see is what you get you know
you're not looking at it statically
you're playing with the system you're
trying to see if you have root trying to
see if you can get shell it's the
trouble here again is if you don't have
those things it may be motivation to
find them at the same time you need to
use both techniques you need to use a
static approach combined with that
because statically you can look at the
file system without ever having to boot
it up you can see you know in the shadow
file if they have undocumented users you
can check you can have documentation
check the shadow file if the users not
there and then maybe you can crack the
password then you know there's a
vulnerability and the procedure here you
need to take the wrong file system and
convert it using like um usefully
something like that and then use some
kind of like imager or forensic tool to
browse it I think the one I use was ftk
imager something like that and it was
pretty good for browsing raw file
systems but the limitations here that
bit me at least once or twice was some
some of them virtual appliances have
first boot boot scripts so as soon as
you boot them they start setting
passwords they start doing all these
things where you kind of relied on that
you know maybe it works at first but as
soon as you boot you know things start
changing so you gotta kind of again you
have to use both approaches to to get a
good picture and confirm the bug cindy's
so now the meat the meat I'm going on to
the bugs the vulnerabilities that I've
discovered into virtual appliances again
very broad categories a lot of
undocumented users and then a lot of
miscellaneous from there and some
passwords litter so the first one look
at Cisco paging server it's a IM for
single wire software you know they
provide paging you know server stuff if
you ever use a paging server you
probably haven't is fine so on this one
there's actually three interfaces to
authenticate
the ssh daemon web of men and the web
interface for the first two of these you
know obviously if you know linux pretty
well you know the web man and and the
local 10 occasions in which acetates
usually uses share the same they're the
same they're they're your system
passwords all that the web interface
cisco took on this approach is different
it uses a totally different way to store
passwords check out medication so what
happens when you change the admin
password in the web interface absolutely
nothing on the on the you know the local
system so when you're documenting only
to change the administrator password on
the web interface and you never talk
about changing any of the other
credentials which are still default on
the system well even if you even if the
password is for example change me you're
never going to change it you're never
going to change that password because
the documentation only tells you to
change the web interface you know unless
you're some you know really skeptical
administrator you're not going to worry
about system at this point you set up
the paging server the 'pliance is
running fine you know anything to worry
about so you could chalk it up as a
documentation bug sure but really you
can just say take this and a bunch of
paging service because no one is ever
going to change a password that's
technically undocumented Channing the
passwords with an undocumented
authentication system even so the next
one EMC power path so here's a virtual
appliance that I found a couple
undocumented account song EMC update and
service user so guess I'm going to do
with those dictionary attack so load
them up and John the Ripper found emcs
updates password is password the other
one and took I think I was cracking it
for quite a while probably a week or two
and never did find anything so must be
you know random complex whatever but for
this one we just got a remote on the
system to the web interface just by an
undocumented password so now we can
control things on this appliance by
default with an undocumented user
because of this mistake just leaving
them on for
you know not either not restricting it
to you know maybe local only or
forgetting to change the password when
it first boots up this is never
documented so therefore a remote on emc
for this one so this one's in IBM
SmartCloud monitoring virtual appliance
so i only tested the trial so that's the
only one I could have available it
looked as if you could upgrade it to the
production so just copy out there I'm
ninety percent sure this still works in
the in the official version but only had
the trial to test on this one just FYI
so 26 users with bash shells on the
system two of them are undocumented das
user 1 and db2 SDF e1 so we find a
password and now we have a remote on IBM
SmartCloud monitoring virtual appliance
just by again undocumented accounts
there's no way to change the password
you know through the documentation again
unless you're just a paranoia
administrator that looks on your system
all the time for these things and you're
not just one who sets it up then you're
never going to find this out so VMware
horizon mobile manager this platform is
of course for managing mobile devices
and there's an MMP and documented user
on this one so what do you think happens
here boom vanitha password is actually
NM p and now we get a remote on a vmware
vmware virtual appliance it's kind of a
recurring theme at this point but so
there's caveat with this one to actually
sent us the vmware but it was end of
life so i found this a few months ago it
was becoming into life just recently
like maybe a week or two ago and should
have a bed this slides actually did they
did confirm this was vulnerable but then
we're going to fix it because of into
laughing the product but if I found this
two years ago it was still been just as
good that would just in de la fit today
though Cisco mobility services engine
another interesting virtual appliance
there's two user accounts on the
appliance route and Oracle so of course
root password is set by the
administrator when you
install it Oracle's untouched so this is
going to be interesting so I try the
cracking the password here with for
example John the Ripper and it was
unsuccessful but they have to set us
somewhere it has a password it has a
shadow entry in on the system so there
must be a password somewhere right it
took a long time but I finally found the
script that sets the password I don't
know if you can see it yeah so this is a
really huge screen right there to the
bottom left ex-mp DBA 123 so this is one
where I actually could not crack the
password after i had the shadow file
because they said it complex enough to
not allow for that to happen in a
reasonable amount of time but i still
found them setting it later on so still
a remote on the cisco MSC appliance but
take this a little bit further so now we
have oracle which has a shell for some
reason and can log in remotely you know
you can stop that if you just turn off
in the in configuration file so they
chose not to do that so let's see if we
can escalate our privileges a little bit
more with this one so if we look at the
post install log file they make suid
copies of Chima and shown I know you
guys know what those utilities do if
you've let you use linux for any amount
of time you don't want to set the seward
route bit on those on those binaries
what they did so let's use them to first
change permissions of the sudoers file
so this is one way to exploit it there's
a million different ways this is the way
I chose that was probably the easiest
way to just go ahead and add ourselves
to the sudoers file so we can just
automatically upgrade to route but we
got to clean up after that so we make
this really really stealth so if you're
actually hacking systems out there this
is going to help you clean up after
yourselves assuming it will have some
file system monitoring going on gotta
look out for that but I'm sure you know
now to do that anyways what you add
ourselves to us to do is file and now we
have root so through one mistake of them
having a complex pass for
which wasn't crackable but finding it in
an install file and I'm also making a
silly mistake making a sua drew copies
of Challon into mod you know we were
able to add ourselves to sideris file
and escalate to root so this one is
Pinocchio on site so if you never happen
oh piya that's fine their support by
cloudflare that's pretty big so lots of
people you know probably going to use
them if there's ford by cloudflare so
they actually did a really good job here
generating random credentials so default
passwords should not exist and that's
just the after I go through a million
these virtual appliances you there's no
reason to have default passwords this is
actually the right way to do it the
on-site key is essentially the password
for this appliance so they generate upon
boot generate a random set of
credentials great security only one
thing here they did wrong which got them
they forgot to remove the bash history
and you see that line after sue you pan
dump um in that long alphanumeric string
looks like they made a typo when they
were when they were escalating
privileges earlier so let's take
advantage of that now this is not even
the administrator account for the
appliance this is the i guess you would
say the vendors administrator account
for the appliance the ministry password
i showed you earlier they randomly
generated is for the customer this
particular vendor Pinocchio apparently
has other accounts that are only
accessible by the vendor another really
interesting thing in the virtual
appliance field a lot of vendors are
making putting a council in a system
that the customers don't have access to
so now we found out their master
password for all these virtual
appliances that they're shipping to
customers and the customers don't even
know this password so
you know it's cooler than a remote user
guess what Pinocchio man also has to do
privileges so now we have a remote root
on every customer virtual appliance that
help you has shipped it's not good not
good for them yeah and again my point of
them keeping static passwords that's
another question needs to be raised to
should vendors be keeping static
passwords the customers aren't even
aware about rent into that a few times
my research so sev one another one you
may not have heard about they are
definitely used by a lot of people a lot
of interesting people verizon comcast
HBO that they get a lot of free TV for
this but they had to do a silent patch
recently so i was looking at the virtual
appliance a ship I found an undocumented
account CMC dr with a password of CMC dr
ok so great now we have a remote so i'm
looking on the system and there's a su
binary sudra binary AAS look up it looks
like a custom binary so i was just
playing around with it what i usually
like to do with custom binaries that I
like to do 10 or 15 years ago and
actually work much better give them give
the command line arguments a bunch of
characters guess what the nineties
attacked worked again so there's a
buffer overflow in the first argument of
a Eslick a su binary you get the point
so we have not only a remote but a
possibility to exploit that to get root
privileges as well but i did a search
for CMC dr user and there was actually
some release notes where they had
released a new version that contained
information about the patching but the
URL have been removed thankfully google
caches everything for better or for
worse and we look at the cash and see
that platform remove shell access for
CMC dr user ok IES looked up creek
corrected an issue yes you did so they
put in the release notes which
now removed and the release ads were
hosted on a website that wasn't even
related as far as I could see to sev one
another strange thing so the latest a
public download for this virtual
appliance was 536 and apparently it was
fixed in 538 so they fixed the bug but I
don't know you have to be a customer I
guess I i assume you get an email if
you're if you you know pay for support
this says hey we fix some interesting
things you should upgrade but everyone
else downloading the public version is
just screwed so that's not great so
let's go into command injection I be a
subclass of getting a remote root or
remote shell at this point this is EMC
recoverpoint pretty popular virtual
appliance from EMC it provides
continuous data protection so they will
protect your data if you use this
appliance that's what it says right so
the default and also unchangeable these
are not just default there is no way
that I found there may be some crazy way
to do it but there is no way that I
found to change these credentials they
are locked into this virtual appliance
box management box management so now we
can ssh into management interface and we
get this cute little console interface
that Travis restrict us from doing
anything but what they want us to do
well if we look at the diagnostic
section of this we found one that says
run internal command and that would
pretty interesting but there's only a
certain set of internal commands we can
run if there was only a way we could run
other commands than that you guys forgot
this is command injection right boom
command injection so if you just use SSH
this is a valid command and give it some
shell metacharacters and fix up your STD
out you can break into a show so now
that we have a shell with a box
management user undercover point let's
see what else is interesting so the run
being run box management is the console
interface it just calls a Java for the
UI which is in
you know calm kasia recoverpoint
installation jar there's a class in that
jar file that looks pretty interesting
and you know run internal command we
want to decompile that and see what else
we may be able to do you know because we
have access to this interface see what
else we can do with the appliance so we
look at the D compiled code here we can
see we can run arp our ping daily stool
some perl script and it just puts the
output in well it takes the output it
prints it to internal command in the
temp directory and it puts if any of the
commands are on the list it puts sudo in
front of it so from that we can know
that any of these commands are going to
execute with root privileges so if we
can execute any of these commands with
root privileges what can we do with that
so there happen to be and again we
confirm our options in the suitors file
and we see that we can execute all these
but I found that ARP will actually read
a file I didn't even know that for I
tried this so if we if we have to do
privileges to risk we don't need to use
a console anymore once we break into
show we just pass whatever file we want
to read to sue do and it will output any
file reading as a system on the
appliance so definitely I would like
outlook to the perl script I couldn't
really found any interesting bugs there
although it did some bad stuff so the
closest I got on this one I didn't
actually escalate route i guess but i
can read any any file on the system as
root so there's a starting point so
there was a little bit of confusion
about this one so what is the root and
Men password it so that there is one in
the shadow foul but it's not given the
customers and if you ask for it there's
just you know for example something I
asked for here how do you reset the
admin password for a government and the
fix that they say is the solution
requires assistance from EMC 'contact
m.c support service and it's just you
know again the theme of the vendor
having credentials that the customer
doesn't he know about I don't know our
customers feel about that
they know about it yet but uh definitely
a point for discussion so the next one
is SolarWinds log & Event Manager I
wanted to highlight this one it's like
45 hundred dollars and it's a it's
actually a SE IM or SI m and it's easy
to use logs for security compliance all
that stuff so as default creds for CMC
password and runs a ssh server on 3 20
22 I think this one's actually
undocumented a CMC user as well so once
we login as cnc user we have another
command injection we use literally the
same string we use to exploit the the
emc bug for this one we drop into a
shell so manager config is the main
interface for this one and it's actually
written in perl so contigo control calls
a bunch of shell scripts to implement
commands contigo control is a course
rideable ba contigo user that weird just
logged in as and it calls it's allowed
to call any of those script as root
that's not the best idea so if we add
something useful to take you can control
lock I don't know give us a shell for
free no password if we just do that then
we can just upgrade for free so that is
a very very straight forward command
ejection that we use to first break out
of the shell and then go to and add
ourselves via a local vulnerability to
escalate to root and there's one more
bug in this appliance as well for
mastering bug I don't know if we have
any old timers out there for these bugs
but they were super interesting they're
still around a little bit i found them
from time to time but again the
interface is in perl so if you you know
if you give it % p % and whatever
accepts and then there's a format string
bug there but they're actually some
exploitable format string bugs in perl
so there's a really interesting paper
back in 2005 if you want to look at that
there's actually maybe an exploit out
for that
well but sorry I'm a pretty big fan of
for mastering vulnerabilities and I keep
hearing their dead but I keep finding
them so that's that was fun so another
thing this was about the root password
people asking about it they're like yeah
you can call support and we can use the
root account to get in and reset the
password for you like I don't want you
to do that if I ever buy this appliance
a lot of confusion around that issue so
a time for some crazy suid binaries I
know we exploited a bunch of bugs those
before let's talk about one in time
Cisco prime infrastructure so if you
have a linux box at home you know that
if you you know take a log of all the
suid files there should be no where near
67 that's way too much right there's
usually 2025 67 you know there's going
to be some problems here so if you just
grip the fault the file for shell the
word shell we have some interesting ones
one run shell command one run shell as
root what do you guys think they do
probably be helpful to us right so
they're so poorly written actually run
shell command if you don't give it an
argument it crashes on a null point de
breff so they didn't even check if an
argument is given so you know the
quality of the code there's going to be
some more bugs here I just I just could
not believe they didn't check for an
argument that's like did you wrap this
in 30 seconds or what so now saying it
was aliens this certainly could have
been so the way it works here run shells
route you put whatever commands you want
in a file you pass that file to it it
runs on this route ouch what about run
show command well even easier you just
pass the command to it and it rents it
as root for you so these are local
binaries that are suid that are
executable by anyone on the system and
trivial to get you know privilege
escalation from here well I gotta give
them credit they
really stepped up security and they sued
rooted the user add binary and they made
it only executable to root that doesn't
make any sense whatsoever why would you
sued root it and the only let root
execute it why don't you just leave it
alone but I guess we can't use that to
do anything right I'll offer out we have
run shell command so we can just add a
route to user with everything we need
old-school styles you like it and boom
we ever now we have crazy suid binaries
plus a remote going on so we have I know
there's a lot of cisco virtual
appliances that with cisco prime
infrastructure this is cisco prime
collaboration insurance there's many
many more i'll try not to confuse you as
much as possible so it's two accounts on
the system quickly there's a corner case
with the setup it's not la blaze
foldable but it's a noteworthy case
study so we'll go through it quickly the
interesting part here i want to get to
is with the java debug server if you
guys have ever used it but there's
interesting suit of binary here firewall
guess what it is controls the firewall
so they're running java the bug server
as a rename process called am sam
perfmon engine and it's listening on the
network interface but the firewalls
turned on and they did a really good
security thing by making sure that no
one can access it from the firewall
although they could just as easily made
it listen on localhost knowing had to
worry about that i digress so that's
javed the bug server and I'll active did
some really cool research on this they
did a you know hacking Java debug wire
protocol basically any as the TLDR says
turn any open java debug server into
reliable remote code execution so let's
see how that works but one thing we have
to access it we want you know we can do
it locally but we want to remote at this
point so we just turn the firewall off
because it's suid
and we have privileges to do that so
just turn it off so now we can access
this remotely so this is X boy the aisle
active wrote I just used it and I'll
just hold it and I actually to make it
easier up netcat on the system whatever
you can I just just to make it easy as
possible to explain and now we have a
remote root on the system through job of
the bug server so anytime you see Java
debug server running especially remotely
so if it's local you can get a local
route if it's running remotely anytime
you see java de bug sir it's literally I
think a design flaw and the server this
exploit still works today and I think
it's a year or two old there I don't
think there's any patch that you're
literally have to redesign it or just
don't run it so very important if you're
doing a pen test for that you only live
once so I know you guys are probably
tired of hearing about remote roots
right those are so so many of them so
I'm going to conclude with a few things
all you people out there wanting some
defensive stuff don't run away yet
because i'm talking about that the first
bender communication so scare many
offended very policy this is actually
facebook's first responsible responsible
disclosure policy and they FY they say
they won't sue you if you make a good
effort and work with them ouch i think
the change by now but this was a few
years ago so brief disclosure timelines
the SolarWinds solarwinds bug they took
a while to send me their pgp key and i
don't know if they had to generate it or
if they just forgot where it was I don't
know what happened but they fixed in a
few months but it was just the first
response was like we'll get you the PGP
you soon I'm like isn't it just an email
I can just send me into it to me through
email and the AMC fixed it almost over a
month which is really nice and then the
guy was working with amcu left and now
I'll probably never get a bug fixed
again so that's great Pinocchio noted
they patched a potential security
vulnerability sure cisco with the
primary structure it released a private
advisory you have to log in to see it
not searchable not the best way to do it
VMware as I said send the Volt so
initially disclose this back in
September and they they sent they
contacted me a couple days before I
disclosed and said hey can you tell us
anything I'm like yeah I mean if you're
going to contact me about it sure so I
gave him the full details and they
decided not to fix it's reasonable
because they end alot the product
SolarWinds they fixed it sep tember
cisco fixed it a couple weeks ago and
emc the VRP a that released advisory in
july if you didn't see it up there it's
maybe not fixed so plain defense cleaned
up before you ship it I mean you guys
saw the bash history where you know
you're able to get a remote route just
by a typo don't ship bash history to
customers that's nonsense all the crazy
suid binaries on boxes don't assume that
nobody can get a shell that nobody can
you know do anything a local system so
don't put you know give me give me root
binaries on the box and then passwords
unknown to customers that just blows my
mind I don't know if that's the new way
of thinking or the or not that's just
strange fire Wong is definitely a great
practice here but don't you know don't
let me turn off the firewall of course
and like i said before generating random
passwords on boot there should never be
another default password like literally
it's unnecessary you're just asking for
trouble using default passwords when you
for virtual appliances set a random
password on boot and be done with it you
never have to ask him to do anything
because they have the password on the
local system if they're looking at the
local system you probably already
screwed so one interesting thing i saw
that this is from cisco prom
collaboration deployment different from
the other ones i promise they actually
blacklisted users for remote access this
was an interesting mitigation but called
I thought at first I had a remote on
this virtual clients I thought I had
other I saw informix and formics done
undocumented have a remote and I tried
to log in remotely I'm like why can't i
login remotely
I cannot login anywhere but the local
system because they mitigated this
problem somebody probably saw that and
thinks well this guy doesn't need to log
in remotely so let's just you know
didn't put them up the dot denialist on
the ssh server very good mitigation is
practically useless now even if there is
a default password because I can't log
in remotely for vendors here this is
very Minerva cific but don't make trials
and demos and it's just super confusing
and not only for try to ruin some my
bugs which didn't really affect me much
but just for the development team in
general they're gonna be like oh this is
a demo so we don't need to put in
security and then the guys shipping it
like oh no we're ready to ship it's
actually a trial and then that leads to
a lot of bad assumptions don't ship the
master development vm us all earlier
shipping bass history shipping all these
other files i mean there should be a
development vm and a clean copy that you
build from that and i know i've heard
from vendors all we do all that stuff
it's like okay why do you have these
bugs in why do they exist you're
obviously not doing it we're not doing
it for all the appliances and a list a
tick list of must not have this was
something that every every development
team should have when they're shipping a
product for these appliances you know I
listed much a bunch of things and i'll
list a bunch more these are things again
for developers don't do this when ship
the device or is for bug hunters to look
for when they're testing virtual
appliances whatever side you're on you
can use this so default passwords of
course undocumented one if they're
undocumented document them it's an
opening my own system remove them simple
files obviously unencrypted passwords or
unsalted passwords i should say on this
any sensitive data all the suid world
writable scripts bit bit was emc a
minute ago a world writable script able
to get root from that some of the
services if they're meant to be local
make them listen on the local interface
don't listen on the network interface
again very unnecessary and then using a
different authentication systems that
was a kind of a subtle one-off example
but
I could see that happening in the future
actually that was a pretty interesting
bug and assumptions again it all comes
down to assumptions in the in this space
don't assume it's not for production if
your shipping is don't say I can just
hide this private key in a file black
Cisco did a while back and got all their
virtual appliances compromised you know
don't only assume administrators can
execute the script because somebody's
going to come on late come later on and
say huh here's a new feature we're going
to change the way this works maybe
you're not in have to company anymore
you know I'm looking at this as a very I
guess as a software company view where a
lot of things I've seen you know people
leave they come back and then bugs
happen the cause of some shins being
made and then again with co turn and
updates a lot of things can change so
don't make any assumptions don't assume
shit and then esoteric thoughts here
there's a lot of helper if you're going
to go look at these devices I haven't
broke them all I don't think I'll have
access to all of them now saying I could
have had would but again if you want to
go look at these think about helper
services all the helpers all the things
that maybe the external facing server is
talking to an internal service a lot of
those go unchecked support services
remote access are always juicy fertile
ground for bugs they have a lot of
backup restore directories so you can
look in those for the installation files
maybe see how they're doing something
how they're setting a password and then
really read the documentation coast it
can be the difference between a bug and
technically a feature forensics oh my
god if I had a million dollars I
wouldn't buy a forensics sweet but if I
had two million dollars or three if I
just had a lot extra money I would Bob
forensics fleet and just own a ton of
these virtual appliances because we
deleted all the sensitive files yeah you
can guess how forensics works right you
can undelete things and that would be a
pretty pretty good game changer I think
so like I mentioned before Cisco got bit
by this huge bug they ship some private
keys on a bunch their virtual appliances
so anyone who had X
two could just get that key and get
remote root on all their stuff pretty
big deal so in conclusion as always area
is still unexplored there's a lot of
stuff I didn't have access to a lot of
stuff is really expensive a lot of stuff
they don't offer you know to to non
company ended to use or whatever at the
moment and the only going to become more
prevalent like I said things are moving
in a way where physical appliances once
we have you know the data centers are
getting more more more advanced more
more processing power dis space all that
they're going to be able even if you
have a really high performing device
we're gonna be able to make it into bits
and just push it push into hypervisor
and a cloud somewhere or something like
that and there's a lot more work to do
it like I said getting access to these
and then getting the vendors that
properly fixed some bugs it's always an
issue as well so interesting area to get
into and let me know if you have any
questions that's five minutes or so this
guy i was told will throw a box at you
and it won't hurt oh oh you that was
close ok um could you please go back to
the slide before must not have must not
have yes the foremost I house yeah
revolutions it's like not questions kind
of suggestion you probably print it out
and send out to every development team
point of every product in this world
because it's not about virtual
appliances it's about basic security for
every software production no matter its
virtual appliances or whatever else i'm
glad i made a slide that will stand the
test of time thank you thank you uh yes
i will try to get that too if you give
me a list of companies i'll email to
them I really will I really will okay
thank you though shit it any other
questions I can go back and forth
probably on slides I got like three here
we go sorry
have you used any special software to
scan about for example the files within
correct permissions or because we have
like UNIX previous checker we have also
windows purvis chicken around saw those
things yeah so I understand correctly
have already need tools to to automate a
lot of these you know the most not hats
looking for bad either bad permissions
or things like that I haven't came up
with the toolset for it I've literally
came up with these slides recently for
the must not have I actually thought a
couple times about writing some tools
for it but I don't know I got to the
point where I was kind of you know I had
certain projects I was kind of done with
this one and I didn't want to spend a
lot more time writing tools for it so I
just wanted to kind of come up with a
list but not hard to do definitely not
hard to do if you have if you have an
automated framework one vendor was
telling me that they were going to take
like the must not have stuff and kind of
put it into their own tool set they have
checks for so maybe in a way I kind of
assumed that there is some framework
that may be a lot of software vendors
already have to do certain checks that
and you know take those rules and kind
of put them in there like that but no I
don't have any tool set to do that but
you totally is totally possible to do
that thank you very thank you any more
questions anymore a couple couple of
good questions once more of a compliment
I still appreciate it hopefully
compliment no more questions everybody
understood everything really well I hope
I wrote it when I was riding the slide
that was like I have to make this simple
enough for everyone to understand but
also stay awake most of you still seem
awake that's good thank you
alright if there's no more questions
come back and see me six o'clock in the
other track but also say for this guy
and thank you very much