[Applause]
um
so i'm actually quite surprised by like
uh how many people showed up
i expected there to be like two or three
uh and
for the talk to be more of like a
discussion format so i'll be happy if
you
guys join my name is joseph
i maintain the local hackerspace in the
basement in case you haven't been there
yet
go to bordell when you see the
the red known sign saying bordeaux just
you know don't be shy and sure
um but yeah today uh i'm going to talk
about identity
uh in general about identity in the
context of
digital totality um and um
how i think the identity space and the
identification space
um is is going to evolve especially in
the context of web3
um so beyond um paraneopolis uh i'm
involved with in the ethereum community
i've been
um working on like few projects uh one
of them was
touching identity about like two or
three years ago um
so um in the end like we can also
discuss like implementation details if
anyone is interested so first of all i'm
going to talk about like what is what is
an identity
uh how did we get to where we are now um
through like the evolution of
authentication um
then i want to talk about the 3 paradigm
and like how does that fit in
uh and in the end i want to mention like
few in my opinion interesting groups
that are
kind of researching the identity topic
for
20 years now and
then about some like practical use cases
that can be already tried out
so uh what is identity um
the cambridge dictionary uh and like
bunch of other random
google searches uh we'll show you uh
show you this
um identity is who a person is or the
qualities of a person
or group that make them different from
others so
this means it's just those set of things
that it's like different from anyone
else and that's how you
identify and now what do you identify
uh we can talk about like personal
identity uh we can talk about an
identity of an organization
um or like a nationwide identity or
identity with a tribe with ethnicity um
and about like identities of whole bunch
of other things i'm sure at one point
we'll talk about
different identities and the
distinguishing factors of like
different um popular ai um
setups um so that that would be kind of
the
uh you know like human sciences uh type
of definition
um the other one the more exact one uh
you can say that identity is basically
uh
a mathematical operator uh the equal
but we are not going to talk about that
um
so during this talk i want to focus
mostly on personal identity but i think
uh it's still worthwhile to kind of like
reason about
um the other connections because
especially like throughout the evolution
um
those things are interconnected so what
do you what do you think was
the first
way to identify one another
um within within like a you know like a
group of people
humans um that that's known today what
do you think is the oldest thing that
people use to authentic
authenticate themselves
what a name as like a verbal operator
um so sure uh that's
that's like a label of a person and then
you would just like distribute knowledge
among the group any other thoughts
all right uh yeah now we are getting
into like
the identity of of like a different
tribe system
uh but the the kind of first associated
item
um talking about like um a physical item
uh that's known is uh jewelry or like
visual symbols
um so um
[Music]
roughly 100 000 years before christ
people used to
like wear different jewelries to
associate themselves with the tribe
basically these these insignias
are used today uh even even like
in this age but uh prevalently like
those were just used throughout the
history you could you could say
you know like the the local shaman or
the local king is the guy with the crown
right that was that was his
identification whoever had the crown was
the king
um that's how you tell he's a king um
but
even in like more you know like um
primitive
um social groups uh they were just like
different types of bones like different
types of rings that people are wearing
to identify themselves with
like their family or their tribe
so roughly um
2000 years before christ uh at least
depend you know like um given the given
the archaeological research
as far as we can tell tattoos were this
old
um and like one of the one of the ways
like people
started like identifying themselves
personally um
with something you cannot remove from
them going beyond like the physical
objects or tattoos
uh so this is a study of a man found
somewhere in china um um
apparently originating like thousands of
years ago
uh this is a member of jacuzza who was
uh arrested like two years ago somewhere
in malaysia i believe
um but this was this was kind of you
know this was like getting chipped
right like you just use your body to put
like all of the symbols
so people can tell like this is the guy
you know like uh
you don't you don't need to remember his
face just like see
if he has a tattoo but obviously like
this is still kind of forgivable like if
you you know uh
you could the same way you could just
like take the insignia
um the jewelry from somewhere some
someone before you could just like make
make the same tattoo and like try to
peer trying to infringe
someone else um with
ancient rome and um
and creek we are getting to like more
formalized
um formalized even um
you know like human societies uh in
general but also
to uh more formalized identity documents
so this is
um this is a so-called diploma a
military diploma
uh yearly 200 years before christ um
where um this this document
is basically a cv of a soldier uh which
just enumerates like
all of the battles that that person went
to um
basically granting him the citizenship
um
uh of rome uh which then gave him like
special privileges like
uh being considered a citizen being
exempt from taxes
uh for the military service um
and being able to like participate on
the higher society
um basically like you can you can forge
a document as well
then in 1414 uh we are getting to like a
first type of um
[Music]
like a passporty document where a king
could basically give someone a paper
which
authorizes that person to do acts that
just says well
me as a king there is there is my stem
my sigil
um i'm calling this person um
whatever citizen gives him certain right
um
then again continuously in britain um
in 1829 uh robert peel started
um um like obviously he wasn't the
person issuing those numbers but he
started using
personal identification numbers or
suggested those to be used for
uh all citizens of um of the kingdom
um then later on we are going like to a
bit more detail
of what a con like what what an identity
can consist of
um with um negative photography
um in 1840 obviously a whole you know
like a whole new branch of
um identification
um was there to be used so
then with the next uh discovery of
fingerprints and the possibility of like
using those to identify a person
30 years later we obviously get like a
yet new aspect of what
objectively you can you know of the data
set that you can
kind of gather to identify someone
uh then throughout the 20th century uh
we basically got where we are now like
we went through
physical passports that enabled
traveling between countries that
um you know had some some sort of an
agreement about like accepting those
we go through like regular passports
boom now we have everyone has an
identica are obviously connected with
your
personal id issued by
the local government
in 1980s there are yet
two new like innovative things being
introduced
one is the first digital ids um which
uh include a sign-in key where you can
basically
identify yourself digitally and the
interesting part is that we are kind of
like getting back to
well yet now having having an object
for for identification
obviously with biometrical data with
photography
and a whole bunch of other stuff also in
the 80s
the dna profiling started to be used to
identify an individual
um now we get like more up to date
um the buzzwords that you can all um
that you can often hear in connection to
um kind of evolved in a way where
in 1999 you started uh accepting
electronic signatures for
um for signing official documents in
2001 through
the patriot act uh a thing that we all
love and
adore aml and kyc started being a thing
uh for basically anybody
um in 2007 the uh
psd payment services directives in the
eu
um also like in connection to uh
ml and kyc um kind of shape the way
the state is trying to like utilize the
the fact that they
uh have the data and can like identify
you online
from from psd um
there's the eides initiative uh which
tries to
kind of bridge the differences between
how like digital line
identities are being used across the eu
uh current like very up-to-date buzzword
psd2
um which is um
again like an advancement that should
enable
uh also like reusing your identity
between like service providers um in the
banking sector
um and then uh obviously gdpr
uh which kind of
goes against like all of these because
this is the point where
people started realizing yeah well maybe
uh if we create these
like huge databases being able to
identify everybody
well that's not always good and maybe we
actually
uh once you kind of keep
some parts of the information for
ourselves
so this is all this all relates to
kind of governmental systems and money
money transfers um but there are there
is also
like throughout the 21st century there
is also like a whole another branch of
how authentication in connection to like
your personal identity is being handled
which is through you know popular
services
uh such as google login uh facebook
login or like any
other service provider that's out there
here locally that would be
my id but i'm certain there are also
like different services
handling the same thing in other
countries um
so yeah these these solutions are kind
of cool right those are not
those are voluntary like you don't have
to use those services uh you can sign up
you know get uh get an excellent like ux
benefit because like you don't have to
like every every app like all of a
sudden doesn't have to
build their own identification system
you can just get some data from
google which is good for the business
uh so um
yeah so obviously there is a there is a
way out of this but
what this also enabled um because like
these types of login services became
quite popular i'm pretty sure pretty
much like everybody in the room has
ever used those
if not then talk to me later i'm just
interested in like
how you spend your time uh
so um this also made
civil attacks like much easier because
like all of a sudden
there is like an alternative way to how
um
like states tend to identify to people
to just like create your online identity
picking like whatever service and it
doesn't have to be just google or
facebook right like you can
just go to go to a random forum start
new nickname uh and you can spin out
like hundreds of these you can have like
a
unique identity for any service that
you're using
you can even have like multiple google
logins etc um
so it was all good until like recently
um especially the big providers started
like utilizing
phone numbers as a way to like limit uh
the artificially
created profiles uh that can be used as
a as a cover for
another person uh so it became a bit
harder
now you have to you know get a phone
number
um it's like somewhere it's easier
somewhere it's not
so it's already constraining you um and
now
you know like now there is actually like
a feasible way
to just live your daily life
uh except for the cases where you
actually like need to sign something to
the government and you have to
like go back to whatever they are
offering you but hey this is a feasible
alternative like
actually like any government government
could just like tap into that and
instead of like building their own layer
they could just like use some of the
service providers right
but we are again getting to like a
corporate surveillance we are getting
into
like these companies utilizing all of
the data they have and
having like the power over your identity
because they hold your data and now like
linking is back to like gdpr that that's
like a governmental attempt to
you know uh balance the the fact that
they don't actually have as many data as
these companies
um so
especially um in the web 2 contacts with
google auth and like facebook logins um
it's kind of obvious that given like how
many people
use these services uh the the user
experience of like
being able to tap into someone else's
security tap into someone else's
database of users
um and not having to start everything
from scratch again um
has bigger value to people in privacy
for
most that's kind of true um luckily like
this is changing these days at least
in central europe you know like there
are events such as this one
but even the companies in the identity
space that
make surveys and um try to understand
like what
what the people what the users actually
care about
figured out that thanks to like
cambridge analytica and
uh whatever like other types of leagues
people are actually like more aware
of um the the strings attached
and are starting to value their privacy
yet again um now i guess it's kind of
obvious where
where it goes to you um because
with with your governmental identity you
can just have one
most likely there are i guess there are
ways to get
your second identity somewhere else uh
those are definitely non-trivial
uh if you know those i would be also
interested in like
uh talking about it later um
but um but yeah like as
for i guess for people in the room the
benefit
of not being able to um or
for someone else not being able to
identify you easily so you can keep your
privacy
is a valuable thing and now we get to
dissociative identity which
most of you probably already have in
some way
um i don't want you i don't mean i don't
want to make fun of like
mental illnesses but uh
when you when you search for like the
ids the centralized
identifiers decentralized i need any
standards um
it also matches with um another did
uh the dissociative identity disorder uh
which is basically
multiple personality disorder um
and i mean obviously it's considered an
illness
um an unwanted
state of state of mind but for us
being interested in um keeping your
digital privacy this is actually
something we want
we want exactly we want a disorder right
we we want to we want our image
or an image of our identity to have this
type of disorder where you can
basically maintain different faces for
like different circumstances
also you know being accompanied by a
memory gap like you don't want these
two words to be linked for whatever
reasons
um and this is the this is the point
where
i get to web 3 and uh like the
the technical implementations of
allowing dissociative identities
uh in the digital space um so
well obviously again with like web 2 you
could
spin up like bunch of your own
identities uh
it's getting harder these days but it's
still the same type of infrastructure
it's like
the same type of process where you have
a user
the user uses someone else's like server
database to store their
user profiles and then like through that
he interacts with those services and
like these you know there could there
could be like little services you can
connect directly to facebook
just leaving the information with them
or even using
those identification services as proxies
basically telling
facebook to give a subset of your data
to another service provider
and this is the world that we live in
now
where you basically just have to log in
information that's all you own
like you don't have the data you have to
ask them like they should give it to you
um but you never know um in the web 3
context
the difference that that the
decentralized identity
standards are based on um
is the fact that in that realm you
should be the person holding all of your
personal data and you should only allow
services to tap into that without like
storing the data because they don't
need it unless they use it for some sort
of computation like even then
you could do it like homomorphically but
the service providers like they don't
really
need the data right like if you you know
like everybody is ordering stuff online
like on every single website on every
single eshop
you're filling out the same information
all over and over like the address
your credit card numbers if you don't do
it i mean
good for you uh you can even like come
up with
multiple but the fact is like it's just
easier to
like use the man address where you're
certain your packages are going to
arrive
now does like every single eshop needed
information
do they need to keep it after you're
finished with the purchase
likely not uh but even the architecture
of those services isn't ready for
just like asking for information at the
time they actually need it
and that's that's what's supposed to
change with web3
where the user keeps this user profile
and he just allows services or
credential validators which can be like
other
horrible word kyc providers or
authentication services
without like ever giving the data away
um
and that's that's already possible
that's already possible like with the
technologies that we have
um but it's just a matter of getting
there
so so the web3 context the paradigm is a
pushback on that old
architecture or the current architecture
um
as i mean as again as it happens like
every now and then
um the point here is to keep those
services
as peer-to-peer as possible um
meaning that um whatever information you
can like
leave at one point and you don't have to
like distribute it anywhere just like
keep it there
um
just as like with your
uh with login info um your
online presence profile whatever um
all of the you know like if you want to
interact with the service the service
should
just should ask for like a concrete set
of data and it's already happening with
like google out and stuff
um so the main point is that you should
keep your own data you shouldn't like
leave it with the custodial services the
same way like you don't do it with
crypto
um and what's what the new paradigm also
allows are
like different types of recoveries
because like obviously if you
if you own your data you also have the
responsibilities the same
thing with your private keys since this
is also about like maintaining your
private keys
and like all of the info that you want
to share at some point uh you're
responsible for
not getting it lost uh and that's why i
like new
solutions for that that's like social
recovery where you a big bunch of
friends who can then authenticate you
back into the system are being used um
one like subpoint this this leads to
like
creating essential like reputation
systems in different contexts this is
like what a lot of companies are trying
to achieve these days
what's also a new thing is just
provable usage because like in web 3
contacts obviously like everybody has a
everybody has a crypto wallet everybody
has their set of private keys they know
how to handle it
or they use a custodial service
uh but now with a bunch of these like
keys being used
on chain you actually can use
or can boonstrap like reputation uh
using on-chain data you can just say
well um for instance i only want this
app to be
initially used by by the people that
use like bitcoin before the block x and
you could you could just like get all of
the addresses and basically create a
notification on that
um or just use all
um like a markup proof uh in a contract
to identify to to do it like seamlessly
um so
so yeah uh the what's the hard part like
given given that like everybody here
probably uses crypto has some experience
with that you you know what the
ins and outs are you know what you
should avoid you should
you know you know how to protect your
private keys
um but what do you
you know what do you do when when you
just want to like
use another private key and start your
identity um
uh from scratch because like in in the
online world it's it's easier obviously
it's like not so easy
when you want to actually do something
with the government but that's where
where like the additional kyc providers
get to play
um because um
the fact that in in the initial point if
you
you know there are these like two
domains like one is the governmental
identification the other one is
the corporate one uh you could probably
like it could look like the same
uh but in the beginning the the person
that ky sees you
is obviously the government the official
service uh in the other cases it's like
a corporation
um and most of the identification is
just based on the fact that you
have an email that you have the ability
to get an email
so i mean these images are essentially
the same right
there is like not a huge difference you
still could have like intermediary
services
uh the big difference is that now when
you can
just like you don't have to you don't
have to
ask for like a personal number right
like you can just pick
any of the any of the private keys out
there you just pick a random number
boom you have a key that can sign stuff
about like your identity
um and uh you can start your
your own thing um you can start like
interacting with the services
um and then it's like up to those
services what types of
authentication they require so if if all
they need is just like knowing that
that address um the private key was used
before a certain blog hash that's easy
if they want you to be like kyc by
another provider
the way the centralized identities uh
according to the did standard handle
this
handles this is that um
you spin out your own like self
sovereign thing which is your private
key or like set of keys
um then you go to kyc provider
you do the kyc ritual with them whatever
that means
in different contexts and they basically
issue a statement which says well this
set of private keys or like this
particle key
went through our process and with our
key we approved that it actually
happened and then it's again
on depending on the the service provider
it depends on them if they are
if they're if they decide to accept this
type of authentication
um so
this is obviously a lot of work um and
for
for your second identity for your alter
ego to be actually useful
um you you have to decide like which
types of services do you use with like
your
your own like new bootstrap uh social
brand identity in which you
uh which you associate with the one that
for instance like went through a kyc
um the one point which i figured to
mention is that
um none of these like interactions and
this is where the like the peer-to-peer
part comes in
needs to be public right like all of
these claims all of all of the
identification that happens between the
service provider and you and between
like these
parties like those can remain offline
like you don't you can decide
never to publish them unless unless you
want to use them
for authenticating with someone else
this doesn't
this doesn't need like any you know
anything being public and you can just
decide like
individually like what the rules should
be
so the hard problem is like keeping this
consistent because
it's it's like super easy i'm sure it
also happened to you just like
you want to keep one of your addresses
private but boom then you
like accidentally or not accidentally
just like need the money to transfer
somewhere else and boom you you
uh reveal like the entire track of your
like bitcoin transactions or like
whatever crypto are you using
so that's that's a hard problem um
i guess there is no solution for that uh
so if you if you are actually aware of
of these types of solutions that
services that kind of
take care of certain aspects of like
keeping your identity separate
um please share those um
i'm not sure how much time we have um
cool what i want to encourage you
is to like start your alter egos now uh
if you
if you have a way um
to um get yourself kyc then like
bunch of different names uh you should
do it as soon as possible because as you
could see
throughout the evolution of
authentication and
identities um in the beginning it was
quite easy to
just like have have two separate
identities right you could just have
different like jewelries you could have
like different types of documents but it
was getting increasingly harder to
to do that with those corporate
identification services and the fact
that those are being so popular that
you can even like use them to uh to
handle money
um you can still achieve it to some
extent but it will like tomorrow it will
get again a bit harder than today and
if you if you kind of
maintain consistent identities that
are for instance like utilizable in the
id standard
um to which we'll get a bit later
then even that set of data that identity
has
has value so if you if you like create
artificial identities that
uh which basically can be any set of you
know aspects it can be like having
multiple
gmail accounts maintaining like multiple
numbers
um kind of creating consistent track of
like
appearing to be somewhere else not being
you
that's valuable i'm quite certain that
uh
you could even like buy identities now
um
but i'm certain that in the future you
will actually have like a whole market
for trading your
set of keys that people used and like
reputation systems and
um you know use for certain services and
you'll be able to like
get someone else's name uh for a while
and then decide sell it as well
depending if it has any value to anybody
so
a lot of the identity stuff just to wrap
up is
connected to standardization because
like obviously like we cannot use an
identification service
um if if we are like the only person
using that then we are
back to where we were and especially in
the context of decentralized
uh identifiers um there is a
there is a big group of people working
on specifying and implementing
implementing the standard
uh there is like a lot of a lot of stuff
to read
on that note i definitely wouldn't go
through that um
there are even like implementations that
are completely unchained for instance on
ethereum the erc 720 to
uh 725 735 is basically
um a code implementation of what i was
just talking about like the
the standardization already happened to
some to some extent
and now depending on like the service
providers
having the willingness to start
utilizing these services
um and that's just a matter of adoption
right
the trends that are kind of obvious um
are utilization of zero knowledge proofs
and
like whatever is on chain when i go to
like the uh
the blockchain specific part um
and even more interesting is just
identification based on ownership and we
just like recently
uh had a quick chat about this this is
kind of like a digital re
introduction of out of authenticating
with a physical object
like jewelry uh like now again you can
you can own an nft like a non-fungible
token
which can which can be used for you to
be authenticated with a service
um but you can also decide to just like
sell this nft to someone else uh and now
whoever owns that
whoever holds that token is the king
[Music]
so as the last part a shameless plug of
some of the things connected to this
place in particle
um if you're interested in the
the very like technical specifics of uh
the ids
um i would definitely encourage you to
um to reach out to this group or
rebooting the web of trust
uh parallel nipples was lucky enough to
to host the
um the last workshop that happened
i don't know when some sometime last
year uh two other things that i wanted
to mention
citizen k is one of the uh one of the
art pieces by stovan
uh there is even like a documentary uh
which basically 10 years ago
deals with the topics that now are
getting implemented
the fact that you can uh create um
like a merch identity and just kind of
swap it as you as you go
uh so i definitely encourage you to um
look at that
and another thing which i found out
about during
hackers congress in like 2017 i don't
know
it's a documentary by dylan reibling
which is called looking for mike
uh and that part was kind of very
revealing for me it's like a 30-minute
documentary i think it's
available online that one is about his
friend
who who passed away and after it
happened
dylan actually found out that the person
wasn't the person who he said he was so
that guy was using a fake identity for
several years and created like a
whole new life story um and for me
the documentary was especially
interesting because it just like shows
you
how you really cannot trust people
because like you know
even if you knew them for you know six
years
um that was it thank you for coming to
the talk if you want to
chat about that later i'll be happy i
wasn't sure like how deep can we go but
we can even talk about
the erc implementations
does anyone have any questions
[Applause]
okay thank you josef so we have about
eight or nine minutes for
questions um i guess we can take some
from the room i saw one hand are you
okay all right
i was going to oppose your first point
that
isn't smell the first way to identify
other individuals even before our
vision was good enough to do it even
outside humans but that's another
question my question is
how do you think we can prevent identity
theft
in a world where the identity that you
use is no longer
connected to your physical uh
being things um
well um i mean there is like a
always a trade-off right
if we if we try to completely avoid like
identity theft
uh we'll probably go in in a way of like
trying to
strong in the connection between your
digital identity and your like physical
self right like having i don't know like
dna records
as claims connected to your to your
identity and again having like a
maintainer having like a
surveillance who who knows the truth um
so i'm not i'm not really sure like this
should be
like generally prevented because that
will also mean that the chance for
getting your second identity
is much lower um for me it's
it the core of the question is like um
you know are you are you cautious and
do you care about your privacy
to the extent that you're willing to
like handle your private keys yourself
because it ultimately goes down to
whoever has the signing right
to the information because that's where
we are heading
in my opinion so um
[Music]
if if you want to prevent like privacy
theft in
in that realm just store your private
key safely
uh but that's that's connected right i
was i was actually concerned about the
situation because like i
am one of those uh stupid human beings
that will definitely not be able to
remember all of my information that i
use to access various services
so i have the choice of either writing
down everything on
a paper which is extremely unofficial
and efficient
or exposing myself to the danger that
somebody will steal my
information so i am sure that
this way like if we if we uh
we will inevitably expose ourselves to
the danger of somebody stealing
every our online whole online personal
from us because
we do not have any way
of ensuring that it will be always
connected to us
yeah right um i guess that depends on
again on the like the way to like access
that information that you use for
logins i mean like now you use logins in
my opinion you're going to in several
years you're just going to use private
keys
even for logins uh because like you
don't really need logins
um so
i i mean in that way for me it goes down
to how you protect your private keys
because like i don't think the
identification as you know it now with
like email and password will stay here
for long
[Music]
yeah but i think i essentially think
this is the way i think like the
way is to uh you know get rid of like
the
the two-way identification system just
like leave it on
on a secure key that's um
that anyone can get you know um you
don't because like that login
information is still in the database of
the
of the identification service of the
service provider uh but i think we are
getting away from that
to like a you know like a leaner set of
keys that you can then use instead of
that type of login
it but yeah the thing is it can
and it doesn't have to you can you can
still
keep a lot of privacy um but you can you
can also distributed knowledge about
like how these keys are
connected it just depends on you like
what's the part that you're comfortable
with revealing
um and with having like even multiple of
those identities you can decide like
what needs to be connected what needs to
be you and what what
what's the set of data that can be your
alter ego
okay can we try one more question yeah
okay so if
if in the context of what three you only
need to sign uh
to provide a signature that you are
having a
key that you are the imposition of a key
what is this
erc
yeah is it doing this it's like yes
processing a signature or it has some
fancy special features
uh so those contracts are basically just
the standard interface that the apps can
then use
uh to utilize that as for like
authentication or for
passing over some of the data uh so it
basically the contract
is is a definition of like how do you
it's just a
it's just a formatting standard of like
how you store the information about the
the keys because you can you you start
with like one key right but you can by
uh by using that key to
for signing transactions toward if if
that's in the case of a contract
for signing transactions towards the
contract you can like add multiple
keys that you can you know you don't
even have to reveal those you can just
like publish hashes of those keys just
so you can then
if someone asks you you know you want to
identificate and you send them like a
bucket
bucket with data saying hey this is a
this is that
authentication service telling it's me
it's like i possess like this
set of parameters so you can
authenticate me because that's what the
service requires
how do they know how do they know like
it actually originates
with from like one point or it's
associated with whatever you're like
sending them right now like whichever
key you're using so there is this like
um list of like public keys that you i
mean the same way you publish your
a pgp fingerprint to an attacher right
uh you can just like have multiple of
those and say
well that's me i'm signing it with this
key uh have a look
there like to blockchain for instance uh
to verify that it's actually me and this
can happen
off-chain right this just happens like
peer-to-peer and they can
have a look into like a central database
in this case
uh to verify what the association that
you're telling them there
it exists actually exists okay
thank you okay i think that might be it
for q a
right we
okay we have one on the stream
okay do i okay i'm gonna read this all
right
okay uh is there a way to use an alter
ego in a kyc
request i assume as some sort of
authentication with kyc
yeah uh that that's a good question i
would like to
know where it's possible the easiest i
think like for instance
as i mentioned as i mentioned the
citizen k
document that's where you kind of can
see that it in some ways it's possible
and um you know like still a lot of the
stuff that we
that we deal with on a daily basis is
just based on like different
different nations these different states
having like certain contracts and
certain types of acceptances between
themselves
so for instance uh and like these days
for effective area reasons um the things
like eides are basically trying to
like reutilize your kyc for like
different purposes
so once you find once you find like your
heck into the system
uh then um you could probably achieve
like having like a good
second track with strong kyc like
it's not the best example but um
i believe like in the us uh if you
uh you can you can just be kyc like by
one bank in order to get
um uh to get an account win another one
so you can either go through like the
kyc that the bank provides or you can
tell them hey there is already another
subject that already did that
and through that appeal uh you will
basically be considered
fine for them uh so whenever you find
like
the the weakest uh part of the chain
that's where you can enter
uh and this doesn't have to be like this
doesn't have to be in one state right
again we can probably go to
um i don't know where and gets uh
get a passport uh um
and use that to somehow like bootstrap
that alter ego
so i'm i don't know like what the one
way would be i wouldn't definitely
say it uh even if i knew
okay i think that's it then for q a okay
thank you very much jose