[Applause]
so
today uh when you opened the news in the
morning
you could see the big titles how the
elections that happened
yesterday and the day before
uh finally uh happened what were the
results
so again in czech republic we
went through this ritual of uh regular
elections so people went to vote
and uh when we will talk about
police i think it's interesting to stop
at this point because czech meaning of
the term to vote means halasovat
or dadlas to give a vote
has very interesting etymology because
when you strictly translate the term
alas it's not a vote it's a voice
so when you when you vote in check it
means you give a voice
when you give a voice you give up your
own voice
you hand it over to someone else and he
got the voice and he can tell you shut
up i have the voice no
so what we are going to talk about is
different way a
different attitude you can take other
than
giving up your voice not to
give up your voice not to vote for
usually we say smaller evil but
there is possibly another another way
but we are here to talk about the
concept parapolis and
where it comes from and uh
i have to say a little story behind most
of you probably heard about it
but for those who didn't this space
was originally inspired by a slovak
hackerspace progress bar
and progress bar uh was a little bit
different hackerspace than others
because it was not primarily um
geek club where you just bustled and
worked with
with technologies and so on but they
were very much focused on
um lectures and education
and gatherings which we liked a lot
that they didn't only close up to to
small community but they also promoted
they also promoted uh some new
technologies crypto technologies and so
on
so we wanted to have something similar
in pla in prague
and we were searching for a format a
space some venue for it
and of course a name and when we have
found this house
we realize that we can be something
more something wider than just the
hackerspace
it can create a space that will serve to
public to
to get simply knowledge ideas
inspiration whatever
whatever else and then i uh one evening
when we were setting up this this
premise and we were
preparing the first hackers congress six
six years ago
we uh i talked to
my friend who studied political sciences
and i was describing him
what we aim to do here i just i i told
him about
bitcoin and liberating technologies and
encryption and creating some unique
special and separate sphere of
relationships beside uh
beside the state an official one and he
told me
the the thing you are calling that are
you talking about
uh bender called federal police
uh it's the same thing you want to do i
said
i've never heard about it but i will
write it down because it sounds really
cool so we started to
we we took this word these two words
and we started to study what's behind
and we realized that
we know all the context but this small
word the particular phase
parallel police remained just in in
some texts uh from from the past from
communist regime from
70s as you will see and
it it remained partially forgotten so
pearl police
until 214 wasn't some hyped
war that everybody knows but exactly the
opposite
like only a few historians and few
political scientists
knew the word the term pearl police so
we realized so we
decided to take it up and give it
a new life
as we were diving into into the term
um it was interesting interesting and
important
to understand uh where where the term
comes from
and especially for those of you who are
not into
mid-europe history
it's very important to understand at
least the very basics
how the environment and the era
where the polish comes from looked like
and how it developed
so we are we are in deep 70s
when we talk about police and
at this time you can see it was uh it
was deep communism
here which started in 1948
with very brutal uh change
uh which was very very unexpected and it
was big lesson because after the second
world war
everybody thought that this animal
stuff and terror and brutals that
happened during the second world war
will not happen again and huh 48 and 49
and it was here again
in in a very very sharp way
the communists achieved during one or
two years
to to spread the fear and and orders
so effectively that that
[Music]
they they simply smashed all opposition
or
or other voices and and
established really tough uh totalitarian
regime
then in 58 you probably know about
khrushchev and his critics of stalinism
and so on so
so the situation stabilized a little bit
and
and the environment became a little
little bit more
liberal and breathable
then a very important uh part was the
prague spring
67 and 68 which was an era
of very high level of liberty
and very optimistic social atmosphere
then especially art literature
but also many other professions could
suddenly express themselves much freer
than it was
used before and
to this situation without any warning
in 68 there was this direct
invasion of ussr armies you probably
know
about which which
was like a punch from the soviet union
that nobody expected
and to this peaceful and liberal
environment suddenly
came the soviet tanks and started to
uh started to shout to
public buildings like national museum
and so on so
for for the witnesses uh as i was
interviewing
uh during uh during my program uh police
101 uh zero oh
that was exactly about this era
they told me that they were totally
shocked
by what was happening even though they
already had the experience of the
communist region before
then from the 1968 and 80s
after the occupation there came
so-called
normalization it was very tough wave
of uh totalitarian practices
which we will be going to talk about and
in 80s
there started some stagnation the regime
started to be more in defense than in
orphans
and the structure started to
simply disintegrate and uh
and uh um and so on
so when we talk about parallel policy
and when it
happened so we talk about this era this
70s
after the ussr army occupation
so we call this era normalization so
what what what happened in 68
the tanks cam the the armies and
after that there were a couple of
individual
uh acts of protest one of the most
famous is a self-burning of jan palach
and his followers which was very strong
act of protest but
uh but the regime succeed in spreading
fear and
and simply discouraged
the opposition to uh act somehow
in a unified way and and in some
structured way
so only very few individual activities
of some protest this and and so on
remained
one of them was so-called and one of the
most powerful in
czechoslovakia was so-called second
culture which was represented mostly by
fall underground and other
musicians and then some theaters and so
on you probably know
story of what's la favel etc so you can
you can see
uh then uh lots of
uh intellectual elites were fired from
universities
and scientological uh
works workplaces and so on and
they lose their job lost their job and
had to find something else to do usually
it was
some uh workers uh
like second class kind of the work like
manual work and so on
and the only way they could continue
their work was to
to go to underground so they started to
create so-called
apartment universities and small groups
where they
continued with teaching
and doing publication activities and so
on
well what's also interesting is uh
that very important role played the
christians christians groups and and
churches
which is not frequently mentioned and
then in uh 1977
the the one of the most significant acts
of
of resistance was so-called chart of 77
which was a like um
part or or some result of growing
influence of
of different small movements and
individuals
who started to be more and more
discomfort but also encouraged
due to the regime practices
so what is interesting and important
also is to see that
uh the the czechoslovak context
is very different from other soviet
uh countries even in the european bloc
so when you when you search for other
dissident movements in other countries
you see a very different strategies that
have been taken
one of the most powerful
this is a movement was uh was
was established in poland uh
where in 80s
lekh walesa and his fellows kind of
hacked
the system in a very interesting way
because what they did was not any
unofficial movement
but they they found in the
constitution that workers had have a
right
to create unions unions of workers
and these these unions have a
right to to partial independence
and sovereignty and self-governance so
they claimed
uh they claimed this these rights and as
they were
workers movement which was the basic
vehicle for for for socialism
they they kind of hacked the system
because
they achieved uh that the government and
the and the kurds
had to admit that they have this right
and they they have this sovereignty and
then
they can continue to work and in
1981 they already had 10 million
10 million subscribers because as it was
workers union they could suddenly spread
around poland
in many different cities and and
whatever whatever kind of organizations
that had
more workers and uh and
that's why they were in a mass way very
very successful and
very influential in hungary
when i take another uh example uh
the the opposition or or the protest
movement were more like
relevant political opposition they they
were more like reformists
who wanted to discuss with the system
and
and push to change to change the system
so it was more like political
way of of changing things
another example is uh for slovakia
where where the dissident movements
were very small like in comparison
especially to poland but
even with with uh czech republic but
they
they had different nature for example
environmental
uh protecting groups or or churches
or or individuals
um who who operated
in in different spots in slovakia so
so we have to understand that that
the context of these parallel policies
if we
if you use a very wide term
differed country to country and culture
to culture let's say
but now we are going to talk about
charter 77 because
there is a direct link between the term
para police and charter 77
that i will uh explain you to you
so uh what what was charge 77
it was basically a petition
of of so-called civil society
that just wanted uh an
appeal to government to keep the rules
that they
they accepted via international treaties
that
that that contain
norms related to human rights
it was signed in helsinki in 70s
but immediately the regime started to
like interrupt and not to not to keep
the rules
so so charity 77 was an appeal
that wanted to be legal and
direct dialogue with the government
and applied to appeal to
to comply with their human rights
rules here you can see some
some quotes so you see the narrative and
and examples of the text
so it was it was really like
um from from from our perspective it was
nothing nothing very uh
aggressive because they just asked to
keep
the rules the state already accepted
but in this time it was
really very uh very brave act
which which the regime
took really really really bad
uh how how the charter 77
worked so it was a text elaborated by
a collective of authors that wanted to
remain
uh anonymous but one of
one of them were over was also vastly
bender and others other other important
names
of the czech dissident movement
they they insist on remaining
unpolitical in
in terms that uh charter 77
unified different professions different
uh
political uh
thinking different different currents
of thought and so on so
so they wanted to unify all the streams
of
of uh protests and and opposition
movements
uh together uh
they didn't achieve that much uh mass
influence finally
it had like one one one thousand two
hundred
signers uh until the end of communism
so it remained a very small uh very
small initiative
but the reaction of the regime shows
that it was
it was like a hit to the black uh middle
point
because uh because the the regime react
really really um you know in a strong
way
so all the protagonists afterwards were
were
uh quite brutally chased and
interrogated
and and still under uh
still under surveillance criminalized
lots of them uh remained or ended up in
in jail finally um so what was the
reaction uh vaslav bender describes uh
the ways of reaction
uh in in a in a small article
from uh 1968 where he summarized that
a very interesting uh point
and it was that the the regime had set
of strategies
that they repeatedly uh changed they
they
they still use the same they only
changed that this time we're gonna
create some anti-campaign one of
examples is so-called anti-charter
which was a text that was refusing uh
the charter 77
requirements and and appeals
and they they uh asked all the
uh czechoslovak elite uh especially
artists and
and uh teachers from professors and so
on and so on to
to uh to sign it
so so they they've created a very strong
uh media pressure based on uh defamation
you could read that the charter 77s
representants were were like junkies who
who took drugs and poisoned wells
and were funded by by imperialists from
us
and so on and so on so really really
like
so if we if we talk about fake news
today it was nothing
in comparison to fake news generated by
by the communist regime
at this time another another way was
bureaucratic prosecution so whatever you
wanted to do
and you needed some approval for it you
didn't get it
you couldn't travel you couldn't study
you couldn't whatever
you were still in some clash with
administration
another another way was police
repression
so everybody from the movement knew that
they have
their own police officer they knew that
the the power tries to persuade other
people
to cooperate with them and became agents
so they knew that
there are probably are infiltrated
agents among them
and they will they were totally without
any reasoning
suddenly arrested interrogated for a
couple of hours and then
they let them go and and they did it
repeatedly all the time so you never
knew
if you come back home or not uh any day
another another way was that they
created criminal trials usually
construct
from constructed uh reasons and
background
and uh then they imprisoned
the the actors uh
based on these these constructed
accusations
and in general they they spread fear
and intimidation
so this is how they reacted and
now we're gonna come to the
parapolis term where it comes from so
the author
uh of the term is watson bender
who was a politician he lived here in
prague
i i sat at a table where the charter 77
was written
his wife is kamela benduva is still
alive so
we interviewed her a couple of times and
it was really interesting to see because
at their family table a very part very
big part of
czech history happened and one of one of
them was
that the charter 77 was written there
so so he was kind of a key person
in the movement he was mathematician and
philosopher
and all his interest can be covered with
this triangle if you use the parapolis
symbolics which was catholicism politics
and philosophy so these were three
top topics of vassal bender
which tells you that he was a deeply
believing
catholic uh who who
uh always imprinted his uh christianity
to his texts
with philosophy and so on
and uh what what bender openly was
was also he wanted to be the kind of a
kind of a leader of the movement um
uh he also hoped that if the regime
fails fails one day which he
really believed in uh and there was not
many
there were not many people who really
believed that the the regime will fail
but
he was one of them and he hoped that he
will be
the vats love but but not the havel who
finally become
became the political leader but he
wanted to be the boss of harold
which he finally didn't
didn't become and one of the reason
probably is that
uh in country where is the highest trait
of non-believers uh uh and a taste
it's it's uh quite difficult to become a
leader
with with a catholic program
so now where
how it happened um vassal bender
in 1978 started to realize that
uh behind charter 77 movement there are
some patterns
uh of the behavior of the movement that
show us some some
interesting phenomena and the phenomena
is that
uh as as a
as an act of uh self
protection and survival in the
in the environment of the oppression
they had to start
to behave in a different way and take
different
tactics and uh vassal bender
was describing the tactics the
strategies
and he covered those strategies with the
name of pearl police
so what is pearl police according to
bender
is a set of strategies that the movement
take
took to protect against the uh against
the totality
and uh to to create
an environment that is not in clash in
direct clash with the
government but uh creates
our its own uh social structures that
work
beside the official one and
uh it's also interesting to see uh
the two words to take a look at them so
first
police what does it mean because uh
very frequently people think like polly
is like
like the the state police so you're
joking of fritz
or or what no it's it's a police
in the old uh greek ter the old greek
term
that refers to uh
ancient police so-called city-state is
the
like most frequent uh term you you
you realized but uh but
of course the police also developed it
uh
it appeared around 800 before christ
uh as as the population of greece grew
uh so uh there started to
appear more and more police uh
these city-states which created some
basic organizational structure of the
society
so police is basically a
basic social structure we we might say
also community
so the basic unit of of the of the
society uh what is also important there
is is the
is the personal identification with the
police so i am the part of the police
where
in the greek times originally there were
tribes
but but what happened was that
with the with the rise of police uh the
tribe system
uh was changed into the identification
with the
with the police more than with the
tribes
and uh what was the primary
uh visible character of police was that
every police has had its own army its
own laws
and its own set of gods
then the word parallel was also also
interesting to take a look at the
etymology
because very frequently people think
that it's something alternative
something something derived from
uh from the main thing so we we take the
official main thing and we just create
some fork of it or so
but parallel uh doesn't mean
alternative it means
it's also from greek is a para means
alongside something
something something out of i would say
in aleos uh
is one another so so we see the differ
the total differentiate the
likes of the subjects so it's always
something totally
separate um
it's also interesting to see other other
definitions of parallel which is never
meeting however far
extended but have the same direction
so this is this is uh the term parallel
police
and when we come back to what's left
bender
so what what were the main pillars or
the principles of parapolis according to
so the basically what it is
is creating of autonomous
social and other structures that
are independent and beside
work beside official regime or other
authorities
he also named some um
some parts of or some pillars of the
parallel polish that
that were uh characteristic for the
charter 77 movement one of the
one of the most important word the
plural education
then of course parallel economy parallel
culture
the second culture
[Music]
then it was the principle of active
civil rights protection
they had their own information system
called samisdat which was like uh
organically
uh or we could say peer-to-peer
uh spreading of uh publications
and and other information and
they claims to have several
international relationships
uh also uh foreign policy we might say
uh so these were these were those that
were characteristic for charter 77
but what is important and and uh bender
bender expressed this as it in the essay
is that
these are only some examples and
there is not any limit or or some rule
why propolis couldn't do
many other other things and operate on
other fields
so it's usually it's always depends on
the
circumstances environment era culture
and so on what uh
what the parapolis in this exact
condition is
is if you remember the
the examples from other countries
so the pearl police in hungary in
hungary
was totally different of parapolis in
czechoslovakia it was totally different
to
paropolis in sloven in poland sorry
and later as the the term was discussed
within the dissident movement
uh the other authors like vaslav havel
shimechi and others uh elaborated
some some idea what is the goal of
parallel police
because otherwise it was just an
description of
of strategy like for example crypto
anarchy is
but the the the arc articulated goal of
prior police which is independent
society
and it sounds very general so what does
it mean and i
i love the most the vassal of other
definition
which is very idealistic but it says
that
independent society means that wherever
the civil society can organize itself
this the state should make the step back
like okay you are able to organize by
yourself
i give up my rules and my authority and
leave it up to you so the ideal state
co-living with pearl police would always
make the step back
when the self-organization is able to
govern
our own things without the state
authority
so now maybe it's a good question to us
so what can be
palace is it only the house in holla
chavitsa
or in vienna or in bratislava as it used
to be
or what what can be what all can be
parapolis
and not long time ago we had a very
interesting
interview with smuggler and frank brown
on their podcast with stream
cyberpunk and
we discussed there that parapolis
probably is just some
expression of something that is
deeply in our human gene in our human
nature
because when we apply the principles of
parallel police back to the
historical historical effects
we can see that in in history many times
uh wherever whenever the state power
grew too much there were created some
kind of parastructures and that's why i
placed here this image that i really
like
um it's it's uh it's an image from the
asian rome
this this uh up on the ground
it is the rome empire and the and the
governance
by the roman empire and here under the
ground
are the catacombs uh that
that you can visit especially in rome uh
which were occupied by the first
christians
after uh after the um
bc simply
and as you probably remember from
history
the first christians during the first
three centuries
after christ were illegal and chased and
haunted by the by the rome
imperial power so they had to operate
totally illegally and their strategy was
that they
dick into the ground and created under
like truly underground uh cities
or catacombs it's it's it's called
so even even back in history to 2000
years ago we can see some expressions of
of need in this case to to freely
express my
religious preferences
and it can of course also be
uh something that will happen in future
i i chose an example of
uh of parapolis 3-0 which is a concept
described by yuray badnar who is having
parallel talk right now
and i recommend to read it if you
haven't
it's on the website of slovak police
parallel now police.sk
and it's it's an idea how a parapolis
concept could develop for future not to
be dependent on
physical space physical premises so
he proposes kind of a fluid structure
which anyways uh anyway is happening as
as
other parapolis and in different forms
are growing
uh not only in czech republic
so uh this this is uh this is some final
thought that i would like to propose and
uh i would like you to think about
uh and learn from history because
maybe some form of parapolis is some
kind of anthropological constant
something that is common for
all humans all human beings and we can
see
throughout history that that uh some
forms of parapolis happen
and we can learn from the strategies we
can see
uh even now in the world when we when we
take a look to different regimes that
that things are happening there when you
take a look to north korea you can see
that
there are youth smuggling
into this north korea
culture especially from south korea but
from from other countries as well and
even though the region did a really
really good job
in brainwashing the people they didn't
succeed
some some some basic need
for freedom remained even in this north
korean
regime and some versions of parapolis we
probably don't know about
now are happening there as well
so it's my call to
to study history and search for parallel
policies
and principles and inspiration for this
so i would like to end up with this
with what what i've uh what i've started
with
and it's the moment when uh i was
talking to my friend
about crypto technologies bitcoin
decentralization and so on and he as
political think political scientists
realized the connection
some some relation to the to the
historical
point from seventies to pearl polish the
concept
uh and and he proposed that and for me
this is very interesting
moment because it connects some
some very small piece of our history
with uh something that is happening now
and which was the very grain and seat
of this concept we are participating on
now
so thank you very much for your
attention thank you very much
[Applause]
do we have any questions raise your hand
please
could you please tell a bit more about
the future
the visions for parallel police
sorry that's a very good question uh
because recently police is going through
very dramatic changes you probably saw
that slovak parapolis has closed down
it was not feasible to to keep
the premise they they found
uh bratislava slovakia uh
there was pro police for two years or
three years
um another parallel police was
established last year in vienna
operates totally independently in a very
nice way
and there are other groups uh like in
kosciutz
and other places they
somehow want to uh
deal with this what what we've done here
and
continue with it and follow it up but
even even this this project this this
like first
police i would call it uh goes through
changes
uh which which are organizational which
are
related of course to to uh
needs to create different model
different business model for
for operations such of such a big house
and there is also this concept of
parapolis 3-0
like a new new version that wouldn't be
that much bind to to physical premises
to some like institution in the physical
way
but uh could could provide us
some tools to to uh
to cooperate and and work together in
another way
which i think is very important for
future because what is happening in the
world now and it's the topic of this
congress
is that
accidentally the situation can get much
worse
and even keeping the physical space
might be too big obstacle due to some
operation repression whatever
from the site of the state and
we have to be ready for a moment when we
won't have won't be able to operate a
physical space
charter 77 also didn't have their own
coffee and co-working
and and so on because it wouldn't be
possible
simply and we have to get ready for
for a moment when when it won't be
possible to operate
in this nice way anymore and i think the
concept purpose 3o is exactly the
the way the direction
uh that that is interesting to to take
to talk about
have you thought about um trying to
reach some billionaire
um like some some billionaire
um billionaire yeah like peter thiel
and and um or some foundation i mean
which
could theoretically i mean more easily
add funds and i think these principles
are set from the very beginning
uh very clearly there are different
kinds of memberships in parapolis uh and
one of them
is so-called board of donors the highest
uh way of of
of member members or not highest but the
most generous i would say and
these people pay a quite significant
amount
per month i think it's like 700
euros 600 euros something like this per
month
but the point is that nobody can pay
more they
they have like uh strictly done
uh set up the the fee the the membership
fee they pay
so uh which we should protect the
organization from one general partner
who will donate us lots of money one
year
so so the organization starts to operate
with different budget
and another year he can say ah if you
don't do this
thing that i like i will stop my funding
which can be fatal for the organization
so so that's the principle how we
reach the money of let's say more
wealthy people
but but
of course it's living organism and
things can change
in future i don't exclude it
yeah sorry there's another question so
we can get back to you
if there are any other
so at this moment would you say that
parallel new police community is
more has more of a physical presence
or online presence if you should compare
it
it definitely was more about physical
presence
and i think that during the last year it
takes
a serious important lesson
that being depended on the physical
presence only is not the good way so i
think now this congress
is exactly good good example how
how the things evolve how do you think
evolves and
uh um and i i can't imagine that
that it would come back uh to physical
premises only
presence uh i think the the online would
be more and more important of course
the other questions
just to add on the idea i mentioned
before about the
billionaires because i think that
there are many people some people or
many many people in the
in the crypto space which um made a lot
of money
with rising crypto prices some didn't
i mean some even had losses because of
unfortunate things like mt gox and
etc um but
i recently saw some article also that
the number of
of bitcoin uh billionaires is or um
multi-millionaires is like again rising
very much and
so um maybe
we have through networking we can reach
to such people and maybe if um
for one time because of corona also um
you could set a clear rule like okay
this time we will accept
larger donations um but um
with absolutely no interference of
course
in the operations because
um i think that at least a part of these
um very rich people now um
they um if we um
made them become very aware that
they only did
get this money because of satoshi and
and all the others
who contributed um then
i think this is such a great place and
um
such many good great things come out of
here so that uh
um this is very nice to hear of course
uh donations are always nice
but what's what is much more valuable
and sustainable is uh when the when the
organization is able to create the
fundings itself
so so i think this this should be still
the main focus
how to be totally independent on the
nations and then the nations can be
nice to have uh edon or
or some network that that
protects you from total fall in case of
some critical situations uh then
some donator who helps not to fall to
the ground
can be of course uh important and
in other player policies in history of
course
it was uh very very important as well
uh the the frequently uh
uh frequently uh quoted
soros the this this big uh
donor one of the biggest in the world uh
also supported
charter 77 uh in the 70s and 80s so
so yeah we can see lots of pearls
with history as well but not not for our
policy he didn't fund purpose
as far as i know there's
one more question last question i
appreciate
um this year there's the the
online version and the physical version
and also in previous years i'm sure you
recorded a lot of the
the content so now it's kind of it's not
just like a physical thing because it's
um people are experiencing in real time
anywhere and we just spoke about
like a sustainable way of surviving like
in a material sense
what's your plan or
vision for you know this content or the
stuff that's being generated
um like does does that relate in some
way to um
to sustainable way of like for example
you could have like a library of content
that you pay to access or
like there's this um now that you have
the
the valuable stuff in in in this form
and and you're open to uh you know
opening it to the world you don't have
to be here like how how do these two
relate or do they relate
in your vision i'm not the person in
charge
for this uh i i
am since since may i'm not member of of
the
of the leadership of this organization
uh
so it's not in my hands anymore but
uh as far as i know the slovak
model will be followed so slovak
parallel police create
a paid zone for for
courses and and lectures and so on that
happened in pearl police physically
so you you cannot access all the content
for free
but there is some paid zone and i think
this makes sense
because it worked pretty well uh
in slovakia uh so so i think this
this should be followed um
as well and the ex and the user
experience with the hop-in with the tool
for the for the
for this congress is quite nice i'm
positively surprised
how nice it works so i i think that's
that's exactly the way how to do stuff
[Music]
[Applause]