Brian Baier co-founder and CEO of red
Canary here to talk about building an
atomic testing program Brian Leeds red
Canary to bring world class monitoring
detection and response to every business
prior to co-founding red canary Brian
incubated cybersecurity products at
Kairos innovated big data processing
solutions for the intelligence community
at Northrop Grumman
and start his career in cyber security
at man Tech's computer forensics and
intrusion analysis group please welcome
Brian Baier all right I have the dubious
honor of standing in between you and
drinks but here's the good news if
you've heard about atomic red team today
and are wondering what that is this is
your crash course before we get down to
drinks and maybe talk about it more all
right so to dive in we're gonna talk
about what it means to build an atomic
testing program so what is this atomic
testing that we speak of to start with
think atoms the basic unit of any
chemical element not blowing up your
security program not that type of atomic
our battery is running low noted I'll
move faster can you click the most if
you get a second please all right
so atomic test has two traits the first
trait is that they are small think that
that test is mapped to a single atomic
technique or a single attack technique
and not more than that
the second trait it has is that they're
very easy to execute we want this to be
something that anyone can very quickly
pull up execute on their systems and see
the results this is what an atomic test
looks like we have a name we have a
description we have an annotation that
says what platforms they run on and as
well as the actual commands that you
would copy and paste into your command
prompt so the point of this again is
wanted to be simple to very quickly go
from an attack technique to the actual
code you would run in order to exercise
that test without needing complicated
frameworks coordination with your red
team
want to make it simple so why would we
do this there's a couple key beliefs
that we had the first of them is that we
believe that testing your coverage is
one of the most important things you can
do to continually move your security
program forward right now in a lot of
security programs it's something that's
done only when an external third party
comes in and does your quarterly or
annual pen test now in this room we've
got a lot of really smart teams we've
got a lot of great red teams in here for
some organizations it's a test that's
done only when the red team shows up and
runs a new campaign what we believe is
that the best way for security programs
to evolve is to be able to run tests
like this not just quarterly or monthly
or weekly but even be able to do it
continuously now one of the best ways
you can do that is this testing has to
be fast and easy and if you do all of
that there's this greater part of
knowledge which I think we can all thank
attack for is that defenders have to
keep understanding how adversaries are
operating as wild as it may sound it's
just as important for blue teams today
to understand how conflict works from
2008 as the equation group from several
years ago both of those techniques are
very much mapped to attack and very much
still used in the wild today so this is
something I found this weekend that I
thought was an awesome suggestion comes
from Tim Mel converter out at Walmart as
well as Tim McGee of this suggestion of
how do you actually start testing
against attack and their original idea
was well why don't we just roll the dice
a roll a big wheel end up with two to
three techniques and have that start to
become the adversary you're emulating
and so for the last couple minutes we
have here we're gonna walk through that
here's our giant attack matrix we're
going to pick one get your bingo cards
ready it's not processed doppelganger
instead squiggly-doo this is what we
have a red canary call it Casey special
it's the nightmare thing that shows up
on Twitter that you have to figure out
what it actually does all right so
probably very useful
and so what do we do now if you're like
me the first time that shows up you have
no idea how to actually run this test
yourself when it first showed up I
didn't know what commands that I would
go run or if I was on a blue team to
simulate that behavior and that's the
point of atomic red team so to be clear
atomic red team is nothing that we sell
it's an open source community many of
you have contributed tests to it and
been a part of that community you are
awesome and what atomic red team does is
it's a github repository that has in it
a definition and a set of tests that
lets you actually run these exact things
yourself so you can jump to the github
repository say I'm looking for T 1 1 1 7
you can see the information sucked in
from the brand new attack website which
I think went live today this runs from
the same sticks behind it and then you
can see what tests are out there so you
can see in this case with squiggly-doo
we have three different tests we have
register of 32 running from local com
remote com local DLL and then all of the
steps you would take to run it yourself
and so some ideas of how you can use
this things we've seen teams use that
really helped us become ingrained in
their culture 1 make yourself a
recurring calendar invite set something
up for every week that just says go roll
the dice pick a new technique and run
that test and then see if your blue team
calls you second the whole point of a
lot of this is understanding what your
gaps are like some of the priests of
presentations talked about earlier it's
less about pass or fail it's more about
knowing what you do and don't have
visibility into and then one of the big
drivers behind all of this is use this
information to both hold your team and
yourselves accountable but also your
vendors so finally to end on a little
bit of fun they had such a good idea of
rolling the dice that we actually
shipped that onto the atomic red team
website this weekend so if you want to
roll the dice go on there click the
button it randomly selects a tactic
technique and test copy paste and run it
on your system and pop some calc so
final thing I want to end
would love to know show of hands how
many of you have run atomic tests from
atomic regime awesome how many of you
have contributed to it alright we got
maybe just davier is the whitter perfect
so the one thing I want to end on is
atomic red team and miter and everything
you guys have done only works because of
the community here want to say huge
thank you from myself from Casey from
Mike everybody who's worked on this you
guys support what you've done with
attack what you've done to support all
this this only works because of the
community it's awesome to see it all
come together so the thing I'd love you
to do come contribute additional tests
to atomic red team tell other blue teams
and red teams so they can use it as well
and let's keep moving security forward
thank you well thank you we have plenty
of time for questions so do any
questions it for the win it's going in
question aren't you Scott the answer is
atomic red team is one year old that's
how long it's taken yeah how long did
that yes if the question Brian is great
talk the question is tell us a little
bit how complete you'd say atomic red
team is like what what kind of
percentage coverage do you have and how
do you feel about that right and how do
you feel what confidence self do you
have that kind of you know gets better
or maintains over time I think from the
last numbers I've seen it's somewhere
around 40 to 50 percent of the attack
techniques have a test behind them some
of them you know if I think about the
theoretical max is probably going to be
in the 70 to 80 percent range because a
lot of the attack techniques start to
get a little more esoteric and I don't
know how you'd write an atomic test for
a supply chain introduction maybe email
Bloomberg maybe that's just it I'm not
really sure Wow
there will be there will be a limit of
what we can get to confidence level I'd
say overall is very much
we need continued support from the
community to flesh them out more all
right there's a lot of techniques who
only have one or two tests behind them
and there are a lot of variations of
techniques and procedures that the
attack team has been working on that
would really help fill in a lot of those
gaps we had another question any other
questions so I had one while people are
thinking so for your car do you have a
navigator layer that shows what tests
are covered or not we don't yet we're
going to all right okay good sounds like
a good hackathon project every time
someone uses the Navigator an angel gets
their wings all right or any other
questions yep right there so just in the
coverage that you were talking about I
know this is you know a lot of this
tagger tool they really focus on the
same installation or the middle part of
the chain where the attackers on the box
is using existing tools but finally too
so they can emulate things like
privilege escalation or a full browser
exploit or you know Sembach summation
deter things are a little bit more like
a high bar but we showing attacker
that's almost really rare a bit so this
mean that basically it's a lot of the
tools or I mean the writing tools or
these type of attacks are much more hard
to find so the cost is higher this means
a busy no they are more expensive I
think there's there's probably a couple
different things that feed into why
certain squares may be filled in more
than others one of them is going to be
based on prevalence of what we see in
the wild so some of the history of
atomic red team was that we wanted to
help you know potential teams evaluating
products like red canary or other EDR
vendors we wanted help them better
evaluate like an adversary actually
works not just download ten samples from
virustotal and see what happens and so
the initial set of tests very much skews
toward what we see in the wild
the other part of it is you know as we
continue to grow and build it will
definitely favor easier techniques to
test and implement and a lot of the
execution based tests are a lot simpler
to simulate than something that may
require a full payload to be built
compiled tested cross-platform
that might do things like sandbox
evasion so it's one of those things
where I expect that the first squares
that get filled in are the simpler ones
and the ones that get filled in later
tend to be harder so if you have
expertise in that looking forward to
seeing your pull request yes machine
zina day's story yes please more zero
days thanks any other questions for
Brian here we go
just hey are you are you aware that some
people are actually detecting the usage
of a framework so like detecting polls
from your github repository and things
like that like what can be done for
everyone to raise the scrutiny whether
or not people are actually properly
detecting Mac techniques versus a
detecting atomic frameworks so you're
asking how would we make it easier yeah
aside from people just cloning the repo
or hosting the script somewhere else
which then you know aren't gonna flag on
those same detection that's that's the
best way to do it I mean what one of the
things we've tried to be careful of is
making it clear that what sits up in
that repository is something that you
should be able to know hey that's where
I'm actually getting my tests from and
so we do a lot to make sure that you
can't try and hide that and make it
simple that if you do want to detect
things coming from atomic red team you
can right in my opinion that's something
a blue team should be able to cheat if
they want to and say I'm gonna pick up
everything who comes in from atomic red
team but if you want to use it in a case
where you know someone might be cheating
against you
absolutely clone the repo yourself keep
it local use interesting execution
frameworks in order to muddle around
with some of the command line parameters
all of those are great ways to skip past
the cheaters yep
cool any other questions for Brian if
not please join me in thanking them
thank you
you