so I'm Adam Pennington part of the TAC
team and also coordinating bingo and
lightning talks so I wanted to start off
technical session this morning with
something to try to get people's blood
pumping a little bit
we put out a call just a couple weeks
ago for people to give us pithy short
five minutes zero to three slide talks
that we're on either you know
work-in-progress you know something that
was half-baked we even told people they
could give us a five minute rant on
everything we were doing wrong with
attack but no one took us up on it so
what we have instead our talks would be
seeing in a few minutes we're gonna run
these back to back so no time for
questions all the speakers are actually
attendees at the conference though so
plenty opportunity to catch them as
they're out and about yet they handle
Mike Rinder you go and so without
further ado I'm gonna have our most
interesting interpretation of zero to
three slides Paul Ewing and Ross wolf of
endgame hey how's everybody doing we we
did have a very different interpretation
so we try to convert a video into slides
so you guys better be ready for a
montage of slide where okay so I'm Paul
this is Ross we're gonna give you a a
practical guide of taking an attack
technique and then actually try to
parlay that into a detection so at
endgame we're no different than the
theme of the conference so far if you
can incorporate attack you're really
going to transform the way you do the
way you do things but the thing to keep
in mind is it's not as trivial as you
may think to take a technique and turn
that into a detection in fact we made
this kind of fun almost graph to show
what it's like to groom a detection so I
mean I like to think of this as an
example where say you're looking for a
schedule tasks turns out you have a
group policy script that's a scheduled
task okay times of false positives and
then you start finding some applications
in your environment that cause more
false positives then you looked you
fine-tune your role too much and you do
too many things you miss out
stuff and eventually if you get to a
point where you could profit so we're
gonna walk through some of this right
now cool so let's say you've done some
gap analysis and you've decided all
right the next technique I want detect
is bypass UAC so yeah this counts for
bingo I think so you pick your tech and
you could go to attack this is I guess
attack - old miner org and and you might
read up on it realize ok bypass UEC
actually has a lot of flavors a lot of
different ways you can do it so maybe
you google you look around you pick one
and you see that okay well I actually
want to detonate this technique since I
want detect I want to know what it looks
like and there's this blog post I found
that just has to run these two commands
in a nun all evaded shell and it will
give you an elevated shell so the top
you see that on an elevated shell the
two commands I pasted and then it
successfully ran the task and then at
the bottom we've got like an elevated
shot cool it worked and then what once
were here we actually want to leave a
trail for ourselves to to find to
actually start walking up and figure out
the process tree of where we are so we
can run a command and then the next step
would be start searching for it so we've
got some helpful PowerShell scripts you
can use two of them grabs s monologues
out I'm not gonna read these and so uh
for bypass do you see the most useful
piece of telemetry which I would say
just from looking at this and this
technique in particular is command line
monitoring so we run the script and say
like give me the most recent process
executions and so now we've gotten
process executions who actually we want
to search them and figure out where
where our command was and so we left
token for us to find just called find me
and so we search find find me in the
command line and we get the process of
everywhere and it's running elevated so
we can see that from a Tegrity level
there's also this field called parent
process booyah so we can walk up the
tree the process tree see the parent and
the parent looks kind of weird because
it actually matches the command we ran
earlier so okay this is noteworthy we
won't run up one step further and
realize this parent is actually
legitimate Windows running and we can
look up that service and see oh it's
just the task scheduler okay that's too
far so we kind of think we know where we
ended what we want to look for so next
step would be how do we take
that knowledge and turn that into a
useful analytic so now we can refine the
command line and say okay finally
anything that has this substring how
does that work okay we found what we did
we did it earlier we found that - oh
well shoot the thing ran legitimately
this is totally benign this is just
Windows we don't want to detect this so
we refine our query and we say okay now
find a one that matches this but not
that and we get a hit and we get our
other hit from test in the technique a
second time and that was it so we've got
some prototype the next step would be
for us to actually take that leave
Windows at that point because now we
actually need to test to me but in real
endpoints with our sim whatever that
happens to be and so we would translate
this to equal which is the language we
use so this would be just like the
one-liner for this rule because this
would look like so like look for this
clean manager with an extra space in the
beginning and then we just search all of
our endpoints how are we doing with this
we're still refining the analytic and we
see we see 24 hits so it's not quite
right and so we can tune this we find
that oh this is just legitimate Windows
I'll meet just my query rip that out now
we have no hits and this point we've got
like a decent detection yeah so I guess
in like the final seconds here so pretty
clever here together through in five
minutes but so we're not saying anything
earth-shattering by ignoring a parent
process is gonna find two new rules in
every case we're not trying to share
that we're just trying to share the
actual process so if I had more time I'd
reign on some of these but just to pick
one out of just unique things the second
one is always kind of fun where say
you're trying to look for a malicious
link and so you said oh I want to know
about a browser launch from Outlook that
then dropped a PowerShell script makes
perfect sense
but I'll tell you what what users do is
when they read their email first thing
in the morning they click that
legitimate link they open up a browser
and then but they they open up a browser
and then they and then they do their
normal business and then eventually they
do something that triggers your analytic
which you've now associated with Outlook
so again you have to use temporal
analysis and really think about your
analytics but anyway thanks for time
happy to talk more about this
you