final speaker for the session it's going
to be Bryson board
safe is probably the best shirt of any
of the speakers today
all right well at least I got that down
good morning so I'm Bryson Bork and
there's probably only two things you
need to know about me one I have an
offensive security background and two I
was an Army officer which means that
you're going to get very simple very
simple words very simple concepts if you
want smart and complex talk to Blake or
you know somebody like Sunil who's
actually got a brain well that changes
so in terms of thinking of things simple
I was one of many folks who has stumped
yesterday when we got the questions and
they said go to the miter attack
framework out there and put your PIN to
something and I sat there and I looked
at it for about ten minutes I'd like
that one oh wait but I forgot about that
one because there's so much and I heard
over heard several folks talking about
the challenge with implementing this
into our environment because we're
talking about operationalizing it I mean
it's great to have wonderful
intellectual frameworks to think about
it's nice to have huge results in a lab
but what we want is something that
changes things in the real world and so
the value that I think of when I think
of the attack framework starts with it's
like the periodic table it's a simple
group of elements that allows us to all
talk between each other in a common
vernacular on top of that if we combine
them we can create complex equations and
complex compounds it allows all of us to
understand that but at the same time
it's something that is still common so
that a layperson can follow what we're
doing going back to what the NCC group
did right most of us are offensive and
because of that we are offensive to our
customers I know that one was not as
good
now there you go so I I simplify this as
the potential attack space is there is
an infinite number of ways to gain
access I can gain access through
technical means I can gain access
through social means I can gain access
through insider threat close access
there's an unlimited ways to gain access
once I gain access really it comes down
to two things I need to be able to talk
and I need to be able to do things and
if we look at that then the mitre attack
framework provides us a confined attack
space where we know that that is where
the attacker is talking in some form and
then doing certain things to their
advantage
keeping in mind we only care about the
things that affect us if an attacker
gets on a computer and plays minecraft
we don't care we care when they're
stealing credentials we still we care
when they're doing different kinds of
privilege escalation and they're doing
the things that they can actually
accomplish either stealing or harm to us
it's the way that I've mapped that
communications and behaviors back in is
those high levels of the mitre attack
framework are really just those pieces
so where's the breakdown because we've
got threat intelligence that has so much
promise we've heard some talks today
they were talking about how do we create
detection paths and how do we do
different things to bring this into our
environment and the challenge that I see
is I don't see any cyber threat
intelligence that actually allows us to
just automatically consume it giving a
shout-out to Palo Alto unit 42 with the
adversary playbooks that's the closest
I've seen where they're starting to look
at how do we update sticks how do we
turn this into something where it is the
red informing the blue to have a purple
effect but the threat intelligence is
not automatically there if you look at
threat intelligence we get a lot of
ephemeral i/o sees and we get things
where we can manually scrape it but
there hasn't yet been anything that
automatically pulls that imagine that if
I could just have a catalog that is
updated constantly and then I'm able to
run that through my detection zhh
without having to manually parse that
that's something I think the industry
needs to move to the other challenge we
have is while the mitre attack framework
does a really good job of providing us
this wide range of behaviors and an
overall
framework of understanding isn't there
that goal that we all want to just be
able to go I completely got this block
across my organization but why can't we
do that and the reason that we can't do
that is that tension of when you
actually start to look at where the bits
meet the road there's an infinite number
of ways to do any one of those
particular things so I just call that
two examples here of like what we're
talking about binary padding right
binary padding would be the behavior but
there's two explicit ways to do that
among many and among many more and so
what we need to find is a way to both
look at the mitre attack framework not
only is that vernacular but also as a
driving ability to how do we constantly
match that tension of an overall
behavior detection and then at the same
time not missing out the fact that we're
talking about complex computers and
finite state machines and how does that
actually happen down there at the bottom
thank you
you