so our next presenter has a long history
with cyber espionage and targeted
attacks which I when I read that it's
like what exactly does that mean but
I'll leave it to him to answer
Robert Falcone is a threat researcher
with Palo Alto is unit 42 and has spent
the last 10 years focusing on malware
analysis reverse engineering and
tracking threat actors primarily those
associated with cyber espionage and
targeted attacks he's also worked as a
security engineer within an operation
center for a managed security service
focused on intrusion detection and
prevention
please welcome Robert Falcone thank you
everyone so thank you rich for that
introduction I'm not gonna really
introduce myself because I was a you
know pretty decent job what I do want to
say is that I'm a threat researcher okay
so I'm gonna be talking about a specific
threat that we've been researching for a
while now called sofa C and I'm gonna
talk about how we're using attack when
we're doing this kind of threat research
and specifically with one of the one of
the concepts we're starting to really
focus our attention on and that's
adversary playbooks okay so I'm gonna
start off talking about adversary
playbooks the concept behind it and I'm
gonna start off by asking probably the
most important question of this entire
conference and it's uh did anyone back
you know late 8990 play Nintendo and you
wouldn't know what this game is wow
that's a pretty decent amount of folks
okay so for the folks that don't know
what this game is this is what's ahead
okay yeah I know right in the right
right country American football so this
is for those that don't know this is
Tecmo Bowl it's a football game from
Nintendo and I think there was a Super
Nintendo version but the idea was there
were two players here and one player was
on offense and one player was on defense
and the offense would try to choose a
play from a screen like this and it
would be like a run play or pass play or
whatever and the defense would try to
pick that same play okay and if the
defense
pick the same play they overwhelmed the
offense and just dominated them okay
just like this so even though this is
you know Bo Jackson about to get the
ball he gets crushed he's not able to
get you know anywhere and I'm using this
metaphor in this analogy because that's
where we want to be from you four by
using absolute play books if you know
what at what play the adversary is gonna
run to his attack an organization you're
gonna have a much better chance of
defending against it
so let's you know get away from Tecmo
Bowl for a little bit let's talk about
how we've decided to approach this
problem and to make this no longer
concept but actually put it into reality
and put it into our workflows as threat
researchers so we started off with the
attack lifecycle just because that's how
as researchers we are focusing on how an
adversary is gonna carry out their
attack and it's just a face based
approach you may notice a lucky kill
chain or you know whatever but again
it's just a phase based approach and
what we did was we wanted to use the
attack the attack framework to to be
able to identify the activities that an
adversary is gonna have to take in each
one of these phases and we wanted to be
able to share this with the community
because that's a big part of unit 42 is
that we want to share the intelligence
and with the you know the the
communities for a greater good so we
ended up fusion using sticks to version
two to be able to you know create
objects for each one of these of these
attack techniques and be able to apply
it to the killer chain okay so you guys
probably recognize this we've been
talking about it for two days so I'm not
gonna talk about it much but I just want
to take this time to thank the folks at
mitre that worked on attack and all the
contributors cuz this saved that without
without this framework the playbook
concept would never have gotten off the
ground so thanks everyone I appreciate
that so I mentioned that we're using
sticks for to be able to disseminate
these these play books and disseminate
this intelligence out with the community
and I mentioned that we're specifically
using
- and there's one main reason for that
we chose version 2 it's the latest and
greatest but it's also in JSON format
which is really really helpful because
we don't have to parse XML anymore we're
gonna start using JSON JSON objects to
be able to identify the entities within
these playbooks and one of the other
really important parts about Stix - is
that you can relate any entities
together or other JSON objects together
using a relationship object and this is
actually really important because this
allows us to kind of bind things
together to actually be able to create
these plays and play books okay so how
did we approach this well like I said we
took the attack lifecycle where we took
the attack framework and pre-attack and
sticks version two and kind of threw it
in a blender just to see what we could
come up with at first and I think it
actually worked because we're starting
to be able to create these play books
during our research efforts so here's
how we actually looked at the play book
concept so at the top here we have an
adversary or intrusion center whatever
you want to call it and underneath that
they're carrying out attack campaigns
right and each one of those campaigns
has a set number of techniques that
they're gonna carry out to take you know
carry out that campaign and each one of
those techniques may have a set amount
of indicators that you can look for and
observe - to be able to see that
technique happen so in our PlayBook idea
we just kind of replace some of these
words with with these words instead so
at the top we've got the adversary now
being the playbook because if you think
about it an adversary wouldn't have
multiple play books if we continued that
analogy with the football team a
football team wouldn't have multiple
play books that doesn't really make
sense they would just have multiple
pages of plays within that playbook
that's why campaigns themselves are our
plays getting back to the techniques
themselves
we just mapped like I said we use the
attack framework we just made that
mapping very easily and indicators
themselves are just sticks version to
indicators which are just indicator
patterns that
what what we're able to do now is we're
able to use six relationships to be able
to bind all those together make those
relationships between sticks indicators
observables to the actual techniques
that you can you know identify with that
with that indicator and be able to
relate all these things together from
there we use another Stix object called
a bundle a bundle of sticks right I
think that was a sticks joke but so what
that what we were able to do with the
sticks bundle is we were able to take
all these JSON objects that are related
to a play a playbook the attack
techniques that were used in that play
and all the indicators and we're able to
put them in one object to be easily to
be shared with the community we could
just create one object and share it out
as one giant JSON object okay so I
mentioned that we had we were using
sticks sticks version two but we're also
mapping the attack techniques to the
kill chain and I wanted to provide a
quick mapping of how that works we just
did it really you know very simple very
dirty kind of attack tactic to kill
chain kind of mapping and it kind of
worked out okay for the most part if you
probably can't read all of these but
some of them there fall into multiple
phases specifically I think its
execution has some techniques that
really belong in the exploitation phase
so we had to kind of make decisions on
where these where these techniques
actually fell in the kill chain and
luckily because we use sticks - these
are all JSON objects we can manipulate
them a little bit like right here you
can see we're able to assign not only
the the kill chain name for the attack
tactic well you can also change which
which phase on the Lockheed Joe chain it
actually belongs and you'll see this
when I show you our viewer why this is
important okay so this is a playbook
isn't that doesn't that look great right
humans should never read
this is the JSON output of our PlayBook
creator right I just wanted to emphasize
this is really good if you're a machine
and need to parse this really quickly
because they're all really concise JSON
objects really easy to consume from a
machine standpoint I also mentioned a
human shouldn't read this we actually
created a viewer that will parse all
this for you and actually make it so you
know your eyes don't bleed and I'll show
you that in a little bit okay so what
I'm going to do now is I'm going to talk
about a specific thread actor called
sofa see I think someone touched on on
this threat group earlier in the at the
conference but I want to talk about this
specific threat and use this threat as
an example of how we're how we're
building these plays and playbooks is
for their campaigns so let's jump off
into some of the activity that we saw
this thread actor carrying out in early
starting in January 2018 moving the
February you know another attack
campaign in March 2008 eeen I don't have
time to go into all of these but I want
to focus on one that occurred of one
campaign in February 2018 that we
internally call Lucky Strike okay
this was targeting government
organizations in the EU and in the with
America okay so that we call it Lucky
Strike
internally because of the tool that they
use to create the delivery document okay
so what I'm going to do now is I'm going
to go through each one of those
operational phases and what the
adversary actually did in each of those
phases so then afterwards we can
actually build a play using the attack
framework okay so start in the
weaponization phase like I said this
group used the this this tool called
Lucky Strike I'm not sure if you guys
have heard of it but it's an open-source
tool it's freely available on github and
what it does is it takes an Excel
spreadsheet and adds a macro to it and
embeds a payload to it of your choice
and in outputs another weaponized excel
document pretty straightforward okay
so this group used that to generate
their delivery document
that then they deliver via spearfishing
email as an attachment and this is what
the email looked like and the
interesting part about this is the
delivery email itself spoofed a very
well-known organization in in several
different industries and you know the
actual content of the of the email was
you know written really well really
decent Spearfish here let's move into
the exploitation phase let's look back
at that delivery email you can actually
see there's a spreadsheet attached to it
and I drew a box around this this part
of the email it says note if you're
having trouble viewing the document you
can try to enable content to resolve the
issue now many of you may know macros
are not automatically run in in
Microsoft Office products you actually
have to click the enable content button
to run it this is just giving you a hey
if you can't see the the contents of the
of the document try clicking enable
content it may it may you know fix it
well guess what it does so when you
first open it it looks like this all no
content in it well once you put the
enable content button all of a sudden
you see the content so I mean you're
seeing you know that the email is was
right you you know now you click the
enable content button it resolved the
issue everything's grand right but
unfortunately what you did was you the
macro ran and the first thing it did was
it just changed the color of the text to
black okay so if you're just if you were
just to highlight all of those cells it
would have showed up and because you
would be able to see it it was just in
white text okay
however the macro itself also installed
the trojan and this is that the code
that would obtain the embedded payload
from within the spreadsheet then the
macro would take that encoded data right
into a text file and then use the cert
util decode application or in this case
the switch to decode that base64 encoded
data and write to an executable which
would later in run okay so that's the
installation process that would occur
now the payload that was dropped was
Sofia sees pretty much go to first stage
payload some folks call it setup loader
we call it soap see convert but it's
there
their primary go-to for stage payload so
that initial payload in the command
control phase would use HTTP to beacon
at situ server and it looks like this
well technically it's an HTTP this is
just the HTTP request that's going out
as you can see it's just an HTTP POST
request to a specific domain has some
cipher text in it and that's the C Tube
channel let's move into the objective
phase and I will be honest we we don't
have a complete view of what was going
on here we didn't see any lateral
movement because what we found was that
when we took a look at the the data that
was sent out in the c2 it looks like
this which is encrypted
once you decrypt it you can see initial
local reconnaissance being done you know
running running running processes it's
checking the hard disk in some of the
NIC information that kind of stuff also
sending a screenshot that is meant to
filter out you know analysis systems and
that kind of thing okay but what we can
surmise based off of the command handler
of that payload is what they were
actually trying to do this is just like
I said their first stage payload all
they're trying to do is to you know do
initial reconnaissance find out if
that's the system they want to they want
to you know compromise and then they
load additional tools to be able to
carry out further activities like
lateral movement privilege escalation
that kind of stuff so now we've gone to
that whole process that was the Lucky
Strike attack you know looking at it
from the kill chain perspective now I
want to talk use that same attack and
talk about what how we created a play
for our play books using that
information and I mentioned earlier when
I showed that JSON that would make you
make your eyes want to bleed this here
is the viewer that we created to parse
all that JSON to make it so a human can
actually click through these these play
books and understand what TTP's are
being used in the in the life cycle it's
you can access it right on our github
page there's the link right there so if
you're interested in kind of playing
around and looking at looking at the
play books that we have and the
indicators that are associated with them
you just go right right to our github
also that the raw JSON czar also freely
available on our github as well so you
can do you know whatever you want with
them so let's go through the same life
cycle phases and kind of highlight which
one of the attack TTP's that were in
those phases now I'm not sure if
anyone's still playing bingo but there's
gonna be a lot of T attack techniques
here so you may you may win and if you
win please shout out because I do have a
prize so if you win let me know okay so
then recon we have the identifier
business relationships from pre-attack
and the reason why we have that there is
because they the actor clearly was able
to identify that there was a
relationship between that spoofed
organization and the target the targeted
org that you know would help them be
successful in their attack moving on to
the weaponization phase we have these
techniques here and I'm just going to
highlight the by domain name in the in
the black text here you can see its
newly just newly registered domain that
is our description in in our play for
the reason that technique is in that
play okay so we're able to provide a
little bit more insight and for the
viewer why that is there and below that
you can actually see the the indicator
the sticks version two indicators that
we created that is nowis is related to
that that attack technique right there
so if you were to see that that that
domain CDN verified net you know exactly
where or what adversary is associated
with where in their operational phases
that it belongs that kind of thing okay
moving on to delivery phase there's some
interesting techniques here which I'll
talk about in a little bit but here we
have spearfishing messages with
malicious attachments and as you
remember the the Excel spreadsheet was
attached to it email sent to the target
and here you can see there's several
different indicators associated with
that with that specific technique moving
the exploitation phase
another interesting technique authorized
user performs requested cyber action
this was to capture the there was no
software vulnerability that was
exploited so we had to use a technique
from attack to specify you know clicking
that enable content button to infect
themselves and that's what this is used
okay in the installation phase here's
several different techniques that were
used and the I'm just gonna highlight
this one real quick the login scripts
it's a very specific registry key that
was used by the payload to automatically
run each time and here at the bottom I
just want to kind of highlight in orange
you can see that the the actual
indicator pattern itself includes some
logic there's an and in there right so
that I just want to highlight the fact
that sticks to you can actually write
some pretty pretty accurate indicator
patterns by using a little bit more
logic to them like this one requires a
registry key and a specific value being
used so interesting stuff
okay moving into a command control we
have standard application layer protocol
one of my favorite one of my favorite
techniques which you'll see in a minute
service queue burp uses HTTP and there's
the technique that's being used and in
ACTA objectives phase these are the
techniques that we were able to just
kind of speculate on because we didn't
have a true view into what they did
after they got there their initial
access but this is what they did right
when they got to the to the system one
thing I do want to highlight is the fact
usually when I get this presentation I
go through multiple of the different
campaigns so you can start you know
comparing them together but once you do
this kind of create these plays and
start tracking the the techniques that
are used during these campaigns you can
start seeing overlaps in different
campaigns by the same threat groups so
it shows that they continue to use the
same techniques over and over again and
there their attack campaigns which is
kind of interesting okay so I don't know
how much time I have left but I want to
talk about a little bit about the
challenges that we came across
we're creating these play books this is
not a bash vest
I love attack and the framework itself
and sticks but when we first set out to
make this concept into a reality we came
across some some hurdles that we kind of
had to overcome first off the standard
application layer protocol is a good a
good scent a good example of where a
technique is a little bit too broad so
for in our plays this doesn't really
tell you what what standard application
layer protocol right it could be in this
it even says RPC SSH RDP all those kind
of things right luckily we were able to
kind of overcome this in our plays
because we're able to add descriptions
so we're relying on that but this was
this is an interesting one that just
said that showed that some of these are
really really broad techniques execution
through API very very all-encompassing
because this pretty much captures almost
any Trojan that runs on something else
using an API like create process or win
exact or load library anything so any
any Trojan that loads something else
would be captured by this technique so
this would probably pretty much show up
in almost all of our plays use of open
source tools like the Lucky Strike
attack that I just mentioned there isn't
a technique for that and I know that the
miter folks are really receptive to new
techniques and we've been kind of going
back and forth about this one because we
don't know if it's really a technique or
not but it is the flipside of using
custom tooling so there's a conversation
to have there and in my favorite and
this is a lot on us because I know that
several of the techniques have been
deprecated as you probably noticed in my
might my talk a lot of the a lot of that
play some of the techniques have been
deprecated and so it's it's one of those
things that now we have to go back
through all of our plays and find the
techniques that were deprecated and
figure out what to replace them with in
some sort of some sort of formal manner
because quite frankly there's not like a
really one-to-one kind of over place
one with this it's so we have to kind of
go back and do some legwork there okay
moving on to sticks I like sticks it's
fun it just sticks to is great because
it uses JSON said XML it's lots of
documentation so that information is out
there but there there's like eight or
five different documents they're all
like seventy plus pages and they're just
there's a lot of control F going on here
to be able to find anything that you're
actually looking for okay
that being said there are things that
are sort of missing here especially with
the indicator objects these these things
called cyber observable objects which
you use within your patterns and in this
case there's a there's an object for
HTTP requests but there's no object for
HTTP response so you can't write any
patterns for anything a c2 server would
reply with because there's no object for
it okay
sticks to is great because it actually
comes with a Python library and which
you know allows us to create things
really quickly and one of the things
that we ran into from an issue
standpoint was the pattern validator
itself was pretty broken unfortunate but
fortunately the sticks folks were able
to fix that with a new with a new
library but for a while there we weren't
able to create any any indicators with a
double quote in it it just would break
and it wouldn't work at all so here you
can see it just had a traceback error if
when I try to create that and this is
one of the patterns we try to create for
this specific play that Lucky Strike
play but we weren't able to because of
this of this limitation but like I said
they fixed it with their new with their
new library okay I'm not gonna really
talk about the tech navigator much I
wish this tool existed when we kind of
first started going down this path
because there wasn't a way to real
really visualize and interact with the
attack framework in any sort of way
other than into in the wiki itself and
this is actually a really cool tool that
allows you to kind of interact with it
and this is that same play all these
these boxes are the same play that were
on the that that I built in the in the
playbook
you were but just aren't using the
attack framework or detect navigator
itself okay that's all of god I did want
to kind of end and just say that you
know as unifor to as we're going through
our research we're we're starting to
think about attack and the attack
techniques and the adversaries and how
they're using these techniques to carry
out these attacks and we just wanted to
be able to disseminate that kind of
information to provide more context to
the the Intel that we're gathering on a
day to day basis for the community to
absorb and yeah that's all I got here's
the again the URLs for the the PlayBook
viewer and our blog where most of the
other information that we have and thank
you yes you do said any questions by the
way as the guy who created sticks and
taxi okay I will cop to sticks one being
something I will take to my grave glad
to see that you've toughed it out and
stuck with 66 to is there it I mean
Jason's much easier to work with and as
much as I kind of gave challenges up
here it's still well these are you know
standardized frameworks like it's still
better than me creating our own so I
mean it still have to give thanks for
thanks to Stuart ya know it's an awesome
application alright questions for a
Robert come on you can do it
where'd you say was like the level of
effort that it took too big to like put
together one of these play books to do
all the mappings you know is it like a
month a week a day that's a great
question I think at well at first to get
this process started I think I was given
a timeline the first one had to be done
in like a month and that was daunting at
first because we didn't have any tooling
to be able to create these in any sort
of manner so there was some development
effort upfront so the the level the the
effort level was daunting at first but
since we've actually started to do these
in you know more repetitive function and
got more familiarized with not only
sticks to but also the attack framework
it's been easier I will also say that
the tooling we have now is much better
than the you know the stuff I wrote
because it was really poorly written but
just getting familiarized with the
framework and that kind of thing was
probably the biggest hurdle I will also
say there were a lot of arguments
between analysts like oh does this apply
does this apply that kind of thing
between techniques themselves but yeah I
would say at first it was a heavy lift
but then after you know after a little
bit it got it got easier I have a
two-part question okay the first is do
you have you guys written software for
the ingest of the data so the actual
data import and the second how much
adoption have you seen from the
community have you seen other people
writing these and using these so
ingestion not yet we're actually
thinking about even creating tools to
create them yourselves
how much adoption have we had we have
some serious interest in it how how
those folks are actually do using them
I'm not entirely entirely sure but we
are having people you know pulling down
the JSON sand you know kind of getting
excited about it
could you talk just a little bit more
about the process you guys are using to
evaluate the malicious activity to
create the playbook and is there any
automated processing that you're doing
to identify the attack techniques being
used no not yet I should also mention
that this is a it's we're still working
on this in fact our our our tooling is
not even fully there yet we do have
ideas of how we could start automating
some of these things but it's not there
right now it's up to the analyst as
they're going through their research
efforts to identify which techniques are
being used and then apply that to the
play so it's largely manual right now
but we're working we're working on it
any other questions for Robert great all
right please join me in thanking Robert
you