CIM alex Pinto who is the principal data
security scientist at Verizon Enterprise
Services where he is responsible for
data science analytics and machine
learning capabilities of their Verizon
autonomous threat hunting and Risk
report products and Alex joined Verizon
through the acquisition of needle where
he was co-founder and chief data
scientist and while both Alex and Gabe
Bassett developed his presentation
unfortunately Gabe has a good excuse for
not being here which Alex will explain
so please welcome Alex Pinto how's the
audio we're good we're great awesome all
right so let's let's get this started
then so I am Alex Pinto right I am NOT
Gabe Bassett and I want to talk to you a
little bit about this crazy idea that me
and Gabe have been kicking around the
office called V cath so if we could just
get to the slides oh I do have a clicker
don't I that's great idea I'll get there
we're doing this live guys this is how
it works
oh yeah this is what we were talking
about this is this is kind of what we're
doing so we all know about attack I'm
sure most of you don't really know what
varies is about we'll cover that right
and it's really a very very crazy idea
about bringing those two things together
right so anyway this these are us I am
pretty much my day job is taking care of
capybaras but on my spare time I do a
lot of security data science right so
rich already told most everything that's
relevant about me I most of my quote
unquote fame came from doing machine
learning stuff with threat based data
with event data right and Gabe has been
working on the DB area for many many
years now he's probably part of the
furniture and has done some very very
interesting stuff over the years on
graph analysis so graph based analysis
which is also a callback to what we were
talking about on the keynote right and
this is really
where we are where we're coming from so
suddenly Gabe couldn't be here and
anyway this is the I'm gonna start
talking about this and hopefully all
will become real clear this actually
it's probably going to be a more
abstract talk than you're used to in
this specific venue right I'm
specifically showing shying away from
showing any spreadsheets or Excel right
good Excel guys everybody here right
yeah yeah everybody anyway I'm not so
much concerned about mapping things down
we're in downstream right we're trying
to get the attack framework and we're
trying to okay how can I tie this to
these specific things that's happening
on my network ax I've been thinking
maybe we should try to me there's
another way to look at this at the more
abstract than you right also this
presentation I think it's a shitty bit
more abstract than I normally do right
I'm not gonna going going to go into
details of what exactly we're doing
right and there's two main reasons for
that first of all there's legal right so
as rich has already told I have just
recently joined a large company I'm
still learning a lot about what can and
cannot be sad so blah blah blah
forward-looking statements I might not
even be here right now right this might
all be an illusion right but we are
actually I'm gonna talk about I
definitely don't want to reveal anything
that we may or may not be working with
ahead of time right so that's thing
number one and reason number two right
it's Bailey's right so babies are the
main reason why maybe the stock is not
as this research is not as far ahead as
we would have wanted to right mainly
because they Gabe just had one right so
that's the main reason why is not here
and I have one due in January right so
it actually takes a long time it's
actually my first child and it's
surprising how much stuff there is to
read how much stuff there is to learn
about them I've been reading all these
parenting books I'm spending so much
time trying to understand how they raise
a child
where's the manual what which buttons do
you press right and there was one that I
recently
reading which I think was been
fascinating for me which it's called and
this clicker is flaking on me it's
called the whole brainchild let's talk
about parenting for a bit we'll get to
you're normally advertised content
pretty soon but the thing that I really
enjoyed about this book it's a it's kind
of like cognitive behavioral therapy for
children like dumb down a little bit
right and we need the idea is that if a
child is upset and it's you know it's
struggling with something you're like no
no use your words like name it what is
it what is the thing right so we're
trying to transition the kid from I'm
angry or I'm sad or I'm not banging on
the table to well you know what I'm kind
of upset because I really have to eat
all these Brussels sprouts until I get
to the server right so by talking to the
child right and engaging with them
giving them the vocabulary so they can
express what exact threats are happening
to them in a specific point it helps
them find out their deficiencies right
and help them understand what controls
they should be implementing right in
order to address that problem right and
I'm clearly not talking about children
anymore right so the point here is that
what has happened with attack at least
what has come to my realization while we
were working through this is that we're
kind of graduating from everything is on
fire right run for the exits do not
tweet out of the way right - you know
what we have determined through a very
careful simulation that there's a tiny
deficients on this specific thing we're
all very sophisticated now because we
have the vocabulary right we can now
talk about specific things that might be
missing on our space on our environment
right in order for us to focus and
address the points right I think it's
super exciting because if any of you has
ever seen any of my talks before and I
obviously apologize for you having seen
any talk of mine before
I've always been very very angry about
nonspecific security marketing it's not
so much
oh yeah buy my product because I'll
solve everything okay when I need
everything I'll give you a call right
this is what I need now these are the
things that I should be looking at this
is the next step on my journey to make
this place more secure and now we're
starting to get the vocabulary right on
how we can address these things anyway
this was not the first time I had kind
of this realization the first time I had
this oh wow we're really getting
somewhere
what's the first time I saw the dir
right so really the the idea this crazy
people right and some of the original
authors are here on the audience by the
way right they were like well what if we
like gave name to things and try to
count them right and try to put some
structure around the actual threats the
actual breaches that we're seeing right
they probably did something right
because it's been like 11 years right
and I can assure you there is a 12th
edition being worked on right now right
so it's keeping on keeping on right and
it's a lot of data to obviously go
through a lot of data to are obviously
organized but then finally we're
starting to talk things like this right
and oh that's there so if you go to this
website right they actually have like
some of the live data you can click
through and you can start to measure
anika start to see that over the years
right the prevalence of breaches that we
have involved a physical matter or had
involved some misuse or some social
components has fluctuated over the years
right of course you have to take all of
this of a grain of salt because it puts
it obviously what the dir sees is tied
to the data that'd be our guess right
they don't claim to have all the breach
data in the world they're definitely
trying right and I would wager that they
are probably the more
the closest they probably have the most
data than anyone else because again
they've been around for a while and they
put together some good relationships but
Mike here is that we're starting to
measure right we're starting to see and
it becomes valuable for a company to
understand that you know what because I
am this kind of company and that's the
great claim to fame big claim to fame
right because I am from this specific
industry maybe those are the things I
should be caring about right and there's
some cool stuff other cool stuff on this
website this one specifically made me
make me think about this right
specifically about this talk well you
know when we were when you're looking
specifically about the action Espionage
right which we all love here in this
room I'm in the right City so mostly
those things were involved backdoors and
see twos right and I do appreciate how
unhelpful backdoor sounds and we'll get
to there in a second right but it's
giving you an idea right so if somehow
you are able to accurately detect
backdoors or C choose in your
environment right
suddenly you're probably better at
detecting this kind of activity into
your next word and that's really all you
can care for right if you believe you're
being targeted by that that's what you
would care for right and financial read
somewhere was a big big winner last year
this year not so much people are talking
about coin - you're in it correlates to
activity have seen as well right
but again ransomware is not helpful
right how do you protect against me
somewhere well there's an email and
there's a place to download and then the
data has encrypted there's some data X
few I mean hopefully the key gets out
right so that you can pay for it and get
the key back sometimes it doesn't but if
you think about it on a tech terms which
is what we'll be talking about there's
actually a lot of ways you can slice
this out you can be more granular and a
little bit more tactical right on on
we're seeing here and hopefully most of
the audience has already got to where I
want them to do so anyway although all
those things are not random
right so the there is something called
various right which stands for
vocabulary of isn't with sporting
reporting an incident sharing right and
it's one more of those standards they're
frankly not enough people care about and
what I specifically separated here is
what we call the action varieties so the
things that happened which core really
correlate to this is what you would
observe in your network if you were
breached that way right so it actually
works the other way around when you
think about the DBA are oh there was a
specific breach then we see what
happened right and then we say oh these
were all the actions that were occurred
so there's six major things there
malware hacking social misuse physical
error and environmental which is my
absolute favorite and they break down a
little bit like you said the backdoor
see - so I'm just giving out some
examples here we don't really need to to
get stuck on them right and again if I
meant oh is the best right meet you
right right and you have to understand
right this is mostly risk analysis right
there is an odd chance a meteorite could
hit your data center we have to make
sure we are prepared for that right and
I'm not going back to that slide but if
you see the prevalence of the so
environmental has been a zero forever
right I really hope we don't have to put
a meteor right there right but it would
be funny I'm sorry that's just the kind
of person I am it's just like oh that's
so curious this is the reason why we did
this right anyway so but what's the
point right
why are we talking so much about risk
the the point here is that again this is
a drama keep beating all the time as
well is there's not enough time to do
everything right and I honestly think
attack simulation is an incredible idea
I enjoy the concept of attack simulation
I think it's way more
it's a way some of the new concepts that
are there for security products in the
market are not as interesting as the tax
simulation so that was the most polite
way I could I could put the sentence and
but still when it comes back and say oh
look there's a hundred and fifty things
you're not able to do the question
becomes okay which one should i do first
right and nobody has a good answer for
that but then if there was a reasonable
way where we could actually measure the
prevalence of the attack things right
the actual item atoms right as they are
correlated to breaches and near misses
maybe we could start to go into a better
direction as to which one should i do
first right so this is really kind of
what I'm seeing right so if there is
fairies through the DBA all right and
I'm using various instead of the BIR
because you can just go there and use
the standard yourself you don't have to
wait for us to print a report please god
no
it takes forever and we do it on your
own stuff right if that is able to help
you with prioritizing write and attack
with the data that you have on your it
delimiter analysis are the from a need
in your perspective over a natural
process and attack simulation can help
you figure out what you need can't we do
some magic stuff here in the middle
right that's able to make them talk to
each other right and again help us
prioritize the things that we were doing
right so that tiny little magical thing
right is what I decided to call V keV
right it's not decaf okay a lot of
caffeine will be involved in making this
thing work okay so if you guys are
familiar with the PMI the project
management institute the PMP the five
stages of project management right this
project is currently between the anger
and bargaining stage
so we're hopefully new hopefully there's
I mean there's there's some early
exploration light we're pretty much
figuring out what we need to get this
done right we know there's a lot of work
but there's also a lot of potential data
that we might need and some of it we
have right and release the thing that I
I I'm gonna touch into more detail but
of course Verizon who uses a lot of the
data from their breeches right when
they're creating the DBA are everything
synonymous blah blah blah you know how
that field works right you know how it
works but we have the actual technical
details of what happened so we can get
to that level of granularity once we
have the mapping or the the granularity
can help us do the mapping because we
see oh we need to rent somewhere
actually these are the atoms that are
activated so we don't really have to
think that hard to figure out how we
should organize the specific things but
for other breaches that we receive
there's there's a real unevenness of the
detail of the data that we receive but
before I make you the pitch let me tell
you why what I believe this could help
right so I think there's two main ways
two main things as we connect those two
standards I guess the word I'm looking
for two main objectives we can get to so
first of all connecting this strategic
to the tactical right and I talked a
little bit about the ideas that I have
and I do intend to go into a little bit
more detail but one of the things that
do want to do is that there's a lot of
stuff in various right which if they are
it's I know the meteorite thing is a
funny joke but a lot most of the stuff
that are in the action varieties in
various they actually come from actual
real-life incidents that have happened
right they're not there by accident
right and we do not have the words we do
not have the atoms in attack for some of
those things right so I this is a bad
way to putting it right
I think attack is too focused on the AP
cheese right so and to be fair I get it
I mean it way one the constituency right
definitely the people who are most
interested in doing this
sort of work are the more mature and
they believe that the other types of
detection that we need is easier which
is not wrong right i I do agree it's not
wrong but still I think we could finish
that work through the more quote unquote
normal stuff that actually happens every
day right
we still need to measure those right
even if it's things that are not really
really happening right
and when I say TVs there I actually mean
action varieties right so so maybe the
most popular ones we could also expand
and have a different namespace
it's the AVI calf attack expansion
whatever namespace I have no idea how
it's gonna be called but and well this
is some other thing that people can use
if they so wish we certainly will be
using those right
maybe pre-attack has a little bit I
don't know I don't know if fishing on
pre attack it's just for like w2 stuff
BC or an actual email delivery like link
delivery would happen I don't know if
stablishing the infra would counter see
to so there's a lot of exploring we
haven't even looked at the mobile stuff
yet right but one one main tenant is
that I don't want to do the work that
has already been done especially because
like I'm lazy it's why why would I do it
again so it's really about identifying
where we can add value there but the
cool stuff here in my opinion is really
the strategic was tactical right so
there's two things that come to my mind
very very clearly first of all all that
dbi are machinery that i showed you
right it's just counting right it's not
nothing
nothing really complicated but it takes
a lot of work to do that to apply to the
breeches because the breeches are
structured data so we have to have a
teeny tiny army right of gabe's
which they put this data together and
classify it against variants so then we
can start to doing those things if we
are collecting this data straight from
all your wonderful security tools that
have already tied it the downstream
right from attack to the actual things
that happening on the wire suddenly we
can all
automatically we don't really need to do
any sort of fancy analysis and this is
not like oh this is Verizon things do
know this the actual analysis the
various framework the code to run it
it's all open source it's on github
right now right we could use the same
techniques like that right and
specifically tying to your experience on
the bond your breach analysis and maybe
even the larger dbi are when you think
about it right we could actually use the
attack the level of granularity attack
to drive what a detective or protective
measures people should invest on first
so this becomes the literally the non
security cell which is we have
analyzed your environment right this is
the result it looks like the next thing
you should buy is and if your solution
okay that was easy but you know what I
mean right
you can tell you exactly where it hurts
this is where the mythical ROI which I
don't actually subscribe so much to that
but at least you can kind of tell people
where you're going so what and this is
something this is a joke I missed from
way back when but I'm gonna make it now
is that actually right we in InfoSec we
are the two year old doing a tantrum on
the boardroom right we want something we
want money but we can't tell them what
it is right maybe this is the way for us
to be able to explicitly tell our
boardroom parents what we need and what
we want right so anyway one of the other
cool things you can do once you have
that all in right which is again tied to
this to this specific likelihood is of
course multicolor simulations right and
a quick explanation which absolutely
makes it no justice is you just kind of
know how freaking things are you count
them once and then you just run it a
million thousand times and see what
shape the data becomes like is it more
likely to be like this is more likely to
be like that you kind of draw what the
probability distribution would be right
if you were to replicate this data a
thousand million
thousand times in the environment right
so again you can start simulating the
attack paths so you know from the
breaches that this is what happens and
this is what happens and you can try to
figure out what exactly is the best way
for one of those things to end up with
and if you have a huge concentration and
this is not based out of attack data
right all those things on the left side
here they're talking about the action
varieties that we have this is from the
DPR data's from last year I think right
and you can start to see if if the dot
is big enough right and it goes back to
your place as the attack progresses it
seems to go a lot and so that's a very
repeatable specific atom that gets
triggered all the time that's probably
where the best bang on you of your buck
for detection comes out this is this
again this is a very simple example it
doesn't even need the mapping right to
work we could be doing this out of like
real quote/unquote live attack data from
somewhere right and we can try to again
what's the best bang for your buck their
ongoing those things so you see most of
the attacks that are very short right
because I mean why are you gonna be
doing a lot of different steps you want
to make sure you're detected the least
right this is why they're all a little
bit on the left side anyway right so if
mapping is hard right it's very very
challenging right I mean at least I know
that I won't be needing to be mapping
the meteorite to anything I don't need
to be right oh this is from a comment is
this from a an asteroid but I mean what
am I gonna do with boot kits right what
what standard application layer protocol
which ones you need guys
so what you know what I mean so some of
these will not be one-to-one right some
of these will be will be will take a
little bit more work and we hope the
data will be able to tell us instead of
us just making random wild assumptions
and being terribly wrong right we can be
maybe a little less wrong if we have
data back from it right we will
obviously be using data from the
breaches that we were collected from the
dir this year from Verizon itself right
and any actual real-life data from near
misses so if you are an attack
simulation company and you would like to
contribute to the DB IR and some of you
do and we're very very thankful I'm not
going to exactly see the names of them
but please open your last year's dir
look for their names on the cover and
please give them lots of kisses and hugs
right we can use this data at samples of
data to again do this measurement and
work around those things right so yeah
give me your data maybe right that's
pretty much where we are now right and
I'm not the right person for you to give
the data to right I would not know what
to do it but there is a process for that
to happen and we're happy to talk to you
whomever you may be an actual company a
vendor or somewhere in between
I don't know right and it again
depending on how how the babies turn out
how much worth they let us do right our
goal is to kind of have an appendix
about this on actually the VAR right I'm
not really making any promises
right I mean legal is is watching this
right now as we speak but we're
definitely gonna try that's definitely
what I would like to do anyway so please
make sure you give you a contribution
right this is this is Kyle Maxwell so
Kyle was a Verizon employee at the time
this picture was taken so he has
actually for fate use of this for all
eternity for Verizon specific
presentations right so anyway that was
pretty much all I got
thank you so much
you