we've we've reached the halfway mark the
fourth talk is by
ronan lashmirez
uh ronan is a currently a research
engineer at inria and he's going to
answer for us the question can we solve
timing side channels in the cpu i hope
the answer is yes otherwise
it's going to be an anti-climax
so over to you running
ah ronin it appears your mic is not
working
now can you hear me
yes
okay so i'm going through with the
webcam
so can you see my slides
yes we can
okay perfect
so
thank you for the introduction then um
and for that please uh the answer is
more balanced than that
so i'm ronald
from india in france and i want to
talk about styling such a names
in the cpu and this talk will be related
to the fancy informal group
so this is my personal take on the ideas
that we have
so keep in mind that this is not the
official stance of the of the group but
just my personal opinion
so i want to start by motivating
i want to start by motivating the talk
by
showing you that the issue is far more
general than just cash timing attacks
and then i want to give you
mental models on how to think this issue
through
then we'll talk about the isa
modifications that we can
propose and what are the traders
so the motivation first so basically
this is a meltdown attack
what we want to do is load a secret
at a given noun address
and for that we'll first load the
address then
touch a cache line
with the address depends on the secret
so we'll want to chain two loads
with one within the secret
then the attacker can find the secret by
finding the addresses of the data in the
cache
that depends now on the secret
so there are two in fact vulnerabilities
there the first one is the access
control
we normally shouldn't be able to
load the secrets
but there is another one that is that
the attacker can exfiltrate data it can
create a covert channel in order to
transmit data where normally it
shouldn't be possible
so for the vocabulary vocabulary of
cover channel
is just a communication channel between
two entities that are controlled by the
same attacker so the trojan
tries to communicate to send information
to the spine
in this particular case that we are
looking into
we just want to focus on micro
architectural leakages meaning that the
attacker can
cannot send information using registers
memories special registers
or any architectural features
only micro-cultural architectural
filters will be used
the communication will be done like that
the trojan want to send the value i
and will try to encode it into the
microarchitecture
then we'll switch to the domain of the
spy and the spy will test a value o
then
we have a success if the spy can
determine if i is equal to o
ok
with these two
informations i want to give you an
example
so cash training attacks are well known
now and a bit too much because a lot of
people think that they are the only
vulnerabilities
so i want to show you that we can create
a cover channel really similarly to
caching attacks
with for example the bht which is the
branch historic table
so this is the
simplest way to do branch prediction
basically
you will look at the branch instruction
addresses you will keep like the four
lowest bits for example
and for each of these
values for the lowest bits you will have
a counter from 0 to 3 that counts the
number of taken branches out of the last
three branches
okay so you will see it when we replace
the attack
to do the communication will have a
gadget which is filled with
branch
instructions
and more precisely will have
instructions that branches to the end if
a0 is lower than a1 b2's branch if lower
than
so first we want to clear all the
counters
for that we'll call the first
instructions with a not taken condition
so the first instruction is executed
not taken the corresponding counter is
decremented
then we go to the next instructions the
contact is decremented etc extra until
the end
now the treasurer wants to encode a code
value i it will just execute one
instructions
at address i with the taken conditions
so the counter will be incremented
and we just jump to the end now
then the spy can test for o it will do
the same operation as the trojan with
the taken condition
but it will measure the time taken by
the instruction execution
so now if o is different than i we have
mispredicted the branch
so basically we have to
rewind the execution
execution in the hardware so it will
take time but if i is equal to o
then we'll have a fast execution and so
we can measure this difference
and this will give you that kind of
diagrams so you have seen similar one
from generator for example
it's a bit simpler because i have
deterministic benchmarks that benchmarks
so we are visualizing
really directly the timings the cycles
what we see is clearly that the diagonal
where i is equal to o
have lower timings so this is a leakage
in a secure design we shouldn't be
shouldn't be able to see that so you can
see on the right that you don't have any
horizontal variation so you don't have
leakage in this case
so these diagrams are
built using our benchmark suits which is
open source and you can find
on our gitlab with the name timestag
patch
if you want to test it
so now
how do you how do we think about this
issue
i've shown you an attack with the bht
the bench history table
but in fact the problem lies in any
shared resource
any shared resource can be the support
of the covert channel and buffer and
execution units because its availability
is one bit of information
any finite state machine any abuse boost
etc
any memory
so now you can see the scope of the
issue we have
on our hands
caches are not superb
it's really the world macro architecture
but in fact the fact that we have this
to catch is usually okay
so the leakage is the this is
because it's enhanced performances
but sometimes
you'd want to prevent it and that's
where we have a problem because the
hardware cannot know when it could
prevent leakage and when it is okay
so this is the distance between
the gay newspaper uh the new hardware
software contracts
and how can we do this now
in today's hardware so we have mainly
two way to do security
to interface for securities the first
one is the interface between kernel and
users so the privileges
which is an access control to the core
configuration
but we also have processes
where
where each process defines the memory
mapping and so define a memory space
so processes define an access control to
memory addresses
so we can use these tools in order to
improve our security but what about unix
server dealing simultaneously different
users
today we are using
insecure servers by using different
processes to deal with each user
but it is not really
a tool to do that or you can think about
a clone machine with several vms
runnings how do you prevent
communications between the virtual
machines
so basically what we want is explicit
security domains
so we are we want to have domain
boundaries defined by the application
logic but enforced in the
microarchitecture
and of course the boundaries must be
communicated to the hardware this is
where the iss instruction set
architecture must be modified
now we have two kinds of showing
temporal sharings so this is where when
security domains use the same resource
alternatively in time
think about about a cache when you have
a process then a new process
okay they are using the same resource or
cache
alternatively in time and you have also
special sharings where
you can use the same resource
simply simultaneously
by for example two domains
so in this case think about a
multi-threaded core with two arts
accessing to the same
cache again
so now you have to split the cache to
have indebted independence
[Music]
in order to be able to independently
deal with the two domains
i want to stress out that secure
methylene is possible so mature escrow
fluid
phd students
de-design
the cellular score with secure
multi-threading
so it can guarantee that the two hearts
are
perfectly
independent with respect to timing
channels
and it's not a small a small
fit
you have two solutions for the two kinds
of showings first for temple sharings
what do you do you flush all the things
basically when you are switching to the
new domain you flush all the states
remember it means that you have to
flinch
buffers but also finance submissions
the access to execution units etc etc
but it can be done
quite easily if you modify it a bit the
macro architecture
but either you do secure special shanks
now you cannot flush everything now
because they are
shared simultaneously it does no meaning
and then you have a bunch of solutions
that are quite okay but not great so you
can partition resources in order to
split
each resource in for example two slots
you can use fine-grained mutual
threadings
where you will lock time slots for each
secured security domains
for example an even
clock cycle domain i will have access
and on the odds clock cycle
domain b will have access
you can also lock the resources for the
whole lifetime of the security domains
so this is the kind of strategy that you
can do
but for that we have to modify the isa
first i want to
start
by stressing out that we have a
fundamental philosophy problems of what
is the iso world
you have two visions first the isis air
is an interface to allow the software to
control the machine
so you have instructions in order to
tune the machine to do exactly what you
want to do
or it can also be an abstract interface
to the hardware now to hide
the implementations
for the software use
but you can only pick one either you add
the implementations or you allow to
control the machine
and it will give
two ways to modify the isa either you
add restrictions to control all the
micro architectural structures or you
add instructions in order to define and
end up secreted domains
then you have two semantics another two
control domains
the first one are the fancies so this is
the stateless definition of security
domains you only delimit the boundaries
of the security domains so i'm now
switching to a new security domain
buy it
or you have context stateful security
domains where when you switch
you
define the new security domain id
now i switch to the secretive domain
with the id number one for example
and so we have two proposals academic
proposal funnel the first one is the
fence t proposal from
generalizer and all
published for example at diets this year
to simplify bits you have a fancy
instructions that is able to flush all
necessary microstructures
and you can give
an argument to these instructions with a
register
where you have several possibilities
either this register is a bitmap in
order to address the microstructure you
want to flash
or it's a value that designates the
interface for example this is a flush
between the process to
go into a channel or we are going from
process to another process etc
or it can be also valued designating the
risk
of the security domain switch
so
i'm now switching to new security
domains but i don't care if i leak
information or the the old secret domain
is critical and must not leak any
information at all
so as we have seen if we flush
everything it's nice but only for temple
sharing
so this proposal cannot deal in itself
with special shines
in order to do that
in the paper what they basically say is
that
you of course that only shared
high level cash and for that you do a
cash coloring at a level
but so you are totally forbidden
forbidding
any multi-threading course
the other proposal by us at indriya with
mature and jack funny and john milaney
published later this year
is consists of domes so stateful
[Music]
context and what we are doing basically
is that we will tag the domains with an
ids that we can use in the
microarchitecture in order to know when
we want to flash when we want to
partition it when we want to lock
resources excellent later and so this
allow
this kind of stuff where you have two
arts
systems two two arts running
simultaneously and you can prevent any
communications using the
for example airs l1 data cache
what we see is that we have a cost in
cycles here in all accesses and this is
because we are doing fine grain test
reading so we are we have reserved time
slots for each security domains
so the issue here in this proposal is
that who choose the security domain ids
if the attacker can choose the ids
the world
culture measures for
another possibility also that we are
investigating is that can we use process
ids
and
as domain ids because the process id is
used
today in order to tag the tlb for the
address translations in order to improve
the performances
can we infuse the two concepts maybe
so now a bit a small slide in order to
show you that we can go further with
confidentiality so basically what we are
doing with turnings is we want to ensure
confidentiality
in the microactual architectural states
that basically fancy or any other
solutions against these leakages should
be part of a more global confidentiality
extension
i want to give you small ideas that show
you that we can do stuff really easily
for example with confidential registers
like you declare for example four
registers as as confidential and we are
no longer authorized to leak data just
just as as easy
you cannot use them to branch you cannot
use them for load and store analysis any
constant time assumptions can be used
with respect to these registers
and you can
add any additional other hardening that
you want for example masking adword
masking
or you can also use security domain ids
in order to perform in line memory
encryptions where you encrypt
data in memory upon load and stores
instructions
so these are quite easy to define when
you have
the basis for confidentiality extension
so the conclusions
so here's the problem we have a bunch of
solutions but we are not exactly sure on
the best design and we really want to
avoid bad bad design
and i think
that we should learn from the
cryptographic community
where they show that you cannot think
about just
being reactive by batching new shoes as
they happen
which is a bit where we are now
considering the timing issues in
hardware
we also have to deal with
complexity as a security topic
on its own
because if we have too many security
decisions if you have
an extension that is too complex it
increases the attack surface and reduces
the security
and at the end it must also be clear and
simple everybody should be able to use
it
because if not again the security goal
is not achieved
and in this example i want to give you
the example of the
last generation crypto library so you
don't use anymore the ies were in cbc
mode for example with your own
iv and when you you want your own
library what you do is use
lip sodium for example where you box
encrypts
and that's it and you let the library
decide
and we should i think in my opinion have
something as easy if possible
so thank you for listening and i'm i
really would love to hear your opinion
of this topic
in order to see
really what's everybody thinking
thank you
great thanks a lot ronan so i guess
that's an invitation for questions in
itself
um
so there's a
couple appearing in the chat already let
me let me read those out for you so nick
asks what about out of order cpus where
speculative execution may continue using
and even bring back the state just
flushed
from the domain we just switched from
okay so
the two answer properties is that we
only need a few academic papers but
basically the idea is if you are able to
tag the security domain in the
microarchitecture
you are able to revert the state also in
the macro architecture
for example tag your audio um
let's say your
control flow pass into
your speculation
let's say
to say that
you tag you take every speculation with
the security domains and if
the speculation is not correct you
just slice everything that is in the
security domains that is not in this
element so you evade the states you
invalidate the cache and validate all
your microstructures
that are
no androids
and basically speculations
in two
different security domains should be
completely
invisible to each other
you cannot use any
you will lose performance but you will
again in security
i'm not sure if i'm
clear
so of course uh the way to do properly
that's it's far harder in practice than
just injury
okay so
ben
i asks
so then ask if we can if it's easy to
clear large amounts of micro
architectural states quickly
and
the answer is today no
basically you will have to
make different products in the
microstructures
so the best example i think for that are
the cache the l1 data cache and you have
let's say two modes wide backwards
where you will write the data back to
the upper level cache only when you want
to clear the states
or you will have right through mods
where you will update upper level cache
as you write to the first cache
if you have a white back and you want to
flush everything it will take a lot of
times you will have to transfer the wall
l1 cache to l2 for example
but if you have a right through cache
then it will be fast
what i think i think is that now
today we are using right by cash mainly
for performances
but for security we should use right
through caches you know that were the
best trade-off between security and
performances
so this can be done for caches and in
fact you can have the centered off for
nearly every microarchitecture
architectural state but you will have to
design your core fonts
okay i think it answers the questions
so andre asked is there any public
implementation of them switch
instructions uh so
today is not available it will be part
of the artifact of our paper that will
be out
in november so we have to clean up the
code but it will be available
for november normally
for the cadis
so basically you have a updated
toolchain
programs and course that use this
instructions
which core are you using to implement
this side of interest
so we are from the sketch
they've been done from scratch
so typically for the for the point that
ben uh
was the point been made that's we try to
modify a crow but in fact it's a lot
harder to modify an existing core in
order to modify all the microstructures
to handle quick flashing then just make
your own
so we have two
completely new cores for that
okay great so well actually one last
question we
i guess we're up against time but maybe
we just squeeze this in so
yunsi asks if you revise the icy with
additional instructions where
where do you add these instructions to
what stage source code or compiler
i i think that the answer is not no so i
think that's the question is should
these instructions
should be transparent to the developer
or should they
be available to developers
and i think it's a good question i don't
have
a nice answer too
easily of course the compilers and
i think the operating systems should
hide them item
but it may be interested
uh interesting to use them in
applications like for example you are
doing your server and you want to switch
to
to serve a new user then now you should
use these instructions
so the answer will depend on how easy
they are to use and how they interact
with the patching systems
great okay so let's
um
call time thank ronan and move on to the
next talk