a few closing remarks i don't have too
many but for sure i want to say um some
thanks and particularly to the speakers
at the workshop for
their time and their effort especially
simon who i think came from another
meeting so he's had a busy evening um
also to kay for the technical help as i
said at the start i don't think we could
do that without that help
and then finally for everyone for uh
attending um i said at the start there
was some debate whether this workshop
made sense but i think the kind of
number of people with some interest sort
of validates that
um i've never really seen a successful
round of applause on zoom um but maybe
you can sort of show some love in the
chat window for the speakers and that
acts as some kind of replacement or i
can give you a
a visual round of applause anyway
oh everybody can unmute and clap their
hands huh we're not going to crash soon
try try hard
thanks to dan for organizing it