talk
um
so our next speaker is
barbara gigle
uh barbara's currently a phd student in
the secure systems group at graz
university of technology and she's going
to talk about coco which i guess is more
like an approach or technique enabled by
risk five rather than something kind of
within risk five right
over to you
okay can you see my slides
uh yes you'll just need to um we see all
of them ah never mind that's good i will
tell you that there is a small black bar
in the upper right hand corner that is
most likely the zoom controls
if you can move those out of the way
that would be fine but if you don't have
any um
any content up there then it'll be fine
i think it's okay like that right okay
good
okay so
welcome everyone um my name is barbara
and today
i will talk about coco which stands for
co-design and co-verification
of mask software on risk-file cpus
this work was joint work by
my colleagues and me from kratz
university of
technology so
in physically side channel attacks the
setting looks similar to this so we have
one attacker
who has physically access to a
cryptographic device
and for example the attacker can use an
oscilloscope to
um
yeah to observe the power consumption of
the device in our case this device is a
cpu
and in that case the power consumption
will depend on two things first of all
the instruction which is currently being
executed and second
the data which is involved in the
instruction so the data which lies in
the register file and the data memory
to prevent such attacks we can apply the
masking counter measure this which
basically splits any intermediate value
s
into multiple random shears
and um the attacker can now or has to
now
observe or shares
to be able to deduce some information
about the native value
and as you can imagine constructing such
masked implementations is not an easy
task and therefore we want to have
verification tools which help us by
doing so
and such tools can
more concretely check the separation of
our shares
when a certain mask program or
a certain piece of musk hardware is
computing something
okay so
those
masked
verification tools
so far exist either for masked hardware
circuits
for example here we have rebecca and
mask for reef as one of the first tools
and
basically these tools check
for a given
mask circuit
whether there exists the gates which
combines two shares and these checks are
done in the so-called classical probing
model
which defines the abilities as an
attacker
in the classical probing model the
attacker has
d probes and these probes can be
distributed
onto the
gates
and then the probes will deliver
basically the value
which are computed by these gates to
their attacker
and most importantly this includes
glitches and transitions which might be
visible on
on a certain wire which is being probed
the second class of verification tools
are constructed for verifying mask
software
in the so-called software probing model
and these checks are rather on
algorithmic level
and hardly consider the hardware or cpu
which is in the end
used to execute the software
and the assumption is basically that the
hardware is secure so our processor does
not introduce additional security
threads to the software
unfortunately this is often not the case
because
as it is with every hardware
there can be glitches and transitions in
the circuit
therefore what we want to have is a tool
which can verify a certain piece of mask
software when we execute it with a
certain concrete cpu
and the cpu is
best represented by a netlist so after
the synthesis and everything
uh yeah and with cocoa we have such a
tool
now let's look at one specific example
which we have in almost every processor
we have a register file and the register
file can be
um
yeah a thread to your mask software so
this is a good example of hardware which
yeah which might reduce the security
level of your mask software
in this example we have four registers
here and here we have a multiplexer tree
which is used
to
address
the registers
and here in the gray box you see the
software we want to execute so we want
to store x2 and then x1
additionally we know that we have a
program which has two shares s1 and s2
and the shares are in registers x1 and
x2
okay so in the first cycle
we want to store x2 which means
we have to read x2 from the register
file
the multiplexes here
get their respective value
and the value of s2 will kind of
propagate through the circuit until we
see the date at the report
in the next cycle
we want to store x1 which means we have
to read x1 from the register file
and what happens now is that this
multiplexer here switches
the select signal from 0 to 1 which
leads to the output of the multiplexer
switching
from the previous value to the new and
we have a transition from one share to
another which means we have a leak
in our program
this is
you might argue that this is a rather
obvious case because
you're kind of accessing your shares in
two consecutive cycles but
there are cases in which it's not that
obvious for example here we want to
store x3 and then x4
when we read in the first cycle x3
this multiplexer again has the value 1
but this one kind of selects that the
data from the lower part of the register
file should be read in the end
and in the second cycle we want to read
x4
and again this multiplexer switches from
one to zero
which is why we have a transition now
from the first chair to the second on
this wire
and this means we have a leak in our
program even though we do not touch any
of the shares
and such situations are
very hard to find without a proper
verification pool
so
this is why we yeah constructed coco
which basically takes a piece of mask
software written in risk file assembly
and
the hardware which is used to execute
the software in our case this was the
risc-5 ebx core
yeah and coco can then verify or prove
that the software as executed with the
e-bike score is secure
or does not introduce any leaks in the
context of masking
we cannot adapt the classical probing
model which we already saw for hardware
here but we have to kind of make some
constraints to this classical probing
model because in the classical probing
model the attacker can kind of observe a
wire for an infinite amount of time and
if we do that
in a cpu the attacker can simply choose
the register file output and observe it
for an infinite amount of time so for
all the cycles
the program will last and then our
scheme is immediately broken so we
constrain the classical probing model by
the notion of time what does this mean
now the attack has again deep ropes
and can
use one probe
to measure information
at one specific location but also in one
specific clock cycle so this means the
probes can be distributed
to be either at the same location in
different clock cycles or at different
locations in the same clock cycle or a
mix of both
let's have a look at the co-verification
flow of coco so here we have again our
software and the hardware and the first
step is to simulate the software
execution with the hardware
there we get out
a dump of control signals
which kind of maps the software to the
hardware in terms of control signals
next we perform an annotation
which means that we tell the verifier
where the shares and randomness is
located
so in which registers is
the first year for example and this is
done on bit level of course we cannot
only annotate registers but also memory
locations
and these two things are then given to
the verifier the verifier will run the
verification for a few cycles
and then output yes the execution is
secure
or no it's not secure and there's a leak
in cycle 8 at a specific gate
ok
so
the co-verification methodology itself
was inspired by rebecca which is
a pure
hardware verification tool
and we extended it such that we can
execute mask software
on a concrete cpu netlist so on on a
hardware
and
it works roughly like that we have the
labels which we saw earlier in the
annotation step
and we propagate these labels through
the whole cpu netlist
and um
for each gate in the sibu netlist we
then compute the so called correlation
the correlation will tell us if there is
a correlation to a native value which we
don't want to have
and can either be saber or transient
transient means that glitches and
transitions
will be taken into account
let's have a look at the short example
so here you see a circuit
which consists of a wire a which comes
out of combinatorial logic and a wire b
which comes out directly of a register
and both inputs then go into an and gate
and in this case the value b will would
be our control signal
and um
here you can see the dump of contour
signals for three cycles n n plus one
and n plus two and you see that b
first is one and then switches to zero
so the output of x will basically first
be a and then zero
when we now want to compute the
correlation of x
we would for first of all focus on the
stable correlation set so in the first
cycle since x displays the value of a
x will correlate to a
but then
since x switches to zero it then
correlates to zero or a constant
the verification tool does not
make any difference between constants or
or the zeros that you see here
then
for the case of the transient
correlation
we also have the same in the first cycle
but in the second cycle we have to add a
to the correlation set
why is that the case because b switches
from one to zero
so for a short amount of time
in
the first
yeah in the first
time frame of the cycle m plus 1 we will
still see the old value of the wire a
until the 0 from register b will
propagate to the end gate
and in the next cycle we can safely
assume that x does not correlate to a
anymore because
b has been stable 0 for two cycles now
yeah and this is a quite
nice concept which we also applied to
the register file so to construct the
secure register file which you see
here so we placed an
gate before each register
and this gate determines if we
we will see the the register value at
the gate output
and as a gate value we use the one hot
encoded register address
so in this register here
at most one bit will be one
and this refers to kind of the gate is
open and we want to read the register
if we now consider the example where we
want to store x2 and then x3
we see that in the first cycle
x2 the gate of x2 will be open and
therefore the data can kind of
be seen at the read part
and in the next cycle
we will have
the data of x3 here at the read port so
at most we can see at the read point at
the value of two registers
yeah
and
now let's come to the second part of
coco which is called the co-design we
conducted the case study with the risc-5
e-bikes core
and the e-bike score is a rather small
core a 32-bit core with
which is in order
and has a two-stage pipeline
and uh yeah it's applied rather to small
iot devices and smaller use cases
and then we tried to harden the ebex
core with cocoa against side channel
attacks so what we did was we
constructed a
set of mask software implementations and
then tried to verify
that software implementations with cocoa
and
yeah coco reported a whole list of leaks
um
and
in yeah this leaks were in various parts
of the cpu and we had two strategies to
remove these leaks first of all
sometimes we decided to
do changes in the cpu
or in the hardware itself so
this
would
for example be the same as we did in the
register
we introduced the skating mechanism to
have to enable secure register
reads
but sometimes um changes in the hardware
are too costly and we rather want to
adapt the software
and this is what we call the software
constraints the software constraints are
basically a set of rules
and if these rules are followed by the
programmer of the mask software
this already helps to prevent some known
leakages and of course if the the
software does not
meet this software constraints coco will
report it
by pointing out that there is a leak in
a certain cycle at a certain
gate okay let's have a look at an
example of how a software constraint
could look like so here we have our
hardened register file again
with two shares in the registers
and now we want to first store x2 which
means we see the value of the second
chair at the read port a and then we
want to store x1
which means we create a transition here
and the software constraint to prevent
such kinds of
of of leakages would be the chairs of
the same secret must not be accessed
within two successive cons instructions
so between the two store um instructions
there should be another unrelated
instruction for example a knob
which prevents this transition at the
read pod a of the register file
okay then we also found some further
problems in the
in the core
um
first of all we found out that there is
a hidden state in the load store unit
which is basically a register
and every time you store something to
memory this register
gets the value of whatever you want to
store so this could be a bad if you
store two shares because then you have a
register override
um another thing where the computation
units so the alu the multiplier and the
csr unit because they were always
computing so if we
kind of
for example execute a load instruction
still the alu would compute
the xor
without being needed and
this specifically
creates leaks when you want to use
parallel masking schemes
so in in these parallel masking schemes
you do not place all the bits of one
share in one register but distribute
order n bits of one share to end
different registers
and then
this means that one register will then
store
the different shares of the same secret
and in the case of for example the csr
unit or also the multiplier
some parts of that combine the bits of
one register and this creates a leaks
because your bits are two shears
and one point is also the communication
with the data memory so um there are
strategies
you you can follow to have
secure loads and stores from into memory
but i won't go into detail about that
right now if you're interested you can
simply have a look at our paper
okay
now let's have a short look at our
evaluation so
the total overhead of the
um yeah of the security measurements we
built into e-bikes is about 10
so we compared here the basic design
without any security feature to the
design which has or security features
enabled
and we also tried to um
yeah to to
do some small benchmarks so to benchmark
our tour
um for example here we tried some simple
end gates but also
some broken implementations
broken means that the software
constraints which i showed you before
were not met by the software
and
yeah
coco in this case pointed out that the
12th cycle is the problem
we also had some bigger test cases like
the ass box
and also some higher order tests like a
ketchup s box and a third order dom and
gate
yeah
so
now i want to give you a short outlook
on what could also be done with coco
we managed to analyze
a bigger core also the risk five swerve
core
um the swerve core is also a 32-bit core
is also in order
but has a dual issue pipeline which
means it can execute two instructions in
one cycle
um it also has instead of two
pipeline stages it has nine pipeline
stages so it's bigger than the ebex core
and also has some other applications
like
automotive or more data intensive iot
devices
and in our analysis we tried to
yeah we tried to find out
whether
these pipeline stages or execution units
or data caches in the core
have some effect on the security of
masked hardware of mask software sorry
um yeah and we could do that with the
coco
tour and uh yeah just to a short outlook
we we managed to show some interesting
properties
of those pipelines
in the connection of mask software
yeah so
in summary there exists what we call the
hardware software cap because former
proofs for mask software often do not
consider
the hardware
as it should be
therefore we can have coco which helps
with the co-verification
of mask software
on concrete cpu netlists
and also with the co-design such that we
can find
some patches for the hardware and also
constraints for the software for a
specific cpu
here in this talk i presented the case
study about the ebooks core which you
can if you are interested also
read up about in our paper
and if you're interested about the
second case study with the swerve core
you can also find it here in the paper
and yeah i also included the links here
so this was basically my presentation
thank you very much for listening if you
have any questions i'd be happy to
answer them
yeah thanks very much father that's
really interesting
um we have got a couple of minutes for
questions if if there are any
okay so a lot a long one in the track
window from c
let me read it out for you so
do the proposed revisions security
patches eg gated or unused computational
units have an impact on the verification
performance
um
i
so
on the verification performance
yes it kind of did because
for the
for the case of the computation units
which were kind of always computing
we also introduced such a gating
mechanisms such that the alu for example
would be
turned off when we do not need it
and therefore of course
the data will not enter the alu anymore
during verification and this
yeah this kind of cuts away the alu from
the verification process and this
increases the performance
yeah
and
yeah about the second part of the
question
um yes we could actually apply coco
also to arm processors but the problem
there is that we do not have the net
list so the net list of the processor is
not public and
um yeah without the netlist we cannot do
the verification
and
yeah but if the net list were
public available
we could of course just apply the same
approach we have with coco
for an arm assembly executable and for
any arm core you wish
i hope this answers your question
great okay
um also we're kind of up against time so
if there aren't any other questions then
i think we thank barbara and move on to
the next talk
thanks a lot
um so