alright we'll go ahead and get started
here thank you for the introduction a
little about myself before we hope go
ahead and dive in headfirst Josh
Danielson i'm a senior security manager
with an ax way actually has a greater
organization focuses on b2b EDI type of
software as cloud has kind of exploded
we've opened up our new cloud computing
division probably about seven years ago
and I've been hitting up all things
security since then so I've been with
them for a level four years and I was
probably the first security dedicated
higher since us and things got started
it's been an interesting challenge
because we've taken a traditional
software company and tried porting him
over to be a true cloud company so it's
been a very challenging interesting
process we've been going through I got
my started got my start in DoD moved to
the the academic space did some stuff
around there move the ax away and
actually Albia moving over to head all
things security at a capital one in
their new cloud computing division at
the end of this month so things keep on
going as we all know feel free to follow
me on twitter as well lets you keep
pretty active on there what's the first
thing people think of when they think of
cloud people think secure right well
yeah not so much despite all be all the
newer technologies on all the
advancements that have been made in
cloud computing it's still not a trusted
platform by and large but we all know
saying no as a security failure we've
all been to experiences in all of the
meeting to the floor that all the
infrastructure all the application all
developer folks will get in one room and
buy some reason all the security people
don't get invited I know I haven't I
think a lot of you actually have as well
there's a very good reason security
people hold things up they don't see
value add a lot of times and I think
that's one in our case is where we have
to do a better job communicating what we
can actually do giving them more options
and actually showing true value add to
the organization outsourcing in general
one of the first things we discuss in
information security won't ever talk
about cloud is you can't outsource your
critical functions that's insane they
control the data you have no control
over it well we do these things every
single day right after all we don't have
a money under store in either mattress
and despite we know and trust the big
we trust the overall governance in the
overall structure in which these these
components work under cloud computing is
still continued mature so I'm not way in
any way comparing it to something much
more to mature as far as the banking
industry we have the FDIC and all these
other kind of checks and balances but it
is getting there this is one of my
favorite quotes from from the CIO the
formerly with the US government
basically he summed it up in one long
sentence Amazon Web sevens on web
services google impute all these large
platform providers they have experts
that can do these things and can focus
on these security tasks better than any
any one of our groups that more than
likely can so it's kind of more
important thing and that's why some of
these organizations such as Amazon Web
Services can't have true enterprise type
of platforms that we can piggyback off
of so I'm going to preface the rest of
rest of everything I'm saying with an X
way you we do use Amazon Web Services
I'm not going to say they're the best
cloud provider or they're the only one
if if you're in dog Gartner and all that
a kind of marketing stuff there at the
top right corner which is a good thing
so just kind of one bird note I don't
work with Amazon we don't have any
partner we don't have any other
partnership besides we use them I'm not
getting paid for them but rest of my
conversation will be will be a lot of
focus around amazon web services
technologies the shared responsibility
model this is probably one of the few
things that shows a lot of security
especially a lot of season people off I
regularly get in discussions with
auditors and a lot of potential
customers they bring the security folks
in and then we go through traditional
audit the hoops and whatnot and one
thing they'd actually don't understand
is what you're responsible for as a
customer what the provider is possible
as a provider and what our customers are
responsible as a customer so you can
take a nice look right here this is one
of the things I stole from amazon web
services they have a lot of
documentation a lot of white paper some
really good stuff if you're really
interested in learning some more it's
freely available there's hundreds of
pages of this stuff you can dive in
headfirst and get a better idea their
security programs and recommendations so
we talked about the blue stack over here
at the top of what they recommend you do
to do as well so this is kind of
important distinction we're going to
kind of strip away some of the layers of
cloud and explain why this is actually
more important when we strip away the
layers of the CloudStack you can see
that kind of blue area amazon web
services fun
at the very bottom and infrastructure as
a service as you go up and see platform
and software as a service these are the
areas that people become a lot less
comfortable with i'll give you one
specific example i know work with
auditors quite a bit customers and pci
and others of the like they come in and
say do you do logging for failed logins
well we do at the operating system level
at the infrastructure as a platform
service truck sure as a service level so
we checked the box and keep going
unbeknownst to them they forgot to ask
about any other stuff and these are
seasoned people have been doing this
stuff for a very very long time they
just don't know so knowing knowing your
shared responsibility knowing which what
cloud solution you're looking at who
you're looking to partner with and what
you as a as a customer are you looking
to get into it's really critically
important you understand what service
you're looking at so know where you're
at in the cloud but if you suck now
you'll still be pleasantly surprised at
the lack of change when you move to
cloud you're still responsible for doing
the same stuff and now although amazon
web services may take care of the data
center and they may take care of a lot
of physical stuff and they may take care
of some of the other things basically
the the the mason-dixon line is right
below the hypervisor which is at the
operating system level so you're
responsible for it within apps amazon
web services for doing the operating the
host excuse me the guest operating
system so red hat windows whatever you
may be and they run some bastardized
version of zen that they run underneath
the end a responsible for you and that
same thing on the network side of the
house they were on all the network
hardware you're responsible for doing
all stuff right above that so you can
still have the capability to networking
a CLS and whatnot so instead what we're
left left left with is not inherently a
secure or unsecured cloud but a platform
that can be secure for certain use cases
when you use appropriately so a quick
rundown of agenda items I'm going to go
over cloud principles understanding what
a cloud actually looks like there's been
a lot of misconception as far as what
the cloud actually is I have to
constantly report back to my boss and
tell them all the crap that's coming out
that is just complete garbage so all the
stuff that's coming out recently around
the business side of the house is that
cloud is not cheaper in fact it's
actually more expensive
well when you do this thing called cloud
washing you take your traditional
software you plop it on ec2 instance and
you call yourself cloud oh yeah that's
not actually cloud and actually spending
more money well going through a few more
use cases you can actually take take
advantage of the cloud principles and
you can have a really true cloud
solution so that's kind of an important
distinction we talked about Claude 10 on
that cloud 20 you will never do patching
again you will never do vulnerability
scanning again people never ever log in
or SSH rdp are otherwise directly into a
box I'm talking about admins route
otherwise I'm not just talking about
users I'm talk about no one the ssh 22
is off security and DevOps will kind of
talk about how everything kind of
merchants and blends into a cloud dev
psych ops model and then have you
actually manages a scalability when we
look at some of the true unicorns in the
industry right now if you want to take
Netflix as an example when house of
cards came out a few a few weeks ago it
was rumored that they actually they were
using one-third of the entire Internet
bandwidth at that single weekend that's
pretty freaking insane how do you manage
all these systems that are coming up and
down so you have a Friday night comes up
everyone turns on their house of cards
saturday morning around 1am everyone
spins it back down you have to stand up
hundreds of systems thousands of systems
actually could facilitate this so we'll
talk about how you actually manage that
type of elasticity in these environments
and then a little peek about what's
coming next
principles the first one is service base
so this is this is commoditization of IT
we all know what this is this is you
plug in your your lamp into the wall and
the electricity kind of works you plug
this in you plug in your server and then
that kind of starts working and you're
you start up your server and starts
working automatically so that's kind of
service base we all know what that one
looks like scalable and elastic so this
is one of the things a lot of security
people kind of fight with initially and
say we can't secure this systems are all
constantly coming up and coming down how
do you actually secure this stuff well
I'll tell you this is actually one of
the things that usually used to our
advantage when Amazon Web Services was
notified and everything came elwell
shell-shocked a few months ago they're
actually able to patch shell-shocked
across their entire load balancers
within three days when you talk about
enterprise and doing any type of
patching patching anything in 3d is
absolutely ridiculous so this is but so
you entirely look at it what's something
that looks like a disadvantage and you
turn it into an advantage so using the
elasticity using scalability to your
advantage shared to some degree there's
going to be something that is all we
shared I talked about the shared
responsibility model earlier you have to
understand where you are in that stack
and kind of what you actually have to
provide for your customers or what you
have to actually manage on your side of
the house of things metered by use this
just basically means you get a bill at
the end of the month kind of like you
get your electric arel tricity bill or
whatever it may be and then you get only
pay for what you use and you don't pay
for what you don't when you're talking
to your business people out there I
always tell my boss this is capex versus
effects and he gets all excited in the
Google we only pay for what we use for
and what not so the business people kind
of love that term when you talk about
meter boot by use use of inner
technologies this is really leveraging
open api's this is using mobile and what
not to take advantage of some of these
type of characteristics so we'll dive in
cloud 10 versus cloud to cloud 10 this
is the original model t it's good for
what it was but it will no longer
suffice what does this actually look
like so that I was giving the example
about cloud wash this is saw the
organization's right now that are just
taking traditional piece of software
they spin up an ec2 instance on amazon
web services and they install themselves
there and they call themselves cloud or
they come up with a hardon appliance and
they install into the ada US marketplace
and say we're in the cloud now yeah
not really don't tell some of these
vendors out there because I want to blow
their mind stepa with several releases
annually we know what this looks like
whenever there's an update of a database
when there's an update of major
operating systems and a major update any
type of software it's all hands on deck
it's a pain in the ass for that whole
week everyone's on call you know it's
going to be a pain we all know what this
looks like it's these huge massive
updates that we no one knows what's
going to happen but you know something
bad is going to happen and cloud washed
I mean this is kind of a marketing term
that is going thankfully starting to
become a little bit more use and kind of
calling out these people are trying to
be cloud but really actually aren't so
that's what cloud isn't what is cloud
then so I cloud I say cloud 1 dot 0 and
cloud 20 cloud $1 really just porting
your stuff over cloud to da dough is
really building your software on top of
the platform to take advantage of some
of the things that I was describing
earlier so this is building your
software on top of the provider within
amazon web services they have different
types of storage you can actually use so
you can use local volumes called EBS
volumes you can use something that
functions a little bit more of a slower
sand is called s3 and have a really long
one really for archival purposes called
the glacier if you can kind of tear out
your stuff so we actually tear our logs
for example you can actually better take
advantage of that but you have to be
able to custom create your applications
on top of this infrastructure as code as
cloud it becomes much more popular there
will be less and less administrators and
will be much more type of developer
types i could say right now i'm not a
developer but i had to spend a lot more
time learning JSON XML and whatnot
because guess what my job as
administrator and architect isn't going
to exist in the same way it does in
about 5 10 years or so you have to learn
to code from where comes the rule sets
when it comes to embedding hardening
baselines and whatnot I'll going to get
into cloud factory of how you embed
these things in by default so you no
longer have to do patching you no longer
have to do one ability scanning stream
streamlined agile processes this is
taking advantage of some such things so
you don't have to do patching into
whatnot so I'm steel too much of the
thunder coming down but i just want to
point that out and what does this look
like several releases the day so i know
i said the example earlier with amazon
web services of how they actually patch
shell-shocked win a few days some of
these organizations are known for doing
few hundred updates in a single day
opposed a few every single year if you
learn to take advantage of those it'll
really change the way you can actually
manage your environments so what are a
few traits of a successful cloud
security program some of this we all
know is kind of redundant so I'm not
gonna dive in that know what framework
you're working with have some reference
architectures I know I mentioned a
little bit of api's one thing I what
kind of touch on is some of the logging
some organizations that are truly cloud
and when I really take advantage the
average lifetime for server is 22 days
that's kind of around the benchmark
that's around the threshold so no longer
our servers these cuddly pets that you
keep forever and eventually they die in
six or seven years there are things that
actually are constantly rotating on a
regular basis so how do you actually
monitor those how do you actually log
those how do you go back when you try to
find a host for a system you're trying
to look at and it no longer exists
because it got it terminated Oh three
months ago I'll talk about some of those
things coming up see I management so for
any people have to do only this type of
process or ITIL and all these other
types of terms we all know we have to
comply with configuration items good no
longer will you ever have to do change
management around your servers
fundamentally that completely changes
because your servers always coming up
and down instead you're CIS become your
your cloud for mission templates your
docker images your open stat scripts so
that will change and you will no longer
have to have change control on your
servers as this H is off our DP is off
no one's logging into any of these boxes
they have no reason to why does someone
actually log into a box for linux box to
do something they go in to fix it update
a config update some type of parameter
you go back and you change that in your
CloudFormation template and you never
have to log into the box there's no
reason to you shoot the box in the head
you spin up a new one in its place and
it gets stood up and it gets repeated in
a few instances that's how you actually
do things and how that's how things will
change in that way um see I management
for the first time ever I came from
government I was doing auditing kind of
analyst work there for a while and I
remember one of the biggest things i
actually had there's always some jerk in
the coroner who decided that he didn't
want to wait for IT so he wanted to put
in his new his own
this router and whatnot and he had his
whole thing going because he had his
other personal laptop and whatnot so for
the first time ever in cloud you
actually know what you actually have in
front of you so this is a screenshot
that we have in a console you know
exactly what's in front of you that's a
luxury i know i never had in previous
environments you know exactly who's
connecting what within your environment
and we kind of take advantage of this
with our configuration management tool
we use puppet other people you chef and
what not the puppet worked in our
environment we bounced at the
configuration within puppet against us
in real time so anytime anyone stands
something else and it's not enrolled
within puppet which controls all of our
logging all of our hardening and whatnot
we get a notification in real time if
something isn't within scope everything
is being managed by our security teams
so DevOps what is DevOps I'll be honest
I've been working on cloud for dedicated
for about three years now I still don't
really actually no I was doing some item
riding variety square coming out with a
new cloud security certification and
they had all these people from Miss in
ISO all arguing with each other and
they're arguing that the sea in cloud
should be capitalized or lowercase I
like good God these are supposed to be
the industry experts creating all the
baselines and all the revisions to see
firmness yeah that's the state of the
industry I'm sorry to say so when all
these people and my boss and all these
other people start using these terms in
cloud and whatnot start misusing them no
one can argue if the sky is blue because
we all know it is and everyone says it
is isn't we know they're crazy if
someone says cloud isn't cloud and
weirdness using things and kind of using
these terms it's because it's not
defined yet even people working on it
really don't have a good enough idea yet
to come up with a single set of terms
and whatnot I sing these people arguing
it doesn't make you feel good but DevOps
it's really just the it's a philosophy
of how do you actually connect debe
development with operations we've we've
had a few successful experimentations in
this it's really just making everyone
own to whole solutions instead of one
group pointing four fingers at the other
and vice versa and what not is having
them kind of collaborate much more of a
collaborative type of culture and some
things we've actually done to make this
much more successful we've made some of
our developers be on call and fix
operational issues we've taken some of
our system administrators and we pour
them on the
a development side of the house and may
then write some code so having them have
dual ownership across the board is
really kind of critical to building that
culture of DevOps and making sure that
you actually build solutions that are
much more robust much more agile
so I talked about this before we're
really beginning to streamline and
really assembly line driven asset
management enroll used to this type of
stuff as far as provisioning new system
and it comes down the line and six weeks
from now you get it racked and stacked
you get it connected and then you can
kind of use it and we're like that's
that's assembly line use well then
everyone kind of goes in and a custom
I'm talking about a hundred percent
managing customized from the get-go so
like I said before instead of actually
managing servers we don't manage any
service anymore we managed docker images
we manage a fuse OpenStack we don't use
OpenStack house but it's another one and
then also cloud formation templates
those are the things you manage those
are the things you need to scrutinize
and make sure that people aren't going
to messing with your servers no one's
logging into them who cares they're
constantly coming up and down anyways
those are no longer things you have to
scrutinize and worry about because you
know from the core you know from the
very start that they're being being
secured by default you begin to rely on
tagging logging metadata these are what
your configuration items are there are
no more snowflakes no longer out these
kind of one-off servers that are kind of
floating in the corner by themselves and
everyone oh yeah that's the one server
that there's a one critical function so
don't touch it because everything is
going to break this has a heavy reliance
than api's this is where we worked with
a lot of vendors so far and we really
haven't seen a lot of integration quite
yet we've had to kind of build our own
so allowing all these kind of
configuration uh to be synchronized with
in we use splunk spunks probably one of
our favorite tools mom that's probably
the only one I'll men because that's one
of the few that does a really really
good job at doing it but they gave me
much more relying on these api's we're
really be critical to your success and
managing all these systems across the
board so I kind of poked at it earlier
but we're all used to server hugging
everyone gets a box and he likes the
cuddlin like to keep it forever they
like to name it and they have their IP
and they had their hostname and these
things are really meaningful some people
actually rely on we also used to
remember the people who can spit him out
an X remember him off the top of the
head and nose every single hosted within
your environment or at least has a good
idea of them there static systems they
never really changed he stand up for
they stay up for a few years and they're
used to staying there forever we never
really moved them their shift them they
stay the same there are snowflakes
they're all kind of sora one-offs each
server is different than the
and otherwise or looking at now is
service orientated solutions not server
orientated solutions so this is where I
peas and names you come meaningless I
don't even I can tell you the ranges but
I have absolutely no clue what the bot
what our critical boxes energy I peas
are almost no one else in our
environment either again these systems
are ephemeral like I said servers are
now lasting several days not several
years anymore these servers become
mechanized by code so I'm not a
developer but I had to learn a lot more
of the development JSON XML and
otherwise to begin integrating a lot of
these components together you have to
also be able to shoot the other node in
the head you have to be able at any
moment get rid of any air systems any of
your servers and know that they can be
resilient not to come back into place I
know I use netflix has a lot an example
but they have a tool called a security
monkey I cheeks chaos monkey and it goes
around shutting off shutting off random
service about the entire environment the
whole goal is that if you're resilient
at any given time when something that
actually does happen you'll be ready for
because you've already been ready for it
so managing scalability I'll give kind
of a simplified version of this but I
think it's still pretty useful oh we
call it a Bluegreen deployment we've a
few other people actually using this
environment to I haven't seen it cut too
much fire yet but you can find if you do
a few searches for it basically it's
this you have a running stack you have
your green stack and it's running all
the stuff you currently need so if this
is patch management this may be a dated
version of open SSL a new vulnerability
comes out you have to create a new one
so you actually update a new a new stack
and all this stuff is being done in real
time this is not a whole bunch of server
in whole bunch of time this is all being
done in real time in cloud formation
templates it takes several minutes to
mimic a current environment of a few
hundred servers if this isn't a whole
manual process that has to take a
scrutiny week or so to get done so you
stand up a new environment with the open
updated version openssl you swap this
through your load balancers that you
have in front that's kind of pron kind
of tried anything looking thing in front
and you swap it to the new one and keep
in mind your your static content
whatever maybe you can see the back end
database on the other side in the back
end that stays the same but your servers
that are just doing the processing those
are ephemeral and then you get rid of
the old dated version
so kind of quickly touching on this as
far as a security management I know I
talked about vulnerability management
patch management and whatnot monitoring
a little bit well but this is how things
will begin to change you will never have
to patch your systems again because
there's no reason to you update the base
image in Amazon they call it a mi and
Amazon machine image you upload that
base image you shoot any type of servers
you have in the head and you replace
them you back fill them all this happens
in a few minutes so what we do we
actually have a cloud factory so I want
to give one specific example in here of
when we stand up a new customer
environment we have our base am I we
have multiple products multiple types of
solutions but we have a base am I Amazon
machine image we have and it rolls down
to factory line and in there we're able
to embed all of our security baseline
wearable ensured that splunk forwarders
actually monitoring to our indexers
properly we're able to ensure we're
building out documentation for our
customers that need that some have some
specific requirements that have
everything that need to be document some
some governments and whatnot still want
to ensure everything named everything's
Probert will give it to them we have
this all created this is already
scripted as well we have performance
testing integration testing across the
board as well from there we can do our
install scripts for some of our
customized stuff and at the very end you
have a lot of stuff so I'm not just
talking about the image i'm not just
talking about single server i'm talking
about the entire environment i'm saying
network ACL security groups load
balancers all these types of things that
you have to create an entire solution on
not just the server or an application or
a database or whatever this is
everything that comes into one single
piece if I'm zooming interest that first
slide this is the cloud the cloud bakery
so you had the base am I it rolls down
the factory for the bakery floor it
turns in these two instance you're able
to insert any type of repositories
anything that's actually custom for that
single a single solution back then at
that point you're able to install the
any type of custom applications in our
case we have our axway products will be
able install whatever that version
whatever that type of software our
custom need in that environment and it
rolls down and it gets born into an ec2
instance
and then within the cloud formation
templates this fits into the bigger
picture as I was describing before we're
not only you have everything sitting in
its own subnets and its own DMZ its own
back in its own front-end type of
systems you have its own virtual private
cloud as well so each new customer that
we provision has its own virtual private
cloud and this all comes together you
can see the left and right we have
different production systems this can be
a this can be your dr this can be
whatever you want it to be but we want
to show together and this is all
automated this is all comes together
this is not manual type of hands on the
keyboard type of work and I touched on
this before the best way to avoid
failure is to fail constantly and this
really i know i talked about security
monkey before but this is the ultimate
test of resiliency i'm not sure that
many people here can say with confidence
if you go out and plug one of your
servers that the surface is still going
to be up and running and you're not
gonna have too many complaints these are
types of things that you should be able
to do on a regular basis when you have a
true cloud environment because why not
if something fails and you know it fails
you can know what that looks like you
can script it to automatically become
resilient and self-healing Netflix is
everything gonna they're really one of
the huge proponents in this area and
they've open source a lot of stuff
they've come out with their whole simian
army they call it probably the biggest
boldest thing that came out with this
chaos of gorillas so if you're familiar
with amazon web services they have
certain availability zones within each
region and they have multiple regions
throughout the entire globe so in the
united states they have one in North
Virginia they have another one in
California somewhere and they have
another one for government up in Oregon
I think it is so within a single
availability zone though you can have a
cask real shut down an entire data
center for whatever you're running right
not everyone else's stuff but you can
have to shut down absolutely everything
that's running for you this came in
really useful a few years ago when
Amazon actually did have this happen and
they had an entire availabilities to get
zone go down and every single customer
went down in that availability zone
except for you guess that Netflix well
actually was testing this constantly
having a redundancy and constantly
testing their environment for these
types of things
a few things for embracing the DevOps
philosophy I encourage everyone to read
these aren't security Burke books per se
but they're really critical and
understanding how you can better manage
these types of denied dynamic
environments probably the one I would
say is kind of security is anti fragile
from the same to lib he describes a
property of anti fragility or there's no
really word for being anti fragile we
use words such as robust resilient to
describe things that you're resistant to
breaking so if i have a steal a steal
pot and I drop it may be resistant but
isn't anti fragile it doesn't become
stronger because I did do that well
that's the types of environment were
trying to build that do become stronger
because we actually have it undergo
these types of stress stress tests and
what's next a home or homomorphic
encryption this is probably one of newer
things that I think will really start to
get a lot of things take enough in the
cloud for a lot of businesses in a lot
of those countries over and over in
Europe I have to deal with these things
on a regular basis actually is actually
a French based company and our largest
revenue generators actually based out of
Germany so we have a lot of privacy
concerns from a lot of potential
customers all the time even before they
had Snowden stuff of the amount of two
years ago there was always Patriot Act
Patriot Act Patriot Act I mean all the
time we have to hear about the Patriot
Act and horrible we were as Americans
and whatnot and I guess it's kind of
true I don't know but anyways with the
advent of homework homomorphic
encryption these are the types of things
that will be and facilitate a lot more
trust for cloud so Alice hands Bob a
briefcase Alice ellen's Bob the account
how much money is in the briefcase and
Bob naturally says give me the key so I
can open up count the money Alice's know
i want you to count it by just from the
outside without actually looking at it
that's kind of home at homomorphic
encryption be able to process data just
looking at the encrypted bits this isn't
no longer theory anymore there's been a
few more updates on research I've seen
recently that this is already actually
happening it's nowhere near efficient
but it's already actually happening so
the biggest hurdle has already been done
indigestible big data I got a friend of
mine who actually runs the security team
over there at a Microsoft and Azure he
doesn't hold too much against me because
we run amazon but one of the things he
shared it was one of coolest things are
doing
there with endure us security operations
center their sock was actually making
big data much more digestible as you're
having so much more data than ever
before how do you actually respond how
do you actually alert to these types of
things so this is an actual screen shot
of one of the things that they're one of
the panels they actually have in your
sock you can actually see and hear
events as they're happening in real time
so you can see is kind of the analyst
right there is kind of zooming into a
subsection within a greater spectrum you
can actually see and hear these types of
events happening in real time so with
that thank you and that's everything
else i'm not sure if there's any
questions but uh no questions all right
feel free to come up i'll be around oh
no you did not so one of the pieces that
for actually I had the slide in here too
i think last time i did this
presentation i ran over a bit more let's
talk let's catch up after this because
it's probably one of the ones i actually
have a dedicated slide for this I ran
over last time as actually was giving
this talk at cactus con last week and so
they kind of scolded me so let's catch
up after this and I think that's a very
good question of Logging's one of the
bigger things that we have to do so
anything else so because we actually
don't have everything we have everything
located initially under local servers
which come up and down we have every you
splunk so we use slunk as their stem all
that data is actually still kept in
archive within splunk and we have that
teardown civil type of tears so for
hippo we have seven years for example
for those types of customers and we have
that in s3 bucket so we still are able
to maintain those to actually address
those compliance regimes and whatnot but
we do it in a little bit of a different
fashion so when they come back and look
at a server we act
can't go to a specific server that was
actually looking at we can go back to
the overall service and we can show them
every single server that was potentially
within scope of that which always
existed and we can show them the
assurance controls we have ensuring that
all systems that you just cause it
doesn't exist anymore that we have
changed control around the templates we
have changed control and all the logs
are within cloud sure we can go back and
show them this is when the server was
stood up this is when the servos stopped
they want to go through and look through
a few hundred servers have at it I felt
working with we worked with KPMG for a
sock one and ISO 20000 one stuff when we
worked with a few other organizations in
the healthcare space and also in the
financial sector as soon as you saw in
the assurance controls and you got a
really get them the warm fuzzies as far
as what you're actually doing it
actually works well they feel a lot
better at it and you can actually just
go to splunk and you can show them this
is what we've got Oh what server do you
want to look into we can show you all
the servers that were terminated within
the past year past month what do you
want to see all the servers that were
started in the past year past month we
can show them all that and we can show
them in a few moments not even minutes
we can show them like a few seconds it's
an easy drop down so once they kind of
see we actually know what we're doing
and you actually have a good handle of
it it usually gives people the assurance
they need and all the data is there it's
all within our splunk ins and indexers
so it's not actually hiding it's not
actually getting terminated the servers
are because they were really a femoral
that's just the processing piece but the
log data is still there anything else
all right thank you