awesome thank you keep it up for me
right alright so this is a title Justin
Larson follow me ironic nickname that's
because my nickname is slim I'm not
quite slim anymore good web app security
for work front formerly at task if you
don't know who work for an is and I'm
not good at slide so i just threw to me
so at least have some some fun so i may
be talking about layer which is a pen
testing collaboration framework tool it
was developed by Dan Kammen and tom
steel they both work for fishnet
security and it's a great way to
collaborate with your team as you do pen
tests so so there's a few problems um
does anybody do pen testing here on
their own maybe on their own stuff or
maybe they're not a pen tester because
I'm not a pen tester by trade but we do
pen testing and so there's always lots
of output from a hundreds of tools that
you can use to scan or do anything and
he times that by the number of testers
in the engagement and then so we have
duplicated work data gets lost and it's
very unorganized just some classic
problems with pen testing that we as a
team run into as well so actually Chris
just walked in he's the one that found
layer and showed us how to use it he
works at work front my boss so but layer
it runs with meteor and node J s so I
wanted to abandon even writing this
presentation once I found out about
meteor because it's a it's a pretty
awesome framework so you can do its jess
its javascript on the server and the
client so it's pretty awesome breathe
you get all the
the buzzwords down at the bottom slit
clean simple but it does so it like
it'll listen to the mongodb to see if
there's any changes and it'll just
update the page automatically without
having to be refreshed it's really quick
and the dinosaur is very important that
you save this so from asteroids if an
asteroids are in space the meteors that
stores are dumb so these are these are
the commands that you can do when
installing meteor or not meteor layer so
we'll go through those in a sec though
and if you don't follow infosec Taylor
Swift on Twitter you should it is a good
laugh just so you know and we'll go to
the demo that's the end of my slides so
I'm do you like demos then buckle up
that big enough can everyone see that
how could a group okay so it's pretty
simple to start you and able to start
script give it the IP that you want I'll
just gonna do localhost here and it
starts up so I've done this a few times
on this machine in the very first time
you do it it's going to set up a
self-signed sir i'm not going to go
through that this time because I've
already got to set up but it does that
and the first time you set it up so so
we don't have any MongoDB user setup so
we'll say yes wait note we wanted to say
no don't never get stopped
should read what it's asking we'll just
set up a Mongo user called Mongo the
password then it has to set up a layer
user and we'll do that as well and we're
up and running so pretty hard to do that
so this is actually wear layers running
so there we go and so first thing you
got to do is you get to create a user
and a password and it's pretty pretty
bare obviously because we haven't
created anything so we'll just create a
simple b-sides slc project and now we're
actually in in layer and so you can go
in we have house services
vulnerabilities yep I better okay is
that all right sighs can you see that
okay yeah so you have a lot of different
things you can put into to layer from
what I've noticed it's more of a network
penetration testing rather than
application I think maybe in the second
version they'll probably do some more
application specific because you can
import stuff from from Burt as well
and so but to me it's more of a network
security pen test so we will nur ability
services notes credentials and
contributor so little will create a
contributor I'm actually don't creating
them here setting so
I had one complaint
don't let you specify your password
twice so if you put in something you
don't think you put in OPM nightmare
you're set to delete the account but so
contributors we can just we add another
person and I only show that really
because down here on the bottom right
can you see that you have message you
have a little chat if you don't want to
use like your internal chat or whatever
and it works sometimes so if we logged
in as that other user
I got it right sweet so there's a chat
from earlier pretty simple okay so we
can go in and we can add hosts manually
which is always real fun add the IP
whatever fake hostname windows and
submit so there we have our our host
just one of them but who wants to
manually enter everything that's a
that's a pain so dan and tom created
what they call drones which are written
in python because they didn't want to
write them in javascript in case people
didn't really know how to write
JavaScript Python is pretty simple but
with a drone what it does is it will
parse through your data from your tools
that you have in imported directly into
layer for you so they've written drones
for see meses next pose and map and then
they have a Curragh one if you want to
pass in JSON to it and there's also
putter with a purpose eat one and I'll
see you there but and you can install
those the path just using pip which is
what I do makes it easier but or you can
just run it as a script as well but
let's get into down a the fun part so
this is our longer-dated database how we
get to it so we have to export
environment variable I spilled it very
closely so I did a really basic nmap
scan and to use the drones you just
drone dash in map and if you haven't
installed two paths and then what you
need layer is the project ID so it knows
which project that's going to and it
gives you that right at the top there
pretty convenient just paste that and
then you need the path to the file and
so connects and then tells you a
successful the project and then so it
processed seven house if we go back
there they are pretty quick and so you
and you change the colors whatever you
want the colors don't mean anything
unless you specified within your
organization what you want them to but
we can get to that we'll get to that
later on how you can automate that so
right now we did a very basic nmap scan
so we don't have any ports or anything
like that it was just a find the host
and you can go into this log and it'll
show you all the commands that you ran
so this was what our nmap scan was and
then this is what the drone imported and
it will tell you every event that occurs
so now if we go to her services we don't
have anything in there yet it's actually
that cutting up that's actually okay so
if we run another important another nmap
scan than they did you can watch the
data as it goes in so the bottom there
it is and then at the top it fills up so
and there's no need to refresh or
anything like that just quick and snappy
and then you can search I'm poured or
whatever you want to and then it'll show
you all those and then it's pretty cool
is over here this is just a text area
that shows up just the host IP so you
need to import this into another tool
you can is which is what i did so i used
a brute forcing tool called Medusa I
think it's pretty similar to Hydra just
little fork I found it first before I
found Hydra so I I used it so but I
think it will also work but the drone
that I wrote will work for Hydra as well
so we call dusa make sure that we have
this in our foot board
should go to prudential so this is where
do so will send its input C so we have
the four IPS that we put in the Medusa
somehow we were able to brute force all
of them not really that's fake data but
that's how you how we can import it so I
wanted to explain a little bit about how
that works so this is actually the drone
to get the script it gets called and it
imports this Medusa module which is
another python script that's actually
doing the parsing but it's going through
knit it's so the project it requires
argument one is that project ID and then
the argument to is the file and it sends
it to Medusa dot parse which is this
which I need to work on still but it
basically just looks for success in a
line and then it parses that line the
data that it wants and it returns a
dictionary and Python dictionary and
then all those so in the back end it's
all junk JSON isn't what the mongo DB is
so I'm burning those two JSON or
dictionaries that JSON is really easy
and so that's where it imports into the
lair database I wanted to show something
else record on this what this was the
my Medusa file both four lines that
were just harsh than in pudding so the
drone module so these are all the it's
the data model model that you have to
import the data all of the data that you
have access to through the drones so
this is what logs your tool way you use
the command OS I mean credentials
pretty self-explanatory but they're just
dictionaries with lists for Python so
pretty pretty simple if you have ever
done Python before I'm not an expert
i've only been writing stuff in python
for about a year and it's pretty easy so
that may make it so easy so that you can
if you have custom tools that you guys
are using internally you can easily
write something to import your data into
lair that's that's the whole point but
see we go to the next part so we have
the lair drones also come with Nessus
and expose so we'll look at some of
those vulnerabilities that it found so
right now we don't have any obviously so
so the imports all those and it tells
you who it was last modified by which is
nice so that you can tell if it was a
user or tool and who's working on what
it'll tell you over here on the right
side then also let's just do the next
one
so in
from expose anybody think this would be
useful I don't know we find it very
useful it helps when we're all working
together to to stay on task and not
duplicate the work that everyone else is
doing if we go look at the logs it still
shows us all the commands for each tool
that we used even though the next post
scans pretty generic and nessus shows us
the Medusa humanity ran and the other
and maps can and then everything else so
it's very auditable if you want to see
who's done what and where so there's
another tool that I wrote another drone
for called the harvesters anyone heard
of the harvester before great a pretty
cool little recon tool to look at a
domain and see who works there how they
have their email addresses and whatnot
but it just does searches on on google
and LinkedIn and a few other things so
you just look at it so so Google people
PNG PGP google profiles a ghost google+
now being dick shot jigsaw linkedin and
all so let me just run a quick one i
just did it on b-sides slc fellow or
hope John doesn't care good thing about
it is it never never touches anything
that you're looking up so just using
google and other sources to find that
data so this might be kind of slow so I
what
as I give it the domain and then the
amount of results you want from each
service so tan and then what service you
want I just did all and then it exports
it to xml so now give us emails found
didn't find any people host information
pretty cool pretty simple so I wrote
drone just a process that information
and put into layer
so there really isn't anything for like
recon like that for like a phishing
attack or anything like that so I i
could put these into like notes but i
chose to put them into credentials even
though they're not credentials they're
just could be user names or whatever so
we'll run it and it should populate with
a few more usernames there we go so it's
got Shawn got Jackson it besides admin
some really weird email address and just
the b-sides org so now that we've got
all of our data in there it's time to go
through it and see what's relevant to us
and so you can actually with lair you
can run client-side scripts just from
the console log and and see or and
manipulate the data so we'll do that
real quick hope you guys don't mind
getting out early so but so these are
really easy to write so these are just a
couple so I call this function orange
it'll go in and change everything orange
that has any type of credential like any
type of either username or password
doesn't matter blue sea blue if this if
the OS hasn't been determined yet on a
host read it will change it to no that's
the wrong one red if the vulnerability
is above and if a host has a
vulnerability above an eight then it'll
turn everything red and then green will
change you'll be able to select all the
vulnerabilities by a certain name giving
you some regex so you just
just copy these and just paste them
right in and they worked awesome so
we'll just run orange checked it wrong
okay so you stop blink and then it
didn't change so we have to first go in
and change the settings to allow client
site updates just because you can run
your own scripts on the client that's
bad for any kind of other web
application but since you're doing your
testing it's okay so we'll go back into
it whip arrow we're running again so
everyone ow we have all the hosts that
have a credential either a username or
password and so we can just focus on
those ones for now or we can run script
blue and now we know all the ones that
we probably aren't going to worry about
or probably just need more recon to find
out what the OS is for each of those and
then do red so red will change the host
and also in the vulnerabilities tab it
will change the ones that are above 82
to read so so those two something wicked
in eb e both have vulnerabilities that
are above an eight which could be
exploitable within the pen test and then
it marks on both red and it's flash
player for mac hasn't been updated
that's I never worked for anybody right
and then the last one we can do is green
and we just give it some regex see you
so you kept on and kept it wrong
there we go so now everything as
vulnerable has a vulnerability for
Apache is highlighted pretty simple you
can do that with any any other thing
that you want if you want to highlight
SSH or or whatnot so okay so that's
pretty much what layer can do so now if
you go to the front page eat all your
colors that you've changed them to show
up in these little little Donuts I don't
know why services services don't have
colors so they're always gray but
another cool thing if you're a pen
tester and you're working for some
client you can export all the data that
you found you neither export it to some
server or you can just download it and
then send it to them somehow but it's
just a JSON file of everything that you
found and they could just if they wanted
to throw up a layer and then import it
and look at it it's pretty cool so it's
open source it's on github ch.1 so you
up here layer dash framework / layer so
they Tom steal tweeted a while back that
they're working on version too so
hopefully it can come with some more
advanced stuff but I think it's very
simple and pretty effective and what it
is right now and I don't know I have so
this harvester is all the tools that i
use for open source and go find and add
tune layer drones are there as well if
you there's a whole bunch of browser
scripts that you can run that are
already written as well they can do
certain things like the ones that I ran
to change the colors you can specify to
count every object or whatever you want
it to do so sky's the limit really
that's pretty much it I don't know
anybody having questions or concerns
yeah I thought I thought there was maybe
I didn't look like there was don't see
you burp there like in so like if you
get a vulnerability and vulnerabilities
to have to find those or yeah so I have
it I took most of my time in the lair
drones part I haven't done much of the
development in the lair art but I
actually wanted to because I've if you
look at meteor meteor is awesome and I
really want to get in and learn and dig
deep into meteor so but I imagine it's
as simple as just adding something in a
tab and then creating a collection and
the database for for something like that
I'm pretty sure if you have a developer
on staff that could you just fork it in
that at yourself for or whatever but
yeah it just spins sometimes yeah so
pen test we've used on this has been
network pen testing as well not now so
but I'll going to look into doing that
so we have another pen test coming up so
yeah John someone's got questions if not
that's it