I feel like I need to do the can you
hear me because it works so never mind
wow what is okay is this better so I'm
going to warn you right now I pace this
is a very good chance I'm going to pay
swear I'm not supposed to deal but uh I
don't know what else to say right you
know we should have a line don't go past
this I'm Kevin it's not that exciting at
least well I'm excited by it because
well I'm me I didn't pick this name when
I turned 18 so I probably should have
picked something better you know Kevin
Johnson's kind of boring especially
another Kevin Todd Johnson with the same
birth date in Florida he's always wanted
by the police so that was a mistake it's
awful I uh the reason i point that out
is when i was flying out here it's the
first time it's affected my flights
normally it just affects things like if
like I had a car stolen when the cops
picked me up to show me you know come
bring me downtown to talk about the car
being stolen they ran my name it was
like you know you're wanted in Miami my
god no why so you know but I'd say I'm
one of those weird things today we're
gonna talk about security researchers
security bits merger I do believe that
site that last word is one I made up um
but I think it works right it's like
it's kind of like gruntled you guys know
about gruntled right disgruntled people
and gruntled people recording the
dictionary gruntled is not real either
so I don't know it's one of those things
we're trying but we're gonna talk about
a lot of things today and of course I
turned off the remote so that didn't
work me whoo i am the founder of secure
ideas that is a security consulting firm
based out of Jacksonville Florida Salt
Lake City Tulsa and Charlotte um mostly
in Jacksonville sorry guys we are
building up our presence here in Salt
Lake City we've got two consultants now
at the awesome Danny and Jason would
and uh we're also mean if you ever want
to reach out to Danny just to email him
at seahawks at Scare ideas calm so the
people who know Danny will understand
why that was his mean as it was i'm the
founder we've been around for four and a
half years we're just a bunch of nerds
that accidentally got into security
consulting and people keep hiring us
we're not sure exactly how that keeps
happening but we're not complaining uh
you know I tell everybody I have a
business goal of being a one-percenter
um I'd like them to have an Occupy
elderberry court because I own I have so
much money um hasn't happened yet but
I'm working on it right I'm also ions
faculty ions is this company their group
if they do these interesting things that
they call ask an expert but then they
let me get on the phone so I'm not sure
how that works I and uh I'm a course
author i wrote the web pen testing and
mobile security curriculums at sans
institute and continue to teach various
classes all over the place as matter
fact we're really excited the first
professional evil pentest training class
course event whatever the heck it's
called you know what they don't have to
speak for my job but um it's coming up
in April we're really excited about that
I'm a podcaster an open source project
lead and I have to say it my wife says
it's the nerdiest thing ever I am a 500
first member the people who don't know
the 500 first is a worldwide charity
group that dresses in screen accurate
costumes from Star Wars right so uh you
know there I am in my imperial officer
my daughter and Darth Vader and you know
Harry Potter and I have an imperial
guard I'm building a stormtrooper I am
building a Wookiee Chewbacca and let me
just tell you that the idea of latch
hooking seven feet of mesh to fur is a
as tedious as you can imagine um so this
is what I do like I said my wife says
it's the nerdiest thing I've ever done I
pointed out she met me when I was 20
six she doesn't know oh so and i'm a
nerd right I've got two kids who you'll
hear a lot about Brenna and Sarah Brenda
and Sarah Brenda will be 13 next month
which means that she will enter the time
where she hates me for a few years and
Sarah will be nine in June they are
amazing I'm biased right I learned when
brenda was born my oldest that every
parent in the world believes that their
child is the smartest most beautiful
most amazing kid ever the second thing I
learned was every other parent was wrong
right and so they are one of the main
reasons I do what I do and they're
actually what drives this talk because I
think that this talk is something that's
critical for us as an industry but I'm
biased right so uh let me know if you
want to reach out to me ever now of
course this doesn't work that's
wonderful that means i have to be up
here I hate being up on stage I really
do it's funny I'm a traveling consultant
that speaks all over the country I hate
public speaking I hate traveling and I
hate meeting new people so I picked this
job I don't know how that happened right
but the reality is that what we've got
today is a wild west of security right
everybody and their brother knows about
security today they may not know good
things they may not know correct things
but it's something we talked about it's
a big topic hell the fact that what we
do has made it to the state of the union
address two years in a row freaks me out
because look around you we are the
people the President of the United
States is talking about and I don't care
about your politics I don't care whether
you hate the man or love the man or
indifferent the fact that what we do is
a topic of such importance that it's
talked about at that level should scare
you
it's constantly being brought up in the
news hell we have TV shows by the way
there's gonna be a pg-13 talk should
warn you now but we have TV shows about
what we do and they're very accurate um
cuz how many people here saw how many
people here saw the first episode of
scorpion right yeah how many people here
your heads hung themselves from an
airplane flying over a runway at 200
miles an hour right yeah with a cat5
cable you pulled out of the plane on
sorrows 5e I apologize you're right see
I'm not even accurate ah right I want to
know where that cable came from right
this doesn't matter but and we talked a
lot about right you hear on Twitter Oh
CSI cyber bra why can't they make it
accurate because our job is boring come
on how exciting do you think your mother
is going to find it watching you type in
VI because we all know VI is the right
answer right yeah I said that once in
class was teaching a class and I made
the comment yo yeah you know the only
religious war i get into is VI versus
Emacs that's cuz we all know VI wins
it's kinda back the room slammed his
fist into the desk bra stood up and
walked out hey what the heck not an hour
later he came back in he was a little
calm oh i don't know like dude what what
the heck right what was that in he
turned out he was one of the developers
of Emax and so my response was dude
emacs is an amazing operating system but
you guys just so you know i don't
necessarily say the right things at the
right time right very professional
person says it my slogan professional
evil but um I spoke at NASA once that
was awesome I started my talk whole
bunch of NASA scientists in the room and
I started my talk with hey guys when
we're done can you show me the fake moon
landing site too soon
haha there was dead silence in the room
right it was like ah ok I pissed
somebody off so I decided to try to save
it right cuz you got to save the joke
and I'm like don't worry about it
Mythbusters proved you were there that
didn't save the joke I just so you guys
know and I should have warned you I
basically a man a TD speaker alright
square what are we going to talk about
today so you'll hear lots of random
tangents and things like that the other
thing is I have an amazing sense of
humor I do want to be clear I did not
say an amazingly good sense of humor
right but I like my jokes my favorite
joke currently is uh do you guys know
why Walmart wasn't hack
they weren't a target but right come on
I told you it's not good said to you I
told my daughter's recently I'm like hey
you know it's blue and smells like red
paint my daughters are used to me so
Brennan came out with blue pain she was
right but uh haha so yes I'm warping
them both of my daughters will have two
years of counseling for every year they
live with me but the reality is jumping
back is that security is miserable
you're all a pen tester plain and simple
my job is to come in according to many
people by the way they're wrong but many
people think that my job is to come in
beat you up tell you you suck can go
home right did you get hacked yes I have
to oh well the reality is our job is
actually show problems and give
suggestions on how to fix it right our
job is to actually improve things but as
an industry I didn't we move more toward
the idea that our job is to beat up on
people right because there's tons of
issues out there there's tons of
problems I go into organizations I mean
look as far as I'm aware it is 2015 and
yet i regularly find ms 0806 seven or
networks so the people who don't know
that is the stereotypical way to
demonstrate hacking a machine and the
patch was released in 2008 so seven
years ago by the way if i recall
correctly the operating system it's for
is no longer supported by microsoft
right i don't believe in its weight its
support affected anything new currently
if i remember correctly but that's
ridiculous i have been in major
organizations i have been in critical
infrastructure and found ms 080 is 67 no
of course my day just got easier right
as Danny said yesterday oh it's not how
he phrased it but same thing
there's tons of issues and that were
just ignoring the fact that we're not
maintaining our stuff well we also have
on a hacktivist oh you're a dickhead
right I've it but I just it's ridiculous
on a hacktivist what made you a hack to
this I took the word put it on my label
how many people here are a member of
anonymous just asking but if you go on
facebook how many people have the guy
fawkes mask as their profile picture
next to their real name email address
and physical address yeah you're
anonymous what the hell right I don't
think that word means what you think it
means so we got hacked miss we got
hackers right apt everybody drink right
advanced persistent threat also known as
fishing bothers me right and then not
even starting to talk about the
disgruntled users I was in the airport
right which by the way I can almost
start every story i have with i was in
the airport um it's bad enough that the
night staff at the atlanta airport know
me by name and will actually bring me
blankets when i'm there overnight right
you know you're being treated nicer by
the cleaning lady than your own family
you travel too much but we have
disgruntled users i'm sitting in the
airport and I'm eating my lunch cuz i
was flying out here and i had a bit of a
layover it was hope so really a long
layover for me i normally have 45
minutes to bolt through atlanta i had
three hours I didn't know what to do so
I went I had lunch and these two guys
are sitting next to me and they hate
their boss who by always just be clear
it's not me but there's sit there at the
table and these two guys are ranting
about the problems they have with their
company and they're releasing details
that I would love to share with you
right now because
companies based here and I know
information about problems with their
systems I know ish information about
data that this exposed where it
shouldn't be exposed and I happen to
know the domain administrator password
for their network because they discussed
it and I'm sitting on I'm write this
down right this is awesome man I hope we
get a pen test with them all right I you
know it disgruntled users do stupid
stuff and then there's mistakes people
just make mistakes oops I didn't mean to
do that and it exposed stuff right and
we have all these problems going on and
then we have new technology coming out
right how many people here have an Apple
watch it's hoping right nobody yet but
how many people who are gonna have an
Apple watch right yeah I saw a hand over
there right hey I'm getting one but I'll
admit it they're ridiculously expensive
but I don't want to tell everybody I'm
buying the addition one for fifteen
thousand dollars that's ridiculous but
that technology is coming right wearable
technology we now have the Internet of
Things wasn't the internet always of
things right like I get what they're
trying to say but we're making our jobs
more difficult we're making it more
complex and the reality is in my opinion
our jobs aren't harder now than they
were 20 years ago and i'm an old fart
enough to know what our job is like 20
years ago it's not more complex we still
the same problem you accepted input
trusted the input and made use of it
right is that the nature of our problem
sequel injection what is it accepting
input trusting it using I'll for
overflow accepting input trusting it
using it social engineering accepting
input trusting it using it right that's
it yet if you read twitter if you read
any news feed we now have cross-site
scripting report read friends sequel
injection command injection that's one
vulnerability
right we now have run out of one in two
word vulnerabilities and we now have
five and ten word vulnerabilities I was
just talking to a guy and I'm gonna mess
up the name of it but it was like path
traversal cascading style sheet
injection I wish I was making that up
right I was like what are you doing well
you inject a path that reference is a
different cascading style sheet and they
load that other one in that cross site
scripting right but somebody had to have
an ego come up with a new name because
we have to be famous we in my opinion
have turned into an industry of bullies
right we have we name in shame we beat
up on people we tell them they suck
we're mean how do we even know what the
real threats are according to mandiant
it's the chinese or north koreans right
so mandiant says so it must be true
because they make lots of money right we
attributed Sony hack to North Korea why
because of a stupid movie anybody watch
that movie did you enjoy it really okay
I'll go with that right i've not watched
it why does it look dumb to me I hadn't
even heard about the movie until North
Korea supposedly attacked sony right we
don't even know what the real
vulnerabilities are I talked to
developers all the time because I
believe part of my responsibility is to
sit down and actually educate people
right not just coming and go wow you saw
what to say here are the problems here's
why they are problems and we talk to
people and they don't even truly
understand what the issue is right I had
a developer once logged into it one of
their websites through Burke of course
right herb and I look and they've dumped
down a whole bunch of visual basic
script an individual basic script is the
connection string for the sa password
with the essay account with the sa
password and it was a really long
complex password
and I say the developer who's sitting
next to me I'm like hey dude okay your
connection string right here you're
connecting his essay and I now have that
and the guy goes yeah but look at how
complex that password is yeah I get it
it's complex but you're the key word
there was look right then I had another
guy in class once right I'm teaching a
class we're talking about cracking
passwords and I got this guy and he says
to me oh I'm not worried about that I
have the world's strongest password it's
really he's like yep I like what is it
he told me so like okay but even worse
it was a four letter name so I say this
guy dude I say dude a lot in stories I'm
sorry but am I dude how is that the
world's strongest password because you
don't understand I'm 40 I'm 52 years old
I almost gave my age of 42 but he's 52
years old and that was his dog's name
when he was four and nobody knows his
dog's name when he was born and you know
what he's right if the threat really was
somebody finding out who he was and
trying to determine his password I won't
call it a strong password but it's less
likely that somebody would know that
that's a good point the problem is
that's not the threat that's not what
he's trying to protect against what he's
trying to protect against is somebody
with a script going after all the
possible accounts on that system in
which case a four-letter password I
don't even consider a password it might
as well be blank right so I explain this
to the guy and the guy gets freaked out
we're not even talking about the fact
that he said he had one password right
but from Tallinn guy and he's freaking
out his eyes get this big and sweat
comes here and he told out the door and
he comes back in about 45 minutes later
it's like whoa okay he's like yeah man
you oh man you freaked me out i just
went i changed I changed my password
it's really good you should pick
something I did you pick
than good he's like yeah what is it he
told me so I fixed part of the problem
but not the other but we're working on
it right well and now we're even into a
problem are we even allowed to test what
we want to test how many people here use
cloud-based stuffs right yeah you guys
know why it's called the cloud
nope Vizio icon for the Internet is a
cloud right it's on the internet so it's
cloud so here's my deal here's what I
want you guys to start doing start
referring to databases is the cylinder
right I found cylinder injection in your
application every awesome won't it yeah
so please do that for me but like are we
allowed to test our cloud apps are we
allowed to go after those things so we
go after that third party can we
determine what's going on we don't know
and we have major flaws at least
according to Reuters in the news and CNN
hell they have their own logo I've been
a nerd for way too long right I grew up
nerdy I joke can say the guy that you
steal my lunch money in school still
does but he makes a damn good subway
sandwich but no nobody told me if I
wanted to be a hacker I had to be good
at photoshop people were actually
disappointed last Friday or is it this
friends last friday the ssl
vulnerabilities came out right i was
track of time there wasn't a logo and
people actually said that the goose
can't be that serious it doesn't have a
logo if you were one of those people who
said that please do me a favor beat the
out of yourself right i mean come
on we're building this a heart bleed ah
shellshock didn't even have one logo it
had multiple logos right and put what
the hell is poodle I mean poodles are
freaky looking dogs but they don't
really scare me but we named a
vulnerability we have logos and a lot of
people talking about this and I have had
people send me all the Kevin that's good
it's good we have logos because now
we've got people talking you know what
they're talking out their ass so it
didn't help and then worse and Friday
proved it
I have major companies that I've worked
with that did not apply the patches last
week because the severity of the bug
can't be that high because there wasn't
a logo we've had companies that have
come to us and have said can you verify
we're not vulnerable to heartbleed you
know you're still running Windows 311 no
no we just want to make sure we're not
vulnerable to heart plate that's a
problem that's a negative we are
actually being detrimental to our own
security by doing this crap but as an
industry we're doing it and we're making
it worse right and my question is and
this is what really drives me on this
talk right is how do we even know what
we're allowed to do and we say all the
time right a charity was Jeremiah
Grossman came out with an awesome blog
post test yourself hack yourself and
Troy hunt out in Australia wrote a great
blog post about the same thing and i
agree i think you should be testing you
should be assessing your own stuff what
about the people testing the internet
what about the people who just say hey
there's a vulnerability let me see if
they're vulnerable to it I don't know
them but I'm going to find out we
allowed to do that and some people tell
me we are some people tell me we're not
right here's an example and I want to be
very clear here I respect Robert Graham
greatly he is a smart person but this is
what he posted on Twitter during the
shell shock stop this is me right now
seriously did you people think I
wouldn't the people who don't know
that's a screenshot of that wireshark
right I almost called it TCP dump like I
really did because i don't use wires
your got use TCP dump but to do the
captures but that's just because I'm
nerdy but Wireshark of him scanning
internet-facing IP addresses for the
shell shock vulnerability and exploiting
it
and his answer when we called them out
on it was well I'm just running ping
pings not that big a deal the problem is
he knows he's just running ping I know
by looking at that that he's just
running ping in the capture I see but
what else is he running and if you're
the he's running Wireshark good answer
damn it hahahaha he's a genius hahahaha
so what we are hiring but uh so but what
else is he running and if you're the
company that had that traffic come to
you and you detected it don't you have
to respond as if he's malicious isn't
there the potential for you to have to
do a breach notification if you can't
identify if you don't have enough
information to say that he didn't go
further my read of some of the breach
notification laws is if you can't prove
you weren't breached you have to notify
that you were right that's a problem and
when I've talked to Robert about this by
the super efficient way to have a
conversation of Twitter um he doesn't
think that's an issue i do right and his
answer is we're doing it for the greater
good we're trying to help people so i
asked him great you're trying to help
people out of all the IP addresses that
you identified that were vulnerable as
shell shocked how many of them did you
reach out to and notified and the answer
was none they can follow me on twitter
how egotistical is that if you want to
know if you're vulnerable follow me on
Twitter right now I looked at his
follower list it's not everybody on the
planet right it's not even every
business owner on the planet yet they're
supposed to know that Robert Graham is
nicely exploiting their system not a
full ability assessment here right he
exploited it but it's for the greater
good greater good for his fame but we
have other network examples right the
apple developer network went down a
hundred thousand records were pulled
because I
hacktivist security researcher isn't a
lab coat but he's a researcher right
found a sequel injection flaw and I want
to be very clear I agree that Apple
should not be vulnerable to this totally
this guy pulled a hundred thousand
records they took the developer Network
offline for more than a week which means
that every one of those startups that
are trying to build the next Angry Birds
didn't have access to do the things they
needed to do people who had jobs weren't
able to do what their job required right
people who were interested in learning
IT and programming and security weren't
able to and when you ask this guy hey
why did you pull a hundred thousand
records his answer was well I just
wanted to prove it was a problem how
many people here have done the sequel
injection before right I'm not going to
ask you did it legally right how many
people here have done sequel injection
before right how many of you that raised
your hand know about the count function
we're instead of actually pulling the
records he could have said count how
many records I would have pulled he
still would have gotten a hundred
thousand number he still would have
proven that he was able to do it but you
know what it's not it's sexy he's not as
headline-grabbing it's not as bad to the
other company right it's we have people
doing this but don't worry about I don't
worry about I know you guys are
concerned it's okay he posted on Twitter
Apple this is definitely not a hack
attack i am not a hacker i do security
researcher now i do want to point out he
said sakura trees not research not
researcher but i do want to point out he
didn't copy apples twitter account he
just said apple right so somehow apples
supposed to know it I don't know who
Mike butcher is I should have found out
before I put this in the slide but he
now knows right again how egotistical is
it I'm a Turkish guy that is so awesome
Apple must follow me right and that's
what he did but he's a security
researcher so it's okay because it
wasn't really hacking it was research
right
that makes it fun but you know don't
worry about it he targeted Google to
write and this time he actually crashed
the servers right twice when that wasn't
enough they brought her back up he tried
to Sumer and he could do it again you
could he was just verifying that it
wasn't a fluke right that it really was
him that crashed it again I hear from
security researchers all the time on the
internet that it's okay because there's
no cost to what they're doing it doesn't
hurt anybody yeah I'll tell you right
now Google had to react to that it was a
real hack because you know what it was a
real hack matter what the guy calls it
it's real that's like me walking in here
holding up a gun shooting somebody and
saying wait look I was just researching
whether the bullet would actually go out
you never know some guns jam right it
was research wasn't murder doesn't sound
like it's a shoe it's okay it's not so I
psychopath to you does it here this is
what we've got going on and we as the
industry seem to push this up and go
this is awesome look at that guy he's so
cool let's put him on stage right we
talked to you out ethics and this is
what I think we're lacking here and
here's the problem when you talk about
ethics a lot of people say ah we don't
need laws matter of fact Robert Graham
posted a whole blog post where he
discussed the fact that we should not be
under the chilling effects of the law
because we're researchers that's a scary
phrase we should not be affected by the
chilling effects of the law you know
laws like don't speed don't kill people
don't steal right those are laws and
while we may not agree that the laws are
good I will argue with the best of you
that the CFAA needs improvement but the
reality is there are laws we have to
follow them what I'm going to talk about
laws here talking about ethics there are
things that are ethical yet illegal
and there are things that are legal yet
not ethical right and i'll use Godwin's
law right it was illegal for people to
hide Jews in Nazi Germany during World
War two but I don't think it was
unethical the high Jews in Nazi Germany
right and I'm not comparing this to the
Nazis this is not a security researchers
or Hitler right good appreciate that
right but the reality is ethics are what
are allowed by your sense of right and
wrong we need ethics to guide us and
I'll I'll be blunt I'm gonna stand up
here and tell you I'm not smart enough
to know the right ethics because I was
asked once I was I was somewhere and I'm
talking about doing the right thing and
having permission having scope and this
guy in the audience said to me so Kevin
you're telling me you would never hack
somebody without permission
you'd never break the law I said no I'm
not telling you that at all because I
speak I drive too fast in my poor little
Civic right and I'll tell you right now
somebody mess with my daughters who bets
are off haha right I solves and forget
the professionally and professionally
evil you know I'll admit that I don't
know where my line is but I know I have
a line I know that there will be
something that will make me consider
crossing that line I'm not gonna lie to
you and tell you I'm a good person
because I learned a long time ago I'm
not good I don't deserve what i have
i've been blessed but i do believe that
we have to have an ethical standard and
we've got some out there right we do
have is c squared has a great ethics
code of ethics right by the way i hope
you heard the italics and quotes around
great there you know according their
code of ethics you should not interact
with black hats so does that mean I'm
not allowed to run tools the black hat
road or to my read yes I'll tell you my
clients would be at a disadvantage if I
didn't run tools that black hat wrote
right so I violate that code of ethics
every day and I'm a cissp so if you want
to report may have a blast right I
follow black hats on Twitter I follow
black hats on the Internet to see what
they're doing I think that's in
mandatory for us as Danny said yesterday
in his talk right we should constantly
be learning and has to have an ethical
guidelines that tells us we can't learn
from the source of the attacks we're
trying to protect against is asinine not
even getting into the fact that most of
the ethical guidelines we have from
sands and G a canned is C squared or
driven entirely by capitalists agreed on
the certification company you'll pay me
to certify you and you'll agree to
follow the ethics I have that bind you
to my certification brilliant right
money and this is what we run into we
run into things like this and I'm sure
that if you look up on this slide you
see people up there that you admire and
people you hate
cuz I look up there and I see Snowden
and I could get into an argument but I
believe that man is a traitor and needs
to be shot in the head because that is
the penalty for traitor in the United
States and other people will look you in
the face and tell you he's a hero he's a
whistleblower he saved lives hey you
know what I'm feeling both of us may be
right right because again I'm not smart
enough to know what the right way is but
i'll tell you that I look at things that
Snowden did I look at things anonymous
does and some of the stuff anonymous
does i look at go yes do it again and
there are days i look at what anonymous
does and say burn in hell right I look
at jester and I cheer every time he says
tango down right and I'll admit the
hypocrisy of that right I got no problem
standing up to telling you I'm a
hypocrite but I am and I say it's
because I'm not smart enough to know
what the right answer is but here's the
problem we are smart enough to know what
the right answer is and if we don't
stand up and say this is okay and this
isn't we're plain and simple it's
we need to we need to stand up and say
this is okay and this is not and there's
ways to do this right one of the ways
that I hear about all the time is we
could pass a law yeah was it rapid7 just
started a petition to like modify the
CFAA those it rapid seven I don't mean
to pick on a company if it wasn't them
right they'll call us anyways try to
sell something but um
so right we need to change the CFAA and
I don't know about you guys but I've
presented to the Senate I've been in a
room with senators and House of
Representatives and their staff and I've
talked to them about security issues and
been embarrassed to say they represented
me because they don't know what we do we
have a congressman that's in charge of
the Technology Committee that proudly
admits he's never written an email and
again I'm not arguing Republican
Democrat any of that crap because I
don't care but I do know that if we're
gonna have people who don't understand
what we do making the laws we're screwed
we need to provide that guidance and
I'll tell you this is why right I'm
sitting in a plane and I had a lady
sitting next to me and I talked to
people right I don't know why I hate
people but I'm talking to this lady and
we're having a really good conversation
which is wow that's wonderful here's
pictures of my kids here's my lego all
this cool stuff right and then the woman
says to me very nicely obvious question
hey what do you do and I said what I
always say I'm a penetration tester and
I get the answer does that have
something to do with oil no no it
doesn't well it depends on the target
all right I don't know and I what is
that and I said well you know companies
hire me and I hack into their systems to
find vulnerabilities I steal data to
show them where the risk is and then I
tell them how to fix it she looked at me
cuz you're a hacker and I suggest ma'am
I am right she didn't talk to me the
rest of the flight yep another time my
daughter was five my oldest brenna we
were a restaurant we're sitting there in
the waitress comes up she looks at bet
on your salad or she's friend this
beautiful there's no way my jeans
created her but um she says the
Brenneman what do you want to be when
you grow up and Brenda looks at her
proudest day of my life Brenda looks her
in the face and says I want to hack
computers like my dad
right yeah right and the waitress with
the binos what did she say and I'm like
grinning from ear to ear right like she
said she wants to hack computers like
her dad and she goes are you her dad I
said that's what her mom says right the
waitress laughs there's no proof like I
said they're beautiful they can't be
mine but my wife hates and I say that
but the wagers left we had a new
waitress the rest of the night the new
wager said I don't know what happened
over here but she won't come back to the
table because somehow I was gonna steal
her identity at longhorn right that's a
problem because we're supposed to be the
good guys we're supposed to be the
people helping and I feel very very
strongly and I i mean this this is from
the bottom of my heart our job is to
make it better and we're not when I look
at my daughters and this is why i say my
daughters are a big part of this my
oldest Brenna has a neurological
condition she was diagnosed with at nine
years old right she has a seizure
disorder she has OCD and yes I'm
violating hip all over the place here
all right but she went to Wilson's
Children's Hospital where she was
treated and thank God and I mean that
truly thank God she'll outgrow it by the
time she's 16 not the OCD but the
seizure disorder with no long-lasting
effects right we're blessed that two
months after she went to Wilson's we
were notified by Wilson's that they were
breached and all of Brenna's data was
stolen they got her social her date of
birth where she was born her address
everything about her everything they
need to steal her identity but don't
worry about it Wilson's takes this very
seriously and they gave her a year of
credit monitor right after people who
don't know at nine years old you're not
allowed to sign up pretty here of credit
monitoring so wolfson's paid for
something nobody can use and the problem
here is this is not a year-long problem
Brenna's identity has been stolen for
the rest of her life she may not have
long-lasting effects from the seizure
disorder but she'll have one lesson
affection
that wolfson's didn't protect her data
to the level they should have protected
it too and I believe very firmly that
they didn't protect the data to the
level they did because we fail we as an
industry hey we are so busy building up
our own egos we're so busy being rock
star ninja famous that we're not helping
the people that need our help we're
supposed to be the superheroes no caves
but we're supposed to be and we're not
and if we wait for laws to come out and
guidelines who in the world can pick
those right we got certifications doing
it how many people here are GX certified
whoa so you try to sign the code of
ethics right did you read it nope nobody
does right how many people here have a
cissp yeah do you want them picking our
ethics if you want them and nothing
wrong with certification I'm not sitting
here telling you certification is evil
right i used to work for sams i have
tons of GX certifications i have the
cissp right I'm not telling you that's
wrong I'm just saying or there is that
where we want our guidelines built is
that where we want our ethics to be
determined and I don't know about you
but my answer is no well I have amazing
respect for Allen power well I think
Alan Paller is an amazing man I don't
believe he is the only person who should
be determining what are I fix on and I
know I know they have an ethics board
and all that kind stuff I'm simplifying
this significantly right but that's an
option right we also have bug bounties
this is a great idea let's just open up
our systems up and say to everybody hey
hack me please tell me about it though
right exactly though most of the bug
bounty programs i see they're finding
low-hanging fruit which in my opinion is
a failure of a bug bounty program if you
still have low hanging fruit like
cross-site scripting in a search button
search box you shouldn't be opening up a
bug bounty because you're not ready for
it yet that's like giving a
four-year-old the keys
over art
right you can't do it what that's one
thing and then there's questions right
how do you do it how do you know you're
doing it right how do you know you've
got the right people looking at your
system how do you know that threat that
you always hear right Adobe did a bug
bounty program and people bitched
they're just going to give us a t-shirt
no money I'll just sell what I find
right that's what people said is that
throughout we want to go again I go back
to we're supposed to be fixing things
we're supposed to be the good in what we
do and I feel very firmly about that I
feel very strongly about this I believe
that this is the route to go and this is
not a popular one you say licensing
people gah i don't want license I don't
the government to determine whether I
could be a hacker nobody determines
whether you can be a hacker it's a
mindset and I also want to point out I
didn't say government license it but I
do believe that we as an industry need
to start looking at something that says
I am able to do what I do that I follow
a certain standard that I have a certain
set of ethics and that when I give you
the results of what I give you you can
believe it was sufficient that it met
some standard that I'm not some jackass
who paid 1600 dollars for an SS license
and called it a pen test right do you
know how many reports I see where all
they did was take the logo off and put
their logo on I mean he'll I was looking
at a report just recently where the
links went still out to the tenable
website for information about what the
findings were if you're not even smart
enough to change the links get the hell
out
but licensing would fix that but I will
agree that I don't want the government
to Isis I don't I'm a big believer in
small government and I'm not saying I'm
a Republican I'm just saying I believe
in small government right and i think
that the minute you say that the
government's going to license something
we have a problem so what I think we
need to do and again want to be very
clear I'm not that smart in just some
jackass who started a business right if
we started something up like the infosec
bar right lawyers have it now I want to
be very clear the legal bar is a
government entity I don't want to model
that part but if we were to stand up and
we said hey look this is what we're
going to do we're going to create a set
of ethics we're going to create a set of
standards on how you test how you do
deliverables and what a report should
include how you determine that something
is high risk how you determine something
is medium risk how you determine right
we set up that standard we could then
start working with it and you're not
required to do it you're not required to
be a bar member right many of the states
the united states allow you to practice
law be calling yourself away but if
somebody wants to hire your service
you're able to say I'm bar certified
right
and we could hold you to a set of
standards we can hold you to when you
screw up things when you screw your
customer when you do things that violate
our ethics you lose that bar affiliation
and the reason I think that this will
work is because the movie industry and
no it's not because i watch CSI cyber
the movie industry was forced with the
same idea movie industry started
releasing movies and people started
complaining that the movies were obscene
and the government started talking about
legislation their favorite thing right
next is taxation but they would
legislate it passed laws to what the
movies could have right they would pass
laws to determine if a movie was ok and
the movie energy though we got it dude
and they created the rating system right
and they built a rating system they
started raiding stuff they in self
inflicted a standard and the government
went oh cool you got it awesome right
and then back in the 80s I don't know
how many people are old enough to
remember the eighties but I do this
horror horrible disgusting obscene movie
came out gremlins and um he people are
like haha they blew up an alien in my
grave kids shouldn't see that and people
started talking about censorship people
started talking about legislation
obviously Hollywood has gotten too big
for their britches so we should
legislate them and Hollywood said well
we got this one and they change the
rating system to include pg-13 right and
the new rating came up and the
government let they went dude you did it
awesome good going have a nice day and
they solve the problem and I'm not a
doom and gloom guy right I'm not gonna
sit up here and say the world is going
to end but I do believe very firmly that
if we don't stand up as an industry and
say dude we got it and then actually get
it if we don't actually
stand up and say this is the standard
we're going to follow then that doom and
gloom of the government passing laws of
the government saying security research
is bad by the way there's some security
research that I think is valid right we
like Germany distribution know it and do
not see comments now distribution of
hacker tools was illegal right now they
change that but if you were distributing
hacker tools it was against the law in
Germany right which I found funny
because I couldn't give you a copy of
samurai WTF or weaponized flash or
anything else like that but I could give
you a copy of adobe flash and internet
explorer but that's the route they went
in Italy IP address IP addresses are
private information laws passed by
governments about technology suck they
can't keep up right and that's why I say
what we have to do is we have to stand
up and do better right and I do think
that it's something we have to do soon I
think it's something we have to do now
and I'm not the only person who can do
it matter of fact I'm not the person to
do it because again if we have one
person stand up and say I'll create the
standard so be based on that person's
opinions and what I think is okay isn't
what Danny face is okay isn't what jason
face is okay right and while the three
of us may agree on most things we don't
agree on everything right and as an
industry what we do is so diverse
because we're not just talking pen
definitely reverse engineering forensics
Incident Response security we want to
have something better than something
like pci which is you must be this tall
to ride the internet right we got to do
better that's what it boils down to we
got to do better and I know it's a
mushy-gushy thing but if we don't do
better I'm scared to death for my
children and my children's show and
that's why we gotta fix
okay so got three minutes its own
supposed to be off the stage so any
question yes sir we would definitely get
badges but we don't need stinkin badges
hahaha and so well in that case thank
you very much everybody I'm honored that
you SAT here through an entire talk