so what we're going to be talking about
today is red team this goes beyond a
little bit more than what a typical
pentest typical engagement is if you
were here for the manipulating GUI
elements I'm sorry I'm not decaf I know
it's a letdown but close second maybe so
a little bit about me i work for dell
secureworks i'm one of the red team
members kind of just hanging out
specialized in apps act net tech mobile
security generally speaking i'm working
with a team of two to four guys i've got
guys on site that are breaking in
dropping boxes on your network once
they're in it's my game of where you'll
find me make me Mac on Twitter you'll
find me on IRC on freenode usually
hanging out in the DC 801 chat room etc
etc etc just were to note this does not
endorse say anything for secureworks I'm
speaking on my own today so about you
who in here are my blue team does
network security defense at your
organization's cumplea what about GRC
compliance guys that who in here are my
professional pen testers yeah what about
huling here is responsible for your
organization security well first off the
GRC you guys get out of here no just
kidding you guys make my life easy make
user sloppy but blue team members thanks
you guys do get a lot of good work work
long hard hours you're doing what you
got to do the pen testers keep doing
what you're doing let's keep fighting
this good fight and for who and here is
responsible for your security I'm
disappointed every one of your shutter
raise your damn hand because just
because you're not an admin just because
you're not involved in security doesn't
mean I'm not going to exploit to you to
get break your company security by you
clicking my link I win and you cost your
company 191 million
like what happened to target last year
I've forgotten put on fancy animations
in and not even usually it was let's
start with some quick definitions here
about what a red team is and what's the
defining factors and what's the
differences so who and here knows a lot
of vulnerability assessment is anybody
what's the vulnerability assessment
Danny do you actually exploit them do
you actually go in and do you do more
with it great it's exactly right all I'm
doing is I'm going to scan to agenta
scan look at what's running let's
listening there you go how about a pen
test then those little penetration test
is what would be a penetration test what
would I be doing different definitely on
by the way I didn't say this I'm going
to be asking questions please give me
feedback talk back let me know if you
have questions concerns comments please
chime in you know I don't want to be
just standing up here to talk i'll
actually want to give you guys some good
information something you can take back
to your organization yep generally
speaking i'm going to find us vulnerable
service i'ma find every vulnerability i
can on your network i'm going to make
sure i can penetrate those i'm going to
document patches fix it here is
everything usually limited the scope
though meaning i'm coming in i'm doing a
network pentesting i'm not looking at
all your applications I'm not looking at
your mobile I'm not social engineering
your users oh it's a webapp lesesne okay
i'm looking at just these web
applications i'm not looking at the
network I'm not looking at everything
now here's the fun Red Team this is
where it gets good who in here knows
what a red team minutes
yeah yes to an extent so one thing about
it is especially in terms of IT what is
your environment so for example your
users your applications your network
your physical security your environment
everything you have that is in scope for
me so if I want to come in pick a lock
at two in the morning walk in and drop a
box great I'll do it I want a social
engineer your CEO get him to click link
because there's new article out in
Harvard Business about hey securities
great you need to come read this article
well that's a lie stroke it's laced PDF
we went the other fun thing about this
is i am not looking for every
vulnerability on your network it doesn't
matter if you've got em SOS 67 on four
hundred boxes sitting across the network
if they're not going to help me i'm not
going to explode it and i'm not going to
put that in my report because i'm not
going to be looking for my job is to
come in undetected so you don't know I'm
there generally speaking I get on to
your network you will never know I'm
there unless I do so danger I'm
going to say this up front with a red
team engagement this is for companies
that have an established security
practice they know how to monitor their
logs they have patch management they
have firewalls they've got security
teams compliance teams so i can promise
you if you don't have it you will never
know I'm there and likelihood is you are
pissed off at the end of this report
when I walked in sat down to the cube
none of your users questioned me I
logged into your shares oh wait a minute
here's the master password list included
your domain admin great where's that
sequel server bingo game over i won I
walked out with your credit card
database you up left it wide open
for me I walked out I'm done in the day
reports going to rep represent that
you're going to be bitter and hurt
because hey this this isn't fair you
didn't give us anything and frankly the
waste of my tummy so as I said this is
for established companies this is your
fortune 500 your large institutions that
really need that but that's not to say
that every company shouldn't be striving
for this so you're a small company of 20
people big deal you've got an
established security practices and built
your organization you've gone through
pen test you've gone through moaner
ability assessments regularly now let's
going to red team in to tell you hey
this is where you risk still are so a
little bit of a creepy story here how
many of you in here outsource your
printer maintenance anybody printer
maintenance you got your big
multifunction printers copier scanner
fax machines all in all do everything
right how many so outsource the printer
maintenance okay or have to call in a
third-party repair company from time to
time because you don't have the in-house
staff and technical parts let's take
care of it how many of you in here would
think that your printer will give away
your entire network
you're right so here's something to
think about co-worker of mine use this
walked in wearing a Technicolor shirt to
service a printer locked up put a box in
line two ports started capturing traffic
they'll credit to the back of the
printer you know pull the printer apart
a little bit put it back together walked
out came back a week later grab the box
went home hold the creds off hold the
traffic off it hold the creds out of it
less than three days later full domain
admin remotely think about it will kind
of get back to that a little bit stop in
red team can it be done who thinks it
could but is it easy no so what I'm
hoping and this is kind of where I'm at
as I want to show you how you would stop
someone like me how you would stop my
team when we come on site or when we're
an area because if you're not paying
attention you're going to lose it we got
three high levels of touch points we
have physical security human security
information systems security those are
the three areas within an organization
that make up your security posture as we
said before a lapsim one will lead you
to a full compromise to this little
hofstra just kind of a little diagram of
what I'm saying here and they all
interact humans and we as humans we use
information security we use technology
we go into that the human factor also
allows for the physical how many of you
in it here have ever tailgated someone
walking in or out of a building great
how many how many of you in here have
left a computer unlock by accident and
walked away
didn't even think about it left it
unlocked walk away or how many of you in
here in your organization bolt your pc's
down both all your laptop's them
physically bolt all your servers into
the rack with heavy-duty cables and
locks nobody what would happen if I as
an attacker walked in at two in the
morning hold serve wrap hold all your
drives out decrypted everything that was
on there if you're even using full disk
encryption took the data put it back
before you got on site now I've just
stolen passwords likely I've gotten a
domain admin password or a server admin
password you know what do I find I found
a web app server great I've got
something important there how about a
sequel server now I've got the sa
password what can I do how many of you
in here would know what I'd do with the
nests a password what could I do with it
even better how about log directly in as
a my seat earn ms SQL client and start
querying the database and do it back up
to my own external box what can I do
with that data well it was that your
credit card data was that all of your
external users their usernames that
passwords their ph I your health care
organization and I just stole all your
pH I what's going to happen to you
that's why I say a lapse in one will get
you fully compromised so humans human
security a couple of things about us we
like to be helpful how many how many of
you in here we're taught by your parents
hold the door for people be polite help
them out you see a guy carrying a arm
full of books or carrying an arm full of
boxes pushing a cart
what are you gonna do oh here let me
hold that door for you mmm yes okay we
like to feel important how many of you
in here like to have your boss come up
and say good job or a client and say you
know a good job thanks for doing that
you know it makes us feel good we like
to feel good about what we do are you
hear from your wife your significant
other who ever hey good job thanks for
doing that we don't like conflict as a
human we our natural tendency is to back
away from conflict we stay out of
conflict as a group we're okay with
conflict because its safety in numbers
but in a one-on-one scenario I start
getting up in your face start getting
real pressing with you what nope I'm
done no I don't like conflict so the
other thing about us we're emotional we
aren't always logical we do not always
follow things through step by step by
step and make the best decisions we let
our emotions play with us and as in as a
red team member I love it we are the
weakest link in security by far ninety
percent of what I can do as a red team
ur can be done by just a social
engineering engagement the reason being
we as humans are weak links in our
organization security phishing emails
phone fishing vision I mean it doesn't
matter what you do as an organization if
i can get you to click a link open a
file give me your creds recent
engagement just fun sorry about this
we're doing a red team engagement
company we fished 135 users we had 90
people give us their treads
what did we do we played off the fact
that there was a recent large snowstorm
in the in the Northeast up in the Boston
Philly New York area right we said hey
we're looking at a new experimental work
from home program so when things like
these happen we can allow you to work
from home we can give you an opportunity
to do this so what we need you to do is
go fill out this survey give us some
details you need to log in with your
credentials silicon log in every pretty
much everybody logged in and give
secrets we ran rampant across that
network they're like when we deliver the
report to the customer they just shook
their head and cried the other thing
about it was ninety percent of these
passwords bald a very simple pattern so
for you red team guys in here little
trick little pen test guys cracking
passwords here's something to look for a
capital letter followed by a
predetermined number of lowercase
letters followed by a couple of numbers
and some symbols so instead of trying to
brute force the entire key space book
for specifics generally speaking users
will use a capital letter at first why
they are required how so in your
organization what is your general
password complexity a number a capital
letter maybe assemble 10 or 12
characters think about that physical
security how many places have you gone
into that don't have bad rieger bad
badge readers or how about no biometric
access just because you have a badge
doesn't mean I can't clone it we do it
all the time walk up walk by someone
carry the Badger your stuff in our
backpack we clone your badge we come
back later bagent as you
with biometrics that would stop it she
blocks no locks just because your ex
Terriers from you've got a solid
exterior does not guarantee your
interior is not soft and squishy just
because everything's set up nice outside
doesn't mean that once I get inside I
can't get that I can't get inside so you
don't need to worry about do you have
locks badge readers biometric access to
get to your data center or your server
room at the location if you even have it
set up correctly what about no cameras
no alarms do you know if someone in your
organization whether maliciously
accidentally or you have something else
going on walked accidentally went into
that server room or went into your telco
ring you have an alarm there because if
you don't one thing I might just do is
walk in go to your telco room plugin
will you even know I'm there and how
many of you on a regular basis go check
your telco room or your server room for
extra boxes or a raspberry pi for
example that I just plugged in on your
network how many of you know I want to
see hands how many of you in here go
regularly physically check your server
room for extra boxes do you have guys on
static site that do it you know in the
day in a datacenter yeah now that brings
a good question of it do you trust AT&T
completely to know that they're not
plugging something in or they haven't
been compromised exactly exactly how do
you know to trust these people it's the
old thing trust but verify you need to
know hey wait a minute I've just checked
this is out of place here why do I have
this little tiny box that's no bigger
than that
plugged into my switch and whose is it
what's it doing here or how many times
do you go check that teleconferencing
room where all your video equipment is
for that little box that's plugged into
the back of the TV sucking down your
wireless and just sitting there because
you've left your wireless wide open and
all your users use it and how many times
do your users use the same passwords at
home that they do it work because if I
can capture passwords going across that
network on the wireless you can be damn
sure I'm trying those passwords for
their internal ninety percent of the
time it works no cameras you review your
footage information system security now
this is where it gets fun here's a few
points to look at that your network
scanners your security teams your
compliance guys your admins everybody
they will not catch this so how many of
you in here and again this looks a
little bit window centric because most
corporations do have a large windows
base and just because you have some some
of your most secure stuff is linux unix
based services doesn't mean that
passwords aren't going to be reused and
there's not going to be direct ties so
how many of you in here have shares
network shares really that's it not
everybody has network chairs okay maybe
I'm maybe I'm doing the wrong type of
thing then group policies got group
policies do you check your group
policies regularly to make sure that
something hasn't been left over or
checked your logon not bat checked your
login scripts checked everything have
you gone through everything and I doubt
it how many how many of you in here run
a perfectly configured dns service that
i mean there is no possible way that
that's going on and that all of your
worries that may come out of every host
on that machine on these machines now
we'll get caught by your dns meaning
that if they fat finger instead of SRV
01 and they type svr 01 it'll get caught
that your dns will catch that because if
not netbios will give your network away
reason being if you're familiar with how
when does works in general it looks at
its local system looks at its hosts file
it doesn't have the name it then asks
DNS it's going to get a DNS response
back of a host doesn't exist so what
does it do hey everybody who's SVR 01
yep I am and by the way here's the
challenges here send me your hashes all
login what do you do as a Windows client
oh you do and guess what I've just
captured your hashes now let's go back
to what I said earlier what are humans
the weakest link what are their
passwords likely going to be not that
bottom pass were there hell no that's
too hard to type what is it going to be
something like besides 2015 that's
likely what their passwords will be
which means hash cat set a couple of
masks 20 minutes later I have captured
and crap every hash that gets since
across this network and so here's a
question by default who in here has
their dns set up internally to have the
name host w pad and has a valid record
for it think about this for just a
second what did I just say happens from
a windows client so in if you don't know
what W pad is its windows by default one
browsers fire up they search for W pad
looking for their proxy settings if you
don't have a valid response for that in
your dns every time someone starts a
browser on your network guess what I've
just captured their hashes and now if I
want to be a real dick and have you even
more fun with this I'm going to say yes
and here is your proxy settings all
traffic comes through me oh and by the
way to help you here's an executable you
need to serve them give them an
executable to run that will now be my
meterpreter payload who in here besides
you Danny and such knows what
meterpreter is for those of you who
don't know what it is it is a very
powerful shell that gets leveraged on
your box that allows me to do whatever I
want dump the hashes if you've got
administrative privileges I can dump
them clear text I can start to use it to
use your box as a proxy to get to other
boxes just because I'm isolated to one
VLAN doesn't mean I can't get elsewhere
because of your box because it has
access so more your printers so let's go
back to that question I asked earlier
what about your printers so who in here
knows why your printer gave you away
your big nice multifunction you know the
twenty-five-thousand-dollar printer you
bought that does everything who in here
knows why that gives it away anybody
else have any ideas as to why
no how do you log into what do you do
with them your core your clothes well
let's go one better how many of you in
here know that with your nice
multifunction printer you can configure
a username and a password in there to
scan the email or scan to a PDF on a
share right or you print to that so
let's think about this generally
speaking those devices have elevated
privileged accounts not because they
should because most organizations do not
know how to configure their shares
correctly so what do they do they give
that user elevated access reason being
is Bob over and marketing needs to scan
to his share Rob over in IT needs to be
able to scan to his share CEO needs to
be able to scan to a little special
shared just for him so what do they do
they don't know how to configure either
multiple users configure it configure
their shares correctly to give just this
little low privileged user right to scan
here so what do they do here here's
domain admin here's service account
admin level give you access to
everything right so what happens i plug
in line i capture your hashes i capture
the traffic going from your printer out
and what's coming back so i capture
everything that that's printer doing and
how many of you in here know about smtp
what do you know about smtp by default
what does it do when it sends an email
when it logs in is that encrypted
no it's plain text have you configured a
different user for your smtp then you're
what you're doing to scan to share cuz
you're using your same internal domain
right so what happens you'll login it's
clear text I've been capturing traffic
what did I just take I just took that
password clear text off the wire I come
back leak week later take that box out
do something more with the printer I'm
gone how many of you in here actually
would have caught that on your network
caught me put in a device in line
passively sniffing not sending a bit of
traffic other than forwarding it on an
inline bridge and just sniff and
everything as I go anybody know what
about the tools your IT department
installs by default or they leave over
by chance how many of you in here have
used the PS exact tools the PowerShell
to not powershell tools the ps1 is a you
know the old you know microsoft's PS
tools sysinternals thank you you know
you've got the ability to shut down run
commands do everything from those right
your IT department builds the golden
image what about i need to manage how
many different machines oh I'm going to
leave these tools around not because I
them right away because I'm lazy so what
happened they leave them installed just
because as a regular user I won't go
look in c colon backslash random folder
backslash tools you know oh we're safe
nobody will know these are here me as an
attacker i get on your box first thing
i'm doing i'm going through every damn
folder and drive i have access to and
i'm going to suck every document you
have on that machine off and i'm going
to read it i'm going to play i'm going
to look at it
wait a minute can i modify it and put it
back to you great I've got more or can i
exploit something with them or even
better you you just left PS tools
installed with passwords or you've left
history for what these users are done
great now I'm going to use that against
you so another thing how many of you in
here knows what SCCM is couple people
how many of you have ever validated
every package that's on your SCCM and
how often do you do it how many of you
are know anything about it to where the
fact that with SCCM it's admin creds are
left with in the configuration a lot of
times so that you can push packages to
install with administrative privileges
and a user has to click oh okay I accept
to install your desktop deployment stuff
it gets left guess what your creds are
left now good story happened to a
co-worker of mine just recently they
busted SCCM they pushed a new package
was a matter pradesh l their servers by
default pushed and installed these
packages immediately workstations will
give him a chance to do it he also
thought hmm better make sure I'm getting
enough shells he updated the log on da
bat for the domain to also include his
meterpreter shell his attack box crashed
when just after his 8,000th shell came
in he had eight thousand active shells
two different boxes on this network
because of SCCM what could you do if
you're an attack or someone maliciously
coming into a network and you had eight
thousand shells on the network had a
shell on every box in the network how
many of
boxes start up a run with administrative
privileges your sequel server just
installed my package I just took all
your data and you gave it to me because
of your SCCM another thing how many of
you in here use something like SCCM or
some of these other nice fancy desktop
deployment tools and you can do pxe boot
so when joe over and marketing gets a
virus and screws everything up for the
fourth time this week you can just tell
them reboot hit f12 select this option
any of you ever done that desktop
deployment stuff how many of you check
those logs watch for servers boot or
machines booting up and taking those
images how many of you have ever gone
back and checked your DHCP logs for it
to see what happens because I'll tell
you what this just happened for me
recently got onto a network that already
had a few good findings but I decided I
want and domain admin so the admin
credentials to join you have to have
domain admin credentials or very
elevated rights to install a machine to
the domain to join it to the domain sure
making domain level changes so now I
boot up a vm start pixie boonton it gets
up partway right as it's getting ready
to join the domain i disconnect it and
stop to stop the vm so vmware how does
it do its memory what does it use
anybody know especially when you pause a
machine what does it do for with its
memory it writes it to a file on the
disk what's in memory what I'm trying to
join a domain what kind of credentials
are in memory when I'm joining that
domain in clear text
domain admin credentials are in that
memory dump I just grabbed use another
tool pull the credentials right out of
memory wait I've got domain admin and
you just gave it to me because of the
fact you're using a CCM or some other
desktop deployment tool and you're not
checking your logs you're not
restricting access to who can boot
you've got it on your public VLANs all
your major V lines so anybody can do it
you don't have to go through any
configuration to get that machine to
take a new image so me as an attacker
I'm taking it because also if I can't
get domain admin get unlucky I don't get
domain admin out of it I have now got
your standard build which likely is
going to point me in the direction it's
going to have other tools installed it
may have thick clients installed and
again we go back to the old question of
netbios on your network right like I
said it's send in traffic out how many
of you in here doing development work
you know you wrote a big thick client
that's an application but it's got to
get something from the database right
you got to be able to update data or
pull data damn how many of you over the
last few years have rewrote that to make
sure that it's using proper paths you're
not doing any in secure coding practices
right how many of you in here have ever
and if you don't want to raise your hand
you don't have to but think about this
hard coded credentials into your
application to log into the database
happens more often than not especially
you know you find an older application
that was written ten years ago nobody
even thought about that I pulled that
application of Park start looking
through strings dumping it oh wait
here's the seat here's the user name
here's the password the log into your
database there you go
sloppy housekeeping this is where gets
me fired up every time you're leaving
logs lying around on the machines you
leave logs lying around up yours network
seems you don't check your network
shares and don't validate that your
users or following the rules engagement
we're on right now just kind of give you
an idea company thinks it's small I wish
I had this problem by sloppy
housekeeping left a bunch of PII credit
card type data on a network share we
went back to the customer and said hey
look mister customer here you got this
they said oh yeah that's just a child
company of ours not something we're
really worried about they only do four
billion in dollars annually that is
nothing compared to the 990 billion we
do annually we don't care you think the
SEC or whoever else regulatory
commissions that could be involved in
this would care about that little 4
billion dollar chunk because credit card
data because very valuable very
sensitive information is left on a
network share and just because it's a
separate little child company it's under
this parent company do you think they're
going to care whose it was and where it
was now what about one of these you know
and you think about this what about you
leave that information lying around and
you work for something like on the Wall
Street Stock Exchange or you work
somewhere else then you've apps
accidentally left around stock
information or credit ratings for a
company that have not been published yet
and me as an attacker I see that I go oh
wait a minute this company is about
ready to explode in growth I go buy up
as many shares as I can
or I find something else and I get you
to buy it up for me because we've done
it we found a way to get your company to
buy shares and put it to my account
because you had a vulnerability in your
application now i just bought a million
shares of Acme Corp this rating is going
to go from you know very poor rating to
they've got this new great innovative
thing they're going to skyrocket the
predictions are the stock prices are
going to rise from penneys two dollars
anybody know what that's called that's
worked in the financial institute what
insider trading everybody in that
organization that may have touched that
will be going to jail or will be getting
sued and it's going to bust your company
that's called sloppy housekeeping how
many of you in here actually and I want
honest people please raise your hands
review your logs on a weekly monthly
quarterly basis religiously look through
your logs anybody else besides one you
don't look at your logs how do you know
if I'm there how do you know if an
attacker is on your network just because
you're not your antivirus your
anti-malware you know your IDs your neck
your mac filtering all those things just
because they're not alerting doesn't
mean someone is on your network so
thing about it is just kind of give you
here is a typical red team engagement
this will give you an idea generally
this will go anywhere from a few days to
a week we physically break in or we do
the poof magic moment happens we don't
want to have you do a physical
assessment for whatever reason we're
going to let you come in walk in we're
going to give you unrestricted we're
going to give you guest access on this
network here you are you have no creds
nothing now let's see what you can do
generally speaking we start looking
around on the network we fire up we
start capturing traffic we fire up a
tool called responder start netbios name
spoofing like i was talking about we
capture creds we find your hosts okay
can i log into your machine I can what
do you have I'm going to start looking
around you what's your neighbors okay
great now I'm going to jump there I'm
going to run responder I'm on that
network capture more creds war machines
keep going around keep jump around oh
wait a minute I'm also now reading your
email how many of you and ever here have
ever been emailed a password or emailed
someone a password thank you how many of
you have a corporate password reset
functionality that you can do yourself
CA i dinna ca's identity manager some of
these other fun tools reset your
password users on leave because I found
you know they haven't logged in in 30
days cool I'm resetting their password
I'm logging in when they get back wait
my password is not working IT help okay
here we go or here let me go reset my
own password again in the meantime guess
what I've read their emails I know what
they're doing I've used their account to
jump through your network how do you
distinguish me impersonating that user
and that user how do you tell the
difference
so okay now I'm jump around wait a
minute I see what's users I want to
target I've read your entire ad
infrastructure as a regular user we can
do that I see the users I target oh wait
that they sit here can I get another box
can I get something else on this part of
the network can i log into his machine
even as a regular user okay cool i'm in
i'm sitting there i capture his hash he
may not be a domain admin but i've
captured elevated privileges privileges
I login to the servers do a little happy
dance you know now I'm on your server
network I'm capturing live creds for
memory on your server because likely
you've got running processes that I've
been able to exploit as not even explain
being able to see inject into as a
regular user or an admin user that has
those privileges on that machine I
dumped the passwords from memory wait a
minute now I have domain admin as a
domain admin where can I login to on a
network anywhere I want so again i'm
going to your database servers i'm going
to your sharepoint servers that houses
all your intellectual property i'm using
it to create another user to give myself
application access to your front end
system so that i can log in and dump
everything because the database is too
big for me to dump too slow for me to
top copy everything over oh shoot i'm
right at the end so that being said a
couple of things in conclusions things
as an organization you need to be doing
check your logs watch them religiously
know and distinguish traffic if you see
Bob from accountings logging into your
servers at two in the morning what the
hell's Bob doing is it really Bob likely
no likely it's me likely I'm slurping
your data down
why is your essay a counter why is your
service account logging in and checking
your databases when it's not back up a
scheduled backup and why do I have
interactive login rights to your servers
you need to be checking your logs you
need to be vigilant just because you
think you've set things up right you
need to be looking for you need to be
looking for the UNAM nominalist traffic
the other thing about it is you need to
be the strongest link you need to become
the strongest link because your
technology will and can fail can and
will fail we will find ways around your
technology but you as the as the admin
the users will find those things
happening and can report it up to the
right people so that they can raise that
flag and say hey wait we're done we
gotta stop this thank you everybody
hopefully gave you something to think
about and consider