better awesome thanks guys so I've
noticed that a lot of lots changed since
I've been laid off in the last five
years the markets changed a lot and I
found something kind of disturbing
that's happened in the last several
years I'm talking to a lot of other
people that have been employed
unemployed lately as well and some of
these guys are having a hard time
finding jobs which is odd this is really
australiana point rate in the United
States for information security
professionals is point six seven and I
do believe that honestly honestly there
should always be a certain percentage of
people always unemployed yeah you have
those co-workers so point six seven so
why why are people having a hard time
finding a job so this is some original
research I did I did the other day and I
thought did a search on on indeed and
monster and I looked at the number of
job postings for cissp and then I
divided that by the population of that
job market and I found Utah is second
for the last there is only one job
posting / 78,000 people in that job
market whereas who would have thought
denver denver is the hottest market
right now for information security
professionals almost seven times as many
jobs / kappa then there is here instead
the Salt Lake market when you look at
other job titles like information
security architect same kind of thing
you're seeing 212 job openings in in
Denver you're seeing 19 in Utah when you
adjust that it's it's another nine times
different so you know just something to
think about why in this market our
company is not investing in information
security why what why is that I would
love to have a drink with someone at
at the bar tonight and figure out I have
not figured out why all the variables
why companies in Utah aren't investing
in information security professionals no
I I have noticed that three-fourths of
the jobs that I've applied for their
work from home jobs at first I didn't
know how to find those jobs just so
anyone else if you find yourself in the
same situation I go to indeed and under
the where put remote and that will list
all of your work from home jobs okay now
to my real talk that was just a little
side bit informational thing that I just
found is interesting and thought i would
share maybe give you a little warm hug
and figure out why you hate living in
utah so has anyone ever heard before
everyone heard this from senior
management we be more than our
competition does to protect our
customers data oh we you know we we
invest millions of dollars millions of
dollars the investor cuts to protect our
customers data we you know how could
this breach have happened we spent all
this money but we still got all what's
up with that you know using public
information I I can find all sorts about
it at company without even right running
and in that test if you're going to do a
pin test google is your friend so you
don't even generate all of this noise
before while you can tuck your your
preliminary phases of your of your pin
test cut your noise out with Google and
let me show you some other other ways
that you can harvest really great
information for a pen tester all from
these public sources having having this
data I can actually build org charts and
so when I'm when I'm doing social
engineering I can go into the org chart
and say hey cuz I have the entire org
chart up when I'm doing social
engineering pen test
and I say okay I know everyone in the
company and a lot of times I have their
phone numbers their email addresses so
it makes pentesting so much easier itn
staffing levels execution in the
boardroom I've been able to go into the
boardroom and say hey all of our
competition they they have X number of
information security professionals /
thousands of employees why are we
staffed at one-tenth of staffing level
as our competition using this
information has provided me an emission
to get more IT staffing 44 by
departments because ultimately I I can
say I'm secure not secure really all my
all my management cares is that they're
cooler than our competition is so how
can a bad guy use this information okay
if I was a bad guy and I saw two
separate companies and I saw that this
the put this company over here had a
hundred infosec employs and this in this
company company be over here had ten
infosec employees which would I choose
as a target so having this understanding
what helps with target acquisition as a
bad guy project just justifications are
great to justify your projects knowing
what your competition is running helps
you justify your projects for example at
my last company I've been trying to push
a citrix vdi project through i wanted to
remove all the data off of everyone's
laptops container eyes it and make it as
so it was a one-way container and
management kept pushing back at me
because it was a large financial
investment it was a lot lot of money and
so and for a year they told me no and
then I started I came up with this this
method and that's when I went to
management says okay tell me who you
perceive as our top 25 competitors I
want to know who you perceive as being
competition then after that I took that
list of who they perceived as the
competition and then I turned around and
that's when I started doing doing my
analysis because they took those people
as serious then I went to the board and
says hey seventy-two percent of our
competition is using VDI to da another
eleven percent have opened job
requisitions looking for vdi
professionals so that's eighty-three
percent of our competition is using the
EDI and also another one of the
executives and the boardroom turns turns
to me and says well if they're doing it
why aren't we my bit my head was like
all but all us another their light
turned on because all of it was real to
them they don't care what what Gartner
group says well I form it Wow ok so so
where is all this data coming from that
we're finding on the Internet well it's
mostly coming from your the employees
that you have and your HR departments
that are the most guilty so let's let's
go into how we're going to find this so
let's start with linkedin profiles so
first we need to have a discussion
around being able to do meaningful
search on linkedin without paying a lot
of money you need to have lots of
connections originally when linked out
linkedin came out it was like i'm only
going to connect with people that I know
and just keep this close-knit little
community well if you want to do this if
you want meaningful searches you need
lots of connections so you can see that
i currently have 26 hundred connections
but i can see their friends and i can
see their friends of friends so in
reality i have access to 29 million
linkedin
files right now so the question you're
asking so if how do I build my linkedin
network so i can spy on my competition
lions lions is the key here oftentimes
what you'll see is you'll see someone
with their profile and it will say lion
what lion means is if you send me a
request i'm just going to say yes I
accept I don't care if I know you or not
so it means linkedin open network I'm
open to open suggestions for requests so
that's what you can actually do is when
you do a search search for lions and so
and then just start sending them
linkedin request also there's mailing
lists that you can go to to find a email
list of people that are welcome to being
lions these are CSV files at first I'm
like how do i import all these CSV files
just quick tip real quick you just go
into connections say any email and then
at the very bottom you can say import vs
CSV and that's when you import these
bulk lists that contain thousands of
email addresses that you can connect
with and that will bolster your your
connections really quick like I said
before if you don't have all these
connections you're gonna have to you're
gonna have to pay for it even even if
you don't pay for it they do have hey
walls so you're only allowed as a free
subscriber I think about a hundred
searches per month and it resets at the
first of every month so if you do too
many too many searches you're going to
be locked out for a month just be aware
that that exists when I was doing my
research I'm like oh dang it p wall so
what when I'm targeting accompany the
first thing I do is I I look up the
company and in LinkedIn and what I'm
looking for it first is their company
size what LinkedIn
thinks their company sizes then the next
thing I look for is how many had
connections do I have into that company
so I can see that there's 363 361
employees in LinkedIn which is right in
that 500,000 target size and I have
direct connections to half that people
so I have really pretty decent coverage
inside that company once you've once now
you start doing searches for all the
employees in that company you can just
say show me when you search for the
company there's a little link on the
site that says show me how I'm connected
this is how you start building your org
charts it's very important to build your
org chart and you can even a lot of
times you have pictures put your org
charts they're really pretty so start
targeting down the infosec departments
for these these companies that you're
targeting okay so all of a sudden hey
this guy this enterprise architect here
that works for this company he says that
while he works at this company he did
Active Directory 2012 exchange Lync 2013
office 365 hmm I wonder what they run
inside their infrastructure he just he
just told me right here I know that this
company runs act of directly 2012 here's
another one I work on the firewall
administrator I run palo alto here's the
model numbers of the palo alto here's
the version of my palo alto that i'm
running building budgets is also helpful
when you're justifying the the size of
your IT department and you're trying to
use this information to justify your
you're spending at an organization it's
pretty easy to estimate someone's IT
spinning
let's see here these running
distribution switches of 36 50s and 37
50 x is this looks like his core
switches are looks like a pairing of 70
tens and 70 18 and he's running cisco a
sa 5515 firewalls it's pretty easy that
for me to tell you one that has some
background and Cisco can get on their
calculator and tell me what their annual
budget is it's pretty easy developers
but I want to find out what programming
languages they're using in inside their
development I can just search for the
LinkedIn profiles for those developers
and they don't tell ya hey I'm ready I
write PHP hmm wonder if there's some
Java vulnerabilities if I can find some
Java developers are there sometimes all
you have to look as job titles people's
job titles citrix senior netscaler
engineer do you think they run thats
killers at that company odds are yes
fail but we're okay sorry hey another
way you can once you you have your or
chart now you can go to salaries calm
you take you take all the headcount you
found from linkedin and now you start
plugging it into salaries calm and you
can actually build in what their annual
IT spending is for headcount what their
head count budget is so I know X company
over here based on these job titles
they're spending 3.7 million dollars in
spending so when I go to management I
can say hey they're spending that much
I'm spending one-tenth that what's going
on here guys so if I don't have enough
data from LinkedIn profiles let's switch
okay let's switch to resumes now you
have a LinkedIn I or chart you've built
out now you have specific names
that you can go out on the internet and
start looking for their resumes that
they've posted online because I found
that people put a lot more detail of
what they did at an employer in their
resume then they put in their LinkedIn
profile so what you do is you go to end
indeed com and click on resin to find
resumes that middle link at the very top
left and you just type in their name and
then I just put in Utah and so I'll go a
walkthrough of the entire or chart
looking for people that have posted
their resumes out great way to harvest
information about a company so you can
see this guy's in this this resume here
in his resume hey I worked at this
company and here's some specific things
about my organization about this company
things that he didn't share in his
linkedin profile but he would love to
share in the resume that he posted
online so if that doesn't work now we
switch to job postings so job when
companies look for people they'll tell
you the world of what they're looking
for they'll say I'm looking for a Java
developer with this version of Java that
has this experience or I'm looking for a
sissy sissy DN that has cisco ucs yada
yada yada so now just by reading a job
posting I pretty much know what their
infrastructure is so there again when i
do that pin test i can generate a lot
less noise so you can see this company
here is looking for specifically a
vcenter 5.5 guy that has experience in
vm turbo this tells me a lot about the
organization same
thing I can see that what their
antivirus program is so if I know what
if I know what their defenses are if I
if I can look at an organization and
says okay your head you have an in-depth
a defense-in-depth strategy you're
running these security protocols and
these products I'm going to go ahead and
fire up in my lab that exact same
environment and i'm going to start
creating exploits and payload that i can
test in my lab before I I try it in on
that company so it helps me develop
payload as a pen tester work has a bad
guy because I can mirror what their
production environment looks like one of
the trouble things that I didn't find
that I wish I would have found was a
free site that allowed me to do
historical searches on companies job
postings I found one website that does
it but charges tens of thousands of
dollars to basically say show me show me
every posting that this company has ever
made for a sysadmin if you guys know the
site that there's a warm hug it in
exchange for that information another
awesome place to find disclosures that
they shouldn't be posting press releases
this this this example here comes from
VMware so VMware did a case study of
cornerstone lending it's a mortgage
company and so in the case case study
they says okay our VMware environment
consists of HP BL blades with this much
memory so if I'm trying to do an
estimate estimation of how much of a
denial of service attack how much
hardware I'm going to need to flood out
there there there VMware environment
that pretty much tells me exactly what I
need I know exactly what kind of storage
they have and they published it right in
their white paper when they did the case
study and then also
here's another great one they had a
video they had a video of their case
study and they see they show these guys
in their data center and Allison so I
don't even care what these guys look
like that they're wearing those little
hot sexy man blue shirt what I do care
about is what they're standing in front
of so on the left one there you can see
a VNX I see two big-ip controllers I can
see specifically I can see exactly what
technologies are running in their data
center because they took a picture and
posted it online I was floored to see
the number of data center photos that I
was able to find from companies online
it was like really really you posted a
picture of your data center online
really now some of you might be going no
I don't think that's a big deal but
others I think others in this audience
or the lights coming on going maybe this
is a bad idea you know other thing in
this this posting they took a screenshot
in the video of their public of their
vcenter environment this is there like
here's a picture of RV center with all
of our server names they put in a press
release so these are not the kind of
things that I'm looking for so I can
quickly do an analysis of a company in
an hour or two so the question you can
you can ask yourself is this worth doing
once or twice a year spending a couple
hours once or twice a year and and as an
information security professional and
just going through and just searching
for this really quick I went to our HR
department our legal department I says
okay do I have the ability and the right
to tell sis admins that they may need to
take certain information off their their
LinkedIn profiles and the the feedback
that I got from my legal department when
I did have a job was the combination
while running a particular technology
like Cisco is not proper wouldn't say
earth-shattering
the combination of technologies that
your company is running and can be
construed as your company secret sauce I
it the combination itself could be
alluded as proprietary information in of
itself so the people the legal people I
talked to said yes because in most
employee agreements it says that you
cannot disclose proprietary company
information but check with your legal
departments so first off should we we
talked about if we should you should we
monitor this should we watch for this so
how do we stop it how do we stop this
disclosure of information having company
policies in place I second don't use
vendor specific job titles instead of
instead of saying Citrix admin or
vcenter admin just call it us this
engineer or it's just admin so work with
your HR departments into making your job
titles more generic and not specific
towards up take a particular technology
I I did some scouting in that list of
companies that my organization took as
being serious competition i found one
particular organization that they had
posts that you could tell they had gone
through and sanitized because when i
searched that company all their IT guys
all it said was this admin no
description note of what they had while
they worked there and when i looked at
their job postings they were very vague
and so what they had done is they were
leveraging their HR is systems and their
HR department because now when they when
they post a vague job posting it takes a
lot more HR resources to filter that
down to what they're actually looking
for so they relied heavily on their HR I
asked system to filter out job
submissions people that have made job
postings
to really get what they were really
after so it was a bit more work for
their HR department I'm a kind of guy
that just talks quick you'd like to link
in with me there's no there's my contact
information if you'd like to send me a
lengthy and information invitation
there's my email address that's pretty
much all I have does anyone have any
comments questions useless trivia yeah
go ahead I didn't go down so what he
asked was is are there any other sites
that you've used besides linkedin or in
da torso or what you presented in this
presentation you know you have cyclic
montego which is another great resource
twitter twitter facebook but where i had
the most luck with that i didn't mention
in this is once you have people's names
from that org chart that you did so you
created this org chart now you start
scouring message board forms for for
postings that that person is put like I
love to scour Microsoft's technet site
looking for postings that that questions
that that engineer is posted because a
lot of times people disclose too much on
unform sites that's that's another one
do you have anything it is there any
other suggestions that you would you
would have
yeah so so any see any site that people
were willing to disclose sensitive
information on go blast door that was my
other one I forgot to mention that yes
glass door is another great great
website the people will disclose too
much it's like buying a buying an
engineer a beer he'll take it anything
any other questions okay guys appreciate
that thanks guys