we are really stoked to have ava talking
about a really interesting topic
all right ava you're on everything looks
great take it away
let us begin
so hi everybody uh my name is eva
galperin and welcome to hey siri find my
ex tech enabled abuse in the apple
ecosystem
you may be wondering who i am unless you
already heard patrick's very kind
introduction i am the director of cyber
security at the electronic frontier
foundation i also co-founded the
coalition against stalkerware uh you can
reach me at eva
eff.org or you can annoy me on twitter
at evaside
so let's go ahead and get started and
the most important thing that we that we
need to talk about is
so what is tech-enabled intimate partner
abuse
um so as most as more and more of our
lives become digital uh abuse has really
uh moved online
it is now extremely common for us to
keep uh
most of our lives in some sort of uh of
digital device so your uh your calendar
is online your photos are online your
messages are are in some device uh your
social media uh
accounts and more importantly your
location because uh now that we all
carry cell phones around uh we are all
essentially carrying
location devices in in our back pockets
at all times and this is information
which is extremely tempting
for
governments to go after which is one of
the reasons why we've spent so much time
for example talking about pegasus and
for exactly the same reason that this
information is tempting for uh for
governments it is also tempting for
abusers
the
primary method
in
use that um
that abusers have used in order to sort
of
keep
on their on their survivors and targets
victims
is
a class of software called stalkerware
stockerware is a class of software that
enables someone to secretly spy on
another person's private life via their
devices
the abuser can remotely monitor the
whole device including web searches
geolocation text messages photos voice
calls and much more
these programs are easy to buy and
install and
they are commercially available
the primary
marker of of stalkerware
is that it runs hidden in the background
without the affected person knowing or
giving their consent
uh it is very easy to find these
products for example this is a google
search for spy on my partner's iphone
the iphone is not some sort of magical
device that is
immune to
these kinds of
of attacks
so your
not particularly technically adept
abuser starts with a google search the
google search provides them with links
to a variety of products
and here is what they go on and do
so first
the abuser purchases the license for
this doctor where
then they entered the target's apple id
and password into the stalker
website uh one of the um
one of the things that actually made it
really difficult to convince av
companies at first to
recognize stalkerware as malicious was
they said well in order to to use these
products you need to have the person's
apple id and password and if you have
their apple id and their password then
that is essentially legitimate access to
uh to the user's device they should be
able to get this information anyway why
should we label this software as
malicious and i have news for them about
how abuse works it's actually extremely
common for abusers to have their
their targets apple id and password
because they're able to coerce it out of
them
then the stock award company uses these
credentials to log into the targets
account and it downloads data from the
icloud backups of devices
and finally the abuser logs into the
stock aware web portal
to view the data which is updated with
every icloud backup
so
apple knows about all of this and in an
effort to combat breached icloud
accounts
apple has made a bunch of security
improvements to their services over the
years which helped make icloud more
secure the first thing that they did was
they added to 2fa to apple id
first it was introduced and
now it is the default setting for apple
ids this is an effective mitigation
against abusers who do not have physical
access to the targets phone but it's
less helpful for survivors who still
live with or share space with their
abusers apple has more recently put in
place restrictions relating to icloud
this makes it much more difficult for
external devices such as spyware to
retrieve backup data from icloud whether
the account has two-factor
authentication or not
so how effective are the icloud
mitigations uh certo i a uh security
research company which is also a member
of the coalition against stalkerware uh
took a look at the top 25 stalkerware
apps and in their report they wrote that
of those 25 apps uh only three uh offer
an icloud solution that could allegedly
get all the data from an icloud backup
of an iphone
they tested icloud products uh from
these three spyware providers with an
apple id that had two factors turned on
as well as another apple id that didn't
and none of the products were able to
retrieve data from the backup in their
test icloud accounts but
what about partial data
uh of the original 25 uh another seven
spyware providers claim to be able to
steal data from icloud but in a more
limited way uh so rather than acquiring
a full backup uh they were claiming that
they were able to download uh
download data that had been synced with
icloud however and that can include
things like imessages contacts photos
real-time location
certo
tested all seven of these services with
their test apple ids only two of them
could successfully download the synced
data from icloud the other five failed
to establish a connection to apple's
servers regardless of whether the
account had two-factor authentication or
not
so basically most of these services
don't work a lot of them still advertise
themselves as working and if you look
through the reviews you can see
a lot of complaints
so does that mean that the problem of
stalker wear on the iphone has been
solved completely and the answer is
no
so this is web watcher uh webwatcher
uses a feature uh called itunes wi-fi
sync which is a built-in ios feature
used to backup an iphone to a user's
computer on the same network as opposed
to having to use a usb
this feature is used by web watcher as a
way to retrieve data from the phone onto
a computer on the same network
this can be the attacker's computer or
the victim's own computer
in addition the hacker can set up a
feature that will cause the iphone to
automatically back up all of its data to
the computer every time the phone is
synced via the network usually this is
overnight when it's connected to the
wi-fi
does it work
sort of
web watcher reviews are full of
complaints about the limitations of this
product including the lack of real-time
data unless you're on the same network
uh so that's great
however it is very useful for an
attacker that that lives with their
target because uh the target is coming
back to uh to the same place as uh as
their abuser and they are often using
the same network i indeed they are using
it overnight which makes web watcher
perfect for this particular type of
scenario
the other sort of downside of web
watcher is that it's very easy to detect
because all you need to do is check to
see if the itunes wi-fi sync is turned
on
so it turns out most methods of spying
on ios devices these days are detectable
through a thorough review advice and
account settings and
to this end apple has written a really
fantastic manual
with the world's most boring name
it is called device and data access when
personal safety is at risk and i've put
the url up here and let me tell you i
have a huge crush on this manual
this manual has everything it has
reviews of account settings it has
reviews of device settings it includes a
discussion of the apple watch it has
screenshots it has checklists this is
everything that i could ever want and i
constantly point uh people who are
concerned about their
um
about their phones and their their apple
devices and their
uh apple ids to
this particular manual it's really easy
to go through i think it's something
like 18 pages and you can do the whole
review
relatively quickly
so everything is great in apple land
uh until a couple months ago when apple
put out a new personal tracker called
so tracking and monitoring a person's
location without their consent is is
really
it's not new
uh apple did not in fact just invent
stalking uh
non-consensual tracking existed even
before the internet uh it's just a lot
easier now thanks to the internet of
things and our increasingly digital
lives because again we are carrying
tracking devices around in our pockets
and when those tracking devices fail uh
now we suddenly have these uh these
nifty little iot devices uh that track
our our entire digital lives
so the appeal of a product like the air
tag is that it's designed to make it
easier to keep track of things that you
have lost so the air tag
is something that you attach to say your
keys or that you stick in your wallet or
a bag and when
you then pair it to uh to your phone
they communicate over bluetooth and when
you have uh
moved your keys or your bag or your
wallet uh a certain distance from your
uh from your phone you will get a
message and furthermore if you are
looking for your keys or your bag
you can simply call up siri and you can
say hey siri find my keys and it will
give you a location if you are within
bluetooth range if you're not within
bluetooth range we will talk uh about
that a little bit further down the line
so this is a wonderful way of keeping
track of your lost stuff
unfortunately the flip side of this is
uh is a problem uh the
you cannot build a device that will
track people who have stolen an item
without alerting them
without alerting them without also
building a tracking device that aids
domestic abusers and stalkers and that's
why these devices are usually not
marketed for this purpose so basically
you have created something that helps
you find lost stuff and that's great um
but once you create something that helps
you find stolen stuff then essentially
you have also created a perfect stocking
device
so let's talk a little bit about
the the greater impacts here
the
advent of the air tag means that there
is
increased access and increased awareness
of this sort of non-consensual tracking
i it also means that there are more
unaware of victims there are people who
you know do not yet know how uh what
these things are or how they work and
they don't know to look for them
and
finally
the way that the air tag works
allows it to leverage a vast network for
long-range tracking which is
particularly disturbing so now we're
going to talk a little bit about that
so the close range tracking on um
on an air tag is done
via bluetooth what you do is you pair
your phone to uh to your air tag and if
you get out of range you you know you
get an alert
um
and this is fairly normal we see these
sorts of things all the time it's pretty
standard um
for example the
the tile does something
does something very similar you pair
your tile to your phone
you have the tile app installed on your
phone and then um
if you lose your tile it will let you
know when when you are out of range and
it will also tell you you know where
your tile is if you have lost it and
it's out of range um so with a tile uh
you're
uh if you have you know lot
lost your thing with a tile attached to
it in the middle of nowhere and you are
uh
you're not near a whole lot of other
phones you are really dependent on
somebody else coming along uh within
bluetooth range who has the tile app
installed on their phone
um the air tag on the other hand is
considerably more powerful which is one
of the reasons why uh i was i was so
outraged when uh when the air tag came
out
and what the air tag does is it turns
every single iphone with find my turned
on into the network which uh the other
air tags uh that the other air tags talk
to so you can probably go all day
uh without running into somebody who has
the tile app installed on uh on their
phone
but
uh
going all day without running into
bluetooth range of somebody with an
iphone that has my uh that has find my
installed on it i is considerably
less likely
so the the tracking power of the air tag
is much much stronger
so apple uh was was not completely blind
to the potential for misuse and it
includes some kind of anti-stalking
mitigations and the mitigations are as
follows uh the
iphone if you have an iphone
and the iphone notices that there is a
an air tag that's moving along with you
that is traveling where you are
traveling
it will give you a pop-up notice
uh furthermore when the air tag first
came out i it would uh it would wait uh
three days if it was out of range and
then it would start to give a sound
alert there's a little beeping noise uh
that beeping noise
is not very loud it's about 60 decibels
and it is extremely easy to muffle
so it has kind of a limited utility
especially if the person that you are
tracking uh has uh has hearing issues um
or again it's really easy to just like
stick it between some cushions or you
know uh tape it up so that it does not
it does not make this noise so the
effectiveness of this mitigation is
really limited
um
one of the things that apple did after
the
uh
after the air tag came out and there
were a lot of complaints about its
stalking abilities was they shortened
the amount of time that the air tag
would take in order to make this noise
uh from three days to one day so now
instead of three days of free stocking
you only get one day of free stocking
before the easily silenced beeping noise
begins
so what happens if you have an android
absolutely nothing uh the uh there is no
android app uh that allows you or rather
apple did not come out with an android
app that allows you to know when you are
being tracked by an air tag i and again
the sound alert is not very effective
uh furthermore one of the big problems
with the uh with the little b
noise that uh
that the air attack makes
when it is uh is out of range a phone
with which it is paired is that
frequently we are dealing with abusers
who
live with the people that they are
abusing and tracking i and if uh the
again the uh
the reset timer was at three days when
the air tag first came out so as long as
the air tag got within range of the
abuser's phone every three days the
even the little ineffective beeping
noise would not be set off
i and now that's been uh brought down to
24 hours which again is still
approximately as often as a uh as an
abuser will see their victim especially
if they are living together so
their reset loophole is kind of a big
deal
there are again a bunch of reasons why
we are concerned about the use of uh of
air tags uh as part of intimate partner
violence uh the first is that a partner
can
stick the
stick the air tag say
uh
in the back of a car between the
cushions or they can
stick the air tag into a into a bag
belonging to the victim that they that
they are trying to track i and again as
long as they come home once every 24
hours in order to reset uh they will
never be the wiser except for
uh
if they have an iphone and if they have
an iphone they may receive an alert that
tells them that there is an air tag
traveling with them if you have an
android you are out of luck
so we can talk a little bit how this
about how this uses uh
find my
uh we are already seeing news articles
uh both about the about the tile which
has been out for a very long time uh but
also about people being tracked using
error tags uh my contacts in the
domestic violence world uh have uh
informed me that they almost immediately
started seeing air attacks appear in the
bags and cars of uh the people that they
were working with who were trying to
escape intimate partner abuse
um there are some options or rather
there is one option right now i if you
are concerned about air tags and you
have an android uh which is this uh this
app right here uh airguard airguard is
uh up here on uh on github and you can
install it on your uh on your android
and it should tell you whether or not
there is an air tag or some other sort
of find my accessory following you uh i
cannot guarantee this because this is a
fairly new app and i have not yet had
an opportunity to test it myself uh
apple has also announced that they will
be coming out with an android app
but we are led to believe that it will
be coming in approximately december
which gives us several months of free
tracking and is very disturbing
so
what should apple have done
um
it turns out that there are actually
some guidelines for how you build
products that are resistant to
technology enabled intimate partner
abuse
the first is to
is that you should ah wrong slide
the first is that you should promote
diversity
i when you have teams composed of of
many different kinds of people they are
more likely to create products that that
address the needs of a more diverse
community
the second is that you need to guarantee
uh privacy and choice you need uh you
need your products to make it uh very
clear what information is uh is
available to what users and how to lock
everything down
the third is that you should
build your products in such a way that
they combat gas lighting
one of the ways in which you can do this
is
by having reliable logs
on your products to show you know are
you know who logged in at what time what
device were they logging in from and uh
and what did they do because uh
gaslighting is really one of the most
powerful tools of intimate partner abuse
uh the fourth is that you should
strengthen uh your security and
again the security of uh of the
data that uh that you are gathering uh
one of the interesting things about
studying stalkerware is that frequently
stalkerware is uh is not very effective
but in addition to not being effective
it is frequently not very secure there
have been uh i think something like half
a dozen
different instances in which a
stalkerware product uh was storing all
of the information uh that was uh you
know being covertly exfiltrated from
various users uh in a cnc and that cnc
was left wide open uh or was very easily
compromised uh so apple actually did a
fairly good job of that
but that is one of the one of the other
concerns and finally make technology
more intuitive the easier your
technology is to use and the easier it
is to understand who has access and who
does not have access
and how to use all you know all of your
your different settings uh the less
likely it is that your technology will
be used uh for intimate partner abuse uh
i am not the person who came up with
these principles these principles are uh
are from ibm and i strongly recommend
that that you read their report uh and
more importantly i strongly recommend
that apple read this report before
they put out more
new and exciting products
so where do we go from here
there
there is good news and there is bad news
uh the good news is that when it comes
to stalker wear
stalkerware has uh has definitely seen a
downturn
in the
in the apple ecosystem it is harder and
harder to use stalkerware
to spy on somebody's ios device uh
furthermore we have this wonderful
manual the manual allows us to uh to
lock people out in a way that is very
easy to uh to implement and that is easy
to follow the downside is that this
manual is in an obscure portion of the
internet uh and does not have a uh a
title that
uh that is very googleable and one of
the uh one of the downsides of this is
that i frequently have to be the person
who points uh the survivors of intimate
partner uh violence to this manual
instead of this manual being very easy
to find uh for survivors um
the bad news is that apple keeps putting
out products like the air tag so with
one in hand they they take it away with
the other hand they give it to the
stalkers
i was actually so angry about this that
i wrote an op-ed uh with albert foxconn
for wired called uh air tags are a gift
for stalkers um
and the mitigations that apple has in
place have a tremendous blind spot uh
the remember the number one uh principle
that people should be following in order
to build products that are resistant to
intimate partner abuse is diversity on
your team and uh i don't know how
diverse the team was that built the air
tag but i can tell you
that they had a tremendous blind spot
and their blind spot was android users
they simply could not imagine people who
lived entirely outside of the apple
ecosystem and as a result those are
people who are particularly vulnerable
to abuse using their product
so everything is great but also
everything is horrible
i am keeping an eye out for the android
app which apple has promised us in
december i and i am also keeping a very
wary eye out for future iot products
because i am fairly certain that that is
where we are likely to find uh sort of
the most disturbing developments
thank you very much
[Applause]