[Music]
praveen and nils would you please
uh start your presentation and welcome
to nalcon online
um hi
i guess you can see my screen
absolutely we can see your screen
praveen
so i'm praveen
this is a joint talk with nils we both
are senior security analysts at riskier
this talk is going to be um
how to based on fault injection
and we achieved arbitrary code execution
on risk 5
based
risk fire based devices using fault
injection and we'll show you
how we achieve this
so we start with
a basic introduction to fault injection
attacks
then we explain what is our exact
contribution
and show the different approaches
to controlling program counter
on risk firebase devices and we finally
show
experimental results on one of the
risk 5 based socs
so what do we mean by fault
fault is anything that triggers an
unexpected
and incorrect execution
but that happens by intentionally
altering the environment so sometimes
false can happen
unintentionally but here the goal is to
actually alter the environment in such a
way
that the program execution
uh changes let's take an example
so this is a simple piece of code which
checks signature of uh an image
to authenticate uh before it
executes it so you can see uh there is a
function called check signature
and the image is provided in in this
argument and if
this everything went well
uh the authenticated will be set to true
and if that is the case then
the device starts executing the image
otherwise
uh it does it just resets
the device or it it knows that
the image is not a proper one so it
should not continue execution
so this is normal what you see in most
of the
yeah secure devices
so let's say we want to
induce false while this piece of code is
being executed right
so
specifically we want to induce
faults when this if check is being
performed so
as i mentioned if this authenticator is
true
then it should go here but let's say i
induce
a fault when this if check is happening
and then change the outcome of this if
condition
what can happen instead of going to the
else
the program actually starts executing
and thereby
an image which was not authenticated
will be executed on the device giving
attacker runtime control
so that's that's what
fault injection can do but how can we
trigger falls into devices
typically any uh integrated circuit has
a safe operating area where
what kind of frequency it can operate
at what kind of uh voltage levels it can
operate at
so you see here uh the safe operating
area
right
[Music]
yeah so this is the safe operating area
and then anything
beyond this is not gonna make the chip
work
but uh
let's say the operating area is 1.8 to
5.5 volts
and if you go beyond 5.5
for a long time that could kill the
chick
right so it's overpowers and then it
might kill it
then if we go below 1.8
for a long time the chip might not even
boot so nothing happens
both those scenarios are not something
we are interested in
what we are interested in is
making uh changing this voltage
for a very uh slight
amount of time so that the chip
doesn't uh die
our chip doesn't just not boot uh
but it's it keeps operating but it
triggers
a faulty execution on the program
so we want to change this voltage
outside the safe operating area
only for a very slight
amount of time and then
if you remember the previous example
what we want to do is we want to change
this voltage
exactly when this if check is being
uh executed and but by that
we uh we would be able to
execute an image which was not
authenticated
then um there are a lot of techniques
with which we can
inject falls into devices
we can use laser uh
this allosa is inducing very precise
falls
into a particular part of the chip even
like your cpu or memories
flash um so you can
very precisely in inject falls into a
particular component even to the level
of
a few registers as i already
mentioned earlier you can use voltage to
either
go beyond the operating area or below
it electromagnetic pulses
to create um yeah em false
temperature change the uh yeah
over uh yeah go beyond the
operating conditions of the chip or even
clock frequency
so there exists a lot of ways in which
you can induce faults
into the device
but another thing to note here is that
faults are not limited to just hardware
[Music]
you can induce false even just from
software
there are quite some results
in the recent past which proves that for
example
row hammer attacks which
attacks the dram by
repeatedly accessing certain memory
locations
um then we have clock screw
where this is pretty much similar to
what i explained before the physical
falls
but you don't really have to change
anything
on the device you just need to write
a program in the non-trusted part of the
system
which can change either the clock
frequency or the voltage
uh that the device operates on and then
that can
manifest uh the required falls
um yeah there are some more results that
are similar to that
as well so faults
are not only just limited to uh
hardware but you can also induce them
uh software as well
and yeah so there are
a lot of results uh using fault
injection lately it has been uh
quite let's say uh in the news
um you can see some of our colleagues
also had um results on for example esp32
secure boot so we were able to
bypass the secure boot using fault
injection
and then uh name data hacking
yeah all sorts of things that were
done with the fine
so on this particular topic that
we are going to present today uh
a lot of our ex colleagues and ex
interns
also worked on it similar thing um
some of the examples that you can see
here
um specifically uh controlling pc
on arm this was one of the first papers
which shows
uh how fault injection can be
used to directly control a program
counter
and if you can control program counter
then
you can execute your own code on the
device
so but this one was particularly uh
for arm 32-bit architectures
so then there was later
another presentation by nick and
christopher
this relates to a bit more generic
way of inducing false and yeah
data transfers so that you
get code execution so not only just
changing the program counter but there
are
other options that they show are
possible
to achieve the same uh end result
so in this
uh contra our contribution here
is that we do a similar thing which
is showing that program counter can also
be
controlled on a risk firebase
devices and
while doing that what we discovered is
that
we will get into bit more details later
but the idea is that
in risk 5 i say program counter is not
directly accessible to the programmer so
it's
internal it's not directly exposed
in the programmer model of the isa so
the previous attacks basically for
example on um
how they work is you have uh you change
the destination register of an
instruction
to program counter and then if
you can do that then you you can control
pc
right but
this is possible on arm because um
exposes the pc directly to a programmer
but in case of risk five pc is not
directly exposed
right so then
our expectation before we did this
experiment
was that yeah we cannot directly control
pc so we need to find
indirect ways but during this uh
experiments
we realized that we were still able to
directly change pc
uh we do not exactly
for 100 know how this happened
because sometimes fault injection is
like that we don't know
what exactly happened but we have some
hypothesis
nils will explain later uh during the
experiment
experimental results um what
what i'm talking about here but yeah so
that's also another contribution which
is that
we find new fault models not just
the direct instruction or data related
but
more related to the hardware itself
yeah so then
as i mentioned we are doing it on
risk 5 based devices so some of you may
already know but
for those who don't it's um it's in
free and open instruction set
architecture
and uh the good thing here is that
there is no license fee to
use it um and yeah that that makes
the brings the barrier down
and it's based on reduced instruction
set computer principles
just like uh um our
mips and it has modular design
right so there is a base integer isa
that that is there for all the
implementations but then it can be
easily extended
and because of its modular nature
it makes it very easy to
extend it for your own use case
and we expect that
risk five will be very popular in the
near future
because of the reasons that i just
mentioned
so let's uh
see a bit more into the details of the
risk
uh and if you look at the registers
available
there are 32 registers
um yeah i mean if you if you looked into
any if i
says you know there are a bunch of
registers
some of them you could already see
for example a retina address which is
called link register in
arm and then you have the stack pointer
uh and then you see some of some temp
registers that are
typically used uh yeah to
transfer data uh during the program
execution from one to the other or
operate
on the data and then yes
some registers to store the function
arguments written values and so on so
these are all
nothing fancy here so if you if you
looked at
any other isa you would see very similar
things
but two things here as you as i
mentioned already you don't see
a program counter here so this is not
exposed to the in the programmer model
uh and that's why
we uh we do an
indirect way right so we we still want
to
get code execution but we don't we can't
really control pc
at least as i mentioned that's uh that's
our understanding at the beginning
so what we wanted to do was we wanted to
indirectly
change the program counter that we could
do
um like for example when uh
when a function is exiting
then it has to go back to the called
function
right that which is the color and
uh the the
the address at which it should go back
to is typically stored in this
written address register and we want we
could
change this register and
start executing our payload instead of
the previous function
so that's one target we wanted to uh
have and the second one is stack pointer
so
again here uh you have uh
when when there are nested function
calls or the local data
you have all of them allocated on the
stack
if you can change the
register where the where you know the
top of the stack is located we can
redirect the program execution change
the data
and that all could lead to um
getting code execution on the device
that's about registers let's look at
some of
the details about instructions provided
so as you can see there are uh six
different
instruction formats right um
so the the each
uh instruction will be uh coded using 32
bits
um and instruction is a combination
of what is the operation that it needs
to perform
what is the source register and what is
the destination register
so as you can see
[Music]
different instructions have different
way of
[Music]
presenting that information but
overall the
what is the instruction can be decoded
from
three different uh parameters here func
seven font three and opcode
okay so these three combined will tell
you what
exactly it needs to execute and then
rs1 and rs2 are source registers
and rd is the destination register
so based on the instruction type
some of them might be present some of
them not but you at least have
one op code one source register
and one destination register right
uh yeah sorry about one op code and
either one
source at one destination register
okay so
if you go a bit more into detail this is
how
different instructions look you have the
opcode here
and then other parameters that i just
described
but in particular what we are interested
in is
load operations i explain why
a bit later but let's say uh the
load word instruction here so there is
an
awkward here
this i believe is from three
so these two combined will tell that it
is a load word
operation and then uh you have rs1
which is a source register and this is
immediate value which
means where from from rs1
you add what is there in the immediate
to
go to that particular uh location
and rd is going to be the destination
register
so basically what it does is it loads
from the address that's specified by rs1
and immediate
to register rd
so it's just basically loading a word
from the memory
why are we interested in load operations
because
firstly they are operating on uh
attacker control data right so you
uh we as an attacker can specify
what is being loaded even if you
remember the first example that i was
mentioning the image
which is being authenticated is a
collection of data that we are providing
to the device
so that it can uh authenticate
the data that we are providing so
we have control over what uh
what goes in here and
uh typically they are executed multiple
times
right so basically loading from memory
uh uh external memory to for example
internal memory there will be a bunch of
load operations loads and stores
so that means these are executed
uh a number of times during the copy
of course there are other ways for
example if you use dma this is
different but in most of the
cases uh earlier during the your
for example secured flow you you may
not use dma you just do a simple copy
um and most importantly
they are not protected
especially against fault injection
because yeah i mean
you don't trust the data right you in
any way you are going to authenticate
and
do a proper authentication before you
execute it so
you don't really uh have to add any
protection and i mean that's the normal
um
thinking of the designers
and um yeah as i also mentioned this
the use case so this secure boot
in case of secure boot you you uh load
the data
from an external flash for example into
internal ram and this involves a lot of
uh loads
in stores uh
yeah so that is why we we are interested
in
uh injecting fault into
load operations and finally
we we say that we are targeting a lw
which is load word
but um you can do the same attack
on other kinds of loads as well so
there is nothing stopping uh us from
attacking other load operations
okay now
how we actually do this right
let's let's go back and see uh i
mentioned two registers
right the link register and the stack
pointer register
so the idea here is that
we change the target register in an
operation
in a load operation from something which
is
normally used by the program to
uh our interest
register which is ra here so
if you see if you take any disassembly
of
a simple mem copy operation you would
see a bunch of loads
happening from the memory
into the register so this is a temp
register p0
and this is actually loading
uh from the memory address
a t stored in t4 into
t0 right so this is simple load now the
idea is that
we want to change this t0 to ra
so how can we do that so if you look at
here on the right you see how this
particular instruction
is encoded in binary right so
this is this 32-bit instruction refers
to
this one now if we just change
this particular one
here to 0 then this instruction will
completely change
so instead of the
data being loaded into t0 it will be
loaded into rna
and now imagine if at this location
we store our payload address
right then because of our fault
the ra will have
our payload address instead of the
previous
functions written address now
if you do that what happens when the
current
operation which is in this case mem copy
is returning from the copy operation
it will start executing what is there in
ra
which as we have uh
loaded with our value then the device
starts executing our code
so that's the uh that's the way how we
take control
um yeah so another example let's say
instead of t0 that's t2
then uh this is the uh this is how
the binary looks like and
here instead of a
one bit modification we need to do
we need to modify two bits using fault
injection
then we get the same result again
okay so that's that's what uh we want to
achieve
so we just we discussed what is fault
how to induce faults uh what is risk
fire say
what are the registers what are the
instructions and then finally we decide
we discussed how uh
how we can induce false so that the what
what we want to do for example rea
corruption can be achieved and similarly
we can also do
uh with stack pointer as well
now finally what we
we have seen all the theory now we want
to see
how to perform this attack and to
before we describe the uh actual attack
itself
the target so this is as you can see
um the microcontroller from sci-fi
it's based on risk five uh and
you specifically used a high five review
development board um
and then uh yeah it has the
uh risk five uh basin teacher
instruction set
implemented and uh it can run
quite a reasonable speed with 320 plus
megahertz
for for inducing volt hfi and
specifically
because this is what we did
we we need to look at three different
parameters
right the first one is
the glitch so
here is the place where you have
your trigger let's say this let's go
back to the previous example this is
where let
your uh if comparison is happening
but you don't know where exactly this if
is happening in your program right like
it's not uh it's not straightforward to
know where exactly it is
because of several reasons now
you want to have a
proper point in the program
where you know okay this is where
uh i know uh in the program where
exactly i am
right so this is the place this could be
a uart output this could be a c
flash read you know this happens all the
time
at the very precise moment so from here
you need to go to the actual if check
and this is what we call the glitch
delay
so this glitch delay is from the
relayable trigger
to the actual operation of interest
and then you need to change the old days
right
you need to take it to uh
take it away from its operating voltage
either by reducing or increasing
typically we go below because
that is safer and finally
how long you want to induce this click
so how long you want to
keep the voltage to that level
so these three are important parameters
sometimes we you may also have to uh not
sometimes but most of the times you need
to uh
provide your own uh old power supply
so that you can control it and
some sometimes you may have to remove
the capacitor so that your
glitch is a lot more effective
so this is a typical setup looks like
we have the glitch generator to generate
the
voltage glitches and
glitch amplifier which amplifies the
given uh voltage glitch which will be
provided to the chip or the target
in this experiment
and then uh from the target
you have a trigger signal remember uh
the trigger signal is something that
comes here
and then uh you need to communicate with
yeah with the generator and the target
using the pc and then yeah sometimes it
may also be
good to have a way to reset the device
directly
uh during fault injection
so this is how it looks like
uh you can see the spider which is a
glitch generator
glitch amplifier and then the bunch of
pins here which can be connected to
control either the triggers or resets
directly by ourselves
yeah and then we have a program to
control uh all the
[Music]
setup how to when to inject glitches how
to inject glasses
glitches and when to get the data
and then the parameters that we need to
give
and finally once we have the data how to
interpret it
so let's take a simple example here uh
this is uh before we do the actual test
we want to know
uh the parameters that i just described
how they look like
uh what are the ideal parameters so to
do that we do a simple test like
um doing uh 10 000 times a simple add
operation
and see if we get output
proper or not and during this ad
operations we just
glitch
and then you see here the outputs
from the uh function if the output is 10
000 as expected then it will be marked
as green here
uh if the device
resets or doesn't uh respond back
because of our glitch
or fault uh because we mark it with
yellow and
reds or something that are interesting
because
they they provide uh an
unexpected output for example instead of
10 000 it
sends back 99999
or yeah something like that so the reds
are our interesting
uh uh results
and specifically here uh
we are interested around this region
because here we see a lot of
rats and uh for the actual experiment
which involves corrupting our
ra rsp we use this area
so yeah this is how
we do characterization now uh i will
give it to news to present the actual
experimental results for
uh ra or xp
thank you yeah i think you can hear me
now
yes
and i think you can see it now
all right uh yeah one thing to note here
is that if you are attacking a real
device
or you would try to do something actual
like some actual attack you would
stay a bit longer in this phase and try
to optimize where you get these
successful results
but because they're they are so we're so
abundant in this
particular cpu and we want to generate
these nice pictures for
our own experiments as well
we picked the area where we covered both
successful and unsuccessful
faults
so once we had this we had our
uh yeah our settings for our fault
injection campaign
so then the second thing we needed was a
experimental setup in terms of software
which we can use to show
that the attack we proposed is actually
possible
so for that we used a
yeah we used a small software that's
very similar to what i show you here on
the screen
so there is a test function which is the
entry point for the
for the experiment we wait to receive a
command from outside to actually start
the experiment
and then we have a sort of mem copy
but slightly modified so that it works
for our setup
so what we do is we put some local
memory address in
s7 so that would be our pointer in a
real mem copy to the
uh to the source
of the memcope and then we set up
we load the address of the source of the
memcop into another register
and we store that in this previously
used memory address
and we need to do it like this because
in a real memcopy
you you also have this
method where you dereference a pointer
and that's what you see here in this
load word operation
so here you dereference the address of
s7 which is this local memory address
which contains our payload destination
and since we are doing an experiment
here we put everything just in our local
memory already so in the real world
this payload would be somewhere in your
external
slash for example but here we just put
it alongside it in memory and what the
payload does
is it does two things it puts the
current return address into temporary
register one
and a magic value and temporary register
too
and this information helps us identify
if our
experiment succeeded in executing this
payload
because if
in a normal flow or there are no faults
we start executing a test function
we receive a command we receive the
command to actually start the mem copy
we do the mem copy and then
we reach this return function and what
the return function does is it sets the
program counter to the current return
address value
if there was nothing weird going on the
return address contains the
dislocation where i mean this location
the next instruction after our jump
and then it just keeps loop forever
now with our if we take our fault and
our fault is successful in changing this
temporary register into the return
address
then after we call the return function
the program counter is set to
that value in the return address which
is our payload destination
so if we and then after it's it's not
shown here but after each attempt we did
all the registers on the register values
and if this t2 register contains the
magic value
that we put here in our payload
destination then we know that our attack
succeeded
yeah here i just showed one instruction
but in reality there will be
many instructions in one loop iteration
if you would compile a actual mem copy
it would stick to those temporary
registers there are
six or seven or eight of them
but since we are doing experiments here
we also try to see what happens if we
just use all the registers
and our expectation was that there is a
higher success rate if you use all the
registers
as you cover more of those temporary
encodings
and
yeah how this would look more or less in
memory is that
on the one hand you would have this code
that you trust which is executing the
mem copy
and it will copy into memory this
entrusted code
into interested data which first
contains the payload and then
the address of that payload many many
times
so that every time you copy this address
of the payload is a potential
successful a successful fault could
happen
and we need that level of indirection
like ravine said because we
are not loading this ad address into the
program counter directly
but we are dereferencing it into a
another register
um so in summary we
for so far since we're doing experiments
with a
target we completely control we can
cheat a little bit by using a gpio bit
to trigger a default
to have a very constant moment in time
uh
in a real world scenario you might not
have this so then you might have to rely
on using usb activity or uart activity
or if nothing is there you might have to
take some kind of side channel analysis
probe like
to measure current or to measure em
fields to get a
reliable point to trigger your fault
uh we considered our experiment
successful if we
observe this magic value in d2
and we did two rounds of experiments one
where we use all the
almost all of the registers that are
available to us
in our mem copy and another one where we
only use the temporary registers
and what we found is that both gave us
successful faults
yeah this is a picture that the preview
showed you also during the
characterization
step so there's the green which had no
effect
and then you can see that there is this
curve of yellow where
stuff started happening and if you are
not colorblind you can see there are
some
red dots in here as well those were the
successful folds
yeah this is the numbers so you see the
amount of attempts we did
and a very small percentage of them
succeeded
note that this is a very small one of
the reasons this is the smallest
percentage is because we had a
wide range of parameters we tested if
you were to zoom in
into a region or a
configuration of parameters where you
observe more red
than others for example here you see
none this would
increase your success rate which is
something you would do
in a real attack but since we're just
doing experiments here
we stick to those and also it allowed us
to better compare these different
scenarios
uh yeah what we see here is that when we
only use the temporary registers the
success phase
success rate drops by half
or even more almost by a factor of 10
and then in this last column i i gave
you an indication of
the time until we had our first
successful glitch
and this is of course a number with very
high variance because
yeah since you had it's a statistical
exercise so you might get lucky you
might not get lucky
but yeah you can see this big order of
difference between the two
now i will try to
one last thing i would like to share
with you is that
we had we observed something interesting
here
because if you if you recall what i
showed you before
the payload what it does is it sets a
temporary district to the current return
address value
and another one to the magic value
but one thing we also observed is that
we ended up in our payload
so we got this magic value but the test
function was the return
well not actually the test function but
this gym to test function was
the value in the return address and this
suggests that we somehow
managed to reach our payload without
hitting
a copy instructions situated the address
gets loaded into ra
and yeah if we split those out from the
successful results you can see that
in both cases it's more or less a 50 50
division between
reaching our payload through the return
address and also
the other half was re able to reach
payload without changing the return
address
now there are some theories on what
happened here
perhaps we you we changed the load word
into the
jumper link register instruction
which takes a value in a register and
jumps to it
so you yeah that's you don't control
pc directly but it's almost directly
because you
change the pc to a value in a register
that you specify
however another thing this instruction
does is it sets
a second register argument to the
basically the return address program
counter plus 4 but it doesn't have to be
the return address register
however when we looked at the other
registers we did not observe this value
so
it could happen but it's not likely
another thing that could have happened
is that we are
executing our load words in a loop
and this loop goes back to the beginning
of the loop using a branch instruction
and this branch instruction takes an
offset and perhaps its offset was
changed
again this could could have happened but
it's also unlikely because it would
require very specific bit flips to get
the exact offset required
and then another uh possible explanation
is that
even though we cannot directly load
values into pro
into the program counter using the
available instructions
if you think about the hardware in the
end the cpu will have one big
multiplexer to select which register to
use
for a value that's somewhere else in the
in the cpu
and even though it's not exposed this
multiplexer will
also be able to reach the program
counter register
because it needs to update the program
counter
so although it's not exposed as an
instruction there is still a data path
from whatever value you have in your cpu
for the current operation to the program
counter
and what we suspect and if you would
look at
open source implementations of the
risc-5 architecture
you can actually see that this data path
exists
so this is our like most what we
think is the most probable hypothesis
about how we are able to reach our
payloads without
going through the return address
interaction that we expected to be
necessary when we started these
experiments
so we are running a bit out of time so
i'm gonna just
fly through this second set of
experiments
just in a in a brief summary we also did
the same experiment with trying
we try to target the stack pointer
one downside of using return address as
a target is that
if you are not in a leave function so
memcop usually is a leave function which
means it doesn't call other functions
so it does not overwrite the return
address but if memcopy would call
more functions then the return address
value would be updated
to the return address of that
of that calling function and that would
negate your attack
however if you do it through a stack
pointer
then you would need another level of
interaction because you have to go
not only through the return address but
through the return that is stored on the
stack
but this is more powerful because you
are not
restricted to those leave functions and
then it's basically
a classical stack overflow attack you
know from software exploitation
that we just triggered it not through a
stack buffer overflow but
through fault injection yeah
we also succeeded in this if you compare
those percentages they are lower and one
number that really stands out
is eight minutes here because
here we needed 22 minutes to reach a
successful
fault here we needed nine hours
and here we needed only eight minutes
but even though this percentage is super
low
and yeah this is comes back to this
variance i told you about
before for about this number we just
like we just got lucky here
which i mean that's one of the sexy
things about fault injection you can
always just get lucky
yeah so quick words about again why this
is
such a cool thing to do our typical use
case is that we like to bypass secure
boots
and this is a really cool way of doing
that
because you uh do it before
even reaching any authentication or what
whatsoever you are like you're right in
the middle
um
yeah you like you don't even have to
think about the authentication you just
jump directly to whatever you are
copying into your
device and another thing
is privileged escalation so most cpus
have
some kind of distinction between the
privileged and non-privileged mode
in our address 5 we call it it's called
user mode and machine mode
so you can imagine that if you are
if your cpu is in machine mode and you
manage to make it execute codes that you
control then you suddenly control the
machine
mode or if you think about res and these
if you manage to get the ide to execute
your
re code then suddenly you have control
over the team
yeah some quick conclusions uh
we explained to you what is false
injection we explored various options
use this to control the program counter
we showed that the
two cases we thought would be successful
before we're actually successful
i've also got this unexpected result
where
we directly control the program counter
even though
the program counter register is not
directly accessible to the instruction
set architecture uh yeah some future
work ideas
by the way if you're interested in this
we are also always looking for more
interns so if you're interested in
researching this kind of stuff please
get in touch with us
for example trying to do this with your
gym for branch instructions
and yeah we did not really talk about
countermeasures against this kind of
attack
or how you you could protect this but uh
yeah once you protect it how could you
circumvent those protection is also
interesting to look at
so i tried to rush to the end here so we
might still have some time for questions
i'm not sure
it's already 8 o'clock here on my screen
so
i think we even ate into your break
uh thank you so much niels and praveen
uh
there was one question asked uh
by upper uh is there an alternate way to
where is that uh
let's say i'm doing it on actual device
is there any other way
from apart from side channel attack in
order to extract the instructions where
i want to inject the fall and praveen
has already answered it
that there's no other way uh so yeah
thank you so much niels and praveen for
this amazing presentation
friends this presentation is recorded
and they will be uploaded on our nalcon
youtube channel
so you could watch them after we do the
minor edits of audio and video quality
uh yeah thank you guys so much
my pleasure thank you for having us all
right
[Music]