[Music]
so
two of our panelists uh couldn't make it
but we have uh
suhaas and akshith uh joining us akshat
is the
found founder of uh saiware and suhas is
senior vp at ajah cyber security
burgess uh is also joining us for this
interesting panel from reactive to
proactive
operationalizing your threat intel uh so
yeah over to you akshat to moderate the
panel and ask some challenging questions
uh this time to burgess who's on the
other side as well
correct hey thanks a lot uh anthrax for
uh
giving us this opportunity for hosting
this panel and uh thanks burgess for uh
helping us at the last minute so i'll be
putting you on spot as they see so as
well as a big for both
anything for afraid anything for a
friend thank you thank you
and thanks a lot suhas for being with us
for uh this panel
so uh i think i'll start with uh
suhas first and then by this i'll move
on to you so
today we are going to discuss about
threat intel in terms of proactivity in
terms of reactive
in terms of how do we
operationalize the threat intel which
has become a commodity in
recent times spatially post-covered if
we see
things are like moving whether it's
solar events whether exchange attack
whether it's
hundreds of things let's not go in each
one of them but intel has become a
commodity
now and it's becoming a problem for each
of the companies
to uh utilize it operationalize it and
make use of it so
so as based on your experience like you
have been in different hats in last few
years
you have seen a wide spectrum of things
we have seen iot space we have seen
multiple space
so wanted to know your thought process
on uh
how can we make the overall intel
journey proactive
so thanks sasha uh hybrids so one
uh important aspect when we are talking
with
multiple cios and csos it is coming up
you need to move from saw to cdc this is
one big trend we are seeing
so if you say three four years back
everybody was talking like say i need to
monitor
all my blocks i need to integrate all my
infrastructure components applications
whatever is there in my ecosystem i need
to monitor
and after that people will monitor alert
and
i will respond on that now scenario is
very different
so most of customers are asking about
offensive security
so i don't have time to wait
till the attack happens i need to have
some intelligence beforehand
and i need to have offensive security
team members in my team
so initially if you see combination was
like say some stock analyst or sock
managers
we used to deploy in song now scenarios
are changing i need to a combination of
offensive security guys
then sim architect as well as si manuel
space
so that paradigm has been changed
significantly
that is the one trend which we are
saying soft to
cdc cyber difference centers that is
what we are seeing
at most of the places second this is
like
devices perspective everything is
connected now and said
from your health care devices from your
say ot device says i want to devices
everything is getting changed
a lot of data is getting generated so
last week we were working with one of
the large connected devices company
so their per unit transactions or alerts
with 2.7 billion
that is a huge number and when we were
analyzing that part so
most of the attacks were in different
shields so
when we are talking about the devices
space attacks on reverse engineering
attacks on devices
they covered everything now getting
everything at one place
and capturing intelligence that is
important aspect and that's why
we are more keen on people are adopting
threat intelligence
so whenever we are talking or you know
gartner or
or when they are putting up what are the
major things in offensive security
threat intelligence threat hunting and
policing these are the
which together in that space third
intelligence is the major thing which
plays lot of
uh bigger bigger roles to detect and
alert systems
in beforehand something goes wrong a big
way
okay perfect thanks thanks i think
that's a good
uh insights which you shared like the
stock versus cdc how that stock versus
cdc concept is moving
and how we as a industry has to align uh
as the
industry is moving towards it uh let me
jump to
uh mr burgess uh sir so you have been
on the other side of the table like uh
as a cso of large telecom then
uh being in big four you get to see
different industries different sector
various things which are happening
how do you think like uh anyone today
and i'm covering everything here not
only a cso not only a company
but me being a security analyst a sock
l1 because i want to
hear it from their angle that what what
they should be doing
to start kind of
understanding this intel world how they
start
moving towards proactive part of the
entire
security story entire predictive part of
the security story so if you can share
some
lights or vision on how me starting when
i'm starting my career as a stock l1
analyst
in any industry any sector how do i
adopt
these things and how do i kind of become
master of it
thank you akshat always happy to
contribute like in any warfare it's
based on deception
and intelligence right whether it's
physical warfare or cyber warfare
and timely intelligence makes a big
difference
uh to you being able to either thought
yourself from the enemy attack or being
a victim
uh take an example as you mentioned
rightly daily there's some amount of
some yesterday microsoft in a new patch
or solarwinds happened
and some attacks happen from the this
sector
i think it's all about the bent of mind
you know if i'm an l1 analyst and i will
only
do okay something came and do my job and
then that's it
but if i have a curious mind oh that's
attacks happening how can that affect to
me what are the iocs can i know is my
company secured you know what is the apd
number can i
it's that inquisitive that attackers
mentality
you cannot be a good defense guy if you
don't know how to sense an attack and do
an attacking yourself
and i think it's a state of mentality
often of an l1 guy he could be in the
blue team
but if he does not think like an
attacker the
football parents the attacker will run
rings around him and sort of you know do
the goal
so from that perspective clearly the
bend of mind
uh the attack mentality is very
important for
l1 analysts to think
how will he ensure that the intelligence
is timely used for his perspective
that's my point of view
perfect perfect i think there was an
echo in between somewhere
uh so swaz let me jump to you and ask uh
one more uh story around how do you feel
like uh
the cross sector intel is is it getting
really
operationalized and because you interact
with
so many sectors so do you think
there's a role of cross-sector
helping each other benefiting each other
bfsi working only with bfs io bank
working only with bank not even with f
and s and i
so do you think that somewhere that
cross-sector
harmony in this entire world has to come
together
on the proactive part of defense system
so that's not even limited to intel
but the proactive part of the entire
defensing system or overall defensing
part of it
like all of us have to come together to
fight the bad actors
so and they're working together as a
group so anything you see as a trend
anything you see
that we should be doing or things are
moving towards that
yeah so uh there are a couple of
examples that simply happen so one part
is like say
health care industry so we are saying so
even today morning's news is about
many countries targeted on vaccine
manufacturers that is the one case
second case is like
similar type of attacks has been
happened in last week on airlines
and few attacks has happened on ot part
so you might have
seen a large article day before
yesterday where
a particular state has been targeting uh
indian
uh great power uh plants and control
systems
so these are the three classic examples
so if you say
almost three are coming in critical
infrastructures national critical
infrastructure and
it has huge impact on human lives
and their day-to-day work part so if you
say
attack pattern so everything is up for
health care all the critical
infrastructure ics ot
that is there that part is common
although industry is different
similar stuff is for the power and grid
their control systems are comes under in
ics part
and third piece is the airlines also lot
of sensor technology they are using
and complete aviation power control
systems
that also has been targeted in single
industry now attack vector
threat intelligence across all the three
part sign prediction part
so now there is another trend which we
are seeing cyber prediction
so with laptop uh big data at the back
end and analytics
and using all these threat intelligence
for or across the industry
that is getting on common patterns and
it is helping
another example is like for the citizen
cyber prediction for cyber time space
so there is also lot of things which are
coming up as part of like say human
behavioral patterns
people are using social media those
parts are also com
some parts coming into other sectors so
sector-wise scenarios might be different
use cases might be different but attack
patterns or intelligence patterns are
similar and interlinked sometimes so ics
and ot is the classic examples
which i would recommend perfect perfect
um i'd like to add there it is clearly
collaboration
you know it doesn't have to be matter of
bang non-bank
uh collaboration between the cso company
which i think is really there now
uh one thread comes in a few seconds
cesars are all over the place iocs are
shared
attacks so i think that is clearly their
informal channel of collaboration is
really active some of you will be in our
whatsapp groups
uh the signal groups that really sector
works and
one person asks for help and the enough
of five guys to
sort of give the right information which
was not there five years ago
uh that so that i think in the indian
sector i'm sure some other places
uh the collaboration between csos is
just fantastic the amount of whatsapp
groups the amount of
intel uh i think that's really helped
propagate
right timely until the right place
irrespective of
official channels of communication yes
and i think i think i can
i eco you and uh
we see this trend as you said across
like
not only in india even in middle east uh
where
we talk to various csos and various
whatsapp groups literally even ioc
shared even in arabics
and even in us and the cross sector is
need of the hour
and cross sector is happening and will
continue happening and
i think somewhere regulators will also
start playing that role
the moment they start uh importance of
that
so it may become or will become
eventually where regulators are also
uh helping each and every one in sharing
that on a lighter note actually very
often i get your thread intel's from
other people before you send it to me
so it means it's working your company is
doing a great job
thank you so uh but just let me come to
you and uh
let me switch the gear a little bit from
this side to the cloud part of it
so uh there is a buzz around cloud we
are saying like
traditionally people say that india as a
country runs four or five
years behind in adoption of the new
technology whether it's 2g 3g 4g 5g or
even clouded option
on the cloud adoption eventually has to
happen
right in steps as a slow
or faster pace depends on which sector
you belong to how compliant it is
how regulated it is for from a cs1 from
a big four consulting point of view
what what kind of risk you see in the
cloud movement and how
the overall intel and proactive approach
can help reducing or mitigating those
risk
which people have as a fear oh no no no
i should not be moving to cloud
i'll next i get attacked because they
feel cloud is s3
and s3 is the biggest vulnerable
stuff in cloud so what's your experience
there and how do you think the proactive
approach can help mitigating
or making that fear go away for moving
to cloud for many of the indian
organization including bfsi or non-bfsr
so clearly cloud is more than s3 as you
mentioned and clearly cloud is imminent
uh you also write that many people have
hurried journey to the cloud rightfully
so because covet came in and
you didn't have the people so one thing
the cloud clearly
rules over everybody else is the speed
the the part of elasticity
which it can happen it just needs a
thoughtful process to migrate the cloud
if you have a cloud first strategy is
that really working
have you thought through cloud is
somebody it's a data center right
have you done that very well if you have
that thought process
and you have the right security checks
and balances of getting to the cloud
and if you have either a dual cloud
approach a hybrid cloud approach or
all there on the cloud and production on
whatever if you have
thought through that well cloud journey
could be a much more
certifying uh peaceful
uh helpful journey if on the other hand
you have not done that probably in just
a ad hoc reaction
or someone said so someone read so
someone said is cheaper it does not have
to be cheaper
it may become much more prudent in the
long run so i think a careful thought
through process
of spending the right introspection
saying why cloud
how cloud when cloud can make all the
difference but yeah you're right cloud
is imminent
for the future it just depends how well
you get there
correct correct so here uh actually two
are double on
this point so another trend which we are
seeing a lot of adoption for cloud
native assignments or capabilities
so there are about major eight to twelve
uh players
those are providing these services and
initially when we were talking say
five years back so it was like there
were two three on premise assigned place
where there
so now people are changing so largely
for the
sme bank or organization side so they
are adopting for this cloud native
assignment so so that is one good thing
which we are seeing in india or apac
region so from the cloud assignment
second piece is like if like what you
said
if we do proper strategy on cloud
security fundamental part is like you
need to have cloud native security
that needs to connect first whenever you
are taking any cloud setup or you are
hosting whether it is large organization
or
it is a small one instance you need to
have those things right
rightly set in the foundation itself
native security controls
your all the governance compliance space
and third one is like
whatever you are doing a regulatory
driven part should be
mandatory made in particular region
maybe in india maybe in middle east or
maybe u.s so these three things
are acquired necessary for cloud
adoption and
securing its entire end-to-end
ecosystem has been hosted in proper
environment that is needed
perfect perfect and let me stick with
you second inhibition
and this going forward is probably the
only other inhibition of
going in the bad is the ability of
trained manpower
you know most people uh in all phases of
life
cloud is a new thing so while you can
talk cloud cloud but actually going to
the natives of
securing the cloud quantifying the cloud
and configuring on the cloud
is a big uh sort of challenge if you
don't have the right people and support
to get there
right we'll see that as a fear do you
still see
that as a barrier do you still see that
as a big no
no no i will not move sorry not for next
five years not for next two years
people are moving but it is slow see
so what is happening uh some places
people are doing pilot but
what they are just checking whether
in the flow or as part of digital
transformation journey they are trying
for the few pilots
but getting right people on ground to do
all the security because pure insurance
is like
what budget said if you are not setting
it with properly native security
controls no right talent
now majorly hard two or three cloud
players are
playing transformation journalists and
there is a lack of
skill the manpower people are there from
the infrastructure point
whatever work they have done they are
doing posting but doing all the detail
cloud foundation security
all your advanced cloud native control
security so that part
somehow we need to be skilled we started
that journey in india specifically
hardly you will get say 100 guys who has
done this native and advanced security
controls implementation properly
so that we need to create and support
this entire transformations
sure uh but if you want to add something
i think you'll be unmuted
i just thought yeah thanks for your
smart idea uh and also could be
a question we ask ourselves what are we
doing to empower the cloud journey
how many guys are we training what
session are we being on awareness
uh to ensuring don't worry you know you
have the right hand holding the fear of
unknown always slows down progress right
because you don't know what's there
but the questions i would ask myself and
we should all ask is
what are we doing to allay the fear of
the unknown
right exactly
so but let me state to you
another thing which i wanted to check is
uh post covet like the moment all of us
went into lockdown exactly i think for
most of us last travel was this nalcon
goa
if i remember correctly and i think
since then we were not traveling but we
stick to our home and everything so
suddenly everything become
work from home right and many of the
organizations in india especially banks
and all they did not even have laptop
with all the employees
so where i'm taking my question is
towards endpoint security
because at the end of the day my laptop
my device my phone where
i started working to work for my company
for my office applications for my
work applications which probably none of
the organizations or many of the css did
not even get
proper time to implement it because if
covert was not there
they would have done this kind of
exercise in two years but kovid made
them do this
transition in two months probably with
minimal disruptions
so where do you feel that is there a
scope
that on the clouds endpoint security
what happened post covered a are we
taking enough care
b how can we be proactive by
operationalizing
the intel aspect of it to be more secure
in the overall endpoint security
where everything is kind of work from
home semi byod
multiple combinations which people never
thought that will be moving so fast in
you're right akshat what had to be done
had to be done right got done and
i think the true value of the see so uh
to a value of the captain
it comes in adversity the ship is
sailing nobody realizes but when the
ship's going down
so true value of the ciso and the cio
really came out during this time i did
16 sessions of moderating
fireside chats with about 800 people
during this whole time the learnings of
these were
said it has moved from a business
enabler to a value creator
okay if it was not there probably the
business guys would have been home and
unable to work
and uh yes security moved to the edge uh
people did ubers and olafs to send
workstations laptops
whatever was available rent tire bag
borrow people paid money to companies to
uh to employees who use their own home
laptops imagine taking some job of
saying i want for the office but my
company is paying me and i had all those
cases people saying but clearly now the
time take pause
reflect uh see the digital advances
happened
i we may have may not have gone the
cloud but has that journey been secure
and it's a good time to introspect
reflect and make corrections do before
somebody else forces you to make it
correct perfect first you want to add
anything on this aspect
yeah so to continue on that part uh most
of the organizations say
in india 90 percent more than 90 percent
we can say
adoption was good people started working
home
hardly uh any organization has not
enabled their biod
and remote work facilities so here
risk from the remote desktop or endpoint
or security edr specifically or you can
say xdrps
so that is much needed so we need to
look out at least once
in a quarter whether my xdr journey is
really secure
whether all my end points has been
really covered all the assets on the
cloud whatever i have posted
risk assessment on those points also has
been covered
so primary
risk assessment for your inter part and
x data coverage
that we need to measure correctly
it will give us lot of intelligence how
many loopholes are in my system
and what are the improvement plans i
need to consider
that is the important piece perfect i
think we have six more minutes
uh meanwhile are there any questions
from any of the audience
please just type in the chat uh
meanwhile i'm just moving on to one more
uh
input which i needed from your budget is
is
from the entire solarwinds story which
shook all of us because the kind of long
impact it had
and and reaching from there to oh
probably in turn had a weak password
right so um how we all of us
is there something proactively can we do
because where are we lacking is in the
actions
everyone knows that this is my bullet
list everyone knows this is my hygiene
list
but somehow that hygiene is not followed
up
how what all of us as a like
organizations as a company as a cso as a
captain as a cio as a
cto as a devsecops
devsecops head or even as a developer or
as a intern
because what happens i'll tell you the
real practical ground problem
everyone knows that one plus one equal
to two everyone knows this is my hygiene
everyone know that i am not supposed to
do this everyone knows i am not supposed
to
have this weak password everyone knows
that i am not supposed to give a ci cd
pipeline to an intern
what all do i do what all should i be
doing
proactively because my focus today is
proactive part of the things
that another solar one does not happen
so i'll i'll say
i'll start with the captain right you
ask what the captain i think it's the c
source job and responsibility to set out
the
priority for the company because if he
does not do that everybody else will do
what they want you know
in a sinking ship or a ship going
through a storm you've got to have clear
command control you cannot say ah baby
karo of baby karo
so the cso's a bid to give the clear
mandates with the torture from the ceo
saying
i will say these things debate fight but
once that order the command is given
everyone yours is not to question why
also just do and die as they say
so not die hopefully but come out of
this but that command has to be first
thought through by the ciso and cio
agreed with the ceo
and then once given what is really
priority because you cannot do
everything to everybody
but if it means you are in this industry
you secure if it's ot then secure the ot
line if you're in
uh devops and you secure the dev cycle
agile
but whatever you agree on i think you
first need to prioritize
there's so much things to do and
everything is important
it's clearly for the seesaw to mandate
and say what is really important during
this point of time for the next three
months
we call it vital essential desirable
what is whitetail
what is hygiene has to be done in the
next three months then
uh essential okay three to six months
and then desirable but what's vital
what's survival right now that priority
has to be said by the ceo cesonc
and the ceo and then taking it forward i
think that captain's direction during
these tough times is so very important
otherwise everyone will do what they
think is important i agree
agree really appreciate that those
thoughts there's a question which has
come
from in the chat in audience is in a
season opinion
on the digital transformation that
happened during covet times
are they satisfied that it was secure uh
i'll had a couple of points from couple
of uh
comments from my side and then and i let
suhas or burgess any one of them had
as buddhist already pointed out like
whatever happened had to happen they did
it in two months they did it in two
months
and i think combining the vital
essential desirable
they did it with the vital part of it
then i'm sure all the cso started moving
towards the essential part of it
and then they started moving towards the
desirable part of it
so uh over to use uh versus
any one of you want to add anything on
this question whether you
are satisfied that i am i'm secure
yeah so here one part definitely uh
they are satisfied by entire digital
transformations where
many years people couldn't do that that
happened in
a shorter time many initiatives has been
rolled out
on immediate basis but on the
satisfaction phase
it is very uh so very big
part i would say that organizations are
happy that their business has not been
impacted from the business side
from the security side unless and until
uh it was not detected
whether attack has been happened really
or not or it was compromised
until the time we can say it is secure
another point is like
unless and until we do throw a review
third party reviews or some audits
around whether entire ecosystem which
was unable to
for this remote work whether it is
secured that we need to do unless and
until we run such programs
then only we can ensure that 100 percent
work from home
has been enabled and this digital
transformation is successful
another piece is like say whenever we
are uh
so the second question from the odc part
so this part we have experienced
so badly in past because many customers
because of their
sensitivity or confidentiality part very
critical applications were hosted
in particular series or of odc part
it was not possible to do work from home
at
such scenarios many so for the most
european and u.s customers
50 60 percent customers allowed to do uh
remote work
but few critical components were asked
to do from uh orisa's only at that time
proper care from the uh infrastructure
side has been taken care
but that was very limited broadly
majority of large organizations has
enabled
uh remote work versus thank you i have a
slight different opinion
what had to be done had to be done got
that doesn't as you said it's more
important what you can do now
i think cesar should do a pat on the
back the very fact you survived the war
and pandemic was no less than a war
each of our companies uh as a ciso when
you are protecting them must have been
through money attacks
you survive that onslaught partly brutal
partly come out whichever way
it's more important what you can do now
to ensure your journey ahead is secure
you know if you may have been attacked
not attacked partially attacked control
victimized ransomware come on stronger
recovery whatever
more important is what you do now so as
to secure the journey forward and that i
think will
determine the test of time correct let
me ask last question by this to you and
then we'll conclude
uh this the recent grid scenario the
chinese attack on national grades
uh railways many more and many more of
this might have happened
uh i'm taking it to the concluding point
of like intel and proactiveness part
what me as a ceso if i was a ciso what
me as a captain of
ship anywhere uh
should be having any lessons from all of
this which keeps on coming or
highlighted to us
how still i keep on getting i give it
you give it everyone gives it
everyone is giving it what do i do how
do i still
become proactive and import understand
the importance of this
intel because if you see many of these
grids
were not they were saved because of the
inter by the way
because they received intel in time and
that's how these grids were saved
so how do we how do we all make
ourselves
understand the importance of
proactiveness and intel and our board
and everyone so firstly i think you
have some aspiration to become a cso
because you keep on saying i wish i want
to see so i think you like a legacy
thanks to your intel yes resource would
have survived that onslaught
uh it's a question of not
today i think every board also
understands the importance of cyber
largely thanks to media and
uh conferences like these and many
others it's just a question of how long
do you stay in a state of ready alert
you can't stay in a hyper state too long
otherwise that itself becomes a dull
state
it just means sensitizing your people to
the right intelligence at the right time
like i said
every warfare decide works on
intelligence and deception that's the
basics of any warfare
cyber is no difference how well you
deceive your enemy and how well you
are the right intel will determine
success or failure so
being on that state of paranoia working
on every intel
calmly but you know swiftly and acting
on it
protecting yourself the next thread
comes without
losing your state of alertness is the
survival sta
point from my perspective okay i'll just
take a question uh from the chat and
i'll probably try to answer it myself
before
unfliction anyone ping me that you are
done uh
so as mentioned that ciso now these days
use the current communication text such
as whatsapp to spread information about
threat mitigation
some i'm just summarizing like oh should
it be sharing in the
whatsapp group so i think here is my
take on this
let's let's divide this information in
two parts sensitive and insensitive
or public versus non-public so whatever
is public whatever i'm getting from the
public domain i should be sharing
on the whatsapp i should be helping
people to find the public information
which is scattered in 100 places
at one place no one knows that who all
could be there in these whatsapp groups
but let's come to the non-public part of
it or insensitive or
with sensitive information part of it
which i might be getting from my
regulators
which i might be getting from something
which only i should be private
that information we should not be
sharing on those whatsapp group
i don't know badges and swaz if you
agree with that point that
sensitive and non-sensitive information
in public versus non-public information
so us
see it has uh different
aspects when we are sharing such
information sometimes if it is only
informational
page then it is good uh but most of the
csos
i don't think they are sharing critical
client related information or
organization related information
but from the information say this is a
ioc or
this is a critical incident which we
observe recently and
uh that should be blocked at
organization level i think search type
of scenarios definitely we can share and
uh it helps to prevent
such type of attacks in future i think i
don't see any harm into that
but uh if somebody is by knowing
unknowingly if they are sharing some
information
related to our nationality classes then
can be
prevented but most of the places i have
never seen such type of information has
been passed through
i think most of us are that much natural
that we are not sharing
critically informed words tend to agree
sharing good
information which is public in nature or
channels to us to a faster reach and
timely action is important
yeah everything else is professional
they will not share beyond that your
position of maturity and respect that
chair
but sharing intelligence of common
attackers just like attackers share
information
uh sharing proactive defense information
amongst peers and colleagues who help
each other
i think is a plus point it actually
helps csos in the industry
[Music]
really really appreciate it uh and uh
thanks anthrax entire nalcon team
for hosting all of three of us for this
panel chat hopefully
uh it it gives some insights on some of
the mixed topics we covered here
uh anthrax over to you
thank you akshat for moderating this
panel and
uh suhas and purchase for sharing your
insights
just a kind request in your cso group
just add me
also i get some intel's as well
perfect do you also aspire to be a
seesaw just like actually
not really but i don't want to be the
same
all right thank you thanks a lot and
guys thank you everybody
all the very best for a great conference
thank you
you