[Music]
next
talk uh one of the most
technical uh and the most critical
infrastructure today
that most of the nations are trying to
protect is the telecom industry
and since we are rolling out the 5g
infrastructure for various nations
globally
innovation comes with its own challenges
and weaknesses
so let's find out more on the telecom
security
challenges for 5g network via the
founder
of matrix shell technologies
akip sayad akib over to you
thank you anthrax let me just share my
screen
okay guys can you see my screen guys yes
it's visible
okay so thank you anthrax for the
introduction
so i'll be talking about the security
challenges in 5g
okay as we we are moving towards the 5g
india is gearing up for the 5g
technology
there are certain challenges that we
need to look at when it comes to the
security part but first i'll tell you
about me and
i'm working in telcon security since
last eight years my first talk was in
nalcon
and i really appreciate that nalcon gave
me a good platform without any
without having any initial experience in
security i thank you see my thank you
anthony chandan and the rest of the
nilcon team so i am a gsma member i mean
my company is a gsm member so i am
actually contributing to the foreign
security group as well
i'm founder of metric shell doing that
we are doing the telecom security
research all the time
and yes we are hiring whenever we
require some more strength anyways
let's go ahead what i do for the telecom
operator
i do all the telecom audits when it
comes to any technology like 2g
3g 4g 5g as well as penetration testing
of the voiceover lte fixed ims or it
could be air interface
and we have we used to do some uh tech
testing for the telecom operator which
is manually now we've automated our ss7
diameter and gr explanation testing
we also do the telecom forensic for the
telecom network
let's leave that part now and let's get
into the 5g now
so what exactly is a 5g uh that
interests us is most of the time is
speed
we started with uh 2g speed then which
we had 2.5 2.75
then 3g then i had 4g now we have the 5g
so 5g is claiming to be going up to 20
mbps
speed which is 10 to 100x faster than
what we get in the 4g
okay we also have the low latency
network okay when i say talk about the
low latency means uh
i think uh technology people do
understand this point about the latency
but the 5g is claiming to give one
millisecond latency when it
reached to the core and goes back
returns back from the core
it also claims to give a up to 10 year
battery life for the low power iot
device
using like a narrowband iot or catim
devices
also the 5g can replace the traditional
wire broadband like uh i'm not saying
about the
the fiber broadband but i'm talking
about uh i'm talking about the wireless
broadband wherever there is
not less possibility or less
difficulties to get the fiber
laid out the mission critical
communication is also a good part of the
fire of 5g because we have 5g supporting
uh multiple
technologies like uh push to talk
instant post to talk services
or some some more there are no more
details into that we are not looking at
this
right now 5g also claims to be as 4g
claim for the v2x
vehicle to everything firefighter also
giving the immersive
entertainment like virtual reality
augmented reality
as there is a less latency and a higher
speed so what is the 5g and wi-fi ge
from security point of view 5g
establishes end-to-end trust
when it comes to authentication
integrity and confidentiality
you might say that these points are
already there in 4g but
why we need them in a 5g again so there
are some issues in the 4g that actually
gives out the initial information like
your mc when it when you're transmitting
or you're trying to connect to the
network after switching on your phone
so 5g also prevents that by doing the
encryption
and then only revealing the identity
after the authentication is verified by
the
telecom network which is the home
telecom network also
5g resume removes all the assumptions
when it comes to safety from product or
process means
uh in 2g and 3g and 4g we saw that okay
we are relying on the product or we are
relying on the certain process
to have a security okay but 5g removes
this part and 5g is contained
with the city of security i mean we can
say that 5g
is a like secured by design but still
there are some issues still exist
now mandatory encryption is there for
intro traffic or the internet traffic
what i mean by the inter traffic means
it between
into inter traffic and inter traffic
means whether all the interfaces in the
5g
are interested whether it is a core
communication whether it is
some other communications like you know
between the operators between the
uh operators inside the country yes they
have the monetary encryption for the
same
5g improves the confidentiality and the
integrity of data
as well as the there is a home control
authentication
now some of the issues which has come to
the 2g 3g and 4g
is the visiting network decides whether
the authentication is completed or not
this is improved
but this is a lack issue in the 2g 3g 4g
but in 5g the the home network decides
whether the authentication is completed
or not
also 5g has a integrated roaming
protection called security edge proxy
protection
this protection gives you gives the
full roaming security if it yes of
course if you implement it properly yes
now how 5g is better than 4g first thing
is that
encrypted user identity over there so
whenever
uh whenever there is a non encrypted
communication that is happening when you
switch off the cell phone
so those that's why you use as a soupy
it should be sushi not soupy not the
permanent identifier it should be sushi
so
it's a concealer concealer identifier
okay so also there is a home controlled
authentication
authentication check means the ue the
sorry the home network can check if the
particular cell phone who is requesting
the 5g service
is actually roaming there so 5g does the
sale it does verify like that
there a cpa scpp security edge bucket
cluster protection is like an edge
firewall
which uh legacy technology fails to
provide
there's a network exposure function that
act which is integrated into the 5g
uh fights uh 5g network that is
giving the third party api into the
third party api to the integration of
the third party app
what do you mean by that so let's take
an example if you are using ss7
or if you're using a diameter you need
to integrate this
all your services inside the specific
protocol
so if you want to have any external
function for
some banking application whether it is
based on the ussd whether it is based on
the location whether it is based on some
other stuff
so you have to integrate the entire
network or the entire stack of the
protocol inside the
operator's network and it becomes
difficult for the operator
to actually control it they can
implement the firewall they can
implement
some other thing but 5g exposes the
certain function which is required for
the third party application to function
yes there is the nef function is there
in the 5g now improved aka
authentication key agreement for the
protection of the initial nas messages
now as i said in previously like
whenever you switch on the cell phone
in legacy technology your nc goes over
the air unprotected
so whatever your plane takes imsi it
goes over the air directly
but 5g came up with something called the
supr sup
which is a private identity but when it
goes
over the air it is encrypted by the cell
phone
and then sent over the sent over the air
with encryption
and when when the when this reaches to
the core network when it reaches the
core network the core network
will then authenticate it if after the
authentication is completed
then only the so the private identifier
identity is exposed to the
amf that is mobility function but
one thing here is that the home network
always verify whether the authentication
is successful or not
5g also claims that they are going to
implement the 256
bit encryption for 256 bit encryption
and integrity
of the user data that is actually
proposed that is not yet
finalized so what are the 5g modes of
deployment
there is a nsa mode that is sa mode when
i speak about the nsa mode it is
non-standalone
it means 5g network has to rely on some
other network let's say 4g network only
to provide the 5g services means the
tower of the telecom network
that belongs to 5g another tower of the
telecom network that belongs to 4g
first phone will be latching on to the
4g network then the data traffic
data traffic of the fire will be
transfer sent to sent to the 5g tower
and it always relies on the 4g control
point there are multiple multiple
different modes as well in the nsa but
we are not discussing it i have those as
of now
there's a standalone which uses the 5g
cells and the 5g code for the signaling
and the data
so let's look at how exactly the nsa
looked like
if you can see here let me just uh take
a pointer there's a pointer yeah there
it is
so this is a nr like a in 5g i forgot to
mention that the 5g
has a new name that is 5g nr new radio
so if you see this this red color is a
5g tower
and this is the gray color it is an old
lte tower
and the gray color epc evolved packet
core is a
old epc of the 4g now if you see about
this thing
a dotted line is just a control plane
okay
and whenever you switch on your phone
you go to the lte network you go to
register over the epc
and then epc will be sending that okay
there is a 5g network in nsa mode
available in your area you should send
your data
to the 5g network so that we can you can
get the file services
now one of the operators in india
recently tested this and had about i
want i will
not name this because i don't want to
get into any conflicts so they tested
the whatever the mode they tested that
is the nsa deployment
so initially all the operators are going
with the nsa deployment because you know
uh epc that is a 4g core is already
there
and they don't want to again invest into
it
easily because 5gsa comes with another
cost
but still let's look at the how uh 5gsa
looks like so we have completely
different network here that we have 5g
core we have epc that they can
communicate in the between them just for
the
any handover or a downgrade downgrade
purpose also
they have the complete different led
network complete different new
new radio network and all the signaling
that is dotted line
and that uh complete line the single
line or straight line that is the
data which is go through go through the
core network and if there is a necessary
or necessity of the epc and the 5gc
communication or
in terms of data or signaling yes that
happens between the code directly
no need to involve the bts okay
okay so let's uh go to the high level
components of the 5g actually i wanted
to keep this talk
more on the technical but uh as people
are not much aware of the how the 5g
is what is what it is so i'm limiting
this to very high level components
so we have the radio access number
network which is called the new radio
we have the msc that is multi-access
edge computing
we have the 5g core that is the 5g core
handling all the traffic
we have the roaming that is sa roaming
there is non-sa roaming
now when you speak about the sa roaming
that is s8 sar sa network to sa network
roaming when there is nsa roaming there
is nsa to nsa
next thing security challenges in the 5g
let's start with the radio access
network
so increased bandwidth increases the
protocol complexity yes exactly the
point so this allows the room for the
implementation vulnerability as well as
the configuration velocity
if you see the previous technologies
that is uh 2g 3g and 4g
you must have seen the ss7 there is no
way to perform i have encryption there
is no way to perform the authentication
there is no way to perform the
check the integrity of the data or
confidentiality of the data
but when it comes to the 4g yes they
have implemented all these things
but this actually allows the
implementation one if you like the one
video
which we discovered after fuzzing so
those vulnerabilities are still there
and it is a good chance for the
researchers
to start with the fuzzing the radio
network whether it is a cell phone
or whether it is a tower yes that is a
good chance there
there is a signaling drag now what i
mean by signaling drag is see
to communicate with any network you need
to perform
initial signaling for that so whether it
is a 2g 3g 4g signaling
it has to be there when it comes to the
implementation of the file
nobody can go like say that okay from
today onwards i'm
only going to use the 5gsa network in
the country but
if he wants to if he wants to actually
give this functionality in the country
okay khalashi can give it no issue
but when the the subscriber of the 5g sa
goes to the other country he might get
the nsa he might get the
2g he might get a 3g so 2g 3g signaling
drag is still there that allows the
older vulnerabilities to
exist in the network there is a roaming
interconnect issues
roaming interconnect mandate and mno to
support the legacy protocol for the
roaming the same same part that is
actually dragging the signaling part
here
we have the zombie ue problem what i
mean by zombie ua is
let's take an example we are in the in
the area
in the air in the area that is actually
about the
mobile malware so just imagine a case
like somehow your phone or your from
either from your browser or
from the malicious app your browser or
phone sorry your phone was compromised
and if he is sending a dos attack
towards other subscriber or the network
imagine the issue that can cause
so we will look and look into that what
exactly the zombie uae can do it's
just a basic use case here we have the
edge computing now what do you mean by
edge computing is let's take example
we have let's say example we have mumbai
in mumbai we have a dock
that is a shipyard okay so there they
were there there is a huge
whose transport of the containers and
everything so 5g gives one advantage
for these people to have their own local
private 5g there
okay now just to have a local breakout
or the
faster breakout so 5g implements an mec
that is multi-access edge computing
so this this allows you to have the
local network and the faster
communication
so as we see the in the 5g we have
one point that is the function network
function virtualization so they are
using virtualization they are using some
other techniques okay it could be the
vmware base or
a container based so all the issues that
is applying to the
open source or the container security
threats that applies to it
as well as 5g is moving more towards the
it rather than the teletradition telecom
protocol
because first initially 2g was most of
the asn sn1
3g yes that was true but 4g when it
comes to signaling it moved little bit
from radius to diameter which is from
from traditional telecom telephony to
the to the
normal i t but now the 5g comes with the
http 2 protocol with the json interface
so there is a good chance for the web
application developer to get into it to
learn about it
also the configuration issue still
applies if the
weak configuration is there and more
interfaces and more open source code is
going to be there
unless there is a some uh test cases
test cases validation or the fuzzing is
there
there will be some issues that will be
applying let's take example we have the
kubernetes or we have the containers or
we have the locals
so if some issue applies to that yes it
is going to apply
to the same same instance which is using
that version of the
docker or or anything so it too has
defined the threat landscape for the 5g
so there are multiple parts of it like
you know
like illegal intercept dos attack slash
traffic
which is actually a toss then the
privacy breach
fake bts slicing or resource threat that
is actually coming into the nfv part
then we have the threats originating
from the internet someone who is trying
to attack
inside or the to the subscriber then
there is a security policy conflicts
so there are multiple threads that we
are those are there that it you had
defined
let's look at what are the key areas
that can cause the
security weakness in the 5g so if you
see about the 5g we have the cloud-based
architecture that can cause a problem
network function virtualization software
different driven operations then we have
the software defined network
we have the data security at the edge
and the ran
and the zombie ui let's look at them one
by one so cloud-based architecture
completely based on sharing the hardware
resource like let's take example you
have one
where you have multiple options either
you have the infrastructure as a service
or platform as a service
so the owner of the platform is going to
share the hardware resources between the
different different
uh different different users or
different containers or different
virtual machines
so if there is a hardware limitation or
if there is a hardware problem
that is going to cause your msc to
collapse also if the host is having some
vulnerability
that can cause a problem yes that is
going to affect the
internal internal network elements as
well
privilege escalation is a major issue
but if
that is the if the if we can prevent the
privilege escalation
that could be either on the specific
container or virtual machine or
any virtual instance we also have the
session flooding issue in that
the risk of the open source in the 5g
like i said earlier right if there is
anything that is
affecting the linux kernel it affects
everything that who is using that corner
same way if there is some issue in any
version of the docker the
that the the epc or the core core
network is using yes that is going to
affect them as well
so it could be a open source software it
could be open source library it could be
open so protocol stack
or it could be a custom protocol stack
as well so recently there was some
research that is done by the some
organization they were cleaning claiming
that the tcp stack was having a huge
issue of the buffer overflow that that
was causing the issue in the iot devices
so those issues if you're if the stack
is the vulnerable so anyone who's using
the start is going to be vulnerable
software do an approach approach our
operations okay so
everybody right now is mostly going on
like automated automation so and gate of
trust is properly
needed to implement the properly the
automation in that
sufficient auditing has to be there to
prevent any issue
in the in the automation part we have
the orchestration
we have the share control between the
system users that is going to cause the
problem
lack of the supports and updates and the
sql communication
now let's take an example we have one
virtual machine
and there is a host of the virtual
machine so if we are not updating and if
if let me give one example of the
telecom ecom in telecom
it is not like we got an update and we
installed it first
the lab is update is implemented in lab
it is tested thoroughly whether it is
affecting anything whether it is doing
anything
by the time we actually implement the
you know by the time we actually
implement the patch or the new update
it is going to take at least three to
four months minimum i'm talking about
also ai ml is still difficult to
implement in the
in the telecom because it's often black
box and it is learned and trained on the
database
ai based this decision will take time to
mature because
in telecom there are very uncertainty
because let's take example if you are
using
ai on certain parts or certain things
okay
so let's take example we are using ai on
the certain uh data set of
data set of the business application so
you have certain
criteria defined but if you talk about a
telecom
subscriber could do anything anything
means anything
he could browse it it could do it it
could be any any use case so it will
take much
so ai or ml based design will take time
to mature if you are implementing ai ml
in the using in the software
operations we have the nfv that is
network function virtualization
management and orchestration of the nfa
security could be an issue as of now
then the resource isolation and securing
the traffic now we have seen uh
as the people who are experienced with
the docker they will be able to easily
tell what what is that why there is a
need of virtual firewall ids or ips
because let's take example the
containers or the docker
they implement the secure they implement
their own
internal network okay so like a software
defined switch they implement
so if we need to do some port filtering
if we need to do some
some ideas implementation or ips
implementation
we have to be part of that particular
software
like a software firewall or it has to be
there
we also need to block the unused
unnecessary port that is the standard
practice actually
when it comes to software centric
security secure against the common
software vulnerabilities has to be there
and there has to be a
thoroughly testing like fuzzing has to
be there
now we need to do the nfv monitoring
that is uh
it could be software defined network or
virtual monitoring we also need to do
the virtual sockets monitoring that is
between open between the different
virtual machines
as well as the health monitoring
attestation of the hardware or the
software component
why we why it is needed because let's
take example i'll give one example there
is a buzz in the
in the deep web that is there is the ss7
module what this ss7 malware does is
it patches the kernel and after patching
the kernel it sits between the sctp
protocol
protocol pad protocol area and
it just monitors everything in between
and if necessary it modifies it
so there is a need of in maintaining the
integrity of the software component by
it could be a digital signature base or
it could be some other means as well but
digital signature based that is that is
necessary
that we have the we need to do the
software software define network
security why
because we need to maintain this
complete sdn controller in an isolated
environment
okay like uh i mean yes it is not
completely practical but we need to
implement those
excuses we need to implement the api or
protocol level security we need to
protect the route between the if it is a
virtual route or is it up there
if it's a physical route on it could be
on virtual interface or in the
physical interfaces as well
data security at the age network now we
uh
as we see in that you know we've seen
the example i gave the example of the
mumbai dockyard okay
so first thing is that if you are
implementing any edge computing then we
need a physical security we need a
necessary alarms implemented at that
that place we need a regular security
audit of that place
also there shouldn't be any credential
caching on the msc side
now edge for a computer framework for
the orchestration and the business logic
has to be audited
whenever necessary and it has to be done
on the on the regular basis
we have multiple issues as of now when
it comes to the radio
it could be jamming spoofing of the
network interception of the traffic or
redirection
now how this could be happening now
let's take example if you're jamming the
network how do it how do you identify
or if you're spoofing the network how do
we identify in the energy in the cell
phone there is a option called as a
measurement report actually this happens
in background like a neighboring cell
measurement report or you can monitor
the sudden drop in the signaling from
specific area
okay then you can investigate interface
there could be a check of the
downlink and uplink jamming by
identifying the parameters in the in the
network
or by by this uh by the in general b or
e not b itself if it is nsa mode
then we have to physically secure the
site from the physical inclusion
also there is there has to be a
validation if if someone
someone is moving the network how we can
do the cells let's take an example i'm
running xyz networks impersonating
pqr network okay i'm impersonating them
and the phones nearby are trying to
connect to me
so what initially uh the the frequently
the
network network or mno could do is they
can ask for the neighboring site
measurement from the ue and they can
identify which belongs to them which
doesn't belong to them
also there is a technically speaking
there is always a room for the spoofing
but still this is the minimum that can
be done also there has to be
implementation of the end-to-end
security between the ran and gore there
are multiple
uh halls here like mid hall front hall
back hall
those security has to be implemented
here now
coming to excuse me coming to zombie ue
infected
for phone causing doors okay you must
have seen the movie that is mummy the in
that that
immate says okay do they do that
same let's look at the one case to use
case one smartphone with the 5g kfig
connectivity generated
30 mbps of doors on a website imagine
what this thousand smartphone could do
it could generate a 30 mbps 30 gbps
and imagine a 1000 smartphone 10 000
smartphone generating a 300 gbps of
dos on the website now we've seen in
india we've seen one thing that
the internet penetration is big and it's
huge
when the jio came as a player and what
we are seeing like what we are seeing
right now is
anybody with a smartphone is going for
it could be a video doing the tick tock
or
tick-tock alternative youtube everybody
is behind it
for that purpose the main reason of the
youth
joining the tick tock and the joining
the videos is is a monetary gain so
there could be some uh as as this uh
monitor gains
expectation goes higher so what we can
expect
from them is we can expect them from is
there uh we can give the chance to the
this this opens a chance to though
actually this roster or who wants to
commit sunday
such a crime okay so that gives them uh
an opportunity to
you know send the phishing may have
means or send a spoofed application
or some uh like a application that can
promise promise the user that some money
so that can cause
uh opening there so we need to also
implement the ai base artificial
intelligence based traffic shaping
because you know it is a huge data
imagine even if we are even if in india
we are able to give one cell phone a
gbps speed
that is a huge speed for us for someone
to handle that
so we need to do ai based traffic
shaping for the for this uh for the gsm
for the
network that is going to be there so
requirement of testing in 5g
so i've defined there are multiple
interfaces we have 5gr interface
which could have the 5g handset wireless
5g test nodes could be there
so we need to do the air interface
assessment we have the mec
mobile edge computing platform sorry
multi-access edge computing platform we
need to do the testing of the msc and
the backhaul
then we have the core network we need to
do the complete coordinate of testing
now as we've seen that in the curve in
the 5g
we have the protocol called http 2 and
the json-based
apis so that opens up the web
application
developers or web application security
testers a good
area to go go and explore into it
one of my friends said that i know what
is the what is up with the
people who designed the 5g that they
want to bring in more i.t
companies rather than the telecom
companies so he was saying that there is
something happening in the background
okay let's leave that
i'm like let's secure it let's focus on
securing it now there is one more
remaining uh interface that is the
roaming testing you need to do the
continuous roaming testing to test your
5g or the
legacy technologies readiness for that
next we have what we can do in the air
interface testing there could be
configuration testing there could be
non-access station protocol testing
we can do a ddos simulation we can also
check the nfv or the container burst
when the actually nfv and container
burst is the orchestration failure
when assigning a task to the new
container or popping up and popping
pushing down the popping up and pushing
down the new container that
as required we need to do the g node b
testing
it could be configuration assessment
physical attacks on the hardware because
the 5g claiming to be the
huge uh number of gene would be is going
to be implemented
we need to do the rru and the open ram
testing as well like remote radio head
and
open run testing has to be there we need
to do the mec
backhaul threat testing when it comes to
mac platform audit it could be
platform as a service infrastructure as
a service
slicing validation traffic segregation
has to be there
when it comes to front hall mid hall and
black hole testing we need to do the
network architecture audit
configuration review traffic analysis
and the attack whenever you speak about
the traffic analysis we should include
operational environments user data and
the signaling as well
now there is one more nice part for the
web application developers or
verification testers
that the mec application exposes the
wave api
to the third party also uh when it comes
to nfv is nfp sorry msc and nfv
bus testing yes we need to do the data
simulation to test the what what can
what can go wrong in the first nfv part
we have to do the 5g core testing that
is analysis of the deployment
architecture
how do we also we need to do the
different slicing validation
we need to do the signaling protocol
assessment okay where
whether it is http 2 or json based
whether it is a pfcpf at a protocol or
whether it's a dos attack
we need to simulate as an internal
attacker it could be on a vm
virtual machine or a docker we need to
try for the privilege escalation we need
to try for the
uh some disrupt specific vulnerabilities
of course disrupt specific
vulnerabilities could be
uh disrespectful vulnerabilities like
you know those could be
like uh just like
mr specific vulnerabilities uh could be
like you know
uh there has to be found out of out of
the fuzzing
uh then we need to also do the ddos
stimulation from the core network
impersonation or the data interception
has to be there like pfcp is
vulnerable for the session modification
attacks
next thing is that uh roaming and
internet testing we need to do the ss7
testing
just to be actually ss7 doesn't actually
realize for the part of the
s7 and diameter actually doesn't rely
for the uh essay or an sa mode but the
thing is that
to be compatible with the legacy
technologies when our when the
subscriber
of the 5g network goes outside of the
country and rome in another country
so for that purpose we need to do the
ss7 and diameter testing
gdp testing has to be done as well as as
well as and we need to do the internet
testing as well
coming back to the technical details of
the testing yeah air interface
multiple things are there configuration
vulnerability physical silent projection
nasty record and you get a nas protocol
one repeats ddos simulation
or the s cast validation has to be
tested as we have the short time i need
to
quickly go through them not sure we have
to do the msc and the backfill thread
testing
uh analysis of the different models of
the mec it could be fast i pass
is okay now then slicing validation like
i explained this uh
everything uh to you guys in the
previous slide but i'm still explaining
them
one is a network architecture audit
configuration review
traffic analysis has to be done based on
the ai based
as well as the diesel simulation has to
be there we need to test the web
application as well as the wave api in
that
when it comes to nsa core and is testing
then we have to do
test the epc and the ram in addition of
the with addition of the gene node v
we need to see how what signaling drag
is affecting my network whether it is
going falling back to 2g 3g whether
because as of now enough there is a
voiceover nr is there but still
the in the nsa mode the operator are
still going for the voiceover lte based
nr so okay and if there is no voltage
there then from 4g to 2g3 you have to
come back
actually one of the operators already
switched off the 3g network from india
pass from japan india so they are using
2g if there is a no voltaic capability
available in the phone so from there the
user comes from the 4g
to 2g network and then performs a call
there if there is no volte capability
then we need to identify the different
path for the route looking or core
network exposure in the in the user
plane we need to see what are if the
slicing validation is properly properly
done or not
coming to the sa code we need to check
most of the thing like
initially first we need to check what
are the risk of open source time
we need to check the lack of core
signing we need to check what are the
different threads for the 5g
that is affecting the http under json
api that could be
hidden manipulation session hijacking
malform traffic generation
protection mechanism bypass it could be
proof uh
like a pfcb protocol testing i will be
explaining what is
in the last in the last slide so we need
to do the roaming testing as i said
earlier like seven diameter gtp
and the 5g cbp testing has to be there
yes the
5g claims that we have the sap but yet
there are still some vulnerabilities
that could be affecting him we need to
test that as well
so gsma has come up with a nice
initiative for the telecom industry that
is called
the nissas that is network equipment
security assurance scheme
it is defined on the compliance check
based on the cgpp document
it is called the s okay this oscar's
document
they define what testing has to be done
for the certain network element
if it has to be deployed in the network
so there are multiple vendors for
parties who are already participating in
this that is nokia
ericsson z huawei actually i'm expecting
the india
is uh is the most of the most of the
part of the india that is uh
sorry most of the telecom stacks that
are going to be that are being developed
in india like if you speak about the go
to the internet and search for the
stack development most of the countries
companies in india that are developing
the
protocol stack so they has to purchase
they have to they need to participate in
the in this testing
so that they can check their complete
network they can check their computer
strength of the
network that you can check the center of
their devices because what i've seen
that is most of the indian vendors they
are just developing the stack and they
are selling it to the european companies
or any other companies who are
interested in buying stack
saying that we can give you the stack
but we cannot sign the sla but
if you implement the nissas and some
more trusting yes
indian stack vendors or the protocol
vendors can say that yes we can sign
this right because we've seen that the
government the stack vendors or the
network equipment vendor they say that
no we cannot sign their sony that was
the case
with the one of the operator not sure so
thank you guys thank you for
uh your attention if you want to contact
me you can contact me at
as.metricshield.com
also we are going to start one free
webinar series on certain topics of the
telecom you can
check this link and submit your interest
for this
so as of now if you have any questions
just let me know
i will be happy to answer them please
thank you okimp i'm sure the telecom
industry needs
more assistance and audits uh when it
comes to 5g networks
we have few questions okay i'm going to
read them out for you yes please
uh at what layer does 5g implement
encryption to protect voice data
so as of now nobody is implementing the
voiceover nr
but it is still there in the
specification so whenever you are
talking about the encryption there are
multiple encryption that is happening
that is
first one is uh over the non-access
terminal detail that is a signalling
protocol there is a
access stat and protocol so if you if
you're talking about the access
non-access data it is encrypted
end-to-end means if it is going from
your cell phone it is going till the
core
and then it is decrypted but if it is if
you want to do
a data that is your traffic user traffic
that is encrypted from your cell phone
and that is goes to the goes to their
till your tower
all right uh there's another question
uh aren't there any interface management
mechanism like
zc sequence or something as of now i'm
not aware of it because
even we are studying the 5g we started
our internal research like
three to four months ago and we have we
are able to find out some
vulnerabilities in the pfcp as well as
in the air interface but that is still
our study is still going on as of now
all right
uh i'll take the last question uh
before we open for break uh required
hardware
list for testing 5g network like sdr
frequency range support
actually if you see a usrpb210 sdr
uh can be used in the nsa mode but
you'll need two usrpb210
with a stable clock i will say that they
have the
special clock like a tiny device but it
costs 700
for that you'll need two devices of that
and you will need a
extreme edition of the i9 processor to
set up your own
5g network whether it is nsa or sa but
approximately i'll say that that budget
is going to be around six thousand to
seven thousand dollars
the rest is that if you if you want to
test the open source version of it you
have free phy gc
and ran simulator where whether you can
actually where you can actually
simulate the actual 5g traffic in sa or
nsa mode
yes that that people can implement it on
open source but if you want to actually
run your cell phone
on the 5g network in ssa or an sa mode
yes you need at least 7000 to 8000
6000 8000 budget for that
all right thank you for this amazing
presentation
uh we look forward
uh on your upcoming webinars and
learning more about telecom security
thank you anthony thanks for everything
[Music]
thanks