yeah thank you brandon uh yeah so i know
we haven't talked about supply chain
enough already so
we could spend some time on that today
but before we do a fun fact i just
learned from
uh the bird app is that hitchhiker's
guide to the galaxy was released on
october 12th 1979
exactly 42 years ago
that's your fun fact you learn nothing
else from this talk you can tell your
friends that fun fact today is the 42nd
anniversary of it
so yeah i i'm really honored to be here
and speak with you
um i'll introduce myself in more detail
in a little bit
um
but i want to talk first about a story
because
i think a lot of what we've heard about
securing the supply chain
great tools around doing it
maybe doesn't have all of the historical
context
uh that we we can give it
and and so it's important to think back
you know in our history when i i say in
our history i don't mean like
the early days of kubernetes i don't
mean before kubernetes existed i don't
mean uh really any history you or i
uh were around for you know this before
hitchhiker's guide for the galaxy long
before
you know it over the entire history of
like human society
where we've organized ourselves into
society
and
then had adversarial relationships with
other human beings
there's always been
supply chain attacks
always been a feature
adversarial relationships there were
wars over many years that were won and
lost on
uh you know the ability to control
uh your supply chain or that of your
adversary
in fact you know entire civilizations
have either thrived or perished
because of their supply chain or
logistics
in fact in the art of war uh sun tzu
writes that the line between disorder
and order lies in logistics
so this is something that's been around
a really long time
and the reason we're talking about it so
much right now
in our industry and in software is
because you know we've got this concept
that software has eaten the world and
because of that um now this kind of long
ago
you know supply chain style attack that
we've seen
is now something we see in in software
and so it's not that new right it goes
back to
times long before
and so in that sense that you know the
solar ones attack that you know it's uh
oftentimes cited as
one of the key
uh attacks that we saw to make us all
think more about supply chain
isn't really that new
uh but it also doesn't mean that there's
nothing to learn from it
so i think it's been mentioned a few
times today in this
conference but solarwinds themselves
actually spoke
at the
supply chain security conference
yesterday
they had fantastic technical details in
that talk
about you know all of the
technical things that went wrong went
right all of the efforts their team put
in
after the event
i want to talk about some of those today
but i
also want to talk about the human
factors and then some other factors that
we don't often
bring into the discussion around supply
chain
because it's not just about this you
know single event um it's kind of easy
to point the finger and say oh here's
here's the thing that shows us supply
chain is important
but
you know it it's it's not new again it's
not new and we're going to talk about
why in fact
you know one of the the victims
of this uh attack
was actually the first people to report
it fireeye
they previously had written
a report
to
uh nist the national institute of
standards technology called the supply
chain risk management report
and they had talked about how
organizations
putting uh you know greater and greater
security and and maturing their security
position to the rest of the world
is is a good thing but it means that
adversaries will necessarily go up the
chain or down the chain in the supply
chain to then attack
um their real targets
right because solarwinds wasn't even the
target of this attack that we all call
you know solar winds or sunburst attack
and that's an and that's important it's
worth it's worth knowing just a little
bit more about what happened so that we
can talk about that
so if you weren't familiar with the
details attack again yesterday
you can get the real deal from from the
firsthand source if you watch the the
videos from yesterday
but just to give you a little flavor you
know it wasn't this kind of like
full-scale assault that you might think
of
when when you think of an attack right
it was
and it wasn't against the intended
target right solarwinds was not who was
targeted in this attack
they targeted solar winds
so that they could get
at their real targets
right the customers that solarwinds had
who relied heavily on the software that
solarwinds was producing
you know they installed that software
pervasively throughout their networks
um you know gave it expansive
permissions
and then accepted you know updates
directly from solarwinds and that's what
made them vulnerable uh to
an attack on solarwinds as part of their
supply chain
and again just to kind of give a little
bit more of a detailed overview
um
from from what we know
is you know this attack wasn't even
one point in time
uh the attackers were very sophisticated
and originally gained access to
the ci cd build structure or build
infrastructure rather
solarwinds built infrastructure
and
that gave them the ability to
to inject their own code into the
pipeline um where solarwinds was
building the orion product
and at first they kind of just tested
this right they didn't really
um
deliver the real payload there was this
thing called sunspot where they were
just kind of testing to see would they
be detected right they
inserted these dlls uh named them things
that
looked like and sound like classes that
solarwinds was already using
in the package so they didn't really
they wanted to know where are we going
to be noticed and when they realized
that
they were
able to get away with it then they uh
released sunburst which was the the real
trojanized code that got injected into
the orion software
but even that wasn't the end goal right
so
then they moved removed all the malware
that they had from the from the vms
where the builds were happening and the
code was signed
um to try and cover their tracks
and then it wasn't until later that they
then activated um
the the code
to understand you know
to actually get at the attackers the uh
their targets that they were looking at
and it was kind of aptly pointed out by
one ceo in a blog about it that you know
they're not the only ones that have this
kind of infrastructure there's you know
build machines that are signing code
um they're definitely not the only ones
vulnerable to this type of thing
and that's you know kind of the point of
this talk right we have this kind of web
of dependencies and we're going to talk
about that in more detail
but as we build our modern
infrastructure
on top of you know more and more
dependencies
you end up building on you know
something that eventually you don't know
right you have this little
little piece uh holding up everything
else and so we're gonna talk about that
today
um
again i as promised i'd introduce myself
i'm brendan o'leary i'm a developer
evangelist at get lab
i had the inverse problem that dan pop
was talking about
um or no sorry that dan lorenz was
talking about
his hair grew out from worrying about
supply chain i used to have hair before
i thought about supply chain security
now i don't
so yeah
i think that as it may
so
you know we talk about these
dependencies right we saw that funny
xkcd that talks about dependencies
and again we've talked a lot about that
today and these these tools to search
for dependencies and
talked about the software build
materials and all these things
but i want to really define what that is
because i think it's really important to
this concept of supply chain security
so of course a dependency is you know
traditionally what we think of is a open
source dependency that we bring into our
project a library to do something better
to interact with a known api
to interact with um
you know piece of hardware maybe we're
using right so this is some data from
the activers report
that shows you know the percentage of
of projects in different languages that
use open source dependencies this is not
news right we talked about this somewhat
this morning
but one thing that that doesn't cover
uh is transitive dependency so the the
graph we just saw was
dependencies things we specifically call
out in a package manager file or
elsewhere to say hey we've made a
decision to include this library
into our product
now the problem is though or or a
concern there is
that those dependencies come with
dependencies of their own right so you
end up with this web of dependencies
that come along with it
right and so this kind of graph kind of
shows us that and
um
as an amateur
ish
no developer i can attest to that
javascript line right there like if you
just look at node modules on this
computer in any file you'll you'll see
that that
that bears bears out
but these are the transitive
dependencies that we bring in
as we're adding these other
dependencies but it's not even just that
right
like that makes sense we've got open
source libraries we've got the code we
write right that's part of
what you know our is included in our
final product again that's not new
and then we said okay it's not those
libraries it's also
other third-party libraries that we
bring in maybe those are you know ones
that come along with these open source
dependencies
maybe they're closed source ones like
you know
things used to access the operating
system or from some vendor that again
hardware vendor or
some api we're using that's that's
closed
right but that the library then really
is a dependency as well
and then of course both of those have
their own open source and maybe closed
source dependencies
right this is where
when left pad gets taken out of the mpm
registry all of a sudden nobody can
build right not that many people were
pulling left pad
to pad some numbers into their code but
they had depended on something that was
doing you know how they were doing their
ajax calls and that thing was depending
on left path right
and and there's more right so then you
have what about our devops process right
we heard this this morning
what about
all the things that we're doing to get
code into production
that is a dependency
um we've saw that in the solarwinds
attack right it's
a clear dependency to our production
environment and then there's our
production environment
and then of course in there
are a bunch of other vendors with a big
s
and they have a lot of open source
dependencies that they rely on and they
probably have a lot of closed source
proprietary stuff they rely on right so
this web gets a lot bigger than just oh
these are the dependencies called out in
my files
and so i think it's key to understand
that the sum total of all those
dependencies really
is what you should think of when you're
talking about supply chain
um
and so
so okay so let's talk about then what is
a supply chain
[Music]
yeah
so we got that i thought we had 20
minutes no just 10. oh
um great sorry that must have been
returned
okay well the rest of the talk is online
if you'd like to take a look at that
uh i'll i'll tweet it out uh soon on a
lyric crew and i'll elegant all right
thanks brandon yeah thank you all right
um