so
how many of you here are familiar with
you know i hate switching tools too i've
gotten so used to uh google slides
and here i am in powerpoint
so how many of you have heard of magic
eye illusions
only f yeah fair amount fair amount so
magic eye is actually a company and this
is a trademarked thing
so but it turns out there's a free tool
that you can use to build these for
yourself
so i used this free tool
to create this particular illusion right
so there's
images there's an image hidden behind
this now i also learned that it's
actually really hard to see these on a
computer screen
so if i'd learned that soon enough i
would have printed out versions for
everybody to try and use yourself but
you know when the slides are posted if
you feel like it you can print
um and take a look it also turns out
that not everybody
is able to actually see
the images that are in a magic eye
illusion
and that's because not everybody's eyes
work well together
and to see everything it's kind of a
stereogram to see this you really need
to have your eyes work well together and
to have them work well with the brain
and i think of this as being really
apropos for how we need to work together
to deliver cloud native security right
so we have to think
from the security perspective that's
really important and it is absolutely
true
that not all developers understand that
and we have to think about it from the
app developer perspective and the
business needs as well
and it's a balancing act it's a risk
management act to figure out
how do i meet the business needs which
include a good security posture while
also enabling the app dev team to do
what they need to do
and to deliver quickly
so
also there's this ever expanding
guidance that is coming at all of us
you know nist 800 190 that's been out
there for a while
cncf open source to kubernetes security
audit in 2019
awesome really great content and there's
another one in progress right that i
hope we'll see in 2022.
there's guidance from analysts like
gartner right we need to think
differently about how we protect cloud
workloads especially since they're
ephemeral and they move around as was
noted right we're not we're not dealing
with ip addresses
there's the new executive order which
has created this intense focus on the
need to create software bill of material
and the way to create um and and to
improve security in your supply chain
again some great talks yesterday if you
didn't get to the supply chain security
con
watch the recordings and then of course
the nsa sisa guidance for hardening
kubernetes honestly it overlaps a good
bit with the cis kubernetes hardening
guide that's great
but it's a lot for everybody to absorb
and when you kind of look at this and
put it all together
i do think that the guidance really
comes down to
the need for a devsecops approach
to securing both the platform
and the workloads that run on the
platform
right we need to control application
security in the ci cd process
we need to protect the platform at
deploy time the platform
ensuring that it's configured correctly
kubernetes is complex
also ensuring that you've got
protections in place to check workloads
as they're deployed
and then we know that we can't avoid
every there are unknown threats
so we do need that visibility that
observability that we just heard about
earlier to help us detect and respond to
runtime threats
and part of that response one of the
things i see kind of when i talk to
people about devsecops
i see a lot of emphasis on shift left
which is important
but i think of that as devsec right a
lot of that focus is how do i integrate
security tools
into my ci cd pipeline there's sort of
this assumption that secops right we
kind of know what we're doing
and yet it's really true that kubernetes
and declare the declarative environment
the fact that containers are ephemeral
even if it's a long-lived workload
sorry you can um
that that
where that pod is deployed can change
right so you can never fix a running
container you need to rebuild and
redeploy
which really means that we have to think
through
how do we close that devsecop loops how
do we feed that information back to the
development team
so
red hat has done this survey
on contain on the state of kubernetes
security
and one of the things we hear and i've
also actually seen it in survey results
from idc
a lot of people
say that they are doing devsecops that
they have strong debt secops adoption
now i think that that's true for
folks who are more on the bleeding edge
and i think that enterprises who are
still in their cloud adoption journey
may think they're doing devsecops but
they're really just kind of doing that
shift left i've got vulnerability
scanning in my ci process
and that's about the extent of it
so i think
you know one of the things we really
have to think about
is how can we as a community
help organizations
demystify
what they need to do but also help and
and operationalize their use of
cloud-native workloads but also kind of
we're all here looking at a lot of
different capabilities a lot of new
tools and things that we can do to
address these key requirements
but that comes with its own set of
complexity
right so we need to be thinking about
not just technology and tools
we need to be thinking about processing
people as well so how do we help ensure
that that process is agile and how do we
help the companies that we support
future proof what they're doing
think about solutions that can apply no
matter where somebody is running
kubernetes or their container workloads
or their cloud workloads right a cloud
can be on premises
as well as in public cloud providers
so
technology people process all of these
remain key
and it's important that we think about
the people in the process as much as the
technology
so some of the future investments again
i love this that this community is
investing
uh in many many different ways right
when it comes to application integrity
and that ci cd process
the sig store project has just kind of
exploded how many of you are familiar
with sig store
right so one of the things i love about
sig store is how it makes it simpler for
the a tool chain to sign artifacts as
the artifacts are moving through the
tool chain most signing solutions that
enterprises are used to using aren't
designed to be work to to be used in a
pipeline
it also includes a transparency
signature log right the recourse so that
you can check
and make sure that and verify your
signature
tech on cd chains again another way to
kind of document and log how things have
gone through the process
encrypted containers storing and running
encrypted containers adds to
uh the ability to manage application
security and then rootless builds right
there are many there are some build
solutions that require you to have
privileges to build that container image
be much better if you didn't need to do
that especially if you're running your
builds
on kubernetes
integrity integrity for the platform how
do i attest the host the nodes in my
cube cluster
how do i uh invest in
things like kubernetes support for user
namespaces
this is something that you know we've
been talking about for a while it hasn't
been delivered yet
and you know there's still conversations
ongoing about the complexity required
there but most of the customers i talk
to are looking for that additional
protection because it's really hard
especially in certain verticals as they
move workloads to the cloud
some of them need privileges this this
they aren't able to re-architect
everything to be truly micro-service
based or cloud-native and so in
particular in telco is you see
containerized native network functions
delivered
those often require the ability to for a
certain level of privilege that is
better protected with user name spaces
and then also honestly one of the
biggest attack vectors for any kube
cluster is the cluster admin privs
and this is a place where we don't yet
have
genuine separation between the control
plane and the data plane and this is an
area that red hat's investing in and i i
would love to see the community invest
in as well
with the runtime again deep
observability as was mentioned earlier
absolutely key
and the ability to use that data that's
collected to automate response to what
you discover not just network policy
which is a great thing to help automate
it confuses
uh our network security teams how do
they get visibility how do they
understand
also
automated response to vulnerabilities in
the runtime environment and a better
risk assessment right are those
vulnerabilities in pods that are
actually exposed to the network or not
what's my level of risk so that i can
really
kind of triage those things better
and then
so active recommendations really key
and and again just that ability to
respond
um
we look to the community to help deliver
on all of these things again lots of
great work happening
and i think one of our big challenges is
going to be how do we help our customers
our end users
operationalize
everything that we talk about everything
that we're working on have them work
together
as a as a whole solution and how do we
help them bridge
the silos that still exist
between the different teams security ops
app dev
right that's that's a people thing
that i think we should be thinking about
as well
so that's it for me thank you very much
and um
not sure what
whether we have time for questions or
somebody's up next
[Applause]