s-bomb
the rest of the story
introducing our three explorers
alan friedman is a paladin a warrior who
swore an oath to protect and help
everyone else protect themselves and
others
he isn't actually good with weapons but
has studied many in arcane tool and art
a noted scholar before taking the
paladin oath six years ago he recently
sojourned from ntia to sissa he works
with communities and trades across the
realm to help build shared scalable
defenses well not scalable like a ball
because that would be bad
while he certainly didn't discover the
book of s-bomb he has spent far too much
time talking about it
nisha kumar
nisha is a barbarian a fierce warrior
that rushes in to defend open source
from the dangers of clutter and toil she
is most effective with the snake staff
but is also pretty good with the gopher
club nisha belongs to the open source
technology center tribe at vmware
and emily fox emily is a former paladin
turned rogue known for her stealth and
getting software engineers to develop
more securely without their knowledge
she lurks in cloud services at the fruit
company providing precision in security
architecture design while also
co-leading the security technical
advisory guild in the cncf she
repeatedly demonstrates resourcefulness
cunning and versatility making her
skills and those of nisha and alan
essential to any successful s-bomb
adventuring party
our story begins
in a world of compliance requirements
security compromises and ridiculously
long dependency chains
three unlikely travelers cross paths to
clear the smoke and mirrors around
s-bomb the rest of the story
our champions of security compliance and
open source nisha alan and emily have
arrived at a local pub to catch up
they talk about the latest supply chain
attacks the residual effects of solar
winds how everyone is seeing an increase
in attacks
eventually their conversation
transitions to the most recent u.s
executive order on cyber security and
the multiple efforts cropping up across
the world to implement the software bill
of materials
as they talk a stranger approaches
our travelers break off their
conversation as the stranger stares
intently
weirdly
their face appears to be worn by
countless hours of
excel use
the stranger whispers
that which you seek
can only be found
over there
the stranger extends a long crooked
finger
to indicate a shelf in the corner our
travelers don't recall being there the
last time they visited
the stranger coughs
and turns back to our intrepid trio
they warn
you may never use it
but when you need it
it is
valuable
alan jumps up off of the stool and walks
over to the shelf
grabs a heavy
large
book
closely resembling the complete rainbow
series in size
and holds it up
emily
looks at nisha
who shrugs as the stranger fades from
view
so alan what on earth do you have there
why this is s-bomb nisha and i have been
chasing down the mysteries of this for
quite some time now
indeed i feel like we spent the last
year chasing and talking about this
artifact what's another session to set
everyone straight on the actual spawn
story
alan drops the s-bomb in the middle of
the table
our companions settle in to begin
planning their journey
two strangers sit listening intently
so i recall alan and i talking about
this a long time ago back before
solarwinds consumed any sense of supply
chain innocence how do we expect folks
to use it should we just throw it at
people like a confusion spell because
ultimately that's what it's bound to
cause what kinds of information are in
this thing
i don't recommend throwing it at people
we want it to be useful not confusing
and it really depends on the s-bomb
there are a lot more metadata that could
be included beyond the minimum
requirements
some can provide information about the
source code the build environment and
the actors who attest it to the process
that makes sense i mean security folks
scare enough people as it is anytime we
can help others produce actionable
security relevant information that is
easy is a win in my book but what about
formats is one better than the other i
keep hearing that there's a lot of them
out there
true standards both are likened dignity
in fair software where we lay our scene
alan no wrong book
oh sorry i got a little confused in
costume so basically there are two
primary formats that are reasonably
widely deployed today uh cyclone dx
which comes up the oauth world uh it's a
a
fancy project there and spdx which is a
linux foundation project that just got
iso status both are great both have
active development communities um and
the important thing here is that
a standard format
enables you to create a broader tooling
ecosystem so what we're interested in
doing is saying what's the metadata that
we're tracking let's have a common way
of tracking it with clearly labeled
fields
and so we can use the minimum sets to
convey and move the data around
so it sounds like if someone is already
using one format over another there's no
reason to change it
but what if i'm not producing s-bombs or
and i'm not using a specific format i
don't want to upend my entire tool chain
and tech stack and tech technology
ecosystem just to be able to produce
this thing that somewhere somewhere on
the internet or in the world is probably
going to use
might look at but then not know what to
do with
as alan said the specific format is not
important but the metadata within it is
regardless of what format you choose it
becomes useless if the metadata is not
there
if you are not already producing s bonds
look for tooling that complements your
existing tool chain there are many open
source tools created and maintained by
volunteers in the community and in
industry working together to make the
state of the art better this is how open
source works
yes so the success of standards is
openness uh and the vision here is that
we should have a shared understanding of
what we have and then building on top of
that data layer as an industry so
we have a great open source community
and open source tools and that's great
there's some people trying to make money
by building tools and hopefully they're
interesting enough people say hey yeah
i'll pay for that and that's okay too
the important thing is that we have a
shared vision about the value of this
data layer and that we're building on
top of that
so it's not the portion of invincibility
that i keep hearing about and it's going
to solve all of our problems in cyber
security and cloud native right
um i don't know too many people that
have actually been saying that i think
that's something that people sort of as
a straw man
try to poke at but reality it's it's
just a data layer and we think it's a
foundational data layer so imagine it's
something to akin to
cve right there's nothing magical about
giving a vulnerability a data string uh
or a number string that doesn't help you
but
once we have this shared vision where we
can communicate about say a
vulnerability or about the components
that we're using then we can work
together and then we can build more
tools and find more use cases on top of
that
having navigated past the misconceptions
in the pub
our travelers embark on their quest
so this book has a lot of information in
it that's great
what can we do with this information
how do you all see this meeting and
s-bomb consumers needs what use cases
exist for the content in an s-bomb that
metadata that nisha and alan have both
referred to
so an s-bomb is an important part of the
balanced supply chain breakfast it's the
beans in your english your full english
it's the chocolate sprinkles on your
dutch roll it's the muesli in your
morning routine it's
apparently alan skipped breakfast today
but i'll go with that analogy
s balm is like a key nutrient that if
you were deficient in
manifests itself as symptoms that seem
unrelated
once you have an inventory of your
deployed software you can do things like
correlate what you have deployed with
what
vulnerabilities exist
or if you potentially have software
whose license doesn't match your
organization policy
excellent so it can help organizations
not only make but automate compliance
and security decisions before deployment
and after deploy that's fantastic
what's important is that it won't convey
vulnerabilities but certainly provides
you with a map about what you've got to
match against what is vulnerable this
sounds like it really was designed for
on-premise environments actually the
impetus was for on-prem in the midst of
time when software used to live in place
rather than in the ether the value was
really uh that defenders needed to know
was on their network and you can't
defend what you don't know about uh and
in fact a lot of the early adopters uh
that care about this are in critical
infrastructure dealing with on-prem
software things like medical devices in
energy industrial control system world
um but the spirit of needing to know
what we're dealing with what we're
trying to defend that lives on with the
cloud native security warriors today
honestly that's a great point between
on-prem and cloud native with more
organizations either moving to acquiring
or being born on cloud companies are
constantly evaluating their current
product space i can see the s-bomb
helping here
yes
companies are making acquisitions
consolidating and driving digital
transformation
having an s bomb would help consolidate
in key areas and reduce
variety of versions of one software
component
organized deployments and so much more
essentially not having an spot was the
supply chain equivalent of forgetting
your 20-sided dice in d d or maybe
not bothering to comment your code
as nisha emily and alan continue on
their journey the beast of secure builds
steps in front of them blocking their
path they must confront it before
proceeding
i've heard so many things about s-bomb
it seems everyone is assuming it can do
everything except be that portion of
invincibility
it that it can provide integrity over
the entire supply chain solve open
source security and auto report security
vulnerabilities for you that's ludicrous
right
so
in fact
s bomb doesn't do any of those things by
itself but
try doing any of those priorities that
we all should be working towards without
an s bomb it's painful we've all tried
to experience doing it and trying to
build our own or roll our own and it can
be very difficult and s bomb makes all
of those easier and more scalable
yep
you are responsible for your supply
chains integrity and s-pump can help you
establish the state of the items it
knows about
this doesn't imply integrity of the
software supply chain and signing an
s-bomb is not a minimum requirement if
an attacker were to successfully
compromise the publishing infrastructure
that produced the software and the
s-bomb and if all of that were signed
you'd simply just have an inventory of
everything in the software including any
libraries the attackers introduced in
the code base through the build
the s-bomb doesn't stop that
essentially though folks can generate it
from source build or post build with
binary analysis generating the s-bomb
from the build seems the right way to go
based on what nisha is saying
if you build it you better s-bomb i mean
we know that compilers are the dark arts
and build systems really can be as well
these days
ah this is why it's so important that in
addition to source code security folks
are paying attention to what goes into
their build workers disabling ssh access
and so much more the build system can be
compromised and impact what is in your
software and your s-bomb
that's why in the optimal case a secured
build process is what we need not just
for our software but for the s-bomb data
to track it especially in cloud native
as our vision is that we're agile and we
like to move fast and break things
having subdued the beast of secure
builds our travelers have approached the
swamp of sharing uncertainties
unclear on how to move forward
there are a bunch of minimums and
depending on your industry or regulatory
requirements these minimums may vary
right
so at its core an s-bomb is about
identifying a component and to do that
there's some basics that we need uh we
need to have some identifiers ideally
some identifiers that other people use
so you can map them between databases um
and then there's a bunch of other use
cases as well uh so
one popular way that people sort of say
this is we want to use s bombs to track
vulnerabilities and in fact
some of the data formats can track
vulnerability data in the s-bomb which
is very useful if you're a developer one
of the risks however is if you start
depending on the s-bomb
to track this data and it moves across
organizational boundaries then you're
not sure if it's live and so we have to
be very very careful about the
assumptions that we make about the state
of the data in the s-bomb and what we
can and can't depend on to be completely
up-to-date
so
basically
because we've got so many
vulnerabilities today and we want to
make sure that the information that's
available is complete accurate and
up-to-date because we've never ever
deployed any software anywhere in the
world that has remained secure for its
entire lifetime
yeah we can actually take a page out of
the manufacturing playbook where the
bill of materials is something that gets
passed on from supplier to supplier
until it finally ends up with the
product that gets shipped
and then there is a remediation process
where defects out in the field get
collected and sent back to the
to the suppliers and they use the s-bomb
to find out which component has the
defect so that they can fix that
component and the cycle repeats
so that makes a lot of sense and i'm
assuming that they have really good
established relationships they all trust
each other everything's good but
honestly that s-bomb is probably going
to come from a complete stranger all the
way on the other side of the world
somebody you've never met how can you
trust what's in it to be accurate and
what if it's incomplete what tools exist
to produce s-bombs and isn't producing
an accurate s bomb a challenge to begin
with and and don't even get me started
on consuming them that just seems like a
nightmare
so we've got a couple fun challenges
here you're right they're all things
that we need to tackle so one is hey
who's this coming from and of course uh
we have natural tools for that uh
signatures uh digital signatures but of
course um those of you who play in xml
and json know that rapper signatures are
non-trivial fortunately both spdx and
cyclone dx have been working on
developing those and they're great
projects like sig store to enable it
second challenge is saying well how do i
know the data is true and there are a
couple of things you can do one you can
count on the fact that it's illegal to
lie about a product two you can always
do the trust but verify uh you know when
you should talk to earlier about uh
source composition analysis tools and
binary analysis tools those may not be
the first best option but they're a
great way to validate some of this data
and then lastly we have the question
about how do we make sure that we can
consume this data and where we want to
head is supporting automated decisions
based on rules and there's a huge
development opportunity here uh we're
going to need smart people to think
about this
this is the whole growth area of
code is compliance and uh and policy is
code
what we want to do is sort of think
about customizable approaches that are
less complex and more straightforward
and to do that to make progress we need
to share what we have and work towards
common policies and decisions that are
useful to the s-bomb consumers
that's right alan making the s-bomb
actionable for policy makers in an
organization is an opportunity right for
the taking
a swamp monster emerges from an alcove
of algae and growth and announces loudly
ha
i already have that with my source code
analysis tools
nisha rolls a 19 to detect glamour and
the swamp monster fades to reveal a
small fly
aha dependency trackers like you see in
source code analysis tools typically
rely on a package manifest a package
manifest will give you some of the
information but not all of the
information what actually gets installed
is determined by say it with me now
the builds
so what about sharing s-bombs
ah
there be dragons as we've reached the
limits of our map um
we know that this is a priority and
there are a lot of folks that are
exploring how to do it um one of the
easiest ways that we can do it today is
there are companies that are already
saying hey i've got my live build i've
got my live s bomb and i just post it
online and that's great for a lot of
organizations however there are going to
be some folks that say you know what i'm
not ready to make this data public for
whatever reason
and so then we're going to need to think
about what access control can look like
or
you could publish your s-bombs through
customer portals or websites or even
shipping it along with your product very
much like how you would be able to ship
s-bombs with container images and store
them both in a container registry
and there are emerging technologies uh
like manufacture usage descriptor which
is a way of having a secure pointer to
an s-bom or the d-bomb model which is an
access control overlay that allows you
to sort of put a lot of supply chain
data
pretty much anywhere and then assign
read and write and edit access it so
that your customers and your upstream
providers can all talk about it and you
can control how they're doing it
right and that makes sense and what's
important really here is that it's only
good if it's relevant to the software
that's in use not two versions behind
and that's why it would be great to be
able to produce it as part of your build
because it can reliably match what
you're shipping or making public at the
time
so given that i'm a crafty clever fox
that i'm putting on my attacker hat how
do i explain that no attacker is going
to leverage the s-bomb as a shopping
list of places to exploit as this seems
like your really key area for doing
reconnaissance work so you know it's
2021 so we didn't just talk about
attackers or monsters uh we actually do
a little threat model
so
you're really powerful attackers uh they
don't need this right if they're going
after your software um you know jidra's
free they can do reverse engineering
they're not going to
they'll figure out what is in your
system and at the other end of the
spectrum you've got your automated
attackers right people who are just
doing spray and pray looking for a
toehold so they can start a ransomware
project or something like that um and
there again they don't need the roadmap
um
they're just doing automatic scanning
and if you have a flaw they'll find it
what we need is to give the defenders
the roadmap so they know what it is that
they should be paying attention to and
worrying about
that's right the s-bomb is a tool for
the defender not the attacker
if you were to give a map of your castle
to an attacker but have uh each entry
well defended the map is not going to be
of any use
that makes total sense and
like
it's part of a good defense and depth
strategy the s-bomb is not going to
defeat that all by itself realistically
even if they had that full shopping list
they're going to have to do a whole lot
more work
but what about sensitive information
such as sources and methods we can't
possibly share everything please tell me
no one's putting secrets in this stuff
no the s-bomb is not meant to store your
secrets
there isn't really a formal standardized
way of sharing sensitive information
spdx has this concept of profiles and
one of them is the usage profile which
gets shared between suppliers of
components and
consumers of those components and this
is something the auto industry is
championing
this could probably provide a template
for how other industries could share
information
i mean ultimately you want uniform
adoption across the board s-bom and
supply chain security is way bigger than
just cloud and cloud-native some
industries it sounds like are moving
really fast like automotive and finance
that's right as a cloud native community
we want this to be adopted beyond just
netflix and twitter
and for that to happen we need to be
really careful about how we
build and inventory our software supply
chain and we need to consider what kind
of checks and balances we need before we
deploy our sas offerings
a lot of people
in cloud native when they think about
sas they think twitter and we really
want to
move on to
we want this to move on to industries
that are uh more serious like uh
healthcare and
uh finance and uh
government uh systems
things that keep grandma
are you saying that there are people
involved in security that aren't on
twitter i'm pretty sure i would have
read about that on twitter
our travelers have navigated the swamp
of sharing uncertainties and are heading
back to the pub to share their story
but how that story continues is up to
you the community and industry to make
something of s-bombs to use them
the winds coming across the land blowing
from executive orduria hint that this
issue is not going away and will only
get more important
that's right the leaders of the realm in
the white castle or at least the white
house have decreed that s-bomb will be a
priority uh anyone who wants to sell
critical software to the government will
eventually have to have an s-bomb and i
have a hunch that companies aren't going
to want to have two different versions
and so we're going to see most
organizations realize that this is
something they're going to need to have
can we succeed on this quest
our party of adventurers have some solid
members and alan
hey
but we need more help how can folks get
involved
well uh one thing folks can do if they
want to sort of see the big picture on s
bomb is join this international
community-led effort uh that's brought
together experts from a range of sectors
and different types of technologies and
to do that uh
very excited it's an open effort uh and
so get in touch with me through email or
find me online
or you can join the amazing open source
projects out there both svdx and cyclone
dx are open initiatives and
would love your help a project that is
near and dear to my heart is the term
project which generates s1 swat
container images so it sounds like
there's a lot already out there but
there's even more for folks to get
involved in
tooling that can help generate s-bombs
as well as complement the overall supply
chain security process such as tough
spiffy and toto sift so much more
our travelers return to their table
awaiting new friends and colleagues to
join them on their next quest will they
see you there the rest of the story is
in your hands
but are you willing to commit
thanks for watching s-bomb the rest of
the story
stay tuned for scenes from our next
episode where our explorers figure out
how to do a live q a
see you soon