hi welcome to the section in this
session we'll talk about how open policy
agent gatekeeper
can help you to strengthen your supply
chain security
i'm rita
hello i'm sartech
we are maintainers of the oppa
gatekeeper project
so uh first you might ask well what is
gatekeeper
um well gatekeeper is a customizable
kubernetes emission and mutation webhook
it helps us enforce policies and
strengthen governance
it enforces policies executed by the
open policy agent
a policy agent for
cloud native environments and it is a
cncf graduated project
let's see how you can leverage it to
extend supply chain security and
governance in your kubernetes
environment
all right so let's uh
dive a little deeper in gatekeeper for
supply chain security
with external data feature
gatekeeper can now
be used for validating and mutating
kubernetes objects using
the data that is coming from external
data sources in a generic and plugable
way
gatekeeper is an interface to external
data sources such as image registries
and it is developed using a
provider-based model
so that the specific external data logic
can be written by providers
outside of gatekeeper
and let's look at some potential use
cases
for validation for example we have image
signing
we can check whether an image is signed
or not
another example is image vulnerabilities
you can check if an image of critical
vulnerabilities for example
and then on the mutation side
we can mutate an image tracked to a
digest uh so which helping us to uh pin
to a specific uh shot digest for for a
uh for an image
and um another example of a mutation is
uh we could use um active directory or
ldap directory uh to mutate uh labels
and or annotations to add owners so you
can tell who created those communities
objects
do we get to see this in action
yes let's do a demo awesome
yeah let's start with our demo and we're
going to look at take a look at our
cluster first
here you can see our gatekeeper
controller manager and gatekeeper audit
pods here
and let's look at our providers next uh
here you can see there are the the
registered providers uh with gatekeeper
they
basically uh map to services that are
running behind these
deployments such as the treaty provider
or tag to digest provider
so in next we are going to look at our
assign
crd which is the mutation
crd
one of the mutation crds for gatekeeper
so you can see that
this
[Music]
this object uh takes a an image
and
uh for for all containers and then it
uses the
external data data source which is value
at location which means the images
images value by using the tag to digest
provider
to mutate
the value of the
image to the same um
value of the image
a pendant would it with the
image image digest
and in the
next example we are going to
take a look at the
the
deployment file
here you can see
uh the tag
which which does not have uh contain a
sha in here is the the one uh with the
digest already included so we should see
the first one to mutate well the second
one does not get mutated
so let's go ahead and deploy
our
deployment
and then let's take a look at uh the
object
as i mentioned earlier we could see that
the first um container got mutated with
the digest while second one still has
the
same digest
very cool
and then the next one uh we want to take
a look at is the cosine provider uh
cosine provider is a validation based uh
provider where um you can check the
if a container image uh is is signed or
not using the cosine
project in six store
and um this is our gatekeeper constraint
template uh where we pass the container
image to the external data source and we
basically check the response from the
external data provider and then here you
can see our constraint which has the
enforcement action denied so we we
should uh didn't deny the deployment if
it is not signed
and then in here you can see a test
deployment which is an unsigned image uh
this is like a pause image which is not
signed
so we are going to go ahead and deploy
this
and we should see
our container should be denied
and uh like we mentioned um it did get
declined because it does not contain a
valid cosine image
and then so let's look at a a signed
image so in this case we are looking at
the distributor static uh
latest tag and we're going to deploy
that and this should
go and be created
all right so next let's look at how we
can use this feature to block
vulnerabilities
here as you can see is a gatekeeper
constraint template which contains the
rego that says hey for any containers we
want to
talk to the trivia provider
which provides us with vulnerability
data right the attribute
does a lot of
scanning and returns the number of
vulnerabilities and the high low or
medium and based on that then uh you
know we in the in our policies we can
decide if we want to deploy or block the
vulnerability or not or or maybe return
a warning right so here uh next we're
gonna deploy this constraint template
and
and here
gatekeeper will basically reach out to
trivia provider
and then here as you can see we have a
constraint
and the constraint says okay enforcement
action is worn so i don't actually want
to block but just give people a warning
that they're deploying something
bad and here as you can see is an
example deployment that contains vote
that may contain a vulnerability
and here we are using alpine as our
example
image
and as soon as i deployed this let's see
what trivia returns
all right and here as you can see it
returns a warning it's telling us hey
for this alpine image you have 30
vulnerabilities but we're not actually
going to block the deployment
all right uh next um let's see how it
will work for a phone an image that's
not vulnerable right
um here as you can see we're using uh
the static digitalist image
let's see if um if we're right let's see
if see if trivia identifies any
vulnerability
all right so it was true
yeah
all right next we have the aad
use case
in which case you know a lot of
companies a lot of organizations want to
identify owners of kubernetes resources
and here we are leveraging
mutating the mutation feature in
gatekeeper which as you can see here
is a custom resource called assign
metadata which says hey for
you know for config maps that i'm
deploying i want to
provide a label called owner and that
data actually comes from a provider
called aad provider right
and that data will then be mapped as it
would then be used as the owner label
for
these configmap resources
so let's take a look at how that works
so we're going to
apply
this assign metadata
resource and then
and then now as you can see we have a
test config map
and once we apply it let's see if it
actually
gives us the
label it looks like you're applying that
with a specific user um
yes you're and this is the user the aad
user
all right let's take a look if the
mutation is
working
yeah it looks like i the labels got
mutated and that's my
yeah it's you
so it works great
all right that was a fun demo um hope
you enjoyed the
demonstration of many many use cases
that you can actually
start applying in your organization with
gatekeeper and the new external data
feature
we would love to get feedback
from from the community so definitely
come give us feedback and open issues in
github and slack and join us in our
weekly community call
thank you thank you