solana are you part
so at jakes and I'm at amelie a a year
ago exactly a year ago so this
conference is actually quite special for
me exactly a year ago I quit my job the
day before I came to speak at RV a sec I
came last year to speak about cloud
security so I was the ciso of Heroku at
Salesforce prior to that I was a SOT
vote part of that was it did me cetera
whatever I quit my job literally a day
before I flew out here at RV a sec to
stand up and talk about cloud security
and everybody saw my email dress with
blue box and everybody's very curious
and the company had not launched at that
point I think there was a three or three
of us working at my co-founders living
room in San Francisco small tight and so
we started that company I came out here
started speaking and it was very
nerve-racking one year later almost
exactly for the day one year later I'm
now here to talk about BYOD and mobile
security so my new company blue box
that's a space ran this is not a vendor
pitch anyone in here that knows me as
ever work with me knows I suck at sales
and should never be allowed to do it I'm
horrible at it but uh we're going to
talk a little bit about enterprise
challenges with BYOD and mobile in
general so again this a little bit my
background this is why I'm here speaking
and I would've been there trying to sell
you on a product right I come from
enterprise that's that's my space i am
not your normal salesman i don't
normally come from the product space my
co-founder does but I come from the
enterprise space I have the same
problems that most of you probably have
so let me just get a quick check those
have never been in a presentation with
me will quickly fine i like to talk to
the audience and get you guys
participate because I will go hundred
percent off deck if we have to make sure
we cover with you guys want to cover how
many guys here are vendors okay small
percentage I asked this question a
couple months back in this like brown
team forum forum thing everybody but one
person raised their hand and I'm like oh
i'm giving a talk to enterprise and
everybody but one person is vendor this
isn't going to go well for me so I like
check that how many are government state
federal local anything like that okay
all right more than I expected that's
that's good how many just enterprise the
standard business enterprise okay all
right and the rest I'm gonna sue more
educational or unemployed or whatnot not
to say educational unemployed of the
same thing didn't mean that sorta okay
all right so anyway um how many you are
you know trying to deal with mobile
strategy and be wipe good percentage how
many of you have solved this problem in
your enterprise okay no hands all right
good every now and I have one person
original hand I'm like please tell me
that solution I would love to put that
up here will be done in one slide that'd
be great alright so how many of you
right now arm our one allowed byob and
you're in a project okay how many of
your like hell no no BYOD okay couple of
people all right so shout it out give me
a reason why no BYOD it's hard to hear
all right don't have to allow it because
it's already there so the people that
want to just keep it completely out of
their enterprise able to shut down give
me a reason nobody okay I'm gonna put
you out the spot I'm gonna let you guys
know them up a little bit but we'll come
back to that all right so BYOD most of
the reasons why people say why they
allow VoIP is right there is that answer
we got it's already here your data is
already on mobile devices via laptop via
phones tablets whatever it is right so
most people say okay we just have to we
have to enable this we have to well we
have to get our hands around it because
we can't stop it we're in that trend
right now I hear a lot of different
things we have BYOD I hear BYOD bring
your own technology there was like three
others that I heard last week and some
bitch but we're at this interesting
place and technology right now wherein
users are driving more of the decisions
for us than they ever have they can now
go out and they can sign up for a seven
dollar a month cloud service they can go
get whatever phone they want and hook it
up to email assuming you know you have
access to me from the outside they don't
need IT to come over and say hey
configure my outlook and my PST and my
offline you know and all this stuff
right they can just do it Apple has made
it very very simple Android questionable
how simple it is not an android fans
personally but Apple anyway has made it
very very simple to be able to adopt and
use BYOD inside the enterprise and this
is why the BYOD it makes it just easy
access to data easy workflows increases
the productivity of end users there was
an article that was published on wired
not too long ago that I wrote that
talked about when i was at disney i was
a blackberry fanboy how many of you
still use blackberrys okay just a couple
19 not that min fortunately um so I was
a blackberry fanboy I used blackberries
from before it even had a phone when it
was just a email device it was the
greatest thing ever right my neighbor
was a was a tester for ram and so i got
one really really early and then I got
the workforce I kept using them and it
was great when I was at Disney and I was
running security for a couple divisions
of Disney IT came over one day and
they've been chasing me for about a week
we gonna have something like that to
take my blackberry away from me and they
wanted to hand me an iphone and I
remember looking at the guy and saying
what do I do with this toy this is a toy
can they even do email can they do
calendaring probably anybody who used
the first iPhones knows calendaring was
horrible on it like things got a sink
things got deleted it was back rim was
dominant in the market for that it was
great so they took they took my my work
device away from me and they and they
apparently I'm probably first person to
stress test this area of the of the
stage right here it's freaking at me and
they gave me this little toy that jobs
who's on the board it isn't it time said
I had to use and I was pissed by this
fast forward about four or five six
years and i was at tebow and I was going
overseas and said here take the company
blackberry with you my
fine whatever i'm usually library is
fine I get to Hong Kong and I'm trying
to send an email I can't figure out this
stupid thing I'm like how do I tension
photo of what I'm trying to send how do
i save this document how do I Esau and
how do I share I just couldn't figure
the thing out right and what it happened
is I guess so dependent on these
applications that i could go and
download utilize got no longer knew how
to use just the standard blackberry i
had a better workflow I didn't want to
go back to my hotel to find my laptop to
do whatever I needed to do so this is
open up this whole new world of
productivity for end-users and we have
to figure out kind of how to adopt it
because if somebody said it's already
there so give me another reason where
are the other reasons why some of you
are looking at BYOD other than it's
already there any other reasons or does
all come back to it's already there and
productivity is that somebody say
something no nobody said something speak
out guys seriously I'm fully awake this
morning i'm on west coast time you guys
should weigh more weight than me at this
point all right so this is one of the
reasons that BYOD and mobile is staying
at the enterprise IT teams are scared of
mobile and scared of BYOD it's something
new it's a challenge right and so these
are some stats that were put together by
some analyst firms to basically say why
enterprises are scared about mobile what
you know security threat says it does it
pose what I find is very interesting is
that employee owned I don't if you can
read this subtext there but the employee
on tablets is what's are all the way to
the right employee own smartphones is
what's next to the right yeah to your
right there those are the two that
people are most concerned about they're
not concerned about the company own
devices which is which is interesting so
let me ask you why does the
employee-owned devices pose more risk to
the enterprise of course for you guys
there any other
it's all about the data you can't
control the data okay very good right
can't enforce security policies okay and
so let me ask you like the security
policies what kind of security policies
would you normally want to enforce okay
and um the unknown what are some of the
unknown things that might be scary what
they've installed gotcha gotcha okay
what about mobile malware retraining if
mo you know mobile malware concern as
well okay and I see a lot of hands not
up anybody want to counter that anybody
have a point of mold now or not being a
screw to risk anybody there's a lot of
you smiling you guys are just you just
don't want to speak up but that's okay
i'ma let go cuz i can remember i can see
you so i know which one you think it
about this okay I'm up here I can see
everything okay anyway so mobile malware
is the one that interestingly enough
when I talk to people so unknown
securities in data those are three
wholeheartedly I agree with that's why I
got into this space mobile malware is
one that comes up a lot there's always
some new article mad props to the pr
teams and marketing to use for some
these look out a fair notice here look
out as a sister company of ours from the
same investors so I did tread lightly
I'm told um but uh always some report
that comes out like this this is this is
from last year but it shows this huge
spike and I just saw enough when the
other day it said mobile malware has
increased three hundred percent 3,000%
quarter-over-quarter but when I went and
pulled up the report it was like
hundreds of samples like hundreds of
variance of the same couple types of
mobile malware it wasn't like there was
thousands or millions of new samples
again here this is uh so this is a
report from lookout that talks about the
different types of malware so we have a
toll fraud we the green is just other
malware and then we have spyware and the
toll fraud stuff is the biggest is the
big
thing there I just it was just instantly
other day and I was talking about how
toll fraud is my favorite thing right
now in malware his toll fraud is a
throwback to the Internet dial-up days
when you would get some kind of virus on
your computer that would then change
your dial up internet settings and would
route your your your dial it for your
internet connection you thought you were
calling your local AOL or whomever and
you're dialing you know some total
number and your upper middle east or
wherever and you're getting charged like
$18 a minute while you're on the
internet and now we're seeing this with
malware on mobile phones where they're
doing it with SMS or changing SMS
gateway whether they're texting out to
total numbers or the rerouting some of
your calls and I absolutely love this
because a throwback to the old days so
it's my is probably my favorite thing
that's going on right now but here's a
list of some of the things that I hear
from people that are risk for mobile
there was a stat that came out said
fifty five percent of people send work
email and documents from their mobile
device through their personal email so
that goes back to the data control and
do you know that people are doing that
that kind of thing you know most people
will use insecure Wi-Fi networks you
know I am one of those I travel quite a
bit so when i'm here at conferences
actually I'd never used the conference
now are close to be home is one of it my
hotel that's the best place to attack me
I'm not a coffee drinker but if I was
i'm sure i would use it at starbucks or
peets or whatever you know or if i was
here at a campus working you know um i
think one of my my favorite things on
this slide though is this survey from
IBM i don't know why but i love to pick
on IBM for some reason i have no real
reason why but they just always have the
best data for me to pick and this
basically just says that most of their
employees were just completely unaware
of the risk right this which is
interesting when the the thing was the
CIO or the CSO i don't recall which from
IBM came out a few months back and said
you know we're not doing BYOD we have
our reasons and we don't want to do it
and in the rare cases we do it we lock
it down they back off that statement
quite a bit now and they're they're
really broadening it out and because
they're trying to sell solutions to
their customers so they can't say that
it's a bad thing they're trying to sell
illusions so uh but but I think that's
all one how many I don't think we survey
because this last numbers always
surprised me how many apps you have
installed on your mobile phone apps that
didn't ship with with the phone just
yell out some numbers just ballpark 2350
oh crap okay alright so the average here
is a 41 this is the stats about maybe
six months old or so but the average is
41 when i sold this stat when my
marketing guy came and my marketing guy
brings me all these stats and things
like you've got to use this got to talk
about this it's important i'm like i
know i don't want sort of stats out
there i thought this one was interesting
somewhat and surveyed the office and the
office was somewhere around 30 on
average I've 858 I do my entire workflow
my entire life with like 8 apps on my
phone and I'm quite happy with that I
apparently am missing out on some
goodness somebody's got 50 I got to get
a list of that I gotta I gotta
understand what I'm missing all right so
anyway so it's a list a bunch of the
BYOD risk this is the stuff that we hear
people talk about your journalists say
this is what vendors were pitching evil
vendor all that does this resonate it's
a little more comprehensive than what we
talked about earlier with some people
say so let me ask you what about um you
know rooted or jailbroken phones are
those is concerning your enterprise
would you allow a rooted jailbroken
phone to connect to corporate email or
have propia see some nose your nose okay
so what about a non you know company or
organization approved root and fix I'm
going to call that anybody would allow
just say straight up rooted device any
end user to connect I see anybody say
yes so give me some of the guys that
said no why not don't know what's in it
okay so we're back to the uncertainty
thing okay very interesting yeah the
NSA's research is quite interesting so
we work with we work the NSA quite a bit
in CI and there's sampling some of the
stuff that we do and some other stuff is
quite interesting their approach to it
and it some of their stuff only ever
works in the government in that type of
security environment it won't work for
the rest of us in the world but it's
quite awesome i like it quite a bit so
some of these things so the jailbroken
devices at permissions you know this is
AB copying your corporate day
are doing whatever it supposedly does
cloud storage your enterprise lack of
enterprise control talk about that one a
little bit device patching is always an
interesting one we always talk about
patching servers I'm going to talk about
patching you know laptops and
applications I'm just now starting to
see discussions around patching mobile
devices does anybody in here have a
policy on patching mobile devices or you
know thinking about one trying to
develop something around that space ok
let's see much there so this is
interesting because full devices tend to
roll versions much quicker and on us the
adoption rate of a new version is
ridiculously fast I mean users want that
new version and so old versions roll out
pretty quickly so the the risk window is
kind of small so we use a Alex were
there with risk and it's read learn from
Alex and on Android on the other hand
because there's so much fragmentation in
the market and you have some devices are
that are at the lower end of the
spectrum we see the doctor is still
quick but much much slower so device
patching is something that I'm actually
seeing more and more companies concerned
about but how do they make sure that
things are getting it fixed because
we're starting to see attacks against
mobile devices I'm sorry about that on
there was a on Twitter last night if you
follow the normal folks there was some
discussion around a DHS FBI bulletin
about attacks against mobile devices
they're starting to see that and there
were some people like that countered it
like Charlie Miller who's brilliant
brilliant researcher said you know we're
not really seeing it I got a discussion
with Charlie and said Charlie you're you
know I said you know you come from the
spook world Charlie's former NSA I feel
you come from the scoop or do you know
how this game goes there's stuff that we
don't see or we can't talk about that we
do know about on the vendor side that's
happening and this is why you know you
get these early advanced things so there
are some attacks that are happening but
when I serve it most companies most
companies are unaware of any direct
mobile attacks right now trying to
attack the operating system remotely but
infinitely enough it's starting to
become a topic everybody kind of agree
with these risk
any that you would disagree with know
any that you would add to this all right
that must be doing awesome today this is
good oh that's all hand right here legal
discovery yes yes I don't have legal
discovery on here yeah so legal
discovery the big one um I was in the UK
about six months ago and I was at this
event and I got cornered by like 20
people afterwards talking about
ediscovery and forensics and and which
we talked forensics here proper like
chain of custody you know this has to go
to court that kind of thing in the EU is
very very big they're trying to find
solutions for litigation support and
forensic analysis that'll hold up in
court on mobile and they're having
difficulties from what I'm understand
from a lot of the banks so I take us I
take a kind of a different approach to
to some of the my entire career been
much more progressive I say let's find
the progressive solutions let's find how
we can solve problems while moving
everybody forward and let's get the
understanding of the unknown risk then
evaluate what we have to do and so this
is my this is this is slide that my
co-founder uses all the time he calls
his guy Guido I'd love to just meet this
guy get him to come one of my
presentations because he's been in so
many of them at this point call this guy
Guido and the concept here is that
there's old school security and new
school security the old school security
was lock it all down deal with the user
problems afterwards right I'm guilty dad
I've been in this business a very long
time I am guilty of doing that the new
school says let's think about the users
think about the workflow let's address
those things up front the reason why
this is so relevant today is BYOD we as
the enterprise as the employer we don't
own the device now in mobile security in
general we might on the device but we're
seeing a big trend of many companies
moving away from owning very many
devices they might own a couple they
might own some test devices they might
own a couple for you know some employees
here therefore key executives or
whatever but BYOD by large is the mass
mix of the mass of our mobile
deployments so how many of you have more
be why
the devices in your organization then
enterprise own devices ok how many of
the Alpha said way around how do you
have more company owned than buiding
okay a few more hands all right now let
me ask somebody just put up your hands
on now and shout out an answer why do
you have more company own devices than
BYOD devices legacy and do you see that
eroding and going away yep okay and
that's exactly what I hear from most
people is that we did a big investment
we bought beds or we bought good or we
bought whatever we have these devices
and so people just have them but as
they're breaking as their and as new
devices are coming out people are saying
well I want this new fancy device IT
says we can't afford the cost on that we
don't have that but go buy it and find
will we'll hook it up we're seeing that
that creeping in most organizations it's
also a very East Coast West Coast thing
will throw this back to Big E and talk a
little bit here on the East Coast we
actually still see businesses more
conservative around technology more okay
the company owns as a company runs this
on the west coast west coast on the west
coast we have um that's right i throw
gang signs and stuff that's how we do so
how the west coast because so overrun
with technology companies right not to
say companies on the East Coast don't
adopt technology but because so many
companies are technology focused their
early adopters and their liberal hippies
on so they that's just my political rant
the air about San Francisco and they
they tend to say oh do do as you want
you'll bring in whatever device you want
very interesting trend that I that I
watch and I have to remember which coast
on what I'm talking to customers about
that because I go yeah everybody brings
in their own advice and like no no we're
in New York bank we don't allow that
okay interesting up Midwest but there's
a midwest bank as a customer i'm hugely
progressive all about BYOD in the
banking industry and amazes me they're
very very new school what i call new
school all right so um we talk about
trust and YB why would you skip to us
right so there there's some things that
as we enter this market that we have to
say okay we're going to get rid of some
these legacy devices they're going to
die users going to buy new devices
they're not be supporting or whatever it
is they're going to go away users are
going to just you know have a poo and
and take over IT whatever whatever it is
right and so what we understand is that
there's certain things that we have to
be able to do for the company to be able
to trust BYOD first and a lot of that
comes around just the visibility side of
things who is accessing what where are
they accessing it from where is data
going is it stored on the device is it
stored in a nap is it stored to some
cloud service just go through three four
five cloud services right one of the
common use cases that i have that
frustrated me to no end when i was at a
tebow and salesforce and even disney is
my day is packed with meetings right I
am just running between things all day
long and I hate carrying my laptop even
though this you know new Retina is much
lighter and I can go get a macbook air
and it's even lighter I hate carrying it
I want to do everything on one device
and so I have my phone and if I get an
email and it's a purchase order
statement of work or whatever it needs
my signature I want to e sign that I
want to send that back I want to upload
that to whatever system accounting or
purchasing tells me you know where i
have to upload it to i want to send it
to the vendor i want to share my team
you know whatever it via email or
wherever we store those kind of things
all that kind of stuff and i always have
the problem of doing those kind of
things you know before I have all these
little fancy apps but then when company
started restricting what I could do on
my phone then I couldn't do it and it
all came back down to exactly what we
talked about earlier is the lack of
insight even I as the CF so what
basically sat down and said what I allow
anybody else to do this hell no I get to
do it because it's my privilege as its
you know my title and job which is not
fair but that's why I allow myself to do
it bro in law anybody else because I
couldn't figure out where that data was
going I couldn't figure out what apps
they had installed were those apps bad
were they not with a copy my data did it
go to China Russia where was it I don't
know and so this whole visibility is the
big problem that we see that starts the
conversation would be a BYOD in the
enterprise and kind of mobile in general
right and then the kind of the last
thing that we see there though is user
acceptance right so for fortune 500 um
you know we we also have to have user
acceptance of this how many of you get
yelled at probably on a weekly basis but
some irate employee within your
organization for something that
your security did yes I heard more
laughs than hands going up nobody wants
to admit that right it's the dirty
secret we all know it back in the day
right I remember closing out a ticket in
the helpdesk system and I put that it
was a problem between the keyboard in
the chair little did I know the help
desk admin had actually changed it so
Reza ticket resolutions got emailed to
the end user holy i spent some time
with HR over that one but the fact is
that we have to take the user into
account and I'm the first one that's
always like user i don't care i'm gonna
see so it's how it goes oh yeah i
learned my lesson somewhere along the
way probably that day I got yelled at so
bad for that I don't think that was that
bad either but whatever okay and so we
have the other problem here of though
what is a user need so these are the big
concerns that we hear from the users
right it is their privacy their impact
productivity that single user experience
and we're going to that in a second any
other ones you guys get any so those of
you that have rolled out some kind of
mobile solution right now or looking to
roll out and talk to end users you get
any concerns from from your end users no
yes there's some concerns so anybody
yell out what are some of the concerns
that you guys get from your end users
share privacy that's the easy one sits
on the slide deck that's fine that's
fine ok go ahead it's slow interesting
ok you have the performance of it slow
is that just the performance of the
device or of the workflow or both what
security slowing people down ever that
doesn't happen secured I didn't have
this magical it just work so you never
see it anyway that's my average good
don't just go my feature yes that's
that's a good one um yeah I was screwing
around with some of my staff yesterday
while I was traveling and I just kind of
wanted to I'm oops
like give you guys government okay
they're good so we have this policy and
house called eat your own dog food and
so we make everybody in the company use
our product and people will randomly get
moved between different groups and
configurations and our product and so
I'll just randomly grab somebody and
throw them in a new configuration and
let that force down to them see what
that impact is to see how the product
works but also going to really get their
feedback right because I don't believe
in going to a customer and saying hey
yeah everything's right users going to
love this unless I can see what the pain
points are and I allow them to do this
to me as well to be fair so anyway I
just threw some restrictions on
yesterday and holy crap you think I'd
kill somebody's dog um like there was
like a couple features i disabled just
see if they would if they even notice oh
they notice fast um luckily for me I was
on the airplane so I'd have to deal with
it so it's good be in the boss you don't
do things anyway so privacy is the
number one concern that I that I here um
sometimes it's not articulated very well
but inner but you basically say this is
my device I have a two-year contract and
I got a deal from AT&T for you know 399
or 299 over the current prices for an
iphone and why are you installing
something on it why are you doing
something with it what can you do are
you an autumn are you going to
accidentally erase my device all this
kind of stuff and it's a long
conversation ends up having a half of
the users the larger the organization
the less you have to have this
conversation because you're just begging
you don't care and you say eat it and
whatever the smaller the organization
the more you have to do with it deal
with it because they can come and find
you they know where your desk is and so
you have to actually talk about this
that's what I find um and so a we have
to we have to remember that it is the
end user's device it was a Brian cats
had an article published on information
world either yesterday or the day before
the days tend to blur together for me
when I'm traveling but within the last
week he's had an article published that
was great and it said why everybody has
failed to BYOD or like basically hey
guys this is why we've all screwed up
and his whole point you can boil the two
page article down to one point and it's
it's not the enterprise's advice it's
the user's device respect and this is
where the privacy comes in the features
all that kind of things
interesting side note I have determined
that the cost of user privacy is 39
dollars a month that's the cost of it I
have multiple customers that have all
come to me for advice you know because
we we work with a lot of companies that
were in early pilot program and they and
they came to come to us provice and I
was sitting in one of their offices
actually the the same day I name the
company blue box sitting in their office
and I was I was chatting with the
director mobility for the company and he
said yeah my users are pushing back on
on you know enroll in their devices and
I said wine said privacy and I said well
how you gonna get around found that if i
pay for their data plane every month and
see concerns go away someone's I cost
you forty nine dollars price of privacy
forty nine dollars a month so anyway use
that all right so uh speeding through a
couple days here a little bit but um
here's here's where we have an
interesting disconnect right now trying
to meet those enterprise requirements
and the end user requirements
enterprises want to want users use these
enterprise great apps right so
sharepoint interlink citrix watch docs
these sort of things I love watching us
by the way um but employees want to use
you send it box drop its sugarsync
pretty much any one of the fifty
thousand apps that are out in the App
Store's these days they want to be able
to use it interesting story about you
send it a buddy montse ISO of a big
credit agency and they use one of the
container solutions and he said the
containers aren't working I said why
what's up hey and he said well we have
this internal file sharing app because
we don't allow people to you know have
the the files natively on the mode on
their mobile it has to go through the
container and I heard that people were
using yousendit so I called up you send
it and I said hey I heard one of my
users like you want to find out how many
active users we've had in the last 30
days with you know email address at our
domain sales guy falling all over
himself right huge huge customer he'd
see how many users he thinks is a sales
opportunity doesn't realize talking to
the sea so he's got to shut this down
feel bad for the sales guy so sales guy
goes yeah you've had 400 different users
use our service in the last 30 days 400
so I asked my cell how much did you pay
for that container solution said two and
a half million
enterprise-wide very large enterprise
okay but 20 million and just to give you
kind of context so you can put that in
terms of your own enterprise so how much
did you pay her devices on per device
license how much you pay her device he
goes well it lists for 10 a device we
had a huge volume discount at eight I
didn't that was a huge volume just now
but I was like hey that's great twenty
percent awesome no that's that um so
eight dollars per device right across
you know a two million plus and spend
and his data was going around it I asked
my said why our users going around the
container his answer because it didn't
work for them I said so now you have the
sense of security because you have this
container but you found that you have
this risk because data is going around
it so in reality you had a false sense
of security so by implementing this
container you actually created another
security problem he goes yeah 2.5
million dollar security problem awesome
so this is where we have the big
disconnect is that the way we see the
world and waiting and user see the world
is often very very different and we have
to figure out how to bridge that gap and
close them in all right with all of the
risk and all the problems that we have
in the cost of the Audi and mobile
security in the Chinese and our mobile
devices and baseband exploits and all
this good stuff I was worth it what
would you all say if you could if you
could turn back the clock and assume
that v y ou D is not already in your
interview but it would go forward with
adopting a solution yes or no anybody
yes couple how many know okay almost no
nose okay so a lot of you guys aren't
voting on that okay good just check my
math skills today I would do it I would
just because I've learned that it does
create so much more productivity for
myself for end users I would do it but I
would do it with the proper visibility
the proper controls the proper data
tracking and handling right but i would
i would definitely go forward and do
that so let's talk about so we talked
about the we talked about the
the enabling it and the benefits of it
no more kinkos how many guys do this
like when you're traveling where you get
something and you have to go find like a
kinkos or fedex store or something and
actually print something out sign it
figure out how to scan it how to email
that back to your work email get back to
your hotel room login your laptop email
that's somebody's and save to the file
share does anybody else have similar
problems to me okay thank you I'm just
making sure there's not a first-world
problem or as one of my friends calls it
a champagne problem they're like poor
you you're traveling in Europe and you
have to go figure out how to print a
document shut up so I mean friends I've
made friends okay so this is kind of the
the mobile security landscape how many
of you guys reckon recognize these
acronyms at least one or two of them on
here okay all right i got the 20-minute
mark excellent all right so um this kind
of what the mobile security landscape
looks like so we're gonna we're gonna go
through this a little bit about strategy
and what's good and what's and where you
will run into problems so MDM we all
know nvm right is the MobileIron or
watch the zen browser or citrix now
these guys are great at what they do
right there asset management they're
like your land ask your mobile devices
they say yep you have 500 iPhones and
you know 3,000 androids or whatever
usually it's always more iphones um and
I'm going to let you put a passcode on
there I'm going to let you inventory a
it so you know what apps are on there or
what or what you know version it's
running etc right a lot of security and
it's got past come to remote wipe I
don't generally consider the security
myself but I consider just general
configuration features but you know
nothing to protect the data nothing to
protect applications or control
application behavior in pure play nvm
right but they're good at what they do
they're good at the I have a bunch of
devices I need to be able to manage
those I need to be able to wipe those I
need to understand what's in my
environment that's very very important
in my opinion right so that's kind of
convenient play this is i would call v2
on a maturity of mobile v1 was we just
kind of give them to actually I sorry
I'm gonna call this V 2 and a half v1
was we just we give people mobile
devices and we don't really think about
it kind of v2 or count
be one and a half was okay yellow some
view ID let's lock it down via
activesync or whatever and then we kind
of get a proper strategy in two ND
ambient that's where we started actually
paying attention when we had these
vendors out there the next week
container so these are the goods of the
world right the company that keeps
reinventing itself and will never die
because of litigation because they have
so much pee in their parent company
they're awesome IP attorneys just by the
way if you ever get sued by good be
careful their parent company is just
awesome it's where they actually make
all their money it's quite interesting
to read if you see who they're suing
these days so the in theory the great
thing about this is that it's a
container you have your work email you
have your work calendar it's all this
low container I can't get out at can't
escape but as we saw with the yousendit
example it does escape also a black hat
Europe there was just a talk I felt bad
for the container guys it was just a
talk that basically destroyed all the
containers and showed that hey look they
the great other I don't I don't to go as
far as to say their security theater one
of those researchers might have said
that I'm so I'm not going to say it but
you know they they pretty much said hey
look there's a problem here it's a naive
state so that was really interesting but
they're great in theory and they will
improve and it's kind of said it forget
it but it doesn't allow the user to
maintain their workflow the apps they
need it still causes some problems this
is where we saw a very small interest in
the market called ma'am mobile
application management there was three
four companies that played in this space
and their idea was that instead of
controlling device control the
applications cuz that's ideally where
the data is and why do you care about
the actual device I tend to kind of
agree with this strategy i think the the
strategy depends on your organization
and your risk profile but for many
organizations this does actually make
sense the problem is that the ma'am
market never matured nocona and wraps
fear got acquired before they went big
actually before they launched app
central got acquired by another company
because they were stalling the market
this market actually never matured kind
of unfortunate our IP in this is quite
mature we're not a man player so it's
interesting that this market never
really really evolved
to the potential everybody thought that
it would have but the idea was taste
take an app from from a vendor go to go
to since they use box we want to secure
it hit their unsigned binary put it in
your custom app store tell your users to
download that one if you integrate them
your single sign-on and you know sam'l
and whatever's right and it would have
security control policies around it
right it's a wrapper around around the
code and so the idea was great there was
business scale problem you problem it
rang kind of a month but it was probably
one of the most hyped things in and BYOD
for a very very long and then the last
one you have is a private ation this
goes to to the malware and malicious
apps which most people here didn't seem
to really think was the problem kudos to
you because it's not a huge problem
right now it eventually will be just
like anything else we can see kind of
the trend we can see devices becoming
more and more open right people are
pushing for more more control their
devices as that as that progresses we'll
see more and more malware and malicious
apps progress as well but it's not there
yet this is years off at this point
though it though it is starting to come
so that's our landscape right now right
but what we need and what we need to
make sure that we're doing no matter
what spooked when we go with and whether
we're docked in BYOD or really mobile in
general in my opinion is that we need to
make sure that we're applying our
controls and our believe disability is
is the key really to hear because this
is a space where we have no visibility
you know we have these vendor lock
devices and we get no visibility and so
we need to make sure that wherever data
is whether it's on the device crossing
the network going into an appt out of an
app to a cloud service back and forth
that we're able to track that we can
actually understand what a user is doing
who that is what device that is what
data the context of that data right now
that it's just corporate data because as
we all know from our failed dlp
implementations because you know there's
a cup of you that did the same thing
we're like dlp let's buy it let's just
throw it at everything holy crap this is
a flood of information let's back it
down and restart right we all did that
not all corporate data is equal right
the the jpeg is attached to your email
signature you don't really care about
securing but the word file that will
attached there that had the new
company's strategy or had your audit
findings that you care about right and
so not all data is is equal so we need
to apply a risk-based approach just like
we do in other areas of our business
right now so understanding all of that
across wherever the data is wherever the
applications are ever the device is
being able to log on portal mat so that
we can understand it and then obviously
the the user empowerment empower the
users to be able to use the applications
that they need that make them productive
and actually honestly make as easier
right because the let the more users can
do for themselves unless we ever have to
talk to them which is my goal I don't
want to talk to users all right so this
is something I solved from pwc a while
back and I just put in here and
basically just says that you know from
mobile you need to have a an approach
that works on any device across
everything and it's great there was
another PwC quote that I talk about
sometimes because I thought it was
complete another bullsh the first time I
read it and then it was probably out a
week later that I sat down and I just
happened to see it pop up in an article
somewhere and I go actually that was
true and it basically said that mobile
and BYOD is one of the biggest
fundamental shifts in enterprise IT that
we've seen in many years and they put it
all the way back to personal computers
I'm not sure I'm ready to say that quite
yet but it is a huge huge shift with the
whole bring your own device bring your
own technology the consumerization of IT
and corporate data makes this a very
very interesting time an interesting
space where we actually have to start to
think differently because the game has
really changed like we have to take a
different approach neck because we can't
lock down a device that we don't own up
and we have to figure out though how to
understand the unknown how to protect
the data and how to apply our controls
I'm glad you guys three all three of
them said those because I just that
rolls really well into my presentation
all right so we're coming up close to
the end of time but I want to leave some
time for some questions you guys are not
a chatty group but i encourage you to be
so because i like it any questions or
just comment anybody you can raise your
hand you can yell out I'm good either
way alright so they give me the
five-minute warning i'll slip in one
more any questions before lunch
alright nothing is it