alright welcome everybody thank you for
coming out today um I have the highly
desired after lunch slot so I'll try to
keep you guys awake as much as possible
so first order to start off with a
little little survey how many pen
testers are in here today raise your
hand okay good number network security
background raise your hand application
security okay now are you now or have
you ever been a developer all right
that's good to know what about managers
managerial roles got a few all right
well the good news is that this is going
to apply to all of you so more more
sensitive developers but really it
applies across the board because it's
about how to change the behavior of the
development organization so yesterday we
heard about you know a lot of the new
security features of html5 and some some
novel attacks on that today we're going
to focus a little bit more on the
development side of things how you as a
developer or as a development
organization can really make a
difference in the quality of the
software that you produce and and how
that affects security so here's a quick
overview and I'm going to just jump
right into the introduction and then
cover some software security basics to
make sure everybody's on the same page
and we're going to talk about some
common application vulnerabilities now
hopefully none of these are going to be
news to any of you what's what's
important here is to focus on how we fix
that what what can we do to actually not
just address the to kill the exploits
but the actual root cause the
vulnerabilities that lead to these
exploits and we'll show some code
examples and then we'll take a step back
and talk about how can we build this
into the software development lifecycle
at the organizational level at the
process level so just a few words about
digital I work for four digital which is
a software consultant software of
security consulting firm we were founded
in nineteen ninety-two which is
a good while ago in this industry
certainly and we started on the software
quality side and we've now moved into
software security and almost you know
ninety-five percent of what we do is
application security and software
security whatever you want to call it
and we've written a lot of books yadda
yadda yadda not me personally all the
other sharp guys it's digital like a
like Gary and everybody else so they're
they're doing great there so and I know
there's a couple of former or current
developers in here so no offense but why
are most programmers bad at security
well it's usually it's it's simply not
part of their job description they are
not there they're focused on very
different things than security
professionals they're usually under time
pressure they're focused on adding new
functionality adding new features and
they're not the incentives are not there
to really help them be successful at
creating reliable secure software a lot
of times design of a system and
development of a system is very much
focused on the positive path the if
statements not the else statements what
is the expected behavior and a lot of
times when I tell a programmer okay well
you've got this vulnerability here and
you know an attacker could could type
something in here well our users
wouldn't do that that that's not how
it's designed to be used so there's a
lot of focus on what the expected
behavior is versus what some alternate
ways are of abusing the system and
really the bottom line is that input
validation is much harder than it looks
on the surface especially doing it the
correct way which is white listing and
I'll talk some more about that so
basically what we have right now is that
most of what qualifies as IT security
was actually bolted on way late and
development cycle it's it's either its
pen testing just before go live it's you
know slapping a firewall in front of it
slapping an IDs in front of it just to
see if you can catch some of the things
but it really doesn't address the
underlying problem so what you end up
with
you have short term protection that's
sort of limited in scope so a better
approach is to really think about
security from the beginning to build it
into your development lifecycle so you
start with security requirements you ask
the right questions during the
requirements gathering phase you ask
business owners what is this software
designed to do what what are the
security implications of that are we
storing any sensitive data and all of
those types of things and then you bake
that into your design into your
architecture and into your code
eventually and then of course you test
it as you would any requirement and so
what you what you get with this approach
is robust long-term security because one
of the things that you know a lot of
times developers don't think about it
this way but you actually have a lot of
power because you as the developer are
creating the rules of engagement that
any attacker has to play by if you
design the lockout mechanism and you do
it the correct way the attacker what
won't be able to get around it they're
going to have to play by your rules to
get into your system so there's actually
quite a bit of power that the developer
has these are the seven areas where
things most likely will go wrong in any
particular application I've already
mentioned input validation there are
multiple different ways of representing
input in in any context think about URL
encoding HTML entity encoding all these
different ways of representing data
Unicode all these different things so
API abuse is another one so having you
know this again comes back to our users
wouldn't do that api's are often
designed for one thing but they can also
be called by by other third parties by
other people that they weren't designed
to be called by and used in different
ways that are unexpected security
features can actually be a detriment if
they're not implemented correctly and of
course there's time and state race
conditions temp files that are created
that can lead to issues we have standard
error handling can either be too verbose
or
it can ignore some some failures
silently that just you know are not that
leads to unexpected behavior down the
road standard code quality issues memory
leaks things like that and encapsulation
having strong boundaries between your
data inside the application in the case
of object-oriented programming you know
having the correct private variables and
so forth so here's just a quick recent
example of a pis and this has become
more of an issue as web services have
become more popular because as we heard
yesterday you know most Twitter Facebook
they're all accessible both via the
front end and via the API and a lot of
times if those two are not in sync if
the security mechanisms are not
consistently enforced across those two
you can end up with issues that an
attacker can abuse so I know a couple of
years ago yahoo had an issue where they
were not enforcing a password lock out
on their API so if you went to the yahoo
front page and you tried a whole bunch
of different passwords you would get
locked out after a few attempts but if
you did the same thing via their API you
could bang away as long as you wanted to
and people were actively exploiting that
to crack a week yahoo account passwords
so now we're going to dive into the
vulnerabilities and again these are all
well known vulnerabilities but the focus
here is on on fixing them and I'll just
give a brief description of each of them
to make sure everybody's on the same
page and a lot of this material is um
owasp is a great resource for anything
application security software security
related and they have a lot of good
resources there so we're going to talk
about unvalidated input injection flaws
cross-site scripting cross-site request
forgery what the difference is between
those two improper error handling broken
access control and insecure storage so
can anybody tell me just shout it out is
does this look like a good idea does
this look like a good way it can ever
everybody can read that does this look
like a good way of taking an input
parameter and if not what could be the
possible issues here good exactly so
that's exactly one of my examples an
attacker if you're not validating this
correctly they can actually access
internal hosts on your network right
through through the front with the
public-facing web server potentially or
they can use it to browse of files that
are present on on the local server where
that application is hosted so it's very
important to think about what the
intended uses of that code and to
validate that input accordingly so thank
you for that it was almost like I
planted you in the audience so so what
do we do about it well actually first
let me take a step back first we have to
realize that you know and most of you
I'm sure already know this but the
attacker can tamper with any part of the
query string talking about the URL
itself the query string anything that's
part of their initial request coming in
headers cookies it should be considered
tainted untrusted data and of course
there's a whole long list of attacks
that rely on on poor input validation
but usually it comes down to two things
either filtering is implemented as a
blacklist or The Improv validation and
believe it or not we still see this all
the time it sounds so obvious but a lot
of times improv validation is either
only performed at the client or it's
inconsistent it's it's not the same
validation is not performed on the
server as on the client and you know
some people still think that a drop-down
or a bit of javascript is a good way to
perform input validation which is great
from a UI perspective it really makes it
easier to use but it has no security
value so this is a bit of a dated
example from 09 but I just love it so I
wanted to point it out real quick Time
Warner Cable had these neat little boxes
that they would give all their customers
65,000 of them and it had it used
JavaScript to hide admin functionality
turned out that if you just disable
JavaScript
your browser you could then see the
admin functionality without any password
and even better you could download the
configuration file for the router but
wait there's more it had the plaintext
admin password and username and password
in it and it was the same hard-coded
across all of the devices they deployed
so um I mean it's and this is I mean
this is out this was out there just a
few years ago and I'm sure it still is
today so we keep seeing the same
mistakes over and over again and yeah
here's a little little description of
what happened there okay so what can we
do about it as as a developer as a
development organization what can we do
about it all input needs to be validated
on the server and it should be done by
whitelisting so there's a couple of
different things that you want to check
and only if that input passes all of
those checks should it be allowed to
proceed so you can check things like the
data type are you expecting a string a
date and integer check the Mac minimum
and maximum length and whether for
example whether or not a 0 null value or
blank value is allowed and if it's a
number check the numeric range to make
sure that it's within whatever the
expected value is and of course a lot of
this falls under this last category
which is there's there's well known data
formats phone numbers zip codes dates
email addresses those are easy they have
known format you can whitelist validate
that with a regular expression and
there's anything extra in there you
reject the input whatever you do do not
strip out anything don't don't try to
look for bad characters and strip them
out there's all kinds of ways that that
can go wrong and that can get abused so
always just if there's anything
unexpected if it doesn't pass the reg ex
just throw an error and don't abuse
hidden fields uh just there's there
should be one cookie that your web app
uses and that's the session cookie
that's it don't store anything else and
hidden fields cookies anywhere else
stored in a session variable that lives
on the server that the attacker can't
mess with
and so here's a quick java code example
very simple about how to do date
validation so you can see first we've
separated out the validation logic so
that's just from a low design
perspective is a good idea and it might
be a little hard to read because it's
great but it's at the bottom here you
can see the regular expression it starts
with a carrot which is important because
that means match the beginning of the
string so there's any extra characters
at the beginning it's not going to pass
and it ends with a dollar sign which
means match the end of the string and so
forth and so four digits dash two digits
dash two digits so standard sequel
year-month-day format and only if it
matches return true and otherwise throw
an exception and and obviously error
handling should be done via exceptions
not via you know true false return
values and so forth so simple example
but you'd be amazed as you know how many
people still get this wrong day to day
so moving on to injection flaws so of
course the most well-known of these is
sequel injection and this again is a
very simple PHP example where queries
being built from a string concatenation
to user-supplied variables all the
attacker has to do is enter admin single
quote for one equals 1 comment out the
rest of the query and sure enough they
change the structure of the query and
now now you're no longer in control of
your database command because they've
they can now inject anything they want
and so obviously it'll authenticate in
most cases and sometimes you even get
lucky and it dumps the entire contents
of the user table and you get a list of
all the all the valid user names so in
general injection flaws can really occur
anywhere where there's an interpreter
involved so that can be Perl Python
JavaScript of course sequel anytime you
have an external shell that it's calling
a command shell if you do an operating
system calls database systems and of
course half
so when you're calling when you're
building strings to access system files
so I'm going to use a few screenshots
there was a recent web app pen test that
I was involved in and we found a single
command injection vulnerability in a
third party tool kit image processing
tool kit and this allowed us to run
shell commands unprivileged as the web
web server user essentially the apache
user and but eventually we were able to
use that through a sequence of events we
were able to use that to gain admin
access shell access to the server
because of some other configuration
mistakes that they have made so I'm
going to use a couple of screenshots
from this to show some examples so
here's the first example it's probably
really hard to read but basically in the
URL up top i injected LS dash LH read
just by appending a semicolon and then
LS LH and also cranked up the debug
level 29 the highest value and so we can
see the result here that it shows the
the LS output there and we were able to
use that and I'll show another example
later of how we got additional access
from that but it's basically just it's
poor designed they weren't validating
the parameter correctly they were
expecting a number but actually they
allowed me to put in an entire command
string there so what what can you do
about injection flaws in general you
want to try to avoid external
interpreters whenever possible so for
example in the Java world if you're
trying to send mail from inside a Java
program don't use runtime that eggs act
to call send mail use the Java mail API
instead always make sure that you encode
special characters before you send it to
the back end and that depends of course
on what you're sending it to semicolons
and back ticks are sensitive in the
context of shell commands single quotes
obviously in sequel statements but for
that is actually better to use
parameterised queries and you know
know how that goes and i'll show a quick
example on the next slide here very
important to run the external
application with limited privileges you
may want to have a separate account you
don't give you can run it under the web
server user but it's probably a better
idea to have to yet another separate
user account just for those back-end
applications that can't access anything
else very limited privileges make sure
that you check all the output return
codes and error codes from the third
party application so that if there's
anything unexpected you stop your throne
error and don't proceed so here's a very
quick example of a PHP parameterised
query or what they call a prepared
statement and so again you set up the
structure of the query this is the same
example that I showed before PHP has a
kind of a neat feature where you can
actually name the parameters it's not
just positional you can actually assign
different names to them and then you
call the to bind functions there you
bind the values to them and then you you
execute the statement and it's really as
simple as that and when you're doing
that bind it automatically knows that
anything in that string needs to be
escaped so you see at the bottom here
that it actually puts a backslash in
front of the single quote which means
it's just part of the string and so that
request would obviously fail because
there's no user that's named admin
single quote or one equals one and I
mentioned owasp they have a lot of these
great resources they call them cheat
cheats they have it for across that
scripting for Caesar for query
parameterization so there's a link to it
they have a you know examples in
probably a dozen different languages of
how to do this in your environment so
just a quick reference makes it easy so
we hear a lot of our cross-site
scripting cross-site request forgery
most of you are probably familiar with
it but I'm just going to cover the
difference is real quick and add to kind
of show how they relate to each other
cross-site scripting injects content
into an existing page while SI sirve
takes an action on behalf of the user
that's currently logged in now xss can
often be used to launch see serve and it
makes for a much more powerful
surf attack once you have crossed over
into that trust boundary and you've here
in in the in the same code base as as
the mid native JavaScript so here's two
quick examples pretty pretty
straightforward cross-site scripting
posting you know a comment for example
to a message board and injecting some
script tags into that and here is a
example of adding a friend adding the
attacker as a behind the victims back so
to speak adding them as a friend on
their social network so they can see
their contacts so cross-site scripting
basically the attacker injects malicious
code into the web page it's sent to the
browser and the browser basically just
assumes that that part is that code is
part of the web page and runs it and
that script now has access to any of the
same cookies session tokens anything
else that's stored you know in that in
that context for the domain you've got
reflected and stored cross-site
scripting on the other hand see surf so
another way of looking at the difference
between these two is to say that
cross-site abuses or miss uses the trust
of the user in the application while see
surf is the other way around it abuses
the trust of the application in the user
because it thinks that the user is
actually taking an action that the user
didn't intend to take and cross-site
scripting misuses the trust of the user
because they think that the
functionality that they're seeing is
built into the web application or they
may not see the functionality but it's
really not intended to behave that way
so cross I see surf is a good example of
Caesar is basically making an
unauthorized request on behalf of an
authenticated user such as initiating a
bank transfer without them being aware
of it so and you know the simplest way
to launch see serve is to just to put a
link in an image tag and when that image
is loaded the get URL is is accessed and
and that's you know that's easy to
defend against a more sophisticated see
sort of attacks that are very difficult
to defend against are the ones that are
launched to be a cross-site scripting
because then now you have full sort of
interactive program
ability you can you can make a get
request you can get the token back you
can post the token with the next request
so it makes it a lot harder to defend
against that so again what can we do
about it is this this is really where
boils down to again I'm going to say it
again input validation it's if you do
you interpret validation right and if
you do whitelisting then it's going to
stop most of these attacks just in case
you missed something you want to also
use output and coding as a fallback and
this is going to be dependent on the
context of where you're putting this
this output if you're putting it into a
HTML context it's going to be different
encoding and if you're putting into a
JavaScript or CSS stylesheet context and
so and for example jquery has an encoder
library that that does that has
different functions you can call to to
do exactly that see sort of prevention
as i mentioned is a little bit trickier
because you can prevent the simple
simple attacks just by using a token so
that every form you know has a unique
value associated with it or every
request actually has a unique value
associated with it and if that value is
not included in the next request then
you just discard the request but it
doesn't doesn't help you if the attacker
is actually exploiting another
vulnerability such as cross-site
scripting to get inside the application
so really the strongest defense and this
this is very much dependent on what
you're trying to defend if I mean if
it's if it's a sensitive transaction
like a bank transfer then you would
probably want to go to this length to
make sure that it is the user who is
intending on performing this action so
you can do things like CAPTCHA which we
all know has some issues but it's
nonetheless you know effective if you
want to go you know even further along
the spectrum you can reap romp the user
for their password and again you would
only want to do this obviously for you
know in the cases where it's very
sensitive transaction and of course you
can use something like a one-time
password secure ID to to basically do a
per-transaction authentication
and here is it's actually a very short
example basically a one-liner if you're
doing in asp.net it has this this
built-in mechanism called view state
which is was never really designed as a
security feature but it's designed to
track form values across different
requests and it checks automatically by
design the framework checks the
integrity of that cookie with every
request and so if you simply set the
current session ID to be the key for the
viewstate then it will automatically
perform this validation for you so it's
great in the sense that you don't have
to have any external libraries you're
not making any major code changes to
your application but there's a few
issues with it because this requires you
to put basically a code hook into each
page this is done on a per page basis
and so it's easy to forget to put one in
there especially we have a big web
application and it's even more of a pain
to audit and having to check this across
you know the application and the
developer can either intentionally or
unintentionally disable this feature and
and then there's also some issues with
load balancing because the session IDs
are not always replicated across the
servers so up so this is a great sort of
quick and dirty solution that's going to
get you you know eighty percent of the
way there but it's not sort of the the
best solution so owasp has has three
projects that are all related to each
other that are SI sirve guard in net
java and PHP and what did this does
basically is it allows you to handle
this token management creation and
checking of the token transparently to
the programmer and transparently to the
user so you can handle it you basically
set up a central configuration file that
hooks into the web server and then with
every request it figures out whether or
not it needs to include a token it puts
the token in there and then it checks it
on the following requests and there's a
link in here to to their 20 wasp for
more information so improper error
handling so if you have um if you're
giving the attacker too much information
in an error message that can really give
them a lot of clues of
out how to attack your application and
how to mess with it and so examples of
this obviously stack traces database
dumps specific error codes for Java JSP
compilation errors that may have full
paths in them if you're giving an
inconsistent error message you know
access denied versus found not found or
invalid username versus invalid password
and so forth and of course the knowledge
service and also you always have to
watch out with error messages if you're
repeating any user input back to to the
user that can lead to a reflective
cross-site scripting attack because it
might allow if you're not validating it
it might allow the user to to inject
input content there so how do you how do
you handle this you want to make sure
that in your application you're defining
clear and consistent error handling a
centralized error handling mechanism is
usually the best approach you want to
make sure that you give the user short
but meaningful error messages that are
actionable and you want to log more
detailed information on the backend that
only the admin would be able to access
so you don't want to give useful
information for an attacker stack traces
detailed exceptions that sort of thing
and you want to make sure that you're
catching specific exceptions and
handling them as best as you can within
the application logic don't just catch
everything at the top level and throw a
generic error but you do want to make
sure that as a fallback you catch you
put a general catch block at the very
top level so if you missed anything that
it gets caught there and you don't end
up with a stack trace it's also a good
idea to modify the default error pages
that your web server defines so another
issue that we see a lot is that access
control is not applied consistently and
this comes back to what I was talking
earlier about the viewstate because a
lot of times access control is
implemented with coat hooks so if you
forget one of those then you know 99 of
your pages might be okay but there's one
out there where the programmer just
forgot to put the authentication check
into it so there's you know insecure IDs
if you can guess sequential numbers of
some sort
you know if you know a particular URL
you might be able to force browse past
that path traversal and client-side
caching can also be an issue if you
don't disable caching for sensitive
information so home you know as I
mentioned homegrown authorization
schemes are usually not a good idea
because it can lead to exactly that
issue of missing one particular page or
one particular part of the application
and so here's here's a good example of
this was part of that same pen test that
i mentioned earlier if you just went to
server name / logs you could actually
see a copy of the access log in the
error log from apache there which would
disclose you know all of the IP
addresses that have accessed that server
you could see all the different urls
that were valid on that server that you
may not have known about otherwise so
it's really a gold mine of information
for an attacker so what's what's the
mitigation approach here access
permissions should be checked with every
request and so there you want to make
sure that it's consistently applied that
that there's not a chance of missing one
of these access control checks by doing
it in a centralized way which is easy to
do if you don't roll your own access
control so for example on the Java side
spring security has has a wide range of
features that let you define how you
want to perform authorization checking
and its declare difference that our
programmatic so you're not relying on
putting putting coat hooks in you're
managing all in one place and then other
other things to look out for is you want
to make sure you using HTTP headers to
set the caching behavior for sensitive
information so that's not stored by the
browser and on the server side you want
to make sure that you're using OS
security to protect sensitive data there
and then in secure storage so you know
this is a laundry list of things that
will go wrong and we hear about this all
the time with with the various data
breaches out there you know not
encrypting critical data not encrypting
cups storing keys in securely I mean a
lot of people seem to not have heard
about these things called h SMS hardware
security modules and so they're just
storing all these sensitive keys on on
the file system right next to the
private key next to the public key you
know and it's just it's the problem has
been solved but enough people are still
not using the correct solutions poor
sources of randomness or or poor
algorithms invent inventing your own
algorithm I would still see that and
fail in if you do so we're even if
you're using a well known algorithm
failing to design the system so that it
can easily handle the key changes or
other you know cryptographic maintenance
procedures or revocation and things like
that so here this is the another
screenshot from that web app pen test I
mentioned so in this case I simply
injected the command grep I our MySQL
dot so it looked for the string MySQL in
any of the the files under the current
folder and sure enough it found the
mysql user name and password which you
may notice that it might be hard to read
but it says root so they were using the
mysql root account um and it got even
better because lo and behold that same
password that they use for the mysql
root account worked for ssh for the
system root account so just with that
one command it was it was game over
essentially so again it's you know what
why are we there's multiple issues here
but it comes down to storing the
password and securely and reusing the
same password across for two very
different purposes so how do we fix it
only store data that you absolutely have
to store so for example if you're if you
if your users typically don't have a lot
of transactions they maybe buy from you
once or twice a year you know you might
actually be better off asking them to
re-enter their credit card information
each time instead of taking all the
liability of storing thousands of credit
cards on your servers
and you also for any sensitive
information that you're storing or just
in general you don't want to allow any
direct channels to the backend servers
so you don't want to give people even
you know you even want to limit this
internally as much as possible the
developers obviously need access to to
the database to troubleshoot but you
want to make sure that that is screened
off as much as possible so that only the
people who need access to those systems
can directly get to them everybody else
has to go through the official system
which will have the audit trail and
everything else that you can you can
follow in case something happens and we
saw the screenshot earlier of the log
data in the web server root don't store
anything in the web server root that
doesn't belong there that's not intended
for public consumption log files debug
test code unused frameworks and just get
rid of all that stuff only put
production code in the web server root
and of course don't roll your own crypto
but we already know that so wanted to
take a couple of minutes to talk about
kind of taking a step back and talk
about what this means in terms of the
broader security development lifecycle
so there's a lot of different you know
things out there a lot of different
methodologies for securing the
development lifecycle so Microsoft has
had their sdl for for a long time and
and they've you know depending on who
you ask that has worked out pretty well
for them I certainly say that you know
current windows is more secure than
previous versions of Windows Digital has
has these touch points and I'll talk
about that in a second that basically
lets you focus on what are the
activities that you should be
incorporating into your development
lifecycle regardless of with what
methodology you're using and then
there's a wasp clasp which is a again to
be designed to be a lightweight process
that doesn't impose sort of a specific
methodology
so a little bit more about the touch
points so the touch points are really a
way to adapt security to whatever
existing methodology you might be using
because let's face it there are there
are a couple of subjects that are
completely taboo with any developer
religion politics and development
methodology you don't mess with that and
so a lot of these methodologies that say
you must do waterfall or you must do
agile they're not going to work because
most organizations use some hybrid
approach they have their own methodology
already in place and they're not going
to want to pick they're not going to
want to break that just to adopt a more
secure way of doing things so the touch
points here are basically a way to say
okay at which points in the process and
these these boxes that you see at the
bottom basically exist in any
methodology you're going to have
requirements you're going to have
architecture and design have a test plan
every the one the one thing that every
development effort produces is code
testing and test results and then what
feedback from the field once it's
deployed and so you know again we want
to start with our abuse cases we want to
think of the ways that the system can be
abused and then security requirements we
want to make sure that we're asking the
right questions as I mentioned before
and risk analysis so we need to be
thinking about what are the risks that
our application has what are the
possible abuse cases there and then as
we're generating our test plans we want
to make sure that we're testing those
risks that we identified that we're
developing test cases for that and then
once we where the stage of generating
code we want to perform code review and
the key here is to do it as early in the
process as possible so once you've
reached integration testing or once
you're you know close to going to
production that's almost too late
because in some cases that could be
months or years from from the time that
you started developing the software and
a lot of the people who wrote the code
may not be around anymore so then you
have the situation of trying to fix
somebody else's code and it's always
extreme I mean I go back and look at my
own code from two years ago I can barely
read it much less somebody else's code
so it's very important to push that code
review as early in the process as
possible and so one of the ways to do
that is to basically give developers
sort of a spell check tool that will
catch a lot of the low-hanging fruit as
soon as they check a new version into
svn or whatever the reap whatever repo
they're using and give them an idea of
where those where those potential issues
are now from what we've seen of that
that's not quite as effective as looking
at you know an integrated system and
doing doing end-to-end testing but it
catches about sixty to seventy percent
of the issues that you would later find
and it's much much cheaper much easier
to fix those things early in the
development process when the developer
is still working on it they're still
around they know the code they just
looked at it yesterday so they know how
to fix it tomorrow and and so that makes
it gives a lot more context for the
developer rather and and the important
thing is to do this inside of their IDE
you don't want to throw 100 page PDF
report at them and say oh you've got all
these problems all these sequel
injection cross-site scripting go fix it
it's much better to provide them you
know context specific advice right in
their familiar development environment
and so once we get to the testing stage
again we're doing more risk analysis
because now we're thinking we're making
sure we have everything covered and
we're coming up with more test cases and
we make sure that we're doing closing
the feedback loop there and then of
course pen testing enters the arena so
you know pen testing a lot of times
people see it kind of as the end-all
be-all oh yeah we're going to we're
going to write the code we're going to
test it then we're going to a quick pen
test and then we're going to roll to
production done and you know really the
pen test is kind of a last resort it's
it's what did you miss if you're
building security into the into this
process what did you miss earlier in the
process it's it's it's a safeguard
basically and then of course that
continues on through deployment are you
going to do another pen test a repeated
pen testing of the production system
every year or whatever the requirements
are and then make sure that your main
the system securely during your daily
operations and that you create things
like you know security operations
manuals that tell people you know the
things that they should be watching out
for as they're interacting with the
system day to day and so besom is is an
initiative that citadels started a
couple of years ago that is fairly
unique because unlike a lot of models
out there it doesn't just kind of say
here's what we think you should do in
terms of software security because we've
spent a lot of time thinking about this
and we know worked with quite a few
people it's actually based on real
software security initiatives out there
and so you see all the names on the on
the screen here these are all
participants you know obviously some
heavy hitters here these are all
participants in the besom program along
with you know a lot of other companies
there's 51 total companies that that are
participating in vcm and it's now in its
fourth iteration and there are a hundred
and eleven different measurements that
that it different parameters different
activities that it asks each each of
those participants about and the the
unique thing there is that we we ask
them not what do you think you should be
doing in terms of application security
you know what are you planning on doing
but what are you doing today and and and
then we ask questions around how is it
working what are the metrics and so
forth so that you can get a good idea of
not only where you rank compared to your
peers but also what what your next step
should be to improve your your software
security posture so here's here's a
quick overview I mentioned 111
measurements they're divided into four
domains governance intelligence the
touch points and deployment and you can
see all these different activities that
fall into those boxes and you know for
example pen testing falls under
deployment
we talked you know we talked a lot about
the touch points the architecture
analysis the code review and the
security testing piece of it and so
basically the way to think of this is
that you know if you're if you're an
organization and you want to find out
what should I be doing to to improve the
state of my my software security here's
a blueprint based on what 51 very well
respected companies are actually doing
and have done in the past that has
worked for them so it's very much an
empirical approach to it and it lets you
make sure that you're you know sort of
keeping up with the state of the art so
in conclusion I'm going to say this one
more time build security in so you
really have to think about security in
your development lifecycle from day one
bold on solutions don't work and pen
testing right before you go live is it's
really just a you know an exercise in
futility because you're never going to
have time to fix all the things that
you're going to find if that's the first
time your pen testing so most developers
are not incentivized for security they
are very much focused on implementing
new functionality and features and you
know we really have to make sure that
we're speaking their language when we're
bridging the gap we don't want to talk
about exploits and vulnerabilities we
want to talk about bugs and fixes and
input validation is the root of all evil
really it really is i mean if if you can
get good whitelist validation working
that that quashes you know seventy
eighty percent of what's out there in
terms of ways that attackers can mess
with your system and output encoding is
is always going to be your fallback
because just in case you missed
something then you can make sure that
it's sort of defanged when it gets
output back to the user so I'm getting
the STFU sign so I let's take this
offline thanks everybody for coming out
I appreciate the time
you