alright I guess we'll go ahead and get
started I hope everybody had their
coffee this morning since we're here to
talk about the ever exciting topic of
afisma I see I've drawn a very large
crowd but a it's alright we're against
the solid competition when someone's
dropping some tool and CTF is going on
i'm happy to have some people that want
to hear me talk about the the pros and
cons of afisma and I'll going to try to
keep this exciting a little bit
interactive I've studied up on all the
different security presentations I've
been given at the various conferences i
think i have a winning formula to keep
your attention you know some some good
content some funny jokes and then
putting pictures of animals it seems to
be the winning combination so this is an
overview of what we're going to cover
today just really briefly we'll talk
about who we are talk about why this
talk go into a little bit about fisma
101 but before i get started just since
we're a small audience here just a raise
of hands how many of you deal with fisma
on a day-to-day basis okay how many have
no idea what FISMA is who can spell
fisma so we'll go about some of the good
points of bhisma some of the bad points
about FISMA Andrews going to talk about
from an organizational perspective how
the challenges he's had to have with
introducing implementing technology and
security into his organization in order
to comply with FISMA standards and we'll
talk a little bit from assessment point
of view just to give you an overview of
what goes on in a typical FISMA
assessment who we are real quickly
senator national this is my company
based on Northern Virginia we do do a
lot FISMA work but just real quick my
passion is not bhisma it's uh it's
really in the the I gaming sector so if
you're really interested in that I
I would love to speak to you about about
online gambling and we're always looking
to hire people both on the FISMA side
but also on the technical side I can do
web app reverse engineering security
code reviews etc etc so here's our first
picture of our funny animal we're going
to start off slow with just a cat but
you know typical disclaimer these are
our own views do not express the views
of I guess our company my company you
know we like to do fisma work i guess
and we still may want to keep on doing
that for at least the next couple years
so i'm gonna try not to excuse me it
fisma does pay the bills but we'll talk
a little bit about that as well does not
pay it as well as it used to pay the
bills this is me CTO of senate
international I do know more about fisma
and cna than I tend to like to omit you
know if you've done this type of work
I'm sure you got drawn into these
conversations about what control does
this vulnerability map up to as a CM six
as a cm7 you know and I can't tell you
how many hours I've wasted arguing with
people about that in my mind is really
not important the important thing is
that you discover a born bill you've
mapped it back to specific control but
we'll talk about some of those you know
if you want to give me a file on Twitter
I appreciate it I mainly tweet about the
security issues and and online gambling
so then we have Andrew here say Oh up in
his Andruw too so my backgrounds a
little bit different than Gus's i'm
actually a former software developer so
i'll be sort of giving you an overview
from the from the implementers
perspective on what it took to to
certify a federal application over
shared infrastructure so um that's
that's a look i mean it's it's a it's a
lot more intricate than it sounds so
actually um so what so we had to
basically certify a major application
over not only shared infrastructure but
actually having to deal with a mixed
codebase nested applications and so on
so it's my best advice and if you if
your if your encounter with something
like that is just too
just to have a lot of faith and don't be
afraid all right thanks and answer is
going to touch into some of those
concepts that he talked about during his
portion of it so why this talk no one's
from a department commerce here right
okay good I'm not going you know this is
really not going to be a Jack Daniels
get up here and bash on pci or some
regulatory standard talk at least i hope
not because i do think and we'll talk
about phys most good points i think it
does have a lot of good points there's
some negative points as well and we'll
touch on those but really you know this
third bowl i think it's important
because even if you're not directly
dealing with bhisma right now you might
meet be down the road and just give you
example i just got a call on the drive
down here yesterday for one of our
partners whose a q SI and one of his
customers has to deal with fisma
requirements for whatever reason and he
knew nothing about it you know he's like
was that that 853 thing you know I'm
like yeah we can probably help you there
so even if you don't necessarily deal
with it right now don't necessarily
directly work for the federal government
you might be like Andrew down the road
where your organization company
eventually ends up hosting a federal
system and then has to comply with this
month we just want you to know some of
the pros and cons on how to quote
unquote defend against FISMA so what is
fisma besides being a unicorn I've read
that you have to put unicorns and
presentations because it makes it funny
sometimes but I so FISMA a brief history
of it I'm sure most of you are aware of
police heard of it and what FISMA is but
the core piece dates back to 2002 with
the the federal Information Security
Management Act and that really defined
the state of FISMA as we know it now of
course before then you had OMB circular
a 139 teen 85 and was updated a couple
times which really started this whole
mess and really started the term
certification accreditation and causing
government systems to have to go through
this through a year cycle and become
accredited to to operate and I'm gonna
use the term certification accreditation
throughout this presentation though a
lot of times now this likes you to call
it system
author is system assessment
authorization sa na vs sea cna but i
like cna better for right now and of
course niss was given authority to
establish these guidelines that we all
know of these 800 series of documents
which give you guidance in various areas
on how to implement fisma and a
certification accreditation process and
of course you can go to this site and
you can download those and of course
just real quick there's a difference
between Phipps and special publications
if you're not aware Phipps are of course
mandatory you have to follow those
special publications 800 series our
guidance and we'll touch on a couple of
these 800 series documentation as they
relate to the certification
accreditation process but just so you
know even if you're not dealing with
fisma this has some really good guidance
on their site for example we recently
had to do an assessment on a random
number generator for one of our gaming
clients and this has you know as 800
series document that talks about how to
go about assessing that even has a tool
suite that you can use in order to do
that so they have more than just
certification accreditation
documentation up there but you may find
useful of course fisma is not the only
compliance standard that we have to deal
with you know we mentioned PCI what are
some other standards across the industry
just shout them out Common Criteria what
about banking industry it would would
hmm pci exactly the others locks out
there a hip of socks iso glb you have
all these different standards and
compliance regulations what's different
about these really have you ever closely
looked from one regulation to the other
regulation you know there's really not a
lot of difference in my opinion you
probably may not be able Sivas very well
but was just a crosswalk between pci and
the 853 series in my opinion security is
security compliance as compliance a lot
of times you'll see these all these
different standards and it may differ
slightly between the industry that
you're in but they all have a
fundamental same components of access
control auditing authors
station you know configuration
management so really if you have an
organization like in this case my
customer who is PCI certified in a lot
of case they're doing a lot of the same
things that they need to be to be bhisma
certified you just need to go about and
test it properly and document the
process properly so the current state of
bhisma i listed what I believe are some
of the the core nist special
publications out there and we'll touch
on just a couple of these we're not
going to talk on on all these you can
look at them at your at your own leisure
if you're not familiar with one but
these are basically the the building
blocks of a certification accreditation
process when you get into the various
publications like 837 where you have a
risk management framework when 833 which
tells you which security controls need
to be in place so there's a lot of good
information in this stock in these
documents that you can go through and
learn what you need in order to
successfully implement a fisma program
in my opinion I mentioned 837 in the
risk management framework process and
this is red one which was released in
two thousand or no 2 dot 2000-2010 and
this sort of fundamentally changed the
process of certification accreditation
to what it was prior to rev one where
you have this risk management framework
if you look at it it's all sort of makes
sense from a security perspective but i
guess it was you know pretty
revolutionary or they thought it was to
introduce it so now you have sort of a
different way to think about it but this
is really the way that a mature security
organization should be operating anyways
it's not rocket science to us especially
the part about the ongoing security
monitoring which we'll talk about and a
little bit but 837 is really the gospel
or Bible but you want to follow when
going through this process and of course
in my opinion one of the most critical
components is 853 we all know this this
gives you the list of security controls
that need to be placed by family so you
have your management operational and
technical controls and if you look at
these compare them to PCI compared to
another security standard regulation I
think you're going to see a lot of
overlap I
even compared some of the gaming
standards that were released by Nevada
Gaming Commission to FISMA and quite
honestly fizz was doing a better job
than they were doing with their
standards they could borrow and learn
some from from what NIST has come up
with and you may have noticed one of
those special publications 800 137 was
dealing with continuous monitoring and
just like the other buzzwords that we
hear all the time at the security
conferences apt big data etc etc I think
continuous monitoring its other one of
these buzzwords that gets thrown around
and that this is going to solve all our
problems now we don't have to do the
three-year accreditation cycle we're
going to be doing continuous monitoring
and really if you look at this in detail
and how different organizations agencies
are attempting to implement a continuous
monitoring they're really not getting
the complete picture of its really
focusing on those easy components to
implement which are some of those
technical standards when we talk about s
cap we'll see some of that as far as the
technical scanning the cbec PE stuff and
getting that data submitted typically to
to DHS the other cyber scope but what I
find interesting is that now every
single vendor you know be a tenable
application security you know even core
impact of course security they all have
some type of continuous monitoring slant
on their product because they realize
that sells in the federal government and
that's what they're trying to show how
they can help you comply with continuous
monitoring but obviously I think
continuous monitoring is something that
needs to be in place and should be in
place and everybody should be doing but
it's not going to solve all our problems
from a certification accreditation
standpoint so hopefully that was a quick
just brief overview of fisma I think we
all understand what bhisma is I don't
want to give a you know our long talk on
on the history of bhisma but FISMA does
have some good points and I may have
come across as a little bit negative on
compliance and FISMA but I think there
is a place for it and some of us good
points are we know like any compliance
standard PCI etc it's better than
nothing you know it forces organizations
that probably wouldn't implement
security to actually go ahead and
implement something you know a lot of
very smart people went into developing
this guidance and documentation if you
look at in this special publications you
look at all the authors and the
different organizations I contributed to
it I mean it runs the gambit from NSA to
defense to commercial I mean you have a
lot of different people who provide
feedback so you know a lot smarter
people than than me so you know I that
has to be a good thing of course raises
the level of attention within your your
organization all sudden you know now
Andrew his company you know if they care
cared about security even before they
had to deal with bhisma but it helps
drive dollars it that way so it it helps
with funding it helps raises the
attention and bar and visibility of
security with your organization and of
course as we saw on that one side of 853
controls they do cover a wide range of
areas we can argue about perhaps or some
ones that are missing that should be
there and other ones that aren't is
quite as important but it is a good
starting point and there's of course a
lot of flexibility on how you go about
implementing it within your organization
so you know what Andrew does it for his
size organization and mission purpose
may not be suitable for someone else you
can help Taylor Bros controls and mold
them into what fits for your
organization so it's not a hard and fast
rule that this needs to be there you can
somewhat manipulate those controls as
long as you you know document which is
one of the problems all this
documentation that gets on in what
bhisma but what is wrong with bhisma
it's just that it's just a starting
point I mean if you go just to comply
with bhisma your you still can be
insecure we know that just like we we
see plenty of PCI companies have been
certified that suffer credit breaches so
it is just that just a starting point
organisations comply with FISMA for the
wrong reasons going on with the first
bullet there just a check box and this
story goes back to the point where it
pays the bills because unfortunately in
my experience and we do do a lot of
bhisma cna work and i'm trying to do
less of it because i don't find it
exciting and i don't think there's a big
future in it from a from a service
provider standpoint it's become a
commodity organizations just want to
check boxes now because they begun to
realize that this is a joke in its
current incarnation and that they just
need to keep your scorecard green so if
I can get someone knows how to check
boxes and i's and cross tease I'd rather
pay them a lower amount of money when
someone that really knows security to
come in and do a holistic approach so
unfortunately some organizations are
complying with it for the wrong reason
these controls why they're well written
and documented they're very easy to
confuse and misinterpret I mean if I'm
not sure how many people have looked at
all the different control enhancements
that have to be in place for like a
moderate or high system and you get into
all the different sub bullets for a
particular control but it can be
confusing and that's really why you need
some skilled personnel who understand it
to help implement it correctly it
sometimes it does focus money attention
on them on the wrong security areas if
you have a vendor who's providing
certification accreditation services and
they you know focus on a lot of you know
non-technical you know maybe management
control areas and you have a long list
of poem findings plans of actions and
milestones that you need to fix funding
make it diverted to those where you
might have you know gaping holes in your
application like I'm a security code
perspective that you now you don't have
funding to look at because you have to
close these poem items and it of course
has become somewhat of a paper drill I
don't think anybody can can argue with
that statement so we talked a little bit
about what the mistakes are but I want
to look at some of it what in my opinion
what some of the top 10 mistakes are and
from those of you who have implemented
FISMA or how to do assessments or write
system security plans just shout out a
couple of what you think some of the top
mistakes are besides being a paperwork
Joe any any things mistakes that you've
seen may
throughout the course of doing this type
of work
perfect yep i actually have system
categorization and there's a mistake and
he wants somebody else okay we'll go
through and I'm sure you're thinking of
some of the ones this is one of the ones
I see all the time copying the control
requirements and then restating them as
your compliance statement I can't tell
you how many times I seen this it's just
it's because people are lazy or they
just don't understand so basically it
was you I think everybody can pretty
much see this but it they just restate
the information statement the compliance
statement the require is information
system enforces approved authorizations
for logical access to the system in
accordance with applicable policy
whatever that means you know but and the
implementation method is redacted system
enforces approved authorizations for
logical access to the system accordance
with applicable policy it tells you
nothing so this is one of the biggest
mistakes I see and sometimes it's not
dis bad but not adequately describing
how you're implementing that security
control in your system security plan if
you don't adequately describe it there's
no way for an independent third party to
come and assess that control according
to how you implemented it they're
basically just have to generically test
against this the criteria and at the
same time value to PL 24 system security
plan because your system secure plan is
not adequate on the right level so in my
opinion this is something we see see a
lot and maybe it comes down to cost when
we get to this budget issue as far as
companies looking and government looking
to spend less and less money on this you
know if it's vista system still gets
passed to cares of it has a you know
incorrect you know its compliance
statement you know they should but in my
experience you know we see several like
this mistake number two inheriting
controls that you really can't or having
you know controls listed as common when
they are really hybrid and just real
quick not to bore everybody because you
know people discuss common versus
inherited you know and get confused and
argue about what's the difference but
basically you know in a concept of
certification accreditation you can
inherit controls from a from another
system so if I'm a major application I
sit on a GSS I really shouldn't be
caring about the
operating system controls or awareness
training or physical security i inherit
goes from another system but what you
see sometimes is UC systems like this
we're here SI ten dealing with data
information validation and data input
and they're saying that this is a major
application that is inheriting this
control there's no way inheritance going
to this is a web application that you
know you're entering in information into
it you know so people try to inherit
controls where they really shouldn't or
say controls are common just so they
don't have to discuss the implementation
status which of course when it comes to
security you're really not doing your
your system justice so that's another
common mistake that we do see incorrect
security categorizations everybody
thinks your system is a high because
they think there's at least initially oh
my systems yeah it's really important
I'm important it's a high but until they
realize how much time and money they
need to invest in actually implementing
all the controls of a high-security
category system versus a moderate and
it's a big difference and of course
sometimes you have opposite of you know
so what I have PII and credit card
information but you know I'm a low only
you know 10 people my organization use
it or something like that and but if you
do your data categorization correctly
using phipps one and nine and eight
hundred sixty it's very clear where your
system should fall and of course you can
tailor that based on need but you know
you should least be following that
initially and that's you know one of the
mistakes that we very often see and we
counsel our clients you know to wreak a
tiger eyes your system we don't think it
should be a high you know we look at
that but oftentimes you know they don't
want to make changes incorrect system
boundaries is another and you know you
really sort of like PCI you know PCI's
got a habit of we sort of scope only
those systems that deal with the credit
card transactions into the PCI boundary
to make it as small as possible so you
don't have to waste as much time and
money investing on your pc i it's
somewhat the same theory with with
bhisma and where I really see this
problem is typically not in government
organizations that host their own system
so oftentimes we do because they end up
lumping GSS components in with their
major application
it really should be separate but at
commercial organizations like Andrews
where they have to host a
government-owned system it's on their
network how do you draw that boundary so
you isolated from the rest of their
corporate network from there are other
clients that may not have to show fisma
compliance you know it gets you know you
have to describe that accurately in your
system security planning also
technically you have to have isolation
so you don't have to worry about testing
other components that you don't want to
or need to the fifth mistake not keeping
up to date with the documentation and
and you're supposed to update this on
they say an annual basis it really
should be more often than that because
what if you don't you run into the
problem like I've seen we go through to
do a recertification of a system and
we're doing save a contingency plan
testing portion and we're going through
the tabletop test and we're like and
they're like well we don't really have
that alternative processing society
anymore we move to another one well why
isn't your documentation updated not
just one example but if you're not
updating your documentation on a regular
basis it's gonna cause problems down the
road and unfortunately everyone does not
like documentation we know that time is
this is a six mistake waiting too long
to start the process this is both in
from the from the organization waiting
then you know they know their system ato
expires in six months but they wait to a
month until it expires it's like oh gosh
I need to get the system recertified you
know obviously corners are gonna be cut
mistakes are going to be made and it
also applies to the integrators who are
designing systems are going to have to
beef is more compliant not integrating
those security controls those FISMA
controls early in SD LLC process so they
get implemented correctly from a start
so it's at both places the seventh
mistake not having enough skilled
personnel this is for doing the you know
the initiation phase of a documentation
developing your system security planned
initial risk assessment CP etc and also
the people who are doing the assessments
which I think directly relates to the
fact that certification accreditation
has become a commodity you know if if
it's so competitive to win contracts now
organizations are going to
cut their prices and to cut their prices
they can't have some you know Oh SCP
coming in to do the testing portion of
the penetration test you know they're
gonna have some somebody wrist running
Nessus you know against a web
application and say hey I did my
penetration testing so it goes both ways
both on the side of developing the
documentation and also doing the testing
you know you need to have both if it's
done correctly the eighth making the
mistake that just because you have an
atl your system is secure this you know
don't you need to say anything more
about this but I can't tell you how many
times I've heard it you know when we're
trying to maybe sell additional services
or provide some additional function
they're like oh well my system it's
secure it has an ATO you know I'm pci
certified I'm secure we don't need to do
that type of testing you know usually
the security folks that you deal with
understand that this is not the case but
unfortunately management still need to
be educated another buzzword with cloud
computing you know moving to the cloud
is gonna solve all our problems you know
it's gonna solve everything from you
know every security issue to your cna
issues to your performance issues and I
think this is a big myth and you know
with FedRAMP is trying to solve some of
this process and yes you can move your
applications to the cloud you're still
going to have certain components that
you're responsible for even if you move
a to a system that is FedRAMP certified
and we're starting to get more more CSPs
that are federally certified i saw
amazon just got theirs so we're moving
in that right direction it is helpful
that you don't have to do as much work
what you're still going to have to
ensure about your piece that you're
responsible for is there and of course
the last mistake similar to paperwork
drill is treating the cna process you
know such as building a Potemkin village
and for those of you have heard the term
Potemkin village it dates back to the
late 1700s with Catherine the Great and
Russia and she was doing a visit and her
prime minister Potemkin you know just
built you know basically a facade of
walls along the river so when she
cruised on their boat there it looked
like a very prosperous you know village
when really it was just you know
a bunch of walls and I think that is a
similar process you know it takes place
and certification accreditation you just
have people building these nice fancy
system security plans and doing the
testing but where's the meat to it how
are they really complying with security
in a lot of cases you know they're not
and I'm going to turn it over to Andrew
right now so he can talk about give some
examples from his organization on how
they went about and implemented security
he'll touch on some things from SCLC
process and some lessons learned from
from his experience all right I'm hoping
this interesting for you so what did it
give you know to use some something to
take away from this and without boring
on governance um so um I guess even
whether you're so there's probably no
probably all sorts of you know
widespread ended up demographic in here
but whether you're um you know what your
your company is that your agency is um
is about to your to host something that
a federal application in the future
whether you're doing some sort of resem
Tate reauthorization or whatever my p um
it's really not that bad I mean I know
it's having in my case having two
segments out a legacy application that's
you know that's sort of uh I mean every
software development company every
custom you know software development
company runs into this it's just the
growth of the company you start small
you you scale up one of the things to
not be shocked about when you start the
your cna process and we're running SSP
as is don't actually seriously don't
freak out you don't need so for instance
um you don't need to to to buy you know
an overcapacity sim to note for your
company that the cost though that will
you know break the bank it's really it's
it's it's really running a business it's
running a little miniature business it's
you have to stay profitable you scale
here your controls correctly but don't
omit it entirely so don't skip you know
static static application testing
entirely do it but then you know both
start with open source tools or you know
something
don't skip entirely scale it correctly
so with that I'll start with some some
examples of how we how you can actually
really comply so some of these are
specific to to my scenario so feel free
to to stop and ask questions anytime
there's actually a lot of stuff for for
my slides are kind of dense so each one
of these are it can go on with a little
bit of sprawl so I'll just start the top
so first first of all now if you have a
parent agency to start with that you're
inheriting from to that will they might
be able to give you bass lines as a
start usually um oh I hate is that
usually but it's typically if you are
inheriting controls from parent agency
they're going to be way off the bat
there's just it's just going to be some
um it's a good place to start I wouldn't
just do that and be done with it um I
just want also stress that you know you
want to be realistic about this again
it's it is like running a business you
don't want to go overboard and you want
to stay compliant you don't want to just
be compliant you want to manage risk
which turns to a lot of dollars the next
thing is of course contrast um if you
have any if you're if you have a written
contract that that's your meeting for
for water services you're offering your
lips what I not impact level might be
predetermined so that makes things a lot
either for you hopefully it's just not
all high but if it is high then you're
right there something to fall back on
but of course it was contract written
then it's tied to federal dollars and
you really don't have a choice you might
have written in SL lays you might have
to comply with HIPAA you might have
incentives to go hl7 not sure if
anyone's here and having to work with
that next one is so it's nice to have a
periodic internal security certification
program what I mean by that is so you
want realistically you want a way to
built-in Jack security throughout the
ordinance
asian you don't want so you're not just
you know security isn't some you know
some add-on service that you kasal
periodically when something needs to
look like it's safe for production it's
something that's that should be at the
organizational level which so this ties
to hopefully we would a sound
organizational security program that is
adopted and accepted by all the
directors and and implemented throughout
the organization as a whole and not just
for IT or r instance so the internal
security cert there's a there's a couple
ways to do that so if Fame ones
technical or I don't know so what do you
basically do is you can you can you can
write some scripts have it automatically
discover and audit your your system
engineers that way or you can you can
say for instance write it into your
deployment program that's you'll have
soon you know establish a create a
quarterly reassessment program that you
must rerun these you know said you know
we run a set of set scripts or something
anyway so next one PHP iph I assessments
data usage agreements you might have you
might interact with other agencies so
there's in my case we do do so you'll
have to you might want to look into any
kind of information usage agreements you
might have with them and then kind of
deliverables you might have to meet with
those also so this is the next one is so
so separating a level is why but the
partitioning or system this is something
that if you are a software developer
around if anyone tears if you so system
separation is is um is it's critical
this is something that really has to
start from the bottom up going
afterwards is it's not easy it's not
just separating the majorette it's not
just a bleep sub writing the application
the code
the servers it's really it's really best
from the from the ground up from from
the network infrastructure servers the
application and also within if you are
architecting an application the layers
within the application and into the data
tier if it applies that far especially
with virtualization it's yeah I've seen
it's pretty easy for from a cost
perspective to say let's buy one you
know mega virtualization hosts and throw
it all on there that's not good and so
next a review of externally thought
authenticated resources so periodically
uh you know I don't know if we talk
about more just and there's there's some
things that could some really
interesting things that I probably can't
share if you have threats threats
periodically you might want to
periodically you might want to seriously
just identify the types of externally
authenticated content you have exposed
on the perimeter so just anything
basically an inventory of any place that
are basically in the tat enough
indicated attack surface I mean this
sounds like common sense but it's not
really it's not really done often when
you type resource permitting and for
whatever other reasons um corporate
security policy is very important it's I
mean everyone has a hopefully you have a
corporate security policy but it's
basically a fallback mechanism for
foreign force before enforcement the
contacts into your legally enforceable
rules of behavior if you ever you have
to execute legal action for for some
kind of action risk based decisions so
NIST is a so the NIST FISMA frameworks
even if you're not working with federal
systems they're not yet nor it's
actually it's the result of years of
continuous work of tenuous improvement
it's a lot of there's documented thurs
and this
I line special publication for
everything it is you know and and not
only is there a document for everything
but there's versions of that for
everything so it's a lot of collective
work that um so having a back to do
sales on wrist base decisions so having
a way to track having a way to the track
approve assign ownership for 44 exempted
accepted risks so for instance I was if
you have too often you know there's
there's uh there's there's legacy or
there's there's fire walls with with
rules with comments that you know that
the roles that no one has has any idea
what you know what it does so I as a
starting point um i would probably uh we
i wrote a custom application that that
basically creates an approval process
within the organization that ties into
it basically creates it in tracks it
creates work for their it tracks work
for the organization but it's based off
of its it's based off of anorexic risk
acceptance process that ties to inform
directors automatically and additional
that it's we've incorporated a scoring
system internally so that ties into a
vulnerability a ranking system so it's
so you can do something similar to that
but definitely have some place to
identify and track those risks so that
they're not just lost somewhere and
those firewall rules aren't just sitting
there aging i guess i should probably
I'm going to keep going because uh
anyway
so I'm gonna run through this probably
faster than intended so budgeting
definitely have an allocated sound
budgeting as course that's critical for
for for any federal system it's kind of
a given have an incident response team
this is one so have a prototyping lab
this is not one that you might think
about but in a course you know so
definitely anywhere i go i would
recommend having a prototyping lab for
authorizing technologies because you
mean so so many of the deficiencies many
vulnerabilities so many think too many
times when running baselines and
procedures um you know it's really you
know you need a place to test that
theory I'm not much of a theoretical
person you really need a place to
validate something before you write it
in one of the main differences between
my history at the developer is that I've
gone from from writing code being a code
monkey to a lot of writing procedures
and documentation but it's you know it's
it's it's there it's there for a purpose
it served 24 for others to use PMO
integration basically sdlc integration
others more details out later I'll keep
going external risk acceptance process
yeah basically where that's basically
establishing you want to be able to
establish ownership for a risk for your
two managers or to the your online
business units even better the asset
waiting acid ranking designation what's
cool about that is once you have that in
place you can actually do what I did
actually I've automated it I've actually
have traceability to specific to all of
Miss controls and actually will send an
email out suits to interracial security
when the baseline changes and how much
the score is incremented for every
single change across the network for
across platforms did you do something
similar so once you have some
standardized you have to have some kind
of baseline to start otherwise you can't
say something changed
and like because I can keep on going
forever on this because it goes into
configuration management so again
finally building in the architecture is
owning the architecture is critical well
I should probably really pick it up okay
I'm see let me any questions okay I can
talk to you later so defend the Enver
sec I mentioned this a little bit
earlier so so I'm going over the the
major categories so start with
management's at the highest level you do
want you have to have an information
security program to start dedicated
budgeting where that vulnerability
scanning schedule so when you're
specifying your vulnerability scanning
be realistic about it is so if you're if
you're certifying a major application in
an application like us don't just don't
you don't just include the server
infrastructure definitely going to the
application goes into source control
check-in policies you know it's actually
another dimension that Scott commonly
missed I'm see you know I'll go into the
I was trying to just cut it down to
overview or 1 / 4 the major categories
so operational examples baselining
disaster recovery is big one these are
all really large items so you know
determining whether to to load balance
or fit to duel her bezier your gesture
coveri slight media transport this is
actually real example when how to work
on a case where a manager left a laptop
on a cab in New York had some you know
critical sensitive information on it the
cost is astronomical when that happens
yeah the potential loss is astronomical
so a solution if you haven't had this
happen yet or if you think it might
happen corporate laptops with pre-boot
authentication see some
okay all right technical defenders okay
so basically just at the lowest level of
the technical these are some examples of
technical controls anyway going examples
from ignorance a sickly a recap of the
large items I mentioned previously
risk-based approach which is in
compliance only focus don't just focus
on the wording on what I'm making the
RSS feed look nice it's really it's but
it's real risks for the organization
it's real it's real cost and there's
there should be payback there should be
valued created by that so don't just do
it for the appliance part of it okay
more examples I can talk to you more
about this later but these it goes into
several several different layers
especially in application design
application architecture it's it can get
it I can feel free to talk to me later
or I can give you advice on that right
documentation sucks i think this is yes
last one for me right documentation
sucks yes where maybe you might like it
whatever but if it if it's not
sufficiently documented create a nut
inaccuracies to your SSP and obvious and
additionally it creates uncategorised
incorrectly categorize dependencies code
service otherwise many places many times
there's a company there's always a box
you know the skewer box sitting the
corner and it does something that really
understands I would fix that right away
right Gus thanks to android definitely
sis Andrews very good talk on 101
afterwards if he has some specific
advice on what he's doing he ran through
that very very quickly because he had to
first time we gave him this together so
it's a timing may be a little bit off
real quick I'll get you guys out here in
time for lunch don't worry its box
lunches today so there's not gonna be a
big line Jay told me that
um how do these controls get assessed of
course your Bibles 853 a which basically
tells you how to about go go about doing
it as a lot of interviews allow
examinations you see that last bullet
testing which I think of course is the
most important but of course is I think
it's a phase that suffers most currently
in the climate day or how you actually
go about testing it some tools that
actually perform 833 compliance and
these aren't actually tools that we use
for testing but these are more GRC
related tools that organizations are
using and you know these are the major
ones supposed to automate workflow if
you've used any of these you know we're
very painful it takes all it takes a lot
of time to do it there's still a lot of
writing that you still have to do but
these are the major players out there
that that we've experienced and that
different government organizations use
as far as tools s cap you know when it
comes to an assessment perspective and
typical scanning you know you need to
have a tool that is s cap compliant you
know which is a protocol has a lot of
different components CVE cpe oval etc
etc but good news is most all your tools
are already s cap compliant because just
like continuous monitoring you know the
government vendors realize they have to
do this if they want to sell so all
their tools meet this protocol from how
to go about assessing management and
really a lot of the management process
is a lot of interviews and examinations
and here's what we typically develop a
sort of like an IE spreadsheet where we
have a control who we need to talk to
evidence required you know real fun
stuff often assessing these are easy and
straightforward but you really have to
read the control implementation
statement carefully because sometimes
they have some really good writers and
they'll try to make it sound like it's
really implemented when it's really not
like if you read that one closely later
you'll see that it's does not really
meet the requirements of continuous
monitoring operational one of the
largest control classes but summit
definitely deal with directly impact the
security of an organization i'm thinking
about configuration management and
system integrity controls during a lot
of your technical scans a lot of
findings you can easily map back to
either like cm6 for configuration
settings or si tu for flawed remediation
so there's still a lot of non-technical
findings and operational but you'll come
from from your interview examination
phase you can see these you know role
you know important but but maybe not the
most interesting to us that like to
actually perform security testing but
this is also where at least you get to
have some fun you know if you like
running that map and stuff and you'll
see some findings here you can probably
map you know back to see m74 least
functionality I'm sure that server
doesn't really need all those ports and
services listening technical so
technical controls are typically what we
find where we have the most fun
assessing but no where are you going to
see requirements that you have to go
about and you know run detailed
penetration testing use tools like
metasploit or something you know you're
lucky sometimes if you get an Essex
County of interviews and examinations
you still have to do i'm not sure if you
ever looked at AC to for example account
management that control for a moderate
level system has about four different
control enhancements like with ten
bullets each that have to be met it
takes a lot of time to actually assess
if an organization is doing account
management correctly and for the
interview and examination process and of
course we mentioned you get to have some
fun so you know you can go through and
do your web testing and find
vulnerabilities like sequel injection
yes so what just a sequel injection
vulnerability why is this important in
the context of this presentation well
it's because the SSP for Miss system
says that you know they do data
validation and they strip out you know
dangerous characters etc etc well why is
this in place and also in this
particular system it's funny because the
system had received an ATO from another
government organization so they're like
they were very surprised when we ended
up finding a sequel injection
vulnerability in a system that had
already had an ATO granite just goes to
show you that whole ATO does not equal
secure slide from from before how can we
fix FISMA you know I think there's
there's there's definitely we're moving
in the right direction awareness has
already been raised I think with all
compliance standards but even more
specifically with with bhisma and we
have some recent some recent laws that
have passed or executive executive
orders 13 636 deals with a critical
infrastructure
is actually the federal Information
Security Amendments Act of 2013 which
passed the house and is now in the
Senate which hopes to rectify some of
the problems of current FISMA you have
or other organizations like sands who
really aren't the biggest fan of a
wholeness fisma process if you talk to
allen polar you know and maybe other
ideas maybe we need to require
organizations that provide services on
CA you know are certified but I'm not
sure that's had much luck with the PCI
industry and the whole queue SAS and
everything you still get plenty of
people who don't know what they're doing
so in conclusion and I got a if you're
right on time so it's easy to comply
with fisma you know it's harder to do it
right and build real security into your
organization i think until we move away
from his paperwork mentality that
affects all compliance standards we're
not going to move to real security and
real increase of your overall security
posture but but good news is i think we
are moving into the right direction i
think you as people who provide business
services or deal with information
security and compliance that that you
helped educate system owners management
on why real security needs to be built
into the security awareness process with
that we can move to two questions and
since it's lunch you can go to lunch or
talk to me your answer about other
questions so thank you everybody and
have a rest of a good con