good afternoon everyone we are very
happy to be here with you today
and i can promise you um
we have brought you the best of the best
this is gonna be an amazing panel
stick with it record it memorize it it's
going to be a great fun
so well you know we are the in the midst
of what we say in the midst of uh
of corona uh we have you know 30 million
people already tested sadly close to 1
million
people are dead but what started as a
crisis as a health
crisis is now an economic crisis and it
is clear
we see a lot of us going rapidly to the
digital
we're working from home or from wherever
but not from
office we're working remotely well
we are all actually keeping the hackers
busy
and overloaded with work if you're a
hacker you're waking up this morning and
saying oh my god this is like a candy
store what do i take first to taste
so vigorously actively we fill them
around the world 78 of cyber attacks
over the last
few months where of course related to
corona we're talking about
a staggering number of 200 000 weekly
and that would include also websites or
emails related with the word corona or
covid in their domain
40 40 000 new domains
have recently been opened but you know
of them are suspected as malicious
so guys my esteem panelists
so i would like first of all you know
you've been introduced but i will let
you know
i will let you introduce yourself a
little bit more and really tell us all
where did this pandemic find you i mean
were you busy in the middle of something
were you hiking somewhere were you
skiing some
please share with us amit please be the
first go ahead sir all right thanks tyle
thanks
and uh i'm sure like like me all of us
were busy
in various kind of activities related to
cyber security i
found that in india especially there
were 300
increase in cyber attacks and cyber
crimes
so i got lots of investigation work i
got lots of
root cause analysis work in such a
pandemic
and then it was actually surprised for
me to
understand like these hackers and
criminals they are creating very
sophisticated attack vectors
especially uh during lockdown and not
only with social engineering but they
how could they actually penetrate to
those systems those are considered to be
highly secure
so that was a big for me as well and
it was a great learning for sure i mean
please share a bit
a little bit more about yourself i mean
you're renowned in india but we want to
you know know you a little bit better
sure then so
uh i work closely with all law
enforcement agencies in india
like nia cbi and npa and dpr indian
net grade etc and also state police
department
so if there is any such critical cyber
crime which requires an expertise from
an ethical hacker's perspective or a
security expert perspective i get
involved and i help them to solve those
cases
this is one of my expertise i also work
with tech mahindra
i'm hiding their red teaming operation
here and
that's all thank you thank you thank you
jay how you doing man i'm doing
absolutely fantastic how are you
perfect please share with us where were
you
uh technology greatest cool so
just to give you a bit about myself
today marks actually 12 years
since my last coupon talk so i was there
in the initial stages of cooking when
they started off
and it's really good to be back in
cocoon
so about myself i basically had cyber
security for aia
my primary forte would be on
cyber defense threat intelligence
forensics and that's what i've pretty
much been doing for the last 13 years
i've been working with multiple
government agencies from
all the way from the caribbean to the
pacific to africa
where i spent at least four or five
years in trying to build national assets
establishing national forensics lab and
at the same time trying to build a
national framework
for cyber security so over the
last four months it's something which
everybody can recollect it's been held
frozen over um and to give you how we
have been impacted by kobe it is
my headquarters is based out of hong
kong and my one half of my cyber
security operations
is based out of china so beware the
first hit
when corona actually came out so from
ground reality to
getting it back to operations and
running it again it's been a real
challenge
i'm sure i'm sure thank you for this jay
yeah
hi i think i was caught with the corona
in a more interesting place
i was in a ski vacation then we
receive the message when you come home
don't go to work go home for two weeks
guarantee
warranty and start operating from home
so we didn't have a time to to organize
a little bit about myself i served in
the army as a helicopter pilot
later on went into computers uh
business starting as a programmer
rnd manager on the software house
managing a software house
opened a an office of myself a company
consulting and a wine consulting to the
bank the bank recruited me
to be the cio ceo and cyber security
in charge of the bank so
and last month i started my own startup
back to the space wi-fi space
cyber security wi-fi and regarding
corona if you want i can tell you a
little bit about
organizing we will we
in a minute just for people to
understand in israel
it doesn't matter your age it doesn't
matter if you have a job you need to
have a startup it's like
like you need to have a car you need to
have a startup and it doesn't matter
so guys you all see we have you know
high foreheads
and not a lot of hair some of it is
because the hard work
we had to put throughout corona
some of us had to take care of let's say
hundreds of workers
overnight needing to work from home vpn
was not created to hold a hundred
percent of our workers from home
maybe 10 maybe 20 everything is
congested
we know again that we have a lot of
unmonitored
uh internet systems we are not sure
about the security patches
i mean it's a nightmare to all of us so
i would like our steam panel panelists
now to really
share with us what kind of new threat
vectors
have you noticed during this pandemic
amit go ahead
yeah it was really uh interesting to
understand
these new threat vectors because
traditionally the kind of
attack that we have observed we're
actually exploiting some availabilities
of the system
whether it is uh like either sql
injection or
or xor or any such uh standard iodo or
vulnerability that were exploited
exploited but in this time i have
especially observed like even if an
organization is highly secure and
sophisticated uh these hackers were able
to penetrate them because
of their third party or four party
vendors
so that was really a new thing for me
because earlier we used to think
that we just need to focus our risk to
our own parametrics
but now the risk is there because of our
third party and four-party vendors
that we have missed out and we have
never thought of it seriously
especially for a bank when i was doing
an investigation in u.s i found
like a email availability was exploited
initially
of their law firm from where they are
they were taking services
so basically the vulnerability were
there in in the law firm not in the bank
but then the data from the bank was
stolen so that is something which we i
have observed first time and i think it
is interesting to
prepare ourselves in future considering
these kind of new techniques
clear okay
okay so in my case what i would say is
uh from a vector perspective what we saw
was a rice and
uh phishing or spam emails malicious
attachments
uh there were coming disguised in covet
teams
somewhere around jan the flood started
and
around till march june they were still
going in full fledge
and during that time one of the usual
things is that
we didn't see the normal kind of
adversaries that you would be expecting
from a financial industry acting up but
rather it was more or less like
new infrastructures new players in the
market often people
trying their luck disguising as a
let's say one of your employees has
gotten a uh go with positive
we need you to fill in these details etc
so that was one of the waves that we saw
and towards june we saw a shift in
patterns where we saw a lot more
nation state actors coming into play and
one of the interesting things that
we did observe or what i personally saw
is that
given that people are now distributed
patching of machines becomes challenging
so pretty much all the microsoft uc
critical vulnerabilities
are now being pushed on all over clear
of course we would like you guys later
to share some tips
you know what did you really do if it's
okay to share
yeah you mentioned business continuity
and cio of a bank how is life
during corona for a bank
it's a challenging let's say you know
the the basic culture of a bank is
everything inside nothing outside
everything on premise
nothing on the cloud and suddenly
you have to move from working inside
your territory
outside from home it seems you know if i
talk to someone a month before
everyone will tell you you're crazy it's
impossible
but amazingly people can adjust
and in two weeks we moved from working
on premise
working from home
we had a small group
that was working at the beginning you
know technicians and their
vice president et cetera suddenly you
have to buy
hundreds of left laptops arrange
everything
and spread them around the israel and
everyone was doing that you know all the
banks all the companies all the firms
everyone
needed the laptop so there were no
laptops left
and we needed to be to to continue
working
so we moved into uh
private computers private computers that
were working
on the same computer on zoom for school
or for a plan you know the kids were
home
everything was a mess we have to arrange
very quickly
you know to to to take care of these
home computers
at the beginning we were spreading uh
vpns and direct lines
but it wasn't enough because everyone
was using that
so we have to move into wi-fi and to
spread into
a more security
preventive measurement and then we did
we didn't have enough of that
so we have to buy from few vendors and
to
have more special specialities so
you know it was like a war
exactly well let me tell you let me tell
you the war
is ongoing yeah and sadly it ain't
changing
it will continue and it will be fierce
so what you're saying is that if i'm a
customer of the bank
and i'm used to come to the bank and
sign documents and all this all of a
sudden i can come
but you need my signature so you go
digital
so how do you prepare for all of this i
mean it sounds like a huge
infrastructure
that needs to be in place overnight
yeah you know in the banking
business everything is very slow slowly
slow here
so you are starting new ideas
and checking them validating them on
your own pace
everything should be more secure so
everything but that was on the labs
we everything was very rapid so we did
have something initiatives but it wasn't
on air
so everything was very rapidly growing
and we did everything
as a matter of fact you can see it's
possible okay
by the way i just want to say jay i will
ask you in a second because you
your company is the one of the biggest
in the world for life insurance and you
have tons of documents to sign
yeah but just to say that to the
startups i work with
and probably there are a lot of startups
in the audience
well we knew that if i would to reach
out
to yair as the cio of the bank and tell
him listen i have this new technology
i want you to try it you know do a poc
he will say
slowly slowly i'm a bank but what we
found that
during corona all of a sudden the cio is
very receptive to the problem that he
has and he's willing to take
any startup on board and overnight get
decisions to implement you so what i'm
saying sometimes
this corona also offers a lot of
opportunity
it and it also showed everyone from both
sides
that when something is needed there are
no hurdles
there are no problems you just engage if
it's
100 baked jay can you please
relate to the same problems that the
bank had to endure with the
documentation and signature and all that
so within the
company of within our company itself
it's fine because we actually did move
into
uh digital signatures quite early on
but in terms of working with the
customers and collaterals like
what your heels have said it is a
challenge for us as well
because when it comes to these kind of
things at the end of the day
you need to get that written signature
no matter how much digital you are
trying to evolve into
so that are still there
yeah let me sharpen my question so if
you see let's say a
problem to deal with the digital signing
when you try to overcome it
do you create a solution that fits all
or you need to have several solutions to
deal with the threats
so it would be different because about
how we are structured we operate out of
19 different countries so
19 of them would have different
regulatory requirements based on which
we can't have a single cut solution
for all now most of the ones which can
be commonly grouped in together
they would eventually move into one
solution and the others would be
different ones
right so it's not a one size fits all
solution that we can go ahead with
clear um amit they need i mean
you as an expert these guys have to deal
also a lot with privacy
that's a huge issue gdpr is all over
everyone now
what do you see how do they how do you
how do organizations that you work with
deal with it
so privacy is has always been the reason
of providing the security because we
want to keep our data private and secure
and especially with these new kind of
ransomware attacks
those are actually not only encrypting
the data locally but they are also
stealing this data out and making it
public eventually to the dark wave
i think privacy has become a big concern
if i can give you an example of this
recent
cognition project where they lost almost
100 million dollars because of a
renaissance base their biggest concern
was not that the data is encrypted but
the data was leaked outside and the the
guy was threatening them like
if you don't pay me this ransom we'll
make it public and this data is actually
very sensitive not only from banking
perspective because they have customers
all around the world
and they are offering security to other
customers so a company which is offering
security services to other customers
if they get hacked it becomes a much
more bigger problem for them
so i think uh from data privacy
perspective worldwide if i can focus on
indian perspective
india right now is still struggling to
have a full-fledged data privacy law
and we don't have that law although
there are there are standards
all around the world gdpr and then us
data privacy
acts and builds but in india we are here
to have that and that's why
most of these companies are literally
taking the leverage of it and
are relaxed and that even the data is
out because of any reason
they are not penalized but we are
expecting this bill to come too soon to
the parliament and probably
then we'll be having that sort of
regulations
and the law and order uh boundaries for
those companies
but if i take this example because i
started with this cognition attack
why this attack was successful and how
could it happen
i'll just tell you a story line like
last year
in july this mage ransomware was made
public on 27th
july around and there were sequence of
uh informations
released warnings advisories by
different companies including wireless
total and then fbi and then many other
organizations all around the world
and there were sequence of attacks like
on 8th of june the major ransomware
attacked a threat intelligence
organization then they attacked country
agencies then they attacked
a missile corporation in u.s then fbi
won something on 2nd of jan
and then they attacked md labs what i'm
trying to say like despite of having so
many warnings and
attacks all these organizations or
organizations are not considering
this as an input system with that input
when we did the root cause analysis of
cognition we found that they have
actually not implemented all those iocs
and hash values
because during this all sequence of
attacks same hash values were used
of that ransomware and the source of
attack was also more or less same
so if they could have considered that as
an input timely i think they could have
protected
so these kind of ignorance is actually
becoming a big concern for larger
magicians
where it was not a zero day sort of a
thing it
has been there we had enough information
to protect us against them
okay yeah yeah
before before you answer what you want i
just want to add something to your
answer
um the bank seeing the problem
uh you're facing with the corona did
they really allocate
more resources was more money invested
into getting yourself you know better uh
uh
secured against this those threats
coming now
of course now their budgets are moving
into
cyber security we have new vectors of
attacks right now if before
everything was uh you you took care of
your
employees working on premise it was more
easy
now it's a zero trust environment
because you don't know if your employees
logging into your systems you can log in
from home or from a cafe
or from the way and you don't and
right now the weak spot is
something we call a man in the middle
because
someone can come in the middle between
the employee
or the client and the systems
while in the middle nobody feels it
because
the system thinks it's the client or the
employee
and the employee thinks is on the bank
and
in the middle the hacker takes
everything
he can put materials on your computer
a ransomware and then suddenly
all of the employees can't work like it
happened in tower semiconductors
a a supplier was in a
logging into the systems we put in
and only a ransomware say a
tower semiconductors were shut down for
a few days
every day not working millions and
millions
eventually they paid they paid few
hundred thousand dollars
for their ransomware and now we have two
threats
one and not to work and one
data leaking the the the hacker
they say look we publish
inside information if you want us to
stop
uh pay us and then we will release the
ransomware elsewhere trying to do
to damage the backups first
they damage the backups few
days weeks later when they put on your
their ransomware you don't have backups
so you don't have any choice unless to
pay
and if we are dealing corona i believe
it will continue
like living with corona living with
cyber and understanding sometimes
you have to pay in order to continue
to pay for your faults to pay for your
mistake
and continue thank you uh well i know
from personal knowledge that
your startup irish shield deals with
many in the middle
and uh i'm happy to say that i know the
solution to be
very good uh jay so
we all agree that hackers are brilliant
people
i mean they are smarter like above way
above
average technologically and
psychologically but i know that when
corona and it seems to be still here to
stay
also creates a situation for our workers
when all of a sudden job security is
very hard to find
there's a lot of uncertainty and
sometimes
workers also get this idea that they
need to do something about it
and maybe be a little bit harmful to the
organization also
what do you know to tell us about it did
you encounter any such as
incidents so touchwood we haven't
so insider threat definitely has gone up
the risk scale
in terms of a cio's wrist mapping
one of the primary reasons being a
people have a false sense of job
security some they feel that
they might be losing their job tomorrow
uh p
is this is a time when people can take
the
actual home desktops or laptops back to
their own personal homes
rather than having working it out of the
office and
see is this is also the time where
people are finding
new venues where they can actually start
trading
or sharing information a classic example
which
i've seen in this region would be where
people started selling insider trading
details out
just for that extra cash of money to
survive this time
because different people are treating
the pandemic in different ways some of
them have slash salaries
some of them have given a forceful work
work without pay some of them have been
asked to stay back home come back after
a month
etc so those are the scenarios where we
often
tend to see these kind of activities
happening
i see guys uh would you please press
also the uh
the chatting because we are getting some
some questions from
our audience which seems seems to be
very involved
so please uh run run through them i
think we have touched uh
most of the questions but if you if your
eyes see something that you want to
speak about go ahead
uh amit i know you you have for sure
something to
say yes so i would just like to give you
suggestions
to the organization uh because uh the
thing which we have missed out the
recent uh sophisticated that i like
vectors in the malware that i have
noticed are something like this agent
tesla
is actually creating lots of issues for
us as your relative is creating lots of
issues njrat is there
then we have uh something like uh
thinkbot and emote so these are
few four five kind of malwares we need
to protect
continuously against that because they
are changing their signatures they are
changing their hash values
and they are continuously on rise and
then especially for india if i can
suggest apt41
is actually becoming quite aggressive
since last week
and it is leading when we are
attributing these attacks and this is a
chinese
apt and they are actually disturbing a
lot to
indian banks and organizations
that we have observed and noticed so i
think we need to be
safeguarded against that and then there
are traditional
abilities those are exploited because of
the work from home situation
we were not prepared and there were no
secure
vpn available especially when these call
centers were running because we never
thought that call center will
eventually be running from workforce
situation and these call center guys
actually they have access of this
ei data so all these banks and the
companies are
offering the call center services they
need to take care of
a lot because this data is now getting
leaked i have uh
i think day for yesterday i found a
couple of companies on dog if they are
selling
complete pi database of lots of indian
augmentation
it includes your payment details
transaction details your location
history and everything they're selling
it
and that's when so i think this has been
happening and we need to safeguard us
amit i think thank you for this i think
uh our audience really would like to
hear from you guys as experts i mean
ransom is all around us i mean people
are attacked left and right do you pay
you don't pay what to do they take your
people are lost for answers about it
please please share with us
some something practical from your
experience from your knowledge
what do we do with this see first of all
yeah sorry i think uh yeah
you know it's like dealing with the
virals or with the kidnap
first you don't deal with the criminals
you say i don't pay but first you have
to prepare
to do anything possible not to be
kidnapped or
take a vaccine not to take the virus but
after you got it it's very easy to say
not to pay
but if it's your father lying on the
hospital
and you need to pay for a breathing
machine because he didn't took the
vaccine
you will pay for the breathing machine
in order to take a team alive
so if you can not pay of course it's
better
but if you have the ransomware and right
now it's a decision
either to close your company and go home
or to pay
you you should consider to pay
and that's it you know yeah we have to
admit we are in a business
and it's and it's it's a risk and
what i wanted to say is a vector of uh
infection
from a ransomware you have to
to consider is your suppliers
most cases you you take care of your
customers and their employees
but the weakest chain
in the weakest link is the suppliers
you have to check them very carefully
more than you check your employees and
your
customers okay jay
so yeah i mean ransomware has been an
age-old question of
do i pay ransom do i not pay the most
being one of the proliferances was even
being arrested for paying a ransom and
keeping quiet
so classic example yesterday germany one
of the hospitals which was hit by a
ransomware
the emergency life support system for a
patient field
they could not give him access they
tried to shift him off but unfortunately
he passed away
but that's something which happened just
yesterday so
the rule of thumb which everyone
normally do follows is you don't pay
ransom
so having come from a financial sector
or banking background
especially if you are a dollar clearance
house you could lose your license if
you're paying ransom
and there has been some interesting ways
people have figured it out
they don't pay it as a direct ransom but
there are companies which do
use other channels and means of funding
these people
in return uh but i mean
generally speaking one of the best
things that i could tell you is all your
critical data have it backed up
make sure you have a running copies
that's where your pcp and your dr plans
come into play have a proper rpu rtu
assess your criticality of your business
and look at it from
not just for controlled segment but also
look at it from information and data
from methodology as well
so that yeah show some how many points i
have jay if you can add we have a
question about the vmware
client can can you uh answer this as
well
let me take a look at that one
is it connect is safe is it safe to
connect to a vmware client or is there a
potential risk so it again depends so if
you're using a vdi based distribution
depending on how you have configured it
and how we have set it up
it can be potentially harmless normally
for
servers and other critical assets
what we recommend is to do is you go
with the solution that often
offers you a zero trust based approach
uh like
i don't want to name products but there
are a couple of them in the market
available right now
which allows you to have an agent which
crossover validates authenticates and
gives you access to the authorized
requests
apart from that another way you can
actually manage it
is by having jump servers rather than
giving them a direct access to the vms
sure thank you uh yay we'll come back to
you for the question about the man in
the middle
in a second get your answer ready amit
can you share some
i want to say juicy story but something
that you can you know share with us
lately
so i i'll just i'll just share one
incident
uh i found like one of the the
organization would have having a
ransomware attack because of their c
source
so the entry point was the cso who was
continuously
giving webinars and somebody from i
think middle east
and shared a link to join that and he
clicked on that link
and then he was not able to join that
webinar eventually he downloaded that
client
and when he was still not able to join
that webinar he actually
uh removed like disable his firewall and
antivirus
because he thought like this is blocking
that entire system
and that made this entry point possible
to their servers and systems because
this laptop was having all the
permissions to access their servers
so the point is like anybody who is
actually holding such
serial positions vps and
admins they need to take care of
especially when they are actually doing
any such public
uh facing work they should not use the
same system they should use the print
system
because any of their mistake can
actually lead to such kind of series
okay yeah man in the middle i wanted to
add something regarding
ransomware don't the the
attitude should be don't think it will
not happen to me
think it will happen to me and if it
will happen
how much will i am i am willing to pay
and then take this budget and invest in
backups security and make it
not happen that's regarding what
stay on your side it will be on the
criminals
and regarding a man in the middle i
think it's the most
uh problematic
risk but i i think the solution
is to be to to look to
to be as the fourth guy and you have
the client the the server
the man in the middle if you have a
fourth one
to see all the three then
you can know there is a man in the
middle that's the only way
so i think they are solution going this
direction
and to check everything is the same no
one edited
ba between the two parties
okay i see um
do we see any pr prior uh
priority changes do we see oh i see the
mc is about to to waive us
um sorry to interrupt you sir no sir
sorry to interrupt you sir
so we have we got some questions also in
the question and answer session
so if you want to you can do that yeah
we we do that we go through the
questions all the time and the guys here
they will answer on the fly guys keep
keep on shooting questions
the experts are reading them all the
time and we are answering if something
is not answered please wave again
okay i think one of the most thought
about question right now that i can see
is
quite interesting are remote employees
facing
serious security risk while working
remotely
i guess by the end of this panel
discussion people should be able to
answer that
yeah but
yeah i think the answer would be is it
depends it pretty much depends on how
you have
set up your environment how do people
communicate what do they have
access to and how are you regulating uh
your data so some other people have even
mentioned below that
using a vpn is secured not necessarily
so it's not just about cyber security
that you would need to look at
or you would also need to look at it
from a bandwidth perspective
so for an sme or a small business
company it's fine
but imagine running in a commercial meet
or a large organization
where you normally have your vpn notes
catering for
1000 2000 people one fine morning you
have 50 000 staff working from
home it's gonna be a high impact so
there are challenges there are pros and
cons uh
can we be safe working from home it
pretty much depends on us
there's always the i or the human factor
in any security incident
sure so guys we're getting uh close to
the end
i want you to to prepare some tips you
know your one or two
or three major tips about how should we
work better although we answered most of
it okay
but still people are you know still
unclear in its case by case it's very
individual
but for there's no question about it
that
businesses need to work and employees
need jobs and they will work remotely
and we will deal with the threats and
hackers will be there forever like
corona
this this is the situation right now but
we still
need to keep on going humanity will not
die over
because of hackers or because of corona
we just need to endure
we need to come up with new creative
ideas
i think some of the audience here might
have to you know pitch to you guys
some of their ideas maybe some of their
technologies also
so a little bit of of tips how do you
see things of you know progressing
from here on amit if you would like to
be the first to answer
yeah sure so uh the very first tip that
i would like to share with you all
is like we need to uh increase the
horizon of our information security
policy
it should not be limited to your own
organization or it should
cover the third party and fourth party
vendors as well
and you need to rate your all vendors
against that risk
and this could these could be your entry
point they need to check whether they
have ssl whether they have demar
compliance whether they have
issues in domain hijacking or mitm or
email spoofing or any kind of
social engineering based attack that
could be possible with that organization
you need to rate them as well normally
we focus with our own organizations and
we
think like now we are secure enough but
as i have shared initially like
this is this is the biggest challenge
that we have observed especially with
the large organizations because they
don't
rate their own vendors a third and
fourth party matters
and the data is accessed to them as well
this is very first thing that i would
like to share second
whatever soc is that we have security
operation controls we need to take care
of
all these warnings and advisories
seriously even if it has happened only
once
so most of uh the root cause analysis
that i have done i found
like these issues were already reported
but they were not considered
and not implemented in time so that
the same can be replicated to other
organizations so this is second thing
that
this is a continuous process we can't
just
do it once in a while or once in a month
it has to be on a continuous basis
because
the attacks have become very
sophisticated the mirrors are changing
every day and if we are not updating our
soft controls
we will be always interested
i guess my biggest step would be is to
have awareness make sure everybody is
educated made aware of it people go by
what goes in whatsapp facebook or
twitter even they don't even stop to
think and validate the fact they just
believe it and move on
so i guess my number one tip would be to
have awareness
number two is be mindful of what you do
so if you're unsure something is not
safe always consult someone
if not i would always say rejected
there's no harm in not doing something
because
you're not comfortable or you're not
sure what that leads to
third one is make sure
to actually practice a personal hygiene
in terms of what is being done in your
environment
whether it's at your home or whether
it's in your office uh having that cyber
hygiene
itself can actually reduce the risks
that are associated with it
making sure your machine is up to date
having it backed up
i mean people like me we don't even shut
down our computers like
we shut it down once a week maybe but
practicing that habit of having these
patches
updated and rebooting it getting your
system up and running
those are some of the good things that
can actually reduce the risk
substantially okay thank you for this
jay
yeah go ahead your tips i can if you
i can give a tip i learned as a pilot in
the air force academy
the one that will shoot you down is the
one you
don't see so don't think
you see everything look around all the
time
look for the weak spots and don't think
okay it's good if you think it's good
you have to check again
to see there's no vulnerability because
the one you don't see
it's the one to shoot you down clear
so guys um i would like to thank you at
this time
we're still getting uh questions so i
want to say to our audience first of all
thank you for joining us
will i hope you've learned from hands-on
experience of this
brilliant panel i'm sure you would like
to reach out
i'm telling you we are all on linkedin
that would be the easiest way to go
if you want to share any more questions
if you wanna
maybe offer solutions let me tell you
right off
these solutions needs to have need to
have some traction
don't just fire it as ideas i have an
idea for this for that
we cannot handle all this i mean these
people are bombarded
with technologies and startups left and
right if you have something
you need to have some you know
credibility you need to show some
customers you have to show the beginning
of
something for us to go a step forward
and maybe
look at it still still there is a wish
list of
everyone what we are looking for as
different
institutions um and of course i think
it's also
uh will be shared once you reach out so
we are all on linkedin
and please uh use it i would like to
thank at this time for all all three of
you
all our three great panelists for for
joining us from different places in the
world right now
uh for the for the israelis one i mean
happy a
new year today our new jewish new year
so uh congrats happy new year thank you
for this i want to thank cocoon uh jay
you've been
with cocoon from i think from beginning
of time
uh you were always here and it's great
to see you again i meet you and i will i
know cocoon through you
and actually participated in the 2018
together with you
and with the great jobby which is also
around us here
somewhere i hope and to everyone on
cocoon
to say thank you kerala police for
organizing
and for having us it's a great honor to
be here
so uh farewell to everyone
be protected don't hesitate accelerate
say your goodbyes guys
thank you thank you thank you very much
thank you bye everyone
you