distinguished guests
speakers and delegates in india and from
other countries
on behalf of the board of directors of
the society for the policing of
cyberspace
paul i wish to thank carolus states
police
and isra for inviting pulsate to return
as the co-host at cocon 2020
i am the executive director of pulsate
for those of you who are not familiar
with us
pulsabe is an international organization
and registered in vancouver in canada
as a not-for-profit organization
our mission is to enhance private public
partnerships
in cyber crime prevention detection
and response we provide various think
tank platforms
and initiatives for our global thought
leaders
in criminal justice and governmental
agencies
industry sectors and academia to
collaborate internationally
through sharing policy perspectives
strategies and best practices in
cybercrime management
and that's why since 2013
wholesale has been honored to be a
co-con co-host
sharing our common goal with the kerala
state police
and isra and promoting international
collaboration
private public partnerships and
inter-agency
cooperation
so what could be considered success for
cyber crime and cyber security
management
under the new normal let's return this
to this question in a moment
as all of you are aware even prior to
the start of the pandemic
cyber crime and cyber security threats
have been posing significant challenges
to our daily lives
in our digital world along with the
rapid growth of the pandemic
we have all seen massive surges in
pandemic related cybercrime threats
against organizations and individuals
such as surges in online shopping scams
online dating scams
covet related phishing malware etc
and you will hear further today from our
subject matter experts
regarding the impact of the pandemic on
cyber crime
and cybersecurity threats
while countries are racing against the
clock to develop vaccines to protect us
from the covet 19 virus there is no
cybercrime vaccine
or magic pill for the criminal justice
agencies and information security
professionals
to curb the spread of the cybercrime
pandemic
but there is indeed a best medicine for
policy
and decision makers to prescribe to the
organizations to manage cyber crime and
cyber security
as we move along to the new normal
the medicine is called three c's
collaboration cooperation
and coordination and these three seats
could get us much closer to success
in managing cybercrime and security
we have seen the unprecedented calls
from governments
around the world to escalate the level
of international collaboration
and private public partnerships for
vaccine research and development
similarly executives in criminal justice
agencies
are looking to reach across
jurisdictions at the local
and international levels to look for new
perspectives
and best practices for coordination to
manage cybercrime
under the new normal and to exchange
views
on managing new cybercrime trends or
adapting to new processes
up for investigations such as realizing
some
witnesses and victims are not able to
be interviewed as they are
covet-stricken by the time
investigators wish to talk to them
law enforcement agencies are also
exploring more efficient strategies
that can enhance cooperation between
private and public sectors
in understanding state-of-the-art
technologies which could support
their efforts in cyber crime management
during these difficult times
cooperation between private and public
sectors
is also essential in the urgent need for
public
education during the search and pandemic
related
cybercrime as countries are preparing
for the
second and third waves of the pandemic
we're sure to see that this is very much
needed
this is yet another reason for pulsate
to continue our partnership with cocon
as we also bring the success of the
three c's from
india to pulse sites international
partners
as part of our shared goal in this
two-way street of global
knowledge exchange the success of the
three cities
has also been apparent through pulseps
partnerships
with the kerala police and isra
poseib has facilitated various
connections
amongst our law enforcement and industry
contact points
over the years ranging from cyber crime
investigations
to child safety training
now in the spirit of collaboration
cooperation
and coordination in cybercrime
management
i wish to take a brief moment to invite
you
the leadership at kerala police
other police agencies and governmental
agencies in india
and isra and other international subject
matter experts from this conference
to our annual wholesale international
summit
2021 in the philippines next fall
perhaps you could pop over through to
the philippines
after you have attended the kokon in
kerala next year
next year this time as you join us again
at cocon 2021 i am sure
we would all look back at our
experiences from this year
an extraordinary year and reflect
on the struggles we have undergone since
the outbreak
of the pandemic i would hope that by
then however we shall not
only remember what we have missed but
also appreciate what we have gained
through our efforts in establishing new
partnerships
along our way in pursuit of resolving
the challenges
in cybercrime and cybersecurity
management
finally again i wish to
thank the kerala police and israe
for the opportunity to meet you all at
the cocon
2020 here thank you
and stay healthy see you all at kokon
2021 goodbye