well you guys I think we gonna make the
start and thanks everyone for coming my
name is James and I'm going to be doing
a talk today and a pls anything away is
little bit this doesn't work that's just
a point doesn't actually change anything
so firstly is about me but I said my
name is james johnson i'm a student
athletes Beckett universities and with
my final year studying computer
forensics and security app co lsm is
being developed as part of my family
year project an addition also heavily
involved with lee tackling society and
also been able to attend and the
discomfort is this quite a lot of it and
just off the back of that as well as i'm
not doing any work or anything like that
that's all there is to me greatly so
what am I going to be talking about well
the torque split into three sections the
first section is titled apples and
Packers okay I'm going to go into that
in a bit more detail in a little while
second one is called Phillips security
module framework and the last bit is
about my module itself at CLSA so just
did a shortened way one what I'm
actually going to be talking about his
access controls a load of acronyms Mac
car back that Apple's and hackles we go
an overall and then you'll know all of
them needed by the end of this going to
talk about the different Street
user-oriented and application oriented
access controls and it talked a little
bit about the linux kernel and Colonel
data structures the Linux security
module framework and then how apps Els
then uses the next security module
framework to implement a conditional
access controls that doesn't work again
I'm juniper for now so first session
section we've got apples and tackles
we're going to start off with access
control what is access control well a
definition of access controls is that
it's a set of controls to restrict
access to certain resources this is
something that we all have access
control room we've got this in place
throughout our lives our front door with
let just anyone walk into our house you
would think then we've got a work in the
gym maybe we've access controls in place
there when your phone might not be a
thumbprint might be a passcode you still
access controls in place there your
social social networking even a roller
coaster you have to be a certain height
to get on that roller coaster and you
have to queue in a certain line to get
on there there's access controls before
you're allowed to get on that roller
coaster so the app such controls I'm
going to be talking about is related to
computer specifically Linux permissions
and Linux access controls so now we're
going to go over all the acronyms are
muttered over quickly earlier we're
going to talk about deck which is
discretionary access control as part of
that I'm going to talk about access
control lists and the idea of a program
based access control is and I'm also
going to mention though it's not the
topic let's talk what mandatory access
control is and what role based access
control is as well so we'll start what
is an apple when a call is an access
control is again like I said we're
talking about specifically here Linux
permissions and Linux access controls so
an access control list tells a computer
the access rights and permissions that a
user has to a particular system object
we spray that down a bit so the
permissions of what the user is allowed
to do specifically an access control is
we're looking mainly at read write and
execute permissions an object directory
file something like that so we've been
looking at our access control list tell
the computer what that user is able to
do to that file if we look at it
graphically here we've got a file over
here directory similarly hardly anything
like that now you can have an ankle
attached to it with the user
right execute permissions on there this
is what we call user-oriented access
controls because it defined by the user
themselves so what is our packing and
the package idea is really what my final
year project has been about so in the
same way it tells a computer the access
rights and permissions that a program or
application has to a particular system
object so the only difference there is
that we're specifying an application
rather than by user and to get a look at
it graphically we've got a fire over
here and we've got our program based
Apple attached to it there yet this is
just an overview looking at it sort of
theoretically like that we're going to
more practical details about how that
works in a minute so this is giving us
the idea of user-oriented access control
and application oriented access control
like a sailor is going to talk about Mac
and our back so mandatory access control
labels file system objects so our files
directories with a classification it
then assigns a user a classification or
a clearance the excess is then granted
based on checking the user clearance
against the objects classification so we
have an example here we've got an object
that has a classification of secret and
we've got a use of it as a clearance of
secret that user is able to access that
part under them if that user had
clearance of guests and wasn't able to
access objects with the classification
and secret they would then not be able
to access that file so the rules and
criteria and mac and manage access
controllers they're defined by the
system administrator so normally you
would find mandatory access controls in
something like a government institution
a big big organization where the people
at the top or to really lock down what
their users are able to do and the end
users can't change that criteria there
so now going on to role-based access
control the difference here is the
access is defined by the ability of a
user
perform a task so rather than labeling
each object we're looking at the tasks
that a user is trying to do tasks might
be here in a file creating a fire what
if I were filed and like we had
classifications and clearances before
here we've got our roles that are
assigned to users and that role
determine what tasks that user is able
to do so again in an example we've got
our object by our user with our manager
here wants to modify that far the task
is to modify the role is the manager and
in this situation the role of manager is
able to perform that task say it was
somebody working in support they don't
have the same role they would then not
be able to perform that task and modify
that far so it's an alternative to
object my object based access control as
I mentioned before so rather than having
to label every single object and put
carrying out like that the whole way
through you can easily add create change
or a loon prompt and makes it quite a
good system to roll out if you want to
sort be able to manage it like that so
we've now gone over DAC ackles Packers
Mac and are back and hopefully now to
all of you they're not just the load of
acronyms a lot of you will have heard of
a lot of it before anyway so
implementation of access control
mechanisms again in the next so access
control lists are configured ID user by
a group or by users not in that group
also known as other now the way we do
that in the next is we use the package
apple and you can do that on a deviant
system we're sudo apt-get at all and it
gives you the tools set f a call and get
a faculty I say Apple quite a lot in
this talks by the way so here we've got
an example in a set a pack of command
the first bit specifies the rules that
you're wanting to set to this file the
rules can be defined by user with you
prefix at the start you can divide it by
group with the G prefix or you can have
it on
other with your home you then identify
the user by two ID and the permissions
for that groups are identified by their
GID commissions for that on the end then
see if we look in this example as we had
before the user rule here because we've
got the you user James is able to read
and write that file homes on fire and
looking at it graphically how we did
before that would look like this this
file has an apple attached to it the
user James can read and write but cannot
execute here we go they can read but
they can't execute the dash X option
allows you to remove the Commission's
their say on that fire so what's the
problem or what the problem what the
proper I think we can have a look a
problem on a couple slides in so under
traditional access control lists
applications inherit the privileges of
the user that runs them so you have an
application calculator same route runs
calculator calculator then inherit the
full permissions of room now the
question is does calculate to need the
same permissions whose room I guess it
kind of depends what it's calculating
but generally a calculator doesn't
really need you know all the permissions
in room it's just an example anywhere if
we think about a lot of applications
that don't actually need the full set of
privileges and commissions that the user
running them is granting so here we can
set an ankle for the user James have no
permissions on this file so the user
James would not be able to read it right
it or executor now if the application
went to read that file it would be
allowed to and what it looks like here I
understand that route has more
permissions than the user what was
running it anyway so if we was to run it
it would have the full permissions but
it's just to just to show you how an
application
herricks all of those permissions and
then can access files that it might not
necessarily need to or the user doesn't
want it to so this is pretty much what
I've said here where they don't need the
same permissions so applications can
then misbehave either by accident or
through malicious intent Andy you know
you can leave system resources
vulnerable just application of using
their privileges that's the whole idea
if I find this program based access
control list I'm going through today so
one aim of axial lsm which is the module
I've been developing is to create the
program based access control is a
pathway to prevent applications from
inheriting the privileges of user the
broccoli but that's the first and main
aim of one doing another aim for the
majority for the module comes down to
the complexity for the user so this is
quite a fancy sentence but an increasing
granularity of the security policies
leads to an increase in the complexity
for the user that basically means that
as security policies get more and more
complex it gets more and more difficult
for users to understand what they're
implementing and be able to implement
them effectively over a large area so
I'm now going to tell your little story
you don't have to imagine for a minute
okay and it's the idea of this effective
security versus potential security so
probably right now a lot of you want to
be here a lot of you probably want to be
in Costa right now and we probably also
in this situation before you know
someone parking in a place the quickly
shouldn't be and blocking blocking where
you are so I'm not claiming to be a
Photoshop genius in any of the
pictures that come up so in this we want
to get to Costa we're locked in now
we're going to look at this as an out
from an effective security versus
potential security standpoint and on the
side for potential security you could
have a government-issue bulletproof
limousine vehicle car whatever you want
you know bulletproof is going to get you
there really safe you're going to be
absolutely fine when you get there so
we've got potential security on the
other hand for effective security we're
looking at something that's not quite
this big something that's not quite as
complex not quite a secure and well I
found this and I thought I secure but
that works so you still want to get
across them now this is the problem we
this is the problem with potential
security I couldn't fit him on the drive
never mind get them off so you didn't
get cost up on the other hand fits all
there I think you can probably fit
between the wheelie bins over here so
you get to Kosta I'm really the lesson
from this story in what uses a
bulletproof car to get to customer if
you can't get it off the driveway that's
that's really what when you take from
that story so it's the idea that the
level of security user is able to
implement versus the potential security
benefit offered by that service or
control another wave of apps USM
providers human readable abstraction of
the policy so that users are able to
understand what their implement
implementing they're able to configure
them and there they know exactly what
they are putting in place on their
systems so they're really i'm aiming for
a high level of defective security like
it says there that through control of
the users are able to understand and
manage so the next part of my talk and
if you talk about the lineage security
module framework and how it allows the
development of additional kernel level
security the focus is on
access control modules with the Linux
security module framework selinux which
you might sit on a number plate a minute
ago that is a managed access control
solution that is built using the linux
tutorials your framework there's also
other ones such as a farmer and smack
and there's a couple of other ones as
well so the talk before this for those
of you in here and someone spoke a
little bit about the colonel did we look
at it from a slightly different point of
view so when we look here we've got a
computer and we've got lots of different
things that make up our computer what
we're going to do is we're going to
split this computer up into four
different limbs we've got on the bottom
our Hardware CPU memory I hard drive all
those things are computers need and then
above that we've got our code and then
above that we've got the operating
system and then the applications
installed on top two levels are a user
space the colonel is our kernel space
the hardware is a hardware space the
Colonel's job is to communicate to the
hardware of their half of user space
backwards and forwards it handles that
communication and as we mentioned in the
last book here if you were in here no
problem but user space communicates the
kernel through system calls and that's
so that user space cannot directly
access the kernel memory itself and and
it and it has to do it through the API
and through the system course so it's
just an example of actually putting
things in there again on your limit
might have LibreOffice you might have a
gnome desktop environment and this is
actually the development machine that
I'm testing my module of so hardware
it's just the same hardware
computer and it's running Linux kernel
4.3 with the axial security what you
enabled it's both TV and eight point one
point zero with the DBA desktop
environment and applications wise i'm
actually using nano is a test
application which some people already
turn their nose up but the reason for
that is that actually been able just to
completely shut nano off the system so
it's you know if you want a module that
can stop nano doing anything on your
system I give you that so we're we're
looking at now with this Linux security
module framework is in the kernel where
my man I'm quickly going to mention some
kernel data structures just because
they're relevant to what what I'm going
to be saying as I go forward we've got
our I note which is what most of us see
as a file and it's the file that's
actually stored on it is so the inode is
the attributes about the file and then
it stores a file data structure federal
data structure is actually an open file
object so you're nuts and i know'd on
the distant when you go open that file
if this then a file object for that i
know'd as well when they've got super
block data structure at the Holts
metadata for the file system that i'll
be honest the super robbers and there's
a lot of lot of stuff held in there and
so what is the security module framework
when it provides a general Colonel
framework to support security modules
like I said before primarily focused on
access control modules by itself it
doesn't actually give any more security
to Linux or the system that you're
running on running it on itself if you
were just to compile it just as it is
and run nothing would be any more secure
on your system and actually I'll just
put a little liquid down there if you
want to have a read a bit more about the
framework itself at the NSA's website
it's actually I'm quite a good paper on
it but it's up to you if you want to go
visit so how does it work well the idea
of it is that an app security fields to
these data structures those
talking about before not just those days
structures but other data structures as
well it then insert hook functions at
critical points in the kernel code to
manage those security fields and then
based off those security fields you can
perform access control them so here
we've got a file okay we've got a file
as we know it in our panel data
structure we've got our I know we've got
an application because with our
application or into access controls
we're gonna have to be thinking about
applications as well and when an
application is running its
representative as a process so the lsm
ax security labels to these data
structures you then have functions to
access and populate and make decisions
based off those security labels and what
you've what you've stored in it so with
the inode object we've got security
hooks such as the I lowdown up security
yeah I know free security hook and
they're responsible for allocating and
freeing the memory that you need if
you're actually going to put anything in
the honored security level same with the
file there's an hour security of free
security and the same aetna super block
as well so we've looked at this and that
should all be making sense by now so
this is a diagram from the internet that
explains how the NSM works and this is
where the hook functions actually come
in when it goes up runs a process all of
the standard Linux tough we'll call it
linux stuff all of the standard Linux
stuff happens until just before the
excess decision is made and then the
hook is access so that means that all
your standard deck Jets so if you're at
all the permissions that we've already
looked at any other security in the
linen in limits itself or that you've
got going on it will check all of that
first and then the Linux security module
has the last say in whether access is
granted so now I'm going to go on to my
module axial lsm I'm going to talk about
how up CL uses this little secure
module framework to impair our program
based access control so the first
question here is how do you define an
application or a program as we saw
earlier users are identified by their
you I did if they're in a group I they
GID so like us in there they defined by
their uid now app CL understand if you
uses the path of an application as the
application identified one of the
reasons for this is the aim for a high
level of effective security users be
able to understand what they're doing if
you get a user to specify an application
by the path people will be able to
understand that they'll be able to see
and know what's going on so in example
there with our application nano we've
got the hard bit nano for that so the
key development folks I'm going through
these one at a time the first one is the
labor process with that parts of the
application so that the path stood sorry
so that the process stores the part of
the application and within able to
identify those applications based on the
park so as we saw before we've got
security labels on our kernel data
structures a nap CL wants to add the
application path to the secure today the
second bit is to label and i know'd with
the pack all entries program based
access control list entries so the
application path and the relevant
permissions need to be stored in them so
as we can see as well as the application
path being stored at CL wants to store
the path and the permissions for that
item so then it knows what permissions
about that I know has it's been able to
check the path to identify whether it's
the current application coming to that
in a bit more detail so as an example
width and I actual application in there
got bin nano and are so just before
as we saw this earlier i'm just going to
bring this back up because as i go in
and explain some of the functions
themselves it's worth bearing this in
mind just to see where is actually
occurring when it goes off so how we saw
that set before visually it would look
like this where our application goes to
access the file Ave Maria Commission
certainly that hasn't got right
Commission's so it can't write the last
one is to store a representation of the
permission entries in the file system
extended attributes there is a reason
for this and I think I actually cover it
in a little while so I'll see if I do if
I don't remind me and I'll come back to
it so if you get to keep it on the level
where users are able to understand the
extended attributes are going to be used
to actually set the permissions to these
five and it's done in a very similar way
to how Apple's work so again I'm deep in
you can do the sudo apt-get action which
gives you a file system attribute
package basically so rather than
specifying your access controls you're
specifying a file system and extended
attribute so waste that works as you saw
on the side here we've got our set f
attribute and I'm getting fat tribute
now the set works in the same way as it
did for the at all but we've got a
couple of extra fields now the first one
the dash n is for the exact tribunal and
that tells the security module which
security namespace that this attribute
is for the dash V is the value which is
going to specify the rules and also the
path that we want to enforce and the
dash H specifies the file that which
wanting to enforce the permissions on so
the x attribute name space as i said the
fashion specifies this namespace in the
kernel the security doctrine that name
tells the security module that that
extended attribute is for security
module the axial suffix on the end of
their tell y module that
and security attribute is for app cm and
so from here with the value we can see
that the application nano has read
permissions on the file photo status on
fire then the idea from this is after
setting the extended attribute it
populates the island security label as
we were talking about a minute ago with
the entries and permissions based on
that value so here we can see we set the
value been an 00 appt CL will then
populate your name security label based
on that to see if Italy we've got our
file and we think about our program
based a call that we were talking about
before attached to that far with only
read permissions so it goes to read it
absolutely fine wants to write it not
out so the way this works is you set
your extended attribute which populates
the I know security label and that gives
you your papal over the next bit of the
talks between now and the end I'm going
to talk about how app CL actually uses
the framework and the hooks itself that
I'm using so this will make a bit more
sense so the much of itself is them in a
folder called axial because that's the
name of it and that in there it's
compiled into the linux kernel 4.3 in
the security subdirectory you add the
axial folder and you have to edit the
make file link a conflict just to the
configuration of the colonel when you
compile it the files in there I've gotta
pee LOL s7 ops ii and Audino see which
are my main files and then I've got the
header files for those in an including
folder as well again there's a make file
in a cake config in there for the
colonel configuration and for compiling
as well so axioo understand sorry axioo
underscore i descend or see it
initializes the module it's where the
other sim cook
options are and it's where the
permissions are enforced so this is
where the sir in the axial smh the
header file our security labels are
defined and the actual apple entries
themselves the data structure that holds
the Packer is defined in there as well
then in or did not see it just contains
at the moment a few audit functions
which help me which helped the module
check the path of the current process
against the label on your i know'd and
it counts the number of commission
entries that you've got and it also does
conditional checks on that as well an
ordinance H actually defines a the
security data structure that the part
for the application is stored in called
task audit beta it sounds like a fancy
name so last section in this talk then
starting off in axiom we're going to
look at the security labeling to start
with now the security labeling hooks
that are relevant for this we spoke
about quickly earlier we've got the I
know he'll up security and the I know
free security like we said is also file
a lock and file free I'm not going to
look at those today now this is a
description of the actual hooks
themselves the app sales using this is
the name of security hook app CL hook
name there and this is what what the
hook does so the alert security hook
alligators and attaches the security
structure as we we mentioned earlier and
freeing it then freezing so we see here
it's at that last point just before the
action is made that it's consulted and
then you can follow out your actions so
if we look at the hook itself and this
is how i'm going to go through a few
looks this nice one is just to show you
how I'm going through book so it makes
sense really so with the I know Dunlop
security hook got the inode and the
inode security label the output function
sex and I know security label to null
and then
to that Island the free security hook
app CL sets the inode security label to
know and then freeze the label that was
stored on that island so carry on the
new security labeling this is now
looking at labeling the process path so
the it's stored in the credentials
native structure and so we've got four
different we've got four different hooks
there for that we've got our friend
analog lab Craig free thread repair and
repent transfer it's basically the same
as year Alex security and your free
security except when it comes to
credentials like this you've got to deal
with transferring them over and also
preparing a set before you actually
populate it I'm not going to go into
each of them this is just the table
again same table but it tells you what
each of those hooks do and the top I'm
gonna have a look through now quickly on
this one is the EP RM set crater which
saves security information in the
security field based on information
about a big hero and I'm going to tell
you what aids so binkie our own set
crater so I've said it saves security
information in the great security field
and and the Linux bin PRN structure
which is passed to this hook and it's a
structure used to hold the arguments and
that use we're loading binaries so when
a binary is loaded and it captures the
path of that binary and it stores it in
the credentials for that process so here
as we can see app Co the bpr a hook
identifies the path for that binary and
then stores it in our task or edit data
to run our credentials over there
we then have from that unknown I know
security level set and our process
security level set so going on to the
extended attributes we've got a set
descending attribute apotex ended
attribute again extended attribute a
list extended attribute and a remove
extended attribute pretty
self-explanatory what all of those mean
really what these do is the settings
attribute it checks permissions for that
user to set extended afternoon so just
before you is set all of your normal
access controls go through consult sexy
lsm and it checks that that user has
permission to say extended attribute now
at the moment axial just checks that the
user is running as root and so the user
has to run as root to be able to set set
the attribute so again a table saying
what each of them does bit pretty
self-explanatory from the name its
checks permission before that the only
thing is the post set extended attribute
I was said to set X act checks your
permissions to set them and you purchase
their exact you then deal with the DA
the attribute that you said so you have
to do that in a separate hook itself
after you've checked both permission
Sonia trees themselves and we were
looking at this earlier which gave us
our pakil idea over here but what
actually is this well the only security
language stores an array of an array of
entries and these entries store a pack
of entry that pakil entry has a tag the
permission and a factoring and that's
basically what this is so on our
security label we've got an array of
entries which is our pakil entries over
so like i said about the posts a
extended attribute after you've checked
permissions to set your extended
attribute you can then update the only
security field from them so here the
first thing it does it takes the name
and it checks that it has the axial
security database then it takes the
value and it splits it into the path and
the permissions based on the value
that's been set the function make axial
entry then converts this into the axial
pakil entry structure and that's then
stored as an entry on the inode security
rating now if this is just an example
this is some kernel log output so here
can you see that on the way so you can
just see they offset three values orphan
a no read write execute and the axial
sorry to make pakil entry function as
then split it up so we've got the path
and the permission permission permission
and that would then be stored as three
separate entries on that array in the
lane so now this should make sense um
you know what's happening between each
bit here and walk epochal actually it so
now we've actually extended that idea to
this that we set our value the HCL lsm
security hook then populates the inode
security label from that value with our
apple actually being an array of entries
on the lane now that things are labeled
we've actually not to enforce the
permissions to our read write execute
permission this bit isn't isn't finished
yet the modulus to London developments
there are still still things that need
to be done but it's getting there and we
look really at 22 different types of
commission of reading and we've got our
general permission hooks and then we've
got our more specific permissions so as
I mentioned early or did not see has
some important audit functions for the
rest of this I'm only really going to
talk about three of them and the check
car and print park which just checks at
one of the tackle entry and as a path
name that matches the current process
then it's got a axial check permission
last match which checks the
to Mars against the pack alem trees and
then check out the match checks for a
specific requested permission rather
than a mask that's being passed to it so
here we've got our Rhino permission and
our file Commission so the inode
permission is called in the existing
Linux permission checks so the owner
permission hook gives axial a hook in to
also perform additional access control
when Linux checks its permissions so the
app CEO check permission last matches
the function that's used in this in this
hook you pass the ID own security label
the current credentials and the
permission mask we've got the inode
admission hook takes the inode checks
the path against the path on the entries
in the array and then runs this function
to check that the mask that's passed to
it it's requested permission that the
colonel is asking for is present on the
label if it's not if it's asking for
writing its own you've got read
permission then it won't work around
access based on that there are more
specific permissions we're looking at an
actual operation itself so and I know
the I know Craig hook is called funnily
enough every time you go to create an
item and the I don't rename book funnily
enough is called every time you want to
rename a knife so the check out per
match it takes the I know security label
the current credentials the requested
permission and because it based off the
other function at the moment it also
takes a mouse but those two you pass the
same permission to them and it then
checks
you've got the permission you're asking
for see that in action in the island of
great hook just before and I noticed
created app cl's consulted again checks
the current credential path against that
on the island security label and then
thought I know create and I've specified
that you have to have write permission
to be able to be able to write sorry to
be able to create that far so I entries
had write permission on man let it be
fine look if it didn't if it just had
read and it was asking for ID and then
they wouldn't grant access based on that
so the next steps the next steps the
literal next steps for me is the problem
with all of this is the I know security
label is stored in RAM and so you set
the auto security label based off the
extended attribute this is what I was
going to come back to and I am coming
back to it so I did remember I need to
remind me now and the extended attribute
the filesystem extended attributes
stored on the list whereas the island
spiritual ableism this is one reason
I've been using the extended attributes
so that when you reboot the system there
is still a record of the commissioners
that you want to enforce so next thing
that the module do is is going to
repopulate the inode security label in
the same way it did on the photo set X a
crook and accept it will do it when it
reboots based on the value that's stored
for it so again we can see here the same
i'm not sure why that's in there twice
actually but on the next steps there the
way this is going to be done you got
some more bugs there's quite a lot of
hooks in the NSM framework now when it
first started there wasn't as many
business there's quite a few now now the
steps security get security list
security notify security context and set
security context the couple more
basically all of these have to be
working together just right and when you
remove it or
populated I haven't got it just right
yet so the set security home the idea is
that it checks the security namespace
again and it then runs our make axial
entry function to populate it based off
the value that's that so it actually
works in exactly the same way it's just
calling on a different hook so rather
than populating it when the extended
attribute is set it's populated based on
that attribute when the system reboots
so the last time back to this format
you're probably sick of seeing this
image now but we now have from that our
application oriented access control
model so then further development for
this after the next steps and once I've
got all of that working to two bits of
further development i'm going to talk
about quickly the first one is
application route and the second one is
default application types such as a web
application type i have a PTP type word
processing type something like so the
first one we were looking at groups has
been that cause we saw they were stored
with you uid firms for group ggod depots
now to make it nice and simple and keep
it keep it nice for the user to you so
that it reflects the apple a bit more
and we can just turn this into adding a
you before the parking permissions to to
set our user tackle wouldn't be user
sorry that would be application not user
on that second one so here where it says
user that would be application so ignore
that but group would still be group but
it would be an application group and so
you can set application groups and you
can have the other so we still reflect
about the only difference is beer with
the application not user at the top
there then the second one like I said a
default application types in the abseil
papal entry structure at the moment I
have an unused field which is the tag
and now that will be used for a default
application types so you might have say
a word document
or word processing application and you
know that word processing applications
need a default set of permissions and
you would then be able to specify per
application type rather than the
application itself and then any
applications that fall under that type
would be enforced like that there's a
there's a bit more with putting default
permissions and things like that in
there but that's somewhere that it can
go from here as well so in conclusion
come back to this slide we talked about
access controls talked about map our
backpack apples and Pacal's
user-oriented application-oriented
access controls talks about a load of
the next colonel data structures the
linux security module framework and then
for axial we've talked about the hook
functions you want it functions the
packer design and future work on it as
well has anyone got your questions
did you look at alternative approaches
or using Cypress of ideas simple vs
these places called horizontals on
desktop and I've mainly a part of the
project has been to you to security
module framework so a lot of a lot what
I've been doing has been looking at the
existing modules there which as I said
before is my desi lydic at parmer smack
things like that and the idea was to use
that framework to just try and implement
this model and as far as as far as the
other one though that you mentioned now
I haven't looked into a lot of them too
much at the moment
so on the diagram he has slide that we
have the sort of chain of checks and
then you said the one who has the final
say yeah how does that work that I mean
dude I'm guessing that the steps higher
up the chain if they fail then your
module will never be involved in this
question i'm thinking like if you say
now as we access a file the usual a
zombie access we'll do a little writing
this would be access the like you say
whichever stage it's then denied access
that is where it would be cut off so
they wouldn't consult anything further
down than that so if it's already
already offered by that under the data
check to live there say an error and
then wouldn't wouldn't carry that
through and i started at the start of a
fun year and so would have been except
temara started research forex off in the
summer before this i hadn't hadn't done
any c programming before and i would
really turn all that much so did a
couple of months research like that and
then then you have the developments in
September but I've changed my mind on
what needs to be done so many times
between now and then but yeah
as a reason using them the 4.3 Carol's
owing their features in the lsm those
the reason I'm using the 4.3 kernel is
when I started the current version of
the colonel was four point one point six
and I were developing against that the
problem we're going from kernel versions
of kernel version is nothing is
guaranteed to be the same between each
version so and about January just before
january i decided to update 4.3 a
village before january because that's
what it was at the time and the thing
that they've changed was how to
initialize all of the hooks the whole
way the other celebrate was what changed
and i met with my supervisor and I
basically said I'm not updating kernel
versions again before the project's
finished because he kind of say going to
do that now there's a lot more in there
and that would have taken a lot project
time to change that but following the
completion of the project for unique I
can then continue work on it to update
it to the latest latest version does
that make you like a and it makes a good
case for you if you're doing something
like that submitting submitting the work
up because if you submit some code to
the colonel community and something gets
accepted some of the maintenance on that
kind of get those by the people that
control certain areas but some of that
maintenance get done gets done for you
so it's kind of to encourage people to
submit their code and get it involved
with their search that some of that gets
done for you otherwise it can be
difficult going from version to version
depending what's changed okay and so am
i under something that every time you
make some progress on what're you
active asset that's great so do you have
the development pipeline or sometimes
even through itself to do all of their
for sure how exactly does among us as
the pre your hands also do any automated
tasking on it at the moment i'll be
honest as far as testing goes and there
was quite a long time with development
that there was actually nothing being
printed out anywhere it was literally
just trying to get things to be in the
right place sorry could you ask that
last bit again just forgot what I was
already Thursday yes so I haven't really
been able to do a lot of testing like
that I do have a script because I
develop it and using the IDE actin and
so I develop it in there and then I sync
it to my gear and then I've got a script
the updates it into the kernel directory
and then then does the compile there as
well so I've got that bit automated as
far as going from going from there
through to compile but the testing side
of it and that's just after every
compile I'm trying to do one specific
thing so at the moment I test that and
then I then I carry off so a couple
suggestions are firstly in terms of the
fact of the units on cisco
infrastructure changes or original basis
you should probably out with occasional
charge introduce loads of patching ok
they always say all the security testing
site it would probably be worse you
usually do jokes as Trinity Cisco plus
I've emphasized pretty much to define
some of the Lotus code okay yeah
brilliant thank you yeah ennis
with regards to testing like how do you
approach like making sure the more
you're grabbing is curbside not just
like importantly petrol how to make sure
you can offer overflow in your home are
you checking by handling or is just
bigger welding Department and estar
later and at the moment because
everything that happens within the
colonel is in kernel space the problem
that you've got is like with the setting
extended attributes and things like that
you're obviously taking user input and
your then you let nothing and that's
where you've got four overflows from
come in and things like that and so will
there will be some checking in place for
that but at the moment there isn't and
the extended attributes thing I is
something I've been doing quite recently
so I will be will be putting some checks
in place there but at the moment that's
not that's the window I'll distract are
you planning on I guess once you finish
something off before but you're planning
on a dolphin sourcing at all and it is
actually open now and I've got a
development site for it as well which
just has like my development blog has
not been going a lot part of the reason
I've done that is there's not a lot
material for people getting into kernel
development and Colonel promos not a lot
of material out there for people that
don't necessarily have a lot of
knowledge for it in the first place when
I started I definitely did it so the
development blog got done I've
definitely got out there just so people
that maybe you're interested in it can
see the stuff i stumbled upon the stuff
that i learned as I went along with
maybe the jhino just a bit of a resource
for people wanting to get into that but
if any of you are to have a look at that
website see see what the updates are and
just go to axial dash lsm don't you and
you'll you've ever seen a place to
prevent all the operation but you
we modules of the stasis for the voice
actor and I don't reproach to illness
one present but mass common user
contributions very public policy so far
and that's all right but to be fair I
haven't really been publicizing it or
sending out at the moment especially
with stuff where it was at the beginning
stage you know I've been using it more
than anything just to maintain my voice
and stuff like that but yeah no no so if
any of you want to go to that website
there's a link to my get on there if any
of you after today wanna go and make
some make some suggestions I'd be great
and some feedback on it anything like
that javon up dropping dropping a
message or something we might be
thinking about it that'd be great