all right sorry everyone for the
technical difficulties my laptop didn't
want to communicate with the projector
so we had to come up with an alternate
plan
so I mean jump into things really
quickly because we're already short on
time my name is Aaron bishop I'm a
principal penetration tester at
securitymetrics I've been involved in
the security field for about 10 years
now my starts doing IIT and sysadmin
work taking care of databases web
servers mail servers telephony servers
all sorts of fun stuff and then over the
years I moved away from fixing things to
breaking things I spent this past six
years as a penetration tester today
we're going to be talking about
cross-site request forgery also known as
C surf for the rest of presentation I'll
refer to it SC surf because it's a lot
easier to say and cross-site request
forgery so moving right along what is C
surf Oh wasp defines C surf as it's an
attack that forces an end user to
execute unwanted actions on a web
application and a lot of people they
look at the definitions from a wasp and
the things they put up it doesn't make a
whole lot of sense for me I've
simplified C surf down to just we're
gonna trick a user into doing something
they didn't intend to do and so for the
rest of our presentation here we're
gonna follow our friend Bob throughout
his normal daily actions now I would
have a nice presentation with different
tabs and wind or different windows and
stuff but we don't have that luxury
right now so do it in here all right so
this is our friend Bob so Bob will say
this is his company's website he comes
and he logs into it every day goes about
his work and he uses it when he goes off
to go to lunch or something he updates
his name just display the ease out at
work or out at lunch
so now everybody knows Bob's gone today
where's my wife I must ask not doing any
work he went to lunch and so Bob uses
his time at lunch to visit his favorite
site that hosts some of his favorite
videos online so Bob goes visits his
favorite site it's two watches pink
fluffy unicorns dancing on the rainbow
and when Bob comes back to view his page
I think the browser blocked the attack
okay that's fun so we can actually check
and see if that's what happened here
let's see
yeah all right so browsers do have
built-in C surf protection in some cases
in the sense that this request is trying
to go to a different domain so your
browser blocked that so with that being
the case a lot of these demonstrations
aren't actually going to work so I don't
know if Firefox is on here I'll see a
Firefox hasn't
that's right IV changes develops
username
all right see if Firefox print it and it
did awesome all right well the demo gods
are not happy with me today so that is
an option luckily I kind of all right
document everything that's supposed to
happen and I didn't verify what happened
on those particular browsers probably
should have but I didn't so what would
have happened and what you would have
seen there as Bob would log into let's
say his company site see sort of normal
that page the page would respond by
setting a session identifier something
to indicate the Bob has an active
session keep track keeping track of the
actions that he's doing on the site
things like that and then Bob well then
browse over to his favorite site that's
hosting his unicorn video and on that
site we would see some malicious
JavaScript that submits a post request
to his company site in this case or this
the vulnerable C surf site now Bob's
browser would interpret that request and
then submit the request to the company
site and that will be using Bob's
browser would be using Bob's session so
everything would be presented as it was
Bob making that request to the site now
in this case those requests didn't work
because I was using javascript and those
newer versions of the browsers are
stopping that if you had done it as just
a form just like an HTML form where they
have to click a button or something like
that it wouldn't have been any problem
browsers don't stop those those types of
requests so C surf has been around for a
long time with a really notable attack a
couple years ago known as the goat worm
on Twitter it was known as the goat worm
because users started a user started it
posted a link or tweeted a link and all
of his followers that click the link
would then tweet out a request that said
I like to perform sexually explicit acts
with goats WTF and then the link as well
so the worm multiplied and spread not
sure what happened there
so the worm multiplied and spread and
started with one tweet and then all of
that users followers or when many of I
maybe not all of them
click the tweet and when they click the
link they then tweeted the link out as
well you know why not all of their
followers and I just kept spreading and
propagating and ended up affecting
thousands and thousands maybe hundreds
of thousands of users from the first
couple days so see surf can can be
really harmful or it could be funny
submitting or sending tweets about goats
is kind of funny not particularly
detrimental it could be more harmful in
cases there's one case that or in some
of the pen tests we've done want the
other analyst I work with found an
instance where he could check other
people's kids out of daycare by
exploiting us Easter fatigue
I found sea serpent acts maybe a little
more financially damaging where you know
if somebody would visit my page or click
on my link or whatever would trigger the
attack they would order cheesy bread or
visited my page if they were logged into
a pizza company they would order pizza
and cheesy bread Mountain Dew and
delivered to my house and so in that
case I benefited they were out a couple
bucks for pizza and Mountain Dew and the
company would hang on their face because
their customers were being attacked and
they weren't being protected and see
surf had been on the top ten for a long
time it first appeared in 2007 it was
initially discussed in an OAuth meeting
in 2006 but the attack vector itself has
been known since at least 2001 there was
a white paper published back then
talking about session writing which is
another name for cross-site request
forgery and so with so what yeah a wasp
decided to add it to the top ten in 2007
and it maintained its paw on the OWASP
top 10 until this most recent released
in 2017 2017 it was merged or retired
but it was not forgotten
a wasp said the less than 5% of
applications that were less than 5% of
applications had Caesar identified as an
attack vector personally I think the
numbers a lot higher but a wasp takes
the entire industry into account and so
everybody's gonna have different
opinions it could just be that my sight
sight come acrossed haven't come around
to fixing it yeah I tend I tend to see
it closer to 50% of the time cap decides
today test
end up being vulnerable to cross-site
request forgery in some way shape or
form some instances they think they
fixed cross-site request forgery and a
previous pen test that somebody did but
they didn't actually takes that take the
steps to prevent it they just hit it or
or masked it so I look at some of the
ways that you can protect yourself from
see Cerf obviously if you're using
newest most current browsers they're
gonna verify it a little bit of
protection interrupts your demos now a
really common way probably the most
popular way protect yourself from
cross-site request forgery just use
what's called the synchronizer token and
that's when you just stick a really
large random value into the request
typically into the body of the request
in this instance we would have seen on
the example is the developers just added
a really large sha-256 value as a
parameter in the post body for any
request that changes state in the
application so any requests that Bob
makes after or on the site includes that
request and that interrupts attackers
because it's a large random value which
the attacker doesn't know about so if
they try and submit a request to
ain't change the name like they did
before with name equals Caesar it gets
rejected the site checks and says that
the see sort of taken isn't there
we can see that's what or so if the
attacker then changed to try and adapt
to what the side is done and they start
including the CE surf taken in their
requests that they're making its gonna
check to see if the site is actually
validating the token or if it's just
looking for the sea so surf token
parameter to exist believe it or not
that's a common mistake that a lot of
sites have made so check to see that a
sea sir token parameter whatever they
call it is present in the request but
they don't actually check what the value
of the token is what's is what they're
expecting it's on the demonstration the
attacker would have submitted fake is
the value of the sea surfed in and it
would have succeeded because the site
didn't actually validate it
so if they'd fix it and actually
validate that the token matches the
token that they're expecting and they
would have protected themselves another
option to protect yourself from Caesar
attacks is to require active interaction
from the user that's typically requiring
the user to either re-enter their
password before they're making a change
or doing something substantial like
making a purchase or to require them to
answer a CAPTCHA or something along
those lines you see the required
password a lot on password reset forms
that tends to be popular one where users
have to enter their old password in
order to change to a new password Amazon
has started require or requesting your
password as you're proceeding through
the checkout function just to make sure
that you're actually intending to make
the function but the idea being that
requiring their password it's supposed
to verify that that's the user and the
user actually intends to make the
request the attacker already knows the
user password I don't need to use C surf
to attack site they just log in as the
user and perform the actions on their
own
so it seems to be that there was it was
kind of a switchover in mindset a couple
years ago I don't know if there was a
new batch of developers coming out of
college or just new fancy technology
that was coming out and everybody's
excited about it but a lot of
applications on the internet started
moving towards single page applications
I'm using angular node sales Express
things like that and the sites that were
created were a beautiful they were
dynamic they've had a clean modern fuel
there were a lot more pleasant for users
to interact with it was about that same
time when there was that switch a lot of
people our lost sites started
reintroducing or becoming vulnerable to
cross-site request forgery again the
reason being is that single page
applications as they tend to pass
information back and forth using Ajax
making requests passing JSON with
content type of application JSON so when
a user or if an attacker we're trying to
mimic that behavior and Smid request the
head yeah they had a content type of
application JSON that would trigger the
in browser protections like we saw when
I was trying to do the demos earlier and
I blocked those requests a lot of those
requests if you're trying to submit
requests like that if your your
submitted requests using application
JSON his content type it'll trigger an
options request the demos had worked
we've had a burp log running of the
requests as they were being sent and we
would have seen that when Bob visited
the malicious site instead of sending a
post request I were sent an options
request that options request is a
a result of the core specification that
came out a few years ago if you were in
this top in the talk it took place just
before this course came up briefly
stands for cross-origin resource sharing
it's a specification that dictates how
websites can communicate with each other
how they can share information what
resources one side is enough is allowed
to access from another site and things
of that nature I'm part of the course
specification that say states that non
simple requests require a course
pre-flight that's what that options
request is it's a pre-flight request
preflight request to satisfy the cours
specification just to make sure that
what the site is requesting is actually
allowed by the side that it's requesting
it from now we're we're gonna talk about
cores just briefly specifically about
simple requests the reason being is that
simple requests are it's pretty
straightforward it's a small very
limited subset of all possible requests
that are considered simple it's requests
that are get that are either get method
post method or that use a well it's a
post method that uses a basic HTML form
essentially or what could be submitted
in a basic HTML form whereas all the
other possible requests that are out
there are really large as of talking
about each and every one of those trying
to define a request is non simple a much
bigger pie that's Apple so simple
requests so they're get post or head and
they allow simple headers you can
normally see those headers just in your
normal everyday browsing using the
internet with specific three specific
content types
that are allowed the three that are
allowed if you're using a form element
those being text plain multi-part form
data or application xww
uncoded so it's pretty pretty small
subset of all possible requests are
considered simple and so with the
evolution into single page applications
and everybody moving to using
application JSON as the content type a
lot of requests have no longer fallen
into the simple category the requests
that require a course pre-flight and
therefore lot of browsers are blocking
those requests and then in the
pre-flight all it is is they'll send in
options and the origin site will send in
options and ask with the access control
request and then I'll list off a couple
of the things that it wants or the
special things that make the request not
simple see if they're acceptable by the
other side so the problem with that is
that korres is not a security
specification they explicitly say in the
core specification that it's not a
security specification that all normal
protections should be in place
especially protections related to
cross-site request forgery because any
protection that occurs because of course
being implemented on a browser is
incidental they're not they weren't
trying to secure anything when they
defined when they came up with a
specification so one of the common
things that I've seen that catches
people that are relying on Korres as
their method of protection is they think
that now what are you doing Ajax
requests application JSON for everything
that's in use on our site and so we're
safe we're protected you know cores will
will protect us but then we run into a
problem that if we submit a request it
uses text plane it still passes the body
and what appears to be a JSON object all
the times the sites will validate it or
accept it they're trying to be more more
lenient or forgive
two requests coming in and so they make
it so text plain is acceptable
they just parse the Jason JSON on the
back end text plain is considered simple
no matter what the body actually looks
like your browser is just gonna treat it
as as text just raw text being saying
being sent so even if your entire site
is communicating with the Ajax and
you're passing JSON back and forth
if you accept requests that are text
playing you could be vulnerable to
cross-site request forgery
there's even an even more drastic or
involved way to bypass cores as well see
if this one will actually work so let's
see you've still got Bob he's still out
at lunch so Bob comes back and checks
out his new favorite video yon cat it's
gonna go on for 10 hours and that one
didn't work either
so not entirely sure why that one didn't
work but we'll take a look at what it's
supposed to happen if we go back to our
scenario with Bob we're gonna lift them
off Bob will login to the application
application what's set okey so you see
if I jump ahead to that
[Music]
No
all right so I will just walk through it
in the slideshow I actually have a
working demonstration but another way
and the attackers can bypass cores
perform across that request for degree
attack so Bob logs into the application
gets a an active session and goes to
visit his favorite site that's hosting
the videos he likes to watch while he's
at lunch then embedded on that site we
can either have a more verbose or
visible script that it just creates a an
object on the page which is a flash
object and we pass a couple of
parameters to a flash object or we can
base64 and quote the object and just
include it in an iframe which is a much
easier way to OP you skate the attack so
if somebody were to look at the source
they're probably just see blobs of code
and most people want to care that
there's a base64 encoded object included
on the page and then how the attack
works is Bob's browser would then visit
the vulnerable or the malicious flash
page and visits the malicious flash page
it passes in most parameters first
parameter being the API or the endpoint
that we're actually targeting on the
vulnerable site request method that
we're going to use post content type the
request should be which is application
JSON and then the actual data that we're
submitting to the page and finally we're
gonna pass in a redirect page just a PHP
redirect page and so the flash object is
going to then submit a request to the
redirect page with all or using those
parameters are passed to it to construct
a request and so the endpoint that's
gonna be passed to the redirect page is
yeah this endpoint on the vulnerable say
and then the request is sent to the
redirect page it's passing with a
content type of application JSON with
the actual JSON data and the body and
then our redirect page which is
literally one line of PHP that just
performs a 307 redirect we'll take all
those take the information that came
into it with a post request and just
submit it to a new location and so we
end up with a post to the vulnerable
page that looks like it came from from
Bob's Burgers or with the actual or with
the body to change the change Bob's name
and it's using Bob's session so a couple
things went on that tack that you didn't
actually get to see but I had a walk
order that I walked you through
so why was flash used flash came out
with a cross domain policy several years
before the course policy came about so
they flash doesn't respect cores or
specification they don't adhere to it
they just kind of do their own thing and
then we use a 307 redirect number 302
because 302 redirects ignore the method
that was used if you redirect a post
with a 302 it'll tend to do a get or as
the 307 will honor everything about the
request that came in so who we submitted
a post with a specific content type and
body to a 307 and 307 keeps the request
as it originally appeared and just
redirects it to a new host
so well it may seem that there's always
ways to potentially get around C surf
protections that are out there active
and passive protections do you work with
an ax works next to passive protections
because if cross-site scripting is it
exists on the site
and passive protections won't work
cross-site scripting can be used if
you're including that's Hogan and the
request you can grab that token with
JavaScript and spy pass across site
request forgery protections actually
perform that attack like that on a
client just a couple days ago where they
had they had their c-cert oaken token
included in all the requests it was
large it was random checked them but
they had cross-site scripting on a
couple of their pages and their C surf
talkin was valid for the entire session
and it didn't change so if I got it once
then I could perform any attack or
perform any request as if I was that
user using their ever see surf token so
keep that in mind when you're trying to
protect if you're trying to protect
yourself from cross-site request forgery
so some final thoughts every state
changing request should be protected
from cross-site request forgery
whether it be logging in changing the
username changing your password
transferring money whatever is going on
on the site if it's changing the state
of the application it should be
protected and you can either protect it
with either active or passive measures
don't rely on Caesar protection well
know if your framework is using includes
some form of C surf protection make sure
that it's actually enabled and working
I've come across several clients or
customers that you know I'll report
cross-site request forgery on there and
their penetration test and they'll come
back and say our framework says it
influence cross-site request forgery why
isn't it working like well honey if your
requests included a cross-site request
forgery token or any sort of random data
/ to prevent the attack are you guys
sure that you enabled it all times it's
as simple as they didn't go into a
config file and but see Cerf equals true
or C sir protection equals true or
whatever the framework Adam do
so if you want any more information
there's some of the resources that I
used this swf json c surf they have a
really useful tool to craft to surf
attacks using flash so sorry no man that
now the demonstrations work so you could
see all that cool stuff but good news is
you get out here a few minutes early for
lunch
so there you go
[Music]
[Applause]