I'm Danny MacAskill and I'm a systems
administrator with Frederick water we
are a public utility located in
Frederick County Virginia which is
northwestern Virginia where Winchester
is and I'm doing this presentation on
automating information security this is
my first time at our VA SEC this is my
first security conference this is my
first time presenting but I'm Bob
there's a lot of firsts going on here so
it's very emotional for me I just want
you to know a little bit about my
background I've been a systems
administrator for about six years I
spent the first five and a half years
working in a jail as a systems
administrator so that was that was a lot
of fun I recently graduated from
American public university and this
presentation is sort of aspiration of my
thesis and a little bit about putting
the theory of what I was writing about
when I wrote the thesis into practice
with the new job that I have when when I
came to work at Frederick water they
hired me in part because I have a
security background and we have an ICS
system that we are heavily invested in
for obvious reasons and that we want to
make sure it's secure so they liked a
lot of what I was saying about
automation and my plans for the future
of how organizations can automate and
they wanted to put some of that into
practice so I'm on Twitter at foolish
underscore prof although I don't really
know how to use Twitter very well so if
you follow me it won't be that thrilling
and you can email me later if you have
questions at Danny dot McCasland at
Frederick water calm so when I was
approaching my thesis I started looking
at the current attacks pace the attacks
are becoming more complex than they ever
were in the past I remember when I was a
teenager you had to worry about viruses
you had these old school ideas of what a
computer virus was and a lot of times
you would get these things by having
some like floppy disk that you would put
into your computer and either having
corrupted code on it or something that
maybe someone's giving away a free game
but the free game comes with unexpected
consequences and as things progressed as
we moved into using the Internet
with the rise of web 2 oh we've we've
seen things like cross-site scripting
attacks and we've seen and now the
biggest thing that you can even see it
in our vendor space out there one of the
things that they're talking about a lot
is ransomware because ransomware is a is
a big deal it used to be if a computer
gets a virus you can that one computer
might be out for a while but now if
you've got something that can not only
encrypt that entire computer that can
also encrypt like every Drive that every
every network resource that that
computer is connected to you know you're
talking about a bad time so it's not we
we can't be working at space where we're
just like good enough and we as security
administration as security
administrators and systems
administrators in general we're all
stretched then we all have thousands of
to do I've never worked in a shop with
more than three people in it as far as
IT goes and the you know so it's hard to
maintain all of these things that you
have to maintain with such a small staff
and of course the budgets were tight and
every time you request new people I've
always worked for governments by the way
that every time we request new people
that gets denied and so you just have to
make do with what what you can they do
with and the attackers are getting more
organized in the current position I'm in
I have to worry about something that
I've never really had to worry about for
which is the advanced persistent threat
of course they're going to target things
that are behave you could if you can
target a water company where you can
control access to the systems over the
over the internet if you can turn off
water or you can do something to sewage
treatment that would end up flooding a
local stream with sewage I mean that's
critical infrastructure that we have to
worry about so even though we're a small
shop we have these these goal or these
the worries that we have two that come
up that we can't just take care of with
like the simple tech tool sets so I
started looking into automation I found
that according to the poem on study the
the security teams that automate they
have a load they see a lower cost for
security breaches and automation has
always kind of been part of information
security whenever we get into the nuts
and bolts of this one of the things that
is going to come up is that some lot of
these security controls that get
recommended
the National Institute of Standards and
Technology or things that are built into
the operating system itself things like
user control and group control and
access control lists and things like
that that we have been dealing with
since day one as IT people so the
industry as a whole is moving towards
automate and if you work in a shop where
you do DevOps I'm sure that there's
plenty of functions there that are being
automated with tools like ansible and
chef and puppet that these things are
are becoming automated daily so that you
can send out patches because quickly as
possible and automation limits mistakes
this is one of the reasons that I
approach this and I consider myself to
be pretty good at my job that I once did
a self assessment with user creation
just the simple task of creating a user
and making sure that user can access
everything they need to access on the
network and and do everything that they
need to be able to do and not get into
things that they're not supposed to get
into and I was at about 70% and I
consider myself to be pretty good at my
job but that's doing it all by hand
doing it all trying to remember the
entire process and there would be always
be something typically it was that they
couldn't get access when they needed it
but but still that's that doesn't
reflect well on an IT department it
doesn't reflect well on a security staff
when someone new comes to work for your
company and they have to wait a day or
two before they can say access their
email or log in to a specific server
because you have forgotten to to put
that information and so automation frees
also frees us up to perform higher-level
tasks if we can automate all of this
nuts and bolts work it frees us up to be
able to go to more meetings so that's
what going to work is all about right
it's having endless meetings so at least
that's where your boss wants you so let
me define what I mean by automation and
this is the definitions that I used in
the paper when I say that something is
fully automated I mean that it's going
to take information from a device and
it's going to process that information
based on a predefined set of rules and
do something else with it so this would
be no I mean of course there's going to
be a set up process for any kind of
automated tasks but this would be no
user input this would just be one system
does something think about like if if
you have a task and in Windows that
every time
event happened it would send you an
email that's an automated task the event
occurs it sends an email that's fully
automated a partially automated task is
something where a human has to input
some information in order to make the
task work user creation would be a good
example of this we can't just
automatically create users because then
you'd have a whole bunch and amuse or
names and you wouldn't necessarily match
them up with the real users so you have
to have some user input in that process
that would be like user name Department
full name those kind of things machine
readable data I started to see that
there were aspects of automation that it
wasn't necessarily that the step could
be automated but the step could generate
data that could then be used by some
other system so training was a good
example of this everyone recommends that
you train your employees and your staff
or your co-workers well thank you
security training things like phishing
training and describing like the attack
space and how they can best protect
themselves you can't really automate
that process but you can automate you
can have a test and you can use the data
that comes out of that test to decide
say how often that you want to have them
retake their security finning or yeah so
I was looking at things like that when I
was looking at machine readable data and
there are some tasks that are just not
automatable like meetings so I looked at
I had to have some kind of way of
gauging what do we mean when we say
security controls and of course there's
confirmation bias so I could have just
rattled off the list of things that were
at the top of my head at the time things
that we can automate and said yeah we
can automate all of these things so we
can automate lots of stuff but I needed
some kind of a list of things to go off
up and so I used the National Institute
of Standards and Technology and the
special publication 800-53 media books
20 families all of the controls are tied
to a security framework framework that's
laid out in SP 800 - 37 for how best to
secure your network and respond to
incidents so these are those control
families so there's a lot of them we
have access control
audit and accountability awareness and
training assessment authorization and
monitoring configuration management
contingency planning identification and
authentication individual participation
incident response maintenance media
protection privacy authorization
personnel security physical and
environmental security planning program
management risk assessment systems and
services acquisition systems and
communication protection and systems and
information and there will be a test on
those at the end of the presentation so
take a picture if you have to so and a
few of these uh as I was doing research
the things like individual participation
and privacy authorization were things
that were added between the older
version and the newer one and they
really kind of count for things like
your privacy policies on web pages and
and things like that so how does it all
look this is what I came up with the the
bar represents the fact that the those
particular categories can be somewhat
automatable to at least a certain extent
you'll see you have high marks with the
identification and authentication you
have high marks with systems and
communication protection and system and
information integrity and then the other
I think the other highest point is sorry
I don't even remember what these these
the CM is configuration management so
that's the other high point that you
have and you'll notice low points in
places where you would probably expect
assessment authorization and monitoring
that's a place where you won't have a
lot of things that can be automated
program management doesn't have a lot
that can be automated and some of this
boils down to the way they define the
security controls and the list of
security again there's 200 to 76 of them
so I could get it to provide a full list
you'd you'd really need to check out
their their documents so none of this
really was was all that surprising when
it all when it all came out we already
automate a lot access control most of
our access controls
at least as far as our local networks go
are going to be operating system based
controls or server based controls if
you're in a Microsoft shop you're using
Active Directory and we're a Microsoft
shop I can probably speak more to that
than I can any other so you know we're
using Active Directory and in systems
like that to do all of our access
controls so all of that sort of happens
within that framework Triple A you're
using operating system and radius
controls the for the CIA framework
you're using the operating system for
configuration you're using things like
group Group Policy and chef puppet your
so you we already have these tools that
we've that were we've been using for
quite a while as I said user creation if
you really think about it is a security
task and it's something that that that
is automatable at least that as far as
access goes so if we look at the audit
and accountability families and the
identification and authentication
they're the most ripe for full
automation or at full and partial
automation so it makes sense because
they are required but are they are
handled by the operating system and they
don't require a lot of extra work so you
can create whenever you create users you
have you know what department they're in
you know what groups you can put them in
and least in Windows systems when you
can nest groups you can put someone in
maybe one or two groups that gets them
access to everything they need to have
access to and that that's something that
can they can easily be scripted out
using a tool like PowerShell or even
bash scripting if you if you combine
these with things like triple a and the
authentication authorization and
accounting fry add it you can see how
that kind of becomes easier I my
favorite I love the fact that when I
walk into work I don't have to remember
a separate password for my Wi-Fi account
I can just log in with the same password
that I use for logging into my computer
that's it makes it easy easier for the
users and you know combining that it's
really just a matter of having your
radius
we're talking Active Directory
configuration management nature is an
automated task I mean you're talking
about changing setting and a computer
based on you know predefined set of of
rules and instructions that you've given
it so when you think about things like
group policy that's an automation task
it's a partial automation or and it
actually no and if you really think
about it in a sense it's really fully
automated I think I counted it more as
partial automation because I was
thinking about you have to set up the
rules but once you set up those rules
once in a perfect world you've never had
to change them again but so I really
really think I probably should have
counted that more as a fully automated
task but c'est la vie right so I wanted
to look at a couple of the things that
were a little bit more surprising
systems and communication protection
when we look at the requirements for
what NIST is talking about when they say
systems and communication protection
they're talking about protecting data at
rest and in transit they're talking
about segregating functionality to
specific servers or subnets they're
talking about the separate use of
separation of user functionality and
systems management establishing
boundaries for public accessibility and
monitoring and monitor and controlling
communications at the exterior boundary
so we all do all of this right we all
have separate user accounts for our
admin tasks and our user accounts and we
all use separate computers right for our
admin tasks and our user accounts so
that if something was happen to a
computer I don't think everyone does
that
Microsoft recently recommended that we
all have a separate admin computer along
with our regular computer so we perform
administrative tasks on one and and our
user tasks on another and yeah I don't
see that happening any time soon so if
we look at automation we have intrusion
detection and prevention that's gonna be
monitoring that gateway with firewalls
and firewall rules that are going to be
monitoring the Gateway we have policy
based access control that can allow for
access to to data and all these can be
applied at the network level into the
hosts load
you can have host systems that do all of
these tasks just as well as you can have
Network level systems that are
performing these things system and
information integrity we're talking
about guarding against improper
modification or destructions and making
sure that when someone saves a file that
that file remains as it is in its safe
state ensuring non-repudiation and
authenticity so again making sure that
data that saved this remains the way
it's supposed to be flaw remediation
malicious code protect non-persistence
and memory protection and and so when we
look at automating these we're looking
at scheduled file integrity checks we're
looking at automating access control and
access logging we're looking at
virtualization systems monitoring and
memory for memory protection spam
protection input validation flaw
remediation I think the statistics are
showing that most of our though some of
the bad things that come into our
network are coming in through email so
you know things like spam protection or
of course very important in that space
so one thing leads to another at least I
think it should so I ask the question
why is it that when we discover a piece
of malware on our network that the
anti-malware antivirus doesn't send some
message to the firewall to block
whatever IP that came from why aren't
the clients communicating why are why is
it that when clients communicate with
new malicious IPS they're those clients
aren't being blocked out of the network
why is configuration management
sometimes seen as an afterthought has
anyone ever run into a problem in
something like group policy and just
like got tired of banging your head
against the wall so you just stopped and
said I'll do it myself
why why do we that that's kind of
looking at it as an afterthought and I
do it myself but why why do we do that
if we're if we're really serious about
making sure that we're secure and that
our configuration matches the template
that we want we should be a little bit
more or maybe I should be maybe you guys
are better than I am at all of this
but so I think we have all this
automation in place but we let
everything sit in silos so we have
antivirus over here and we have our
firewall there and we have introducing
protection and and detection or an
intrusion prevention a detection and we
have all of these little silos and we
don't let them communicate with each
other or at least they're not
necessarily built natively to
communicate with each other and now
there are systems in place that can help
do that and we'll discuss some of that
in in a moment but you know I think that
the future of this this endeavor this
trying to automate information security
it's going to involve trying to get all
these the disparate systems to
communicate with each other it doesn't
really make sense if you know something
is it's happening on your network that
it shouldn't be happening it doesn't
really make sense to require some kind
of manual intervention to make it stop
it should be something that the system
itself is a panel on its own so what am
I talking about I'm talking about you
have some kind of a system health and
security monitoring system and I tried
to animate this with arrows and all
kinds of fancy stuff and that was the
point that I figured out I don't really
know they use PowerPoint so so you know
you have systems health and security and
it's informing all of these other things
it's informing provisioning it's been
forming accounting and access it's
informing configuration management it's
informing protection so if something
goes wrong in accounting and access
let's say that there's some kind of a
login systems health and security that
says that a user is that they know is
sitting down the hall is logging in from
a Russian IP that should that there
should be some kind of a protection
thing that would kick in and let's stop
that users ability to log in even if
it's we worried at a lot of false
positives but even if it's a false
positive even if there is some rational
explanation for why it's happening I
asked my boss to this I said let's
imagine that I saw a log that a logs
coming through that said that you were
logging in from China and that's what
the log is showing that you're logging
in from China
my boss has never been to China I said
would you rather have a system that
would just automatically shut down your
account or disable your account so that
nothing could occur and then we can
piece it all together later or would you
rather I come in at 6 o'clock the next
morning and see that that log is there
and then try to do something manually to
solve the problem three or four hours
after the initial breach may have
occurred and he says of course I would
rather the system itself shut down my
user account and it makes sense right we
if if we're dealing with attackers that
are organized and we're dealing with
attackers that can get to us at any time
of the day or night we should have
systems in place that can respond to
those attacks at any time during the day
or night I know that meet that that's
kind of scary because it means that we
don't always have eyes on everything
whenever we make a decision like
disabling it out or blocking an IP
address but at the same time rather have
a few false positives than to have all
of our data stolen because we decided
that we didn't want to have to deal with
the the problems with the false
positives cause so each of these things
can also inform other like a
provisioning for instance if you if you
run some web servers that are that are
under heavy load provisioning will occur
but the provisioning should also trigger
configuration management so that those
servers those new servers that are being
spun up to handle that extra traffic can
get actually function properly instead
of just being empty boxes so all of
these things should have formed each
other and they should also inform the
system health and security if you
imagine this being enacted it's a lot
more spectacular at least it was in my
head so what do we have right now we do
have Siemens source solutions by the way
have you noticed that seam is pronounced
differently depending on what vent like
there's a company called simplify that
calls it sim there's a company called
seamonster that calls it seem it I think
you can just pick however you want to
pronounce it so seam solutions offer the
ability to collect and manage all of the
organization's security information in
one location a thing that I like about
seam solutions is that I can I can have
all of my logs flowing into one location
and I can have each log it's sort of
informing the others so that when I'm
looking at say a fire
waaaagh it's not just giving me an IP
address and the local network that the
thing is communicating with it's also
giving me its DNS name because it's also
pulling information out of DNS so that's
it's very handy
I'm also new at my organization so I
don't know the IP scheme as well as like
my cohorts do so I have to you know
being able to rely on something like
that to help is it's very nice these
they provide visibility and linkage
between multiple events across multiple
platforms and they can correlate
behaviors quickly for analysis so that
is that is really great the first time I
ever tested a seem solution I found out
that there were a handful of users that
were that didn't have password reset
policies I know what he said about
earlier about password reset policies
but it's not even our decision to have
the password reset policies is actually
some auditor somewhere that tells us
that in order to pass our audit we have
to have a password reset policy so the
you know in order to make sure that we
would pass that audit I was able to fix
that problem but you know I it was
something that was done years ago and
for some reason was never changed as and
it was just left as an afterthought so
those are the kinds of things that
having these kind of security monitoring
and controls can can help with source
solutions provide a way for
administrators to automate and
orchestrate their behavior across
systems and tools so this is what I
really that this is sort of the goal
right is to have one system be able to
communicate with another and tell it you
need to do this because something is
happening so having your antivirus
vendor blocking ranges of IP addresses
that it's it's seeing malware from or
having you know a configuration
management be controlled by some other
outside system you can automate an
action based on behavior and you can
orchestrate large-scale automation
changes that require access to multiple
systems so it becomes really handy when
you're trying to when you're trying to
protect your your system in your network
so putting this all into practice like I
said when I was hired with Frederick
water they they said we want to do some
of this and then
I started looking at vendors and I
started throwing some price tags and
they said well wait a minute
because a lot of these tools are fairly
expensive there are some free options
available for managing an organization's
security one of the things that we're
using right now is security onion we had
no network monitoring before we
installed security onion and it's
actually been fairly helpful if there's
a it's a I found it to be a fairly easy
to to start using tool and it's one of
these things where you can start it up
and start pulling in your logs and
learning how to classify things and then
do grow with it you're able to like
learn more about the way the tool works
and make configuration changes to make
it work for your network so automation
can be done through scripting or for the
through the use of more complex tools we
use a lot of PowerShell scripting we use
some Python scripting we different
systems will have different levels of
access that there that you're allowed to
have into that system for instance you
might have a vendor that's going to lock
out certain behaviors and you won't be
able to automate all tasks but you can
automate some differences I'm sorry I
just read that you you can start small
and work your way up to larger projects
the first automation thing that I ever
did was to send emails to users who
whose passwords were close to expiration
because we didn't have any system in
place to do that already so I thought
well this should be a fairly simple you
know get a date check it against uh you
know it within a week if it's within a
week we'll send you an e-mail you can
familiarize yourself with the non
security centric automation platforms
and you you have to prepare to spend a
lot of time upfront you can spend I
think I spent my entire morning writing
a script yesterday that will save me a
ton of time in the future but it took
like all morning to get it right so this
is one of my favorite cartoons I'm
running really fast one of my favorite
cartoons I spend a lot of time on this
task and I should write a program to
automate it this is from xkcd I'm sure
you
a lot of you read xkcd because really
what happens as we get into this phase
where we think you know we can automate
it we we start writing the code the
automation takes over we have all this
free time but what really happens is we
start writing the code and then we run
into a problem or we start rethinking
the way it should work and we do
debugging and then ongoing development
and we don't have time for the original
tasks anymore you want to try to avoid
this of course you have to did that if I
think some of the things that he said
this morning kind of match you we have
to be sort of business centric as we do
this that's why I think the CMAs or
solutions can be very helpful the the
the biggest takeaway that I came that I
got from all of this is that you a lot
of these solutions that people companies
will offer a way that you can pay to add
certain functionality to their to to the
systems or or pay for a whole other
system that can handle things for you
but you can do a lot of this stuff
yourself based on task scheduler x' and
cron jobs and things like that to
perform you know we have I have alerts
that'll happen if certain events occur
on certain servers that where it'll send
emails to me informing me you kind of
wonder why a lot of that wasn't built in
anyway but so as far as open source
security controls go I know this is
really it's probably hard to read but
there's but this is this is a list that
I go back to you can find this they said
that the all of these are gonna be a
little site so you can go back to this
this is a list that I go back to anytime
someone comes to me and says we need to
do X Y or Z because usually they mean
that they come to me outside of a budget
cycle and I don't have the money to just
go out and buy a solution so I can at
least use one of these for a while until
I can get something better in place or
maybe not better maybe better it's the
wrong word something easier to use
because sometimes these can be a little
bit more difficult but they these are if
you're looking for security controls of
course these are options that are
available to you and a lot of
we'll have ways that you can thank you
and you can slide your food in and and
and work work between one program and
another to make it do what you needed to
do so in the past three months I've
spoken to at least three vendors that
have told me that their API is coming
soon
I had a seem vendor who we were talking
with and they had a very select group of
of inputs like they could take an input
from from DNS and they can take an input
from DHCP and they could hey get input
from like five vendors but when I asked
about you know what about other input
what about other vendors like if I'm
using a different a V vendor or I'm
using a different firewall vendor than
what you've got here
can we take in data from there and they
said well not yet because we don't have
our API up yet and I thought well what's
the use of a seam that doesn't have an
open API that you can punch your data
into I don't want to talk I don't want
to say bad things about like particular
vendors so I'm not gonna name names but
so I'm in a small company we have less
than 100 people working for us so
another thing that I've actually gotten
a bit lately is we usually market that
to larger socks or we're sorry but the
current product doesn't sell it to
anyone with less than a thousand
endpoints so and I were you know I work
in government I've worked in government
my whole career and the entire county
that we live in doesn't have a thousand
endpoints like the all of County
government is under a thousand endpoints
like that's a lot and I'm sure a lot of
you probably work for larger companies
but and from my perspective being a
small organization and I can kind of
understand like yeah it can be it can
suck to have to work with a small
company because you're not gonna get as
big of a paycheck or whatever but at the
same time like my secure like if you if
you're telling me you have the best
security whatever you have the best
application for this or that so I'm only
supposed to take second best because I'm
small the other factor is that being
part of critical infrastructure I can't
just say oh well you know we're a small
company I have to do something to
protect that the back end of this of all
of these systems so the fact that we're
small isn't it
sometimes works to a disadvantage for us
because some of the vendors don't
necessarily like to take us seriously in
the automation space or that feature
cost extra
this is something I've you know I think
that you could you could talk about a
sort of ghettoization of information
security because you have some with
particularly with the some modern
systems where you have the the cloud
sharing the cloud based systems you're
now paying extra for things that would
have just been part of your network
before I said I wouldn't name names but
I'm gonna name names office 365 comes to
mind because you can't protect office
365 in the same way that you protected
your on-prem solution because obviously
it's in the cloud you can't use firewall
rules you have to come up with some
other way of protecting it and Microsoft
and will of course
upsell you a protection package for that
but you it's it's something that I
actually kind of worried about because
are we now going to create start
creating some environment where only the
people who can really afford the to add
all these extra features to their
security platform are able to add it
operating systems came with the ability
to use passwords because they were a
necessity for security but now that
we're now now that we're saying that
passwords are kind of overrated and we
need to move on to something else they
want to sell us on here's the something
else that you have to buy that's Pierce
still going to run this password system
that we're that we're telling you is
inherently insecure but we're gonna try
to upsell you on something that will
that will actually help secure you so
that's a different soapbox for a
different time and if I haven't
alienated every vendor in the place
maybe I can come back next year and I'll
talk about it but so so moving forward
the things that that I'm trying to keep
in mind within our organization any time
we talk with a vendor I want to make
sure that they they take the idea of
security automation Siri so you remember
back when we used to have to tell people
writing code like think about security
as you write your code we have to think
about we as security professionals have
to think about automation as we start
buying security packages instead of
thinking about it it's an afterthought
it you know it would really it sometimes
is it's heartbreaking because you get
really into a product and then you say
hey
what about automate tenon oh we can't do
that yet or that's coming later down the
road but it's gonna save you a lot of
headache if you already if you're
working with vendors that are already
taking that that's seriously even if
it's something where you have to go into
the API and do the work yourself at
least if it has an open API for you to
do that
you have that ability we need to treat
automation as part of the security
framework and not as an afterthought
that's that's I think really the key
takeaway if we can if we can do that I
think we will will will actually become
like better as a as an industry I have
this theory that's completely not
evidence-based but that IT security
works somewhat like the idea of herd
immunity like the more we can secure all
the the disparate systems the less
likely it is that the vendors are going
to or that that the bad guys are going
to be able to get a foothold anywhere
because of this the sense that if you
can if most people are protected against
something well they're going to stop
trying to trying to exploit it maybe I'm
completely wrong but but I think that
there's something to that support
open-source developers in the security
and automation space because as we
support open-source developers they they
put out new things onto the market and
those things end up ultimately working
their way into into the the paid vendor
space and it of course drives down costs
I think the perfect example of that is
web browsers the first web browser that
did tabs was an open source web browser
right so and then now you can imagine a
web browser without tabs so and then
utilize available automation solutions
if you have the ability to automate it
automate it you shouldn't be spending
your time is too valuable you shouldn't
be spending your time trying to move
from one system to another and trying to
- tell it to do something that a machine
could tell it to do so use your time
more wisely set up that take the time to
set up those automated solutions that
are already built into your network and
you know let them roll and sure you're
going to deal with false positives but I
think in the end you're gonna come up
with a more secure environment and you
will be you'll be better off for it so
are there any questions anyone want to
throw things at me
you mean like what task has been the or
I have found we've we've tested two
source solutions so far and I found that
to be like really really nice because
most of the time the works already been
done for you beforehand like all of
those all of the scripts that you would
need to run I've already sort of been
built and so you just plug in your your
company's information and it's able to
move data and move behaviors back and
forth as you see fit
so the the source systems that we have
tried use there are automated based on
like playbooks kind of like ansible and
so you you know you're able to just kind
of if you're using for Dannette you put
your net data in it or like information
for how to log in and those kind of
things and then it's able to to take the
that information and and you know
through the play books to to do things
so that's the like the easiest way to do
it it's also the most costly being a
window shop I use a lot of PowerShell so
I have a lot of things where if an event
occurs of Howard's shell scripts will
run and that it'll send me an email
telling me it did something and that's
another thing that I would I would
highly recommend it as you as you start
the space throw in that like send me an
email to let me know that it did
something after a while you're gonna
want to get rid of those because you're
gonna be inundated with email so that
your automated systems are sending you
and you that's the last thing you need
as well but at the in the beginning it
can be very helpful first of all to know
that your automation is running properly
and second of all if you're making
mistakes it's the quickest way to catch
them so if you end up blocking an IP
range say in your firewall that you
didn't really want to block but because
of some weight because of the way you
wrote the code it misinterpreted what
you really meant the you know it's the
quickest way to catch those kind of
mistakes so anything else okay well
thank you very much appreciate
you