arted first and foremost I recognize the
only thing standing between you and
lunch is this presentation I give and
how quickly I get it done good news for
you as I've ingested about 500
milligrams of caffeine today source and
I talk really fast so chances are we'll
finished sooner than later a quick show
of hands how many of you attended Jason
Hills anatomy of a Red Team assessment
yesterday so pretty much everybody okay
good
entertaining educational and dare I say
inspiring
good stuff it's a little background
story on that Jason is the branch chief
of MCATs
I'm his deputy we work together we we
talk pretty much every day but somehow
we both managed to submit an abstract
for our VA sec and get approved for this
conference without the other person
knowing so a lot of what you hear me say
today one said yesterday and a lot of
the slides you see that said I'll go
through you at law office have seen
yesterday that's mainly because when I
gave Jason the slide deck for peer
review he pretty much stole all my ideas
um one other thing we're bringing up I
was looking at the audience just a
little bit ago just thinking about how
great it's been these last couple days
to interact with so many so many nice
Pleasant people at this conference I say
this because the last conference I
attended in Las Vegas where I wore my
DHS shirt within about 10 minutes of
arriving at said conference which will
remain nameless I hear somebody yell
take this you miserable stinking effing
fed well he didn't say effing and as her
turn to acknowledge this warm and
friendly greeting by this individual and
boom boom get pummeled by the two
bananas that he threw at me clearly this
person just did not like the fact that
I'm just a measly civil servant
representing the federal government
point is this it's nice to be at a
conference where I'm not being assaulted
by fruit thank you and have we you know
and one other thing just comments not
kick-ass a quick round of applause
[Applause]
you know it's it's it's not so small
where it's awkward
have you been to those it's like 1012
people are staring around like this but
it's not so big or you're getting lost
in the shuffle so good stuff all right
today I am going to talk with you a
little bit about hackers I'm not talking
about the stereotypical hacker that you
envision sitting in a dark room wearing
a hood or a weird mask or or maybe some
of those stock photos the fun have you
seen the one with the person wearing the
ski mask pointing the gun at the laptop
okay not that we don't do that okay we
find that ineffective we ever hit a wall
with you know brandishing a knife tends
to do the trick alright I'm not talking
about that if you haven't heard of any
cats before and you do a quick search
front of us you're gonna get a whole
bunch of surgeons a whole bunch of
results ignore the first one you see
that's by it's an article written by a
very well-known cybersecurity
journalists slash blogger I'm sure
you've all heard of him I'm sure he's a
lovely individual nothing against him or
the article it's just old outdated an
archaic filled with inconsistencies and
some accuracies or really if you want
doesn't matter anyway taking a step
further I'm gonna share with you how we
at DHS emulates the adversary against
government agencies federal local state
territorial tribunal including private
sector and critical infrastructure
organizations across the country we run
the gamut our customers range everybody
from cabinet level departments CFO act
agencies chemical sector finance
agriculture water industrial control
systems very very soon we are going to
be putting a significant emphasis on
elections because there's a thing
happening next November that's kind of
important so we're gonna do what we can
to work with as many secretary the state
offices in the country so we can ensure
that the integrity of our election
infrastructure is safe sound and secure
doing our little part to ensure that
democracy is safe again kind of
important um I ran into a couple minor
challenges when putting this
presentation together um the first was
resisting the urge to do too deep of a
technical dive the organizers of this
conference were kind enough to put this
presentation in the business track which
is perfect for me because I'm very
non-technical Jason did the technical
stuff yesterday so it's perfect that
we're kind of doing the non-technical
piece when if you're like me and you
kind of lay in bed at night thinking
about adversary emulation
how did Cody Bear execute that payload
on the network you know you think about
the operators behind the keyboard right
it's the magic that they work
it's the TTP's that they employ to be
successful that's adversary emulation
but you can't have a successful team if
you don't have a lot of magic happening
behind the scenes those those those
standard no consistent repeatable and
quantifiable methodologies there's
processes policies and procedures so I'm
gonna step back and share with you how
we do what we do kind of behind the
scenes that will talk a little technical
a little tactical a little procedural
but I don't want to share with you what
allows us to be successful in cats we
strive to be a one-stop shop for all
things mobility scanning and penetration
testing we have a vast array of services
at the end of the day we conduct
cybersecurity assessments that
proactively identify risk and collect
the data necessary that allows the HS to
make informed data-driven decisions that
will make a positive impact on our
nation's cybersecurity infrastructure
one point I want to make we are we've
just recently realigned we're now called
the cybersecurity infrastructure and
security agency so we're at the same
level as like a TSA a FEMA Coast Guard
CBP which is allowing us to make I think
a bit more of a broad and comprehensive
impact to the landscape across the
government and this is one of the
stipulations of us speaking here we do
kind of have to share what what our
services are so we we are not
intelligence we're not military we're
not law enforcement and we're regulatory
which means we cannot and do not tell
anybody what to do if there's a if
there's an issue somewhere and okay hey
fix this fix this this group policy you
know you gotta you got to patch that
system and something breaks they're
gonna - I still didn't just do that so
we don't tell anybody what to do or how
to do we form collaborative partnerships
with the community with our stakeholders
with the system owners with the
innovators with the scientists decision
makers and policy makers so we can help
them identify the risk hopefully
mitigate that risk in the future we were
very much on your side we want to help
and we genuinely want to help and we
want to do what we can again to minimize
the attack surface
across the community and think about
your organization's and and the types of
risk that exist and the list is long and
painful right you've got power outages
you can't control and you know human
error
maybe data breaches you can't control
that there's one variable that you can
control right that's vulnerability if
you can manage and understand your
vulnerability you can end up turning
risk into advantage because it is not
about risk elimination it's about risk
mitigation and risk management and
you're gonna hear the term risk many
many times throughout this presentation
because that's one of our primary
focuses is minimizing risk because we
can't change the world we can drive to
strive to make change but we're not
going to change everything in one fell
swoop but that is one of our goals been
around for the better part of the last
ten years and probably saw this slide
yesterday a number of our services all
of which are free to the community if
you're interested if you're if you're a
member of a government agency private
sector critical restructure raise your
hand and we'll gladly hook you up
cyber hygiene is one of our more popular
services we have the better part of
1,200 customers in fiscal year 18 alone
we helped mitigate 250,000 externally
vulnerability externally facing
vulnerabilities that's a huge slice of
the attack surface there's no longer
there okay our risk and vulnerability
assessment that's a two week gig first
weeks off-site at our lab in Arlington
second week is on-site at a customer
location this is this is applicable to
emulation because it's how we do what we
do that emulation piece that for the
risk and vulnerability assessment we do
our best over the course of a week to
emulate a real-world adversary when we
go on on-site or emulating come that
rogue user insider threat can remote
pentest that's a one week's engagement
external scanning port scanning valen
scanning web app scanning and then we
test a multitude of payloads with the
customer to ensure to see which ones
execute which ones don't
validated architecture design review
that's evaders jason mentioned yesterday
we Star Wars fans here that's tabletop
QA we look at the config files look at
the security design and see how they
they they match up to industry best
standards okay with phishing campaign
assessments you do critical product eval
it's kind of a debauch security
understand Kanna where those issues I
before they're released to the public
working with voting machines right now
and some aviation and we also have a red
team that's a true 90-day engagement to
keep that as an option something to
think about for the future our goals
I have many reduce respond inform detect
respond react conquer destroy at the end
of the day we want to minimize the
attack surface identifies many
vulnerabilities as we can and keep our
customers off the front page of a major
newspaper because of a data breach that
could have been prevented with some
basic cyber hygiene and simple tweaks to
their security configurations we all
know that's an issue if you can just do
some of the 101 stuff I'm pretty sure
you're going to be in good shape
some are our success stories we do the
Super Bowl every year okay we are
working closely with elections we were
featured on NBC Nightly News a couple
few months ago that's our lab kind of
nondescript it's not this impressive
massive room that you'd think it would
be these guys just need a folding table
or a laptop and they're good to go and
then we work with the local and state
organizations to let them understand
where the issues reside this may seem
harmless and minor you've probably seen
the signs before zombies ahead you know
free tacos next exit not a big deal but
it's at public trust if you if you lose
that public trust and there's actually
an issue they may ignore it so those are
the kind of issues that we help identify
um threat emulation comparison I'm
really sorry this has been beaten to
death this week Jason talked about it we
had another session yesterday about
vulnerability and penetration testing
but it's important I think for our
purposes today that we define a clear
delineation of the terms we live
breathing Etha stuff every single day
write to us it's obvious it's second
nature kind of take it for granted but
how many people with whom you've spoken
over the years to just don't get it
Multi vulnerability scans and that okay
you have to scan so when you come
on-site to test our web apps and our
database that's not part of it so these
terms are I think especially pen testing
the red teaming they're conflated can
use interchangeably or amalgamate it
don't even know what that word means it
was just fun to write I've talked to
people before I talked to a somebody a
couple few months ago
he had this really cool title it was
advanced ops red cell extreme yeah you
guys must do some really cool stuff you
know tell me about what you do so God
just use that map deport scans that's
cool if you want to call yourself that
I'm not gonna judge you very much
someone's gonna call you out at some
point so so for him that works but for
our purposes like we're gonna kind of go
through it real quick I'm speaking of
end that you all know the story between
the developer of nmap and the movie The
Matrix anyone see the matrix remember in
the matrix
Trinity one of the main characters fires
up end map and I think she tries to
launch an SSH shell somewhere remember
that I'm seeing a lot of nothing that
happens okay yeah so kind of cool so the
developer of of a van map was super
psyched about this because the world's
most popular movie he's using his tool
so he does what anything else would do
he grabbed a screenshot put it on his
website pretty good next day he goes out
sees a high priority overnight letter
sitting on his doorstep from Warner
Brothers Studios lawyers telling him to
cease and desist because they used to
screenshot without permission so Fiona
goes okay expletive expletive errs you
want to dance let's dance so he sent his
own little better overnight high
priority today I'm saying
you used my tool without my permission
so let's start with giving me 10% of the
royalties and take down every movie
you've ever released you got a letter
the next day overnight high priority
from Warner Brothers Studios lawyers are
saying you can keep the screen shot so
when one for the good guy that's that's
off target I'm sorry I'm way that's
gonna happen a couple times in it a
couple caveats what we do is not
proprietary it's it's nothing you
haven't seen before it works for us I'm
not a pen test or a red teamer I just
worked with many awesome good people who
do this and I want to share what we do
how we do or very transparent so if
you're if you're looking to build some
sort of threat emulation capability
hopefully you can walk away with some
some solid takeaways if you have a team
already if you're looking to enhance it
maybe there'll be a couple of nuggets
that you have yet considered so moving
on we lost our loss of thing
here we go okay bowbully assessment
pretty straightforward I don't think
there's much confusion on what this is
automated tool against the defined scope
set and forget for the most part it's
automated sometimes manual where are
your issues where are your
vulnerabilities I don't think it gets
more simple than this does anyone not
know this I maybe not I don't know again
I've talked to a lot of people who just
don't get it
okay figure out where the issues reside
provide some kinds on how to mitigate
them
and then move on as far as our cyber
hygiene and services go this is just a
quick screenshot of our dashboard this
is what we see this is a bit archaic an
old look at seven-thirty behind us it
shows the the number of vulnerabilities
that we have based on severity number of
reports delivered and if you are a
customer of this you get a nice tidy
report sent to you every week digestible
from everybody technical staff all the
way up to sea level this is the future
some really nifty clever data
visualization we're doing here I think
it's pretty sweet and the idea here is
we're gonna we're gonna put this out
somewhat publicly so if you're a sector
specific agency
say your water or I don't know chemical
and you want to see where the issues
reside in your particular sector you can
login it'll be all anonymized and
sanitized but you'll be able to see
where the issues are so you can figure
out kind of you know where to make your
risk informed decisions think of
something else I don't know I thought I
met somebody from the maritime industry
yesterday how often do you think of the
maritime industry and the shipping ports
I don't think at all until I remember
that Wired magazine article last year
about mercy if you hadn't read that man
that's that's a thing he's like a movie
that's some scary stuff you don't think
we take it for granted and how how much
we kind of rely on the shipping ports of
our country in the cross the world
so maybe the maritime industry wants to
see where the issues are so that they
can mitigate it in advance pen tests
this is vulnerability centric it's going
to help customers identify the
vulnerability is that a scan did not
pick up usually short it's very loud
very noisy kind of like a bull in a
china shop knocking things over setting
off alarms the sock knows we're there
the defenders know we're there we know
they know and
provides a little bit of entertainment
value any-any uh pen testers in here
which is a couple I always find it funny
when you get that knock on the door hey
guys you're busted totally see what
you're doing okay so go ahead and stop
like we want you to see what we're doing
so that that that goes without saying
that's by design
the goal here should not be but
sometimes is but should not be primarily
to get done me an admin enterprise admin
if that's a byproduct for what you're
doing awesome but that should be the
only goal I'm gonna find as many
weaknesses deficiencies and
vulnerabilities as you can so that your
customer can hopefully eliminate attack
path before it's exploited by a
malicious actor
so again vulnerability centric red
team's um low and slow these guys are
like the ninjas our red team is a 90-day
assessment broken into two phases about
60 days in trench and assess where they
establish the foothold and do their kind
of their recon maybe their enumeration
the last thirty days they do something
called measurable events where they
maybe add a file to a system at a user
to a group the desktop background all
the way up to a ransomware splash screen
that the customers or that some of the
users will get just to see how they
respond testing the people processes and
procedures and technologies of an
organization how well is your sock
working how well is your incident
response plan working by and large this
is black box maybe one or two people
know about it so the team will do their
recon much differently than of or they
excuse me a penetration team well and
that's one of the other challenges I
faced how a penetration tester emulates
the adversaries are very different than
how our red teamer does and very
different how vulnerable dscan does is
vulnerability scanning threat emulation
I think that I think the knee-jerk
reaction would be no but then you get
the argument well doesn't the adversary
scan for vulnerabilities if you're
looking at your IDs alerts if you have
it tuned in the right way you're gonna
see a whole bunch of people scanning for
a whole about vulnerabilities so I see
the argument so how each team
each component does their particular in
relation piece is going to be different
so I'll try to touch on as many of those
as I can so a lot of solid information
that can be gleaned from this type of
test one thing that to note this is a
pretty intense exercise for the red team
because it is because it is so long and
it is so low and slow so should you be
doing a red team against an organization
that's never had a pen test or a
vulnerability scan no because it's gonna
be a huge massive mess that's one thing
we try to emphasize like if a customer
requested the what else hey you first
you got to do this then you got it
through this other thing
maybe the pen test for a couple times
get your maturity up to speed then we
can move on to a red team if they're if
they're eligible so why am you late
we're gonna spend about five minutes on
every single one of these topics behind
me no we're not kidding pick your reason
the first question we always ask is why
why do you want a pen test why do you
want to read scene what do you want to
get out of it so we can kind of tailor
our operations to meet that need
and it for us it's obvious and it's
obvious we know what the value is gonna
be but we often get argument from the
customer we don't need this type of
thing right we already do our cursory
vulnerability scans we have quarterly
phishing we have our annual IT security
refresher how valuable is that right and
maybe they have a strong compliance and
policy program all of which are fine and
good but at best those offer I think a
theoretical articulation on the
vulnerability whereas say a pen session
or a red team is going to demonstrate I
think more more value in terms of
perceived and real threats which is more
demonstrable and compelling to the IT
staff to the c-level so come up with
your reason understand what it is be
consistent and have that kind of
consistent repeatable message to your
people who might not get it so emulation
101 pretty straightforward I think it's
very obvious to us what it is you are
allowing an ethical authorized attacker
the person who knows what they're doing
on your network
identify as many deficiencies weaknesses
as you can so what are the last
learn what assets got breached what
users got affected walk away with a
clear concise defined report of what
that was a couple couple pieces I want
to emphasize here the logging the
communication and the collaboration log
everything you do we log everything we
just had a request from I think 2016
that somebody asked a situation on a
network but there was some confusion
about a thing we went back to our logs
pointed it out gave the answer you don't
have that those logs you don't have that
information already stored up so you can
kind of resort to it later might get you
some trouble
the collaboration is key teach learn and
repeat so that process the emulation
process is I mean adversary emulation
test and measure defense and then report
review and follow-up so the moving on to
kind of how we collaborate we use cobalt
strike as our emulation and
collaboration tool that's not the only
way you should collaborate we always
have a repeatable infrastructure set up
or see two domains with vSphere setup
where there's all our Cali VMs team
server a team share set that team share
up so you can you know add your findings
your data repository all your raw data
pretty pretty important because
sometimes the customer will ask for that
and some of this should for us is is
very again very repeatable we have run
books for every single Erma processes
that we have here from setting up the
team share trying to have a run book for
payload creation because not every
payload work so every customers network
so you have to have a solid repository
of payloads and options to use and of
course your domain and set up in your C
2 s to 1 this is a little tricky so how
much research do you do for your
customers before you begin some sort of
threat emulation and do you tailor your
threats to meet the threats that are
applicable to that do that team or to
that agency because the threats that are
going against the finance sector
as much are much different than the ones
going against say I don't know the
chemical sector so can you tailor those
threats by you you know reading those
sweat Intel reports understanding what
those TTP's are the type of malware they
used that can help if you want to take
it that far you can it's a little tricky
because how realistic is it for you to
read some sort of comprehensive malware
report or threat Intel report and
replicate that very thing in your domain
or in your on your team we can try at
least have an understanding of what
those threats are so they can be
tailored accordingly and we have a lot
of different kind of three word catch
phrases I could have evolved and adapt
don't just accept the status quo always
change always be willing to kind of
enhance what you're doing that's what's
one thing that's allowed us to be
successful over the years and keep that
in mind that status quo piece there I
want to come back to it and one other
thing that we do that is of tremendous
value as we map all of our findings - am
I gonna get that oh here is no what
happened there okay we map everything to
different frameworks just 853 so the
findings map specifically there so the
customer knows how that works might our
attack I think there might be a talk on
that this week but we just started doing
that people can look and go holy smokes
hacker can do that so that that's the
something else you can consider and then
also the cybersecurity framework so keep
that in consideration we have our report
templates and all this they were more
than happy to share just reach out and
we can collaborate a little bit more
moving forward um one thing that go back
on here I preach to the teams as far as
not accepting the status quo making your
TTP's adaptable instead of having that
kind of that cookie cutter SOP what you
do with each engagement and what I've
always kind of preached is use the tenth
man rule anybody see World War Z with
Brad Pitt probably remember the tenth
man rule in that you know in the movie
one of the Mossad agents is explaining
to Brad Pitt why Israel
was so prepared for the zombie
apocalypse answer was simple it's a
tense manual the Israel Security Council
had 10 people on it and the first nine
rejected the idea that there was a there
was going to be an issue with the
zombies we don't need to have problem
the 10th mineral states explicitly that
that tenth man has to overrule the other
nine thereby preparing for a Black Swan
event Black Swan event something you're
not prepared for it so that tenth man
overruled them that way they built the
wall kept their zombies out for a while
that's an extreme example
my point is challenging the other
challenge your team challenge or
checkmate challenge your vendors
challenge your customers don't just
accept what it is and their and the
reason I bring this up is look this is
just an example of the Seavey's I don't
know when this is from maybe last year
all based on severity they do a great
job minor does a great job our team does
a great job working with them we have we
have a huge group of people that worked
very closely with with the CVS and with
the vulnerabilities but can can we fully
trust this absolutely but how many
vulnerabilities are we not seeing that
have not yet been assigned a CV I don't
know I have nothing definitive to
support that but I'd be willing to bet
that if if there's a vendor out there or
a component that has X number of issues
X number of vulnerabilities there's
probably a bunch that we haven't yet
identified what do they say for every
thousand lines of code there's 30 bugs
now not every one of those bugs is a
security issue I think maybe two or
three are security and not every one of
those are exploitable but do the math
how many lines of code in Windows 10 50
million or something there's a lot of
potential bugs and vulnerabilities that
we haven't yet identified so do your
research work with your vendors and take
it a step further and don't just accept
this on something as gospel or resist
the urge to stop once you've obtained
your goal maybe you've access that and
that that critical asset it's gonna be
easy if you figure okay we're done let's
stop resist that urge keep going see how
much farther you can take it it's only
gonna help on 301 we kind of talked
about a little bit this may be
automation is that the future I think so
I think there's an option for for a lot
of this to be automated I don't know it
will be fully automated there's a lot of
people that believe that robotics are
going to kind of take
this over and there are some thread
emulation tools out there that I'll
share with you later on and a big thing
you know transparency and if one of our
customers wants to sit in our lab or
alongside of us sit down learn we want
to help we want the community to be
safer and more secure we talked about
the kind of modeling your engagements to
a specific customer if you can do that
it's gonna it you're gonna take the next
step as far as what methodology goes we
saw this yesterday a cyclical process
there's a bunch of these out there go
online in google hacker methodology
you'll see probably twenty thirty of
them all of them different but all of
them very identical ours is pretty
simple pretty straightforward recon
exploitation escalation persistence post
excellent post exploitation now how I
mentioned this before how a red teamer
conducts recon how a pen tests or
conduction week on are two totally
different things so I kind of colored
him in there differently we're not using
OSINT anymore it so since I've ever been
told and advised not to use the word
intelligence I told you before that
we're not an intelligence agency we're
not gathering intelligence we're just
gathering information so that that
open-source information gathering piece
is either passive or recon so a pen
tester is going to do it very very
actively they're gonna scan I'm gonna
let the sock know that they're that
they're there they're doing their port
scans and they're volun scans the the
red team is not they're not going to do
any kind of loud enumeration
everything's gonna be passive and
offline this is fun part so our pen test
team it's just a matter of finding email
addresses we use a tool called simply
mail it's free it's fun quick and easy
there's a bunch of mouths their recon
energy is another good one multigo a lot
of stuff there there's more threat
modeling but I think you can leverage it
if you so chose it's a lot of options
there as far as passive goes you know
going through and you know seeing what
kind of profiles are out there on
LinkedIn I saw a LinkedIn profile from a
target once identifying how exactly what
I work for company X and I oversee a
three thousand host network of Windows
seven
host done now I don't have to I've
already finger prefigure printed for me
something else I think I brought up on
another slide when you when you do your
fishing you know what's a wealth of
information or out of office replies hey
I'm out of office for the next two weeks
at a conference please contact Bill and
Mary perfect
let's find Bill in there and get them
now we are restricted a little bit
legally if you're not doing your
adversary emulation without some sort of
comprehensive rules of engagement you
probably want to consider doing that so
we are limited can't create personas any
red teamers are can you create personas
that's something you can do don't see
anybody we'd love to but persona persona
creation that's serious adversary
emulation if you can do that but we
can't that persona creation sometimes
they'll spend years creating persona and
they'll spend another couple years
creating a persona behind the persona so
that can go pretty far we can't do that
um we can't use customer names or we
can't say hey we're DOJ and put the DOJ
m1 or put it in our c2 domain so we we
are limited with what we can do legally
yeah the person nation is the thing so
initial targets developed off of the
recon that you gather in this face
exploitation what's the number one
attack factor it's gonna be fishing I
think they said ninety-seven percent of
the hacks are responsible do the fishing
the other three percent externally
facing it's still a problem I'm gonna
give you some examples of what our
phishing messages look like and I don't
think you'll be impressed because it's
contest was the sophistication we don't
have to try that hard maybe you'll find
it impressive so that the typically the
non if you're on the red team the
non-technical personnel are desired
because they're not gonna really dig in
to the headers to see if it's suspicious
so they'll focus on that pentest it's
everybody we just vomit out a whole
bunch of fish phishing messages and see
who clicks
quick stat so we track everything from
the time that we hit Send on a phishing
message to the time it's executed on
average is about 25 30 minutes sometimes
it's instant sometimes it's about 30
minutes so we'll say 30 minutes by
weight of comparison the amount of time
that it takes for somebody at the agency
to notify their sock before they block
it is the better part of two hours by
then already established a foothold and
improbably escalated so it's still a
problem that needs to be addressed and
that's exactly what we can show them
look you guys took three hours to do
this you need to tweak your I should
need we would advise you to tweak your I
our program question what are success
stories oh yes yeah I mean it's pushing
100 it's up there I mean every now and
then we'll come across a customer if
it's a small group of 510 working on the
same floor with each other that's not
going to work but we don't usually those
aren't the kind of customers we go after
if it's more than two three hundred or
more than one hundred we usually have
success
there's our another question yeah
government agencies anybody gov federal
local state territorial tribal
pretty much yeah open source stuff it's
all out there yep yep we're to like
gnostic Kent and do not endorse one
single tool but we have our favorites
probably figure out what those are
we're not dropping this yeah we're not
dropping this hero day for the most part
yeah yeah it doesn't take a lot one of
our most successful campaigns anybody
remember the Ashley Madison breach from
while back who was on that I was on it
got divorced I'm kidding that's one
mistake I didn't make I think we use
that as a lure once I don't remember the
numbers I'm just gonna use some
arbitrary number and make 800 people we
targeted 799 clicked might have been
that high but I'd click that I'll risk a
ping executing I want to see who who at
my office was on that yeah so those are
kind of that's all the kind of research
we'll do all right we're going against
the local local agency a state
organization we'll see if there's any
kind of controversy that's happening in
the news against that particular entity
but sometimes I think I've got some
examples here yeah this is a very low
sophisticated example of of an older
phishing message that worked would you
click on this yeah well we this is what
we do for a living so probably not but I
bet some of your users would I bet you
ten years ago you would have I would
have I want to see who got fired but
that you know sophistication wise for us
that's pretty obvious right another one
o self in uses this kind of strikes a
chord everybody has a cell phone we have
a new policy so I want to see what that
is
again sophistication wise
but people still fall for it another one
this one is I'd say kind of ramping up
the sophistication
we see you're doing some unauthorized
activity for your on your workstation
that's gonna freak people out if you
like they've done something that they
shouldn't have but maybe they have
they're gonna see what what needs to
take place and Jason talked about this
yesterday how and this is this is pen
test stuff the red team does this much
much differently they're going to
establish a relationship back and forth
with usually one maybe two people so
they're taking their time
okay the persistence piece affected I'm
this Oh Oh expletive another thing I
want to bring up it's rare that we
actually have to throw an exploit at
something because usually it's a user
error or misconfigurations
the pen test team might because they
have a limited time so they may they may
use Metasploit against eternal blue and
that's kind of unfair for some of our
customers some of it massively
appallingly vast networks 100,000 large
and they could be 99.5% compliant with
their patching and still have 500
systems hanging out there with you turn
o blue just waiting to be ha popped so
it's unfair but it is what it is
okay the persistence piece
most of our on the pen test payloads run
to memory which is perfect because it's
it's not going to get detected on any
kind of endpoint disk security downside
to that of course host is rebooted that
payloads gonna go away so sometimes we
have to install a persistence it's rare
that we have to but that persistence
does enable us to to remain throughout
the reboots just have to be careful I
thought at the bottom there just to show
you that's cobalt strike that's just an
example of how persistence is installed
pretty forward pretty straightforward
install for assistance anybody using
coal Bob strike in here besides us a
couple handful yeah it's good tool any
other emulation pieces op software out
there that you use it's effective you
want to share yeah okay so we can always
remove that and add it as required
hopefully we wouldn't have to rely on
that is we don't want to and the issue
this is where logging comes in if you're
not logging effectively and you leave
your payload that's not gonna look good
so keep that in mind the escalation
piece pretty straightforward again if
you're not if if you have to escalate do
you shouldn't have to if your pen
testing and maybe you don't have to if
your red team just define how you're
gonna do it ensure that you're doing it
and that you're executing with integrity
that's a new three order that we're
using execute with integrity but it just
keeps them running out of time so the
post exploitation piece everything can
kind of start over we can gain access to
those SPS as the sensitive business
systems continue to do your profess can
your recon as needed depending on what
your goals are
again resisting the urge to stop if
you've gained access to your if you've
obtained your object objective quick
attack path demo
fishing comes in sometimes we'll do a
quick local hash dump crack the
passwords offline at that point you
pivot to other users through lateral
movements what's a good tool for that
blood count is awesome that helps you a
graphical representation
representation of Active Directory if
you're not using that do whether you're
on the offensive side or defensive side
so using using the tool like bloodhound
we'll look for users with elevated
permissions such as an admin well Eskil
if they escalate those privileges and
then move over to some of the critical
assets at that point sky's the limit
pretty much game over and we'll test
their data loss prevention capabilities
by exfiltrating some sort of mock PII
there's a tool called egress assess
it'll create mock PII with a credit card
and social security numbers you can spit
that out over a variety of protocol
channels FTP HTTP HTTP SMTP and a few
others
I just realized when we did this that
I'm pretty sure that's a floppy disk
like I think that's the old floppy
that's good or that one right now
younger members of the audience is what
is floppy disk all right so one other
piece that should be clearly defined
repeatable and consistent are your are
your SOPs all your methodologies the
planning phase everything we do has a
specific set of standards specific set
of steps so if you if you're looking for
that create it to find it write it out
we'll be happy to share that goes
something from from your ro e have to
follow that are we go out of scope
that's not good it couldn't confirm
everything some of its obvious the
execution phase also obvious commence
assessment and assessment and everything
in between but are you doing what you
should be in between and that includes
remaining in scope tracking all your
payloads tracking the persistence and
then the post education validation
analysis confirming that that the
findings that you have obtained are
actually true sometimes we'll feel like
we gained access to a critical asset
Winn turns out that's a development box
kinda have to start over so important to
note that okay ata we're gonna run into
a bunch of defensive tools out there
that are gonna really make life
difficult for us one of them's ata it
could be a teepee crotch Ike has a tool
called carbon black picker tool
bypassing this and in some capacity or
evading it is it as an important piece
to your engagement some of these tools
they're it's like anything else you can
spend all the money on a tool and if
it's not being if it's not tuned
properly you know how the right staff
behind it's not gonna make a difference
so the point here is if we do run into
that and have the time like the red team
will pull that tool down install it in a
lab and figure out what the baseline is
and understand how we can kind of
potentially circumvent it there's just
an example of a PTH it used to be you
can do pass the hash all day long can't
do that as much anymore easily
detectable find a way to circumvent that
sometimes it requires a lot of
sophistication other times not so much
here's just an example of maybe one host
it's doing some activity on something
you haven't before you got to be careful
there's ways to circumvent that that are
beyond the scope of this presentation
but we can talk about that after so
other modifications and sensitive groups
this is probably to get you busted but
there are ways again to circumvent this
there's KSA's one thing that to point
out is for your adversary emulation
ensuring that you have those kind of
those set standards for a path for each
of your operators from your apprentice
to your journeyman all the way up to
your master so everybody knows what they
need to do to get to the next level so
you want to be successful everybody on
the team has to advance their skills
that's something on which can you rely
very heavily just another example
technical administrator not even that
technical no not administrative
technical
for every different category and that
concludes this presentation questions
yes no I will so first answer yes our IP
has been out there for years and people
know it they'll submit it to virustotal
and see that's us and do a quick who is
and see it's DHS pentesting teams no
because they know it's us so we're on
the same side just the red team no they
come from the cloud now so no no not
anymore maybe before never right indeed
for what for purple teaming I mean
eventually at some point I think we'll
try to get there as we grow we are
growing looking for talent so yeah
just guys later
we're trying to get into that space the
ICS organizations are more apt to use
our validated architecture design review
they get very very skittish about us
touching their systems and
understandably so but we're working very
actively to get into that space yeah but
we have we have don't Miran we just did
a PowerPoint last year they gave us I
think eight hours to get into that power
plan or might've been in water treatment
I forget and we were able to do so so
yeah sir
technically the barriers are minimal the
biggest challenge we have is our
customers giving us what we need to be
successful
they might scoop us out because we can
only follow what we can only interact
with what's in the scope and they might
just give us 1/24 and that's that's just
not enough and they're resistant to
letting us get the whole scope because
they're afraid they're gonna lose our
jobs are afraid they're gonna we're
gonna air out their dirty laundry which
we don't do important point to make all
the data we collect stays between us and
the customers so that's the biggest
barrier technically you know
occasionally we will hit a snag that
prevents us from doing what we need to
do maybe it's port security maybe maybe
they firewall us off or you know what
that deal don't feel and us off they'll
give us hey here's a here's a great VLAN
but there's nothing in it we can't get
to anything else so we have to work with
the PSC if you want value of a scale
that's in so that's what we're running
to
no no we you know our reports are very
comprehensive it defines the attack path
all the findings all the recommendations
at that point it's up to them we do a
follow-up in six months to ask them what
they've what what about which one of the
recommendations they've implemented that
way we can track that and say you know
across the sector's X number of sectors
that these number of vulnerabilities and
issues have been mitigated over time but
we don't have a policy that says you
have to do that we do when I say we the
government does have a policy for
externally facing vulnerabilities
they're abiding operational directive
those criticals have to be mitigated
within 15 days the highs within 30 and
then we're driving that if we feel
there's a need for another binding
operational directive from DHS that
tells the government that you have to do
this this or this well maybe that's
that's an option in the future we'd love
to do that and think we're something
towards which we're driving is in the
government you know what's what are some
of the common teams you see oh he's
gotta have an engineering team you got a
sock but how many government
organizations have a dedicated
penetration testing team not many so
maybe there's a bad someday that says
hey you got to have a you got a pen
testing hopefully that's the future I
think it's necessary sir
not so much no oh are we red teaming
FedRAMP providers no we won't turn
anything down if it's gonna help it's
gonna help the government it's gonna
help the mission 100% we'll do one can
as we grow I think I think those
opportunities will present themselves
absolutely yeah
the red team's the red team engagements
are limited you may have resources like
a resource issues like everybody else
but can only we can only go so far the
queue is big our customer list our
waiting list is significant not for sy
high but for our pen test and the red
team I mean it's it's up there so the
more resources we get the more we can do
if there's nothing else that will
conclude presentation thank you for
everything
[Applause]