I and I'm strollin
s you guys %uh just of going up
like if
up right that that
up
from today like
about you for quite a while
out
I'll up up
were court
euro go
it other doors open I ob
fell further ado years here's part with
personal favorite up
doing or showed that
a at eyes out certified
surveilling I P games nixon
hello everyone so
before you start drinking your hearts
away and your liver's
up we'll get some more no computer stuff
in
so a and it would happen to have an eyes
on
or had one before release this research
back in October
okay so I was on is a camera that
I am is better I think been around for
four years now actually
and a lot of the people that were part
of the team that created or actually
former
Mac accessory guys through and through
whether it was
audio or just other kind the Mac
accessories a really really good job
breedlove design which you know I think
it's pretty cool camera actually that's
why I bought it originally
one other things though it's like many
things these days
all four years ago this is a little more
interesting iight
you completely mobile enabled it doesn't
a
have a web interface native lead for use
as an end-user
you set it up with the camera on you
actually use a QR code that will show
you in a second to
to scan all that to parrot but very
simple device very
you know very broad obviously between
distribution
I for countries in of distribution
through the channels
up interestingly enough Apple stop
signing this camera recently
and not sure why that is I don't know if
it's related to this at all but who
knows
easier question how many people have a
Raspberry Pi
ok more people ago so I i buy Raspberry
Pi while back
and you know setting up of clinic set up
as a stage
you know through my network and
completely forgot to set a static IP
I don't know what it was like most
people I just and that my network and
try to figure out where the
where this rafter I want and when I scan
my network i'd
in 45 to find this giant will support
that I had no idea why
there on this device what they did et
cetera et cetera on
most importantly I thought elements and
if it's twenty you note 13 at the time
and you see Tom entire network
and you didn't willingly put tell men on
your network
you Pasha look into that the stuff or
what it's worth
I'm so this was a list the port I saw a
pop up on the spot device
very quickly you know assessed that hey
up
I think the one giveaways RTSP which is
on streaming protocol so I seem head Ali
be related I only have one camera online
network so
thats by what it is um but certainly
enough ports
offer anyone the kinda be worried about
especially all those TCP ports doing god
knows what
the high-range so if you have a device
and really I mean we I was chatting with
my wife
my body earlier like the the one thing I
think it's los a la security talks is
actually methodology
how you go about doing what you're doing
I so
what I do this camera existed I knew it
had telnet and I knew I wanted
you horrible things through it I I
decide hey ash make I kinda wish list
I'll what those horrible things might be
so
I was the first home that I think
everyone would think get a shower right
get
hopefully that would be ideal and have
that remote access up but other things
if its running a you know a web service
we saw mobile web service ports
if it's if it has RTSP what about the
streaming protocol does that mean for us
what access can we get for the video and
the device itself
any embedded device has a few you know
core tenants
up from where obviously being one of
them and and other aspects in
it's a camera supply stores data or send
data how do we
intercept that hurt you do things
related to the the camera storage
so again
the entire setup is actually done just
with your mobile app I
it is an I was the only device so you
have your mobile app you have your
camera
I you scan a QR code that you basically
encoded with your SSID and
in oppa JIP here whenever
and this screenshot when I was spring
this deck together while back I
was kinda lazy and didn't wanna just you
know take a screenshot my phone or
something
I don't know why didn't you that but on
so I did a google image search like most
most do and I found this Georgia and I
was like hey you know what's interesting
is
this qr-code like from their marketing
materials i were with the QR code says
I look at the QR code I know it's a
little hard to see but
on the the actual
network is actually stem office 136
and stem innovation is the company that
makes this camera and then the password
is we love Apple
so I've never you know gone out to I
think where they're based in
in Utah by drive by their office ever
and happen issues
SSID you might wanna try that password
so multicast DNS
is one thing that you'll see with a lot
of embedded devices generally if you
have
I something pop in your networking needs
to be set up multicast you know this is
a very quick way to help that parent
process get
get rolling I we see this with I am of
course IP cameras but things like
printers
a a camp like DSLR cameras that have
wifi modules
many similar uses like that so one thing
that we can notice quickly is just some
basics about what the camera is
so it has an arm ship which isn't to
pursue pricing and funny when X which
also isn't super surprising that the
meeting case most the time we're looking
at devices like these
one thing I saw initially though when I
was going you know sorry a look at this
this network traffic with the camera is
I did scene when you
basic bootstrap the camera and start up
for the first time after a factory reset
it sends over this r/c publishing now
if you see public your network from up
and was like a Camry like oh that's
that's good for them it seems like
they're gonna transmit this to me that
and I can
encrypt data and send a back over and
you know have some
integrity to this process on we'll talk
about that
and in just a second I the one thing
that we do see
and I do mean the one thing that we do
see is the
admin password when it's generated it
actually comes over and it's in cryptid
and a few only thing cryptid with on you
know with that public key to be
deliver in the crib you the private key
on the other side so basically doing a
secure transfer about generating
I admin password from one side to the
other so
and that's that's perfectly reasonable
that the I could use a crypto and pretty
common way to do things
onto to jump ahead to slightly in you
guys already know the stocks gonna go
downhill for them for security zone
I'm not really spoiler alert in too much
but I 1
you know one you little the stove ideas
that you should I know about as well as
the camera can only pick up I
attached wanna Canada time that means if
you know like
my wife she can't have of the camera
cache her account
and my count the same time which means
you have to have sure credentials if you
wanna have access to this camera which
is never a good thing I'll when the
device resets though it does pose to
factory mode
these are some that no process output on
the camera
and I I really like this part because
it's the most literal thing ever
it's been factory reset completers
worries that like very little thing
very few things and software is that
were that strict for what it actually
doing so
I found that amusing but the other thing
to know is the admin password
if you do and change that password
everything breaks and
it gets really really unhappy with you
so
in terms over what you could do to
access this camera
there's certainly %ah broad very
Broadway I
you know number ways to go through
trying to gain access
and depends how much time you wanna
spend you know you could go the route up
hey I know this run some web software
lets try to you you know exploit the CGI
ap and try to get like
you know remote code execution or
something right okay that's that's one
route
I'll because the admin password going
over the wire
hurted that seems like a bad idea you
mean you know even though you might not
want to use 1024
our essay to do certain things I wasn't
too
you know concerned like out actually
want to go down that road
it just seems like a fool's errand to
tried you know reports that caused it
could be
a five digit are a5 I'll pick me up nam
Tai password it can be it
a hundred digits or something i you know
I don't know so why waste time there's
gotta be a better way
looking at the traffic you can actually
see that it's doing
HDB HTTP Digest mode for all the actual
on a ATP call everything about I just
mowed
that you need to know effectively is a
bunch of data is public about those
operations like a bunch of the data
coming over those connections is public
on it's all cleared out a cleartext the
one thing that matters
is when you actually compute the digest
about transaction
unless you know the secret key that's
actually creating that said
that he'd I just basically I you can't
do anything
so again if we don't have the password
we have nothing with that told that
I'll try to brute force that sure
you know we have we have network access
to it up but you know connectivity
issues if there's any
modeling built-in if I if the device
just melt become
hit you hard the slight downside to that
it's not like I'm doing a local attack
against like a password hash
it's not so we can be fast or that that
could have an idea
I'm also super impatient and her
modifications nothing I'm super firmly
with I've learned a little bit since
then
up but it's also not you know that time
the
a cuppa tea so things I do know about
I'll
well we'll talk about a little bit a
dripping taps secret the maps is
something that's very easy to do with a
jailbroken phone
I you can do this the hard way you can
GB in you know
you going for a couple stops up but
there are there are applica watch
Arrested crack
I that will do the trick the decryption
for you
as when you submit an app to the App
Store it's actually in cryptid binary
effectively
and when your phone runs of course to
run that app it has to be crib that
otherwise it wouldn't be able to do
anything
so effectively what you're doing and and
and the GB route
effectively short-circuit batted say out
that app is running
and therefore I'm gonna dump memory and
then save this
uninterrupted binary no happy ap so you
can actually I made that very quickly
and once you have the app its kinda crap
shoot as to you if you'll find anything
interesting
lucky for me I found very interesting
stuff in that mobile app
and is worse stuff starts in paris by so
I if you are SuperPro you might use I
don't look at stuff like this are hopper
on Mac or something else
I'll or also if you're like me and
sometimes just want to get some ASCII
austrians is perfectly acceptable to to
find a to so
the top one is kinda more broken up at
the bottom one i think is more salient
that bottom image actually shows a bunch
of contact from this mobile app
all which is effectively one giant shell
script and what that shell scripts the
fact we doing
is its shell script that we'll kinda
bootstrap the firmware upgrade process
and in order to do that it actually
connects to telnet
as root and then basically haps out
a bash script to start this for market
process that is how this camera was
designed to operate itself
with the mobile app so I'll
you effectively have just because the
script in there and ask if course
you have the rip at username and your
password
not just for my camera but for all the
cameras right so
this this falls under the guise of not a
default password but hardcore password
and sometimes people complete the two
combo the default password would be like
your
week this writer has admin admin or
something right well in this case
I don't know if I'm a consumer an
end-user I don't know that there's an
admin group account on this camera I
certainly don't
I know how helmet is right us on this
case there's nothing I could do about
that as a consumer I'm just
up you know I'm lost basically that this
is ahead in value in
and there's nothing I can do about it on
so it seems we get a room login I'm
secure LogMeIn great you know
geiger shelling and do a little dance so
there's the
screenshot everyone takes when they get
rid on anything I'll
so one other tell we see a fact that we
just don't curl the running we are you
are we are news when X so just give us a
little more detail
of course the actual network services
kinda interesting
we knew about mostly those because of
course they their mapped publicly
some the TCP job services running our
not public so
is kinda mixture there mike is more
clarity in the house cameras running
I'm certainly there's a lot softer on
these devices that make big all that
you know different aspects of my IP
camera stream in saving files and
encoding and all this other stuff work
on thats of cool I don't really think
too much look at that
other than what I need to do really keep
breaking stuff
so the shadow file office was actually
using does gripped
which no one should be using desperate
past like 1998
on so this is this is a very common
scenario where
organizations will get like standard
firmware from you know some Chinese
odiaum
and never ever look at it never
interrogated never
hatchet or update or anything else and
the admin password to slash admin slash
and then Merlin I those are actually
hard put a password that come with this
firmware
I had someone else reach out after after
someone saw this talk
and they said hey I know that I know
that username and password
and actually showed me the exact
firmware that this device run that was
just
open you know to the public from from a
distributor up with those those are hard
to passwords in
many devices not just this device aus
dem root of course is the
it cost them one for the repass were but
not a very good one either
on certainly polly I could've helmet up
in a brick or stone and got ask route
without too much trouble
but the thing is a if it to know if it's
known pointedly oh sure I could play
Brick Force that
but again if there was an capitals in
their numbers in there anything else or
taking Muni
a long time mind if I didn't scope what
you know what character sudden stop
so hindsight right
in terms of how do you buy that were the
web app is
I punchy for lobby core crass but the
camera
I rings one young lady so you know
pretty standard lightweight
what web server on big fan personally
and because it's using lady I had seen
previously
if you go to the web you know the Weber
you give your basic authentication type
screen son who was doing some some for
access control
it's just using i-eighty password
effectively ratio access if you will
and so like again I see a user an admin
and I see a hash and I could do an
offline attack against the passions and
see if I can crack down
or just look around the file system and
end up finding that there's a config
file
that has the clear text equivalents of
those passwords so that
I get much easier I like to try to not
waste my time on stupid shit
so I'm this case you might see the one
where it says user user
that is another hardcoded password that
the the end user has no knowledge I love
has no capability to change
the admin password for more we talk
slightly about
me the the transfer of this big Pappa
are the saudis are saying cryptid packin
I'll that wear a wire while again had
tried to put forth that password I
probably would have been way in a really
long time
on that not a quick password to
brute-force somewhat anyways time there
up with the user user1 certainly
interesting on this and this is
useful to think about because remember I
said like this a lot of ways or
course the problem tryna you know gets
access into single stop
I in the case a user user had wanna my
routes been hey I should try to you
I'm just you them for like dictionary
attack against
this web server I prolly woulda gotten
pretty pretty quick
obligate you you never know and
sometimes it's easier to go down the
road that you know are quick
maybe they won't be successful but at
least you know don't spin your wheels
more than you have to
so the camera runs a whole web spot
you know the full web server but it
actually has a full web ap
that actually does basically everything
and more
that mobile app does for you and in fact
a lot about the mobile app to doing
is actually just proxy in fruit man's to
his back and web interface
and it's been stuff out into the aisle
asap %uh so very intelligent
I it's not like a RESTful API anything
sexy it's like hey I miss an HP call at
this
web app and it'll something data back
and see what happens getting back to
what consumers no verse what they don't
know
again this is not a document thing you
at no point I'm
any documentation say hey you have a web
server running on this camera
hey if you wanna login do this new US
consumer never know that
on when you login with the use user
credentials
unlike certain privilege you know level
that might see on devices like this
where they might really restricted in
that part out what you can do
Abu user-level basically what you do any
read operation were lost
but no write operations for the most
part and in this case you can watch the
video
you can listen to audio you can make it
streaming video streaming images there's
actually a of Flash interface in here
I'll you can also see most interestingly
enough you can also see me
API keys for all the third-party
services that the scammers using
so even though you have this user user
login and you can't change settings on
the camera with it
you can get the API keys to which you
can then just communicate directly to
mister pretty services
and do whatever you want those
you also have for more details and
configuration for things like
on motion alarms and sound alarms
I think that which is up
Ari go perfect with you
within that sweet by access that you
have for the User user
you can actually do things like a dual
wireless can so I don't know about you I
definitely had neighbors in the past
that would put stuff like their families
bowl like
you know name for their street address
for their home address like crazy stuff
that
knowing he would ever do but like we all
have had neighbors that would do stuff
like that
I'll soul but you now playing
I guess devil's advocate in this case on
if I were
you know going on showed and looking at
a buncha cameras grammy night he's all
that jazz
on yeah of course with the type you get
a usually with by Karen daily meal
you know your location roughly on and
then let's say you have another piece of
data like a street address or
family name or something else you
actually might be a little work out
where this rule
remote camera actually is and who owns
in which house it is so
that's interesting operates more
interesting because
in with this user user said a
credentialed you can actually see where
the emotional arms are
and you can see what the sensitivity up
the audio alarms are maybe they turn off
my alarm comes with knowing her daughter
some right
ob but if I'm if I'm breaking in your
house i'd have to stay below that my
email
boxes there with up and the motion alarm
will never go all
so this is good in calendar to break
into someone's house and you are you can
see inside their house to see if maybe
someone's home or they just left or
something else
you can also in enable this beautiful
Flash interface if you're so inclined
one one thing to know i mean to scare
with a good camera the the video quality
is
kinda you know passable I guess at the
end of the day but the audio
oMG the stairway in the back is you know
I don't know twenty-some-odd
me from where the camera is and when I
was doing some the test like I could
hear my wife
watching TV upstairs so audio pickups
really good which for
on you as a homeowner is a great thing
but also for criminals
an equally great thing I'm sober tonight
chart ob left side is just for more
details
on notably there's a a web interface to
actually do the firmware updates now of
course in this
in this configuration we don't have up
access to upload for more
up but remember that config file that we
we found the we will convict file
had the admin password so you could just
on as you know
talent in had out you know the the admin
password from that vial
log in as the admin June web interface
and actually just pass it the URL
up new firmware and we actually update
or you just from the web interface
a very simple process in want one thing
I
I was really out in Boston and at this I
G security about
and dangerous parking I and yes the
whole premise in
1i guess his latest you know really in
thesis is
I having a slight end-of-life built into
embedded devices because they're so on
maintainable on the whole
and you know there's also the promise
I'll how do you really verify integrity
up something like this ever because
you're trusting
the device to tell you that up-to-date
ortzy
or whatever the case might be so I
update firmware
on your device I can just always turn
off that it will never update for more
again and never override my settings so
once you have a device on your network
like this after you are and hopefully
even by time you get a
your house after you open the box and
put on your network you really can't for
sure say probably that actually secure
still
on which has you know some concern
implications
%uh you of people things like what ledu
highlights on an often for people out
and I'm
the bottom right pane is just some
details about the API stuff that we're
talking about earlier where you have
access to any third party services
and can see details in televisions one
of the vendors that they were using
I in television and I is effectively
where they're storing all
the videos for alerts so if you had a
motion or audio alert this is where that
they
upload the file and television is just
using Amazon s3 on the back n
so one other thing I'd like to talk
about in
kinda scoping iraqi security and and US
consumers is
you know when I bought this camera and
set it up in creating my account with
these get with with this vendor
on I never knew that I was going to be
also up customer
up in television or these other ones
I'll talk to you about but like I didn't
know my dad would go to s3
you know there are some sure prolly
became and it is probably going to data
center Mike under
arms are just keep in mind as you're
you're buying these things and
transmitting data
I unless it's spelt out very very
straightforward
you probably don't know how many banners
on the back end are actually getting
your details
your date on and what happens if you're
better goes away
or that third parties you break the
contract what does that mean for them to
actually have more data anymore
%uh or you have in your date anymore
the files themselves in that in that
Amazon s3 bucket for their story and
out one bucket so if you're in a WS
person you know that you should
generally segment
user data out into mop bucket to not
have one giant bucket evolved a tuple
they also were doing any form access
control other than the back about
unique URL so if you ever did see the
URL
I by the way all these API calls are
clear text and all the axis
s3 was clear taxed so if you're aburto
10 on a network and you man
and the milling Starbucks you would see
all the data wind I and have always
access anyways
%ah there's no encryption done by the
camera the mobile app before this day is
uploaded so if you have a URL you can
download the file without
without questioners there's nothing else
you up the one below
big caveat here and on you know does the
same boilerplate
thing as every single time is I found
hardcore credentials for a.w.s
API keys in the mobile app I never
tested them because that would be a
really really obvious in blatant us yet
a violation
ob however contextually let's keep in
mind
one bucket all files go to that place op
I have access to the camera so I know
the camera doesn't have any additional
a blessed keys I know the mobile app
doesn't have any additional a top US
keys
so if I'm going to make you know that
happen in Burns I would say that both
he's probably rule them all and would
have probably give me access to all the
files for all users at one time
um but the company never confirmed %uh
nor denied that was the case when I told
them
on hands and subsequently that doesn't
work the same way
it at you stoop so hopefully they fix
some stuff in there
and now it's bad enough that your data
wouldn't be in crypt in when it's
uploaded judas third-party surfing and I
know whereof
I its all so bad that the files were
protected by access controls our
credentials at all
on but also from the mobile app remember
everything's in the model at all
I actually found that if you deleted a
file using the mobile app which is the
only way to delete a file
I it might actually not the week while I
deleted a file from mobile app it was
there two months later I think I checked
a couple more subsequent times
and it's one of those things where if
you have a video that gets uploaded
accidentally
on walk to your house your dog parks in
your naked alright you're like oh that's
funny haha
I would like this video on the internet
know you might actually not the week the
beauty of the Internet
and now we are not too lenient from the
internet with your vendor
you're not leaving it with the third
party vendor who then using another
third party vendor store
you have no idea that files there the
only reason I know that by always there
after the back is because I knew what to
look for and what you are holding 02
on and I was honestly kinda happenstance
that I even realized that
so up pretty terrifying when you think
about where your day is at hand
and what what else is out there that
you're unaware of who will you know who
has that
I'm UX UI see us I'll
they're the people that do the actual
stream in so if you're your amo anyone
stream the video camera to your mobile
app they're the people that actually
opera provide that service the
data that's being streamed and this is
where the
the web interface really comes in
importantly when you request
actually act access your camera though
the way that works
is that I'll there's Damon on
the camera that's making a connection
outbound to
on their streaming server and then your
mobile app
is contacting service provider and
all they're doing is basically proxy new
you are literally seen
this web interface affectively in your
mobile app and just have no idea
and it's not it's not like you're
streaming video from their server
your streaming video from your whole
literally
it's just proximate through their server
%ah so in terms of network
attacks if they have on outbound TCP
connection
that you have direct access to a web
server with if you can find a
multi-billion at web service without
knowing credential rendell's
you can just break-in and you know
execute code or something beyond network
in ATCO tendency with the rest the
network that this device is on
and a lot of hype on you know IP in
in a I embedded type devices like
cameras and similar
are actually going about this in a
similar way which is terrifying
I and I a more ideal way would be data
streams outbound from your network
throughout
up their party service or whatever and
then you connect to that service
and they're basically passion that data
and streaming it live
not opening a proxy connection between
your two networks
that's that's no bueno on you know
having at no point that
terminate those connections and doesn't
like him back in the other ways
is much better way to go
if you can see in the screenshot on by
the way I I'd regret cutting off the
fact that it says HDPE
so it's not a cryptic either on it has a
proxy nine that no it's not that and in
some high number port
flash mob lied I those
I those and points I you know assembly
you can a numerate those
I never tried to actually see if I can
see other peoples cameras by enumerating
those
you know knock yourself out a few wanna
go down that road but
I would recommend it on its 10 things
though
you again as an end-user does you not
know that you have this
open connection for the internet to be
inside her house
like no one's told you that that's how
this works and that's frustrating and
and more frustrating as I said is its
not actually do encryption so if you are
at Starbucks any
are streaming your video that actually
will not
be encrypt it and someone can watch the
video along with you
one other as well now whatever
other but a couple other aspects about
UX getting back to
password security and stuff like that
and and data transfer and who owns your
day and all this other stuff
on when you start to stem innovation
they would actually
yep York your password to a third party
at Ceridian
how with a third party so we talked like
hafer creatures and Twilight well you
like last past financial I know like if
axe gets breach out totally just get
your that password
well a third party vendor now has your
unique password that you created for one
service
so if they get breach and you don't know
your customer of theirs
how safe are you now right so the last
past my works really well when you have
like a single pass for per service and
randomized all that
is that no one else actually use that
password for another account
happy bridge back your knowledge
hopefully obvious this
you know completely read that premise it
actually takes the
past your actual password doesn't md5
sum that password
and uses that as actually liked secret
token went through an API calls
so again if someone's on the network
with you and again all the API calls are
clear text they can get your md5sum
password and if they want just reports
that and start walking
in as you don't have to go through all
this like extra had a
thing just steal your password now from
workforce in a remote able in
and out just log into your account as if
it was you on your wall
on their old on their own mobile app um
soak up a lockable example the API call
that they were doing
about the bottom one will actually
create a token
I and then you know using that that that
mi5 password
animate open itself will come back and
you can then pass the mac address that
twice in
surgeon API calls to your heart's
content
up for what I did I'm
like most people I with that showed an
but what I call did slightly different
than what some people might have
soon on did it's really small in terms
of the number of devices
up for that is market share II don't I
I know it's a lot of places and I know
it has like I really good retail
presence
however keep in mind that in order to
find these cameras
you would have to basically be port
forwarding or have no firewall or
you know some other combination that
allows you to see helmet on the internet
which is
on kinda kinda weird however the other
thing I did
is not look at she peed which probably
would have been a little bit more likely
to be on the network
there was really no consistent unique
signature for the HTTP Server
I felt really confident about so I took
the thing I thought most confident about
which was told that because the telnet
banner was very unique
obsolete I had a higher you know hi sure
that that was a
a positive and not a false one I'll
its you know again this is from July
2013 why when I was doing actual
research so
on you know who knows what the numbers
now and like I said if you did HDPE and
can verify
with some you know it really want to
give your data without actually
walking into people's you know networks
which is a bad idea
I'll you know could be a much bigger
number now so which was wise
you know we have access all the stuff
the only thing I didn't ask what I was
doing this was all abilities
like actually finally is this and again
like they're a lot of the Japs are
probably worse than all but attacks in
smaller cities and stop
that would work but I'll in the case you
start with route
and you have for more like public access
your like funny bone ability is kinda
not necessary at that point I might be
interesting but
I was kinda looking for big ticket stuff
so he was kinda quick synopsis have all
these issues out I think we talked all
these
at some point I'll keep in mind this is
one IP camera this is one internet
things as one embedded device under
network
and with how many Boehner bilities and
how many service you know failures and
third parties and all this other stuff
cornball
and if you think of how many devices the
next year's gonna be fine
and putting on your network you know
your nest or you know your TiVo search
all these different devices that are all
you know network-enabled and
have something better hardware you know
action going on some links and all this
other stuff
I each one of those is a target for bad
bad stuff like this to happen
and thinking about what your I'll you
know
how much risk you really wanna take
because honestly a lot of people are
bringing stuff just like this into their
offices
right you want to keep IP camera to
bring your office and put on your
network and maybe
maybe your eye you know health care
provider now on our health care provider
with a camera that has all these
vulnerabilities
and you know in terms of hip-hop despite
not gonna go over very well
people
um in I in terms of the
research subsequent I will talk about
disclosure in a second but
other some still room to do some other
stuff on this camera if you're so
inclined
a number one of course plenty more
bodies in the actual aP's on the camera
on remember that a lot of the code on
those cameras are actually the third
party vendors code to actually run their
games and stuff
so I'm it's kind of a bigger bigger
scope than just the camera itself but
could be interesting on doing custom
firmware do you know doing
money hack spring-like you know I had on
someone when they walk
fire something there's there's lottery
there if you're if you're awesome
plan to do that kinda stuff on and API's
I really don't look too hard at
I'll mostly cuz most the API testing
would have had to you
involved things up I would've been
mostly legal so it seem like a bad word
to go down as well
on
now in terms of what the FTC thinks
about stuff like this
if you ever heard about the train a case
where actively there was one ability
I it was really gnarly in that you can
just go to you a URL and get direct
access to IP cameras
up someone cradle was about 700 or so
these cameras
put them online people start you know
putting the right for ten dollars or
stop
and I got the attention of water news
agencies which in turn got the attention
FTC
I and subsequently kinda got some pretty
pretty having
restrictions and some other action
against them because of their failure
for security
which is good you know people should be
out you know
somewhat chastised for huge failures
like that with first with regard to
the privacy and safety if so many people
on now
in terms of the language what are the
restrictions was the FTC said that
marking materials train that couldn't
use the
you know affectively the phrase said you
know this is secure or the camera secure
security or
any of those kinda Bob offshoots and we
look at the eyes on what saying this is
again a little bit old now I'll that one
side course at secure bank security
group military all that you know all the
kinda markings that you guys see all the
time
on now I would contend that in terms of
what
trying it did wrong is like very pop
like it pales in comparison
need to how much bad stuff them in a
patient in their camera like
complete pillars obscurity up again I
didn't like
try to put some other people's lives in
danger so I I guess and make not news
disclosure time-line pretty quick time
line I actually had some it this
research
I to public conferences so I have a
click up for mandate when this research
would be released unless someone
directly asked me to you know redact
something our whole back something or
whatever else
which I'm always happy to you you know
do for company up there
acting right way about things but on for
my very first may I said
you know I have some security issues
with the camera I'd like to cure
you know seniors engineering personal
wealth can talk about these pens
issues just so you know I'm gonna be
releasing his research
in October so since email number one
they knew that that was like
basically the Andy up through all my
weird emailed
exchanges and many of them are very
weird I really have
pretty much nowhere until the 14 about
October
when they kinda pipe backup and
I was asked to like have a conversation
with them and talk about like all these
issues that I found
on Abe said like oh and your research is
wrong in this isn't right and
something something whatever else and
who you know I'm a pretty
your humble guy so if you say like the
researchers wrong like I'd love to you
know what got
what what went wrong but keep in mind I
have like
screenshot by has two things I've seen
results like I can confirm that date i
deleted still there I can confirm that
the root password is hardcoded
into all your cameras like that's a very
simple thing to do on
sewing I you know I think it might've
been a little bit more posturing on
their
their side than anything of it why did
offer to meet up and talk and all this
other stuff
they never got back to me and still have
never gotten back to me so
oh well I'll good news is
as far as I'm aware up all the major
vulnerability is our passion
radiated mitigated or some other you
know some other way on
fixed I don't use the camera myself
anymore I
on a different camera from a much better
better for security
and you know so it's you know it's kind
of the way that most things going
put some time and try to get some
results usually results don't come out
until
way after your foster with the vendor
because they've stopped talking your
threaten your are also up to keep in
mind
no wifi thermostat switch you know
nothing stopped by I think he will
actually have their own kind
just like thing coming up very soon our
cameras and and like all these cool
things that we have better internet
enabled her
you know some way or another I'm keep in
mind if that device communicates
out your network I'll maybe it's reverse
proxy
you know who knows right are you have to
verify that your cell
maybe it has hardcore passwords how do
you know dumping firmware going to
mobile app's
you know this is stuff that can as
consumers you have really no insight
into what most people like me or someone
else in the room does research
tell you about the things that are on
your device arms I I would I would
encourage you to look at devices like
this
on certainly don't you know attack
network services out outlook
our scope your network but if you have a
network device in your running you know
are short on your home network and you
but the hardware and stuff like that
oMG you know read reasonably assured
that you will get in too much trouble
on now certainly II I would talk to the
vendor me very kind and your choice the
tree is the people that you're working
with
for security research because lawsuits
are very easy for big companies that
brought you
to keep that in mind as well but on
stiller from Raspberry Pi I know they're
I just complete stop caring and I'm
rubble talking like a year now I still
don't know where that thing is
but obvious with a much more interesting
project in like the like
I don't know the housing you that thing
for a cat internet server something
on so it's a quick shout out sobbing
about the focal White Plains over with
us now to us we saw him away but
II about lab guy like me user cluster
for password cracking to get that one
not
I admin passwords on at the brown by CP
for that
on John oh and Adam it do offer some
guidance from stop and then my body I
martínez at do actually what use is
jailbroken iPhone I love how the
one jailbroken iPhone we had a security
company will along through the video
editing
guy at our company like I'll we'll
subsequently bought our own jailbroken
iPhone for testing
so I'll so contact details you know
please reach out to me I
I'm I'm sure he'll guys who had
recording after the fact if you like
having
double back but on slider speak redact
my personal website on a calm has a
bunch of other street you know dachshund
other cool stuff I and then I in terms
of I guess time
actually finish pretty early are 5-10
minutes for questions
if we don't need that will check out
early and get it for beer but any any
questions yes
that yet
it's a good question for the question
being I did I have a conversation with
the vendor
a voice actual or course otherwise on
all my conversations were the email
I every time I try to I give my phone
number and say hey let's have a collar
or
is there a number i can reach you at %ah
they either declined
and said that they're working on stuff
and they didn't wanna talk quite yet
or are we just never got to the point
where they actually would give me
contact details
that we actually get to someone
important on their help desk
and their I would say their support
staff was actually really responsive at
first
way more make way more responsive than
the actual leadership the company which
is kinda concerning
on but again virtually never actually
got her message with those guys
with your question yeah ho
sure yes I might as well I might as well
actually since I have like a couple
quick minutes
um and of course on that actual life by
well so what's circles the wifi
password start but
bought go II
okay there oh yeah
on a look make them good sure just
your any
so that mostly put some screen area
on so I I
aside another I would you research %uh
since then and you know I'm
have gotten down this road a little bit
more and the same kinda problems kept
creeping up which is no different in a
lot of the research
they that you guys might be doing but on
you know the last
the classroom research I did actual
really really poorly in terms of legal
rats and other bad stuff and %ah so on
myself and then not exactly you're
already mine owners Quine
on we decide to start initiative called
built securely
and affect Lee we're doing two things
not number one
is we're organizing our resources for
engineering staff so if you can read
like
1i West security paper one REST API
slide deck or something else
out you know you can point people here
and hopefully get some decent resources
that are actually useful
and watch the help out build securely
you know buildings more securely than
must be bored doing now on so education
one part on
part number two is we also are doing
%uh you know basie pro bono security
research like
most was due anyways right %ah 4 vendors
that are small commercial
which wraps I'll you know low funded
organization because
reality is a lot of companies are making
I O two devices right now
you have never heard of they're not
Samsung they're not just go there not
Belkin
mostly out here by since coming to the
market are very small organizations
trying to get like a little piece of
that pie because
you think of something like ard are like
Arduino a Raspberry Pi or or gum sticks
are all these different like small
platforms
very easy to build very easy to do
yard to play some software on you have a
free printer you make a case for it like
you have ninety device
like it's very very easy on so what
we're doing is we're pairing up security
researchers from
honestly some a passenger researchers in
the world with NCC group we have I
lacked there we exhibitor
all these all these organizations have
have paired up with us and Dom
affect the world with but crowd give
mean vendors a direct line
to researchers to then hopefully and
most cases
do pre-production security testing so
before you go to market with you I would
you device
these researchers will test it give you
bugs for free
maybe you can help it may be given
teacher like on the harpies is a party
or something like whatever just to say
thanks but
on affectively make it so it not me
testing hardware that I bought that i
won tested
were flipping kinda the script and
making it so vendors are opting in
you having people research and do their
devices so really the benefit to the
researchers
is basic to talk about the research they
get to go to conferences like this
not be threatened with legal action not
be threatened with the Indies
and actually come and talk about the
same important learning that I just
talked with you guys about today
on so that's what we're up to build
securely and
to the long long roundabout answer is I
drop cam
so drop cam is really local company I
actually without
San Francisco during our essay of sat
down with the engineering staff gave
this slide deck and another slide deck
by iraqi security
on they have a great security page they
have a great bounty program
for public stuff there one of our first
partners for bill that securely that
some new product coming out soon that
we're gonna get
access to have when it releases
so that hopefully by the time and and
this is really the goal hopefully by the
time
products come to market they have been
researched and looked at and reviewed
and patched rather than you guys buying
10,000 units
and having to try to patch the after the
fact so that's where ru up to
om its sides it's gone very well we
started in February
were actually just about to put art
where researchers hand from Pinocchio
which is a system-on-chip that's
actually based I'm Michigan
and then drop can have some stuff coming
in July for us are so it's it's been
successful we actually have
you know them like a really good Cheryl
amazing people wait way smarter than I
am
on and work you know we're going down
the right path to hopefully
not probably change security for OT but
certainly help from the smaller brands
and make it a little bit more
easy to %uh get get the assistance to
get to market more securely
and hopefully I can snowballs a little
bit me see what happens so
sorry for taking a to any time any any
other questions yet
um
know this research at honestly a lot I O
T stuff you can get away with with like
you know ob shit at our cap in Wireshark
I mean for all the network's top right
on you know I
if you want to be more them the a the I
west of
again like you know having I'd uproar
something or hopper to do some the
analysis of the actual mobile images is
useful
if I'm going to the hardware stuff by
you know you buy one
%ah some hardware like a tag that's
available or like a logic analyzer
I'll but I yeah most most the work I'm
honestly I as guess I like
estimates got real nothing everything
kinda class for down
I want you can see inside the black box:
it's not
not so much a mystery any more yeah
yeah I wish I could say this a lot like
harder to do but that's why I'm
encouraging you guys like bison I G
proper just a very own
look at it because honestly all have at
least the research stuff to get some
free tickets the conference's worst case
rates up
not the worst of course we live on but
it means beneficially think I'd like
that IP camera
they fix always wonder bilities I
granted like I had a camera but actually
have a
had also bought this camera my brother
who has through like
six-month-old twins like I really want
some creepy person
looking at my nephews like from a camera
on the Internet no absolutely not so
it doesn't just have to be like cool
hacker research project like its
or and altruism what you want to help
people that can help themselves want to
tell people that they were in danger
going to get things patch that people
are you know pain are thirty dollars for
the
you have basic security on you know
there's there's a lot of good that we
can do in the community and certainly
other
you know package for charity in but code
all the other endeavors
%uh certainly had a much more primal you
know benefit but at the end the day
likes safety and privacy of I'll
citizens of our country is
also pretty damn good wasting your time
so yeah I really doing for you guys do
some these private security not
on healthier your flight Dixon future
events
any I the last question cool
Thank You upstart the oh yes oh we
actually out weekly
we coordinate with the job that the PR
teams and everything else
at these at these places on I'll
actually be giving up
on Pocket Def Con on harshly about this
and partially about more I O T stuff and
%ah
we're hoping just just before that to
have some kind of announcements and
stuff go out publicly in
week we've had a captain community-based
right now because we're still trying
like you know the one thing that
frustrates me as someone that's been is
industry a while
when people start a project or
initiative like this and then say like
our to be like huge in the past and you
know I thousand people to join us right
now
and then it goes nowhere we've grown
really really slowly with people that we
trust me know
have credibility and on we want to do
things the right way not the quick way
and so Bob you know by by Def Con time
we should have some cool
news about like you know developer our
researchers looking at are like that
on your pipe in our press release up
with some these companies like NCC group
I'll active
Dropcam Nokia and so on and so forth ob
that makes them look good
to write like they're the only IP camera
vendor are paid right so if you combine
IP camera and you care about security
here's a great in a reference point for
that we're gonna buy system-on-chip
and you want to use up with that on you
to look at Nokia right because they care
about security and
so that's kinda peer pressure thing I'm
hoping for a hoping that
we get enough better than enough spaces
that when work you know
keyboard but you guys are giving out
recommendations on what what IP camera
shy by
I I would hope you'd say something like
dropped out because you know that their
their sirs but security on and up
they're working with both securely like
that's that's a good recommendation to
make at that point so
om that's you know I think I think it's
a beneficial everyone like there's no
one that really loses in the scenario
researchers gonna do research in after
about legal bullshit and get a
Depok on a crowd gets a huge reputation
because because they're
doing all this for free for us are our
researchers individually get there
credit for doing the work the companies
that employ those researchers get credit
for wanting to do the work
and then of course the vendors get good
credit for being security-conscious
vendors
so on you know you really find out
opportunities with so much
upside to it and out pretty cool to be a
part of so great
thanks so much guys and redress the
conference