I really appreciate you guys coming
this is how hackers for charity possibly
save me a lot of money
and I'm your you understand a bit later
why
my name's Brandon Miller ago by fires
here at least I didn't
Navy I never really had a handle but
whenever someone
when I first started talking at these
conferences someone said either pick 10
will give you one so I should all go if
I Z cuz I'm fat hairy and tell bad jokes
so miss my daughter Emily she picked the
name a copy because the first
presentation games at Shrek on
and she hated that I called her chicken
in public so she picked her own
but this is me I'm just a pajama wearing
hipster I love wearing my onesies
around Christmas talking about health
care and drinking hot cocoa with my
family
I'm an analyst dad husband at three
three kids this is the oldest my
children
and I'm a Christian and my shout out to
yeah
do you even know what a bollard is
alright check out bollards Ville
go bollard bill dot com wonderful
website the
only internet site that i've seen
dedicated
to bollards Hannah who
I'm Emily you and I im
a photographer for a lot of things other
than nature like my dog
which technically I guess is nature
letter on
I'm obviously a kid and I have a sister
brother
named Irene Isaac and I am a Christian
now with the stock is not is
groundbreaking
we did not do you any of this research
ourselves we
beg borrow and stole mostly from
drowning on hackers for charity
and he gives up willingly so it's not
like we did anything illegal or
we always give him credit what it is
it's a growth opportunity for Rush
once again I was in the Navy for twenty
years a deployed all hot
so and her formative what I like to call
her formative years I wasn't there
so now that we homeschool and I'm not
alone in the Navy
we do a lot of things like this together
and wished we will be and a course it's
an opportunity for her to learn
I made her do all love it whenever I say
we I mean she
she did everything and then for us
because we're christians
car to serve because we support a
missionary
in Kenya actually missionary in Somerset
Kentucky who goes to Kenya
I little bit a background so this is a
million she's the one in pain it's the
last time she wore pink at age five
that is her second camera with water the
first camera whenever she was 4
there's a little Barbie pink camera only
took 10 pictures
it wasn't satisfying enough or so she
asked for a point-and-shoot
and just because she knew what that was
we went and bought her one
the next year
my in-laws all went to Kenya this is
actually
Rift Valley witches were charming on
skids are in school its kinda funny
small world arm they came back
with all other their stories love with a
did on this medical mission trip and how
they
how they helped and thats whenever Emily
declared that she was gonna go
and if we win sender she was gonna take
herself she was 6
she didn't go in 212
up my wife are my my wife's mom my
mother-in-law
I am she went back to Kenya and the
purpose for this was the stand-up
a clinic the lady on the right her name
is Grace
grace was a nurse on a 2006 medical
mission trip
I the reason why she was a nurse she
felt out of
out of our medical school which met in
Kenya if you get a BF to repeat that
you're over
because she got married her dad dropper
funding so my mother-in-law so how much
could medical school costs she said
roughly
two thousand dollars so my mother are my
in-laws paid for it
and said don't pay us back open up a
clinic
and help out the locals so that's what
she did they all returned Honam
our mission trip and 2012 October so
they went twice that year
and Mamie adopted this school
which you can see the three trees in the
middle there's a school there
believe me terrorist at about two hours
north of Nairobi
and literally someone has to run in
front of the vehicle the whole way
they take turns show that you don't hit
potholes are get stuck because there's
no red
take turns when we went they didn't take
turns the I just ran
way yeah crazy now two hours away
it's only like 10 miles outside the city
but
so but yeah I ran away these are some
other students there's how many
218 think 218 students
Inc any have to pay for your own school
public school cost about two hundred
dollars a year
that is include your books and your
uniforms
this is an orphanage that my
mother-in-law adopted
we say or Finnish flash cool because of
the tourney
9 29 students I don't know numbers
I just give above the 29 students only
three or four of 'em
have funding to go to school so the lady
that runs the orphanage home schools the
rest of them
that's for johnnie long hackers for
charity stepped in whenever they heard
the story because I stock to them
johnnie and shame can chat every
a con from last probably four years
arms and how can I help how can I help
how can help how can I help finding
sam turned on to me and said the old one
is from school at US
just adopted hey I can do that and then
I realized
she can show
Emily decided she basically said look if
you want let me go to Kenya
I'm just going to be a photographer and
that's when I panicked
I don't know anything about art I don't
know how hard to support themselves
arm art to me I can identify our because
I don't know what it is
right I look at something and I go well
that's a wall other two
neat looking thing on a shirt that's
probably art that's my extension apart
try literally panicked
yeah and I decided that I was gonna
refocus her energies
into something technical because that's
what I know
so here we are
sometimes only clams up that's okay I am
so this is our plan we're gonna build a
simple XBMC server
be cuz I want to get rid of DirecTV arm
as a perfect concept it never went live
we also get all the movies we got frozen
well but anything that's come out
theoretically that could happen
or they never work it's in our lab only
hypothetically so we built the Rachel
pie
with our good friends world possible
.org I install Windows 7 on a ThinkPad
that was donated to us
in stock rutan yet show
who hears every screw time heard on as a
wonderful program
you can I install it on any Chromebook
and allows for true dual boot with
another Linux operating system
show there's no rebooting are putting it
in Tom developer mode
you literally hit to Keesh in it putsch
that
n/a it suspends the state almost like a
VM and
opens up the the other instance such
really nice
she can switch back and forth between
Chromebook and whatever you load we
loaded a move to
arm on the fly nice
we were gonna go to Kenya she ended up
going to can you with my wife
Naimi install the learning network
server
I and teach the staff and then RN game
was the talk at schmoke on
I had always been tryin you know for
years to talk to shrink I never got
picked
not complaining I was never really
worthy
I put her name on the smoke on CFP and
she got selected
so says she's a minor I get to go with
her
set up okay what really happened
is he basically followed
a fam around for
years home and finally he just bought
the hi and then that's when we built the
XBMC servers we can watch dollar
be radical stuff and not the Rachel pie
went to Kenya and we actually bill
schoolhouse cuz they they're just doing
in a living room
and their place to teach the people and
ended up actually using is the norm for
for the girls
has your I'm
he installed it talk staff and
then we went to a lot of other places
make sure you call my name aid
he's a steps to bill Rachel pie
him so first one you got a bother at
berry pie
the SD card class 10
it has to be class 10 because it's fast
this Renae capability
and you're actually gonna be rendering
video not rendering video
but serving up video this is actually a
web server
we haven't turned on right now have a
smartphone or anything
I look for RPI our pie and you should be
able to load up the
course where the kids are using
didn't understand a word not really but
I try
own downloaded the break to
hi stuff I'm
are wrote to the SD card shut up the
server and then and then used
literally its if you print out the steps
with pictures its two and a half pages
anyone can do it
the difference between what you would do
and what I made her do as I made her do
everything via command line using my Mac
and she didn't discover until we did
this presentation at Lexmark last week
there I actually had all the commands I
just made her go look for them
are a major google it so she lives in
right a this is the cost have all the
parts
the Raspberry Pi itself is $35 dollars
the whole life I dunkle when word is
7 power Spy was nine
and then the little glass not glass
but fact will that the Mariners
whatever plastic thing was
30 in home
building business building the X team
the server and I took is nice case
and phone maker model legos
I could take the knife the Kenya
head tell you what
used here where's
a this is the second one the book The
Rachel hi
and the reinstall the operating system
aunt laptop
and yeah it
took forever I don't note its night
we started this about lunch
fun who I major read
every screen how many sysadmin so we
have out there ever
your I didn't matter click her I me to
read everything
so you have to experience that one yet
once in your life three
I don't think so K
it so this is it all gathered up
together you'll know is nice little case
that I to
and a little wifi and then to flash
drives message at the Jesus film
to show a church didn't actually a end
up working but we did show it to the
school
en route to Kenya
but yet fully booked the school and this
is what
they the boys have been sleeping and it
was basically
like things that they had found propped
up together into a shack
like a chair a prufer who
I don't know what was in p home so we
actually
the frame building
and it's almost done here and this is it
finished
it ended up being the nicest building in
the village
so that was my cuter
bring out the right very tall pine if it
was working
and that there is no power they had just
moved
old building had power their new
building did not we didn't know that
when are we went
so I want to the van cuz I had won the
little
things are you plug in the charger
it didn't work so at this point
they didn't know I didn't work and
neither did I so she sent me an email
saying how do I i turn this thing on
because I did everything you said
so I responded back with their six easy
steps and then
it still didn't work so she took it
shoot the hotel the
that we are is based out of and this is
salami salami as the manager of the
hotel but she got the orphanage
at least twice a week if not more often
she taught salami how to use it and then
salami would set it up there
when it was all over we decided to go on
safari
because I had never been and we saw some
stuff without
who leopard on the first day we saw lie
in
we saw draft and idoney
I can't even count love they were
everywhere
and then yeah so at this point we she
came back
on a Wednesday and
we repacked our stuff and flew out on
Thursday so that we can make a judgment
on
show it was a it was a tight space there
this is just presenting a smirk on the
really cool thing was joining on King to
russian said hey
I you guys finally when cool can I have
five minutes at the end of it as a
catcher
at the end of our presentation which
fairly similar this
he stepped up on stage with this
this is if if this is 1.0
there the Rachel pie this is version 2.0
which he calls the Pelican pie so
basically whenever we get our lessons
learned
I this device actually takes care of
all the issues that we had and will
explain some what that is
it's really cool other one condition
wise
a Emily had to build this so the what
they did was presented her with all the
parts
salmon johnnie sat with their for hours
washy soldered
taught her how to solder and Dom yes she
had a blast
I was terrified I was gonna burn
somebody with that soldering pencil
doesn't move your fingers away way in
so here's our lessons learned number one
Rachel pi is really easy to build
once again six easy steps you can
actually if if they
require you to do something I there's a
link to how to do it
so it's great with pictures installing
the drivers on the Rachel pie from a Mac
using the terminal window
are is really confusing that was her
take away like I said
I had the Chi Chi she didn't know about
last week
she really got stock in couldn't get it
from Google than I would
I would sure how to do it if the maker
recommends apart use that part this wifi
dongle costs seven dollars I wanted to
save a dollar cuz I found one that costs
six
and um yeah I didn't work the drivers
were incompatible
so you know it cost ish three days
really
well we got the new part I'll
Raspberry Pi recommends 1.5 and power
supply
that's perfect for Raspberry Pi unless
you throw in the wireless dongle
is then some unease wireless on those
actually will draw one amp up our
themselves
so keep that in mind I recommend at
least to an
more lessons learned doesn't work well
on dirty power
the problem with the van and just about
everything that puts out power in Kenya
is there a voltage regulators absolutely
shock
so whenever it shares its putting out
five Oaks you could get one vote to 12
volts
show Pelican pie takes care of that it's
got it on voltage regulator internal
I have a backup plan even though this is
wireless
because it has a Ethernet poor I share
her with a router and
cat-5 cable so if they couldn't get the
wireless working
no problem and then we'll which she
discovered was one of the worst
teaching salami was at Linex was a
little bit too hard for the end users
there
from figures long I would would know how
you could pick up on it because she was
manager at the hotel should use
computers for a few years
but going from when does you know
click to Linex trying to actually use
some commands
it was a little bit too much so what's
next
in lean on the original trip enraged
over a thousand dollars
for this project she Lada herself a
hundred dollars for the project cost 82
with the rest of the money shots to buy
a generator I still have install power
at the house
we just got word that they just got
power installed show in January
should talk about six months for them to
get power
day the so EF it we still had a buyer
president what's up with that
arm three thousand dollars for ticket
was just not enough
soap we want to provide more computers
for the kids at the orphanage
I'll Lexmark stepped-up they patiently
said we don't
handle you know community work at this
level
six computers it's not even worth the
tax refund
and then but we would like to invite you
to to to speak
at Lexmark printer the stem committee in
the back
Christian business association: whenever
showed up spoke they gave us six
computers
so it's pretty cool I the Pelican pi
wanna bring back the Pelican prior to
replace this one
I in case they have power issues this
bad boy
this project gonna do my best vanna
white here
show solar power the power port is right
here
if you can get power in it will convert
it
so it will do 110 to 240 converted to
you of I volts DC
nice pretty clean signal out got a
for current time 6 a hour battery
we actually a 12 hour battery I just
haven't soldered n
arm Scott Rachel pie in there
it also has this little red board from
Adafruit were actually allow you to shut
down
the Raspberry Pi gracefully raspberry
hi will tell you the proper way to shut
down
the pie is poor power and its cuz that's
all they have an anxious to board
with this board does you hold this
button down for 10 seconds
it starts the i-net command and you can
pre program into Telugu
you want your 0 or whatever you want and
it will gracefully shut down there
the Pelican parts that's really nice arm
this is version to version 3 of this
actually has HDMI port now
johnnie uses that for showing videos I
it
your remote villages and I am so that's
this will have this
all day too if you wanna take a look at
it
and then we were planning on going back
this summer or fall
I'll actually a check for going back
next spring the reason for that my
mother Martha
person that we're supporting her mission
there she just had knee replacement
she's having the other one
shown she's not able to travel we want
to take her with us
once again we didn't do any of this on
our own we got it off from somebody else
you can choose when here's the links to
all of it
are there any questions
sir
for me the frustration with sitting for
hours in hours and
hours on end doing stuff that I had no
idea what I was doing
was payoff that 0
okay so in a village that a
director the orphanage name is Jane and
she like she knows
don't use a bathroom in your drinking
water
but a lot of people in the village just
I not so
this'll hope from learn some other
software on it is actually
from the world whore Health Organization
and its
some poor rules to follow and one of
them literally
arm is don't pee were you drink
and that was an eye-opener for a lot of
the villagers
they're like why not so what does it
matter it's just water
so that was a big one for me the the
most frustrating their was
not allowing myself to just do it for
her
especially when we were having the
driver issues
arm and not cheating in giving her
I'm I really did make her do the
research
arm the most rewarding that was just
seen her grow SOC started this project
whenever she was 13
she had never spoke publicly ever
her first public speaking engagement
wish milk on
but the 2,000 people in the room yes
that deserve their absolutely
and I'll tell you a quick little story
whenever I got up on stage I turned
around I let
while and she looked at me and said
dad where they are leaving and
immediately I'm like I gotta protect my
daughter you know this
are a shisha you know sometime the
previous speaker there probably taken
fielding questions outside don't be
upset she just
upset at age 10 either leaving is about
right
and I'm like about right there's two
thousand people in this room
all like 10 and now I'm so that was cool
you edit your question better
okay so the question is when I was
discussing the batteries are psyched
about the 12
I'll 12 hour battery life on on the
bigger battery
and apparently no I did not look at
using
the USB batteries arm I have one in my
backpack
I just ever thought about power in the
Rachel by with it so
at Solaris I know once again
no new ideas here we stole from
everybody else
so if someone else would have done that
I would have done it to you
yes yes
I the question is have you ever thought
about using a secondary K Schwan
inside being used the on outside been
charged
the answer to that is no because
we were able to raise a little over two
thousand dollars for this next trip the
rest of its coming out of my pocket
numb sinning for us this time such
almost twelve thousand dollars total for
all of us
um now this cost three hundred dollars
I can't really afford to do to not not
yet
arm but they only have school for a few
hours a day
on if you've ever been Africa there's no
clouds like in Kenya
it rains like once a year it just
happens Rainford like six weeks
but on so now not not yet
not yet it once we get some are our feet
under us
and get accustomed to this I'm will
probably do that
yeah
right
no so we have not been
accepting money from anyone I'll
were willing to but I'm not promoting
that
the appellation Institute for digital
evidence
hired Emily myself as contractors for
their conference
us so we got paid two thousand dollars
for that which is cool
the Russian stuff is just people walking
up to attain a missed five ten dollars
there
sonar we've never really solicited money
in your tuition for law and that's not
what I was rotten
arm we believe in the class we give
until it hurts
so we have to give until it hurts for we
ask for
cell
how your yeah now one thing you can do
in johnnie logged in
did say was if you go to his website
hey he's got two places you can donate
10 miss the long family journey
so that goes directly to him the other
owners for hackers for charity
you click on that one in in the remarks
at our names he would reserve that money
for Ash
this is actually the first time I put it
out because that's not what we're
looking for
so I do appreciate it and yeah
right break but we don't we also don't
want to compete with johnnie
so were doing the same thing different
different areas
were not as big so and that is our time
as my daughter just wanna die yeah one
minute NeuN last questionnaire
up
we have really done at but that's a good
idea
her baby sister already has a blog so
maybe we'll start you want today
just makers area alright thanks a lot
appreciate thanks