this one's got a huge buyer so next week
I think most people know is dr. Sylvia
Cesare the managing director of info
sect he's worked in technical roles and
been involved in computer security for
over 20 years
including working in Silicon Valley in
the US and working in France and of
course Australia he's worked in
defensive and offensive roles reported
hundreds of software bugs and
vulnerabilities in operating system
kernels he used to work at UNSW Canberra
sniper he's worked as the scanner
architecture as a developer at koalas he
is the co-founder of Bayside's camera
and Seaside's
he has a PhD from Deakin University a
full-time black hat speaker done
academic research commercialization and
authored a book so we are will be
speaking next about heap allocators
[Music]
ensure you're not on mute okay well
thank you very much thank you for
attending virtually the first see slides
and I hope that you enjoyed our dance
talk and I do enjoy my talk as well and
I'm talking about the tax begins secure
heap elevators so memory corruption
I mean it's mean the detective memory
corruption every year for the past 15
years it's still a very common bug in
systems software exploit mitigations
certainly in the past you know 15 or 20
years have made exploitation less common
than they used to be when everything was
pretty much exploitable and you know
what I said over the pomace 15 years you
know mitigations have increasingly
raised the bar to actually deliver a
working exploit people afraid is those
things that are responsible for don't
memory management have likewise also
become more harm and more secure so
we've certainly seen a lot of mediators
in the past 15 years but they're very
early safe unlinking in pto up to where
we are today with many hardening
techniques so this talk will look at
some of the he pardoning techniques into
ql lieutenants and looking at acts
against them and how to bypass them so
i'm going to talk about five things
actually sent four things in my abstract
but i'm gonna actually talk about flat
because when I talk about pointy guard
in jelly bean which is the Linux default
standard c library implementation booty
loop see regularly a heap allocated but
it's very much related to protecting
pointers and memory on the heap so not
always on the heap but protecting memory
and pointers and there's variable later
to the other attacks and I'll talk about
I'll talk about the Linux kernels
default pig allocated which is known as
the school of allocator that's the
default Linux kernel elevator I'll talk
about hardened allocator call I say a
lot I'll go back to the slob allocator
cause we've got another attack that I
want to talk about and then finally I'll
end up talking about the pseudo elevator
which is the allocator used the Android
evil and so quite a few alligators and
I'll talk about individual attacks
against each one of these elevators so
we'll start off with plenty guard
include we've seen now 20 guard is
actually a mitigation
it's the mitigation technically in G
we've seen that they call pointy guard
that protects against pointer corruption
so if you have a winner and there's
memory corruption and memory craft
remote attacker over writes that pointer
with something that they're choosing
pointing out is meant to protect against
them so you can't arbitrarily corrupt
pointers and make them do other things
there are other techniques one other
after it's just iOS as one or a thin
occasion and things like that that might
be another Smoove method to do this type
of pointer protection but quanti god
effectively works by scrambling the
pointer before it's sorting memory ok
and then when the pointer is used at
these scrambles up
and it uses an internal secret that it
travels up with so you're not meant to
easily be able to get this secret from
an interest point of view it's actually
part of thread-local storage they can't
really easily access that this secret
that is using this scrambling operation
now pointing out mostly focuses on
function pointers that's typically what
it protects it doesn't protect all the
pointers in GMC it pretty much does
protects most of the function points not
all the function orders you still found
plaintext function pointers in a process
image like melons but we're going to
talk about that and the idea of
protecting function pointers with
pointed out is that it mitigates the
troll flow hijacking attacks so if an
attacker overwrites a function pointer
points points to the beginning of their
rock chain will this stack if it all
points to some sort of thing execute
code well when he got protects against
that it protects against an arbitrary
write to memory and then check out would
be able to use to override a function
pointer with their arm treatment now if
you looking at the G Lib C source since
you'll see a bunch of references to
point a mangle and point a D mangle it's
sort of pseudo code that I've shown but
this is sort of one of course my pointer
mangle and pointed emailing and the way
that plenty guard works is the
scrambling operation works by X or in
the pointer was the secret that secret
is sorting tread local storage and that
performs a bitwise left rotation and tax
11 bits so that's that's the scrambling
operation so explore the secret and then
rotate it and D mangling is the reverse
of that now the sort of the crux of this
this mitigation is if the attacker knows
the secret that the scrambling operation
works with then the attacker wins they
can mangle and that's okay can mangle
and D mangle arbitrary pointers whenever
they want providing they have lavatory
right actually been a very memory
corruption but we're attacking this
mitigation point again so the idea is to
get the secret now if you just wrap
again through G loop C you can start to
see where quantum angling is used and
there's one particularly interesting
case
in the pthreads initialization code
which I'll show you in this slide
hopefully you can read that and it
basically says that in p3 loop CP thread
in it which is some peace friends
initialization code there's pointer
mangling happening with a function
pointer table I think there's a function
pointer table that's passed to this
initialization routine and then there's
one in mangling occurring in each of
those function pointers now the thing
that and you can defeat 20 God with is
well if you know what pointer is being
manually atlas of the point of that's
been mangled you can recover the secret
and in fact in part of this pthreads
function pointer table we definitely
know which function is being manual
which which which function plan is being
manly and if we have a loosely based
leak then we know where that is in
memory so we can reveal the secret so
that's what we need we need an infant
link to get the loop C base and then we
simply say well we'll just take the
address of this piece and absolute
destroyed function and we can recover
the secret from point agon so that
reveals the secret because we have a
fixed we only have a function pointer
that we know about and we know the
action will address it that's not random
it's a well known addresses it's almost
like 20 texts yeah if we can make this
attack a bit more interesting in fact
let's wonder let's let's have a question
now are there any cases in G Lipsy where
it tries to mangle a non pointer or
another constant like negative 1 okay so
is there a fixed constant that's getting
mangled by pointing on and it turns out
as part of that piece right
initialization code the first item all
the second item in this array there's a
null pointer and that gets mangled
so this is some known plaintext this is
a constant that has been mangled and
from that we can simply rotate our sort
of mangled pointer and recover this
secret and we can we can defeat when I
dive like that if we have the ability to
get an arbiter read and then so we need
it in firmly but you know that's okay
we're talking about memory corruption
attacks and all of these mitigations
assume that an attacker is able to
corrupt memory and do something
nefarious things in memory and it's
trying to mitigate big sin on what they
can do don't this type of defeat is
known as a sort of a known plaintext
attack there's point in mangling of a
non point out and we can recover the
secret it's almost in plane tickets to
begin with so that's point ago that's an
attack on point agon and really you
shouldn't be mangling these constants
you know it sort of you know pretty easy
these for a couple of the secret if it
is the next thing I look at is Linux
kernel seep a locator the default
elevator known as the slug allocator and
the slob elevator uses what so is free
lists and friend lists are chunks of
memory that are free that a part of
weakness part of these free list so that
they can later be recycled by the
elevator request memories Jesus what
free list exists so the elevator can
recycle the free chunk of memory without
asking system memory for something so
there's a well known heap corruption
technique known as free was poisoning
and it basically says you've got this
free list me but these linked lists and
these pointers in this linked list if
you drop one of these one doesn't make a
point to an arbitrary address
well when the allocator recycles these
chunks it'll return to you of mela and
allocated no offer with the arbitrary
address that a poison or corrupted the
pointer in that free list length list so
that's that's called free list was do it
now you can actually turn this into an
arbitrary right committed from an it
from an attacker point of view if you
have application logic that what's
attacker controlled data to an allocated
buffer and you make that allocated
buffer point to an arbitral location
that's basically the same as of white
what we are in the commentary black for
minute so it's a very powerful limited
and many heap exploitation techniques
work around that principle member
historically you could actually be do
freelee's poisoning sort of trivially in
in the linux penalty panna cotta but
some years ago 2017 over lose i'm not
that many years ago they introduced a
configuration option to make free list
hardening
as a mitigation and so they've got this
cloak here and there's actually a patch
that mitigates against one of this high
seat naive friend is poison attack will
simply overwrite one of these pointers
with an arbitrary Atticus that will be
returned by the Colonel jalapeno and the
the key the scrambling function that
they use they have sort of the sort of
the same thing it's point and manually
or deem Englund they use a scrambling
function which takes the pointer excells
that against a secret and then axles
that against the address of the pointer
and our attack we want to reveal the
secret this is what we want to get we
want to reveal that secret so that we
can hopefully craft our own thang
corrupt pointers and make the kernel
memory allocator return an arbitrary
address now the inside of this attack is
that in the Linux kernel pointer and
pointer address pretty much belong to
the same region of memory so they're
almost bitwise identical and because you
have that extra identity we XOR
something with itself equals zero you
basically come to the situation where
you have one an excellent
with almost itself which comes to zero
excellent with the secret thus revealing
the secret so in fact this stolen
pointer in the free list if these
frameless pointers is actually the
secret stone is plaintext and if we look
at the kernel memory allocator and this
was actually done by K school and then
Alice's are currently the blog post on
it only sort of waiting to patch this
this particular problem if we look at
the stored value that sword in that free
list pointer it's almost identical to
the secret value that is not meant to be
known you know two-man attacker or all
be plant accessing memory so hooligans
kernel team acknowledge this as a
weakness a main rotor pack to improve
the security but okay she's not my blog
post one external commit when they when
they talk about this and now they use
sort of the variation on that scrambling
technique is why not application
technique they take the point out they
accelerate with the secret and then they
XOR it with a Indian swap of the pointer
so they simply added that Indiana swap
that's 164 and this is actually much
stronger it's actually a much stronger
as much stronger mitigation and much
harder to to corrupt that pointer and
make it you know do what you wanted to
do so that's the attack on an external
peep the next allocated on a look at is
called bicep outlook and I say L Bach is
a hardened elevator with many security
medications ugly a very good Allatoona
now they actually use a similar strategy
for the Linux kernel slot elevator in
fact they take the pointer they
accelerate again it's a secret and they
XOR it against the pointers address and
I'd be told and I sort of can't verify
this that this sort of pattern actually
came from gr security where apparently
this bug at least exhibit this weakness
existed certainly at least until a blog
article about it let's look at the clue
in I so color and we can actually see
that there's this canary value which
takes is be point of excellent against
this address and then X was it against a
secret and in fact when we print the
value of the stored value and the secret
all the highlights are the same so this
is actually an identical class of bunk
that we saw in a Linux kernel people
look exactly the same but it's taking
even a pointer X or neol with a plant
address bitwise identical they become 0
thus revealing the secret in memory so
very interesting that we saw multiple
elevators that have been hardened
against one frameless poisoning at this
same class of one or the same class of
weakness so the IP male but water and
why cell can eat all it took was the
weakness and I recommended to do the
same thing that moves from touch to
simply use that Indian swap with that
black water swap and I say I like
implemented that change in less than a
week after the initial report
currently it's it is patched much like
the Linux kernel patch and I talked
about earlier so is that the end of
attacking the Linux kernel if a locator
and a lock is there anything we can do
that you know that we haven't talked
about you know there any other attacks
you know is real is poisoning dead now
this is sort of a theoretical attack so
it gets a bit out there I think it's a
bit sort of it's a it certainly more and
more exotic attack than the earlier
attacks now equipped ography there's a
set of attacks known as be flippin
attacks any Lukla attack see basically
takes some ciphertext which you know the
plane takes off and then you flip some
bits in this life to text so that it
decrypt to whatever you want and you can
actually do that you can want to find
the ciphertext even maybe you know the
plaintext and when you know the victim D
creeps the data it decrypts tilapias
happen once that's called a flip and it
turns out that in theory we can perform
a similar attack on the Linux kernel
deep allocator so there's actually some
code in the Linux kernel it's unusual
code and it basically says and you
certainly need you need some recessions
in the kernel to do this you need some
point or restrict permissions to really
on by default but it is there in the
kernel there's some Linux kernel code
that says when it tries to look at this
friend list point up it checks to see if
it's a valid pointer and if it isn't
then it warns you tis an error and says
the free pointer this friendlist point
is corrupt and then it also prints what
it decoded to will be mangled - okay so
it's appointed the manual Oracle we can
basically pass arbitrary corrupt
pointers to our friend lists and that D
manual operation with our pointer D on
the station operation we can actually
see what it comes to so this is the
attack that we're going to do all the
least in theory it's a sort of a
theoretical attack with some sort of
verification it's theoretical really
they'll take a free list point up
and we've got memory options we're gonna
clear up that free list point up with
the value of our choosing
okay then we going to get the allocator
2d naval using ante mangling Oracle and
we're going to note the result given
only that that we've got a demon world
point up from a point of that where you
sort of corrupted we can do a bit
flipping attack and using that we can
corrupt the free list planner again
making it to the mangle to an arbitrary
address of our choosing
so that's a big flippin attack applied
to the Linux kernel heap allocator and
to do this what we're going to do is
we're going to corrupt the free list
pointer with the value and we're just
going to corrupt it with the value 1 and
we choose 1 not 0 because 0 has a very
special meaning it's a null pointer so
might sort of be sort of not work well
why terminate whistles so forth but one
is probably a safe thing ok so we're
going to corrupt this free list pointer
with 1 and then we're going to use that
be mainly Oracle to tell us what it D
mangled to now we're going to call that
point 2 1 now I've got another chance at
corrupting the same trailers pointer and
we're going to take our target address
exel that with one and XOR that with
what adding mangling Oracle's Damus and
this is our op the sanded pointer to
we're going to corrupt the frameless
under with that and guess what when the
kernel tries to D mangle that point it
actually gives you the target address so
it's a big flippin attack and I've got
them like a small proof here showing the
the sequence of next to operations so
that you get your target address out of
it but basically we need to corrupt the
free list point on what's the value
about choosing use that the mainly
Oracle and then re corrupt the pointer
and we can make it to mangle to any
target address that we want so to put
the attack it's a theoretical attack
certainly in sort of with test data of
works but it's interesting that such an
attack might be possible you know
learning cryptography might actually be
useful even to people to be memory
crusher
the final attack that I'm going to look
at is the pseudo elevator and sciutto is
a Highland alligator written and
maintained by Google okay
it's used in the Android easel and on
mobile devices it's very easy to use to
compiling you just use si lang and you
pass that sanitizer word sudo and it
uses a suite of free public beta now
sudo does is the secure alligator tries
to mitigate against mera question and
one of the considered does to mitigate
against memory corruption is that it
puts checksums into mela chunk headers
in an attempt to prevent an attacker
from forging their own fate chance we
can't pass to free a faint chunk because
there's a checksum on the header that
uses an internal secret and a crc32
checksum algorithm to calculate that
checksum so there's a secret that a
cookie or 32-bits cookie that we don't
know about as an attacker that prevents
us from arbitrarily cranial on checksums
only the allocator knows this this
cookie and it uses a crc32 algorithm
sort of a common checksum algorithm
involving that secret involving the
original chunk header you know sort of
in a pseudo header and then it writes
that new checks on to the chunkier so
what we want to do ultimately we want to
fake checksums ok we want to create fake
checksums and we also want their secret
cookie and what we're going to do is
represent this secure checksum algorithm
including that secret value as a set of
SMT equations so a set of constraints
and we're going to assume that we have
an info link but we're able to read one
chunk header of a valid chunk
okay so we have a neat phone link we're
able to read a chunk here we're gonna
represent the checksum algorithm
involving a secret cookie as a set of SN
T equations and then when you cast a
solver to see if it can compute a
solution for the secret cooking
and if it does actually do this well we
can crash correct Chuck's checksums on
fake errors using this secret cookie and
this is a set of SMT equations
represented in Python as entry and
that's enough to represent the checksum
algorithm it only does a crc32 checksum
only on a few bytes for the it's not an
arbitrary length amount of data so it's
actually possible to represent this by
effectively as a set of equations now we
can ask SMT solver can we solve a
solution to give us that cookie value
that secret cookie value in fact we do
get a solution in you know very quickly
in less than a second and it's one of
many solutions that it gives us and the
solution that we get it's not actually
going to be the real cookie okay there's
many solutions that it sort of can solve
that make that check something valid but
it's not you know the real hook effects
used by the system but it turns out it
doesn't matter doesn't matter that it's
not a real cookie because they're a
secret cookie collisions and in fact the
secret cookies that we determine or
compute are good enough to build correct
check sums for arbitrary fake chunks so
you know what does a feint chunkiness
you know why we trying to forward chunks
or build fake chunks
well in many allocators if you corrupt
the slice more than a chunk it up you
can free that chunk and it goes into the
wrong size free list or bin and you can
make the allocator believe that that
chunk
well that chunk header represent is much
larger than what it is that chunk that
it will also is much larger so a future
allocation are quite large
uses that even though it's much smaller
and in fact that allocation overlaps
because it's thinking that it's much
bigger than it is it overlaps that
adjacent chunk to the original chunk and
an attacker can corrupt critical data
structures overwrite function pointers
or pointers themselves and do other
things as well future work is the seat
of such a text of possible on sciutto
using these fake chunk
but it's pretty good you can craft your
own fake chunks given only one infant
like 30 so i presented a number of
attacks against hardened elevators the
mitigations in these elevators all the
steam and attack earth is able to
corrupt memory so on one so this is the
basis you know you can corrupt memory
you know you've got some primitives what
can you do with the allocator and can
you bypass some of the mitigations and
defenses that they implement to prevent
or mitigate against exploitation and it
turns out we can actually do a number of
attacks against a number of hotend
elevators and bypass a bunch of
litigations so that's pretty much my
twitter name is there i also do training
eating face sick that's sort of my
full-time job i do courses on code
review and beep exploitation
check out the website or ask me some
questions in the slack them awesome
that's great can you play the clapping
Sylvie's great great so there are a few
comments on slack sniff wanted you to
know that we can hear you up the back
and then we had one question was about
when you were talking about scrambling
is that the same as encryption yes so it
is an attack - sort of - it is like the
encryption it's like quickly
cryptographically secure scrambler and i
use the words family and city encryption
because in these particular cases you
know the goal is to learn these
alligators to be very fast and they
really just want to scramble in
operation they're not really
cryptographically secure operations and
that's why I'm using the word scrambling
instead of encryption but you know in
one sense you know it is trying to sort
of in encryption or a house or something
you know it's
trying to be you know a little element
of you know how having a secret and not
revealing it but they're not really
encryption they're really more swim
photography caitlin also observed that
you did list your twitter handle before
your actual full-time job so it was
interesting to see the importance you
placed on twitter versus your job it was
quite funny that's great I mean you come
come on to the seaside Channel
afterwards I'm sure people have have
questions
it's always very caring that your
research into that you into the heat
alligator and other things so I guess
this but that ends out our two
presentations for tonight we did promise
or do some great