I want to welcome you guys to our sixth
annual b-sides our to you I was really
nervous that I was gonna say b-sides
Raleigh honestly you know I'm probably
gonna say that a few times but we
options obviously have renamed but thank
you all for coming out every year and
supporting us even when we screw up
which you know sometimes we do if you
guys some how many people have been here
since we're here for 2013 for our first
b-sides alright alright how many our
first-time b-sides rdu Oh percent
awesome yes yes we're all the first time
V sides are to you but you know B says
are you Raleigh so you know obviously
we've got a lot of changes this year
we've got a new name a new venue new
logo only um when we decided to change
the name we were a little concerned that
you know people wouldn't be able to find
us people be confused and that we won't
have lower attendance this year well
thankfully that didn't happen we had
over 500 people register if you remember
previously years we had to cap out at
about 275 because the venue's that we we
had that were smaller so you know in the
new venue that we have
so obviously you found us and thank you
for that so the first thing we're gonna
do is we're gonna play a little game
called breach detector it's kind of like
we G so what everyone needs to do is
first of all we need to dim all the
lights and I'm kidding and and everyone
holds hands and then we light some
candles but so we want to thank all of
our sponsors without them the event
wouldn't happen obviously and it's
because of their tremendous sponsorship
this year specifically that we were able
to make the conference free
so I'll just quickly go through our
sponsors we had a number of platinum
sponsors
Verona's Z scalar sands vert code and
FEA
as well as our gold sponsors and our
silver sponsors and of course every year
we also have our community sponsors that
we very much appreciate I also want to
recognize this year staff all the staff
are wearing white badges so if you need
anything have any concerns questions if
you just find someone with a white badge
and you know tap the shoulder so these
are our this is our staff I want to call
out some specific people pretty much
everyone does everyone does a lot of
different a lot of work over the year to
make this happen
everyone did pretty much more work than
than I did of course this is I just get
to be up here and be the pretty face of
besides our to you which yeah that
that's a fail first of all I've got a
face for radio
but anyway so Renee does our artwork I
don't know if Renee is here yet but she
did an awesome job so you see her around
thank her for for the artwork is very
cool
Susan spent a lot of time working on the
badges and t-shirts
Patrick was our CFP guru and he wrangled
all the food trucks that we're gonna
have I'll talk about that in a minute
Greg handled all the sponsors and which
you know like I said wouldn't wouldn't
have had this conference wouldn't happen
without them and Nate was helpful with
bringing the food or the coffee truck I
like I said everyone else does a little
bit of everything we get on conference
calls weekly and to make this thing make
this happen we also had a lot of people
volunteer this year and and you know
leading up to the conference there's a
lot of work that has has to happen make
it happen but also the day of and the
day before we need a lot of help to you
know put bags together with the badges
together things like that so
I want to recognize these volunteers as
all as well I also want to say that
please consider being a volunteer next
year and years coming up because we
always need more help that's how we keep
this thing going and how we you know
help keep it getting better every year
so with that being said our code of
conduct be cool I mean that's pretty
much it right but we like to mention
this because you know we want to make
sure that's a it's a fun and enjoyable
event event for everyone all right
logistics so we have three different
levels here in the theater on the third
level the lounge is where the capture
the flag event will be second level is
our lockpick village and the vintage
tech museum as well as we also have a
hands-on village which is essentially
we've got some kind of hands-on
workshops going on which is really cool
first thing the first time this year
we're doing that and then of course the
vendor hall you guys probably saw it
when you came in it's directly to the to
the right when you leave here going all
the way down please go go see our
vendors the sponsors that make this
happen and coffee a very important thing
one of the comments that we've had over
the years
we need good coffee so we brought in a
coffee truck this year if you guys came
in you saw the coffee truck outside that
it that does cost money we didn't we
didn't buy them out this year
food truck rodeo for lunch we're gonna
have a bunch of food trucks come in and
you guys are you know welcome to go out
and in eat at the food trucks or any of
the other local places that are here
drink tickets everyone was given I think
two tickets correct one ticket okay yeah
one ticket now I want to get later those
drink tickets can be used
throughout the day you know in years
past we've done like a later event where
we do drink tickets or doing this year's
you have to drink it during tickets once
one now one later and we and you can use
them at the concession stand so you'll
see there's a few different concession
stands yeah okay do you have an onion
the lobby concession stand opens at
11:30 there's a third floor concession
stand that opens at 4:30 and the
concessions there's another concession
stand out past the vendor area that will
open it too one thing I'll mention is if
you're not going to use the the drink
ticket to give them back or you know
give them to someone else because we we
do have to pay for and regardless you
actually get thrown out wristbands
everyone in your bags should have gotten
these two wristbands so what these are
are blue is if you're hiring
alright we're trying to connect people
to the point we're trying to connect
people this year so blue means you're
hiring and white means you're looking
for a job I guess the blue has little
penguins on it and and the White has
zombies I don't know they're really
silent auction if you've been here and
patent in our past years we've done a
silent auction this run really well a
lot of people like doing it same thing
this year this year instead of doing
rubles we're doing bitcoins so we've got
these little coins that we've given out
a bunch of them to the different vendors
and the the different folks running the
events like the CTF and as you can see
to earn those bitcoins you participate
in the events participate in the CTF
lockpick village the hands-on and then
at the end of the night when we do
hacker jeopardy that's when you can win
some of the big money all right so so
when Patrick here runs our hacker
jeopardy he's going to be making it rain
bitcoins
oh you do okay cool but if you have them
in here in previous years what we do is
these bitcoins what we what we use them
for is at the end of the night we've got
a bunch of prizes that we've had either
donated or we purchased and you can bet
you can you can bid on those in a silent
auction so during the day the more you
go talk to sponsors in playing the
events and things like that the more of
those bitcoins you can collect later on
tonight you can use those to bid on
these different prizes so I think we'll
have we're gonna have the the prizes
laid out somewhere at some point I'm not
sure you know what you know where we're
gonna have those all right what we'll
make an announcement as to where you can
see them so that you know what your what
your what you're working for
all right so this is our agenda for this
year most you guys probably already
looked at what our agenda is on the
website we have an awesome lineup
honestly I'm really happy to have all
the speakers that we have here our first
speaker our keynote he leads
gff's grassroots and student outreach
efforts he's a constitutional lawyer
focused on the intersection of community
organizing and policy reform as a lever
to shift legal norms with gret with
roots and communities across the country
resisting mass surveillance Austin from
2009 to 2015 he led the bill of rights
defense committee as executive director
in 2018 she had ran for Congress seeking
the seeking to represent the
California's 12th company