[Music]
mr president mr elvis also from my side
welcome back to the secret hall of
security policy
back to munich and before we start about
talking about digital security
uh
stuff i'd like to
begin with conventional physical
security issues
back in 2007 you also were sitting here
in the ballroom it was your second year
as president of estonia and it was also
the moment uh in in fact it was in
february when president putin delivered
his inflammatory speech in this hall and
literally opened the first chapter of
russian aggression in europe and in this
time only a few people
uh took this speech seriously it was you
your counterparts from eastern europe
who warned and about or want of an
increasingly
aggressive russia in retrospect what
could the west have been done better
well
listen to
central and east europeans a little more
but um
to this day
uh let me start saying that uh i don't
know how you chose the date but um
yesterday was the 15th anniversary also
of the removal of a
bronx statue in tallinn which uh
15 years ago today was then followed by
the first
to anyone's well i mean publicly known
state on state
ddos attack um
before there had been all kinds of uh
things that qualified as cyber attacks i
mean the moonlight mile and all these
things that happened before but those
are always kept kind of quiet
but uh
on
april
28th uh
uh uh we woke up and
many of our services were down banks
were down newspapers were down
government sites were down and it was
a
it was a it was clear it was a ddos
attack though we
i didn't much know about ddos attacks
but i quickly found out
uh what's interesting about it when we
talk about cyber is that if you take fun
clausewitz's definition of war which is
the continuation of policy by other
means
this was clearly precisely a clause of
itsyan defined war
and i guess one of the other things that
is sort of resonates here with
the putin speech right up there
uh is that when we went to nato to say
we had the cyber attack
uh people
no one believed us they didn't even know
what it was and some countries
i guess wouldn't know at that time at
least wouldn't have known a laptop from
a toaster oven
so it was uh it was hard to get this
across the people
um
skipping ahead just to do a little bit
of history 2011 is my memory but maybe
you remember 2010 but 2011
was the uh
to quote joe nye
quoting me joe and i wrote an op-ed in
the iht saying
the munich security conference held his
first panel discussion on cyber security
to which
someone from a small east european
country
that was me said this is the first one
but it won't be the last
so at least i've got something right um
in any case just to bring it up to date
i just published with uh with the munich
security uh conference uh
an article which i would say uh ukraine
has proved completely wrong though i
think that it still bears uh has a
little bit of truth to it
uh in which i claimed that uh that with
the end of the second
uh millennium or the end of the 20th
century we really saw the um
we saw that we're up to the 20th at the
end of the 20th century all conflict had
been kinetic i mean with kind of minor
exceptions but what we have seen in um
since the beginning of the 21st century
is that
conflicts are
um are well are digitally based which
uh changes the entire nature of conflict
and war i would say because uh if you
remember your newton's second law uh you
know
force equals mass times acceleration
which is equivalent to distance divided
by time squared well once you get into
the digital or cyber realm there is no
mass and not to speak of with
uh there is no
distance on earth to speak of nor any
notable time
um and so that means the that that in
turn which we can talk about completely
changes the nature of what geopolitics
is about
but you still need tanks
well as i said uh i blew it on that one
but
one of the things yes that everyone has
noticed is the minimal
role played by cyber attacks in
um
in the ukraine
conflict by
i mean on the part of russia which has a
considerable history of doing all kinds
of things
and not only
ddos and hacking and doxxing but
actually hitting critical infrastructure
with the uh
with colonial oil in the united states
so i mean
it's there
and certainly we also have enough
indications of the russians scouting
transatlantic fiber optic cables and
other things so
uh but what i would i think my thesis is
the reason why you haven't seen it is
that the other half of
cyber as it were is that it is a great
equalizer
that ukraine may not have i mean it may
have a
sort of a third of the number of
people
it may have far fewer tanks but when it
comes to cyber you know they can hit
back and i think that well as we've seen
there's been considerable
hacking on the part of the ukrainian so
um
yes we have tanks but i think we also
have not seen cyber to its full extent
possibly because
um there is some kind of um
some balance there and they said well
maybe we shouldn't go too far with this
because the ukrainians actually are not
nearly as outnumbered and cyber as
in cyber as they are in kinetics
thank you before we come
later again to this topic
you once you described
april 2007 when you faced this huge
cyber attack on estonia you described
that once uh as a blessing for estonia
why
pardon me you described 2007 the 2007
attack as a blessing for estonia well it
was a blessing because actually we had
been petitioning nato to
um
to open a center of excellence for cyber
now nato just so for those who are not
nato nato at least at that time i guess
had at 80 or 81 centers of excellence
on different topics uh for example
at that time at least in kiel
here in deutschland there was a
center of excellence for operations in
closed and shallow waters which is a
pretty
specific topic but it was it was a
center of excellence
yet there was none for cyber and we have
been for three years we've been saying
come on this is this is this is going to
be an issue we need to do so in in a
sense it was a blessing because at that
point nato took it more serious far more
seriously and we ended up opening the
uh the the center in thailand center of
excellence in thailand for for cyber
you just mentioned colonial pipeline
we had also incidents in the past take
for instance solar winds which was
really divesting
we are
in times of war we are in a permanent
causes valley in cyberspace
if we look forward
how do we have to react on that with
comprehensive hackbacks cyber sanctions
well this is one of the most
argued and difficult issues is do you do
hackbacks or not and up to now most
governments
do not allow hackbacks because of all
the different problems that can happen i
mean the first one is obviously what
happens if it's a false flag operation
and then that too is something which
in the cyber world it you can very
easily do a false flag
uh attack which you which is much more
difficult if you're on sort of you're
attacking attacking mariopol you know
it's probably not
you know
it's not saudi arabia doing that whereas
uh or iran say but in a for with a
in cyber uh
we could easily imagine false flag
attacks so that's something that's been
tricky
and
in general it's it's not generally been
done
at least in the public sector i don't
know a private sector might have some
other ideas about that but
i don't know
maybe we'll learn more about that today
from the private sector maybe we'll
learn more about that today about
possible hackbacks well then you'd have
the equivalent of the wagner mercenary
group involved too right i guess i mean
but yeah
you rightly mentioned the wagner group
um let's let's take a look again on on
russia state sponsored hacking
especially that what we see from russia
has always
always usually mostly carried out by an
unholy alliance of state agencies and
organized crime actors
how can we drain this swamp
maybe if we separate
both groups
take a different look on that
well i think what we i think our
response needs to be very different uh
not in the particular technology used to
approach them but
i mean what we see on the russian side
is a continuum
of
of activities beginning with uh
the most basic kinds of cyber attacks of
hacking but then moving on to ddos
moving on to then coming out of hacking
doxing which we saw especially uh
in the 2016
uh u.s elections also an attempt
of using hacked materials in 2017 and
the previous
presidential election in france
um
to
disinformation i mean and these are i
mean i hate to talk about the gerasim of
doctrine because i'm not really think
it's a doctrine but it it the russia
does use a continuum of these various
tools that are all
a function one way or another the
digital world that didn't exist 20 years
ago
um you know even disinformation sure it
existed uh you know so we i mean the
trojan horse is disinformation but
but i mean if you think about how uh
this fake story about the us and
inventing aids it took six years to get
from a communist newspaper provincial
newspaper in india to
the german press i mean it's it travels
slowly now all these things come out
constantly but the point is that not so
much what they do but what we don't do
we do not
we do not cooperate there's a little bit
with the five eyes but as of uh
also as a brexit
europe is not even touched by five eyes
but if you look upon if you look at the
what the attackers are doing i mean
basically the two fundamental russian
groups
apt
28 and apt 29
have attacked the state department the
dod the senate or the congress the
bundestag the stiftungen in berlin
they've attached the dutch for foreign
ministry they've done the italian
foreign ministry and on top as an
instrument of state policy
they've even done
wata
the world anti-doping agency so they
don't care i mean and we and we look at
this i mean our problem is that
not only do we not to do things across
disciplines but we don't do anything
across borders
every single country has its own thing
and we don't you know again with the
exception of five eyes
we're not talking very much i mean the
dutch actually have been doing some
stuff but in general we don't
and um i mean a good example of that is
uh when we discovered in estonia a worm
was about 2011 or so a worm a russian
worm in our military network and we went
to nato and
and said look we discovered this worm
and nato's response was oh you too
this is not the proper response
um so i think that i mean i'm told that
things have improved since that time
um
but nonetheless uh the my point is that
we do need to
take these things uh i mean we need a
hell of a lot more cooperation across
borders than we have
and we have very little of it so
that would be my
take on it and indeed you are advocating
for even the longer time for system of
collective security uh in in that sense
maybe also this day is very symbolic
today um
as far as i know europe japan south
korea australia and the us will launch a
new initiative
sort of declaration for the future of
the internet outlining a series of
democratic principles first that sounds
of course good but i wonder is that
enough
is it really enough do we need a better
cyber nato or something like that
well
i mean i think we have to go look beyond
something like nato because recall that
nato is the north atlantic treaty
organization it is the north atlantic
treaty organization not that we are also
wonderful in this region though we are
of course
but nonetheless it's because of
bomber range
flight fighter refueling
tank transport
troop logistics
that's why it's the north atlantic or uh
treaty organization and that's why japan
and south korea and taiwan and australia
and new zealand are not in nato if
people say why aren't they in nato well
that's because we keep thinking about
common values and those states do have
common values but we are we are
restricted actually by geography
now when we get to
the the cyber realm
as i said you know you eliminate
mass you've eliminated distance you've
eliminated
time as an element which means that um
i love this
tallinn torino toronto and tokyo are all
and toledo i guess i should put in there
too
to keep americans happy and tokyo are
all equidistant
there is no i mean there there are
microseconds indifference in uh in an
attack on any of those cities
now if that is the case then um then
maybe we should come up with some other
way of grouping countries
based on values so that you would cover
all of those that i mentioned but other
democracies as well i mean why you know
uruguay is actually fairly developed
digitally
and it's a fine liberal democracy why
don't we invite uruguay too um and of
course nato does have a few problems i
won't get into for political correctness
reasons with some countries in nato that
perhaps don't always come match the
values of the purported values of the
north atlanta treaty organization but i
would very much like to see
something on
moving in this direction that would
allow far more cooperation okay it won't
be five eyes but seriously let's not
have events such as oh
you you discovered that too anymore i
mean that's the kind of thing we want to
get away from
we're also getting away from time yeah i
think
the organizers would allow two three
more minutes because it's really nice to
talk to you um
mr president if we take another look uh
data
data is also a huge issue and um you
once wrote the real issue with big
brother is not so much the state
collecting data as our own behavior
well actually i said the real problem is
the little sister who knows everything
about you and tells everybody else
which is what i sort of coined to talk
about um
facebook uh which basically i mean
i mean
as we all know for ever since 2016. i
mean they're sucking up all our data and
they're selling it and
and that's the little sister uh
and the state actually does fairly
little and in fact uh there are
considerable mechanisms you can buy for
example in estonia on any of the systems
that we have that are state
based on the state system we have
reciprocal
mutual transparency so i can see whoever
is looking at my data
and if they're looking at the wrong
things they get arrested
but in any case
data the other thing i mentioned about
data is that
there has been especially in europe
especially in this country in obsession
with privacy which
i have nothing really about private i
don't really have anything against
privacy but i think we're looking at the
wrong issue
we should be looking at data integrity
which is far more crucial
data i mean privacy is someone publishes
my blood type or my bank account you
know it could be embarrassing and blood
type who cares
if someone changes the record of my
blood type or someone changes my
bank account and certainly probably not
for the better
um
that is a problem and we need to pay far
more attention to data integrity than we
have and so when we talk about data
instead of obsessing about privacy i
would like to be i would like to see a
far greater concern on
data integrity though of course data
privacy is important too since we see
the country places with weak cyber
security
be it the private sector like the
equifax hack or
or the state sector like with the opm
act that was i don't know 20 odd million
federal employees past and present
including psychological profiles of cia
agents all held in one database and in
clear text not even
encrypted i mean this shows that states
need to think a lot more yeah it's
ironic that right now elon musk is
crying twitter for 44 billion uh us
dollar he could have downloaded the app
for free of course but
um so uh we we are unfortunately running
out of time maybe one one very brief uh
question as uh we also should take a
look on germany's role in cyberspace and
after all we really like to lecture
[Music]
but
on the other hand that makes a view of
our country from outside all the more
valuable what's what's your point of
view what's your perspective on germany
and its cyber security
achievements and strategies
well i think every country ultimately
will have to first will will need to
develop
a strong
state
run most likely robust system that it
would have three components
one is a
secure
uh a secure digital secure you everyone
would have a secure unique digital
identity
and then encrypt that would communicate
with end and encryption and with uh
minimally two-factor authentication then
you which which is
slowly coming into existence in europe
uh it's not required but it's urged
with the adas directive it doesn't exist
in the united states at all even though
i think they've missed a lot of
opportunities to do that
then secondly you need to really impose
a distributed architecture so you don't
have a repeat of the
opm hack but more broadly that you don't
store it all in one place as an
elementary cyber security thing and the
last thing is of course
guaranteeing data integrity so in my
country all critical data
including all citizens health care data
all laws because if you think about what
happens if someone changed the laws or
something uh are on a
permission blockchain
so
there those are things need to be done
now when you say ask about germany
um the problem is that you need to be
able you need to make this minimally uh
sort of
national i mean the problem in germany
is you have all these you have 16 lender
and if each one has its sys i mean
whenever i talk to people who deal with
these issues in germany when i say well
you know this is something it would be
really good to do they go well you don't
understand we have 16 lender and we all
have different systems
especially since what our ultimate goal
should be
is that at least some of these services
should be cross-border
in the european union
for example i mean our digital
prescription
which we have in estonia works with fin
also is i mean is mutual works mutually
with finland and bizarrely enough
portugal and croatia um i mean why that
happens much of that is legal rather
than
technical
uh but nonetheless we need to be moving
in that direction and so the first uh
the first challenge i would say for
germany is to
at least get a national system going
thank you so much a lot of food for
thought for this afternoon
thank you that was president thomas
elvis from estonia thank you so much
that you took the time to travel to
munich to speak to us thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
you