[Music]
i'd like to introduce chris krabs who
today runs his own company but until
recently has been the director of the us
government's
cyber security and infrastructure
security agency
it's a very uh colorful task as i heard
then here we have a
helmet clara who is the chief enterprise
information security architect of the
austrian railways
definitely a critical infrastructure
then i would like to welcome
patch who is the branch chief in the
cyber and i.t i cyber i.t department at
the federal ministry of defence in
berlin
and i also like to give a warm welcome
to jeff brown the former chief
information security officer of the city
of new york
and uh
in your administration though
where i understand as many public
servants as in half of munich that's a
pretty big organization
so you see a lot of practical experience
here um on this podium
our focus here now is not global theory
but it's um the operational aspects the
pragmatic aspects and the first question
i would like to ask
and it's kind of an obvious one
that's perhaps in everyone's mind to
falker
russia's invasion of the ukraine
how does that change
how we need to deal and think and deal
with the threat
of our critical infrastructures we all
know what critical infrastructures are
organizing democratic elections are also
kind of a critical infrastructure
and i would just like to remind everyone
that in the ue eu we have just learned
how dependent we are on russian gas
if we consider telecom
a critical infrastructure
in germany
most of our 5g infrastructure is being
built on chinese technology
is that something we want
um
have our leaders got the right mindset
so folker what do you think um how does
the ukraine invasion change the way we
need to deal with critical
infrastructures
so now being safe from the mouse you
still put me in danger of a lot of
questions but um i still take just the
first one
to set off and i would have a very short
and boring answer
the ukraine war hasn't changed anything
because and i think we already heard
that today
there is
to be really precise there is nothing
new we see at the moment what we see in
ukraine is a full-scale war fought in
the cyber information room domain as
well as in traditional domains alnc
by
doctrines which have been
written down in nato and under under
other countries over the last years
which have been excessively
war gamed
and which are now played out in front of
us so
short shortest answer could be nothing
has changed but of course that would be
wrong because a lot have has changed and
we already hit that today
also
but it's a lot about perception
we knew about these threats we knew
about the importance of critical
infrastructure and the importance to
protect critical infrastructure to
prevent effect attacks and to be able to
bounce back from attacks so to survive
to operate
but
i think what we lacked ins at least and
please take this as a little provocation
what we lack was the sense of urgency
and sincerity in
doing something out of this
knowledge
and this
i think has changed or at least i hope
this has changed and it will stay
changed because it will decide
if the green war can have at least a
small a very small positive point
if we are able to bring all these things
together
and really go a step forward i mean we
heard that in the introductory note
a new social contract
and there's a lot which has to be done
and coming back to my own profession of
course we as a military have a lot to do
and i hope we are doing it right now in
mind you all heard about the special
fund announced by our chancellor and uh
debated right now in the parliament the
extra 100 billion you mean yeah exactly
thank you
and it probably doesn't come as a
surprise that we at last at least are
planning to put a very heavy emphasis on
means of digitalization and especially
communication and control
but again
it's it's not something only for the
military it's not only something for the
state it's something for the
for the community as a whole
and there i think really we have a
change in perception and now it's the
time to to use this change
so no change but a different perception
is there anything you'd like to add from
a us or your personal experience i i
agree with that in general i think the
perception from the government side at
least when i sat in government was more
of a security maximalist position so you
know you mentioned a chinese
telecommunications company that's
building out german and other european
uh telecommunications networks it's
because the economic incentive
structures
lead to that
it is too difficult to go to the
alternative either from availability of
production runs or just the sheer cost
of it
so
when you come back from it from the
private sector side you have to look at
it from a p l perspective and you know
what are the economics of the deal and
security costs money security is
friction security is seen is an
impediment or a barrier to doing what
private sector businesses are supposed
to do and that's
make money and deliver value to
shareholders
so until i think we can solve that
equation
absent any other external factors will
continue to be in this mindset all that
said
i do think that
the last two and a half months
have dramatically changed the way
corporate leaders think about risk like
cyber risk like dependency upon
untrusted sources of technology
and they're making
different decisions
in what markets they want to be in
russia you're seeing this mass exodus
from russia and those same companies are
thinking now about like well what's the
next geopolitical flashpoint that i need
to be bracing for
um
and then and then the second piece is
not just what markets i want to be in
but where do i want to source my
technologies
that help drive my innovations so i am
seeing an awakening
i thought last summer i would have seen
a greater awakening with colonial
pipeline and how cyber is a business
risk not just a technical risk but now
we're seeing it as
this is a public perception risk this is
a stakeholder risk this is an esg risk
this is a social incorporate
responsibility risk so cyber
is now up into the big leagues of risk
management theory at least is
at least we're getting there
how do you how would you um from a new
york city point of view look at this
does ukraine change anything or would
you say same thing except as before
except more sense of urgency
i think the answer that question is
building on the previous two points and
to sum it i think it comes down to
tolerance and accountability
accountability
if you think about it what is becoming
unbelievably
uh apparent as we all think about the
war in ukraine
is there is a very low tolerance thank
goodness
for the types of impacts that cyber and
other types of conflict can have and
what people depend on what people depend
on is the critical services that are
provided by their governments and the
critical services that are provided by
the private sector so that's the first
part what is the tolerance and i think
people are waking up that there are
things that we do not tolerant tolerate
so we have to do something about it
and the second piece is accountability
and we're also seeing that uh for years
we've talked about public-private
partnerships and what we're realizing
now is government private sector we're
both accountable and in order to meet
that accountability to the people that
depend on us to be successful we have to
work together
some of you have would you like to add
i fully agree with
this topic because the
companies of critical infrastructure and
all other companies can do their
homework but for
bigger issues we need support from
military or from government and it makes
it covers um one topic that we have to
act together we build up knowledge
together we have act together we have
fight together maybe it's the wrong word
but we have to
run cyber war
against companies and hacker and this we
can only solve in a
common way
some of you have spoken to a sense of
urgency and prioritization i'd like to
come back on that point
to me cyber security is a c level a top
level
issue
you see the right mindset
with our political leaders
political leaders i mean what country
it depends
i
so
look the the kind of war college
monographs i've used that line before
that will be written about the invasion
of ukraine will be fascinating what were
the intelligence wins what were the
intelligence losses i think the us
intelligence community with some of the
five eyes partners got it absolutely
right on what russia was intending to do
in ukraine others did not necessarily
buy into it what i think we missed was
um you know how the the resilience of
ukraine and the lion of kiev and
zielinski we missed that and that's at
least my take
um
how does that though transition into
this the messaging and the sense of
urgency from political leadership into
those at least in the united states that
own and operate critical infrastructure
and can and can the critical
infrastructure owners and operate
actually
action
the guidance that's coming from
government and the plea that i've made
is that you as a critical infrastructure
owner operator that are supporting the
economy in society have a responsibility
to ensure that you are hardened and you
are not a distraction
to
the political leadership and the the
government that is supporting
the ukrainians because the successful
cyber attack by russia on a u.s asset is
going to not just have a disruptive
effect on the critical infrastructure
it's also going to be a political
distraction it's going to lead to civil
and social unrest in the united states
it is on the we're coming up on a mid
critical midterm election in 22 well
that would be fodder
in the election so everyone has a
responsibility to heart be a harder
target
i think that's in part where we
there's a gap there's a delta
oh i would
gladly
go on with that because i really think
we have to be fair we have to be fair to
our politicians as well as to ourselves
um and that's that's the reason why i
talked about urgency
as the main
changing factor of perps
it's not that we didn't do anything in
the in the past
look for example at germany of course we
have
implemented
our cyber defense center on a federal
level to exchange information between
different uh parts of the federal and uh
and the state administration very
quickly concerning cyber threats and i
think it's
definitely not perfect but it's a very
good first step
again coming back to the to the armed
forces of course we have our
architecture already encompassing ideas
like zero trust
or
security by design or whatever
you all can name them
we've got them
in the past it's been just a question
about prioritization
and it's
not so different between private sector
and us
it always comes bound down to the budget
and the question
what do i do with the budget or more to
be more honest what can i do and what
have i do to do
at this moment with my available budget
and um as a private company has to
to
yeah be held accountable by by their
shareholders
we are held accountable by the taxpayers
so it's more or less the same situation
and we we did all this
but hopefully now we will be doing it
faster and again with a with a much
more sense of urgency and that's the
real difference so i wouldn't say we did
something really wrong we had to
prioritize
and this prioritization was done of
course you could say why wasn't more
money given to this
but
to be fair and honest you would also
have to answer the question where does
this money come from
and where do you take it away from
and that's when it gets
a little bit more complicated to answer
if i could add to this um just
having worked in the de blasio
administration in the city of new york
and you have to think about the city of
new york nine million people 100 plus
different departments and agencies 340
000 employees it's a 90 billion dollar
enterprise
what really resonated from a political
perspective was a simple question and it
goes to the social contract conversation
from earlier what do new yorkers depend
on they depend on core services shelter
healthcare justice
transportation water and the question
that came was can this all get disrupted
by a cyber event the answer of course is
yes and to the point when it comes to
the application of budget what we
observed is as we were given the
centralized authority within the cyber
security organization we were also given
the opportunity to help the city
rationalize not how it was spending on
cyber security dividends but how it was
spending on technology and the reality
is as we adopt technology on behalf of
our citizens or our clients we are going
to spend more and more and more on
technology so if you rationalize that
and you bake security in from an
engineering perspective from a process
perspective at the very beginning you
might find that you're actually spending
taxpayer dollars or profits from the
private markets with much more precision
that in fact is better so i think to a
certain extent the whether politics or
corporate structures when you add the
economics of the discipline into it you
may find benefit
all right thank you
kristin and jeff you mentioned
technology is technology sovereignty
a way forward how does that play into
cyber security
in terms of
exporting chips supplying our
trips or systems
from countries that we may or may not
trust
nobody in their right mind would source
our weapon systems from hostile nations
what about our critical infrastructures
so
how do you think technology sovereignty
comes into play here
is that an issue so
sorry
technology sovereignty there's a bit of
duality of meaning here so
there's one meaning where
technology sovereignty means you're
dictating a certain
indigenous proportion or percentage of
technologies used in your government in
your industries the chinese do that
they've established percentages the
russians are working to do trying to do
that as well
the flip side
uh definition is that you kind of have
dominion over the technologies that are
used within your enterprises in their
trusted
and i like to think of that more as a
democratization of technology with a
really heavy emphasis on
the democracy piece and i think that's
where
there are opportunities
down the road
for and we're seeing this in part in the
5g conversation
of how do we establish a com you know a
set of common
nations that have shared values of civil
liberties transparency and rule of law
that can come together and say these are
the these are the principles that that
we want in our technologies our
technology providers
uh and and then you you can incentivize
the the innovation piece uh you can you
can address some of the economics
because no single country is going to
create a national champion in 5g
technologies that can own the market
alone right now outside of china it's
just it's
not possible so instead how do you build
that trading block and it is not going
to be just the us
in europe you know india is a key player
here the global south is a key player as
well but you have to fix those inverted
economics with heavily subsidized loans
predatory uh well pricing and then
predatory loans so how do you get there
like i said you build that block but you
also have to do it on the flip side
where you disincentivize
the behaviors
that have led to
digital authoritarianism you hold them
accountable you hold the chinese
accountable force
intellectual property theft
in in commercial uh you know tech
transfer and one way i've thought about
doing this is 2019 company crowdstrike
released a report on how the comax c19
which is a airplane they've sold for
regional jet uh it's comprised of about
26 different technologies half of them
are stolen from western companies
so there's a block then of democratic
nations of these shared values that say
you're you're not available to trade
that technology because we can attribute
and demonstrate so we've got to have a
little bit more creative uh thinking
around the incentives and who's in and
who's out
any other views
yep definitely i mean uh
i think nobody will discuss the bond
that we need
sovereignty or
yeah let's let's stick with the term
sovereignty but as chris already
mentioned the first question is whose
sovereignty are we talking about
nato eu europe germany
a coalition of a
i don't know number of states
sharing the same values
as a military guy i say i need serenity
because i do need to know that my
systems do what i want them to do and
only what i want them to do
question is how do i achieve this state
i can do it by
knowing it from the scratch
goes in the direction of security by
design and so on or by owning everything
which is in it i can do it which is very
cost intensive and time intensive by
certifying everything i buy afterwards
which could be argued isn't safe hundred
percent
i know that
um but again i think it's all about
practical practical practicability sorry
um and what we can achieve in a certain
amount of time
um we have a certain need this is to be
sure about what we use
and now it's about to how we can fulfill
that and again it's perhaps about the 80
solution and not about the 100 solution
so that's the reason why sovereignty
which means 100 percent
i sometimes take as the wrong term
okay
thanks
another thing that's on my mind is um
how is their way to overcome the skills
gap
between the public and private cyber
security staff on the one hand
uh the public sector has a public
mission
but they may not be able to attract all
the right talent like has been mentioned
before
on the other hand the people in the
private sector may have the skills
but they may have other motives not
necessarily the public interest at heart
any of you or not jeff perhaps
i think as an individual i've certainly
personally professionally benefited
from exposure to both the private sector
and the public sector and i think the
intersection of both
those
sort of pursuits
can be the mission
and to a certain extent as i think about
the ability to grow a workforce in the
public sector the public sector has an
incredible amount of credibility because
they have the authority to say
we are serving the people that's an
incredible driver of mission
and
as
the private sector
participates in that through its great
innovation advising capabilities you
start to see this wonderful
exchange and as long as you're
offering open doors between those two
pursuits then people can grow in their
careers i certainly think that you can
get
unmatched training across a whole set of
disciplines if you're in the public
sector and you can have terrific like
benefit experimentation
um and really practical application in
the private sector so as long as the
conversation's happening between both
and you're pulling and pushing then you
can grow an absolutely fantastic
workforce
other views has it been an issue in
where you work
the
advantage of austria is it is a small
country so we don't have this problem
between public and private partnership
not because we are working together we
have a lot of models of private public
partnership
and there are also groups
we are as
companies
give inputs for the official parties how
can we
made models
or guidelines they are real working in a
good and effective way for us
so the private public partnership is
very high established in austria
but there is a second point
you said before the austrian railway is
part of the critical infrastructure in
austria and our mission forced by the
stakeholder
and and and honor the austrian
government is
to keep the society and the economic
industry up and running
so for this we have to transport good
and passengers from a to b in a safe and
secure way
so it sounds like very simple and it is
a pretty cool and sexy job but we have
to handle with a lot of different
technologies
um complex systems and we have to handle
with people's life
so
an independent if you have a pandemic
independent of critical uh or political
let's say independences
or nature hazards and so on nobody would
ask how can we fulfill them but we have
to fulfill them and we are responsible
for this kind
the good news is we invest a lot of
money in systems
in infrastructure and in cyber security
but
the bad news are if we invest 100 times
more we never reach 100 of security
so this means maybe we have to change
our mindset
the first point
go away from the cyber security is all
to
to the slogan more or less
that the key is cyber resilience and
cyber security is a part of them
and to fulfill this we need
stable systems we need secure systems
we need secure operating system we are
working with operating system we don't
know what they do and we need a lot of
money to maintain some cure so why we
don't have secure hardware such
operating system made by eu sorry
but this is the best way for us
just coming back
to this question can we close this this
gap between private sector and the
public sector i think um short answer
again yes we can
um but probably the only only real way
to do this is
we cooperation
heard that
can we for example again as far arm
forces can we attract
enough personnel with the right skill
set
i'm skeptical
we tend to have a certain hair card
not so
attractive for a lot of the it geeks
we're talking about
the pay gap was already mentioned during
the former panel
all this makes it a little bit
hard do we stop in trying no of course
not um
we tend to attract a lot of people with
different skill sets we train them very
well and we give them great
opportunities because sometimes
with the armed forces they
may do things
they couldn't or at least shouldn't do
in the private sector
and that can be right quite interesting
for one or the other
um
so
but coming back to the to the real
answer yes we can do it but it's again
we're in this in this new social
contract we have to do it together
it's all about the public in the private
sector working together and please do
not forget we're talking about the
private sector this is not a unity we've
got very large
critical infrastructure companies they
don't have any problems come competing
with us or the world but we also got
smus which have definitely have much
greater problems
and have the same question how do we
as a private company close the gap to
these large companies
so this is what i think of as a defend
today secure tomorrow problem and what
that means is that there are things we
can do today we can automate certain
tasks to take that human element out of
it and push the human source a higher
order bit and the higher order problem
we can retrain trends or provide
training to transitioning to you know
military
veterans and things like that
but but if if we don't fix the
underlying structural problems
we're going to be fighting this battle
for forever and and some of those
structural problems are frankly in the
education system so i live in the
washington dc area i have five kids
and i look at the education
that's available to them and from a
computer science
and
you know software engineering or coding
perspective it's just not readily
available in the public system or in the
private school system so how the heck
are we going to compete compete in the
longer term so we have to invest
in the future or we're going to be
fighting this battle
we're going to be having the same panel
30 years from now
after yeah all right
[Applause]
i was gonna make a bad joke about covet
32 or something but
interesting infrastructure problems um
one thing i was going to ask you as well
is
obviously there's more and more threats
the cost to defend goes up exponentially
and you're never going to get 100 secure
so
should we look into shifting a focus
from protecting our infrastructure to
just accepting a certain vulnerability
but focusing more on business continuity
is that a viable model or is that
nonsense
if i can jump in on that i think that
was one of the great observations
serving new yorkers when we thought
about
what they needed and the types of
impacts and consequences that would be
paid by a cyber event we thought as the
whole apparatus working together and i
think to a certain extent bringing a
conversation around resilience and then
including not just the cyber security
silo but the additional continuity of
operations capabilities of any
organization or organizations together
is the right approach i don't
necessarily accept as an individual that
all that there will always be a threat
that will be successful i i don't accept
that we cannot
succeed and defend
with that said i like the expanded
definition of being successful by saying
if for some reason there's a cyber event
i've got a number of different people
along the line with different
authorities and capabilities to help
succeed
so that's why
i like to think about it all right other
views
yes of course
let's have a look behind the last two
years
i think there's a lot we can learn about
what happened there are positive aspects
from eu and official bodies to make
standards to force security thank you
for this also like in ether there are
also a lot of power for this but on the
other hand we had a lot of negative
topics they have a massive input of
security and safety for the systems
so i said before we never reach 100 of
security so we need both we need
the operations from the pre-active part
to prevent and
detect
incidents
and we need also the condition business
continuity management if something
happened to to start up our systems
again
we need both in a balanced way i would
say
i would
really like to pick up wedge of
stopped um
i loved your saying as an individual i
won't accept that there always remains a
certain threat now let's go on and say
even as organizations we shouldn't
accept this
um because it leads to the best effort
but at the same time we should also
always realize that not accepting
doesn't mean it doesn't happen
and that's what i meant when i when i
tried to define to defend earlier on in
the panel
defense is in the first step about
preventing successful attack
but in a second it's always about
bouncing back
or staying operational on a probably
lower level but
coming very
very quickly back to the level you do
need to operate uh resilience the the
classical term in this discount and i
think that's what we what we really have
to focus on so again i don't think we
need a change or a shift in strategy we
again have to build up on
perhaps it's also an educational
issue because as a society we have to
understand this there is no one no 100
security
and there won't be a 100
security it can't be because there is
nature for example tomorrow i can hit by
a metroid i'll be dead so i can try to
defend myself against it i probably
will be successful because tomorrow
evening i won't be hit by madrid
but
to be not to coming back to it again i
think
no shift
but being clear about this and being
more honest to ourselves as an as a
society as individuals and as
organizations and that's really
important because
when we do this we come back to the
questions of prioritization
when we're talking about funds and
budgets and so on money
it i i think
building on that the resilience piece i
think also if this is a risk management
problem and if you think about risk
management risk is the classic
combination of threat vulnerability and
consequence i think we've really
invested heavily in understanding threat
and mitigating threat we're working on
the vulnerability piece and
understanding where vulnerabilities in
our systems are misconfigurations and
addressing those i think what we don't
do enough of
is managing the consequence variable
and i i've seen that in the us
government where all the prioritization
is on the threat piece
and then you move down the gradient
towards towards uh vulnerability but
consequence is a wide open space
and so if we can focus on that in
understanding into the through the
traditional business continuity planning
perspective and what those you know what
your recovery time objectives are and
things like that you start baking that
more and more into it operations
in the dependencies we have including on
third-party service providers and how
bad a cloud shock would hit us if aws
azure gcp whatever drops out tomorrow
like those i think that's the
the discipline
where uh
we need more maturity we need more
investment
if i can add on that i think to a
certain extent we need incentive to do
so
and right now if you look at how
interconnected we all believe we
certainly are digitally
like the incentive is that we realize
that you know as we observe and
a war
from a digital perspective
we are connected and that is a very
strong incentive because you know though
some of us are so far away
what happens
proximate to that geography
through digital means is directly
able to impact our critical
infrastructure and our trust mechanisms
like imagining that maxar technologies
got down for example maybe one
additional point to manage the risk you
said before we need people to have
knowledge about so and i googled on that
trip
to munich um how many
universities or our schools
offers i.t security so it's not really
much and then i googled about ot
security for the critical infrastructure
i received a result with zero foundings
so at this point we need a push for the
digital literacy
let's make a simple experiment
every unpatched device every arpeggio
device can be used as zombie for ddos
attacks to our critical infrastructure
systems or other systems
so it's it's not very difficult
who have you
so we have to start at our own self
same as mine who of you have configured
your dsl router in a secure way at home
okay
[Laughter]
and who doesn't what is configured
i mentioned i have five kits right
yeah yeah that's what i mean so what we
have to do is to raise up the digital
literacy at the the society starting at
us and and ending at the university
academic line
all right interesting i'd like to switch
subjects a little bit um and touch on
the operational aspects of two emerging
technologies everyone's talking about
blockchain
and quantum computing
how does that affect
cybersecurity
blockchain
is an architecture that by definition is
built trustless
does that make
a cyber security guy's job easier
do uh quantum computers that make it a
lot harder because they can hack
anything or crack any code any views
so just a quick anecdote on blockchain
and cryptocurrencies in particular so
i've
long been banging the drum on ransomware
and i think the last time we were here
in 19 i talked about the the
national security threat that was
ransomware
there are three problems with ransomware
in general first is that
the install base is still too easy to
hit you know the vulnerabilities the bad
guys have just figured out how to
monetize misconfigurations and
vulnerabilities the second is that there
are financial instruments outside of the
fiat economy regulatory mechanisms in
cryptocurrencies and exchange wallets
and things like suez exchange that allow
for that transfer outside of law
enforcement the third is that there was
a safe haven or harbor in russia that
would allow this
ecosystem to thrive
the problem that we saw at least in the
united states was we actually don't know
what the denominator is in ransomware
because no one's reporting it to the
federal government
there's there's about a 15 to 20
maybe
understanding of the types of ransomware
attacks really the only person that
knows how many ransomware attacks there
are the ransomware actors themselves
and the the issue here is that if we had
more timely reporting
of ransomware events with key indicators
including the wallets that you're
sharing
the cryptocurrency
ransomware payments into if you shared
that with
a cryptocurrency forensic team and law
enforcement due to the immutable
characteristics of the blockchain
you could actually probably disrupt
and recover like they did after
colonial
last year
so there are incentives but the again
the legal mechanisms that are in place
the fear of reporting so there are
advantages to the blockchain to cyber
the cyber security community we're just
not realizing them for various lawyers
reasons very interesting
i would take quantum computing um
short version uh course and a blessing
for the military at least
it's a course because it makes
secure communication
and everything which has to do with
encryption
a lot harder
a blessing
because for me as a military not for me
as a person it makes cracking the other
guy's secure communication a lot easier
so again it's
about this balance and it's always about
the situation i'm in at the moment what
it will give me
our answer is we are resist researching
quantum computing at our federal armed
forces university here in munich um
because we
very early started to think about this
point and it's something very high up on
our again
so you're saying it makes sense to spend
time thinking about quantum computing
and also blockchains because it is
relevant
jeff i was just going to say especially
on quantum
it never helps society to back away from
innovation and if you just think from a
math perspective of what quantum is it
allows the computation of exceptionally
almost unfathomable problems which means
if applied correctly we can solve
exceptional unfathomable problems so by
no way should security stand in the way
of it in fact we should run towards it
because we have a lot of problems to
solve
um yesterday i was on a security and
risk management event in austria and
there was one of the master people of
quantum computing in austria also there
and he has a presentation about
and he said
one of the big benefit of our actual
encryption methods are that the
decryption
needs a much more longer time than the
encryption
so and he was proud to present that the
quantum computing
needs less time for decryption was at
the same time for decryption as
encryption
so and if i'm asking okay but what does
it mean for the security community does
it mean we lost our benefit of
encryption because the hacker need the
same time to decrypt what we encrypt yes
so and i'm not sure i'm not sure if it
quantum computing is a benefit for your
security if we don't have a look about
how we use them
to a certain amount would kill my joke
because of course it's it's true that
quantum computing will give us a
special opportunity on new capabilities
in terms of our own encryption
but
i just can't go out in in some shop and
buy a totally new equipment for the
whole armed forces so i will always have
this transitional phase where the old
equipment and this will be
in danger by quantum computing
as well as in the new equipment which
will bring the advantages of quantum
computing to the table so i try to
have my jokes surviving
real quick and maybe you know peter to
think about next year's agenda an issue
that i think we're not paying enough
attention to right now and this is
another one of those defend today secure
tomorrow problems is web 3.0
decentralized finance smart contracts
the the risk that that is being uh
levied out right now is incredibly
complex
and it's flying under the eye of
regulators
and i i don't i don't think we have a
full appreciation of of what is uh
what's being held on to out there right
now without i think we've run over time
i hope it was interesting to all of you
great questions thank you give me a big
give a big round of applause to this
podium
[Music]
you