[Music]
oh
thanks so much for joining me it was
mentioned the spot on panel has been a
regular feature here at the conference
as veterans of the conference know
you might also know it comes with
strengths attached because i'm always
told by the organizers this is supposed
to be the fun panel it's supposed to be
more
i mean of course all the panels are
hilarious but
no pressure here so
just to build up expectations
i will let you in on the secret
apparently in the past years we haven't
lived up to expectations because this
time i was reminded that it's supposed
to be fun and optimistic so we are
supposed to focus on the opportunities
of cyber security so we are widely
determined here to folk to be widely
optimistic to focus to see every threat
as an opportunity of course
during the panel and it's going to be
easy because i have here on the panel
not just
wildly qualified but also wildly
cheerful people i suppose
mary uh who is with ibm who is a
general manager of ibm security is the
largest enterprise security company in
the world period no further introduction
needed
central um who
is not just executive vice president of
mandiant in dc
but also pursuing a phd at johns hopkins
currently it's not for a lack of degrees
because she already holds an mba at from
mit and also master's degrees in cyber
policy international affairs science and
technology intelligence and military
operational art and science did i forget
one no that's all yeah
that's all you have
then we have of course here marcus uh
sorry there
marcus who is uh the group cio at
ohb in bremen one of the leading german
space companies and we have christopher
right here
who has not just five granted software
patterns but also multiple pending so
there's more to come
i'm looking forward to the discussion i
would like to start with you mary uh in
the spirit
spirit of our more optimistic outlook it
is often said that uh people um are the
most vulnerable gateway for attacker
resources so how do you build a con in a
huge organization like ibm how do you
build a more constructive culture i mean
how do you make sure that people are not
just the problem when it comes to cyber
security but also part of the solution
yeah so thank you for having me here
it's a pleasure and so yeah i believe um
people can be the weakest link and um so
we take the opportunity to educate our
people you've just got to create
awareness
um got to create awareness of
you know the level of activity um that's
needed the level of understanding of um
digital education digital literacy but
also understand that
involving um
your people from
the receptionist to the boardroom can be
the source of um exploiting a
vulnerability in your system and so
everybody plays a part and everybody
needs to understand the part they play
so it's all about education it's all
about testing that your education is
effective
and
just
also exercising the muscle memory in
trials and tests and so on just like you
would a fire alarm so everybody can be
the weakest link but everybody can be
part of the solution
how do you make sure that people are
rather part of the solution than the
weakest link yeah you you educate them
but then you run your fire drills and
you make sure that they've deeply
embedded in their muscle memory is how
they behave how they should behave and
how to ensure that they're not the
weakest link
senator with your huge experience both
in the public and private sector how do
you make sure
that people are drive or how do you
identify drivers of trust in
organizations
i think that we think about people quite
a bit when we think about solutions
and i think that there's limitations to
what we can expect through you know
augmenting or shaping a workforce
um vince surf from google said something
very poignant that i i think about a lot
which is that there was a time when
there were so many
telephone operators who are manually
connecting calls that it was projected
that almost every adult in the united
states at some point would have to be a
telephone operator to meet that demand
but what we did was we created
you know direct dial assist
and now we thankfully can have other
jobs besides besides that so
i'm thinking about technology solutions
for
to drive some of these trust issues um
not always thinking about the the
fallacies or the
the weaknesses that people bring because
they always will bring it but what
innovations and what technology can we
put in place that will reduce these work
force shortages that will make uh trust
architectures more efficient and require
less human intervention i know there are
downsides i know there are there are
you know ethical questions and those
things obviously need to be need to be
part of that but you know let's give
innovation a chance when we do this
speaking of innovation christopher not
just many patents but um
i know that to most people here in the
room the concept of
open security is
something they are very familiar with
explain it to cyber idiots like me or
other people in the audience that are
not aware of what is meant by open
security
so actually i don't really know what you
mean by openstack okay when you say it
well and lightness well just the idea
that
you might work with open security
systems that are publicly available and
i think you say open source open source
that's right so no if you think about it
so in the world of security for the
longest time intelligence has been
something that is very secret and it's
something that we can generate
if you want secure a secure world a
world of trust and so based on secret
intelligence and mi6 and spice and what
have you i think and and many with me
that there is a new world out there with
the most important intelligence is
actually collected off the web it's
based on open sources is inherently
shareable his historical intelligence if
i have a secret and i'm going to get it
to you you wrote about all the in intel
stuff and you know people will kill to
keep it secret in the world of open
source we can actually share
intelligence we can develop trust much
much better and i think actually being
able to deal with sort of fundamentally
address
cyber security through open open
information if you want to or open
source intelligence is maybe one of
those ways we can build a better
internet i like to use the analogy of
financial markets imagine if we built
financial markets based on only secret
information it would be pretty crappy
financial markets to be full of bad
actors trying to take advantage of
themselves of of each other
in in financial markets we have
companies like bloomberg that actually
provides information flow because of
that information flow that is open to to
to most participants in the market
financial markets are largely great and
i think this is a key component we've
been missing in not just in cyber
security but in in as it relates to the
internet may be very large and that's
what we're trying to do at recorded
future be the equivalent of bloomberg in
cyber security how do you encourage
particularly companies to be less
secretive in that regard because it i
mean obviously they're often not
inclined to share that kind of
information does it need more public
regulation or does it need more
incentives to
it's a great point so there's been a lot
of talk about information sharing here
today and
to be honest 20 years of information
sharing has led nowhere we our internet
is worse off today than it was 20 years
ago that's the i could say it in a
subtle way
optimistic yeah i know but no i think
i'm optimistic about the future
so so
it's literally the internet has gone
worse in 20 years and as much as we have
information sharing left right and so on
because lawyers
don't allow you to share information and
any sane person who's been in a bad
situation it's not going to let you
share the juicy stuff either but if we
can base build open source intelligence
we can actually address this if it's
shared on a common platform so marcus to
the rescue here would you would you say
that everything has gotten worse over
the past two decades in the internet
from a security standpoint yes i think
from a usability standpoint we we went
through a hyperloop of innovation maybe
yeah everything changed we have all
these social media we have
influences we have just if you look at
your kids and the young generation here
how we deal with information uh we gave
away information not a target show or
something like that yeah we look at tick
tock and we look at the channels so so
lots of things changed
also information is available to
everyone
not all it's not always good yeah
because you also have to learn how to
deal with this overflow of information
but in general i think from an
information stand point of view it
became better however everything became
networked yeah we learned about years
ago about these internet of things and
all these billion of things that will
communicate with each other so from a
security stand point of view i think it
became worse because you have this
network effect we we just learned about
this log4j issue yeah where's one
piece of code just a string yeah that
hits billions of devices all of a sudden
so um it's on one hand a huge chance on
the other hand a huge risk or speaking
of that because i'm married just to
bring
bring you back into the discussion i
mean cyberspace is not just one galaxy
it's a galaxy of so many things now if
you think of the internet of things i
mean how can security prevail in that
environment i mean what do you tell your
people on the one hand you are trying to
build the internet of things and on the
other hand you want more security in
that
i'm kind of going to bring you a little
bit back to open and uh chris did say
what do you mean by open so i'll give
you another definition um so
i think um
how you can be optimistic here is
security is a team sport and we heard on
all of the other panels about the need
for collaboration the need for
collaboration across state boundaries um
you know among organizations across the
various different regions within germany
and etc
and you know while um you can put
frameworks in place and legislation in
place and have all kinds of aspirations
to make collaboration effective you also
can rely on technology too
and
there has been significant progression
in the generation of
open standards and technology based on
open standards to make it actually
possible for for security intelligence
security insights security information
to be shared so that we can collectively
whether we're partners whether we're
competitors you know whoever we are we
can actually choose to share and improve
um our hand and improve discipline look
christopher there is hope is there too
rosy and out there is absolutely hope
the world has become better over the
last 20 years but then at the same time
you take tick tock which is says
programming badness straight into
people's heads
that's a new definition of tick-tock
what is your take on that
let's say we we we're not very fun yet i
just have to say this yeah i know i know
but we have 29 minutes left so go ahead
um so the take on specifically the which
part of of
what where what was your uh focus on the
question well the idea primarily
if things had gotten really worse over
the past two decades and on the other
hand if cooperation is
more likely or more possible now look
the internet is a is a tool for us so
really it is as good or as bad and as
useful or as detrimental as we shape it
to be
and i think that that puts the problem
and the solution in our hands and you
know from my organization what we have
done is we run
at you know in my my group is
the world's largest
commercial intelligence organization
focused on cyber that's not connected to
a government
and through that what we have found was
that we can open the aperture of the
government view and do some of that
sharing of of intelligence to better
decision making the optimistic part of
this is that i can tell you that in in
the cyber security industry
even our competitors are our partners
when things get rough and when things
get serious
my first calls sometimes are to my
competitors do you see this because you
need to let your customers know this is
serious
so you would say the sharing of threat
intelligence has really improved over
the years i can give you a perfect
example after the solomoni killing we
saw passwords spraying all throughout
europe and the united states to critical
infrastructure
and i called
one of my my competitors who i knew had
some presence in the space i told him
what we're seeing not customer data not
you know but threat data threat
information
they said they were saying the same
thing and then we could work together to
protect everybody a global security
community does exist
and
shared values across is what we've been
talking about through this
it exists in the global security
community i i've i've felt it i've seen
it
it's organizations countries governments
who share a vision for humanity that is
not just democracy
because we've seen that some democracies
are illiberal democracies let's call it
not the right kind of democracy but
one's more socontian tradition of
individual liberties and representative
government and that type of democracy so
you know we we are working together in
the cyber security community um even
competitors i've lived it i know in your
organization as well so there's there's
room for hope mark is you're i know you
have european roots as well but you're
the european one here on the panel
because you're literally based in europe
i mean for many years people said here
in europe well it can be a you usp for
us or for our companies if we have a
higher security standard and it is good
for business ultimately i mean is that
still true or have you seen
any of that hope fulfilled over the
years well i think first of all we
should not mix up data privacy and cyber
security i think european paradigm is
always okay we keep the data privacy
high
sell this as a usp and i think the idea
is good yeah however how it is
implemented is bad yeah if you open a
website of any kind you just click away
a privacy note and you're not
even
taking
with you what is in there yeah so you do
not know what you do or you know what
you accept if you click away these
things
so how it is realized is quite difficult
the idea is good and i think it will be
a usp because people will want to have
their privacy
and
we can see that all our world and it's
also i think a political dimension yeah
can we guarantee privacy in democratic
camp countries yeah and and we can see
in china now in russia
the people they do not have this freedom
and maybe by manipulation we're not
suffering by that but i think in a from
a democratic point of view um this is a
usp and i think also if you look to the
u.s we have similar movements yeah not
to that extent not so extreme yeah we
learned already that the europeans but
we're very good in regulating
um and probably sometimes we're also
over regulating yeah but so the truth is
as always in the middle yeah and i hope
what we learned from what we did and
that we can also adjust that
you spoke initially about educating
people in your organization i mean you
know and it was mentioned in the
previous panel as well you have a huge
skills gap often i mean particularly
among
younger and older employees and also
people in the public and the private
sector i mean what tools can you use to
close that skills gap i mean can
artificial intelligence be a tool that
or that is already being used absolutely
artificial intelligence has been used
dramatically um
we use it throughout our entire
portfolio of products and services and
all of our competitors and partners use
artificial intelligence because if you
consider
how
how much cyber security data needs to be
processed in order to find the needle in
the haystack that is the important piece
that you need to respond to
if you consider the volume of that data
humans simply cannot deal with it so you
do need
you know compute power and you need
assistance to the human in order to be
able to process that level of data and
in order to do the right level of
analytics to be able to
you know
separate the wheat from the chaff you
know essentially um so artificial
intelligence is being used and
automation is being used because you've
got to automate
the um
you know the the low level of of
activity that needs to be progressed so
that the short
and the short supply security and
analytics or analysis can actually face
and deal with you know the high value
work that needs to be done so
absolutely um artificial intelligence
but it needs to be transparent and it
needs to be ethical and it needs to be
curated it needs to be watched
and significant automation i believe are
um significant answers to the shortage
in um
you were nodding heavily so i suppose
you agree i'll i'll be equally
optimistic here actually you know for
once finally
so absolutely so intelligence for
example historically has been a very
manual effort and so i'm not an analyst
by background i'm a computer scientist
when we attacked that problem we said
look let's think about this as a data
problem and and then we could do what
mary said and sort of attack
intelligence and and you think about
mark anderson's story from 10 years ago
where he said
software is eating the universe eating
the world and and so software can eat
intelligence as well and so that's the
sort of the way we've gone at that then
secondly on the point on sort of i think
when it comes to hiring and bringing on
people and so on and people especially
in cyber security it's oh it's so hard
to find people and
but it's because they don't want to go
out this in a the real way where you
sort of go hire people from you know
basically off the street kids in school
and try to educate them from bottoms up
and of course if you're trying to hire
the guy with 25 years experience and
they sort of go round around and in some
i don't know what it is
they apply terrible strategies to a
problem that doesn't work out for them
and then they sit and whine about it you
can hire people for out of school and
you can educate and uh we can do that
and if we can do it then many people can
do it
we need to talk about optimistic points
i know we need to talk about a few
issues though that are neither funny nor
particularly optimistic there were
warnings a few weeks ago about malware
that was already addressed on other
panels about pipe dream uh that sounds
like a plot from a james bond movie but
it seems to be very real
sandra how concerned are you about such
new developments malware that we call in
controller is something that we have
done a very deep dive on and the
disconcerting part about it and you're
right this part's not the good news not
the optimistic news is that it attacks
safety systems of industrial control
systems it reminds me of 2017's triton
malware which accidentally possibly shut
down an oil and gas facility
in such a reckless way and thereby
endangering the lives of people
so should we be worried we should
definitely be worried that there's a
capability
probably russian although we haven't
done the attribution completely on that
yet but i would say that we've seen
capability we've seen in tent we have
seen the um gru deploy
recklessly sort of wormable exploits
around the world so in this way i think
we need to be
thinking that
um you know a a friend of mine has said
that it is
not a technology problem but a russia
north korea in a china problem dimitri
alperovitch so i agree with him in that
we will not solve this
on the defense side we're not going to
solve it that way we're going to need to
go to root causes we're going to need to
talk to
the builders of this the the those who
harbored those who provide safe haven
those who use cyber tools recklessly
have to be taken to account we need to
start being
very proactive in those things and now
we're in an environment where we've
probably waited too long because we are
now in a crisis mode and how are we
going to start that diplomatic process
or at least carry out the diplomatic
process we're in the middle of dealing
with um
you know what i will call hand-to-hand
combat in the cyber domain tactical use
of wipers against organizations and
people in ukraine and we're watching it
now the scenario i worry about is these
same actors doing a not pecha event
using wipers
think about that for a second but that
would do to all of us well you addressed
russia explicitly so we need to talk
about russia too marcus
i use so far underwhelmed by the russian
performance when it comes to cyber war
because people were expecting
more
yeah we had we saw already earlier
nobody knows what is already in our
systems yeah
at least on the attack side what we can
observe regarding our own risk we can
also see that the attacks are going down
because it seems that the attackers are
busy
in another war room yeah
so this is for the moment a positive
effect but you should never feel safe
yeah we have to be prepared for next
time and we had it already earlier
talking about the 80 security no one is
able to ensure 100 security whatever we
do um so i think we also have to improve
our capabilities to react yeah and then
it's it's not even heck back yeah we
just have to be able to react uh
if our defense is not successful and i
think we are pretty weak in that area
too yeah we're focusing too much on on
defense on identifying an attack but now
how do we react in terms of
survivability in terms of resilience
that's that's i think a big point not
only for critical infrastructure but
also for corporations yeah in order to
safeguard their business to come back to
our panel's topic building trust and
security when we talk about russia which
is an important factor in this whole
equation i mean how do you
i mean let's say two or three years from
now how are we going to rebuild trust
with russia in the cyber space community
i think unfortunately you're vastly
optimistic if you think two three years
is decades yeah this is decades to sort
of be able because it's true that i
think senator was right on we're not
going to solve this by dealing with
computers you're going to have to see
arrests in russia of cyber criminals
they don't need to be extradited but
they need to be arrested
and their computers need to be taken
away because not you know you will catch
some of them in in spain they seem to
like to go to spain and then boom we
snatch them
and and
it's actually true
but the but we're not going to be able
to do that on moss and and so we're
going to have i eventually will be able
to do that but unfortunately here go a
little bit negative now a whole bunch of
russian engineers are going to run out
of jobs
and some small very small portion but
maybe enough pe set of people are going
to lose their ability to make money and
they'll drift more into this so no
unfortunately that part is not very
optimistic you would say it will take
decades to rebuild that trust or decades
of trust have been destroyed now i don't
really know what the difference is but
it will take a long time how about that
center just come back to that briefly
because on the international level there
have been many efforts also to cooperate
with i mean sometimes russia has even
been the driver on these issues so you
think that is over now entirely or
is there hope
i think that they have completely
crushed
any
um
any trust
through their actions on several levels
not just the cyber domain but but let's
be realistic for a second
we've been tracking russian actors doing
malicious activity
conducting reckless attacks
for years
we know which organizations are doing it
they have missions they come from the
gru the svr the ffsb they have a mission
a standing mission to do these things
they did them before they're doing them
now and they're going to do them into
the future
because that is their mission that is
their job
to conduct espionage to create malware
to have um to to carry these things out
for their political ends so therefore
just back to it it's a it's a political
problem and it's a hard political
problem and people a lot smarter than me
are going to need to solve it and
probably our kids
but i think you would also agree that
it's been pretty remarkable to see
what's been going on in ukraine so you
know speaking in extremely general terms
seeing how we've been able to help there
and being you know put
i'll just say very vaguely put things to
work and not just sort of what we've
been able to do but in collaboration
with others
in you know in here really talk about
public private sort of partnerships that
have emerged in weeks
and and you know maybe months by now has
been remarkable and and you know now
it's always hard with this sort of stuff
to say what stopped what and what time
and so on but even in the short tour
time frame you know
observing that that is cause for real
optimism would you agree coming from the
private sector this is a new level now
in this public private partnership oh
definitely absolutely definitely um
i mean anything that can be done
to
to help um the ukrainians has been done
um whether that's from the private
sector or the public sector and every
opportunity to collaborate
and just um remove any friction and any
sound from their machine has been done
and will be done yes
you had a strong opinion maybe uh what
comes to my mind uh when it comes to
trust and uh i'm a practitioner yeah
day-to-day uh i.t business management uh
so it's not about of a trust to russia
and so on when i think about it's more
about the trust in between public
private and then also trust to american
companies yeah and this is a big issue
we also have a big audience from the
government and
sector here from european governments
we are afraid of using american
technologies yeah and this is just a
matter of trust yeah the lack of trust
the lack of control we have these
discussions about serenity
of european data uh so we don't even
trust each other yeah maybe the
europeans trust the europeans but not
over or even the germans trust the
french yeah so so and i think here
uh we have to develop maybe a community
that builds trust amongst western
democracies yeah
that our platforms can be used by each
other without having every time the
discussion and we start with a workers
council about where data are not being
processed by americans
this ends up
with
government authorities about tax data
and so on that might be processed
in another country and i think this is
an issue if we want to be strong
um against these uh
eastern uh
attackers yeah we
all
first of all we have to find ourselves
yeah and build a stronger command
community
uh in western democracies okay there's
optimism there too so we have we have 30
national security centers slash certs on
the same what we think about because we
think ourselves as a transatlantic
company so we have 30 ncscs around the
world on our same platform and having
through that one data set that is shared
that people can share analytical
techniques on and i think that's pretty
tremendous progress that would not have
happened 10 years ago but having this
sort of is just again tremendous
progress and seeing this then being a
channel to what's going on on the again
defensive side in ukraine is pretty
remarkable so we're doing progress we're
doing probably our basic note again yeah
uh two quick questions to uh sandra and
mary before we open it up to the
audience uh
one to you sarah essendra do you think
this current crisis that was uh
described by marcus is that a sea change
when it comes to
trusting each other
particularly on a transatlantic level
because you see that alliance in a way
now in ukraine
well i think it certainly created a
sense of urgency around sharing um
the uh there's a bit of a hierarchy
though in you know ukraine has a lot of
new friends
right and there are some older friends
who who've been um helping there for
over a decade such as are you implying
that germany is a new friend right so
you know i i think that it is uh you
know there is cause for
for um a new paradigm after this i think
that one thing that we know is that um
it would be great if we had a better way
to sift through all the helpful things
that
all of ukraine's you know the government
and partners there all of the new um and
dilute you know just a huge amount of
information wanting to be passed we
don't really have a good mechanism to do
that in order to then you know what are
the functions and you know of getting
intelligence you want to be able to
detect blocked you know prioritize and
respond and you want to do that as fast
as possible hopefully by automation but
when you can't you need to use judgment
so is it is it a new day in in trust and
all that i think it's a it's an urgent
time
and we should learn a lesson here for
the next time that oh i don't know
another
autocratic government tries to take over
a territory
um in its space
that maybe we need we will find
ourselves in the exact same position
hopefully we've learned something very
speaking of trust does it undermine
trust in american companies particularly
in silicon valley companies like google
amazon others so if they are sometimes
seen
as warriors too because they are engaged
in cyber war activities or do research
in these areas it's not a new
development of course it's not it didn't
just happen but do you see that as a
problem in the medium term well i think
okay trust is earned and trust is earned
by
behavior
consistent behavior over a period of
time and
you know
all of these major organizations and i'm
not going to talk about any of them
individually you know they earn trust or
they do not based on how they behave and
um and how they operate and
and i just feel that um
you know transparency and ethical
behavior and um and that demonstrated
over a period of time is what will
determine
whether you're trusted or not um i think
you're so right as a hundred percent so
i started my company we had google and
inc utel as an investor we had teresa
shea on the board who you know you've
probably written about sir alex younger
is on the board so like it's in one
level as american blah blah blah and the
whole sort of thing as you could but at
the same time we work with 30 countries
in at the national level we speak 40
languages at the company and if you sort
of develop a trust and b act in you know
not the sort of classic american sort of
way it's absolutely doable
thanks so much dear panel uh my takeaway
is that the past 20 years have been
rough but the next 20 years are going to
be even rougher but we will remain
cheerful thanks for that and a big shout
out to our panel thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
you