[Music]
hello i've speed up a bit into because
we don't have tools in front of us and
maybe this little sound distortion will
prevent the band from youtube copyright
bots who knows
i'm phil toen dugox on the internet i'm
a team leader of the cryptography
embedded security team at quartz lab and
you may have heard me about me from
various topics mixing hardware and
software
like gribox attacks against whitebox
crypto tier of attacks against eeprom
such as in rfid and nfc tags
attacks on the titan m with some chip
off and micro soldering
i'm also in the nfc in the proxmog
project i organize hardware oriented
ctfs and i'm in the tutorial team of the
poco gtfo if you don't know it yet i
encourage you strongly to have a look at
it later
so what's the glue key wookie
it's a secure usb master edge developed
by the nc
on the left you see a prototype of the
concept on the right a development board
with its components
uh so it's use an encrypted sd card for
the storage and there is a touchscreen
with as you can see a randomized
keyboard layout at each booty change
and there is also
a slot for a smart card java card
where
the keys needed to decrypt the storage
are held
so how to use it you plug it to your pc
usb you insert the authentication token
you type in first pin which is called
the pet pin
if it's correct the rookie will display
its little pet name
and then you can type the real pin to
decrypt the sd card and the master edge
will appear on your machine
the first phase with the pet pen and
pattern it allows you to detect an
attempt of fishing with a fake wookie
for example if the wookie you have in
hand cannot show you the expected pet
nam
beware maybe someone is trying to steal
your user pin and decrypt your stolen
wookie
a bit of context or why i'm talking
about a few hardware hacks on the wookie
with the nc in france which is the
national cyber security agency it
delivers certifications to products
which are called cspn that's french for
first level certificate security
certification
and this certification rely on security
evaluations performed by private labs
they are called system french
information technology security
evolution facility
quartz lab is one of the cst it's a
software ssd by opposition with the
hardware ssd
and and c organized regularly so called
intercessive challenges typically on
open source products
to check how these labs perform
and the last product to be audited was
the woogie
so it's an open source project developed
by the nc itself they designed both the
hardware and the software and they try
to implement best security practice in
all the layers of the products so really
a good defense in-depth approach
we settled quite large evaluation plan
and each cst received a part of it so
each cst looked at different portion of
the product
and novelty for this entire sst the
evaluation items and the skills were
mixed so the software sst had also to
evaluate some hardware aspects
and vice versa
clearly this talk is not much about the
wookie itself this is labeled episode 7
for some reason i'm aware of at least
four previous tools on the wookie so you
can easily find online more details on
the internals and the layers of defense
and with episode 7 i have some imagine
now what i want to show you is how you
can mount hardware attacks yourself
quite easily without expecting expensive
equipments
i've picked
three topics to give you an overview how
to mount timing attack on a java card
or smart card
how to automate a pin brute force by
hijacking a user interface and how to
set up an electromagic fault injection
test bench at home
so let's go for the first example the
idea is to check if a pin validation
doesn't make anything
in its response delay that would give us
information
useful to find the correct pin
here i show you again the cards used in
the rookie but the same principle
applies for example on passwords to
unlock a microcontroller like an ecu
secure session or on a locked gtac port
etc
the id is very simple you send the pin
or the password and you measure how much
time it takes for the card to respond
if the pin is correct the timing will
probably be quite different but that's
fine that's when you know the pin the
problem can occur if you get slightly
different timings between a completely
wrong pin and one
with for example the first digit correct
or the length correct
so for example here
if it's a pin one two three four
you measure the timing for 999 and the
timing for 1999 and maybe the timing of
that one will be slightly longer than
this one
if for example
the card is stupidly checking the digits
one by one
uh maybe it's reverse so it's good to
test also the end and maybe the problem
is on the
length of the pin so when you try to pin
off the correct length you will get a
different result than when the length is
is incorrect
spoiler alert in the source code of the
wookie we see they use the java cart api
in their plat so there is nothing really
suspicious over there but still let's
see how we can
mount such attack
what do you need to mount it a logic
analyzer a cheap one is okay because
smart car is almost like a uart with a
single line mixing eric's antiques and
you can see here the pinout
so you for one io
which represents really what you get as
eric's and takes on a regular reward
and you need of course the ground to
have a reference and you write a little
script to do trace acquisitions and to
send comments on the smart card
you need to choose a target i accept
quite some pin attempts before killing
itself so here we modify the wookie
applet to
[Music]
to be able to test the midi pins without
triggering the contour measures that
exist in the real
applet of the wiki
so how to hook on the smart cartrio
lines
two possibility one is to pick the lines
directly from the reader
if you can open the reader and modify it
here you see i added a small pin header
to a commercial reader and you see that
we've got only two wires
that go to the logic analyzer
the other possibility if you cannot
touch the reader is to add an extension
with a fake card and a fake reader so
here we have a fake card that goes to
the wookie
and here a cable that deports a fake
reader just to be able to put
the real
card here so we have no room somewhere
here to
get
the i o and ground line that we need for
the logic analyzer
then you record a trace when you send
the pin to the card and you see it's
quite straightforward
you have only one channel to monitor
and you see some activity which is the
command that you send and then some
activity which is the response of the
card and the only thing we are
interested in
is the timing between the command and
the response
and that's what we want to watch
um
so you get your measures here for
example we test for the ping length
we set up first a pin
of length four
in this column
and here a pin of length eight in this
column and then we try pins of different
length
with the wrong paint like we tried to
inject 9 then here 99 and here 999 etc
and you see when the correct pin is sent
the timing is very different
now do you see
something else interesting here
beside the correct pin
look at what are the longest timings
in this list
and yeah the longest timings are here
and there
and
when your pin is of length four
that's when you try a pin of length four
when the ping is of length 9
the longest timing is when you try a pin
of line 9 oops
so
you see we got here
timing dependency and we can
find the correct pin length
hopefully we tested it further there is
no dependency on the first online digit
being correct or not so you don't have a
full timing tag against the content of
ping but still you can discover the
correct pin length
via this method
actually it's not a bug in the wookie
applet itself and it's really in the
java card os of the card we tested
which were by the way our own cards as
we were using modified version of the
wizuki applet
and we found that back in gcop3 and
jacob cop 4 cards which are quite highly
certified one is el5 plus the other one
is an els
again no panic
typically the number of pin attempts
should be very muted in most
applications
but still it's an information league
that shouldn't be really there
and it was reported to the vendor
the second example is taking control on
the user interface via the spi boost to
enable some brute force on the pin
but to explain that one i first to
explain the cryptographic unibt in the
wiki protocol because the pin is not
supposed to be brute force as there is a
limit in the number of attempts
you remember i told about the pet pen
and platinum
and here is how the first phase of the
authentication protocol works
so from the pet pin
where is my pencil here from the pet pin
the wiki derives a decay
by some
derivation function
and the decay is sent to the token
then the token it has an encrypted
keyblock called elk internally
and it computes it decrypts the elk with
the decay that you provide
and it gives a kpk
which is sent to the wookie and the kpk
if it's correct
it's used to decrypt the keystore
and from there it can mount a secure
channel with a token
ask for the pet name to the token and
display the pet name to the user
so
where is the vulnerability here
well actually so
you provide the dk to the card and you
get the kpk back from the card
so you can compute yourself the elk
which is stored on the card because you
just need
to
reverse the decryption that we get here
and
you can just re-encrypt the kpk that you
got with the decay and you obtain
back the elk
okay but that means you need the correct
decay which means you need the correct
pet pin so that's not really an issue
right
well actually no you don't need that
even
because
if you
provide a wrong decay
the card will happily compute a wrong
kpk and return it
so you can re-encrypt the wrong kpk with
the wrong decay and you get back the
real elk
again
so you can extract the l key from the
token just like that without knowing any
pet pin
what can you do with that
once you get the l key the idea is to
create a fake card for the rookie where
we could disable the counter measures
present in the real token
i told you the
token limits the number of pins you can
try and
it has even an additional counter
measure where there is an increasing
delay every time you try a wrong pin
this is the type of contour measure for
example you have in some passports as
well
so with that fake token we can root for
the pad pin on the wookie because there
is no limit
anymore on the number of trials it can
do
and once we got the pen pin we can
go back to the original token put it in
the rookie
and unlock the pet name
so we managed to bypass the first layer
or altercation of the rookie by that way
but to bridge for the pin we need some
automation and the keypad gets
randomized at each boot you remember
so the idea is to sniff the spi command
sent to the screen
to reconstruct the keypad layout
we don't need a graphical reconstruction
and we just quickly fingerprint the
sprites with some checksum to know which
keys are displayed
then we inject fake pressures from the
touchscreen
for that we hijack the touchscreen irq
it's a line that tells to the wookie
that there is some input someone is
pressing the touchscreen
and then the wiki tries to sample the
position on touchscreen because it's a
spi boost
so the touchscreen cannot just send data
like that it's to look up to the wiki to
interrogate the touchscreen
so the rookie is alerted via the irq
line and then it samples the touchscreen
to get some positions so that's at that
moment we send fake positions in the
response to the spi commands on the wiki
and finally we need to keep an eye also
on the smart card communication to see
if the rookie tries to mount a secure
channel if it's trying to mount it that
means the pin is correct
so what we need uh the fake token with
the extracted lk
a simple mincon controller here we use a
tnc with some arduino code but anything
else would do it
a logic analyzer it's not really part of
the setup but that's pretty useful to
debug what's going on
and then we need to hook some wires on
the spi bus
so here you see
we got some micro solders
on the spi lines and
the power supply the ground
the chip selects
um and then we need also to hijack the
irq line so we don't want any more the
irq that comes from the real touchscreen
so we cut the line somewhere here
and we hook
somewhere closer to the microcontroller
but
that setup didn't work very well
because
wrong things were typed on the
touchscreen or actually so it received
not the pin that we were intended to
type on the screen
so we had to investigate that a bit
further
and that's where the logic analyzer is
useful by the way so actually there are
a couple of bucks in the rookie
implementation of the touchscreen driver
one thing is a chip select is always
active so the chip select is the cs line
you get
here
and you can see that line is flat and
when it goes to ground that means it's
active so it's active all the time
and one of the consequence is that the
touchscreen
is still active even when the spi is
used more for screen activity because
the screen and the touchscreen
share the symbols
and the effect you see is that there is
some funky stuff going on on the
iaq line of the touchscreen where
nothing should happen over actually over
there but
that's fine
the wiki is still working by chance it
doesn't perturb too much the operations
but that's the first issue
the second problem is uh
is bigger
is that the routine to sample an average
position
goes on even if the finger is released
for the touchscreen so here we have the
iaq line of the touchscreen that tells
if we are
pressing
the screen and we we see it goes low all
the time so that means there is some
pressure and then here the pressure is
released
what you see there is a touchscreen
activity when it gets interrogated and
indeed the issue is that uh
here on the first line these are the
commands sent by the controller and the
response of the touchscreen that gives
the position so the controller is
sampling the position several times to
make some average and
remove some noise
but the problem is that even when the
pressure is released
the
mcu is still sampling a touchscreen but
then the response it gets is zeros so of
course if you make an average of these
positions plus zeros then you get a
wrong position which is shifted too much
to the left
so the solution
to avoid that problem is to take that
into account when we fake the position
um to be sure to respect the same cycle
of the 16 measures
so we we drive the iq exactly for 16
cycles of the sampling command and we
make sure that we reply 16 times with
the exact same position so at the end we
get something which is even more
reliable by hand because that block
appear indeed when you just use the
wookie touchscreen by your hand
sometimes
it types on the wrong pin
when you know that it can erase stuff
when
it detects too too much error so it can
be really a big problem on that device
um
so here you see the boot sequence
and the injection of the pen pin on the
device keyboard
here we type the pen and then it will
display the pet name it takes a
bit of time to appear but it will be
very quick
yeah here pin okay whoopee that's a bit
name
pet name and then it types the user pin
because here this is the demo board so
we have access to both pin and we can
show you
how the final display is at at this
point uh
secure storage is mounted on the pc
so you see all this sequence is still
rather slow it takes about 15 seconds
to boot
up to the validation of the pet pin so
brute forcing that pin
is quite slow
so after testing the setup on the demo
board we try on the closed sample
for which we don't know the pins
and in about
15 hours we managed to break the pet pin
on the closed sample
thanks to the recovered pin we could
discover the pet name by swapping the
card and putting the real authentication
card on the wiki
so the first layer of location of the
key was bypassed which opened
potentially the door for fishing attacks
by presenting a fake cookie to the user
with the correct spin pet name so he
will trust the fake cookie and type the
user pin and if you put for example a
radio
to x filter the pin in real time even if
you realize that he cannot mount his
data
you
can then decrypt
the stolen wiki content
now a few words on electromagnetic
faults
the idea here is to inject an
electromagnetic pulse that will perturb
the mcu inject a fault in electric
execution like skipping execution an
instruction sorry
typically such attack is done in two
phases
first the characterization of the target
processor by using open sample where you
can run some sample code to observe
easily if a foot is injected or not
typically we put a loop counter so we
can inject at any moment and if we see
that the result of the contour is wrong
we know we managed to inject a fault
during that phase we try to find good
parameters like
how much voltage to inject it's about
300 400 volts
with which duration
where to put a little coil on top of the
chip
and then we can try on the real target
here we try it on the loader of the
rookie where it checked the integrity of
the firmware before executing the
firmware
and we simplify a bit the target we make
sure it
to disable the control measures like it
won't erase itself when it detects an
attack
and we bring some led at the end just
rather than running the full firmware
the main constituents are framework
script that will coordinate all the
hardware
where we will have
something to inject
[Music]
high voltage pulses here i use a chip
filter
which is a bit costly but you can
probably do something by yourself
for much cheaper and you just need a
capacitor bank and a mosfet
the advantage here it's quite safe to
use because if you do by yourself or
something that handles 400 volts you've
to be very careful what you're doing
you need something to trigger it with a
configurable delay
uh there is one in the chip shelter but
we wrote our own trigger in a small fpga
that you see here at the bottom it's an
ice 40 if you know it
to get a better precision
in the timing and the punch length
you need some xyz table to move around
the little call on top of the chip
so here my xyz table was just
my 3d printer
but you can do that also on small cnc
for example
it's a bit easier
and you need the script to to talk to
the target and to reset it so we have
some control here made for the target
and you need to be able to reset the
target but because it will probably
crash pretty often when you try to
inject faults
and the script does also some
cartography and automatic automated
acquisition by varying parameters we've
seen before
here is an example of cartography
um you see there the different
parameters that were used and then
we try
to scan all the chip surface
for a given
height
and we can use some colors to to see
quickly what happens
when it's green
it means a
normal behavior nothing bad happened
here in the blue
the the target was not responsive so we
had to reboot it
here in purple it rebooted itself
so that means also the all
cases that you have to handle in your
script
and the more interesting parts are here
in yellow and
in orange is when only a few number of
instructions were skipped so in the
yellow you see the number that means
there is only only one instruction skip
here two instructions keep here
and with this characterography you can
see for example that maybe that area is
pretty interesting because we don't have
much crash but we have
small
instruction skips so we can try the
second phase only on this area for
example
so after the causalization to find a
good spot and good voltage parameter we
move to the target here the loader of
the wiki that checked the integrity of
the firmware before launching it
and here are some results we got on the
loader we got the first integrity bypass
after
about 5 000 attempts
and after some fine tuning we got a
success rate of about once every 14
attempts
maybe it's possible to get better but it
needs time to explore all the parameters
of an impulse injection
but remember on the real wookie there is
a really defensive depth
as as soon as the loader fails to check
the integrity of the firmware it erase
everything
so
still hard
to really
get a
full
execution but attack parts on the wookie
so here it was uh just to test and see
the feasibility of the foot injection
[Music]
where we disable these contour measures
uh by the way we got also some other
funny and less funny results for the
funny one we got portions of the
firmware leaking on the debug uart that
was not foreseen but
it happened and that's really with fault
injection like anything can help happen
really
hopefully the uart is disabled in
production it's only on debug mode
but maybe you can do something similar
on the usb descriptors for example
for the less funny part we also try to
defeat the stm32ldp2
protection
um that's a protection physical
protection that
forbids you to to dump the content of
the firmware over gtac and when we try
to defeat it we break the dim report
after a while
so this is a gentle reminder
i wanted to share with you that when i
say anything can happen it means
including destroying the target so
always be very careful when playing with
a fault injection
i hope you enjoy these stories
here are my conclusions hardware attacks
are fun to do they are much more
affordable
than some may think
no need for big lab to start poking
around
you've seen it with these stories never
assume that you have in front of you is
robust and try by yourself we've seen
here issues on that thing certified java
cards we've seen crypto protocols weaker
than foreseen
so it's always worth to challenge the
things you see even if it fails at least
you can learn something in the process
and finally if you got a test for the
topic i warmly welcome you to have a
look at two books published very
recently like
and one or two months ago
the first one is a nice introduction to
the topic and the second one gives
it goes deeper in fault injection and
side channel
but
still always install
hacking at home without big equipment
thank you and
i'm hearing your questions
okay thank you phil i think we got a
number of uh questions uh
do you want to start first yeah sure
thank you very much for for the
presentation um just a quick question
about the methodology did you try to use
power glitch in order to to have a
better reproducibility because em is a
bit it's a bit difficult to get uh i
will predictability rate
uh you can hear me i hope
yes perfect
uh poor you mean voltage glitch
it was not part of our plan as explained
we had a huge plan to attack the rookie
and each cesti did
part of it and got the part attributed
and in our part uh it was uh only em
but
if i remember well last year scenic
presented this result on the voltage
switch on the wiki
okay thank you
[Applause]
okay thank you thank you phil
i think you had a question on
on the live about the pts update and
when was it being done before
verification
or not uh would you mind repeating your
answer uh for the rest of the audience
who were not following that exchange
please yeah so there was a question if
the the pin counter check uh
is updated correctly uh before doing the
variation otherwise you could like uh
try to verify the pin and and tear off
the card very quickly before it updates
the the counter check uh again this was
not something that was our own plan and
we had already quite a large plan to do
in the
cspn days that are forcing so that's not
something you we looked at not that we
didn't want but yeah we have to limit
ourselves to
already quite a number of things
but i hope i assume that this correct
this one i mean the the bug we found is
maybe because it was something which was
not really on the checklist
uh for the certification labs when they
attribute an es6 plus but i hope that on
the
six plus checklist at least uh the the
check for tier of attacks
um
we've got uh uh last question from
pascal
yeah thanks for the talk and my question
is how many hours does it take to
solving this challenge
here it's it was three items of our plan
the plan was much longer and it was
filling a full cspn which is 25 days
plus 10 days when you have some crypto
in it so 35 days
uh
but yeah that's a regular cspn including
reporting including looking at aspects
which are not just finding the
vulnerabilities
so
just for these items um
well the first one the the
the timing attack that's something you
can do in a day or in an afternoon it's
very quick
uh
the one with the the instrumentation you
you saw we had some difficulties to work
around the box or finding what were the
issues with the wookie so
that one took probably like four days
to set up
um and the last one the
the test bench
uh
actually we didn't have yet a test bench
when we started so most of time was
about setting up the things setting up
and writing script and writing character
graphics script then running the attack
it's about i don't know one day to set
up the stuff and then a couple of days
to run the tests
okay thank you very much
[Applause]