but we're gonna talk about revealing the
machine and what that really comes down
to it's a study of the rich header and
we're gonna talk really and focus on the
respective triage that you can do with
it it was quite cool so yeah I'm George
we're both PhD candidates at the
Technical University of Munich I
specialize in large-scale distributed
systems and trying to figure out how to
do
Maur analysis at a very large scale
realistically I focused more on dynamic
and static analysis and all that fun
stuff this is Julian he's pretty much
your reverse engineering exploit
development kind of extraordinaire
he also dibbles and dowels with virtual
machine introspection somebody started
talking and getting into the weeds I'm
just gonna hand it over to him and he'll
entertain you guys so what we really
want to talk about first is why are we
actually here like why do we actually
really care so to do that we're gonna
explain the problem now the problem is
data I mean I'm sure all of you as
security engineers have faced this
problem there's data upon data upon data
so if we quickly look at this we see
from virustotal
we're seeing about 1 million samples a
day that they actually have to process
and that's a lot of data however that's
kind of only part of the picture it's a
little bit of a false hope because if
you look from a historical context and
say you go back you know 300 days that's
300 million samples that you have to
analyze and process and look into so
that's a lot of data again however
that's also another false positive
because this stuff that's already
suspected to be malicious what about the
benign stuff what about the stuff we
have no idea
so if you're for a large organization
you're kind of dealing with stuff you're
dealing with a tremendous amount of
stuff that pretty much kills most of our
scripts most of our fun stuff we're
working with and so the question really
comes is when you see a sample and we
start to dig into this like how do you
triage it how do you figure out what's
important how do you find out what's
interesting how do you think stuff
that's related and really it comes down
to how do you make sense out of all this
data so at the university we developed
kind of our malware that really helps us
with our research and figuring stuff out
and we're working on one aspect of the
PE 32 file and we can
across this weird interesting that as we
started to look at it we saw that the
documentation was really non-existent
microsoft says it doesn't exist so
that's not cool we found a couple blog
posts from reverse engineering stuff and
that was interesting but again it wasn't
really right great because they
contradicted each other and there was
errors in it and we looked in the
security community or like well have you
guys ever looked at it and the answer
was no we couldn't find one record so
what is this field this field is called
the rich header from a you know it's
pretty much overlooked it's a poorly
understood aspect but it has three
really awesome things in it the first is
a product ID the product ID is a unique
identifier and it usually goes to you
know a major on a major object or a
major corporation or it goes to a
generic library and that's pretty
informative for us the next is it has
version information so I know exactly
specifically what version was used in
that it also has the compiler flags
built into it too for when that object
was created I got the version I got the
compiler flags and the third aspect it
has how many times the linker used that
object in order to build and package
everything together so that gives us an
idea and the idea is can we actually use
it because that's some really cool
interesting information to kind of put
something together and do some stuff
with triage so in order to talk about
that further we got to get into the
weeds and I'm gonna hand it over to
Julian because he's a reverse
engineering guy and he's going to start
explain it to you so Julian alright
thank you
so before we start talking about the
rich header
I would like to sync us up to get to
kind of the same level of knowledge so I
would briefly like to explain the PE
three-to-five format and also how the
typical Microsoft compiler toolchain
looks like so this is what probably
everybody in this room has seen at least
once in his life so this is a
conventional PE file starting with the
DOS header that dates back to the early
16-bit era era that nowadays does not
much useful information anymore and it's
just the header for a program that
informs the user in case he should run
this binary under dos that hey this is
not a binary that is ms-dos compatible
anymore the only interesting field in
this das header nevertheless is the e
head of a new field which is a direct
reference to the beginning of the coffe
header which then in turn contains all
the information that modern 32 and 64
Windows operating systems usually read
and the interesting part we're going to
talk about is now the rich header right
in between the doors and the COFF header
that is not officially documented and
Microsoft even denied its existence
several times now this is the microsoft
visual studio compiler tool chain I want
to briefly go over it such that we see
what's going on here so on the left hand
side of the slide you see visual studio
with this famous green arrow start
clicking button so if you click this
button to compile your code and run it
in visual studio then what what actually
happens under the hood is that visual
studio calls a command line interpreter
called CL dot exa which according to
what you fed the compiler with either C
or C++ files invokes the correct
Microsoft compiler front-end c1 dl l or
c 1 x x d ll which then in turn create
intermediate files which are then
collected by the microsoft back-end
compiler c 2 dl which in turn then turns
them into object files that you could
link together so the last step of
computation is well nothing fancy here
CL invokes the linker the linker puts
together the object files and either
produce a portable executable toward
exit or a dynamic link library what is
interesting to note here is that link X
actually is a multi-purpose tool so if
any of you ever touched stamp bin which
is well the Linux Windows equivalent to
object dump or also edit bin or lip X
which are a binary itted editor and the
library manager for Microsoft files
then what actually happens under the
hood there is that they are just tiny
rappers are on linked Alexa so leaf dot
XE actually is this or deny army knife
at that point now let me know this we
can talk privately about the rich header
and we will actually be pretending to be
a parser which is trying to get useful
information from that rich header and we
will see what it contains and watch
these blocks that we named comp IDs are
how it is created and also how we could
extract all those information so as
already mentioned the rich header is an
obfuscated undocumented part of the PG
header and one already very interesting
part about a rich header is that it has
been there for quite a long time so we
know that it has been there since at
least which was to year six which dates
back to 1998 and was then well what
could say almost forgotten until the mid
or late 2000s where several blog posts
appeared with information most notably
by Daniel pastelly who provided valuable
insights into the meaning of the rich
header but they left the interpretation
of the data you could find in their
totally open
so suppose we would like to find the
information that the rich Eyler includes
then remember that picture here if you
turn this schematic overview into a hex
dump then we have something like this so
at the beginning marked in blue is the
classical dose header that as you can
see is almost everywhere there zero
because it doesn't make sense to include
any information in there anymore 16-bit
arial era is long over except for that
field at offset three C but I marked
purple which is simply the forward
reference to the PE error which you can
see down slide in orange and right in
between those two marked in green there
is the switch header and one interesting
part to note about this is already that
we don't have a pointer to the beginning
of the rich header but rather a pointer
to the end of the day
you're interested in so while parsing
this we're actually going in reverse
direction so what we can see there at
the bottom of the hetero structure is in
orange just some padding then we find a
well magic value that will later turn
out to be a checksum starting this one 3
3 7 and by the way this is not a header
I made up I directly obtained this file
from Microsoft it's actually the linker
of the Visual Studio 2013 edition so
very leet here and we also find a
hard-coded string in marked in red rich
which indicates that this is indeed a
rich header we're about to deal with now
if you look at this data then you will
see that its contents above the colors
parts are quite entangled or obfuscated
you could say and well some of you might
already have guessed it if I take the
magic value that I have in purple and
use it to soar over the rest of the
header then the value start to make
sense again at the top you can see even
more padding in orange and an automatic
string magically appears
reading Dan s and now the payload that
the rich header actually contains is the
blue part here where we can see what we
named comp ID blocks one comp ID block
consists of 64 bits and we see here 10
comp ID blocks so let's try to interpret
them we have 8 bytes per comp ID block
and what they contain is usually the
following so the first 16 bits are the
miner compiler version that the compiler
which created the object had the next 16
bits are the product ID which identify
not only the compiler version but also
what the object that we're dealing with
was before compilation which is quite
interesting and then there is a 32-bit
count field which indicates how many
symbols within that object are
referenced by the binary we are about to
compile so this is quite abstract if you
take some concrete examples for that
prot ID then looking at this table for
instance the current with Visual Studio
release 2015
you just compiled together a binary and
look at what values you find in a rich
header then they are typically currently
around 256 so hex 105 is currently in
the indicator that for that we are
dealing with an object that was a C++
source file before compilation and had
me spit out by c2 DLL and one thing you
could now do of course is asking hey hmm
so we're currently the 105 what if we go
back in time so this is Studio 2010 for
instance I gave some exemplary values
here has b4 for C++ files and if we go
back even further for instance to visual
studio.net so that's inefficiently
version 71 then you find values in the
range of 5 e for instance and the oldest
one we were able to reproduce this
actually hex 15 for visual studio
release 6 so that was the one back to
1998 some of you might remember relating
to AC file so and if you look at this
then you could try to build up a
database and that's exactly what we
tried to do but the ranges we obtained
still have holes in them so this is
actually a call for participation if any
of you has some old visual studio
releases lying around or even newer ones
we would be very very interested to look
at those files we named there and look
what values they are able to produce for
the rich header so this is one part
about it
the second part about it is that we
sometimes also observe values that are
completely out of that range outside so
we have no real explanation on that it
might be because somebody tried to forge
the values in there but it's interesting
to note that there seems to be a certain
correlation to major companies that
Microsoft partners with so there is a
special prodigy for Adobe products for
instance but everything beyond what we
could say is just speculation ok now we
know what the header includes do you
still remember the ones for c7 checksum
let's look at this limit so in order to
explain how the checksum
I brought a tiny Python snippet here and
I will go through it one by one such
that we get a understanding of what is
going on here
so the first three lines are basically
just a library function you could say
it's doing a bitwise rotate left
operation on four bytes 32 bits so don't
get the math behind it's just believe
that's wrong 32 and then there's the
actual checksum calculation function
which gets three arguments that is the
raw data of the PE file the net
information of the comp IDs we just
discussed and also that is very
important the offset of the beginning of
the Reg header which well some parts are
tend to hard-code but actually is not a
constant value so if you look at the
first loop for instance then one thing
that is interesting to note already is
that the checksum calculation includes
the values within the doors error right
it simply takes the values that you can
find the daus header rotates them by the
offset you could found the value add and
then sums them up that's what the code
is doing and what is also another
pitfall at this point is because the
checksumming function resides in the
linker it doesn't know the value of the
e.l.f a new field remember that was the
little iron arrow I showed you in the
beginning so the arrow pointing to the
COFF header and because the linker
doesn't know yet how big the coffee rich
header will be it simply fills in dummy
values at this part and skips that in
the calculation of the checksum so this
is another pitfall that many parcels to
wrong and well after check something in
the header and we find that it actually
checks Sam's the contents of the rich
header which is just well putting
together the product ID the miner
compiler version and then rotates the
combination of those two values by the
number of times the product had been
used well the result is truncated to
32-bit and then used as the magic once
we see seven value from the beginning of
yeah now if we look at this and step
back and think about it a second then we
might find that this is actually a very
poor choice for check sum function why
is the so well
the point is that rotating a four byte
string by something that is bigger than
32 bits or 32 is Viktor effectively a
knob so rotating by 32 bits 32 bits is
like rotating nothing right
so all account values above 32 that's a
5 bit value are actually completely
congruent to anything below 32 so at
this part you can see that out of the 32
bits that are there in the count field
only the lowest 5 are actually checked
leaving 27 open so if you to do the math
27 plus the other 32 bits then we see
that only 37 out of 64 bits per Kampai
d-struct are checked by the checksum
function which is kind of strange if
there should be a checksum alright so we
now spoke a little bit about the
contents of the Reg header I try to
explain you how the checksum is built up
the last question I would like to answer
is who actually built up the rich header
and this is also no black magic here the
Microsoft back-end compiler puts a comp
a decomp ID per object during
compilation and linked out XE collects
them together such that all objects that
are contained in one executable well are
then put into the Reg header one
exception is there though these are
statically linked libraries dot Lib if
these can contain multiple objects they
also contain multiple comp IDs but in
practice that doesn't make much of a
difference because link exhibit just
well sort them out and add them to the
header all right and that was a
technical dive through rich header and
now I hand it back to George with
statistics all right so we kind of
understand what the rich header does but
that doesn't really help us for triage
so what does this mean how do we start
to put it together and how do we start
to take advantage of it and that's what
I'm going to kind of go into right now
so the first thing is I'm gonna talk a
little bit about statistics so the rich
header is very specific to Microsoft and
we know that by pretty much malicious
file
they love to try to off you skate
themselves and hide themselves so how
prevalent is this gonna be because that
that is valuable so if they know about
it they should hide it so we took about
a million samples and we ran it through
the parsers and we find that it's
actually quite prevalent 71 percent of
all of our samples actually did contain
a rich header this was much higher than
our assumption was initially so that was
pretty fantastic way more prevalent than
we thought our next assumption was well
you know some of your more sophisticated
actors they probably at least strip it
out so we looked at apt one we had a
couple thousand samples actually it's
two hundred and ninety eight samples for
apt one we said how often do they strip
it out how much do they have and it's
98% of all apt one samples that we have
actually contain the rich header so
that's pretty cool we know sophisticated
actors aren't dealing with it so we said
what about you know some more criminal
stuff some common criminal stuff so we
looked at Zeus Citadel we saw from
bridge header it's 37 percent still a
decent number especially for triage but
we're starting to see that something's
different something's weird
but everything's not glorious in this
case because we have 71% for random
which is fantastic 98 for apt 1 which is
fantastic but we got 37 for Zeus this
brings us to the next point is that when
we look at the Medi z' malware sample
set we only had 2% had the rich header
when I go in a little bit of the reasons
why but 71% is pretty fantastic but this
means that rich header is not a sure
shot and I did want to caveat with that
that while it is good it's gonna help
you a lot with triage and we're gonna do
some cool stuff with it you got to be
really careful when you use it because
not everything is going to contain it
the reason it doesn't contain it really
comes down to the Microsoft linker since
the Microsoft linkers built it there's
really no documentation for it there's
no real expectation that other people
are going to do it
so one malware doesn't have the rich
header you pretty much have a good
assumption right now that it's using
those basically built by dotnet Mini GW
GCC or also a packer like D of that
pretty much is going to be stripping out
the rip cutter because it's not going to
include it in the first place however if
we look at what
includes the red cheddar we see we got
visual Studios you know what's
interesting to some partners such as
Intel's compiler actually does include
the rich header as well we don't know if
that includes the linker in it or if
they just actually built it because
their partners no idea but the three
things that are really cool here is
Packers like upx
ass pack and also no soft they actually
do and keep the rich header in there but
they kind of distorted ever so slightly
which really becomes quite fantastic so
so what and once you have this
information we know it's pretty
prevalent it's got some interesting
stuff let's actually see what we can do
with it and how it can really help with
the triage so the first is that the rich
header is really really quite valuable
in the sense that it's it's informative
you can start to figure out how the
binary is actually built and it's got
tons of fun stuff we're gonna ignore
that standpoint from now for the reverse
engineering side but we're only going to
talk about the triage so the first part
is discrepancies are absolutely
fantastic when we actually look at it if
the checksum is corrupt that's pretty
much a guarantee right now that the
binary was post modified because people
don't forget it like they just forget
about the rich header so they're not
trying to fix that checks up so if you
see the checksum corrupt pretty much a
guarantee the binaries post modified the
second part is duplicate entries those
three Packers I talked all of them do
this when they actually packed the
binaries pretty together you see a
Product ID you see a version information
and you see a count and you actually see
duplicate entries in there there's no
reason the Microsoft linker is gonna put
duplicate entries in there so it's
almost a guarantee that that binary was
now packed and the next aspect is to
check this rich setter to start parsing
it and looking at together it's
incredibly fast it's really inefficient
it's really cheap it makes life pretty
fun for us but can we do more there's a
lot of information in there and that's
what we're gonna start talking about now
so when he looked at it we wanted to see
if we could do some machine learning
some deep learning fun stuff and
actually create an algorithm that was
incredibly fast see if we can do it in
near real-time we wanted to do
similarity matching upon millions and
millions of binaries because we deal
with millions of
on a daily basis we also have
interesting stuff with the version
information and we wanted to see if that
could fingerprint the actors and when I
say actors I'm really talking about
build environments there is a
discrepancy it's not a direct
correlation but there is some
correlation there I can tell you what
machine that Mauer was built on so could
we actually do it the answer is yes and
we're gonna go into how we did it now
the first thing is the rich header data
is incredibly sparse from a machine
learning perspective that's not really
great so we needed to fix that and what
we did we used a deep learning technique
call it a stacked auto and coder and I'm
not gonna get into the math but we'll
look at Mario if right now so all it
really does is take this really cool
picture of Mario and it puts it to a
denser lower dimensional space and
that's the two-dimensional picture of
Mario and that's really all we need to
know what benefits us is it gives us a
little bit cleaner results and it's
incredibly memory efficient so instead
of dealing with millions upon millions
of samples meaning gigs and gigs of RAM
all sudden out need a server I can
actually do this on our algorithm and
when I do actually show the
demonstration this was all recorded with
an out just a silly laptop so the next
part is once I have it now in a
dimensional space I can really start to
work with and start to take care of it
we wanted to do actually two similarity
match an aspect of it and we chose KNN
let me chose ball tray and to talk about
the kan km it's a great algorithm for
similarity matching it doesn't really
require much pre-processing it's pretty
easy to work with but the really key
aspect here is I don't need to predefine
my but my buckets my grooves some of the
other app matching algorithms out there
you have to say okay I had a hundred
buckets I got 200 buckets well I have no
idea how many buckets I have a couple
million malware samples KNM is gonna
figure it out for me and that's really
what I want the next is it with the ball
trees allows really really rapid lookups
so these numbers were all recorded on a
laptop and we got six point seven three
milliseconds so that's pretty good so on
my silly laptop it's about three years
old Mac it's not really great I can
throw in a hash in there spit out
results in about six point seven three
milliseconds for all the similar malware
I have
what's also in this vowel tree we did a
static poultry but ball trees great to
work with it's pretty nice you could
actually turn this into real up like a
real-time system where you actually are
doing it on the fly as well so to
actually show you what the training
thing is we have a quick little
demonstration so you guys know this is
going to be fully trained across a
couple of million samples so the first
is I'm going to take it and what's
really going on here is I'm loading
tensorflow all this happening wonderful
thing tend to flow is loading up and
it's a little bit slow lit so here's
where the magic happens what's going on
is it's taking all that data and it's
going to start constructing into a lower
dimensional space and this is real-time
training
I'm not speeding it up this is accurate
on average it's about six seconds or so
so I'm training all of my information
putting into this space I want and kind
of getting my ball tree in order so
there it's done it's now too much a
lower dimensional space I can actually
start working with it I'm pretty happy
and it's creating my ball tray so I
think that was about a million samples
might have been about 2 million
everything's already trained so the next
is we want to do a lookup so what I say
it's really fast so I pretty much have
everything ready to go
it's got my saw pretty much press play
and there we go I got my JSON output of
all my similar samples and it makes no
difference at this I'm telling it to
spit out ten samples to--and spit out a
hundred samples telling it to spit out
200 samples it's pretty much about the
same amount of time which is pretty
fantastic in my opinion but we're
dealing with JSON and JSON is great but
I don't know about you guys I need
pretty pictures so from the printers
perspective we look at what that JSON is
doing is I'm not really clustering
because it's technically not a
clustering but I'm putting them in
little buckets here so we have nearest
neighbor one and we go all the way to
nearest neighbor town on this we have
much more and within those buckets we
have correlations of different samples
from the distance metric we can see that
all these samples in these different
buckets are all actually really quite
similar and we're going to start to dive
into that and go into
couple different case studies to explain
what's actually in there and why this
gets really really cool so the first
case study we want to look at is apt one
so we took a random sha and we said
let's run this through the algorithm and
see what I have what was interesting in
all these results all the AV signatures
were different they're all for the most
part generic but they're all different
generic signatures so the first one is
we saw a direct correlation between
another sample set that we had and this
is only about 200 and I think was 290
samples were looking at just in this
group we found another sample the rich
header was identical what this means
when we started to reverse engineer and
and look at it we found that the code
actually was identical like identical
code base of course that means we have
identical functionality the difference
in the SHA was actually just because of
a compiler artifact so then we neck
looked at our next bucket and we see
three now those samples and the first is
we're looking at basically a different
version of apt one so the version
information slightly off is a slightly
different build environment we also see
an introduction of a new function called
flush file buffers what's happening is a
pt.1 kind of had a little bit of bug not
really bug is kind of a bad performance
technique they're using where they're
taking their information in there but
buffer and they're writing it to disk
when they wrote it to disk they then
open that file again added their escape
characters and then did another riot so
while the introduction of this flush
file buffers what it's really doing is
it takes this information while it's
still in the its buffer it adds the
string cat function finishes everything
and then writes it to DES so instead of
two writes we got one which is kind of
nice now I know that we have yeah
everything was pretty much what we
expected with a similarity matching
algorithm we did actually have matches
for apt one so then we looked at Zeus we
took another random sample threw it in
our system and he said ok let's see what
it can do the first is we had another
identical matching 23 samples that were
identical rich header we started to
reverse-engineer it I'm taking these all
apart to see why is it like
what's the difference of this why do
they have different hashes and pretty
much all the difference was was you see
an optimization between a do-while and a
for loop and we also see that code
segments were reorganised so all
practical purposes that's the exact same
version of Zeus same our variant it's
all the same we looked at the next
bucket then and we detected four samples
this is pretty much a different version
which is exactly what we're expecting
here is we're seeing an XOR algorithm
kind of an improvement of Zeus where
we're seeing the X logarithms looped 8
times more but this is where it gets
kind of fun because we then put back our
1 million sample set we said how is this
across a larger scale what can we
actually see so in this we threw another
sample Zeus and we detected 36,000 606
samples we've started to
reverse-engineer it we automated this
process with IDA probe because no one's
gonna reverse 36,000 samples if they are
they need friends but we're seeing that
there's pretty much identical
functionality going on here the only
difference that we could observe across
these samples was different you know a
constant values changing slightly now
work gets really fun is we threw all
these samples into virustotal and 16,000
123 of these samples had no virus total
signature whatsoever across any of them
so virustotal is saying these are
completely benign are similarly matching
algorithm saying hey it's not benign
it's got pretty much a direct one-to-one
correlation to the sample you initially
threw in of the ones that were detected
they're usually generic they were
mislabeled something was off about the
signature so that's pretty cool I'm
pretty happy the next is we went through
our next bucket and we saw that we had
1567 samples so that's pretty cool but
something was slightly off so we looked
into why was the rich header off and the
answer here was actually a different
build environment so all the samples
were identical in the sense of
functionality we just had to slip
slightly different variations in the
version information which tells us that
machine was either upgraded they have
created their libraries it was built on
a different machine or someone in
entirely actually built it furthermore
511 of these samples again had no
signature detection whatsoever in
virustotal
so that's pretty cool so we looked at
the validation and whenever you try to
validate anything on millions of samples
it becomes a huge challenge especially
when there's really nothing else to
compare and contrast good to so we
looked at this and we said alright let's
correlate Ida ko Ida Pro generated code
and so we ran that through it automated
across a million samples and we wanted
to get the entropy of the source code
and the differentials along with their
entropy of the source code and the
differentials for the rich header well
we see it's a pretty heat map which is
why I selected this one for the
validation but we see a tight little
cluster in the bottom left that's
exactly what we want to see from a
machine learning perspective to say hey
it actually is doing similarity matching
there is a direct correlation if this
was bad you'd see dots all over the
place and I hate when I see dots all
over the place this is good so in
conclusion if you want to kind of wrap
this up a little bit and explain stuff
and then we love questions so please ask
us questions on it we have tons of stuff
we would like to talk about but yeah
conclusion time the first we really
wanted to emphasize here is the rich
header is really valuable for triage and
it's really important to look at this
from a future work perspective and work
really needs to me be hat on this the
first is a product ID like what are
these true mappings I mean I can tell
you right now from a the Builder and the
compiler ation standpoint of how these
are created but we see tons of stuff
that are unique they seem to be really
really constant what is that mapping
thing there's no way I can tell you
because I'm not Microsoft but it does
allow my similarity matching algorithm
to work so I'm happy but I really want
to know what that is
the next is a checksum microsoft's not
dumb why is it so poor i think that
would be really nice to figure out what
was the reason was it just done in 98
and they just forgot about it possibly I
don't know
and the purpose Microsoft has been very
very secretive about this every time
we've talked to him even through him
from our friends at Microsoft they'll
get excited and talking to us and then
immediately it's just radio silent
and we don't hear from for like two
months which is kind of interesting so
why are they so psych secretive like
what is the original purpose are they
doing something fun with it or is it
just basically they're saying hey we're
using this basically to triage your bug
fixes and putting it to our partners
it's probably my assessment I have no
idea I'd love to know the nests aspect
is really from our similarity matching
perspective we focused from an academic
perspective on what is a similarity
matching just for the rich header we
only included that if you actually want
to use this in practice you should
include other features as well you
probably are going to get something
that's pretty nice so we also every
single thing that we found on the rich
header was there's discrepancies in
there things were messed stuff wasn't
really that good so what we decided to
do was go ahead and give you guys our
extractor we licensed it under Apache -
we created a docker service for it and
it's ready to use in our home system and
homes if you're familiar with crits or
Viper it's basically something that
we've developed similar vein but we use
it for millions upon millions of samples
distributed large-scale stuff so you can
access it from homes processing github
do and I'll put that out probably
sometime this weekend depending how good
my internet connection is so the
takeaways for this talk and what I
really want to leave you guys with is
the rich header isn't really really
valuable for triage it allows you to do
quick detection I can identify it packed
and post modified binaries pretty much
like instant real time and it's really
cheap the nexus allows me to do
similarity matching so if you give me
one sample I can look across everything
from a historic perspective and
near-real-time and it's very efficient I
can use my laptop to do it and the third
is the build environment fingerprinting
and this is pretty interesting aspect
I'm not going to say it's going to tell
you where like who the different actors
are but it's giving you a data point
that allows you to start putting out
analysis together and start figuring
that out
additionally we like happy Julien and to
get happy Julien if you guys have C to
DLL CVTs link THC or Emily accedes
please send them to Julian so we can
start to map everything out because
everyone wants a happy
and the next is this was quite an
endeavor to kind of put everything
together so we wanted to give some
shafts out to say thank you to the guys
that assisted and I'm George Webster and
this is Julian Kirsch and we're at the
Technical University of Munich if you
guys have any questions I think we have
to go to the speaker area we'd love to
talk to you more about it thank you