can you hear me okay
thank you for the introduction so this
is me while I do Cliff jump and I am a
security researcher at schilder with a
wonderful team
and I also I am also part of a NGO
called the observatorius.org
and you can find me on Twitter at the
end of the zero
and this is the agenda for today we will
start with an introduction on the
blockchain and on Smart contracts then
the second part will be uh the web free
perspective from a web through developer
going into uh web free
then we will switch our point of view to
security researchers from web 2 going
into web free then one we have some
basic concept we will do some root cause
analysis of the sum of the best
vulnerabilities in the web free world
and at the end we will do some closing
remarks about the concept that we
learned
so some disclaimers this will not be a
buzzword talk I will not try to sell you
Fielder coin in an Ico
and instead the objective of the talk
are to understand the concept behind web
free and these smart contracts and to
learn new offensive and defensive
concept both from uh for security
Searchers and Developers
and please don't use the code that you
will see in the slides in production
because it's not safe it's not reviewed
and you shouldn't do it
so let's start our journey with a brief
introduction uh in this new word
and nowadays everybody knows what the
blockchain is and raise your hand if you
ever heard the word blockchain or smart
contract or something like that
okay I see quite a few ends and
basically the blockchain is a public
distributed immutable database and what
does this mean
uh it is database so it is a place where
we can store different type of data and
it depends on the type of blockchain and
it is immutable because once some data
is added to the blockchain it cannot be
altered or modified and it's there
essentially forever
and it is public and distributed because
every node and every party peer of the
network gets a copy of the data and this
data is public so everyone that gets a
copy can look into it and have access to
this data
and the blockchain started to evolve and
at some point uh ethereum came up with
the concept of smart contract and smart
contracts are like digital contracts
between parties without a third party
that rules over the contract so we don't
have a public notary
like we have in Italy
and a smart contract is a collection of
code so the function of the contract and
the data so the state of the contract
that reside at a specific address on the
blockchain and it is the code that
enforce the rules of the contracts
programmatically
and like everything else on the
blockchain a smart contract can hold and
send money so it can transfer money it
cannot be deleted
and it cannot be altered once the
contract is deployed that's it and the
interaction of a contract and to a
contract are irreversible
this is an example of a small contract
and it is uh developed in the solidity
programming language and at the first
line we have the Declaration of the
solidity version and the compiler
version that we will be using to compile
this code
outline free we have the definition of
the contract in this case the contract
is called greeter
at line four we have a variable inside
the contract called grid of type string
then we have a Constructor and this
Constructor is only executed once per
contract so this contract will this
contract Constructor will be executed
once when the contract is deployed and
then we have atline 10 a function that
is called greetings and this function
accept a string it's public and returns
a string
and how can we go from the source code
that we just seen to the blockchain and
basically we start uh the flow with the
source code we fed it to the Soul C
compiler the solidity compiler and the
compiler gives us output three main
parts so the bytecode
on the left of the contract
you
and then we have the runtime at the
center that is a special type of byte
code that is executed only once and it's
used to deploy the contract on the
blockchain and in the runtime we
actually have uh the Constructor
and then we have the Json API that is an
abstract binary interface in inside the
Json structure that is used for contract
to contract interaction and you can
think of that like uh zwagger or vusdl
file or a symbolic file for if you are
like into reversing and binary
and
I talked about bytecode because the
bytecode of the smart contract is
executed inside a virtual machine
specifically for the ethereum
cryptocurrency inside the evm
and this virtual machine allow us to
build a distributed computing
infrastructure and the state of the
execution is stored on the ethereum
blockchain so we are executing stuff
in a distributed way and the state is on
the blockchain and this virtual machine
has a risk instruction set and we will
talk about it later
so once a participant of the network
wants to do and interact with a smart
contract basically a broadcast they
broadcast an execution request to the
network and the execution causes a state
change that is committed inside a
transaction and propagated to all the
peers of the network and these results
in distributed execution
let's see in depth our uh this works
this is Bob and Bob wants to interact
with a smart contract so broadcast his
uh execution request let's say and to
the uh to the network and then every uh
node of the network get uh the execution
request executed verify that that the
execution is uh correct and then update
uh the local blockchain after a minor uh
validate the transaction
so how can we prevent the flooding of
the network with execution requests
because every peer can request
executions and the ethereum developers
came up with the concept of gas that is
uh to waive the computational effort and
the state change that an execution will
make and so make the user pay for it
accordingly
so these Concepts make the evm a quasi
through incomplete machine and we don't
have altering problem here because once
the gas
is done you need to send a certain
amount of amount of gas and when the gas
is done the execution is stopped and
smart contracts need to be deterministic
because everybody in the networks need
to have the same results and this is
important
so let's start our journey uh looking at
web free with a webview developer point
of view and for the develop developers
in the audience let's assume that your
boss works in your office and asks to
you hey we need to make a web free
version of our product and so the first
concept that you will encounter is that
as I said the public execution and the
public state of the execution uh is
distributed and everybody can see the
smart contract bytecode and the smart
contract state so everybody can see the
values of the variables that you are
using during the execution of your
contract so smart contract should be
treated as client code like the
JavaScript that runs on your browser or
the mobile application on your phone
and since you wouldn't check an admin
password inside the browser you wouldn't
do it inside smart contract and if
you're doing it consider upgrading and
changing and fixing this bug but then
you come up with the second big concept
that is that you cannot really update
your implementation one is once it's
live on the blockchain
and your contact will be available
forever
until you call the self-destruct
instruction inside it
and the self-destructure instruction is
a special instruction in the virtual
machine that tells everybody that this
contact cannot be used and you cannot
interact with it anymore but the state
of the contract and its bytecode will
still be in the blockchain because it
was deployed in a previous transaction
so how can you prevent pushing
vulnerable code on the blockchain
forever by testing before deploy here is
really important and you should avoid
fast prototyping so going live as soon
as possible and there are a lot of
development tools that can help
developers uh with these and you can
also use testnet blockchain or offline
blockchain for it
and a mechanism like updates can be done
with proxy contract and this is Bob
again that wants to interact with your
contract and instead instead of making
Bob interact with the smart contract
direct directly we installed build a
proxy contract in the middle and then
the real implementation contract behind
it so you as a as the owner and the
developer of the contracts at some point
can change
the linking of the proxy contract
tooling to a different contract and all
the proxy contract is doing is taking
the input from the users and forwarding
it to a Smart contract and you ask
why these don't violate the immutability
property that we saw and this is the
code that is used to implement it
we have a proxy contract and inside the
Constructor uh we set the contract set
its owner as the user that's deployed it
and set the default implementation with
an address of a different contract so
inside the implementation variable you
have the address of the contract that
will be uh linked and when you want to
upgrade the contract
you can call the upgrade function
passing an address as the Imp variable
and it will change the implementation
address and from now on all the input
from the user will be forwarded to a
different uh contract and this function
can be called only by the proxy owner
since we have a modifier that checks for
it without require
and so this way the proxy contract byte
code is still immutable per cap so
because all it is doing is forwarding
stuff uh input to a different contract
and
you are lucky because uh as we have seen
uh smart contracts are usually small so
you can read the whole code and spot
easy bugs and uh so also the efficiency
is uh greater because they are small
and
if yeah but it's JavaScript so you are
reading JavaScript and in reality it's
worse than JavaScript and this is a
quote from materials Master thesis that
says that solidity type system is not
safe and contract interfaces are only
consulted and looked up at runtime not
at compile time so if there is a problem
in contract interfaces uh the evm raise
an exception and the user wastes their
gas because for executing it you need to
pay gas
and another funny thing of the solidity
compiler is that at some point decided
to calculate one with the exponentiation
and actually a lot of smart contracts
were doing 2056 to the power of 0
instead of putting one as a constant and
these cost people money
and this is a big Watts
and remind me about Gary Bernard talk
that explains other funny stuff in
programming languages and compilers
and yeah solid is bad but it's still in
an early stage and unlike CPUs the evm
and the compiler cannot bold at speed
and most of the time we can kill
vulnerability classes with breaking
changes either in the VM or in the
compiler
for example this is a vulnerable smart
contract with a buy function and inside
the buy function we can see that it
takes a variable called num tokens and
these variable num tokens is Multiplied
for the price per token constant and
then we have a required that checks if
this condition holds true and is
checking if how many coins we are
sending is equal to the number of token
we are asking times the price per token
but if we ask for a big enough number of
token what happens is that the
multiplication
will overflow and wrap around so we can
send few coin and get a lot of token and
this is funny because uh the ethereum
developers managed to implement like
overflow in a language that was released
like in 20 uh 16. or so and we have
another bug here uh namely Seoul 2018
for
with a smart uh small smart contract and
inline free we have a declaration of a
exp variable of Type U intake and it can
store up to 255
and we assigned to It 2 to the power of
8 that is
256. so uh we will wrap around the X
variable and so uh the value inside it
will become zero then in the following
line basically we do 0 to the power of X
So in theory we should be doing 0 to the
power of 0 and
in version
0.4 or less of solidity this outputs 0
and that's what it's it's wrong
and in solidity
0.4.25 the output is 1 so it's coherent
with math but still not ideal because we
are silver flowing and with solidity uh
0.8.x the execution is reverted because
the compiler the actually the evm uh see
that uh overflow happened and so the
entire uh execution is reverted and
how uh Soul C
o.8.x reverted the execution on overflow
and basically it's adds new byte code at
compile time that guards against uh
these uh kind of scenario like stock
Canary and
this version of solidity is pretty uh
new and it's came out like this year
and these adding uh this new byte code
that is ADD obviously is more gas
expensive because everybody could and
every extraction that is executed in the
evm use guess and so developers started
using the uncheckable keyword in order
to disable those checks and save gas and
you shouldn't be doing this
and yeah it's important to minimize gas
requirement but we need to do it uh you
need to do it in a safe way
and we need to minimize the uh the
instructions that are executed and the
storage that is used
and for example here we have two uh
contracts
and they have the same function beside
the first one that implements another
Circle that checks if the input array
length is less than 256 and in both
contract function we have a fourth cycle
with a uint 8 index
and a condition that says if the index
is less than array length
and here you can see the upgrades that
uh Implement their Circle and how much
gas they take and if we send to the two
different contracts as small enough
input we can see that
without the asserts we gain uh 26 units
of gas but what happens if we send a
large enough array in the first case the
assert will stop the execution and use a
limited amount of gas instead in if we
uh don't have the assert the index was
declared I used I as you intake and the
input length here overflows and so it
will become an infinite Loop since the
condition of the loop will never be uh
true
and in this case the user that is
calling the smart contract lose money
but there are also cases where the owner
of the contract lose money for example
this is the case of party wallet and
maybe you heard about it and at some
point a random guy on the internet uh
like
killed the contract and how was this
possible basically parity was working in
a library way so kind of a proxy
but the first contract that the user
interacts with is a personal contract
and the owner is the user himself and
then we have a library contract that is
used to implement all the logic so we
can minimize the gas costs and if we
have multiple users each user have a
personal contact and all the personal
contract interact with the same Library
my contract and what happens what
happened is that uh the contact at the
bottom was created and deployed on the
blockchain at some point on July 2017
and the attacker noticed that nobody
actually initialized the contract and so
at in November 2017 he called the
initialize function setting himself as
the owner of the contract and at that
point he killed the smart contract
calling the self-destruct op code and
here we can see the contract is not
possible to interact with it it's uh
it's self-destructed at some point and
the balance here is uh only a couple of
milliseconds of ether because all the
money was in the personal wallets of the
users not in the library wallet
so uh I hope I haven't heard too much
the developers in the audience and we
will now change our Focus to uh security
researchers and
uh maybe
uh there is this trend among security
researchers that web free exploitation
is uh like binary exploitation is a
trend and everybody wants to go as low
as possible and I have to tell you that
web free exploitation is as low as
binary exploitation
and
we will start
with the evm and the evm as I said
before is a risk Carver architect
architecture
and is risk because there are only uh
140 defined op code and instructions
with a hard limit of
255 and it is a stock machine so values
are put in the stock and then we can
execute operations on the value in the
stock and get the results in the stack
as well and if you ever played with
Dalvik or Lua they are stock machine as
well
and you can easily prophesy for the
architecture since it is really simple
and you can uh like emulate it with
python and with uh all your favorite
programming language and doing research
uh for the evm is like doing Cutting
Edge uh binary live research because we
have symbolic execution and formal
verification as the norm and there are
like a lot a lot of tools that allow you
to do uh this kind of stuff for example
Manticore me thrill chilling and if you
haven't
I've uh post a blog post on
shielder.heat about using cheating to
reverse smart contracts
and so since we have all these kind of
uh fancy stuff finding Landy low angling
fluids is really really easy and
symbolic execution can give you the
exact input that you can send to a
contract in order to exploit it like
Auto up for from pontoon if you are a
poner and the key here is automating all
this stuff and scan new blocks in the
blockchain and so exploit vulnerable
smart contract as scale
but the bad news is that
also developers have this kind of tools
so they kill low hanging fruits before
going into production and most of the
live bugs are either logical or
financial and I have to teach you some
uh New Concepts about financial and
economics and it will be easy the first
concept is shorting so selling an assert
asset Without Really owning it so
lending it from someone else and buying
it later when the price is lower
and the concept of stablecoin that is a
cryptocurrency whose value is fixed to
the value of another currency for
example the US dollar and this kind of
cryptocurrency uh like they have uh uh
one dollar value fixed for example and
some uh month ago an attacker tried to a
short Bitcoin and used the Terra stable
coin in order to do it and basically
this was the plan so first launch some
Bitcoin a big amount of Bitcoin than
buying a lot of Tara coin with the
Bitcoin
and selling uh 35k of Terra for 34k of
US dollar coin and these two areas are
two dollar stable coin so they should
have a value of one dollar but if you
sold if you sell different amount of
them obviously one of them needs to have
a
smaller value than the other and so the
value of Pera started to go down and
people went literally panic mode and
started selling all their uh para coin
crash in the market and this is what
happened and that's a really bad slow
Pro in economics
and so the pera Foundation the
developers behind the Terra stablecoin
started selling big amount of Bitcoin in
order to keep the price high and keep
their reputation high and at this point
the attacker simply sold everything and
buy back Bitcoin at our much much lower
price at uh at this point they uh the
attacker also closed uh the law on the
initial loan making a big profit
but if you want to stay uh Technical and
not go into financial and economical
vulnerabilities we'll still have
technical vulnerabilities uh not limited
to Smart contracts you can find bugs in
the compiler or the virtual machine you
can find bugs in other virtual machine
for example the optimism attack by sarik
the guy behind Cydia for iPhone
and you can find cross-enteration uh
cross chain interaction box flash loan
box and you can even come up with new
attack classes and attack scenario and
this field is really wild
and
now we can that now that we have some uh
basic uh knowledge we can start some
root cause analysis of web free
vulnerabilities and maybe you saw the
Workshop from yesterday by riando and uh
here we will do some root cause analysis
in depth and the first big
vulnerabilities that happen is the Diego
Arc maybe you maybe you heard about it
and
the deal is a stand for decentralized
autonomous organization and basically is
a uh distributed investment found where
there is no Authority that select where
the found is going but uh there is a
voting system that decide which proposal
gets the investment from the investor
and this is all done with the smart
contracts so there are smart contracts
that raised found from investor and
there there are smart contracts where
voters can vote proposal and then
when a proposal is founded the profit
inside the smart contract can go and
will go to the investor that actually uh
invested in it
and there is a concept in the Dao that
is that if a minority of the investors
object to a proposal of funding and this
proposal is going to be founded then the
smart contracts literally splits the
founding
and allow the minority to retrieve the
found at a later time
and I
written as mole an easier version of
these Dao uh contract and it was like
really big and basically there are three
main parts
the third first part inside the buy
token function uh is implemented to send
coin to the contract and store them
inside a pot
then there are the there is the transfer
token function that is used to found a
proposal
so to transfer transfer money to other
people and then there is the withdraw
function that is used to retrieve coin
whenever like a split happen
and the vulnerability lies here inside
the withdraw function
because the contract is transferring the
coins before updating the balance of the
user that requested the transfer and if
we zoom in we can see that the function
withdraw accepts a recipient and
recipient is of type address so it can
be a wallet from a user but can also be
as smart contract
and at line 16 we just check if uh who
is asking for a withdraw have some money
actually and then at line 17 uh the call
method is used on the recipient and this
call method will transfer money but if
the recipient is a smart contract will
also transfer the execution to the smart
contract and it will be transferred the
execution to the uh recipient fallback
function
and in this way the fullback function
inside the recipient can basically call
again a new withdrawal with his address
as the recipient and this will be a
recursive function uh function call and
the balance will never be updated
because we arrive at line 17 and then we
call again withdraw at line 15.
and if you lost me at explaining the
code there is a simple flowchart and
there is a malicious contract on the
right and the Dao contract on the left
we start from an entry point of the
malicious contract that call the
withdraw function of the Dao putting uh
himself his address inside the
the recipient variable then from the
Withrow we execute
the call method of the recipient and the
execution and the coin are sent back to
the fallback function of the malicious
contract and at this point the malicious
contract coal withdraw again and the
cycle repeats without ever updating the
balance of the user in the Dao contract
I know this is confusing but if you ever
heard about Rand trans vulnerability
this is what is all about
and the attackers that exploited this
vulnerability gained uh 55 million of
dollars and actually it didn't really
gained this uh sum of money because uh
the network decided in to perform a hard
fork and exclude the hackers transaction
from happening and this was only
possible because the majority of the
network decided to do so because as I
said before transactions are not
reversible but if enough peers of the
network decide so that it can happen
another nice vulnerability that I will
explain is uh the fomo 3D Arc and fomo3d
is a gambling game made of smart
contracts where players can buy keys
from a contract and the money will go
inside a pot
and a Time counter will be initialized
counting back from 24 hours and every
time a user buys a new key 30 seconds
are added to the counter and also the
key price uh the key price increase
and when the counter hits zero the last
player wins the majority of the ball
like a downward action sort of
and
we need to find a way to delay others
transaction and these vulnerabilities
called block stuffing and basically what
the attackers can do is to submit a lot
of transactions that will use all the
gas and there is a hard limit for gas
inside a block and if we reach that hard
limit and we pay enough fee for the gas
miners will prioritize our transactions
since they are more profitable and so
we'll delay others user transaction and
these uh evidence of the attack going
from the bottom to the top we can see a
block that contained at the center 103
transactions and only taking 50 percent
of the gas on the left and from that
block on uh the number of transaction
decreased as low as free transactions
inside a single block with all the gas
for the block limit used up and when the
attack finished we have on the top a
block with 166 transaction and all the
gas and basically this attacker throws
the blockchain for everybody else and
only
they could do a transaction and only
they could buy key for from o3d but also
using transaction for the whole
blockchain
and was it worth it and the attackers
spend more than 80k units of gas worth
of money and gas and ether so ethereum
are the same thing
but gained much much more uh ether
so this is the end of our journey let's
see some closing remarks
for the developers in the audience
remember to avoid rapid prototyping if
your boss come up to you and is strict
about deadlines tell him that you have
my approval and do a careful design
before actually deploying Your solution
inside the blockchain and test before
deploy
for the security people in the audience
my uh advice is to jump on the web free
train we are doing a lot of cool stuff
and it's an opportunity to learn new
stuff and to apply your knowledge to a
different field
and maybe you can find the next million
bug and offer me or as a beer and let's
see top that you have learned something
new today
[Applause]
yeah if you have some question
so the the lunch is approaching I will
be short okay uh just in your opinion uh
what will be the
the technique that someone will use
to deploy some attacks after the proof
of stake merge
uh
the proof of tape will not like change
so much because it's just the way that
new blocks are created and we will not
have uh block stuffing vulnerability
anymore for example because that based
on uh proof of work and but all the
vulnerabilities inside smart contract
and inside like the evm or compiler
there they will still be there so they
will still apply after the the merge
thank you
other questions
yeah as we are from the others uh from
the first two talks uh lots of about
back bounties is there something similar
into web3 uh how things are doing there
yeah uh their the field is moving there
are a lot of uh companies that accept uh
bug bounties uh so also the uh like the
price for the bounties are like
higher than for other type of
vulnerabilities and the payout is uh
like is well
thank you