[Applause]
so hello everyone first of all I would
like to uh thank you for the organizing
this awesome event and inviting me for
speaking here
so so in this talk I'll be sharing about
my experience and research in hacking
games and bypassing entity sheets
so the question is why why would you
want to do that and to be honest I don't
know maybe you just want to admit that
you suck at gaming or maybe you just
want to have fun seeing people through
walls or shooting at their head without
even aiming at their heads or maybe you
just want to earn a lot of money because
uh
uh game act uh making cheats is a
multi-million dollar industry and people
are living on it and uh
also uh the things that you learn from
game hacking uh is uh
also the things that you learn from game
hacking can also be applied in other
fields like malware analysis because uh
the things that you learn like internal
Windows API and undocumented function
can also be used in other stuff
so
so despite all these reasons I would
still uh do not recommend you uh to
cheat in the games because it ruins the
experience for others so anyone here
ever played competitive games
like Apex Legend valrent
paladins
fortnite
okay
so I guess no one even used any cheats
before
So I myself have been playing games for
a lot of time and I was always curious
like how these hackers are able to hack
this game like for example
uh this
so if you don't know what uh this game
is this is uh well rant and currently it
has one of the best entity cheat in the
market called Vanguard because it runs
at the boot of Windows and it keeps on
running at the background 24 7. even if
you are not playing games so uh and and
it's not me so I found this server on
Instagram so how did he do it uh maybe
you'll find out at the end of the video
so um so a little bit about myself I'm
Rohan Agarwal my handle is and
and I have a small company in India
called defco security which provide
penetration testing and continuous Asset
Management Services I do bug Bounty as
well and I have participated in hacker
one and integrity live hacking events
and I love playing games of course
without cheats
and so the agenda is get you all started
in game hacking and demonstrate some
working methods that still work for end
for bypassing the anti-cheats and
encourage more research in this field
because currently game hacking is what
is is what was presentation testing or
bug bounties 10 or 15 years back so
there's not many resources on resources
online
so also to encourage the ntg developers
to uh make a more powerful entity sheet
currently it's already powerful but
still there is always room to improve
so before we start I want to clarify uh
what kind of what this talk is not about
so usually when I talk about game
hacking people uh assume that I'm
finding vulnerabilities and finding
vulnerabilities in anti-cheat code
itself or game code itself and
exploiting it to uh hack other players
or hack company servers so the stock is
not about that this stock is basically
all about gaining the advantage
competitive advantage over other players
so I've divided this log into four
section uh in the first one we'll
quickly see the history of cheats and
entity sheets and in the next section
we're going to see some basic stuff that
you need to know for game hacking and
the in the next section we'll go uh
development for finding hooks drivers
and in the last I will show you a
demonstration of one of the popular uh
twitch game uh
which which I hacked only for research
purposes
so a little bit history about game
hacking so the very first game was made
in 1957 and it was a tennis game and but
it was not publicly available because it
was in a laboratory and fun fact the guy
who made that game was also responsible
in making our first nuclear bomb so a
very talented guy
so but the video games gain its
popularity in 1970s and 1980s you know
when uh when the games were introduced
for Public public use
and in 1980s uh modding of uh game
started happening using command line
hexelita tools and uh
and the first import was developed in
1995 for Doom 2 game
but the things uh started getting heated
up heating up when popular games like
Counter-Strike 1.6 uh started uh
launching in early 2000 because you see
when the cheating was done on single
player games uh the only thing that is
getting destroyed is uh the hacker that
is doing the game that is hacking the
game and not the others player or
company servers but when these
multiplayer games get get launched
that's when uh things went serious
because uh hackers were directly
impacting others player experience and
sometimes even the servers as well
and since the success of online games
depends on the uh current active user
base how much uh how much game is
popular so the the developers can let go
of these small set of people ruining the
experience of others so that's when in
came the punk Buster which was the first
entry cheat and in 2002 came back which
is evolved well venti cheat so initially
they were very successful in stopping
most of the Cheetahs but uh as well as
they were only user mode cheats so uh
very quickly the hackers shift their
cheats to the kernel level so that way
they were able to bypass them so
soon after that came these and uh
kernel level entities like easy entity
cheat battle eye or Vanguard and
currently we are at this stage we are
where they are mostly able to stop but
not not all the hackers
so I'm hoping you guys know the
difference between user mode and kernel
mode but if you still don't I'll give an
example like uh whenever you open a
browser so that is open in user mode and
all the core functionalities that do
that it does it happens in card number
like uh Like You are downloading a file
and it it needs to be written to the
hard disk so it needs to it make the
system called in the kernel for storing
for getting the access to the hard drive
and storing that on the hard disk
so the main point with respect to game
hacking is that uh user mode process
doesn't have access to the kernel mode
processor and memory so like if the
entity sheet is in user mode so you can
simply have you can simply make a driver
in kernel mode and you and the entity
will not be knowing because it's in user
mode and and in the kernel World they
don't have access to that
so these are some of the features of
candle antichrades uh think of and cheat
like classic NT debugger and it has
various signature detections so just
like antivirus have signatures for
viruses
so and teach you'd also have signatures
for cheats so initially kernel entity it
was a big step for the good of Gaming
Community right when it's launched 95
percent of the shooters were instantly
managed from the servers and of course
it can't stop 100 of the cheaters uh
because even ntg developers know that
there will always be a dedicated or
dedicated or determined ones that will
always find a way uh to hack into the
game
so now we can move to the basics
so anyone who is making a cheat first
has to decide whether he wants to make
an internal cheat or an external so
internal as the name suggests is
injected directly into the game memory
so as it as it has direct access to the
game it is very much it has great
performance and it is much flexible by
flexibility I mean it has great
functionality it has great flexibility
in adding the new cheat functionalities
and uh internal sheets are mostly
preferred for games with low level or no
anti-cheats and external are as the
names that is have their own processes
and they manipulate the memory of the
game externally
and
therefore since they are external for
each read and write they are making
different calls so therefore their
performance is low as compared to
internal and the functionality that they
offer is also low but it's enough for
doing what we want to do for like for
example if you want to Simply do wall X
or Aimbot you can do that stuff here
and external genes are mostly preferred
for games with strong antigens uh
because uh strong entity cheats have
great detection vectors for internal in
internal hacks so that's why uh we
prefer external for uh strong entities
so we will we will be focusing on
external only
so how do these hackers bypass these
kernel entities
so as you can see here we have uh we
have achieved which is in user mode and
we have a game as well and in the kernel
we have the entity driver which is
supposed to protect the game's memory so
as you can see we are trying to read
write directly from user mode and for
reading we need to have the handle for
we need to create the handle uh to the
game memory So What entity does is uh it
has us it uses the OB register callback
and as soon as it detects the handle it
completely blocks it so in order to
bypass that uh we also need to go uh to
the kernel level as well so we basically
create the driver and we load it into
the kernel space and we send the
instruction from user mode to whatever
and our driver will be uh doing us doing
the stuff for us for example Reading
Writing the memory
all right
so what are the challenge like if you
want to if you want to make your own uh
kernel level cheat what are the
challenges that you will be facing
now the first one is how you can create
your driver
the second one is how we can load the
driver into kernel like can you is it
allowed to even load any driver into the
kernel
and how can you communicate from user
remote to the kanama for example you
have a user mode cheat how will you send
instructions to your driver in the
kernel and lastly even after doing all
this how will you make your driver
undetected because it will be making lot
of noise at the kernel level so you need
to also make sure that it it don't get
caught up with the entity
so now we can move to the cheat
development phase
so basically I've divided the whole G
development cycle into five parts uh the
first one which is reversing so
basically uh you need to know uh what
kind of cheat you are making like what
things you need to manipulate what
things you need to read for so for that
you need to reverse the game for finding
those things uh then uh you need to
create the driver that will redirect
memory that will send uh and third is
the hooking which is the communication
part which handles the communication
from user mode to Kernel mode then the
fourth is loading driver how will you
load the driver and the fifth is the
creating user mode
so now we we can go uh deep into all the
stuff
before the first one is reverse
engineering so usually in game hacking
what we are doing is reading some
address in the memory for example uh you
want your health to be infinite so you
need to First find the address uh
address of that health health variable
into the memory so for that you need to
reverse the game so usually there are
two ways uh you can do that the first
one is debugging that is used usually
cheat engine so maybe you have used uh
in your childhood for hacking uh games
and the second one is using
disassembling using idea or any other
disassembler
now I personally will personally prefer
cheat engine because uh it gets the job
done easily and conveniently with idea
there are a couple of things that you
need to take care of first the game
Winery is heavily obfuscated so you need
to defer status first and for doing that
you need to dump the binary using a
kernel driver
and the second thing is you need to be
well aware of how that uh
how that game is based on like is it is
it based on a Unity engine or is it
based on our undeal engine so you need
to know the structure of that for uh for
disassembling using idea so that's why
uh is ticket to cheat engine so for that
you don't need to worry about all those
stuff
so uh before I go into reverse anything
I first need to clarify what are the
offsets as they are very uh
important point in reverse engineering
so offset by the by the name suggest is
how far is something with respect to
another
and why is it important why is it
important here so as you can see we have
starting point uh a and a is zero
kilometer away from starting point B is
12 kilometers so we can say that b
offset is 12 kilometer away so why is it
important in game hacking
so basically uh the thing happens is
whenever you load a game into the memory
every time it will be having different
uh address so like as you can see here
we have first launch so you can see the
game at the game is launched at 0x1 plus
the address on the second launch you can
see uh game is launched at four five six
letters so let's say I want to set my
health uh to whatever I want to
so at the first launch I have to reverse
the reverse the game using whatever she
attention or disassembler so and and we
get the address one two six so the
second time also I have to do the same
thing so instead of not reverse
engineering again and again what I will
do is find the offset of the health from
the starting point which is the game
Base address
so I know here if you see one common
thing that health is always three bytes
away from the game memory as in first
launch also it's three bytes away and
second launch also three bytes away so
what I can do is
uh says the health offset is always
three but away so I can always find the
game memory first which is very easy to
find using Windows apis or Windows
function
so to clarify all this uh uh again so
let's say we have a game we launched the
game and inside we have uh two
structures only which is enemy and
player and whenever you uh load the game
the
um
structure and the members of it will
always be side to side like you can see
that ammo will always be four bytes away
from player structure but the struct
player structure itself can be loaded
anywhere into the memory so so let's say
I want to set my player ammo to 40. so
first way I can do that is I get the
address of the mo we are basically
dereferencing the address and then we
set the set it to 40. another best way
a better way to do that is that
since we know that ammo address is four
bytes away from players player structure
so we can find the player structure
address add four bytes to it and we'll
get the ammo address and we can then set
to 40.
even better ways to do that
is to find the game address and since we
know that player structure is 10 bytes
away from game so we can just add a game
address plus 10 byte which will give us
player structure and we can then add
four bytes which will give us ammo
address and we can set to 40. and
and this is how we are uh we will be
representing what ammo offset is which
is game uh exe plus 10 and which will
point to 4 and we can set that to ammo
address
so have a quick demo for offsets but I
think since we are short of time and
and uh there are a lot more things that
I need to cover here so I'll just keep
that for at the end and if we have time
I'll play that
uh so this is a screenshot from uh from
that demo basically we uh so we
basically find the paladins which is a
game protected by EAC uh using cheat
engine we found the ad uh Health offset
which is a five level deep pointer
and
and this is a very simple uh C plus plus
program which only works for games uh
that don't have entity sheets so this is
just to show you that how easily we can
uh using C plus plus read or write the
memory for the games that don't have
attitude
so the next we can move to creating
kernel driver and for that uh we will be
needing some tools like visual studio
uh wtk and a debugger for debugging
and so before I overwhelm you with the
uh the whole cheat uh I would like I
would first like to show you the hello
world driver itself like how other
driver you can make it and how you can
debug that
so
so yeah
so yeah so as you can see if you have
ever coded in C plus plus uh so you know
that the starting point is always void
main so same here uh for driver itself
also the starting points point is uh
driver entry and you can also customize
the starting point in the Linker setting
as well just make sure whatever the
driver entries here uh the link or
setting will also we will be having that
so basically what we are whenever we
load our driver it will first go to
driver entry and uh
since the driver doesn't unload itself
we need to create an object for
unloading as well so that's what we have
done here we created object and inside
object we just simply printed that we
are out of the kernel and it also has a
header files as well for defining this
function now I can show you how uh how
it actually works how what happens in
the background
together
uh so I have I have here a virtual box
running latest windows
so this is what uh this is our hello
driver and uh
and follow for loading it
uh one of the ways you can load it is uh
Windows as internal way of loading using
test signing model so you need to enable
test sending mode as you can see on the
bottom right we have test mode open and
using that you can load any driver but
the thing is the end if you are inside
the test mode you cannot launch any game
because NT cheats will will be detecting
this mode so it's just for testing your
drivers and debugging them so first you
need to for entering test mode you need
to set that command in command from BCD
edit dot set and then you need to reboot
your system and it will be booted into
test mode
so the next thing is you need to create
is the service so I have already
so I've already created the service as
you can see it already failed so to load
this driver into the kernel all you have
to do is uh as he create
the driver name
for yes he start
so the driver is loaded
and if I can show you
in the driver View
so it was it is showing all the
currently driver that are loaded on the
system
uh so yeah this one
so as you can see the driver is loaded
and in the debugger also I can show you
the message
just make sure the capture kernel is
open and now I will
I will now unload the driver and it
should
print the message
yeah so whatever the debug message we
send uh it just printed on the Kernel
and we are able to see that here so the
so now as we have seen the driver itself
a very basic driver uh next thing which
is very important here is cooking so in
order to rewrite the target memory using
a loaded driver
we need a communication path for that so
as you can see here we are trying to
communicate to our driver which is in
the kernel and we can't actually
communicate through it so hooking
actually provides a path for it and
cooking basically what does is it
changes the flow of execution of a
function so how are we going to do that
is
we will hijack a system called which is
already provided inside the Windows
driver you can use any Windows driver
like dxg kernel.sears which is a direct
test driver or Intel drivers so they
have system calls in that so what you'll
do is uh you'll place your instruction
that hey I want to uh I want to
communicate with my driver and here I
have send set an instruction or a shell
code in starting of the system call so
whenever I call that system call
the system call will uh
transfer our instruction to the driver
itself and to understand that in detail
I have a diagram I have a diagram here
so as you can see we have a user mode
and the kernel we have the driver with
the system call which we are going to
hook to and we have a driver as well so
you can see that we are trying to
communicate but we can't do that because
the way we will be loading our driver
which is manual mapping and we can't do
that
so in order to do that uh we are
invoking a system call with our
instruction which is whatever read or
write you want to do and it will go to a
system call and inside system call what
we have done is uh we have added a Shell
Code which is basically doing which is
basically what you're doing is uh
setting the racks register to the
address of our function in our driver
and jumping to that so using hooking we
are able to uh
ah we are able to hook the system call
which are which will be uh sending the
instruction to whatever basically we are
able to communicate with the with the
driver itself
so till now uh what we have done is
basic hello world driver we have seen
how we can communicate with the driver
which is using hooking and so what else
we need to do with the driver as well I
will show that
so the first thing it should uh it
should have is able to get the system
call address so if I go to previous
slide we so as you can see we are
invoking the system call so for that we
need to get the address of that first
cell so it should be able to get that
address
uh and the second part is hooking uh it
should be able to place our the Shell
Code into the system call
and
the third is hook Handler itself uh for
so basically whatever the instruction we
are sending to a driver it should be
handled you should be able to handle
whether it's read or write
and the fourth one is clearing the
traces so whenever we load a driver it
creates not a fly noise and there are
some uh tables inside which these things
get logged so you need to also clear
those things
so I can
just go over
the driver itself the code of the driver
itself
true
so just like I showed you in the hello
world driver we have here a driver entry
and we have a kernel function uh so we
can
so just to give you overview uh this is
the part uh where where we are getting
the system call address so in this we
are targeting the system call which is
NT open composition which is very good
and uh
this system call is inside the dxg
kernel.sys so we are targeting that and
and here we are placing uh our Shell
Code into that thing so that it so that
it can transfer our instructions and
and this is the hook Handler
which will be handling all the
instruction that we are sending whether
it's read or write so there are a lot
more stuff going on and uh I can't like
explain all this stuff you need to most
of them are undocumented undocumented
functions so you need to uh explore it
on your own and see what what is going
on at the end maybe just Google these
function and you'll get to know what is
happening
and uh
and I can show you uh
what is happening at the back end
so I already have here the driver itself
and
let me open a debugger
we need to do the kernel debug local
foreign
just reload the driver which is which is
having our system call
and now if we uh we should be able to
uh disassemble this driver
and to show you the system call in this
so this is a system called
so as you can see we got the system call
and if you see the first few
instructions that there is no uh move
racks or whatever the Shell Code which
will be which we will placing so now
I'll just uh load the driver and you can
see our Shell Code which will be placed
inside here
foreign
which I was talking before the move rack
jump racks it will it will be pushed on
the very first instruction of the system
calls so whenever I will be invoking
that it will be jumping uh to our hook
Handler which will be handling all the
instructions
so we have seen the driver itself uh
then uh the next time the next slide is
very important as it as it can make or
break your uh cheated self so what are
the detection vectors while you are
using this Fork so the very first thing
is the hook it's the hook function
itself the system call that I was
talking about uh
that is very widely known by The Entity
so if you use that you will instantly
get detected so you need to find your
own system call it can be inside that
dxg kernel.sys or you can find your own
driver
or you can find the your own driver in
which you can find the your own system
call and the second
thing that you need to take care of is
the style code itself the uh the
assembly code that you are pushing
inside the uh
system call move racket jump racks so
this is also very uh The Entity sheet
have made signature off so you need to
create your own Shell Code which will be
doing the same stuff as what this is
doing the one that I'm using has 11 line
of assembly and the hook function that
I'm using is totally in a different
driver
so as you can see this is a screenshot
of the driver itself so the this hook
function you need to change the NT open
and the Shell Code which you have we are
placing you need to change those in
order to get in order to be undetected
now I can't tell you like
what you should do because as soon as I
do that uh the the everyone is watching
this so as soon as I do that the
anti-cheat company will make signature
for it or if we use it or many people
use it uh they will get to know about it
and they can easily make signature and
it will get banned
so the next thing is how will you load
the driver you have created your driver
you have you got the hook the next
question is how you can load it so one
thing one way I showed you was the test
signing mode but the thing that in that
is uh
it doesn't work with modern entity
sheets so you can't like uh so you using
that you can't load your driver the next
thing is you can pay money to Microsoft
to get your driver signed by them which
will give you the certified for that but
the thing is you have to pay it and it
can be easily revoked by them if if it
gets reported or if it's get detected
so the next thing uh the next best way
you can do is exploit so basically you
exploit the the officially signed driver
itself for example
uh this is a tool called KD mapper what
it does is it there is a vulnerability
inside a
Intel driver which is ikey IQ VW and
it exploits the vulnerable trainer to
manually map a driver into the kernel
memory what I mean by manually mapping
is it allocates some memory and it just
throws a driver into that memory so so
that way uh using some vulnerable travel
which are officially signed you can load
your unsigned driver into the kernel
memory and to do that all you need to do
is KDM app the driver itself
and one thing which is also beneficial
for you of using this KD mapper is that
it will automatically clear most of the
traces like the most major places are mm
and load driver with B cache and G
kernel so these are all get get tracked
inside the kernel when you load your
driver when you hook it so this tool
automatically creates those but it
doesn't clear everything so you need to
reverse the entity itself and see what
kind of buckets or the logs they are
checking in inside the kernel itself
yeah this is one of the easiest steps
for creating the user mode all you all
you need to do is you need to be able to
call your hook function and you need to
be able to prepare those instructions
like if you are sending read you need to
be able to prepare those instruction and
if you are sending right you need to be
able to do that but it gets complex when
you do other stuff like import or ESP
because that requires doing calculation
trigonometry stuff so in those cases uh
making the user mode at yet complex but
usually for other stuff like
reading memory uh it's uh it's very easy
for creating the user mode
so now I can quickly just show you uh
the hack that I made for a very popular
game
so the game is Apex Legends and maybe
you have played it or not but it's uh
just below the Valor end
well read in terms of Twitch streaming
so
I've just fast forward it just create a
just finding the match
and what I've done in this cheat is uh I
have added the added the glow on enemies
itself so I'll be able to see them
through the walls and I've also added
the items glow as well so you can see
the uh items that you that for example
you need to loot a specific kind of gun
like sniper so you can see through walls
where that gun is
foreign
just two three days back
this is the user mode I have already
loaded uh the kernel driver into the
kernel I've just I've just run the user
mode
so as you can see I'm able to see people
through walls
and
if I if I'll go any closer I'll also be
able to show the CD load so as you can
see the blue ones are the I have already
highlighted a certain kind of weapons
which I can see through also that I can
uh allude them
so this is the Border stuff so the
problem with the stuff which I showed
you earlier is that thing works for most
of the game here but there is one
exception which is uh well-rent uh it
has it has a very powerful anti-cheat
and the
the things that is uh uh not working
with what I was showing you earlier is
that the way we were loading the driver
we are not able to use do that here
because in that case we were loading the
driver in the user mode and uh whenever
we start the game at that point entity
runs but in case of valid the ntg trans
start starting from the boot itself so
we need to find a way to load the driver
before we can even start the system
so one of the ways we can do that is is
uh using the bios so in BIOS generally
we can't load the driver but we can use
an alternate way uh is by using UEFI so
it's like a modern bios so you put the
driver of UEFI and your driver inside
the USB and you you plug the USB into
your system and then you reboot and just
like when you install uh Windows using
USB it will first it will go it will
launch the BIOS and in the Bios you will
you will find the UEFI loader and in
that you can load your driver and uh
that way you can load your driver
without before the window starts the
other hacks which are relevant for uh
well rent is external hardware hacks so
so there were many many recently many
people were making pixel pixel bot for
uh well run so as you can see the enemy
here it has it is highlighted with a red
color so they have made a python script
which uh simply you know find this pixel
on the screen and aims at that pixel so
initially they were working the Python
scripts but they were easily getting
detected so next thing they did is they
used uh Arduino for doing that so
whatever the mouse event will fall
example clicking and all it was handling
by the Arduino itself again and using
hypervisor it was able to simulate a
secondary Mouse
so again this was in August it got
passed by well rent the hypervisor and
the next thing the now hackers what are
doing is uh they are using USB host
shield on the top of the Arduino so now
you can just simply plug your mouse to
the Arduino and you already know you can
plug to the computer so it's like having
embot inside your mouse itself so I
don't know how they will detect it or
they will patch it but let's see
so here I will be sharing the driver the
code for the user mode and kernel board
by the end of the day and these are some
of the references which helped in making
of This slide these this presentation uh
the guided hacking this is a paid this
is a paid website which post which has a
great community and it costs around 20
for a year so it's cheap so you so it's
like a go-to for game hacking you can
find lot of tutorials and stuff the
second one is unknown sheets it's game
hacking form and
the information there is scattered so
you need to research whatever you want
to find you will get there but you need
to research on it and the third one is
uh this guy null uh he posts uh videos
about making kernel cheats
so that's it
uh thank you everyone I hope you liked
it