all right so we're going to finish up
here with our last presentation for the
day
Barry Kimball is going to talk about
pixel tracking and how it's used and
abused so it should be a pretty
interesting talk
Barry's worked with computers the
majority of his life as probably most of
us maybe he maybe he started a lot
earlier anyways anyways I studied
materials and engineering Computer
Engineering worked through how to work
through how and what makes a chip work
all the way to programming so you know
hardware and software huh that's pretty
ugly sadly not yeah so he's worked in
several fields of IT and wider range of
industries he's running the Cincinnati s
MBA and member of several local security
groups in the Cincinnati area so again
we have another Cincinnati rep here to
help us out for conferences this year
but again pixel tracking and how it's
used and abused in sonority you know
when I'm Cincinnati when I can't anymore
toto
marry me all right all righty
well thanks for coming out guys and you
know for those that are still conscious
and throughout so far we'll give this a
little run and see what you guys think
feel free to chime in this has been a
talk that's been kind of evolving over a
few years so feel free to inject and
might get out it may be spoken again
sometime
so pixel tracking what we're going to
cover and can't see anything so step
back a little bit more I guess so we're
going to cover what a pixel is and how
how they've been used and whether you
know how they've been abused and seeing
attacks and some of the things you can
do to help mitigate some of the
information that you give to the world
caused by them
of course I'm Barry Kimball I've
searched from a lot of letters that
people probably wow there's a few people
in the room that probably remember some
of the things but I'm the original MCSE
or you know something called son you
know I did my first stuff was Novell
anybody remembers that world oh yes my
favorite protocol huh but go ahead and
head on so what a picture stands for
basically it's the element for what
makes up the picture on the screen right
so it's usually the little square the
screens a whole bunch of little dots
little dots can be used for a wide range
of different things over the years but
it came in the use of 1965 was his first
existence in print as a bunch of people
working on the moon project said it was
in use for a couple years they're in
discussions for a shorthand for pictures
and the quality of pixelation and stuff
for how while the cameras could take
images of the moon for the moon landing
project just for an interesting history
and fun facts properties of the pixel of
cliffs included for RGB which is the
red/green/blue numbers and then there's
the you know ygb or the cy or CMYK wacky
stuff and I never seen anybody actually
utilize it but was on some of the TVs
there for several years so some of the
mostly pixels are use them in the world
of HTML of course is the biggest effect
that the world sees and these are some
of the how to make a pixel call that's
an HTML and I you can see that the these
are different ways and the code which
they hide the pixel for the purposes of
embedding their website with tracking
technology and ability so that when you
visit the website this will reach out to
the world and try to request a
non-existent image in order to purposes
of logging that you visited the website
right and also they can return the
queries to your browser whatever it
wants to do because the browser doesn't
really care whether it sends back a
picture or not so it can request from
your computer a lot more information
than just what the picture it was
originally requesting but it by default
automatically gives that target location
your IP address
so are the first uses originally were
anybody it was in the world of HTML 1
you know it was a great way to count how
many times somebody visited your page or
be able to restrict you know just so you
can do an accurate page counter so
people were interested in that kind of
information the back in the ancient days
is like can you get you know 10 people
to visit your website randomly from
wherever in the world I used to run a
little script to keep track of all the
different countries fun stuff
the some of the uses today it's expanded
substantially of course the web pages
it's expanded in the email advertising
that allows companies to target and
better make money and some people in the
recent years have even figured out ways
to weaponize the ability of what a pixel
can do for it so some of the things to
know of course there every read browser
knows about are very capable of query in
your system or whatever when you use the
web browsers as your IP previous sites
how fast your internet is your operating
system browser plug-ins hardware specs
it's actually kind of crazy with all
that can query for your CPU video
resolution battery level with
orientation of your device like I tell
my pads tablets cell phones of course
give away geolocation GPS they can also
do autofill for purposes of login one
thing that really took me by surprise is
your web browser will expose what sites
you stay logged into so if you're in a
social media like Facebook and Twitter
Amazon Microsoft you have the option to
stay logged in in the background all
those are visible to any website to
choose visit and they can query against
that and ask for what credentials you're
actually logged into so they can use
that to track you as you visit our
different sites that profile stands out
all right so flare your cpu and how much
ram and your resolution and your logged
into these seven sites you know that it
helps them track where you are so if I
visit Amazon and I hop over here - yeah
or go to over to Google they can pin
together the profile of your machine
from all that recorded data some of the
reasons and places use for pixels of
course their traffic analytics is you
know the big thing so I'm who's visiting
what what you doing along that way is
direct marketing you know if your stone
adds to a particular area you don't want
to sell parties in a commercial and a
non Hardee's environment right and so
you want to target the cities where you
want to promote your sales you know spam
costs for like email tracking that gives
back information you know who's opening
your webs or your emails and such and
another interesting thing I found out
was the document usage if you want to
track whether your users are actually
doing their jobs and working on the
documents they should be you can tag
your documents and every time they open
the document Microsoft Word and it's in
it Joey likes to pass on any geometry
that you'd like to record in Word
documents Mike most Microsoft suite auto
passes pixel tracking with no
qualms so we sit in the world of email
several companies have sprung up over
the last several years that allow for
email marketing tracking capabilities
like there's companies like yes we're
banana tag streak prob about seven or
eight and other to become pretty popular
over the years to slice you know so if
you wanted to do mass marketing email
for your company these companies step in
and tag all your email so that when they
visit they can say you know hey your
worker yeah they they sent out these
emails to these companies and these
amount of people open them very
interesting like said online surprises
imagine most everybody in this room is
pretty familiar just how bad different
companies are spying upon us cursing it
between the Amazon and Apple Facebook
and Google there's some information on
the slide there if you guys want to read
through but the couple informations
that's kind of interesting as most of
them have made publicly available how
much telemetry they have collected on
you so like at the bottom of there is
this Google you go to your account then
that website and it will tell you what
they've collected on you there's some
more in later and my slide deck to for a
belief Facebook and Amazon has one as
well it's a little bit more complicated
to get to but so some of the things that
I found the dark side of the pixels is
how people are abusing them of course
there's malware tracking banner
infections stereographic attacks
phishing attack information the word
documents also you know Microsoft
automatically passing information script
execution queries there's many different
ways to collecting information of course
but one thing that was really
interesting this is the matter
some of the more recent malware is
utilizing they can track the spreading
of their malware they started passing
those like pixel calls throughout the
systems as they infect it so that each
one queries out currently basically its
beaconing you know people familiar with
web beacons and when I was first putting
this together it was probably month or
two before this report came out but our
bigquery or things I'd been discussing
with somebody was that they in a cloud
environment is who are you providing the
information to on your documents right
if somebody gets into your cloud
environment and was able to tag your
documents now they are receiving
telemetry whenever you open your cloud
documents right and so you know who's
that information going to is it your own
company providing that data or was that
somebody else has gotten into your
documents and the cloud point actually
had put out a warning that they were
starting to see attacks that where
people were placed in pixels and that
gives an adversary right the information
to who's opening the documents what
users are you know accessing it and you
know what their IP addresses are what
the computer names are giving them a
little bit more of a background
information over your site through the
cloud I would think from a riskless
standpoint that's you know you're
providing more efficient information for
them the better craft if I know sue and
HR opens this document every day on
Monday then you know for different job
postings or whatnot that would be
something I would want to watch or you
know somebody in the accounting
documents you know you find out who
works in the different departments that
aren't necessarily publicly available
information if you get access to their
cloud documents
repertoire up till about a year and half
ago Microsoft didn't really care too
much despite people complaining for over
a decade but in the last couple of years
I started taking pixels in their
documents a little bit more seriously
for example us not as easy to place
anymore you need a third-party tool to
inject them now but you can still do it
but up until about a year ago which was
well before I regionally started on this
but they said some of the different
things that they can pull from your
documents but they the fact that
Microsoft is starting to realize that
they're kind of liable for giving away
some of that information by passing it
automatically right or they don't want
to be on the hook for it but there was a
Trojan and being passed around an office
365 the pixel called and documents where
they advised that you know if you
started pulling documents down locally
to view them and protected mode to
prevent those calls for me and made so
that that information is not passed
outside so some of the other weird
attacks had been over the last few years
there was a couple of attacks through
flash utilizing units and granite which
were different styles of tax one was a
backdoor allowed them to figure your
screen the other ones was targeting the
bank one of the ones I found pretty
interesting is countly which is a form
of JavaScript people were modifying real
heavily to circumvent antivirus and
detection because the JavaScript just so
scrambled it doesn't trigger
any of the previous skin algorithms or
hashes so they're not allowed for them
to spin up things for like stereographic
attacks and actually pass the payloads
through pictures which we'll cover here
in a few moments of course javascript
and had taken on audience for a script
data mining injection which allowed a
query as to where they'd start checking
what other site to use in the background
and kind of download your hashes from
your web browser if you stored your
password in the browser then at least
gave them the hash to which they could
run against because it would auto submit
but you don't realize it's occurring
when you visit the website this is a
this is a tactic that I think happened
about probably about a year and a half
ago was a very small run the personnel
that found this it was targeting a bank
in South Korea but it only affected
about a hundred and eighty computer
handheld devices the people think that
the people were working on accidentally
let it slip out of their network or you
know that we're building the tool
because the tool wasn't completely
finished but what was kind of freaky
about it is that it was utilizing if
anybody's familiar what's on the right
side of their you know your right side
of the screen for you guys in the world
of graphics with that is a familiar with
what that is in the world of graphics
anybody
so it's a transparency pixel herb so so
just doing pixel they're doing an entire
image overlaid the login screen and
which they could record taps on the
device and have an XY coordinate now of
course it wasn't completely finished but
it was collecting data but it wasn't
doing anything with it so like if you
know when you clicked on there to put in
your login and your dressing EULA pop-up
keyboard
so then they have the XY coordinates
they could go back and map you know kind
of like a virtual key logger through
digital screen which is you know stuff
people are evidently working on because
it hasn't been seen since but it's been
a little bit over a year since the
initial outbreak of whatever it was they
were working on we were mentioned a
stereographic attack what's interesting
about this is I priced several you're
familiar with it but um each picture has
the RGB wider RGB for normal pictures or
whatever all those pixels are in binary
right and so you have 255 for green 255
for red and 255 for blue and you can
manipulate the last two bits without
actually affecting the colors enough for
most people to realize that that data is
been manipulated so malware code can be
added to my picture and be your actual
payload and on a website which actually
was utilized pretty recently and no late
in November confident and malwarebytes
Terry really liked seeing a large uptick
in an attack that they didn't understand
what was causing all the traffic but
they managed to trace it down this
little white bar on the top left of the
screen there is carrying a malware who
payload
which once it was decrypted or converted
from base64 back to an open SSL
decrypted and then removed another
base64 and then reverse the sass key the
hex to sass key with source code that
actually activated and downloaded the
payload for a chosen backdoor that was
spreading on a website and affected
primarily Mac devices an apple hidden
roughly 5 million users and on January
7th I believe so it was like one of the
more successful stereographic attacks
that's been seen and then like this some
of the source code in the bottom of what
it looked like and then the hash here
like the the base64 decrypted and then
the secondary payload where it actually
went out and grabbed the code I'm some
of the options so what you can do to try
to circumvent some of the data
collection on yourself from these
various things of course as web browsers
we usually have an incognito mode
nowadays that's not entirely foolproof
any longer is more and more people
develop they still think you're in
enough for your computer that they can
carry through that and using VPNs your
tour helps you know we please get rid of
your geolocation some of the things I
thought came across to is operating
systems some are a little bit more
versatile as some of you hear that
workaround right pattern familiar with
tens I assume it's a rating system
actually created here right patented as
a ram only operating system it's very
nice for being able to use any device or
any desktop PC or laptop that you can
and you have no access to the actual
hardware structure the operating system
runs entirely out of RAM so that leaves
no artifacts or than that part of the
website your browsers can't query
against because you have no access to
the physical hardware other than the RAM
drive that it's operating out of tales
and some other versions of Linux distros
that are been built for tried office
escape what you're doing on the web some
email plugins Thunderbirds one of the
nicer browser email utilities ironically
because that look doesn't carry Outlook
automatically passes all pixel tracks
there's a plugin for Chrome if anybody
uses Chrome as your email browser ugly
mail and then some other plugins now for
Chrome Firefox people of course Mac
users are proximally with Safari with
starting with hi sea air and introduced
intelligence tracking purrs engine which
was become a real big deal over the last
several years and that Facebook lost a
lot of revenue due to the fact that they
couldn't trace Mac or give ads to Mac
users because Safari Auto filters out
their ads which of course Facebook has
recently retaliated and will cover that
here in a few moments but there are
another bad blocker I've really enjoyed
up until last week was you block origin
if anybody's familiar with it it's been
a was a very powerful tool but Google
has decided to start targeting
third-party app blockers and it's on the
it's kind of not working so well in the
last two weeks due to some of the
changes done
so some of the controversy of course is
because you are blocking the ads various
websites and companies don't prefer to
allow you to view their website since
they're not making revenue off yet all
right
anybody here ever visit Forbes so when I
first started building that and trying
out some of these various tools I found
a very interesting that Forbes had what
Sawyer dated at 88 different vendors
just by hitting the home page so I wish
I had thought had the idea at the time
to have taken screenshots of that
because they have since masked what's
visible and but they had a really nasty
gram for using that blockers at the time
which at 88 I thought was a little
extreme myself but I said and then
there's a local channel there but so
Thunderbird has the built-in options
here's the settings for the security and
then you'll get these little when you
know there's a your email has a pixel
block in it get these little boxes
withdrawal squared broken gif files
basically where they're not able to make
the call the phone home in this case
this particular email had two of them
the most I've seen is actually eight and
one email through gleameil really
dissected into the email that heavily
because it's gotten so convoluted in
being able to actually have access to
the raw email at least from the tools I
usually i mean i just use Chrome
and Thunderbirds kind of archaic if
you're used to familiar me it's not very
robust playing the wrong medium they're
all and it's just text only and so that
instead of the actual image kind of grew
it should see you should see the HTML
link what's left and a lot of times you
look at it and if you read it all the
way across there's a little section says
tracker or ID those are then continues
on to whatever and I was curious if you
had a to read on the right side there if
it had something similar to that I'm
tired I did not with some Thunderbird
myself primarily throughout I mean I
used to use Thunderbird several years
ago I got a car liked it from the fact
that it wasn't outlook right but but at
the same time it's not outlook and then
the real problem is is it doesn't do
exporting so if you change computers you
can't reinforce your mail at least at
the time I don't know if it's gotten
better over the last couple of years but
if you're you know is the fact that it
had built-in security features none of
the other ones do that for the purposes
of tracking it's the only browser that
does saw at least as of last year when I
was digging through that part but um
yeah as I say to say because
Thunderbirds a little bit more primitive
on the viewing stuff and raw modes a
little harder to do it might be in there
buried somewhere I didn't spend a whole
lot of time digging into like said
Thunderbird as well as I do a little bit
yeah I said outlook I would assume gives
you a an HTML link this is what ugly now
looks like it'll put a little I in front
of all
it's titles for your email so that
you're aware that if you open that that
you're going to trigger a response there
was another one I don't know if I had
written down but there was a pixel
something Oh give you a little red one
it'll actually let you it won't activate
it so you can actually go into the email
and then see what they are gostrey is an
interesting product gostrey due to the
fact that nobody really bought that or
pays for it for as a plugin for your
browsers they still do sell your
information but they have anonymized it
everybody likes that information right
so they're like so instead of saying hey
user so-and-so visited said site they
say yeah you know allegedly you know 50
people use this site today right so they
don't actually pass on depending on they
give you a breakdown of you know which
one do you want which is kind of
interesting so you can track and see
which the different analytic sites are
collecting the data when you visit a
visit a site and you can whitelist
whatever sites you want you know but
they're there they're still trying to
make money as well so they're trying to
stay afloat they openly admit now that
they sell your information but they just
they strip out your personal
informations and stuff and give a
general you know collection the data I
guess to the different companies pixel
blackness as well I was talking about I
didn't know if I start a slide left but
so it gives you the little red little
red mark in it then you can see and
highlight who it's beaconing out to or
whatever if you open it you can actually
go ahead and click it the source so you
can see cases whether it's more than one
it'll give you a list of the sources and
you can check mark if you want to
actually go ahead and send that pixel
why you might want to do that is if
you're signed up for ads like fries or
Micro Center or something like that they
don't know you're actually opening those
ads right because now you're blocking
that tracker so if you'd like to
continue to receive those ads or their
discounts or their or whatever you kind
of have to make an extra step to go
ahead and say yeah go ahead and let them
know that I opened this you know but you
know if anybody likes their free coupons
for micro Center I'm a fan of free USB
sticks so I occasionally click a couple
of those and let them go through you
know I think I missed one minute and
this is what you black origin looks like
puts the little shield up top you gotten
on the off button you can also whitelist
what sites you want to make available
the pass your information and then it
will give you a running count number of
every site that that particular page hit
count of how many trackers are on that
actual site sometimes those get really
large if you're a big fan of Xbox this
is ending their ad sites for X boxes
ridiculous digits I think - same about
485 over the courses and you may a xbox
an advertisement page really nice if
you're using YouTube or something like
that you get no commercials or ads it's
worked really nice up until I said from
everything I've used for up until two
weeks ago it was a great product is
still decent product for free you can't
knock it but I've noticed
whatever the backends that chrome is
doing
any pixels that are pictures that are
smaller than like a little speaker logo
are now like the little like red Xbox we
had a little bit ago so like you can't
tell what's your like your dropdowns or
what's your speaker control or your
minimize like if you're visiting YouTube
like all your little controls are
disappeared I would assume that the
people that help maintain this will
eventually fix this but also as a side
effect both Firefox and Chrome has
confessed that they're not doing Auto
updates for ad blockers anymore so if
you want to continue to maintain your ad
blockers you have to manually update
them yourself because they are
preventing those from auto updating any
longer as of about a month ago as they
are blaming speed that the ad blockers
are slowing down web traffic browsing
which let's see I got a slide there for
that I thank you yeah so they're claims
from Google of courses that the ad
blockers are slowing down the web
trafficking so much that it's not worth
your time to have them and that they
should build their own web blocker so
that of course Google's will pass their
own ads into their browser and block the
other people's ads here's some of the
time stamps of a third party the effects
of some of these ad blockers which I
can't quite see them from here but
ghostery is pretty low you block origin
I mean it's hundreds of a second I mean
happily put up with a hundred seven
millisecond do not see any ads when I
was visiting Facebook or YouTube or the
like
if you get into other browsers like was
a go duck or whatever DuckDuckGo gets a
little own brutal those are you know
eight seconds is a different story you
can't understand that that probably
would retire from using that that was
back up here there's another guy that
stunner gal I'm not sure but the Robin
lioness has done a lot of work and has a
really recommends no script as a tool to
use in the background for blocking a lot
of this material what's neat about the
site and it was in the slide at the very
end but that you can actually visit
their site and run tests on to see what
kind of information is being passed from
your network by browsing the internet
and it'll actually give you solutions
for different things to plug if you
mostly miss grep will stop almost
everything but it at least give you an
idea what kind of information you are
leaking to the Internet one of the
things I thought was because I tried it
out on one of my boxes for creds and
giggles I let her run for like a 20
minutes it didn't find it in my pcs but
the fact that my TV's visible kind of
took me off-guard because of course IOT
devices aren't robust in security so the
fact that somebody could tell that I
have a samsung television just by this
is ending our website because it's on my
network was kind of an interesting
eye-opener Apple devices and I said with
the Safari and stuff like that they have
built-in that blocking they call it
limiting the ad tracking on their iPad
and iPhone and the settings to enable
that
the privacy badger I've not personally
used it yet but it's pretty similar to
you block origin you can do a whitelist
read list or you know neutral whether
I'm not Irish clear what the yellow does
but some other things too there's a like
pfSense firewall builds a module that
you can put in for blocker in G which
automatically block a lot of the pixel
tracking calls I played with it a little
bit I haven't spent a whole lot of time
making it work but there's an excellent
document there for anybody I'd like to
take that challenge it's several pages
long and very technical not big pfSense
so it was kind of but they keep you
entertained for a weekend or two if you
want to take a shot at it there's things
that came across to you in the later
editions of this is some of the effects
that pixel is having on artificial
intelligence right so because that's the
big thing now but the fact that you can
put a pixel in an image and it will
affect the a eyes ability to detect what
that image is right so it'll cause them
to miss class classified just by dot on
the tire and it changed from an
automobile to a dog you know putting a
dot on this dog and changing it to a cat
you know a horse to an automobile and
it's pretty interesting research so once
they get the three pixels in a picture
the most day I can't identify the image
any longer
so I was interesting
so yeah back in October taste announced
that they are no longer they implemented
what's called the Facebook pixel which
basically is they're given their
third-party advertisers first right
access to the data so that all ads come
through to the users as actual Facebook
traffic instead of a third party app
they've cut back how much ads they throw
at you but the fact that the now means
that if a third party ad has malware in
it the Facebook is passing it to you and
there's you know outside your browser's
bro you're a Z you know I think it's
kind of an interesting response to in
order to catalog and regain the revenue
from mac OS operating systems and of
course I'm sure they probably have
something negotiated with Google with
Google implementing their own ad
blockers and thought was very
interesting to and if anybody saw last
month but Google started putting ads on
their home page which I had never seen
before which is kind of bothered me as
well cuz I always went to Google was the
browser because there's no ads and now
they're starting to put an ad in the
bottom so but the fact that they're
giving first party access to everything
you do be able that means their third
party can trace and fingerprint your
computer just as you've visited their
own website
these were the plugin slowdowns more
recently this was I don't know how many
weeks back those Matt turned me on to
this a couple days ago gentlemen Joe
chasing him he has created a new tool
called subhuman which scans your system
for incoming pixel calls and then
anonymizes and bombards that site with
several thousand calls from around the
world clarion that email pixel track
found is an interesting solution to you
know mess with people that are you know
tracking you on the backend on your
emails I read through some of this
material pretty weird a couple days ago
or last night and her yesterday
yesterday morning or whatever a lot of
people say well aren't you kind of DDoS
in these ads nice like the same way that
you know his response of course was
while we didn't ask to be tracked in the
first place so you know which ground you
me hitting them with 3000 different
random places from around the world you
know to obscure you know where I opened
your actual email it's not as much as
like okay so your email advertisers
wanted to know when you open the email
so when you open the email just subhuman
will hit that thing with like two or
three thousand hits from random random
places on the web yeah so said hey
instead of getting one response with the
information you're trying to track I'm
giving you five thousand copies of me
opening that email every time I open
that email I was a very amusing thing
you know it's a fairly new github
there's the address on the bottom of
thing buddy wants to take a look to get
to work it's it's kind of an
interesting concept to start poking back
at people doing the pixel tracking and
everything that we're doing you know and
these were some useful interesting sites
that said the FF privacy Badgers
considered pretty good that web ke Linus
Pro or Robin - I'm sorry that's let's
talk about theirs they got like eight
different categories of different tests
you can scan your system with the
courier letting them giving them
permission to scan your system right so
as much as you want to trust hitting a
ok button on a random website on the
Internet
have at it said my stuff I don't care
about too much but it did find my
television so that was a kind of an
eye-opener and then places like you know
the analytics to Google and YouTube of
collected Anja and Facebook together the
sites while you're logged in they'll
show you what they've accumulated so but
if anybody's got any comments
suggestions or questions I'm always open
I can send them out I don't personally
got and post them anywhere I think they
were posted online from oh is f-from
we can't go so we want to make sure we
have permission to do so first sound
like we did a person it's the other
thing is that Adrienne is going on his
record of these and they will be on IV
Club Website yes oh and all the dirty
girls didn't moved a bit shoot you down
little multiplied sometime tomorrow yeah
so last year they were off with it and
by the end of the day actually I think
you had before well of course that
actually there was one more thing I
wanted to add on this which was kind of
interesting but I forgot to look into it
too much but um anybody see the article
on LinkedIn this week about that they
have so much telemetry on us that they
can actually track us by our heartbeats
that everybody's heart beats so unique
that they can actually trace where we
are based off our heartbeats and the
devices that can hear it yeah I thought
that was a little fun to dig him down a
little bit more but I meant to do that
before today but I forgot about it
what's that I said I didn't dig into the
actual thing there was an article on
LinkedIn this past week that a friend
had posted that they were that they have
collected so much intelligence honest as
they can trace us and know where we are
based on our heartbeat that that's a
unique identifier that can be used to
locate us kind of similar to facial
recognition I wish you could tell you
more about that was like I just hit that
and skimming and I didn't dig into as
much as I wanted to but I thought you
know you guys might be interested in
hearing about it but I'm sure there's a
few articles up on various websites by
now because it was posted like Monday or
Tuesday you be something to look at
would you ask guess what you're trying
to say how easy it would be to
completely cover your tracks of what
you're doing
visiting the internet from the from a
few various people I've talked to if you
actually wanted to do something
anonymously on the Internet you need a
computer that you don't use exclusively
for that particular purpose preferably a
burner laptop that you don't use
actually plug into anywhere other than
your tor connections and
you know use public Wi-Fi and tunnel
somewhere else in the world and because
it's going to fingerprint that machine
enough that companies like Google or
Microsoft are going to be able to pull
serial numbers or MAC addresses or off
that device to such a point that it
doesn't really matter what you do after
the first day right I say once they
figure I mean that's I've had a friend
show me like once you plug something
into the computer in like 10 or 15
minutes there's a like Google token on
your device that lets them know then
fingerprinted you so once you've got
that token once you put your name or
some personal information into it it's
going to be tied to that token and that
token will be paired with anything else
that you've used yeah so I mean once you
once you put your name in the browser
BAM
you know that's tied to you I personally
have somewhere in the ballpark of 50
some computers which is a little
abnormal but so the fact that you know
my ability to obscure that is probably
really hard because I go out most of
mine are all in one place so but it does
make for an interesting way of trying to
surf the net anonymously you pretty much
have to have a device dedicated for that
now that you put zero information into I
would think at this point