yet
China I guess from the bar too long
I'm
I max Appel I work at intrepid a screw
which is
NCC group company now I'm a senior
consultant
and the research co director were based
in New York City
a I've done some past research a an NFC
and mobile wallets
the Bay Area sports fan so it's good to
see
more Giants fans out here New York
doing so hot now
%uh services talks going to focus on the
Android Open Source project
and OEM's kinda where the two meet what
the OEM's ad on top
the Android Open Source project and what
the consequences are so
ruining some application issues I'm
kinda
delve into some OEM specific
vulnerabilities to cover chipsets back
doors
look at the preloaded applications show
you as a tool for that
they fit together %ah and
and can give you an overview routing
post Android 4.0 that's the theme the
stock
I first what is the Android Open Source
project
its its Android right what
what it really is comprised that is
occurring all hardware abstraction layer
same system services that it's up to the
oh yeah
their equipment manufacture to to
implement the
the harder a factual error code and
drivers for the specific hardware so I
got on this device
you can't just bill the Android Open
Source project loaded onto the device
who dat cuz unit the drivers et cetera
entered open source project can be bill
s kinda sure Android for the Nexus 4
7:10
some Galaxy Nexus devices but everything
else
i sat on their and then with a typically
do is add outs on top
that I'm so you get kind of a sandwich
in OEM sandwich at the lower layer
the application where arms where focus
on
oh %um components not ESP itself
I some device components axiom
really happy that 15 gave us talk before
mine cuz it covered a lot of the stuff
I was gonna come to try to rush through
so hope we're here for that I was an
awesome talking gave a lot of good
background for this stock
to the bootloader like you mentioned
also
insures that only sign code can be
booted I it's the first thing that runs
when you turn your device on
I will cover developer unlocking versus
exploit unlocking your bootloader
which allowed to run unsigned code so
that's where a lot of the
Android 4.0 roots are coming from essay
4.0 on time
4.0 4.1 4.2 4.22
I the recovery partition recovery how
useful it can be
right it allows you to on
out write to the file system as
the reviews are before the device group
kinda separate
partition you can boot into on then
we'll cover
the file system and some permissions so
such system has your binary said so
read-only partition I'm look at data
local prop
I we suffer an exploit but thats
that settings on the device and and
there you can set it to be.
i/debug devices and if you read access
and we look at a an interesting simply
attack
so
to begin I server bootloader unlocking
sounds like we said allows outbidding
unsigned code which can be a custom ROM
or a colonel
I once it unlocks a different OEM's have
different ways of signifying that the
bootloader is unlocked
I HTC has amassed flag display ass on
her ass off
I Nexus has if
Nexus tablet that some like to cuddle or
unlock some porn boots
otherwise it's got a lock symbol on that
now Qualcomm
chipsets have a secure flag
so keep in mind as we go through the
Ceres two very different scenarios for
bootloader unlocking
there's developer unlock where your data
partition all your
all your text messages an app data and
everything is white
and then there's exploit unlocking
bootloader where that stuff is not quite
this with the bootloader looks like
locked on the left there
is an HTC device on the right is a
Samsung device you can see maybe it's a
little small
SAMSUNG official a little point
this point cool director sam se official
a sister official a and then he
CS locked
so those two locked bootloaders to some
other
bootloader exploit unlocks that have
come out I
I mean if you're familiar with at least
one of these
yeah okay cool under vote was the first
first warner's for HTC only I mean
they've kept it going
Norwalk muscle HTC devices I
set that s flag of and give you
capability to leave it off
motor choppers pretty recent this is
like a really powerful one
effects a ton of devices
as it was found by Dan Rosenberg and
Odin
warps come back
hits why it's anyway
you can still see it Odin and I'm our
Samsung
I'm dollars the open source
implementation Odin
and their allies you to flash custom
loaders depends divisive I swear that's
gone away for data partition
right the sandboxes
is why that's happening %ah so
then developer unlocking I'll
always keep talking HTC dev
nations the developer site well as you
use Facebook which
which Steven mentioned I'm in a device
token to unlock the bootloader and wipe
your data partition
on and motorola is now doing the same
thing so
at sorry
you know this get their CS the bar you
can suffer through that for free drinks
right
um iight so here's some on los Pilares
so it is the the same to or similar
products on the left there you can see
on lot right above the fuzzy stuff
and then over here custom a so is what
it looks like when it's on like
I and then a developer unlocks this is
on now
my Nexus 7 device really simple fast
oh yeah man law that's the whole thing
on the bootloader is unlocked and you
can see there says
a racing user data so this is a
developer unlock
way to user data shows that lock sale
lot
and then that's really easy to relock
Sun developer devices the Nexus devices
really easy to lock and unlock your
bootloader
every time you unlock it because it's
not happening within exploit skin whiter
data partition
which which can be a pain I
so once you unlock your bootloader I
would cover the ways you can do that you
still have root access which is what
you're going for in the first place
similar loader on lock allows you to
write furloughed on sign code
and then the next step is usually to
flash a recovery image
I she can do that through fast food or
to flash
a custom ROM or kernel so
custom recovery image is I won't go into
this too much just doing it covered it
so well
clockworkmod team when recovery project
is a million of them out there
I it's their their device specific so
the purpose of this is to allow you
to write your SU binary the route
component on as the user
allows low-level system access for
device imaging
really really useful like you should
know you can back up your whole device
image it do whatever you want and then
flashes back okay
finally route so all route is
just like 1x route to binary with a sec
you I debate
I owned by root so when you execute it
is your root shell
typically just named SU I instead
Systemax finesse you other taper fruit
that you can have as debugging
so there's no binary here if you have it
data local prop
any the following here just keep these
mind
when you start up a DB you'll have a
ratio
so two different two different kinds
every she can achieve
I'm if we wanted to hide
for example I most applications probably
95 percent the applications are a look
at
are only looking for evidence over
they're looking for superuser a PK
system and it is really dry some exploit
junk and a local town
or that s your binary I so one really
simple thing that I like to do on
devices
stick once I root them to a kind of hide
the root access from now where
from applications they're texting resist
name law
it whatever you want steeped in the
system expand directory
and down US-run
law right so messy just run law your
Excel
same exact thing out how
how are we gonna reviews devices on so
divided up into three kinds right
there's drive-by roots
Cesar the bad ones is the ones that an
attacker might use once they get
physical access to your device or
I'm some of them could be run from our
like a look at the
exes attack which could be run from our
and there's a user initiated routes that
require the user
to have physical access to the vice
probably interact with that during the
attack really explain they may be
difficult
taxi queue have a race condition or
something and then there's the data
wiping routes that we covered and
they're not particularly interesting so
drive-by device rates just a certain
with
I on a lost or stolen device
attacker could execute these to gain
access to your data caesar the really
bad ones these are the ones that we'd
like to prevent
on if if my phone gets lost
and it's locked the passcode I
I don't want someone to have access to
that data if one of these
roots exists on the device devices
vulnerable to want to be tried by roots
attacker could have access to my data I
sister be bootloader unlocks
obviously if you have a TV in a mold on
your device
it opens up a lot more attacks right so
that's a that's something that you can
do
to prevent some of these from becoming
drive-by roots
is have ADB disable
then we have the user initiates can't be
initiated by malware
users probably aware that his his or her
device is rooted
summer complex and and then summer
simple so
wall will require the devices on stage
using one of these user roots
I data data wiping roots
we covered is
so what we've seen in in Android 4.0
as opposed to Android 2.2 X
to some extent three-point taxes much
there much difference
pretty landscapes I Android 4.0
added a lot of protections I on device
encryption SLR
doubt I'm not an expert these I just
know it makes it hard to explain the
device
I much much harder to write local
exploits
so we used to see a time right have you
familiar with the server rush dinner
break rage against the cage there's a
million of them right
I couldn't even fit them all in one
slide these were all the local privilege
escalation attacks on Android 2.2 X
I'm most of these could be tried by
roots
I is really kinda like a wild west
landscape
pose 4.0 i've seen one Android Open
Source
exploit it was really involved race
condition with
the backup utility I and I think
I saw this used to launch a
developer on lock to change here carry
ID code
lie to launch daylighting attack
so Free 4.0 impose 4.0 the landscape has
changed
quite a bit but devices come out and two
days later the root it sometimes two
hours later so
how how is that happening
so most serious is focusing on
oh %um components occurred oh %um
sandwich either the applications or the
low-level code that we talked about
before
and so will cover Exynos motor chopper
common and some OEM specific back doors
I'm where the the main ones was the is
ette hardcoded password which made the
news
give or up in arms about this
I'm LG as a as a similar
back door is not I remote back door
but it's less public so I got an LG
device here
and all try to rate it will tempt the
democrats too much
but and then we've got a CTD device with
a FTM
mode again these are all public I'm not
like dropping
trappings there it is fall water
so Exynos briefly I it's a
Exynos chipset is a arm-based
system-on-a-chip manufactured by Samsung
which means Samsung is responsible for
the driver component to interact with
the hardware abstraction layer
right on their adding that coat on top
of the Android Open Source project
so the issue the very bottom you can see
here's
out I the second command I issue is
sound
just listen out the Exynos memory dad
I its rewrite for everybody
and the mistake that Samsung made is
that that gave you rewrite access to all
physical memory
so there it it's pretty simple
find a memory location you wanna write
to
rights to it and get through I
Exynos abuse a PK by the 16-member our
and a patch is the issue changes the
permissions
once you have route to this to the Top
Gear publisher first these
I so that other applications can't
explain it
but the real patch had to come from from
the kernel patch from Sams
the other interesting one that affected
a ton of devices
I should mention action us for Samsung
only and it affected
most have their the line all the all the
devices with these accidents processors
I'm moto chopper also affected
on a device it was called murder trial
for assume for a
Motorola I'm it turns out it affects
Samsung Motorola hallway
this device here using motor chopper
so he Dan Rosenberg from azinger does
tons of awesome Android security
research
you found in arm trusts own exploit on
hot the bootloader
I'm and then and then if your room
binary
through a simple I it doesn't take a few
minutes it takes like a second
when you reboot the device you have
roots in this is potentially something
that I malicious application could run
on the device and then just wait for the
user to rebuild it
or send a reboot command once it as
I'm so anything with this Qualcomm
chipset on that relies on
trusts on a smaller bolt-on chopper so
again
this is not an Android Open Source
project components
this is a Qualcomm concurrent excuse me
Qualcomm component
I soul all time the democrats will try
to rate this old
device but pretty briefly
someone posted this on line sounds like
that can't be true
up so I pulled off a DVD intrude and Ida
I think echoes China
and she says that look at st. car je
secured
like okay so look at it and strings
truly briefly hi it's not our back door
it doesn't mean that LG has accessed
your device
up and it just gives you a a real a TV
show
so I opened a DVD and Ida %ah
went to the string cross referencing you
see here tries to read
this file sticker GE Security and you
know without being a somewhere expert
three dollars assembly is here
check LG official enable root so me that
file has something to do with through
so you
this is gonna be treated
make sure not rated
so
so I just touch that file right there's
nothing in it it's not just a
or note on the desk so
now on the device itself all I'm doing
is
what am i doing developer options
the camera scan on forget turn off USB
debugging
wait a second turn it back on
yes return
so
as super simple and thats LG devices
only
on see
backed here
ID's
okay so this is my little backup slide
you pretty much just follow the
directions you get a real so
this could have hidden route is not so
bad but
like two days ago once a finished
preparing for the stock someone
K case released el cheapo
I which is a race condition in an LG
specific backup app
I it's locally exploitable armani says
that in some cases it can be a drive-by
read it could be something that could be
used by Mauer
so this one is much worse right I'm in
effect forty-plus
Lt devices so between this moto chopper
and Exynos you've probably got ninety
percent of the smart phones out there
covered
right ninety percent of the popular
devices I
this morning really took the democrats
on so
I've got busy T device I'm just going
to you cover a a a soft linking
abilities this was a really common one
maybe six months ago we're seeing time's
a
devices being reverse engineered and
then the initialization scripts kinda
exploited through some links
so when the device person actualization
script will go through
and Sep permissions on particular folder
so one folder is
data local town I'm slashed a to slash
local slashed him
and your foal for write access into that
folder
so it wants to give you write access one
when it boots so will try to exploit
I oh so the first part
this route the devices of
I'm just gonna booted into FTM which is
there engineering so
picture is still the device for you lose
it i turn it off
when i turn it on volume down and power
I'll just take in a minute so
the way that it should work you should
not have right or execute accessing data
local
the way it works
in FTM road however okay now you can see
it just as FTM
just like on the slide
so
a so you can see
I you should not have access to data
local you do an FTM
I their allies
like that so from here it's it's pretty
simple
apps its actually here
so we're just gonna linked data
with data local way
up
just gonna make a backup my data local
town okay
now now we're gonna link data with data
local temp so that when that
initialization script goes
we're gonna get write access to slash
aid
and what is what is located in slash
data that we looked at before
so that local that prop
file which controls whether the devices
return
right alright so
3 the device now old is taking a minute
and we're gonna reboot into a standard
Android
not doing the FTM stuff anymore on
so there's two issues here the first is
that the unit script doesn't check if
if it's a symlink before it SATs I
rewrite execute permissions on data
local time
and then the second issue is FTM this
can pretty much undermine any security
that you set on the device and this is a
custom 00 a.m.
component on top of the Android Open
Source project
right so
its weird ice pack
okay
so now we'll just a
was
echo $this- R O Connell cue you to
data local up
and now show
apps yeah so we're
we didn't have before but now we have
read/write access to slash data
and you can see up the contents of local
prop apps
we did
did I miss something
0 thanks okay so it's fine
hey rival will reboot it
I'll take in a minute
and then that local profile will get
will get red the device its
and we should every
its the survey spirits particularly
slowly
we go
another thanks yes
a okay so I mean I get this morning
kicked off
before I talk about it go because it
takes a little while
what I'm going to do
is use a tool that all describe it a
little bit
onto on it this this while a device to
show
I some entry points into some the
default applications so
you'll just have to trust me that I will
explain it but I'm gonna kick it off now
so we can go
full of absentee compile them what we're
talking about the rest the stuff
keep you from the bar any longer so
to a we're going to
get the PK's going to filter we want all
the ones
better OEM specific call okay so it's
going through its gonna get them in its
gonna do you compile them
and we'll talk about other stuff okay so
beyond rude recovered some ways to root
devices using OEM components now we're
gonna cover some with the
default applications that are installed
by OEM so
we covered the bottom where the OEM
sandwich will look at the top layer
I'll give you a little bit a background
on
Android applications how me before
Android developers are no
everything is as on the slide okay we're
gonna go over the whole thing the soho
for he was 54 applications turn your
sleep cool Android manager job
hi right supported and he's got all the
applications
how sir hope
applications have and points to
communicate with each other
and sometimes for for inter-process
communication right I'm
an app wants to launch another part of
an app us or use these
and points user declared in a file
called Android manifest %uh tax and now
which is packaged with every Android
application Android applications are
dot a PK file such with the tools doing
the background
polling of the ones I was following in
their class name
I mean it's going to be compiled %uh
so we're gonna look at four content
providers
activities services and receivers and
they all have
distinct functionality will cover how to
attack
i'm ok at permission leakage a review
for dove permission leakage have seen it
in the news
on okay is currently dois
six months or a year ago when couples
are discovering that
is applications that are installed on
your device have permissions that you
never granted to them because they came
pre-installed and you can't uninstall
them
I and they could potentially have
unprotected on points that attackers
could exploit kinda the
high-level overview this and then we'll
look at share you ladies
has some the default applications share
you ID's kinda undermine Android
security model
I so activity services
and receivers are activated via these
things called and text messages which is
just
the Android OS messaging system they
pass from app to app
and they launch various components on
these three and points or launch
via in 10 messages they can be sent from
app to app or they can be sent the ATP
so that's what the stools going to do
spit out a way for you to
interact with each one of these and
points using the Android
II activity manager a.m. I
says what it looks like in intent filter
declared an Android manifest that we
talked about before this one's for
flashlight test
you can see the activity activity is
just like a screen
I'm and then the intent filter so effin
intent
down there a TV show a.m. activity
manager start
give it the the right component names
it it will hit this code so you can and
to compile the application and look and
see it
the actual code it's heading I
so content providers are different kind
of the other three
their handle into a database
you can access them via contents colon
slash slash
they specify an authority for access I
mean you can access
table after the authority
activities on makeup and applications
you I
when you so you open up your email
that's one activity then you click an
email message it opens up a new activity
in your reply
opens up a new activity every time you
hit back it closes one activity
activities I can be declared in the
Android manifest
and they can have intent filters as
my doing here and they can have intent
filters as
as child objects and and they can be
launched be in 10 messages
%uh services or processes that run
detached
from the main at their point is not to
not to block the main Android thread
they can also contain intent filters and
can be launched at way from
the command line or from another
application and then receivers
are pretty interesting day
they can also contain for intent filters
so there's last three that were covered
before can all be launched
the 10 messages
I see have some general protections for
the iOS Android and
points you can have a permission on your
Android manifest which specifies who's
allowed
to interact with that application II you
can create permissions and then you can
specifier protection level so if you say
dangerous if a nap requests your
permission
user gets I guess all notification that
app is requesting dangerous permission
or you can say signature or system which
is always
what what would recommend so that allows
only applications and system app up
or with the shared signatures so I
create two APs
and I create a permission this says
protection level signature or system
my abs can talk to each other but nobody
else can talk to them
I you can also set to all your
activities and services receivers
to be exploring the false false which
means your application can access them
I'm so one could one portion of the
application can access another portion
I'm but nobody else can access them
because they're not exported
so post 4.2 it's a little bit different
story
34.2 this was a big issue because if you
have an activity
with intent filter I under its
automatically exported
I everything's exported false by default
have intent filter it gets exported so
think people didn't totally realize that
suppose 4.2 its always false unless you
explicitly say
export people's true
I content providers
here you can specify a little bit more
granular you can specify
read and right eyes to separate
permission so people can read the
database
know if you have another permission you
can right base
and you can also sex for you was false
for these activities same story
Center permission honor and said export
it equals false
I services same thing
receivers a little bit different I any
app can register a broadcast receiver
and then it's up to whoever sends that
broadcast message
to specify the permission required
from the receiver so the permission that
the receiver needs to have in order to
access that broadcast message
I'm million said export it was false on
the receivers
okay so there's a there's a major
problem %ah
with the preloaded applications and
there's two layers of these preloaded
applications you have
applications that the OEM is loading you
have the applications that and I know is
loading
so by the time your Android device
actually gets to you
if it's not one of the Nexus devices or
running pure Android
it looks like Java hi as two layers
pre-installed apps I'm and then they're
installed with the
default permissions that that the user
never went through
accepted so
%uh permission leakage will cover like a
made-up
example in a real-world example us to
say you have a weather application a
request location permission
its its pre installed on the device it's
granted location for missions
and then it exports a content provider
and activity
all because it has no permissions on the
content provider and the activity
I has the potential to to be exploited
or to leak
I location data you can see that path it
can get location data and then it
exports sections ovitz code to be
interacted with by other applications
I'm so potential to for daily catch
their
I October last year
i Thomas can release to Android SMS for
is a real-world permission leakage I
and it was actually on a on Android Open
Source project application
so it exported this SMS receiver service
with no permissions are sections
so any app could send an intense message
to that receiver
I and it looked just like you receiving
an SMS message so
those kinda social engineering thing you
can get the user to act on
fake SMS message that they had received
I so put together a tool to kinda expose
these endpoints
I meant to look at at and rain and and
points
with no permissions and no protections
and I made a mistake one of my coworkers
tool say a name that the manifest
analyzer
I and/or fast
so it it parses Android manifest files
into objects like
you saw their accent now XML files
on FB I top-level tag has a permission
all the maximal children should inherit
that permission
I'm so it's an object-based up parser
and it its
the the point if it is kinda give you a
quick way
to assess I O M applications on a device
and access various unprotected
components I
and kinda give you a place to to delve
deeper
so for this thing ran about cool
that so you so they come in the nation
whose is this
I so it it so it launches a an office
does it take get
anything with WoW and the title it goes
through
and fines despair
if fines a all the unprotected
activities
on this device it taunt it's not usually
this many
I and all the hidden codes
so the pound town codes on you guys
remember the Samsung
vulnerability that would that will allow
you to wipe someone's device
so if find stuff like that
%uh so it'll it'll go through each
manifest manifest manifest
and then I'll give you a summary at the
end so there are no unprotected content
providers
there's lots of hidden codes and now
what's
news so does that work
the flashlight so
then we can just office in the other
window cuz the
I Sisto connected conscious activity
it pops up a screen says flashlight test
they really can turn on the flashlight
so there's there's more malicious are
ways to use this
you sometimes find engineering menus
lotto water a interesting hidden menus
are exported as activities
K it looks forty by the wall
applications
%uh and then it shows all the
applications which
share you I D which right now it's just
looking for applications which request
sharing the I Android system you I D
so I I'm really not sure why
some of these need the system you i'd
which which undermines the
Android security morrow little bit
because any application with the same
you I D
can access I data from other
applications with the same you I D
on and it it gets the same permissions
so if you were to exploit one of these
applications
and you have the permissions %uh the
system you I T
%uh sir kinda ads unnecessary
attack actor so look at some other
things
the school found or
I also the content providers
so Iran on this LG device and I found
this unprotected LG email content
providers so
in the manifest it looks like this you
can see and explore it was true
and then you can access the the content
provider from there
II services which are not
particularly interesting except here I
is again on this while a device I think
one of the ones that came up before
their
it's a copy file service she could then
launch that service from the command
line you could maybe files that are
added some extra strings
I'm you can reverse the application and
figure out what it's doing with
a with the extra strings that it takes
I unprotected activities
so we saw one we saw the flashlight 1
here's one for
I listing files local file activity
so this one is so to
to to compile the application look at it
and indexes are
you can see actually where receives the
in 10 message and it looks for
extra strain called past I
and passes out of so
you can see if if we launch it with the
same thing that I an office
spit out and then dash dash yes we're
just exercising
say half given a pass I'm
starts up that text messages received by
the application and processed and it
gives us
activity which lists that portion the
filesystem
so has a preparing for this
as other courts lab had given a talk
that that picked solely on samsung
and they found a great example
unprotected
receiver so I asked them in with their
permission
showing example because it's so cool so
did the same thing I'm missus
like me recreating it they found
a a place in the application
where the input is controlled by an
intense message and it says
do shell command and launches a shell
with a pram streak
I so if you're on Sat
you just give it an escape
you can you can run any shell command
that you want
by launching in 10 message this is
something that Mauer could do
something you can do from the command
line and you can see here we launch the
intent
and just cat that filing you can see
just ran ID
been put out put into that file so this
could be used to
download malicious files to launch an
exploit
to do really anything
sithole in summary so has the
LG backup program we looked at some app
stores
have some on their ability or bug report
pending that can talk about yet
I don't worry im from it toll-free at
Penn
the wheel annoyed Picard says why would
you do that
using Google Play App Store use Android
wifi hotspot
top told him for in a wifi connection
manager backup programs
keep the app's that are loaded on the
device to a minimum
so example App Store issues
if you have a third-party application
store as well as the default app some
advice
you can't run it securely because of how
Android is set up
I you have to either check this box
that lets unknown sources I but you
could stall
II applications that your operating
system doesn't recognize the signature
for
so I could be something that you've
signed or or someone else assign
I think that's how the Amazon app store
works
or you have to do this workaround and
have
and ringtone extra not unknown source so
what that says
is if you include it with the intent
messages
don't treat this application install
request as if it were coming from an
unknown source
treated as if it were coming from this
application that launched the intent
so if that's an App Store not fringe
system trusts the App Store
by extension the operating system truss
anything that the App Store wants to
install
I that combines with you need ssl/tls
for your App Store in transit otherwise
application can be modified on the way
who knows what could be added to it and
then it would be
trusted by the fall and install because
you're bypassing the signature checking
also bad things can happen
%uh we saw that long lists about the
cations were shared you ID's
shared system UMTS societies are under a
thousand
no applications should use the system
you ideas because they should be
requesting individual permissions
its all time I'm so an office at it and
I
nuit checking a
a commissioner for OEM applications that
have shared system you ID can
undermine the security model allows
access to the existing permissions for
that user
for that user ID I shares data and it
gives you the same you ideas
an existing processes models the sandbox
okay to the bar the wrap-up
the Android Open Source project can
really add whatever it wants whatever
exploit Prevention's whatever encryption
or security but until
oh %um start paying attention to
security on the applications that
they're loading onto the device
and the drivers that they're writing for
device I
devices will continue to be rooted
within hours have coming out and you'll
see
exploits which affect entire classes of
up devices so what the OEM's can do
all course is not possible to not modify
the Android Open Source project everyone
needs their special brand and running on
the device
I thing you can do is pass former
abilities and deploy
patches quickly I'm on those few
applications as possible I don't need
roller coaster tycoon on my phone
in a place where I can't uninstall it I
top reinvent the wheel I and they don't
share user ID
a system ID's unless it's absolutely
necessary
on there's no reason to kinda work
around the sandbox
and then this would be like a dream come
true
dole put pre-installed applications in a
read-only file system
so the user can assaulting without
rooting the device
but them in data app were all the other
happy applications go that can be
uninstalled by the user
and last year's a use a lot loader
don't don't allow it an attacker to run
unsigned code
on my device what the mobile network
operators are kinda the man in the
middle here
what they can do they can vet
applications that are pre-loaded
I'm they can ask though %um not to
preload applications
they can help the OEM's push out Patch's
quickly once those vulnerabilities are
discovered
they can mandate the latest software
version is the latest Android
the latest fixes on whatever
applications though %um has
and they can not reinvent the wheel
we saw okay what you can do
so actually I deviance toppers /a
perfect I
overshoot this line his whole talk was
the slide
I annual really into great detail
you can install CyanogenMod I
barring that you can keep your device up
today when those annoying pop-ups come
up that say we're gonna need an hour
your device and then we're gonna rebuild
at the end you could lose some data
you have to do it you care for
downloading from marketplace's
use Google Play which is I using
signature check
not trying to work around it don't you
root your device if you have to I'm
written and hide
ru like we were never before
a don't don't disable bootloader code
signature checks they're there for a
reason
and check permissions when you're
installing applications and checked them
on the
pre-installed applications
so we'd like to see an Android 4.3 is a
Google controlled secure
chain kinda like the windows 8 model
native support for hardware so you can
just build
the Android Open Source project and
deploy it without room for
oh %um mistakes reading drivers
and then the ability to revoke
application permissions: which
which TV uncovered I've we could granule
early
revoke application for missions or spoof
the information
on that they're getting back like GPS
I'll
that that would be a dream come true so
I posted my tool here
I I war continue making updates to it
probably over the next month in Gravette
now if anyone wants to contribute to the
repository or shoot me an email with
features you'd like to see so the Angola
South kinda an API that anyone can just
important as a Python library
and then use it to to parse through your
manifest file
I is my Twitter and retweet very much a
few
feel free to tweet at me a and I G is
higher
so thanks a lot for listening enjoy the
open bar integral bitterly
is checked them on the pre-installed
applications
so we'd like to see an Android 4.3 is a
Google controlled secure
chain kinda like the windows 8 model
native support for hardware so you can
just build
the Android Open Source project and
deploy it without room
for oh %um mistakes reading drivers I'm
and then the ability to revoke
application permissions: which
which TV and covered I've we could
granule early
revoke application for missions or spoof
the information
I'm that they're getting back like GPS
%ah
that that would be a dream come true so
I posted my tool here
I I war continue making updates to it
probably over the next month grab it now
if anyone wants to contribute to the
repository or shoot me an email with
features you'd like to see though the
angolans have kind of an API that anyone
can just important as a Python library
and then use it to to parse through
manifest file
I is my Twitter I don't tweet very much
a few
feel free to tweet at me a and I G is
higher
so thanks a lot for listening enjoy the
open bar integral bitterly
is