okay well thanks Jason
my name's jury Brianna from Microsoft I
may 6 senior security strategist with
the Microsoft Security Response Center
I'll
someone you may know what am i calling
for name is Katie Saurus
and she's 1/2 for the team that I'm on
their
kinda runs programs for outreach to the
security researcher community
last week we announced
new bounty programs this is kind of a
new area for Microsoft
but are very programs our little bit
different
then what you might be used to seeing
out there today
soda to give an idea we have three
different programs that we announced
one is called the mitigation bypass
mounting a
and I'll talk a little bit more details
about each one of these a but this is
basically up two hundred thousand
dollars for
a novel medication bypass about the blue
had known as for defense is an
additional fifty thousand dollars for
I'll basically defenses a
defensive ideas related to the
mitigation bypasses in the
the the first program and then the third
one is
a the IEEE 11 preview but downey
which will run for about 30 days
as two days ago a and I'll talk a little
bit more about it or the so
the medication bypass banning basically
we're looking for holes in the shield so
these are platform wide a medications
that we're looking at that this'll are
things like that
I'll basically if you can
you to figure out how to exploit that
way bypasses medications
I'll and provide us with enough details
would give you up two hundred thousand
dollars
for that particular issue so
this program is not a one-time only
program this is a
an ongoing program so a it's not a
contest at all I think
I'll one one %uh the gentleman out here
mentioned earlier that
we were running a contest that black hat
for how to
be emit that's not quite true basically
the thing we're doing at Black Cat
is if if you have a mitigation bypassing
you want to bring it
two are both the black hat we will be
doing live point if you got it there and
paying out
hundred thousand dollars or probably not
right
by cap shortly after so
the a blue hat for defense a has
everybody in the room
heard over blue have prize contest that
we ran over the last couple years
this was a a defensive contest we
awarded over 250,000 dollars last year
black hat a four defensive technology
%uh so that was like a one-time-only
contest this is kind of an ex
the continuation of that so this goes
kinda hand in hand with the mitigation
bypassed founding
where a if you you know discover way to
bypass or medications and you can also
supply
a a an effective defense for that
there's an additional there's a
possibility for an additional fifty
thousand dollars
for for that now
the I 11 preview bug bounty so
again this this will run for 30 days
as I love the release of the preview
which was two days ago on
on the 26 and the reason why
we're running this during the beta
period is there are quite a few
a brokerage houses that will buy your
exploits
and you know eventually share those with
the vendors
such as Microsoft and a we're not trying
to
you know really enter in that space but
know those vendors actually
offer any sort of brownies for programs
in the bay the state so
you can see on the chart here the light
gray color this represents
I'll I intenso on the left hand side you
can see
the bug reports that we got externally
while the program is in beta
and as soon as we shifted we got a sharp
enclose increase a bug reports from
external researchers so basically
because nobody's getting paid
a to report bugs turn a beta period
there you know hang onto them until
after we release the product
and then we we get the reports they get
paid that can think so what we're trying
to do here is
encourage people to report bugs during
beta so that we can fix them
before what's the product so this will
only go for about 30 days
I so few are doing in kinda research on
Internet Explorer
the you can go download the when does a
point one preview
along with I 11 and start coming for
bucks
so just so kinda re recap this
the barony for I 11 preview only runs
for
30 days I'll and hopefully by black cat
will
will start to build a up release
information on how many bugs with
we're getting to that program again a
few
wanna come to the booth I think we're
going to be
running the contest not the conscious
but a
anybody who wants to demonstrate an
exploit at our booth
during the lunch hour black each day
so obviously there's a there's a lot
love kinda
rules to the program a so if you want to
find out more
got a Microsoft dot com slash spending
programs there you can
find all the rules for each one of these
programs and how
how to engage with them also a
loss at TechNet dot com slash blue hat
I think we're missing an ass there it
should be blogs
tech meetup com a we made a blog post
they're talking about
why we're doing this and white now if
you have this kind of questions I'll
follow us on Twitter
I'll at Katy Moeller is the basically
she's the owner the program so
if you wanna hit her up on Twitter a
she's a good
contact to ask questions too so again
join us
have anybody gonna black cat one
to okay so hopefully you guys wanna come
by
around lunchtime to the Microsoft booth
and
see what happens there so I'll be around
if you have any
followup questions for me without I
think I'll give some time back