so good morning thank you for coming to
Amsterdam thank you for coming to
besides this is our attempt to put
together the first b-sides and Amsterdam
it's been a long run we try to organize
it the best way possible I don't know if
we are achieved all our goals for the
first year but it was like a sort better
version of the event I we really really
hope that you enjoy the day so please
make sure that you follow the account of
besides Amsterdam on Twitter this is
where we're gonna be posting stuff about
the event is where we're gonna be making
every tweets and things like that the
you should have access to the new Wi-Fi
it's for everybody and some sort
introductions basically these are the
people that had to work together in
order to make this thing possible of
course as you know besides events are a
community event so if any of you or your
friends or your colleagues want to help
out next year to be part of the team to
put this thing together to expand it to
make it better if you have any more
ideas of how you can make it even
greater and enjoyable for people please
come forward it's a community thing we
would love to hear from you of course it
wouldn't be possible without our
sponsors so the Lord came forward
helping us becoming the platform so in
order to put this event together and for
you to be able to be here without paying
anything basically our gold sponsors 12
second security fie security companies
again we will thank we thank them very
much for helping us and put the
conference together and sensimilla
you'll know sons they're out there go
talk to them about certifications and
training again thank you so much for
supporting the event and being here for
us we couldn't be doing it without the
support of for us the room next door is
full with workshop from all Aspen talks
and practical stuff so you can jump in
and off go what's the talks or you know
we feel free to it - enjoy your day
basically these are community sponsors
and
besides organization besides London
actually we have Thomas with us today
who is actually the organizer of the
besides London event
besides Manchester O'Reilly besides
Athens which is also running as well and
if you want to go to Athens next year in
the summer holidays or whatever we will
glad to have you there and peer list
where you can find a lot of formation
about the information security or you
can write your own stuff if you have
stuff to share is really really a good
place to to network with like-minded
individuals all right Lee we're very
kind and they gave us this link
basically it's besides Amsterdam link
where you can download for free a
security you can choose which security
and ebook you want to download so if you
take a picture of that and you visit our
webpage basically you will be able to
download an e-book from them for free
which is really really nice of them for
doing that no post on Twitter we don't
worry every the whole world aboard
aboard aboard the truck schedule because
we didn't want to waste paper basically
it's on this link so if you go to this
link make sure you have this last the
forward slash at the end basically the
URL slash the tracks and slash you'll
find the track schedule so you can you
know well you're gonna go when you want
to visit the talk what the Motoko is
some rules of the game basically respect
each other there is a code of ethics on
the website you know we want to make
sure that everybody is having a good
time talk to each other there are so
many like-minded individuals in the room
they're here to learn and network so you
know don't besides just we're here to
have a good day we really really hope
that you have a good day so please yes
network and talk with each other
um mute your devices if you haven't done
so please did now
be professional don't use the
infrastructure so the Wi-Fi it's at
hours so we don't try to do any you know
cool trick with Wi-Fi or anything like
that
yes we know that you can't button please
don't do it so respect to bang you the
Wi-Fi keep keeps things tidy and there
are no any fire alarm scheduled for
today so if you hear any sirens or
something going on please don't use the
elevator just you know go out the stairs
and please go out and you know guard the
front simple as that
don't wait to push your code in github
or anything like that just you know go
out of the building and that's about it
welcome to besides this is the password
for the Wi-Fi and I really really hope
that you have an enjoyable a really
memorable day thank you so much for
being here
[Applause]