thank you for attending my talk this is
going to be a two-hour talk so thank you
for giving me extra time
so 75% of the talk would be about
ransomware and IOT 25% would be all
about me so this was me when I started
in the industry I had long hair now it's
gone so currently I'm with RSA I'm the
resident principal malware scientist and
before that I was with Trend Micro have
secure and damballa which is a company
founded by Georgia Tech in Atlanta and
if you can follow me at twitter and i'm
also an author of two books my written
botnets advanced malware analysis third
book advanced reverse engineering
hopefully would come in the next couple
of years and I'm also a co-author of the
second edition of hacking exposed mother
in with kids if you buy those books all
proceeds go to my two kids five to nine
college fund so please buy them all
right so one thing I learned every time
I present is that if you tell it as a
story people won't fall asleep and I've
had people fall asleep on my
presentation so hopefully nobody will
fall asleep today so one day a guy named
Sam got an email at work by the way I'll
go fast so please reserve your questions
at the end and then this is what he got
so he saw this and he was saying you
know what this is very suspicious since
Sam went through education user
education training he was able to say
you know what I learned this I'll take a
look at this email and see what that
attachment is all about so the
attachment is a zip file but then when
you save it extract it it actually looks
like this so it's not what the email was
saying but since Sam was trained he was
able to recognize this and he said oh
it's an HT a file and according to the
all-knowing Wikipedia
an HD file is an HTML executable file
introduced in 1999 I was born in 1999
same with Internet Explorer 5 executed
by MSHDA that exe and so he was saying
you know what I can take care of this I
can look at this I don't need to involve
any of our security team so what he did
he he was looking through the code so
what I'm about to explain here sometimes
it works on HD files sometimes it
doesn't so I learned this through trial
and error so I'm going to go through it
in a couple of minutes but you should
even I did this with trial and error
took me like a couple of days so what I
usually do when it when it or not me Sam
what Sam did was so he went through the
code and usually you would go to the end
and then you'll see some variable
declarations and then you just choose
one so here you see this I highlighted
it and you could see here X key so for
me it's all for Sam it means it's
probably an X or key so you keep that
for now and then you look some more if
you look at an if statement or any
conditional statement just get the first
variable that's there
search for it and you'll end up with a
function call and usually that function
call look for the variable in it usually
it's at the end sometimes it's just this
variable sometimes there's a plus
another variable or plus character
copy that look for it again and then we
see it at the end and then what you do
with that variable is you alert on it so
you add this command line of code after
the function and when you run the HT a
file you will see something like this it
will show you the domain where it's
downloading all of the malware or
ransomware or whatever bad things it
wants to download in your system so the
good thing about this is that you're not
running it you're not downloading the
malware
it's just displaying where it comes from
which is fairly safe so like for me in
my humble opinion it's safe to run this
in the production network but of course
don't run it in the production network
still run it in your own isolated
Network so for that specific example
these were the URLs that were revealed
so you don't need to actually run the
malware in a sandbox or run it anywhere
in your test machine you just get this
file here and then you'll get the
malware sample and then you'll be able
to analyze it so that's easier said than
done right because once you get the
Malheur sample directly from those
domains it's going to be encrypted so so
they designed it that way so that if
somebody tries to scrapes malware
samples from the Internet it would be
hard for you to analyze it because it
would be encrypted that's where the X or
T comes from
so it just accelerated with that with
the X or T that I showed in the HDL and
then you'll have the executable and then
you can analyze it they did it that way
to avoid any scraping from researchers
so that if ever those samples get
scraped it will be hard for them to
analyze it so what happens in the host
it downloads file to temp folder it's
encrypted so if you don't have the XOR
key you need to download it you need to
let it work so that you'll be able to
get the malware sample but what usually
happens is that once it downloads it to
the temp folder it's encrypted it writes
it to the idea to a DLL Exe file and
decrypt it using that key which is
converted into a 32 byte exit decimal so
if you visit my blog in ours a website
you'll see there how malware and
ransomware uses temp folder so what it
does it downloads there the encrypted
file it uses the key from the HDA file
the crip set and then write it to a dll
or an exe file injects it or just copies
itself to a different folder where it
gets executed every time the system is
rebooted
or after the installation control is
faster that malware and now it's active
in your system
alright so Sam was so happy he said you
know what I was able to solve it I don't
even need to involve our security team
my training work I can ask my employer
for another six thousand dollars worth
of training in sans because I just
proved to them that I was able to solve
this problem but of course like every
millennial like us
it didn't happen unless you post it in
facebook right so the next thing he did
is he wanted to post it in facebook but
then when he logged on to his Facebook
page he saw this message so one of his
friends send him a message
it's not actually a message but it's an
SVG file so he clicked on the picture
and this is what he saw like it went a
YouTube site you'll definitely know it's
fake I'm sorry the pictures not as clear
but the URL is not youtube.com so you
know already it's fake that's it's
downloading an extension so he was
saying I know this I've gone through
training I know how to solve this and he
looked at the the details of that
extension and as you will see it's
something that really not trustworthy
the attackers didn't even spend enough
time to make it as believable as they
can so most of us here in the room would
say you know what yeah everybody knows
that this is easy to spot but for
non-technical users like our aunts
grandmas moms dads some of them still
get fooled like this how many of you got
a text message from your relatives
saying hey you know what I think I can
pay for our vacation next summer because
I just met this Nigerian prince and he
said I just need to give him this money
and then he'll give me this amount of
money so he was saying you know what I
need to examine this SVG file so what is
an SVG file according to Wikipedia it's
a scalable vector graphics file it's XML
based and it's introduced in 99
again the year I was born and the thing
about it when you open that SVG file
it's actually a red dot so that tells me
I'm just guessing here I'm not so sure
if that's what really the attackers
wanted to convey it's like a target so
if you see a red dot it's usually a
bull's eye it's usually a target so it's
just like saying you know what you got
this picture now you're marked and when
you look at it it has it has a script in
it and using the same methodology that
we use in the HTA file
we're in look at the end you look at the
function and you look at the variable
like for this one I just tried alerting
on the different variables here until I
found one that actually would display
this
so it's an SVG file that points you here
which is actually the fake YouTube
website that downloads the extension for
you so again he was so happy and he said
you know what I'm really an expert I was
able to solve two targets that were
headed my way so I think I am the man
and that's it hope you guys learned
something today
but nobody's clapping so but wait
there's more I think I still have a few
more minutes so let's discuss some more
by the way our IP to this guy's one of
the greatest sellers on TV so he got a
snail mail from Grandma
of course everybody loves grandma right
if your mom says no to you you just go
to your grandma and your grandma say yes
like I remember when I was younger
oh there's this new a Nintendo
Entertainment System and my grandma
doesn't know what it is I just told her
yeah just give me 60 bucks and then
you'll know what it is so usually
grandmas will just say yes yes to
everything
so usually doesn't get anything from
Grandma but this time he got a mail and
this grandma actually needs help on
something so he said you know what
my grandma's been kind to me when I was
a little kid I'll go save grandma so he
went to Grandma's house and then he saw
this on grandma's computer so everybody
knows this is sir burr by the way when I
made this presentation server was the
talk of the town you cannot go anywhere
without anybody asking you about server
so when you got infected by a ransomware
this is funny because some people would
say I need you to detect ransomware on
my system and I usually tell them you'll
know when you have brand somewhere
because it will announce itself it will
play it will play a like a narration
saying your hat you've been victimized
and you have to pay this amount of money
so once it's in your system usually it's
already too late so this is what he got
and since he has some experiences with
HP a file
Sam was taking this with a grain of salt
but still he was reading all of the
instructions here and one thing he
noticed is that when you look at this
it's actually really very helpful it
will help you pay for the ransomware and
of course everybody heard what Betty is
right
so acne petia changed the game of
ransomware because before petia like big
companies would actually pay for
something so that they could get their
data back but then they realized when
that they came they just got played they
paid for something they didn't get
anything back because petia was a
clearly wiper so it destroys her system
completely so he was looking at the
readme HDA it says here you know what if
this address doesn't work you can always
refresh this address right here so let's
say you're still thinking two days three
days from now you're still taking know
what okay I'll pay for this because
these files are important and then you
find out that this link doesn't work
anymore
if you just refresh it and then it'll
give you a new link and usually it says
here that the HDA file is
we don't cryptid files are not viruses
so the HD file it's saying it's not it's
not a malware but of course if it's
coming from a threat actor you always
take it with a grain of salt right so if
you're not sure what it is
make sure it's be careful all the time
so the good thing about server is that
it has a descriptor and again we played
around with this their customer service
is actually way way better than real
customer service how many of you talk to
your phone provider cable provider when
you have to wait a long period of time
on the phone 45 minutes to an hour send
them an email wait a week or so you
don't get a response but server they're
really very responsive because they
wanted to pay like you are their
customers so they want to make you happy
and then they're also very security
conscious so you have to prove you're
human when you're when you're contacting
them or want to talk to them and then
they offer you like a discounted rate
it's available in the next four days
twenty three hours and this is what I
was talking about the tech support if
you have problems and the good thing
about server is that it gives you the
opportunity to try before you buy like
it's a very proven thing when you want
to sell a product like in the US they
would say you know what you can buy this
if thirty days you're not happy can
return it some stores actually offer a
year some stores even offer a lifetime
but of course for them they they just
say you know what we'll give you the
opportunity to decipher one file so the
good thing about it is that when it
comes to grandma's computer she really
doesn't have any files on her computer
she only has one picture file because
most of her pictures are either on
albums or on the walls or on top of a
mantle of a fireplace
how many of you when you go to Grandma's
house is like a museum right you open
the door like tons of pictures there
pictures of your aunts your parents when
they were young and then you go upstairs
there's pictures lining up the wall
going up the stairs so all of the
pictures are there so Sam was saying
grandma it's good because you only have
one picture we don't need to pay for
anything we could just use this there
sample to decrypt your picture then you
don't need to pay for anything
so when it comes to decrypting it you
just upload it and then after a few
seconds couple of minutes you can
download the decrypted file it's awkward
there's a zip file and then open it so
this is what the decrypted picture file
looks like now this is my test JPEG file
as you can see I just put everything
like a aaaa there sorry this is the
encrypted file and this version of
observer only decrypts from the 648
position down so it only decrypts that
part and i know when it gets decrypted
it has to go back to a a a a a all the
time so the decrypted file looks like
this so the thing about not only server
but other ransomware when they decrypt
files they're actually putting it back
to its real previous state everything to
the last bit even to a date date created
date access date opened it puts it back
to how it was before it's better than
insurance company right so when you have
an insurance company they will say oh
when you get damaged we'll put it back
to how it was before but actually they
won't be able to do that but ransomware
they're able to do that they'll actually
return it back to the previous for it
was without so you won't even know that
something happened so
if you're a traveling executive you got
victimized by ransomware and he decided
to pay for it your boss wouldn't know
that you got victimized by ransomware
because everything would be back to
normal so he was saying grandma I'm just
curious what's that one picture you
don't want to us to see and you're not
even printing it it's just on your
desktop and this is the picture of
Grandma and Grandpa by the way they're
not my grandparents they're my
neighbor's grandparents so I had to
cover their faces so words of advice so
for us this is common sense but given my
experience with other clients and with
people that are not really that
technical but has access to things that
will enable malware to move laterally in
their organization this is still helpful
for them so don't just click on anything
if it's too good to be true chances are
it's not and back up regularly so most
user education usually starts with this
so for us it's already common sense but
for unfortunately for most people that
gets victimized it's not really common
for them so Sam was happy and he said
you know what it's late I need to go
home my girlfriend's waiting for me
she's a nightshift nurse so she's
probably waiting in my apartment so he
got home and he said you know what I
just want to relax and chill so I'm not
so sure if in Amsterdam that licks it in
chill is it's a thing I don't know what
it is so I just heard it yesterday so
and then I said you know what let's just
Netflix and chill let's put on the first
episode season 1 of Game of Thrones
where we see Khaleesi expose herself so
but then he said you know what nothing
is working it's like I wanted to relax
with my girlfriend I'm tired from
helping grandma and solving to malware
problems and nothing's working so he
tried other services he tried a
SoundCloud Spotify Twitter PayPal and
nothing was working everything was
unreachable and then as the day unfolds
Sam found out because of the outage
there was a botnet going around called
Mirai
it's a DDoS botnet and the signals or
the packets are not coming from your
regular desktop or PC or systems it's
coming from devices so what is Mariah so
it's a malware that infects IOT devices
for the purpose of using them in DDoS
attacks so it spreads by scanning IP
addresses to find vulnerable IOT devices
and when it comes to scanning IP
addresses it excludes IP ranges of
general electric HP the US Postal
Service Department of Defense and Ayana
I would understand they would skip DoD
but I'm not so sure why they would skip
the other companies here I'm not so sure
what that is but it's interesting and it
also uses a remote C&C to determine its
DDoS target so you could actually change
the target based on the see it based on
the command it gets from its CNC channel
and when you look at the code this is
the IP address exception list so if you
want to modify it if you're playing
around with it you don't want your
company you don't want your company to
catch you just put your IP your company
IP range there and then it would skip it
so how does the attack work so once it
finds vulnerable IT devices it brute
forces its way into accessing it via a
list of com
passwords and then once it infects an IT
device it makes sure it makes sure that
nobody can communicate with it by
closing ssh telnet and HTTP ports
it also looks for and removes another
IOT malware by the name of anime so the
good thing about analyzing malware is
that if it's a malware that is competing
with another malware chances are it
would have the code on how to remove
that malware which saves us time because
you don't need to reverse that other
other malware you just need to get the
code from the competing malware try it
out and if it works it works similar to
during the spy I and Zeus war during the
olden times so this is the least the
list of common passwords so I have all
of this because the Mirage source code
is already public so the good thing
about source code being public is that I
don't need to reverse it just read the
code but then of course it's it's a
double-edged sword if it's available
there somebody can improve it and
release a better version of it for their
own purposes so this one it's a honest
and pious the one that's claiming that
she's the author so senpai is at the
Japanese word for upperclassman usually
before sensei you become a senpai and
then when you're already an expert and
you're able to teach other other pupils
then you become a sensei so I'm not so
sure if there's another sensei on top of
her but for now this is what they're
claiming so since the source code was
public somebody took that code and
attacked Dyne so Dyne is an internet
infrastructure company within New
Hampshire and the first wave started at
7:00 a.m. Eastern
so that 7:00 a.m. in New York and in
Atlanta second wave around noon third
wave started around
p.m. so they were trying to do Netflix
and chill in the morning that's why they
want their not able to access any of the
services they want to access so all of
the traffic to dyn's internet directory
servers cause it to stop
so the ddos there for millions of IP
addresses or for millions of IP devices
so if you have a camera at home usually
when you look at it it says some cameras
have a default broadcast like for me I
have cameras at home it has default
broadcast I make sure I turn it off
because anybody that knows the IP
address of my camera can see what what
my camera see and I usually put my
camera in our guest bathroom so so Mira
what happened September 20 2016 krebs
website was DDoS
Mirai source code with me Diane was DDoS
and then after Dan was ddosed Oracle
bought Dyne
so it's a good business practice and
then Krebs identified the alleged moriah
author but of course in our world any
digital evidence can be faked so even
the source country can be faked
everything can be faked so for you to
not be a victim of Mirai
by the way mirror I just a new wave just
came out I think like a week ago or a
few days ago I haven't really looked
into it yet but it's still around so
change default username and password
disable the necessary remote access to
the IOT device if you just want your
phone or your desktop to access it make
sure it's the only device that can
access your IOT device device device
device and us-cert advisory I have it
here it's long I won't read it once you
have a copy of the slides you just go
through it so here it's a mouthful it's
long you have to memorize it so
and then Sam realize you know what
haven't been doing this just give me a
couple of minutes and I'll make sure I
put those practice into use
and then this is what he saw so this
might be the future you might have an IT
device that's victimized but by
ransomware and say you know what I won't
turn on your heater unless you pay me
this amount of money or oh I have
pictures of you in compromising
positions in your camera and I will sell
this if you don't pay me this amount of
money so Sam was saying this is going to
be a very long day the end oh by the way
any questions violent reactions yes sir
so you were talking about the the
ransomware and that they have this great
customer service and that they do
everything to get your money they help
you out a lot so what change with that
yeah
so with petia the thing about petty is
it's really not ransomware I term it as
a wiper because what it did at first it
it shows message that you need to pay
this or so that and your files have been
encrypted but then when you look at the
code itself
there's no decryption capability what it
does it it actually messes up your
Master Boot Record so once you get
infected by it if you don't have a
backup of it then you won't get your
files back and it actually this is from
the chatter from the underground it
happily messed up the other ransomware
operators and it made them mad because
now the customers are losing trust on
them because they're saying hey we have
this really nice business model and
pettier came and messed it all up now
how will the public trust us so that's
what they're saying
any other questions yeah thanks for your
talk
I was wondering you have been working
for several antivirus companies and I'm
by no means an malware expert but I was
wondering why have we as a as a
antivirus industry still not solved the
issue of well crypto lockers like we
have a lot of behavioral and heuristic
detection mechanism these days how come
that major antivirus systems like for
example McAfee Antivirus security still
has not been able to well detect most of
these these cryptographic operations and
readwrite instructions and those kind of
things in nowhere so it's not only a
cryptographic malware it's basically
malware in general so I had a
presentation before I call it the
malware Factory Korean I showed live how
easy it is to create a new generation of
malware and the thing about usually host
based systems they would rely on host
behavior they would monitor the
environment and if there are changes
they would use that as a signature and
the static signature of the Malheur file
itself and the thing about it is that if
you rely on signatures you can just
change one thing and then it would
totally be different so in my
presentation the malware Factory I
proved there that I just change one
thing and it's a totally new malware
again and we call it the green malware
made of 100% recycled malware so it's
the same thing no matter what even if
it's a cryptolocker or whatever they
just change something there they deploy
it and it becomes new again so right now
there's a movement when it got most host
security systems are using a machine
learning but of course were still far
off from achieving that there was a case
I won't say the names of the company
were in
researcher upload uploaded HelloWorld in
in virustotal
and some machine learning algorithm of
host based systems detected them as a
malware so right now when it comes to
detecting malware there's so many things
you have to insert their product in
which is why the presentation about the
kill chains earlier it's very helpful
because once it's already in the host it
means that your network defenses already
failed and if it's able to install
itself on the host then your endpoint
system has failed so unless we find a
new way of detecting malware that's not
signature based in a better AI or better
machine learning algorithm malware will
still try which means job security for
all of us I hope answered your question
yeah partly by the way when I started in
the industry we were only getting like
13 bytes from the malware code before it
was enough because it was just DOS
malware but then when Windows malware
became a reality everything changed a
very quick one um you know you talked
about you know the grandmother's that
you know looking at ransomware and you
know what to do and you get all these
people but they don't know how to use
their computer this is what they say at
the end of the day they know how to go
out buy Bitcoin and pay for the
ransomware so I don't see how this thing
to relate I mean yeah that's right they
can't they're they can't go out there
the mark the malware offers expect them
to go out buy bitcoins and pay them and
these people don't know how to open
facebook if it's down differently if you
either logged out for example so I
cannot see this is a little bit of a
philosophical question but I think yeah
something there that's having a very
good question so when it comes to
ransomware most of their targets are at
the big companies that have like
multi-million dollar IP on their system
and they have the capability to buy
bitcoins before
or there's a wave of I would say fake
ransomware scare we're actually had the
presentation about it I call it all your
Mac's are belong to us we're in their
targets are really like the
non-technical users they make it very
easy for you because they would even
have an instruction they're just got the
Walmart buy this card input your 16
digit card here or you can use your
credit card to pay for it which is
easier for most of our non-technical
relatives so it's easier to go to
Walmart or go to the Western Union
monogram and send money or I buy those
prepaid cards and like right now the AIA
there's a an IRS scam that's been going
around again it's an old scam but it's
funny because they would ask you for how
about you just pay me in iTunes card or
how about it just pay me in google play
cards and yep yep yeah which is which is
to like most unless you've been exposed
to this you wouldn't even know what a
Bitcoin is thank you guys thank you
[Applause]