good morning everybody again thanks for
for having me here first one of the day
and to ease you into today I'll start
with a not very technical talk or not
technical at all I guess titled what
have we really assumed breach and of
course I'll explain in a minute why I
chose that title first maybe short
introduction I'm Kevin
I work for a Deloitte as a February of
this year certainly a few months
basically focusing on what we call
security restoration so mainly helping
clients who are dealing with you know
the fallout of a large incident or
series red team or pen test findings and
trying to you know improve their
security very quickly and in the first
couple of months and then also get them
into a larger or usually larger
transformation project prior to joining
Deloitte I work for Fox IT for over
seven years doing Incident Response of
forensics so I basically saw a lot of
clients in the worst state you could
encounter them but it gives you a little
a lot of very interesting insights into
what could go wrong and and why it goes
wrong as well which is what I've also
worked into this talk a bit I guess so
I'm going to talk about assume breach
here today you're probably all familiar
with with the the mantra of assume
breach you know you basically assume
that your prevention measures in terms
of IT security are not going to keep out
attackers forever at some point they
will fail attackers will bypass it and
and enter your network your
infrastructure and possibly caused all
kinds of havoc so it's it's something
that you've been hearing for or for
years now in the security industry and
something that you hear a lot of
organizations claim that they're also
doing so they say yeah we're following
this this attitude of assume breach and
and
we worked it into our IT security and
what they usually tell you is you know
out of the Holy Trinity of prevent
detect respond they're not only doing
prevention anymore but they're moving a
lot of effort into detection mainly and
also effective response to to any stuff
day they detect or any breaches that
could potentially occur so following
this logic why am I here during this
talk if everybody already knows what
assume breaches and how you shoot you
should handle if you want to follow that
the train of thought it's because
there's still a lot of stuff that goes
wrong I think when organizations try to
work under the assumption of a breach
that could happen at any moment
so I mainly focus this talk around the
topic of detection and want to take you
through some of the things first that I
see usually go wrong in organizations
and then of course also hopefully
provide some sort of a solution a way of
thinking that could hopefully overcome a
lot of these issues so first thing that
you often see that goes wrong is the
scope of a lot of the detection
mechanisms in organizations so I mean
any larger organization these days we'll
probably have a seem insult and I'd have
run it themselves or have some third
party do it for them maybe they also
have IDs or other clever stuff running
in their infrastructure but what you
often see is that these systems get set
up and collect data just based on on
best effort or what's easy to collect or
what's easy to grab or whatever people
are familiar with so you know any
engineer will probably know about
Windows Event log so might be a logical
thing to start collecting data from
windows event locks and and build rules
around that and see if you can detect
any any anomalies or weird behavior in
that data set but it's not necessarily
what's the most useful part to to look
at in your infrastructure so there's
usually or there's often I should say no
link between the actual business process
and the type of data that gets collected
and analyzed in these detection measures
and then obviously you know just like
these binoculars she can only move them
around within certain limits but around
there there's all kinds of other stuff
that you might not be seeing and it's
it's basically an analogy for for what a
lot of detection measures do within
organizations another thing that you see
is that and and this is awfully
obviously a very hot topic right now in
InfoSec is it's you know having as much
as possible being performed by machines
so obviously we know the basic detection
stuff where you build rules and use
cases and and use it to detect anomalies
in in traffic or in logs and whatever
there's also big rise in in all kinds of
AI technology climbing to basically do
more than humans ever could I'm not I'm
not expert on the subject I should say
that but until it's it's really proven
technology I think the the human factor
in detection is really important so what
you see happen a lot is that detection
measures are put in place and every once
in a while maybe somebody adds some new
rules to D the rule base and and you
know ensures that some new things are
being picked up but it's not an active
feedback loop where there's also
analysts on a regular basis you know
going out doing manual threat hunts and
and trying to find that stuff based on
just their human expertise and a human
knowledge and also their knowledge
mainly of what drives the business and
how the business works and what kind of
applications and system support that
those processes so I think the feedback
loop between threat hunting which
usually results in in what you could
call good hunts useful stuff that you
find while doing the hunting that should
be converted into new use cases for your
detection mechanism right but that
doesn't happen a lot especially with
organizations having third parties doing
the the security monitoring for them you
see that this is is often lacking and it
means that you're you're not improving
as fast as you could I think third thing
that you you often see is what I would
call
monitoring in in a hostile environment
and it's not like the blue team you know
I guess arrest each day physically or
whatever but it's more like the
infrastructure is maybe not ready or
suitable for a very advanced detection
and this could be caused by a number of
reasons for example a very flat and and
unsegmented network so that there's a
lot of stuff going on in the same
central place so it's hard to to figure
out what's what or what belongs to what
or what correlates to other traffic
unstructured networks where all kinds of
different protocols and traffic are
crossing each other over over the same
physical lines maybe so it's really hard
to do decent detection if you don't have
a good overview of what flows where we
also see especially where you just
deploy for example IDs technology within
clients that there's still a lot of what
we call low-hanging fruit in the network
so very easy basic stuff that you know
botnet malware or something like that
that should already have been picked up
long ago and removed but it's still
there and obviously if there's a lot of
noise like that you're it's really hard
to look beyond that into traces of
really more advanced attacks that you're
probably looking for and the final
example that I'd like to to mention here
is that in a lot of cases everybody
except the detection should happen but
there's no real response readiness so
whenever a real alert or possible you
know traces of an attacker found doing
the actual response might be really hard
so just last week I was at a client
where a guy in their blue team spent one
and a half days trying to figure out
what physical device was using a
specific IP address that did some weird
stuff that they saw under seem well you
can imagine that I didn't that was one
and a half days the attacker might have
moved over to all of all kinds of other
places and so it was really hard to
figure out where it was and then the
next issue he had was that once he
informed the systems administrator
that was basically the owner of the
device as well that guy just wiped the
device and reinstalled it removing any
traces of you know data that could
possibly be investigated further so
thinking about detection you also need
to be ready to respond actually and and
not just think when I find it out I'll
just see what happens next
another thing that that that might be
not as obvious when you you think about
assume breach is the impact factor so I
you know we usually approach risk with
you know the formula of the chance that
something happens times the impact if it
happens and you see that that that
impact factor is not always considered I
still think it's it's a really important
part of the zoom breach because if you
assume that attackers might bypass your
prevention measures it's only logical to
also assume that at some point they
might even pass by your detection
measures and and go by undetected and so
in that case it's also important to
think about what can I do to limit
impact or at least you know to slow down
an attacker make sure that he has to
jump through a lot of Hoops before he
gets where he wants to be and again this
should usually be really business driven
and I think we all know the idea of
focusing on crown jewels your most
important assets and and and data and
systems in the infrastructure and trying
to think about how you can protect those
a bit more but I think it goes a few
layers beyond that and you should really
see the entire chain maybe from you know
phishing an employee and getting access
to his laptop all the way to these crown
jewels and see where you can you can
improve and if you think about and
actually work on on trying to prevent a
serious impact from a breach that will
also usually help you improve your
detection again because it will take an
attacker more time and to actually get
where he wants to so again that leaves
you more room for for detection usually
I think one final thing and then I want
to move more to a positive side like how
can we wiki who could we approach this
and remediate this is what can we learn
from real actual real life incidents and
as I said I've been doing it for over
seven years and and you see a lot of
weird stuff happening obviously
especially a couple of years ago you
still saw a lot of organizations who
didn't have the assume breach mindset at
all they were just surprised that an
attacker got in even though they had
this expensive firewall and antivirus
etc but if you if you look more closely
at the incidence there's there are some
things that I think are also applicable
to just day-to-day Blue Team operations
and I think one of the the important
things I learned is that for example if
you have a especially of you more
advanced attackers think the really good
criminals or even nation-states that
might be in your network you might need
to observe before you really act so and
what I mean by that is is you might not
want to kick out the attackers at the
first opportunity you have at the first
anomaly you you spot but you might want
to wade out a bit and and see what
they're heading for see what they're
doing see what kind of or what areas of
the infrastructure they've already
infiltrated or or entered so did you get
a better understanding of what they're
working on and and and where they're at
because I've actually seen some
organizations who just you know kick
them out at the first opportunity and
and usually that's what the business
side wants right so that's that's always
an interesting discussion but you should
be ready for that as a blue team I think
and if you kick them out they might you
know still be in other parts of the
network that you you haven't really
covered because they're using different
software more were there to now keep a
presence stuff like that so waiting it
out and and finding the right time to
start remediating and cleaning up that's
an important aspect that you also need
to take into account with just you know
regular regular detection
and another thing I see is that a lot of
organizations jump into doing more
detection and they want to start out
with the most advanced complex stuff
that they can can buy or can get which
is really not usually the best thing to
do
I mean attackers are probably lazy as
well just economics right if you can get
somewhere easy why try and use do it the
complex way so most incidents are not a
chain of seven zero days that nobody
knows about and are used in insanely
advanced ways now it's usually just
three very simple stuff that everybody
could have come up with but just happen
to be you know unlucky chain of events
you could say that led to a full
compromise and that's something to take
into account when doing detection
because that means that you also should
make sure that you first have you know
that the basic stuff under control
before you start looking for way more
advanced topics and I'll get back to
that in a second as well I think another
one but it's it's to be honest I'm I'm
on the fence myself whether this is
really something we should do as a blue
team in day-to-day operations but again
the more advanced attackers will
probably be interested in what the blue
team has to say amongst themselves like
what are they focusing their detection
on there their actions right now what
are you looking for what are they
developing so I mean it's no surprise
that attackers will probably be
interested in communications in a
company but they might also be
interested in what the defenders are
doing and trying to do so in in larger
incidence it's not uncommon to set up
separate communication channels for the
blue team and maybe external parties to
talking to etc but I think depending on
your or your threat profile and and and
what kind of actress you might be up
against it might be sensible to think
about what do you need to use safeguards
like that separate channels as a default
maybe and I mean it's not a lot of work
to do
it's something you need to think about
so as you can see there's a lot of stuff
that can go wrong but how do you how do
you fix that
actually I think it's it's not very hard
per se but it requires kind of a
different mindset and you need to be
able to step out from only looking at
the technical side of things and make
sure that you also look at the business
and the process side of things and how
your organization actually works and
maybe to give an example what you would
you often see we all know this one right
the kill chain there's there's numerous
variants of it but I tend to see the
Lockheed Martin one a lot when I talk to
clients where they've defined all these
steps and you know that the path of an
attack basically but what bothers me
about this one if you use it to model
your defenses against it is that you
know first of all if you put it more
like in a kind of a time relative skill
these three steps delivery exploitation
installation Dibley usually pretty close
together and might only take minutes
right and then after that comes a very
long time where a lot could happen and
if you look at it honestly I think these
steps there's some stuff you might
detect but in all honesty there's way
more room for detection in in the steps
after that but with a lot of models
that's that's not really divided into
very clear clear steps and so if you're
going to model your detection on this
it's going to be quite messy because
you're gonna say well to detect command
and control I can do those 50 things for
example but it's it's it's messy so I'm
a big fan of using a model like this The
MITRE wanna attack but it basically only
started exploitation so everything
before that is is not covered or a
relative irrelevant for this model but
it's a very useful model for for
detection and response in my view
because they take these ten categories
off of stuff that attackers can do and
mind you these are not necessarily in
the order that an attacker will do this
could be switched around
but what this provides you with is a lot
more it gives you the capability from a
technical side at least to provide more
detail on the areas where your detection
is good or where it's bad or you know
where you're already top-notch because
what mitre also does and and obviously
you can you can modify this or use it in
your own way but mitre has an entire
wiki behind this where they say okay for
lateral movement we've seen these I
don't know 50 techniques that were used
in and per technique they list the
campaign so it could be you know a PT 28
or whatever and they say that's where it
was used it involves this technique they
even say what known detection techniques
are possible and for some it's also
known well it's it's really harder and
almost impossible to detect and based on
that you can this is another tool that
mitre provides open-source tool the
carrots and and so at the top here you
see does ten categories and then below
that I'm not sure if you can read it but
it's all the techniques so for let's say
persistence they list the number of
stuff things that they know happen in
the wild like setting up scheduled tasks
to achieve persistence you see some
colors here as well so this is just an
example where red means we're not
covering that with our current detection
or even prevention measures and yellow
means yeah we're probably covering some
of that and it could even be green
squares where you're pretty sure that
you're covering almost any attempt of
using such a technique now looking at
this you're probably wondering this is
still very technical how does it help me
involve the business side of things well
what you should should add to this layer
basically is you know what I'd call a
scenario analysis or more in-depth
analysis of what the business processes
are that are critical for an
organization and below that you can
usually put like the systems and
applications that support those
processes and when you do that you can
also start think
about what are the attack paths that an
attacker could use to you know get into
those business processes and achieve
some kind of goal which means you also
need to know which actors you're up
against you know which actors are
interested in those attack bats and and
you know what level of sophistication
they might have and how they would work
in in achieving those attack paths but
if you have the attack bats that's where
this basically comes in because that's
where you can think of okay so I've got
this Windows machine here that's
critical to this process so if it's
interesting to an attacker you probably
want to achieve persistence so what kind
of Windows persistence techniques do I
know am i covering them in my detection
on this specific system or not and if
I'm missing some stuff that I think is
pretty vital let's see if we can work to
where it's remediating that I'm adding
maybe data collection and and detection
on that specific specific system on the
relevant log files so I think that's a
really key part of of improving and and
what really what's really nice about
such an overview of course such a major
matrix is that you can basically see
what your current status what kind of
stuff are you detecting and you can also
show improvement over time of course so
you know hopefully more red squares will
turn yellow and then perhaps even turn
turn green so I think this is this is
vital to focusing your your detection
and response operations and and for some
things you could even add a little bit
more prevention but let's focus on the
detection side and based on that you can
ensure that you're you know coming back
to the scope slide that I had at the
beginning you can ensure that you're
looking at the right scope and it might
be a much smaller scope then you're
maybe looking at right now but it could
be a much more useful scope than the
larger one you're dealing with and this
obviously also helps in you know
staffing issues and and bring down a
number of alerts that you get and have
to analyze because you're much more
focused on what's really important for
for the organization
now there's one final issue that that
you often see even if you do all of this
right is that you actually need real
attacks to determine whether it all
works right so if you're one of the
lucky ones who maybe doesn't get a text
for over a year how does the blue team
know that they're doing the right things
and actually detecting stuff well the
answer is easy right you simulate the
attack so I think we all know and and
and all are aware that red teaming is an
important part of building your appear
defenses but what you see a lot of
practice is that the red team only does
what what the red team mainly wants to
do is is usually break stuff and you
know get in and and show that they've
achieved all the the objectives and then
you know provide a list of how do you
attack when what path they chose what
what tools and methods they used and and
say blue team here you go
good luck fixing it and it's usually not
a very constructive way of dealing with
it of course and so I'm a big proponent
of what a lot of people call purple
teaming so bringing the red and blue
team together maybe even during the red
team already so have specific points in
time where you do a debrief of the blue
team and already tell them maybe how far
you got so that they can you know
readjust some of their detection
measures focus again on on whether a
team might be so that you prevent that
the red team spent six weeks on an
attack with the blue team being
completely in the dark I mean that's not
useful to anyone except for the
confidence level of the red team
probably so you want to make sure that
the blue team also has got work on their
hands and and also becomes very aware of
the stuff they're still missing and and
you know basically you want to verify
that this matrix is actually in the
state that it that you think it is so it
could also help it purple teaming to
select specific techniques or detection
areas that you want to test and make
sure that the red team specifically
targets those and does a good debrief of
the blue team in to help them again
improve the detection and you know if he
you're really going to the more mature
levels of doing this this could be like
a feedback loop that you go through
several times where after debriefing the
blue team you might want to try the
attack again because they've improved
their detection and see if you can still
pass by some points of the defense and
then again do the debrief so you know it
becomes kind of an arm race arms race of
a second defense we try to constantly
improve each other
and it's usually a way more healthy
situation for red and blue team to be in
because they can more actively learn
from each other right so I've come to
the end of my my talk here some some key
takeaways as I said to really assume
breach so to really live under this this
assumption is to know what kind of patch
your attackers are likely to take and
and you you take that from looking at
the business side of things I think you
should focus on on defending those paths
first adding prevention and detection on
those specific paths that are critical
to the business and and you better do
these right and and just ignore the
others for now then you know do an
entire infrastructure how heartedly or
without a lot of success then it's also
important to you know test measure
adjust whatever you're doing preferably
through purple teaming I'd say because
no one gets it right straight away
obviously you will always you know cover
some stuff using default rules and basic
stuff you can come up with yourself but
the human creativity is is you know it
knows no limits I guess so there's
always ways finding ways around the
defenses and you really need to to prove
that and test that to really get your
defenses to the next level and I think a
key point in that until you know AI
basically rules the world
is that you need humans to do so and
with that I'd like to end my talk any
questions does it work yeah okay perfect
so you mentioned about the advance
attackers that maybe it's a good idea to
let them go into your network a bit and
then do things about it
but how do you convince like the c-level
executives to allow something like this
because it's it's a risk also because
you don't know it's an advanced attacker
until you've actually looked into it so
how do you deal with that yeah it's it's
a bit of a catch-22 I agree so usually
you have F some some concrete leads or
yeah well if you only have an inkling
that it could be an advanced attacker I
agree this discussion will be very hard
and and even I might suggest well let's
just get rid of it but if you have some
leads that it is advanced maybe because
it's new malware you found that you know
isn't on virustotal yet could be could
be interestingly you know stuff like
that
and then so I've been in discussions
like that a few times I've not always
won them but the times I did I think it
was very important to explain what could
be the consequences of remediating right
now which is that the attacker might
still be in a network but you have no
visibility at all on them anymore and it
also depends of course on the type of
impact that you're experiencing or
likely to experience in the near future
so especially with nation-states if it's
you know espionage or something like
that also depending on the organization
of course it might be not that terrible
began and you know because sometimes
they might be in there for months or
years already so you know the worst
damage has already been done and it's
just just stealing information not
bringing down your infrastructure or
whatever so in those cases I think you
you do have
a good opportunity to convince them that
you might want to watch them a bit more
before you kick them out to ensure that
she can do an effective as effective
remediation as possible hi I was just
wondering if you work got a bit busier
after the latest Shadow Broker the
releases and all these advanced malware
and stuff a bit busier in what way in
cleaning up stuff and helping clients
with not a good did not do a good
patching job and stuff so yeah I think
in general we get busier like every
every quarter almost which is not
necessarily get to do with developments
like that but just also general
awareness of the security you will have
to be approached more seriously what you
usually see when when stuff like that
breaks and and gets in the news is that
there's a number of clients who get you
know do some phone calls to us and want
to get a bit of more info like how
relevant is this to us and and you know
how serious is this should I take this
strap but I think overall you know the
biggest bumps in in busyness are when
stuff like wanna cry or non pity I you
know stuff like that happens of course
because that's when there's actual
impact and I think when there's just the
threat of potential future impact it's
suddenly for the mature clients more
mature clients who worry about that
and others just think I don't know what
it means it's probably not relevant to
me okay so I think we need to move on to
the next question
Thanks thanks guy thank you
[Applause]