andrew is a systems engineer at Illumina
he has over 15 years of experience in
security and quality assurance working
with organizations across Asia Pacific
to strengthen their cyber resilience
having worked with major industry
players like micro focused and HPE
andrew has now represents Illumina South
Pacific as he marries his knowledge of
technology and industry to deep and and
implement solutions that prevent
attackers lateral movement throughout
the organization
can you please join me in welcoming
Andrew thank you very much person thanks
everybody for joining the tool this
afternoon I really appreciate it I think
as we get into this topic and hopefully
actually zero Trust is becoming a bit
more of a buzzword so you've either kind
of latched on to that and you kind of
know what I'm going to talk about or
maybe just that the enticement of
marginalizing the breach will get you
through this particular talk and I think
before we kind of get cracking on to
what I actually mean around that I think
one of the key things that we've found
in in a security world is we've we've
been very focused over a number of years
around preventing attackers from getting
into an organization or trying to be
much better at identifying when they're
in with analytics and heuristics and
machine learning and trying to react to
that problem of what do we do once
they're inside and it's been my pleasure
and I was very lucky to join the loomio
recently here in Australia about 18
months ago and they're kind of looking
at the problem from a slightly different
angle of not of assuming that breach is
going to occur but actually taking
proactive measures to limit the blast
radius or the exposure of their breach
and that's kind of where that the
beginning is of zero trust comes into
life as well as the assumed breach
mentality and planned beyond the breach
and you might be wondering well why
would I be interested in this or why
would I be why would it be required to
think about it in this particular way
and if what I've got kind of up here on
the slide and hopefully the guys at the
back and see this I've got a few that
might get a little bit smaller so I'll
try my best to talk them through but
industry regulation kind of compliance
and internal drivers are all starting to
you know to come along with this journey
with our InfoSec professionals around a
need to be able to can be more proactive
in terms
of identifying what some call crown
jewel applications or at least systems
or software that manages data that is
sensitive and is particularly important
not only to the business but the
consumers or the the trust that you're
building with your particular customer
base and whether that be a particular
industry like financials opera you know
PCI is Swift and other regulations have
been around for a little while
whether it be government and and I come
from Sydney so kind of a New South Wales
government initiatives are starting to
take place of not only identifying those
systems but then having controls that
are commensurate with the risk that they
pose and being able to kind of prove
that we are we're doing the right things
and approaching this problem in the
right way and whether that be you know
financial information health information
personal information I mean we don't
need to talk about what constitutes
sensitive data in this particular
audience but we we generally all have
software or applications we have IT
departments data centers public cloud
that is operating on this type of
information and the idea is that
hopefully we can take a little bit more
of a proactive approach to protecting
some of them now it's that's a little
bit about what we're going to talk about
today and introduce that kind of concept
of zero trust into the mix there and how
that kind of plays in the other kind of
intro that I would kind of mention
around this and comes back a little bit
to the way that a loomio looks at the
world and how customers of Illumina are
kind of approaching this problem is that
if we have kind of an understanding
about our existing known risk or and at
least an appreciation of what a risk
might might contain or what that might
mean as an impact of the business
there's kind of two factors to that risk
and one is the exploitability factor or
how how easy it would it be for someone
to actually achieve a breach of that
mechanism on the other factor is really
kind of the likelihood of it happening
and and when we look at classic kind of
risk graphs that's what kind of you're
plotting on an x and y axis and and from
our perspective and the customers that
we have they kind of look at that
likelihood of that reach ability is one
of the factors that you can actually
have a lot more influence over or even
control to a much greater degree you
know the ability for someone to come up
with a hack that
breach you in a way it's a little bit
less out of your control but certainly
the ability to you know to limit the
possibility of someone reaching a system
that they shouldn't be able to access is
something that we can control and if we
look at the hacking playfield one of the
things that we have as an advantage is
that we should know our environment and
be able to control our environment
better than someone that's looking from
the outside is attempting to break in
okay so think of it that way you know
likelihood or the reach ability factor
is something in our control and that's
what we're going to talk about as we go
through this and think about that zero
trust method and it kind of hops back I
mean whether it's an attack or a mitre
or a kind of an adversary lifecycle
attack lifecycle of going up here one of
the key elements and I'm going to kind
of avoid all the bit at the front which
is the interest it's interesting stuff
about how they're actually going to
achieve breaching an organization but
our particular focus is generally around
how do they actually managed to reach
the systems that hold that sensitive
data and and the typical breach patterns
you will read about hopefully you're not
participating in they all reflect that a
low value low risk system maybe even one
external to your business is the point
of compromise but from there they have
the ability to either live long in that
kind of persistent threat model but
certainly have an opportunity to then
move within that environment to get from
that low risk system they're easy to
compromise system into those systems
that hold that sensitive data so that
lateral movement that opportunity for
walking through a data center now that
they have breached is something that
occurs pretty much in most breach
notifications that you'll read in the
news and again it comes back to that
fact that with the concentrating on
trying to plug all the holes and keep
everybody out we tend not to have a lot
of control once someone manages to
breach their perimeter and zero trust is
very much that concept of rethinking
that kind of turning that on its head
and trying to identify and prevent that
level of movement from happening in the
first place so this is yeah that's going
on so underpinning a lot of this talk
that I'm going to do today is this
concept of micro segmentation or
segmentation that you'll see come
through this talk and just to kind of
give you an idea how that went
passed quite quickly but a blink if you
missed it but but fundamentally if we
think of an analogy around what
segmentation means there's nothing kind
of new in terms of our psyche if we
built a submarine that was on the first
page there on earth on the left-hand
side
they kind of represented that open
system open hole or any sort of ship any
sort of breach any tiny print rig of
water is eventually going to bring down
the whole system that kind of mentality
of having a really high pressured hole
or a strong perimeter defense doesn't
mean anything once it's breached because
down it goes whereas on the right-hand
side which is actually the way they
build submarines don't worry for anyone
that is a Submariner wants to join the
Navy they actually build submarines in
this way with lots and lots of bulkheads
or compartments or segments which
fundamentally means they're expecting a
breach to occur right so they're
assuming breach they're planning ahead
of breach but making sure that when that
little breach occurs and no matter how
big it is that it's compartmentalized
restricted or segmented so that doesn't
bring the whole thing down you can't get
everywhere within the sub just because
you managed to breach that hole
ok so that'sthat's the concept of micro
segmentation it's gonna behind the
perimeter behind the Gateway how can we
ensure that someone can't move or get
access to everything once they're inside
by building these little micro
perimeters or compartments okay and
that's the end of my naval analogies
I've got a couple of road-based ones
coming up soon so the key thing there
yet it said probably inevitable that
we're going to be breached but we don't
have to go down with the ship if that is
the case so we're bringing that kind of
analogy back from naval back to kind of
IT and departments I mean this is
probably not a great diagram that
describes all of your environments but
it's reasonably traditional in the sense
that we've placed those controls around
perimeters we're probably building some
level of kind of zoning within our data
center you know the old classic a dmz s
and trusted zones and probably using
kind of traditional firewalling
mechanisms and switching technology to
kind of group systems together that
might reflect maybe their classification
of data and this was kind of appropriate
in the 90s and then we kind of
virtualized stuff so uses o for those
that can't see we kind of chuck in a
virtualization platform until
their data center environment and it
kind of spans all of that and and then
more of lately perhaps moving up to a
hybrid model around the cloud multi
cloud coming into the play of that what
tends to happen is that if you manage to
breach one of those zones you've
probably got free reign within that zone
it's probably not that hard to then swap
the Traverse zones because typically we
start opening up a whole bunch of holes
between things of exceptions and just to
make things work we've got to get things
working for the app teams and the dev
ops teams who have to run faster and
faster so we probably tend to start to
see a bit more of a porous environment
where the firewalls aren't really doing
what we think they were doing and then
we have to worry about what we do in the
cloud and how that works and do we have
kind of a different security posture
completely in in a public cloud
environment than we would have had
on-premise and and a desire in a lot of
cases to go to the cloud cloud first
strategies and so forth and how are we
going to maintain that so typically this
model doesn't really achieve what we're
looking for if we're looking to isolate
systems and protect that data and this
is obviously what happens in the
breaches today most are operating in
some form of model that looks a little
bit like this and the idea and I
apologize because you won't get to see
this at the back for sure but the idea
would be to build those compartments
within each of those zones or or maybe
even kind of phase away that idea of
these big trusted zones and adopt more
of an approach which is the zero trust
model of don't trust anything by default
just because you happen to be in a
particular part of the data center all
right so each application or potentially
each group of systems or maybe even
every VM that you run should be able to
have some concept of what am I allowed
to talk to and I should only talk to
others in that way and just because I
happen to be in a VLAN does not mean I
should be able to contact everything on
that VLAN okay so building segments is
that way of reducing the attack surface
because it means that if attacker does
manage to breach some part they can't
get out of that compartment that they're
in the submarine still holds and they
can't get themselves throughout the rest
of it but the challenge is how do we go
about achieving kind of bringing these
perimeters closer and closer to each
application or
closer and closer to every compute that
we have and particularly when we start
thinking about cloud where we don't over
the infrastructure we don't own the
network how can we achieve kind of this
network centric security model of
segmentation if we don't actually own
the network
or be able to interact well with the
network at all so this proposes a real
challenge to us so yeah zero trust just
actually by a show of hands is it is it
is everybody heard of the term zero
trust I call everybody so everybody
knows what the definition kind of is
right you don't you don't implicitly you
know trust anything around you or
develop a policy that would mean that
you are implicitly allowed to do
something objects in the network should
be no more trustworthy than anything
outside the network and the idea is to
kind of bring down these micro
perimeters and forest those is obviously
an analyst group that's been pretty
heavy on this chase Cunningham if you if
you're not already familiar it's done a
lot of work in this area in terms of
describing a zero trust framework which
looks to identify how we can protect
data and systems and people in a fashion
that is orchestrated all or automated
okay it's a keep up with the business
that we're running but if then
fundamentally they realize or they
reckon from every particular research
that they can reduce a lot of your
exposure and risk which is obviously a
key goal of any security type program
but you can also reduce the cost
associated with running what you're
doing today and achieving an even better
goal than you have in terms of the
granularity of control that you can have
over these systems so so that's a cool
thing is for those that most of people
said they'd kind of realize they're at
rest there's a second show of hands is
anybody kind of running an entire zero
trust framework already or on the
journey towards I think significantly
enough on the journey towards a couple
of hands so they're probably a lot of
opportunity perhaps to to really key
into that and see how that would kind of
work for your organization all right so
I'm going to kind of bring this zero
trust model back into that concept of
building segments and compartments
because ultimately that kind of really
fits the bill of zero trust no implicit
allows denied by default lock everything
down into small micro perimeters we can
achieve that hopefully we can achieve
that across our you know modern data
centers today
so how would we have done that or how
could we approach this problem if we
were looking to try and reduce
connectivity between all these systems
only down to what is required for an
application to function how could we
kind of do that and one of the first
things that a lot of loomio customers
actually try and do is bring that
network construct still sink that deeper
and deeper into the data center applying
kind of switching level ACLs or dropping
firewalls or bringing more and Drink
dragging those firewalls closer and
closer into the data center to try and
attempt a mechanism of
compartmentalizing and fire warning off
because that's the way that we've done
it and our perimeters are kind of based
on that approach as well but that's
particularly challenging to do it's it's
costly as well as challenging in terms
of the management and the overhead in
the the ownerís nature of managing all
of these more firewalls inside your
particular data center and of course
then what do you do when you're talking
about the cloud and and and how would we
run firewalling in environments that we
don't really control on the flip side a
lot of organizations may have a lot of
these types of technologies already so
one other answer might be well I'm
running kind of an Sdn environment so
can I just you know automate or
computerize the development of policy
and utilize exactly what I've got and
maybe that will be my solution to the
management overhead of those things but
again typically what we find is that
that that detachment of kind of the
business context or the understanding of
the application layer back to say the IP
addressing of what all of these systems
are based on kind of any sort of
mismatch between IP addresses and
systems and understanding causes a lot
of problems in that space a lot of the
time applications don't nicely reside on
kind of these network boundaries that
would make it really easy for any of
these solutions to kind of carve off
segments of networks that effectively
and so although they sound attractive it
generally doesn't actually end up
working that well and what we would
probably like to see though is to to
kind of if you like separate kind of the
operation of our network from the kind
of security goals that we have for the
network
as if we can maybe do that we can get
away from kind of compromising our
network design to try and get security
happy and you all the security guys so
we always want you guys to be happy as
well of course but but it's never going
to work if we can't get both sides kind
of playing nicely and so yeah that the
typical the impact that we see from from
this approach and whether it's a
switching approach or a fire warming
approach or whether it's trying to adopt
the technology you have today in a
network centric approach is generally
that you increase the possibility that
applications or the availability z/os
apps will fail or reduce because you
probably break something as this is all
happening and generally the worst thing
from a security perspective is to break
the availability of an application and
no one trusts you after that let alone
the phone calls that you get all the
time even if you are kind of operating
an SDN style or a an orchestrated
environment the operational overhead of
managing that tends to mean that you are
in a situation where the network is
generally more fragile because of that
nature and the changes that you're
looking to make and their reluctance to
kind of change things that are working
I've seen some great environments where
app team owners know exactly where they
want to request their infrastructure to
be placed because that's where it worked
for them last time if it works for me
there I'll put my next app there
regardless of whether or not it's shares
the same kind of risk profile because I
know that I can get connectivity if I
put it over there and that's kind of it
ends up kind of either reducing the
attacks we're sorry increasing the
attack servers or it's certainly
increasing the fragility of the
environment you have and often an
underpinning all of this is that kind of
lack of agility and again a customers
that we've talked to and a lot of people
we talk to to keep up with the business
week we can't afford to wait two weeks
for the next firewall burn that maybe
gets fat-fingered or misunderstood and
it goes wrong and then you wait two
weeks again for the next opportunity on
a Thursday afternoon for the next file
will change to happen although the
request for infrastructure takes longer
than you can do with a credit card in
Amazon and that just leads to shadow IT
so all of those things tend to kind of
fall a little bit short and you might be
thinking well well what on earth are we
going to do then if we're talking about
a network centric approach and their
traditional approaches that we have
aren't really working
and how are we kind of how are we going
to go about solving this problem and
it's kind of a kind of things is my
second analogy I apologize the the the
picture on the right isn't a Gold Coast
or a Brisbane highway because I don't
think we do this anymore but if you kind
of think of it as then the network teams
and the idea is that we want to have
highly performing highly connected
highly available really fast highways
and open connections because that gives
us that you know the best opportunity
from a networking perspective but then
we've got that kind of compromise or
opposing thought from the security angle
which is well if we're going to control
everything and our way of doing that is
by placing kind of network centric
controls in this case kind of a physical
control like a physical firewall control
then we're immediately kind of
compromising and traffic steering and
and and and really compromising that
position and luckily in the road network
we kind of don't do this anymore
and I'm not really that old enough to
think about it but but generally we do
we in Australia at least and although
Sydney's getting more and more toll
roads which is not what we want but
generally we've now realized that the
better way to do tolling on a highway is
to actually place a transceiver in every
car and then we just simply
electronically retrieve fees by
recognising when that vehicle crosses
boundaries and that's I know the
analogies you'll see I think coming up
shortly but taking away from a physical
cash base control on the network or on
the highway and placing it as a
responsibility or a transponder in each
vehicle or in each server or in each
workload that we are then applying that
control to now in this case it's taking
money from you for driving on the road
but it could equally be or perhaps it
would be a strange Tollbooth that would
prevent you from actually reaching the
road but in our case for security it
could be a policy that would restrict
you from being able to access that
particular highway or that communication
flow and if we start thinking about it
that way we're actually decoupling the
control from the fabric of our network
and allowing the
imitation control to sit on top of
whatever topology or you know an
environment that we would desire to have
we no longer compromising ourselves and
to be honest if we're thinking about a
true zero trust model where everything
should be kind of self protecting you
know and you have to justify and assert
that anything that wants to talk or act
in a certain way has to justify by doing
that the only real way to do that is to
kind of D couple those two things allow
the network to be a fantastic network
allow the security or the segmentation
in this case to do segmentation on top
of that get a transponder in the car
onto each server and allow each server
to kind of do that themselves and I
think that's that's the way we're going
to achieve this and it but it brings
with it a lot of benefits because if
we're no longer reliant on the
underlying network or the infrastructure
or the hardware then suddenly all these
things like public clouds start to
become a little lot easier because the
fact that something's running in a cloud
versus on-prem is no longer a factor
because the control or the transponder
is not on the network it's in the VM
it's in the is instance it's in the OS
of the compute you're running not in the
environment that's hosting that compute
so decoupling is the security policy
from the network infrastructure is
actually going to make this possible but
saying that is really easy how are we
going to go about doing that and what
would we actually need to make that
decoupling effective and achieve this
compartmentalizing strategy and these
are I think some of the key things that
are going to make this work the first
thing to make it work is if you try and
add more and more segments to your
environment more and more smaller
compartments micro perimeters you have
to be able to visualize what
communication or what traffic or then
what the actions or the behavior of
those applications are because if you
won't
you're gonna you're bound to break
something if you can't see it you won't
be able to make the right decisions
about how those compartments should form
so the first thing we really want is
some form of a map if you like that will
help us guide our way through to
building the right segments
but that map will also really be helpful
for a lot of other reasons because if we
can finally understand everything that's
going on in our extended data center
then there's a whole bunch of people in
the organization that can start to talk
about kind of a single view of truth the
apps teams have their context and they
can visualize and understand their
application behavior the network teams
can see at a network level what's going
on between all those components the
infrastructure team know the server's
whether they be containers or virtual
where they reside they can talk the same
language and work off the same diagram
as well and they can all collaborate to
help build these compartments if you
like so understanding what you have at
any point in time becomes really
critical to be able to achieve this and
traditionally a network kind of
visualization tool or network profiling
is good at the lowest level you can see
who's top talking and what's going on
but there's no real link back to the app
context and the application kind of data
flow diagrams they're generally in Word
documents in a desk only the gnomon
reads or on SharePoint now they don't
really help you either in terms of a
reality of the situation so we need
something that kind of joins those two
things together and gives us a map that
includes both of those things app
context network and infrastructure
that's the first thing and to be honest
that there has to be live and updating
it can't be a static point in time
because all around environments are
increasingly more and more dynamic and
we need to be able to see that in in a
moment of time all right the second
thing we probably going to need if we're
gonna start building segments is we're
gonna have to have a way of grouping or
labeling or logically representing the
systems that are going to make up those
segments and when we talk about systems
in a around a kind of a table or a
conference table
we don't talk well that IP address is
talking my sequel to that IP address we
use things like with the middleware
server of application a now is that the
dev one or the prod one is that the prod
one that the app the middleware server
and application a in prod is talking to
the database server in application a and
prod and this one's in Munich and this
one's in the Gold Coast so when we talk
about these systems we were already kind
of applying or understanding
characteristics of the role the
application the environment where it's
residing so wouldn't it be really
powerful if we started building or that
have the foundation of our segments
reflect that same cat those same
characteristics and not only does it
make it easier for us to understand them
and apply them but it also means we're
no longer talking or thinking in IP
addresses which is all ephemeral and
changes and I think the last talk was
all about that - how often IP address
has changed was one of the last
questions that was asked so getting away
from the technical properties of a
system and actually just grouping and
logically naming them so that's probably
the second thing we'd need a way of of
applying attributes and no simple ones
that are good enough we don't need a
whole bunch of things because that just
complicates the matter but a range of
those attributes that were apply to the
workloads so we can understand them and
if we keyed our segmentation strategy
off them suddenly everybody understands
every rule we're not concerned about
what does that firewall rule do well
what on earth is that thing in a list of
a thousand we can actually read these
off in English that would actually make
sense and finally the third thing that I
think is really important to any of this
and to help prevent breaking things
which is the death of security in a way
is that we have to be better than our
traditional security methods of being
able to model and test what this policy
is going to be and what it is going to
do before we apply it so we're not doing
our testing of our firewalls by applying
it and waiting for the phone to ring via
three different teams saying you've just
broken all my software what's going on
so having some method of and of
visualize map write policy that's in
English and then apply that in a staged
fashion that reduces the risk of
breaking applications or reduces the
network risk whilst not actually
affecting the network at all overlay
abstracting away would give us that
opportunity to actually build those
really effective signals and hopefully
you would agree there's probably the
three things are we gonna need so let me
take you through a little bit of an
example and this is sorry this is where
it gets a bit small certainly for those
at the back so I'll try and talk through
it as much as I possibly can
but if we think about securing something
by design or through its intent or its
behavior this is perhaps how we could go
about doing that or a sequence that we
might end up following so I've got for
example a records management application
and already I'm thinking about the name
of it and it's running in my staging
environment out of a particular data
center it could be dug of DC or Equinix
or on my own private one but I'm
thinking about those properties already
and then in my head I thinking I know
what this application is made up of it's
a classic kind of three-tiered app of
web server middleware server database
server and I know what the
communications are between those and and
someone's talking to the web front-end
so I kind of got a picture of what this
thing is and what it should do and if I
was going to apply that same principle
of characterizing and writing a policy
that would say that only the
interactions for this app to work should
be allowed and nothing else no implicit
allows no trust zones deny by default
everything's zero trust then this is
perhaps a rule set that would look to
build the rule set would be something
like this the scope of my application is
going to be the records manager app in
dev and staging running in this data
center and my rules are probably going
to be something like a select group of
people can talk to the web front-end and
only the web front-end no one should be
able to get access to the database
directly that's the first rule in
English the second rule would then be
something like well the web tier should
always go through the middleware tier
because that's its vehicle that's
behavior it should never go direct to
the database so our web tier is going to
talk to the middleware tier and we know
that it does that through you do and
hopefully the application teams are at
least aware of that through do and then
finally the middleware T is going to
talk to the sequel server in my case my
sequel server in terms of the database
and if we could write a policy that
looked like that very different than a
firewall set of firewall rules that have
to know all the IP addresses of all of
those three machines and we'll see in a
few minutes what happens when we explode
those that's actually describing the
behavior or the intent and the minimum
behavior required for this application
to work okay so that's kind of our
starting point and as we go through this
we're going to start
to see in my case it's a bit of a
changing evolving application and you'll
hopefully you'll start to realize that
if we were trying to do this of the
traditional ways it's going to be really
challenging to maintain that same
security policy so in this case some
bright executives decided that we have a
cloud first strategy and is determined
from on high that everything now must
run in the public cloud and so this
advocate this is a bit synthetic because
no one's just going to pick this thing
up and run it immediately in the clever
cloud but we're gonna we're going to
take this and put this in Amazon and and
in doing so well what would transform it
a little bit as well and we'll make use
of some of the you know path services
out of Amazon so make it a little bit
more a bit of experience in that sense
but in terms of our policy for those
that can see you'll note that the
behavior of the app actually hasn't
changed the only thing that has changed
is the locations no longer Equinix its
amazon southeast and the fact that our
database is now an RDS server instead of
a VM running my sequel for example okay
so that that's a minimal change to our
policy which could actually be applied
really easy through orchestration okay
so that's the second one then of course
this application is ready to promote
into production so we're in staging
we've done our testing we're now to go
into production
what is that change to our policy well
the behavior of the application again
has not changed now we just need to
apply that same policy to the production
instance as well as applying it to our
dev and test instances
so again minimal change to the concept
of our policy but achieving that same
goal of separating those applications
from each other and this is where it
starts to get really cool because if we
start elastically expanding any one of
those web tiers in our traditional model
where to start worrying about what are
they all that IP addresses of all these
new machines in the web tier that we've
just expanded up in this model our
policy has remained the same completely
because our web tier is still talking to
the middle bits here using Moodle
the behavior has not changed so this
attribute model becomes really riku to
achieving this goal and allowing that
dynamic nature and then hey let's go
ahead and containerized this thing and
now we've got a containers we got pairs
we got Amazon and we've got this kind of
classic application architecture again
our policy hasn't changed just because
the web tier is now containers
versus VMs the database is no longer
physical it's pass hasn't really
affected the behavior and shouldn't
really affect our security policy if we
do this well and tie that policy to
behavior and intent then we shouldn't
have any impact on that so how could we
really kind of finish this off and I
hopefully this is posing questions to
you as to kind of ultimately how is this
going to work and I'd love you guys to
come over to the alumi o booth and we
can talk about it more and in fact if
you're around at 3:40 this afternoon
we're doing a prize draw for a drone so
if you haven't got a ticket for that all
right
already come over there or grab one from
the guys at the back but fundamentally
if we can decouple the security practice
away from the network the network guys
can concentrate on building the fastest
highest performing reliable network that
they want without compromising their
work the infrastructure team can be
happy in the sense that they can
provision any type of resource physical
VM container whatever it might be in the
future in the appropriate place cloud
private regardless they not compromising
themselves the security group are really
happy because they're achieving granular
policy a much you know more control than
they've ever had before at a speed which
is so much more faster than they've ever
had before and the application teams
kind of assist in this process of
potentially defining their policy and
operating the policy and they're not
slowed down they're they're going at
DevOps speed as fast as they can and
they're not they're having a part to
play in achieving that goal and they're
not slowed down by infrastructure of
security as well so it sounds like a bit
of a Nirvana and I promise you it's all
very much possible as long as we
decoupled our security from the network
so what are the kind of the key
takeaways to this and when you think
about zero trust it's a big framework
around self protecting systems and you
know isolating each other and users to
systems and data and systems these are
some of the practical steps that you can
actually take to start achieving that
goal that you've heard about but you may
be not necessarily at that point yet or
on that journey and the first thing is
that we've got to be able to identify
those systems and visualize those
systems that hold that really important
data if we don't understand that if we
can't see that if we don't have them in
real time we're not going to be able to
achieve
the second one is that we want to be
able to architect these security
policies that are micro perimeters and a
small small segment segments maybe all
the way down to single VMs or processes
running in VMs if we want to but be able
to architect those test them visualize
what their impact would be before we
flick the switch to actually enforce
them and that's a vital part of that
process thirdly underpinning all of this
we've got to get away from that concept
of building fences or that kind of
outside in approach of well we'll try
and block it and if they get through
we're trying to take them and get them
out as quick as we can we've got to kind
of flip that on its head and a plan for
breach and plan beyond a breach and go
for a default denying model you know
where everyone is self protecting and
only having to justify having to you
know approve a flow because that is
required as opposed to I live in a
segment that is open and can be
communicated in this way and then
finally as kind of the example I just
showed you before if we have either an
application that's evolving or different
teams within our enterprise that are
running at different speeds with
different technology trains we've got to
be able to have a way that can both
automate or orchestrate this approach so
that it adapts to the environment that
you have and those network centric
approaches or hypervisor approaches or
whatever it might be that we might have
today just can't keep up with that they
just can't adapt and they're not
designed to achieve that okay so that's
that's kind of my practical steps if you
like for going through zero trust and I
think we're pretty much on five minutes
to go now and what I do want to do is
make sure there's enough time for Q&A
and hopefully there are there are some
questions in the audience I hope you
have piqued your interest enough not in
telling you how to go about doing it
necessarily but it's certainly possible
to achieve all of this and so I'll open
it up and now for thank you very much
for your time this afternoon but I'll
open up for some Q&A thank you
is there anybody yes thank you yeah yes
yeah that's a very good question so the
question was I had a slide there that
kind of identified attributes of systems
in the data center in a very sink trick
around the data center but we had that
concept of a company HQ or certain users
accessing the front of that system how
would we do that
well I think in a similar way we've got
to be able to identify users using an
identity framework in some way and it's
not necessarily the same set of
attributes they don't have a role in an
app in an environment but they do have a
role that they play in the enterprise
that would suggest that they should be
able to interact with certain systems in
the data center and so yeah being able
to apply that identity to that person
and then have a policy that says well
those types of people are allowed to
access the systems so when we think
about in the Illumina world we think
about that is kind of their
participation in AD or you know a
directory service what role do they play
and how would they kind of interact with
the front end but really importantly
it's not how would they interact with
that whole app it's how do they interact
specifically over HTTP only to only the
web front end or whatever that might be
so that you're reducing the attack
surface so yeah that the person and the
system kind of I guess merge a little
bit in terms of each one has an identity
and then you're writing policies on
those identities so hope you know does
that hopefully that answers your
question yeah but we can certainly
extend this concept beyond the data
center into user land as well yeah
please and obey
yeah I think I think certainly that the
concept of it as a framework is equally
applicable in into any type of
environment I guess there are different
challenges with the different IT
environments that you have and in terms
of the way a loomio thinks about this
problem how we've approached this
problem there are some types of systems
that perhaps harder to approach this
from a host based methodology because
that host is maybe a black box T or it's
an appliance or something that you can't
necessarily interact with that well so
yeah there are cases where you may need
to kind of think about well what is
something that we could use it sits in
front of that particular SCADA system or
that ot system they could kind of front
that identity or front that that so we
could apply policy at that point but
yeah SCADA systems are a little bit
different and maybe you can extend that
into medical devices and medical
equipment for example as well MRI
machines that you can't play with for
example so I think but one of the key
things that we have found in talking to
a lot of customers around this is it's
still that boundary between IT and ot is
still a very important one that can this
this is very applicable for and then
depending on kind of the makeup of your
ot environment how far you can get that
down to each self protecting system
versus what might need to sit in front
of it but it's a very good question No
thank you
oh yes right yeah one more use at all
yeah I mean I I tried very hard not to
talk about a loom you know too much but
Italy mio is a software solution that
provides all of these things and then
one of the fundamentals is that map and
we actually have a series of those types
of maps that are kind of relevant to the
different person that might be
interacting with the system it's kind of
a security guy versus an infrastructure
type person but yeah fundamentally if
you need something that visualizes
across the entire environment it's got
to work everywhere and it's kind of got
to work at a big scale so yeah we have
written some technology and that they
will do that up to you know hundreds of
thousands of servers potentially but yes
it's fundamental to I think to be able
to achieve any of this yeah why do you
thought of getting the the northern I
think we're up to times I'd love to keep
talking to you guys but thank you thank
you very much for the questions I really
appreciate it have a great day
thanks very much thunder