here to talk on the topic of how
security teams can evolve to win friends
and influence people from tender min
please welcome the wonderful Jesse Erwin
I'm totally terrified thank you hello
everyone thank you so much for the
wonderful welcome Australia you're kind
of amazing and cool and I don't wanna go
home by the way no one tell my husband I
said that and thank you all for getting
up after what was quite the party last
night and coming to attend my talk today
I am gonna cover a whole bunch of
stories and opinions and thoughts and
feelings about of what we do is security
teams I think that we're at a point as
an industry where we really have to step
back and think about our identity and
our work where we are now and where we
want to go so that's what this is so
you're probably wondering why you have
to listen to me today so I might as well
explain when I have to talk about my job
the only way I can reasonably explain it
whether I'm talking to a bunch of
engineers or I'm talking to
eight-year-olds who just want me to hack
their homework is to say that I protect
people from software and I protect
software from people I have an extremely
non-traditional background to be a
security engineer when I was in
university I studied foreign language I
studied art history I studied
archaeology I worked in a library I
worked in a museum
I'm ground zero for inventory being a
security problem I started working on
communications in technology when I
first moved to the Silicon Valley so I
used to be one of those marketers that
everyone swears sells the snake oil by
the way marketing team is amazing you
better be nice to them or I will get you
when I did that work I learned quite a
bit about risk security controls privacy
and generally all of these topics that
are really really hard for the average
person
to understand and wrap their mind around
when really all they want to do is make
the right phone work
or figure out how to stand up a VPN so
they can watch Netflix from Canada
instead of Australia or the u.s. because
of this they have a lot of
non-traditional ideas about security - I
am the first person to start standing up
and screaming that security is way more
than just finding all of the bugs in
code we're supposed to stop the bugs
from getting into the code sometimes - I
thought maybe we know quite a lot about
how humans work and I think that we
should start designing security for what
we know about people not against them if
we know for example people are going to
do awful things with passwords we should
probably just plan systems around awful
passwords and see what we get out of it
and finally one of my other crazy ideas
is that usability is very much a
security problem and more of our
security problems that we face stem from
IT mishaps than some evil awful sneaky
nation-state adversary getting up in our
business and wrecking our Monday through
Friday and our on-call weekends so I'm
gonna talk a little bit about a few
things today I want to do a little bit
of a deep dive into what security is
because I don't really even know if we
know what it is to be honest but it's
been around for a long time I'll talk a
little bit about how we can win friends
I mean I did say in the title we
probably need to cover this a little bit
maybe how to influence people but not in
a creepy way in a good way I don't know
what we're gonna do in the middle but
somewhere we'll get to the point where
we talk about how we actually improve
outcomes and how we get to make more of
a difference and I don't know like maybe
go kick everybody's butt and be really
competitive and win for a change
so okay what is this security thing that
we are doing security has existed pretty
much since we have as humans it's been
around at least 50,000 years longer than
computers and a lot of people these days
think that
security is a huge technology question
it's not actually in my opinion ah those
people who do tell us that it is a
technology problem there are also the
people saying that software is eating
the world news for you
we've only had software for like less
than a hundred years there were a lot of
us around before that and we engaged in
a lot of different behaviors as people
that really demonstrate security
principles one thing I've learned in the
work that I've done is that our beliefs
in security as individuals as
practitioners as consumers as people who
buy iPhones and want to chuck them out
the window when they don't work they're
about as deeply held is our belief in
politics and religion our ideas about
security are very much a product of our
life experiences and because of that
what we might consider to be right or
wrong or correct in our work is
extremely relative to this this is
something you know to be a very very
self-evident truth if you've ever gotten
into a conversation about a password
manager on our InfoSec water-cooler
named twitter because people i found
when i worked at one password would
basically choose to reject or accept a
password manager as if they were
choosing between the old gods the New
Gods the flying dragon gods or no gods
for me thanks like it's an episode of
Game of Thrones what's interesting about
this is when you start talking to people
online about password managers or you
see a discussion going on the moment
someone disagrees with a personal choice
of which product which tool whether you
should even use that class of software
or not it turns into an all-out holy war
of authentication what's interesting
about this is that the choice of whether
to use a password manager or not is an
extremely personal choice and for many
people it's also the most important
decision they're going to make about
their online security
and if there's one thing that is crystal
clear if you criticize the most
important choice that someone makes
about their security if you make them
feel bad for using you know purple pass
instead of yellow pass there will be
hell to pay it's an insult to the
intelligence of most people to the
experiences that led them to making that
decision or rejecting that decision and
it is all around probably one of the
most interesting as technology adoption
cases in our industry so okay I
mentioned Security's been around for
about 50,000 years give or take
I mentioned that we've seen lots of
evidence of security behaviors but
there's something that's really
interesting that I can never look away
from when people started living in
constructed settlements about 17,000
years ago they started building walls to
protect themselves almost instantly I
think the first thing I figured out how
to break when I started using a computer
was called a firewall and suddenly all
of these magical things made sense to me
when people started living in
settlements they also started securing
their valuables by hiding them we see
evidence of this to this day when
archaeologists are going and digging and
looking for forensic evidence of past
peoples and they start finding coin
hoards with more money than they could
have ever imagined
because people had to protect the thing
most valuable to them and it's not like
they had a crazy modern banking system
and debit cards and all of these
fabulous tokens for payment that we get
to have now another thing that's really
interesting some of the earliest
evidence of security comes from locks
and there are so many locks when you
look in the historical record that come
from as far back as ancient Egypt
something I think is really interesting
is these days we run around with our key
cards to get into our office building we
have our UV keys and our u2f tokens
people use to wear their key
to their locks like a pendant have them
made into a ring or put them in a place
close to them for safekeeping so that
they were always physically secure and
it was a little bit of an indicator of
wealth but really what it said was you
were bound to have something valuable
enough that needed protecting if you had
one of these things it reminds me a
little bit now of when I see someone get
really excited and make a pair of
earrings out of you B keys because
that's a pretty good way not to lose
them and also the kind of fun and it
also reminds me of how we see people
hand out business cards that have their
PGP keys on them even though sorry guys
I don't think I've used PGP in a good
five years another thing that's
interesting in terms of security
behavior before computers ever existed
tamper-evident locks have been around
for a really long time when it wasn't
good enough to just have a key to get in
or get out because we knew people could
probably break into a lock someone
designed locks that said hey actually
someone messed with me in the 17th
century so think about that for a second
we talked a lot about you know
authentication bypasses and breaking
into things and evil made attacks but
these problems existed well before
computers did and the reason we had
these particular security behaviors is
because we were trying to overcome human
problems with technology not the other
way around
another thing that I think quite a bit
about when I'm thinking about security
is these seal stones so three to five
thousand years ago when people were
still sending little bits of paper back
and forth long before we ever got into
any crypto Wars on any continent and had
computers to worry about people were
sending their little bits of paper or
packages that were stamped with wax and
the little mark on there would say hey
this is from Sarah Sarah thank you some
nice wine here's how you know it's her
there we are
it was a form of identification and it
was a little bit of a form of
authenticate
there are also these really interesting
seal Scrolls that basically look like a
bead they're about this big when you see
them in a museum and you could roll one
across hot wax to get a very specific
signature it's almost like the ancient
version of that Amazon tape that they
put on all of those cardboard boxes we
all have to throw out the back door and
hope that the recycling man won't pick
up so if we think we have it bad with
fishing now if we think we have it bad
with trying to make sure that encrypted
messages are signed the right way think
about how difficult it would have been a
few hundred years ago or a few thousand
years ago to verify information to get
ahead of someone who's got a forgery
scheme to figure out whether something
is fake or not letters being intercepted
and open we're still a problem we're all
freaking out about that with what's
happening with our end-to-end encryption
and does TLS do the things we think the
TLS does or did somebody do something to
it that they shouldn't have and then
finally about a thousand years later
after the seal stones weren't doing it
anymore there's another human behavior
that popped up that's really interesting
so this this is called a letter lock and
what it does is pretty simple the person
who would write a letter would actually
end up folding it in a very specific way
that they designed to show evidence of
tampering it's a little bit like now how
when we open up signal and someone's
security Keys changed except in this
case the security key would be looking
at whether the wax that would make its
way down into the middle of the fold had
been compromised
whether it was grainy whether it had
broken that would be the evidence of
whether something's was was messed with
or not okay so we went through this
whole thing about you know what does
security look like before the computers
but the thing that's really important to
take away is we have a lot of ideas as
security people about what security
is and they are based pretty much in our
political beliefs and almost our
religious beliefs it's that serious and
that core of an identifying factor for
us when we move forward and we do our
work the problem with that is sometimes
we get into very big arguments about
principles and when we get into those
really big arguments about principles we
lose sight of the tiny things we need to
be doing day to day to actually get the
job done and to actually drive
incremental improvement so now we have
to tell you how to make some friends
when some influence get some people on
our side so that's this part of the talk
one thing that's really important for
security teams to think about is where
power comes from there's some political
science in here there's some
anthropology in here this is all of
those classes that lots of people did
not want to take at university but a lot
of secrets into what makes your team
successful come from all of these
squishy human factors that everyone
likes to call soft skills
protip they are not soft they are
extremely hard to get right and very
very squishy so if we're asking you know
where power comes from as a security
team it's interesting to look at the
political world because there's a
never-ending debate about whether hard
power or soft power is what wins among
the nation states it's a question of you
know should we be using armies and
weaponry or should we be advancing
diplomacy relationships discussions and
scent of alignment writing policy
documents and wooing each other back and
forth to see if we can get to where we
need to go in our work as security
practitioners it's not quite that messy
I don't think any of us have armies that
we roll out when we're about to really
go to war with the IT team if you do can
I borrow them but in our work the
question for us about power really comes
from another place and it's this are we
a team that says yes
are we a team that says no so I live in
the Silicon Valley and where I live
there are a lot of teams that take pride
in the fact that they have the ability
to veto the release of any product that
comes out of their company in fact they
get really excited about this if you
interview with them and they start
talking about how security is so
important and it's such a top priority
except I don't think that's how any of
this works because if you as a team have
the ability to rip something right out
of the hands of hundreds of people who
have been working on it for a really
long time just because you said so five
minutes before it's going to go public
where were you when people were getting
started with this work how did you get
the ability to roll in and say no if you
didn't actually show up at the beginning
of the development process with a set of
requirements with a set of things to
watch out for with information with
resources and with all of this security
knowledge we have that can help us make
the most unbelievable creative bonkers
ideas come to life some people think
it's amazing to be able to roll in and
completely destroy you know an entire
revenue generating product stream for
two quarters just because they're really
not excited about the way somebody
rotated a key somewhere never mind
that the key in question is a relatively
low-risk asset and development roadmap
is gonna have that ripped out within six
months of the product shipping something
that's really important to think about
here is this you know security teams
wonder when they're the team of know why
no one wants to come and hang out why
they have difficulty getting traction
within their organizations and the
answer is kind of simple in fact
something you can learn by playing with
LEGOs if you are the team that comes in
and you literally take everyone's toys
away or
tell them that they are playing with
their toys wrong or that thing they made
for fun is total crap of course they're
not going to want to hang out with you
of course they are not going to want to
listen to you of course they are not
going to share their Legos with you and
I don't know what you guys but it sucks
to not be part of a Lego party so on
another scale we have the issue of our
profession globally just not being
successful if you look at the
conversations we have and our beloved
InfoSec water-cooler named Twitter they
look a little something like this more
often than not and there's a lot of
arguing that comes from this place of
security teams thinking to be successful
they need to be in control they need to
be playing politics they need to be
jockeying for power the problem with
that for anyone who spent way too much
time in European history is that
eventually absolute power unchecked
power ends up being a really toxic hell
still it ends up creating an environment
where you don't have psychological
safety for your team for your colleagues
for your ideas and you don't feel like
you can speak up or you can actually
advocate for the things that will make a
real difference no one succeeds in that
environment not on a community level not
on a team level and most definitely not
an industry level if you've ever worked
for a team whose enforcement mechanisms
were a bunch of policies that were
locked away in a drawer that no one had
access to you've experienced this very
very specific exquisite form of pain and
it stinks because it's a total double
standard security teams can scream all
day long about transparency and doing
all of this wonderful stuff but then
when someone wants to come back and
audit they use the control they have and
saying no you can't question us that's
not cool
especially when most of the time the
security team already has visibility
into everything inside of an
organization but they can't even turn
around and share their thinking because
they don't want to be questioned and
don't want to give away Legos or share
them with anyone else if we want to make
friends we're gonna have to learn how to
play together nicely with others if we
don't want regulators walking in and
taking our toys away forever we're gonna
have to not only learn how to play nice
we're gonna have to learn how to take
care of our toys better at the end of
the day as a security team it is up to
us to define our charter to define our
identity and to decide who we want to be
as individuals and if we approach others
from a place of control and we have a
top-down authoritarian point of view we
are not going to get anything done which
is basically something that we say play
out day to day in our own sphere so
another thing that you can do especially
if you don't want to be a control minded
organization switch your charter
security should be about empowerment it
should be about finding the right way to
say yes it should be about helping
people make impossible crazy creative
bonkers ideas become a reality in a safe
way one way that you can do this as a
practitioner is to think about your team
Charter and find ways to provide
expertise and consulting to other teams
in your organization but you can also
think about how to focus very
specifically on your user we all spend a
lot of time at conferences reading
papers going through presentations
thinking about attackers we think about
attackers all day long however the vast
majority of the security incidents we
have to clean up aren't because some
teenagers somewhere hacked a mainframe
they're most likely because somebody
didn't go through a training someone
misconfigured something someone
a setting that was really important got
hidden in a menu that no one ever looked
at or quite frankly we just forgot
because the process broke somewhere and
no one ever reviewed it and figured out
whether the right things were happening
to control a particular part of business
risk so there's another thing that can
help become help you become more of a
sort of service organization there's a
really common assumption that security
teams are supposed to know everything
now I don't know about you guys and gals
but I don't anything mostly because of
the Socrates guy and his friends
Aristotle and all those other smart
people who are just like yeah don't
bother you're never gonna learn
everything just put yourself in a place
where you are constantly willing to
learn and maybe once in a while relearn
all of the stuff that you forgot that
usually happens on a 10-year cycle
something that tends to happen with
security teams more often than not these
days is they walk into the room and they
think that it is their job to be the
smartest people there and to show off
that they know more than everyone else
this is a huge problem because nobody
wants to be friends with a know-it-all
it's nice to know lots of stuff it's not
nice when you demonstrate that knowledge
in a way that makes people feel dumb and
it makes them not want to work with you
as a service organization to be security
minded we should actually take a
Socratic approach we should be asking
questions we should be investigating we
should be discovering we should be
learning with our teams but not doing
things for them as if you know we are
the maid or we are the janitor and we
are always there to clean up we should
be step and step with our team's not
behind them not sneaking off in a corner
saying ugly things about them it's up to
us if our colleagues are actually repeat
customers of our organization it's up to
us if we make people feel bad for
clicking on a link or installing the
malware because if we make them feel bad
they don't come back and tell us when
they did it by accident again they just
hide it and we have much bigger problems
that we have to figure out that are much
more costly another way to be a little
bit more of a service minded
organization is to think about how we
educate others I don't know about any of
you but I hate to be told you cannot
tell me what to do you must politely
suggest in the right way it doesn't make
it sound like you're bossing me around
like my mom did or you're gonna be in
trouble
possibly a personal leadership flaw but
practically everyone I work with is the
same way so what that means for me as an
individual on my team is that I had to
start educating and seeding ideas with
people it's one thing if it's time for
us to institute a secure development
lifecycle
and I walk into a meeting with my
developers and say okay guys you're
doing this now it's another thing if I
let my junior developers experience the
frustration of having to find patch
triage manage bugs or sweep up a few
things on the bug bounty program and
they come to me and they say hey wait we
keep finding all of these bugs and we
wanted to write all of this automation
to find bugs but isn't it smarter if we
just don't make bugs at all usually the
young developers like yeah let's just
throw the computers in the ocean now
doesn't work that way unfortunately but
instead of coming to them and telling
them what to do I can say okay well this
is how we stop bugs from happening
before they start this is what you need
to know about the language you're using
this is what you need to know about
sanitizing inputs these are the three or
four things you can think about in the
next month and if you don't have any
bugs and these particular classes not
only will I give you more money we are
going to have a fantastic party with
what we didn't spend on bug bounty
budget silly stuff but at the end of the
day instead of telling my teams what to
do and bossing them around
I can lead them where they need to go
and let them figure things out it is a
much better spot to be in if we are
service minded and we are coaching
people through solving problems and
giving them the critical skills that
they need for thinking and
problem-solving rather than just
dragging them through giving them
checklists and forcing them to do what
we say no one likes that so another
thing that's really important is
knowledge sharing there's something that
went on in my organization that was a
surprising gift and something that I'm
extremely proud of in my organization I
was the first security hire I have a
bunch of security minded developers but
I had seven audits over a year-long
period because we were about to launch
some pretty critical code and all of my
audits were looking at different layers
of my code but instead of doing what I
had experienced in other security teams
which was sitting in the corner running
the audits never talking to developers
never making them part of the process I
decided I was gonna step back and I was
going to be the quietest person and the
whole security audit I grabbed my
developers and said guys we have kickoff
call let's go I've already scoped this I
have already taken care of all of the
administrative work here's how the
process of the audit is going to go but
show up for the kickoff calls show up
for the weekly syncs come and talk to
the people who are evaluating your code
and see what this is really about so I
thought this might be a little bit of a
drag because security auditor is
expensive hourly oh my gosh I don't even
want to know how much money I spent but
my developers were able to actually be
part of a process that previously had
scared the crap out of them
instead of arguing with me about how
dumb documentation was they were able to
see that auditors needed documentation
because they needed to have some
of information to help them know how the
codes supposed to work once my
developers saw documentation as a trust
problem an integrity problem and a
security problem my documentation got to
be a million times better to the point
that I actually got compliments on it
around audit 5 or audit 6 of the process
because my teams were actually motivated
to do that work themselves instead of me
running along and yelling at them to go
write some more and do their homework
another thing that helped us out quite a
bit too was that I was able to basically
get my teams to start thinking about
threat modeling and architecture
diagramming it's one thing if I have to
try to attend every single meeting in my
organization when someone's talking
about designing a thing it's another if
I can scale myself if I can create
education opportunities and I can
actually give them ways to lead their
own work identify their own risk and
then come to me when they need a little
bit of proofreading rather than when
they need me to come and lead every
single thing and be a single point of
failure in all of our processes the
other thing that was great is that
instead of having a bunch of developers
who are mad they had to show up for a
6:00 a.m. call I had a whole bunch more
allies no one actually knew how security
audits worked so the whole process was
less scary we ended up having really
great engineering conversations instead
of having political warfare over someone
asking why did you code this way as if
you were not wearing pants which comes
up in an in a review once in a while and
it was nice to be able to give a
behind-the-scenes look at why things
have to be done
a specific way instead of demanding for
my team
they must execute on this thousand step
fan dance just right they could see what
was important what wasn't important and
they were able to adjust the way that
they performed
and they actually became more
accountable at the end of the day to
explaining why they made specific
decisions and they wrote better tests so
there's another thing if you want to win
friends and influence people that's
really important you have to put your
best face forward I don't mean this is
hygiene advice I actually mean that's
not a very practical no security
practitioners we are compelled to be
transparent we will explain how
something works to the nth degree to the
point that if we are talking to
non-technical folks we might
accidentally tell them everything wrong
with what we are asking them to do
before they actually get a chance to do
it the best place to think about this is
how we have discussions about two-factor
authentication we have Wars about
password managers but we have some ugly
battles over two-factor authentication
the problem is that some two-factor
authentication is better than none for
the vast majority of people those people
generally aren't us so when we start to
talk to users about you know how to
protect themselves we will tell them you
know you should use two-factor
authentication but oh the one that's
most prevalent everywhere on the
Internet the one that sends you a text
message that's crap
actually let me tell you everything
wrong with it let me take away every
good reason you might have to change
your behavior and do something that
provides an incremental improvement to
your personal security or to our
organizational security let me just tell
you all the warts and then leave you so
confused that you don't know what to do
so you don't do anything at all as
practitioners we have to do better than
that because when we remove people's
incentive to change behavior that we
really need to see changed
we basically stab ourselves right in the
heart as teams also we have to
put our best face forward because if we
don't talk about our successes and the
stuff that we get to do well nobody else
is going to do it we can't just be the
team that's grumpy that is overly
political that doesn't get invited to
play with Legos or to go to parties
because we tell too many gloom and doom
tales more than any other job security
requires us to convince people to change
their behavior if we're always good at
social engineering as we see we are we
would have already gotten all of this
done another thing that's really
important is to make sure we're
marketing our work lots of security
folks hate marketing sorry guys and gals
security is a marketing job fight me
marketing teams define identity they
have to do all kinds of things that look
really really close to monitoring
alerting detection threat intelligence
they just have to do it differently
marketing teams also have to understand
people how people pay attention if
people pay attention what they're likely
to read what they're not going to read
and generally how to get attention and
to get people to show up we could use
some help on that front definitely some
days we have to be better salesman and
sales women for the services that we
provide our organizations and we have to
make sure that when we are successful at
something or we can provide improvement
or we can bring something important to
the table we have that as our talking
points and we stick to them we nail them
when we repeat ourselves in the places
where we are successful it's not us just
boasting repetition is key to helping
people learn and key to helping people
remember another thing the marketing
team will teach you is you have to be
really cognizant of your audience and
what's gonna work for them most people's
attention spans are shorter than ever I
think right now if after about 11
seconds if the YouTube video isn't
entertaining enough people just skip on
to the next
one if you only have 11 seconds of
someone's attention span if you only
have 11 seconds to get one thing about
your work to your non-technical user or
to your development team how are you
gonna use it first off you can't bury
the lead in any of your security
communications you have to be clear you
have to be concise go ask your marketing
call your marketing team about what a
good call-to-action looks like you have
to remember no one's gonna read a giant
wall of text
there's a reason bullet points bolding
things italicizing things lots of arrows
and emojis and funding where you need
attention are what marketers do when
they are trying to part us from our
money which they're very good at by the
way another thing to remember if we're
trying to market our work and we are
trying to make people aware that we can
be good colleagues and collaborators we
have to remember that humor can be
really powerful people will remember
when you make them laugh they will make
you remember when you make them feel
good and when you've made them feel like
they make a huge difference and knowing
how to help people connect especially
over food with brown-bag lunch with
education opportunities with silly games
with throwing styrofoam balls at each
other just because it's a Friday that
makes a huge difference and then finally
if we really want to win more friends
and we really want to influence people
we have to completely just reject most
of the status quo around us I mentioned
earlier my job is the butt of a few
jokes because I work in blockchain land
if you have blockchain jokes I don't
want to hear them I've heard them all
already here's the thing about a decade
ago when I started working in technology
I remember when the cloud was the butt
of everyone's jokes except I don't know
about you guys I just looked at amazon's
market cap for their web services we
didn't criticize the cloud out of
existence the market spoke the market
keeps giving them more and more and more
money I'm not saying that these
blockchain kids are the cloud I don't
know
what to do with these things I just know
how to protect people from them but what
I think is that if we just keep
persisting in this behavior where we try
to criticize things out of existence not
only are we not going to get anywhere
we're certainly not going to solve any
of the shadow IT problems we have and no
one's going to listen to us when we're
all running around with our hair on fire
at the next thing that someone just
slapped Internet connectivity into the
main reason we should really be burning
down our isolationist security team
mindset is this there are seven billion
human beings on this planet and many of
those people don't have the same
education experiences or access to the
Internet that we do we are never ever
going to get ahead of all of them and if
we can't beat them we should probably at
least try to get them to join us we
can't afford to make any more enemies
and we can't afford to alienate more
people as teams we should always be
recruiting we should be trying to
distribute our workload we should be
trying to make sure that security is
synonymous with productivity and not
slowing things down the secure way to do
something should be the only productive
way to do something period and we really
have to make sure that other people
around us understand that the blue team
isn't just a bunch of engineers who are
grepping through code and doing fancy
things on github by the way those new
security advisories are amazing but we
should work to be violently
cross-functional with marketing with
legal with HR with anybody else who
might be able to help us do our main job
which is to remove fear remove
uncertainty remove doubt and I don't
know help people use stuff better and
keep people from getting hurt finally
I'm borrowing the conference theme a
little bit but it is really dangerous to
be a security team or a security
practitioner who is out there working by
yourself to accomplish things on your
own
the concept of being a single point of
failure is part of our core principles
for a reason and too many awful people
win when we're at war with one another
and that's not great the toxic community
and the industry and fighting that we
have doesn't get us anywhere it just
makes the criminals more successful and
the people who want us to not win get a
few more steps ahead of us our jobs
already hard enough anyway and lots of
us want to actually fix things we're not
quite sure how the price for all of this
is working out we don't know if security
problems are directly leading to people
dying
we have no idea but kind of feels like
we're not far from that and that's not a
reality that I think any of us want to
have to wake up with one day and say
crap it really should have been nicer to
those other guys on the other side of
the building we have to have resiliency
we have to be able to recover when the
going gets tough and we have to make
sure we have other resources to back us
up when we need them the most
finally I have a couple of things I
always love to say but I will not read
them word to word for you generally
though we can't afford to isolate anyone
whether there are teams whether they are
marketers journalists people who use
technology people who want to throw
technology into the ocean we have to
figure out how to get along with
everyone and we have to be more
compatible with all kinds of people
coming from all kinds of places it's the
only way we're going to get people
paying attention to the software we use
and the behaviors that we need to see
them practice no one's gonna want to
hang out with you as a security team if
they've found out you've been talking
crap about them if your users suspect
that you think they're dumb they'll
figure it out quickly if your users
think that you don't care about them the
first place they're gonna figure that
out is how well you maintain your
documentation and how you treat them
something breaks or when an incident
happens speaking poorly of the people
who we are supposed to be protecting and
defending doesn't make us better and it
doesn't make them safer and then finally
I guess the real point of all of this
talking I've been doing is pretty simple
we have to change what we are doing as
an industry to be well-rounded
well-informed and much more emotionally
intelligent than we actually are
dare I say we probably have to figure
out what that empathy thing is if we
haven't done it already we need to be
able to embrace people from all over the
place we have to recruit for diversity
of experience for curiosity and we have
to find people who want to do lifelong
learning and who aren't exhausted every
time they have to go pick up a new
language or a new tool or you know
figure out what the hell OS query did
the last time that it through a weird
alert we have to stop digging our
collective feet in the sand code can be
learned we don't have to make everyone
be a computer scientist when I was in
college I looked at what they were
trying to teach me and said no this is
crap no one's going to actually be using
this by the time I go work in technology
I wasn't wrong so I would like to summon
18 year old me back and find out what
other what brilliant things she had
going on in her brain but the technology
that I work on didn't exist a decade ago
the language that we use to write it go
maybe seven or eight years old wasn't
around when I was in university either
I'm not a good engineer because I went
to college and learned it I'm a good
engineer because I know I don't know
everything but I'm willing to at least
try to figure it out and I want to be
surrounded with people like me who will
do the same thing thank you very much
for listening to me rant until lots and
lots of security stories
[Applause]
yep
Thank You Jessie a wonderful call to
arms therefore people are inspired by
what you say and they want to go back to
their workplaces not tomorrow that same
Monday
and implement what a three short sharp
bits of advice people can do real things
they can do to move towards those goals
that you're nice so there's a few
different things for one start looking
for ways that you can partner with other
teams and you can use projects that
they're working on to drive your
security goals you can throw out your
security roadmap and say okay never let
a good crisis go to wait there are two
crises where we can make this one thing
we want to do happen much faster than we
even planned on another thing we can do
is to make sure that we are fun and
welcoming and inviting having snacks in
your corner is actually a good thing
because people get hungry people forget
their lunch and people really really
really like chocolate or beef jerky and
then finally just thinking about how we
talk to other people and making sure
that we are using inclusive language
we're not using jargon when we're
talking to you know an administrative
assistant we are explaining things in
very human terms people's eyeballs glaze
over when we start talking about
encryption and all of these protocols
and the alphabet soup of technology we
got to do better and at least give them
something tangible to work with
chocolate or beef jerky that's my
takeaway there give her a round of
applause grab your little Zelda chess
set on the way Jesse great start thank
you
[Applause]