it's my pleasure to introduce la vie la
Zarate I kinda got there nearly here la
vie is the group research manager at
cyber-ark he leads a group of security
researchers in vulnerability research
and writing about information security
which you may have seen in some
magazines and blogs around the world la
vie is also into researching and coding
prototypes and Persis concepts working
alongside a dedicated team he studies
the methods and tactics employed by
hackers to penetrate and move laterally
across an organization's network he's
responsible for devising effective
detection and mitigation techniques to
Swart cyber attacks if you could please
welcome ravi to the stage alright so
first of all good morning and I'd like
to start by complimenting you by making
a great choice this morning to see this
talk I'm sure it will be different
usually this these conversations tend to
be a little bit best practices a little
bit strategy I'll try to deep dive into
the details without making it boring as
hell I'll try to do that so allow me to
start a few a few years ago many digital
business businesses get a new shiny
block about 11 years ago if we talk
about Linux containers and about six
years ago if we talk about docker now if
you are securing containers in the
organization's you are coming from or if
you were dealing with containers then I
have a couple of insights to share with
you today that are usually not talked
about a lot so this is the plan
and I also I also should say that this
session is based upon research that we
attract labs
worked on and I'm really proud to be
part of the part of that group
my name is La Vie la tsarevets and I are
really proud to lead one of cyber art
clubs groups that focus on the security
of emerging technologies emerging
technologies like cloud platforms like
automation tools DevOps tools and so on
so our recent research focused on the
security of our AWS and also jenkins
kubernetes and of course containers now
I should say that this session is based
upon a research there is full of tunnel
details related to Linux kernel and
Cisco's and kernel stuff sieve a very
ugly C code so it was a tough challenge
making this session interesting or
bearable especially if you consider that
this what you see here on the bottom of
the screen is the climax of the research
in this session but this is how it looks
like and I'll return to that later and
I'll explain a bit about that so to make
things a little bit more interesting or
bearable as you may I just to tell the
story of the great Houdini the great
Houdini was famous for escaping
handcuffs and straightjacket and of
course containers so a perfect fit for
the story and so this session called you
see here the Great Escape is actually
about challenging Houdini to escape a
new type of container using new trick
and so this is what this session will be
about and just to get in the mood I have
a little video for you showing Houdini
doing is sensational escape what's about
[Music]
all right now we're in the in the right
mood so there's another reason I show
you this this little little clip and the
reason is that the straightjacket that
Houdini were was limiting his ability to
move his hands and the fact that he was
hanging hung in midair isolated in
somewhat controlled environment same
works of course for containers that
limit a process ability to interact with
the host system to interact with the
filesystem to interact with the network
stack the IP tables the the firewall
rules other processes this is how it
works and and to show you how precise
isolation looks like in a row Linux
command this is how it looks like what
you see here is the essence of process
isolation we call today container and
the unshared Commodore Cisco that is you
see here this associated part of the
process execution context now let me
explain this what does it mean so the
rolling of schematic you see here Forks
a new batch process create a new batch
process a new command line and then
start building a walls around it which
will be our container so it's separate
our process or new process with a new
process ID namespace with process name
names so our process our new batch
process won't be able to see other
processes it builds a network isolation
or network name namespace meaning that
our new process won't be able to rely on
the hosts IP tables routing
configurations and so on inter process
communication namespace meaning that our
process our new batch process won't be
able to communicate or pipe into other
processes UTS namespace unique time
sharing which allows us to name our new
environment and hanging our processing
media which is isolating it from the
rest of the file system this command
that you see here is how containers are
born these walls that you see
are the very same walls that are used by
both open source and commercial
containers to isolated and secured in a
controlled environment this is how it
looks like now I should also say that
the container the pretty basic container
that we built here is absolutely useless
you can't do nothing with it it's
completely isolated so it's not really
fair with rudy' nee to ask him to escape
this and it's not really usable so to
make things a little bit more functional
and usable I have this list of commands
here I'll explain I'll explain in a
moment to allow our new batch process
some basic functionality and to allow
our Houdini or attacker to breathe
within that container we need to poke a
few little holes in our new in a new
isolated process to allowed to allow us
to use it and what you see here on the
screen is actually two shells one on the
host a little bit cotton here and
another shell which we also start on the
house so we have two separate shells on
the same host one will end up as a
usable container and the other one would
just stay shell shell on the house and
this is how it looks like we start with
the unsure command that I mentioned
before see it there we go the unsure
command we build the walls then we start
poking holes the first hole that we poke
in this environment is the hole in the
network namespace what we are actually
creating on the container side we are
creating a virtual virtual interface or
we're setting it up and on the con on
the host side we tell the hosts to to
attach to this new interface the new
left one virtual interface one and we
also tell it to forward incoming and
outgoing packets so this is the first
hole that we've broken in this
environment the other hold of epoch is
the around file system ISIL
we mount basic directories and files The
Temper Fest is a fest and so on to allow
our new process to have some basic
functionality we also name our new
container Houdini's container we change
directory into it and we truth the door
behind us meaning we jail ourself into
new file structure system now we have a
more functional more functional
container we have walls and we have
little holes in it to allow us basic
functionality and communications now
this is a more fair case with Houdini
and on the other hand this is a more
operational raw Linux container this is
how how it looks like now that we've
seen the walls and they are the
namespaces and walls of containers we
can play with it a bit and I want to
first run a quick nut sauce and not so
sensational escape using a POC called
chakra that was developed back in 2014
this is not cyber-ark labs work this is
partly why this is not so sensational
but after running the Shocker will have
access will have read access to any file
on the host system any file let me show
you how it works and then we'll discuss
what's going on
No
okay so our starting point is within
already within the container
now just for from the attacker
perspective it's not always obvious that
we are within the container so one of
the first things that the attacker will
do is try to sense the environment and
looking into the file system there are
some indicators with and these
indicators our file system is very very
lean and not many files or not not many
processes that are running in the
background this is a pretty significant
indicator another indicator that we are
running within a container besides the
fact that we have the container ID here
which won't always be here is looking at
the cgroups so I think I have it here so
looking at a see group we see that the
linux control groups assigned a specific
control group for our container which
means that our container ID here is
limited with the resources it will be
allowed to use so this is another
significant indicator that within the
container now let's try to break out of
the walls that we just the docker built
around us if we try simple stuff like
trying to go to to the root filesystem
of the host will obviously be denied
okay this is an obvious a very naive
attempt now let's use shocker and
discuss what it does to enumerate a
specific file in the file system which
is the EPC password where the user names
and in some cases hashed passwords are
stored so let's have a look and I'll
discuss what's going on so this is the
output of the of the e.t.c password file
system on the host which are not i
shouldn't have access to let me explain
how it works
okay so when running shocker it is
targeting the e.t.c shadow file okay
this is a embedded within the code now
what I didn't tell you is that in the
container that Houdini is in at the
moment there is a special mount meaning
within the container
Houdini can reach a specific file this
file is resolved calm but it could be
any file the ability to access this file
allows Houdini to retrieve a structure
called a file descriptor which is the
metadata of the file and file system
within this structure there is a special
field called inode which is a bottom
lines and is a number that represents
the file in the file system
now what Chalker is able to do is take
this number east inode and just rotate
it just look for insert another number
in it and this is what you see here
shocker just enumerate the number the
inode and it find the home directory the
serve directory the bin directory and so
on till it finds the e.t.c directory
which is on our path to the target so
after finding the relevant inode it fine
it found the etc' directory and then it
started doing the same for the shadow
file and this is what you see here there
is another thing going on here requiring
chakra to do 32-bit brute force I won't
get into it but it's nothing serious and
as you as you see here it happened
really quickly
so after enumerated all the AI nodes for
the shadowfied it eventually found the
relevant inode and after getting this
inode what chakra is able to do is
insert this inode within the file
structure that it had for the result
conf and ask from the system from the
kernel to read that file and so this is
what you see here this is the output of
the dtc password within the host file so
this is how chakra works it allows only
read access so it is pretty limited
but you see that we broke out of the
fire world or not firewall but the file
system isolation so this is the first
thing that I wanted to show you second
sensational escape is one that we worked
on inside rock labs and this escape is a
little bit more complicated I have a
video demo here with me and I'll show
you in a moment this escape allow
Houdini or the attacker on the other
hand to compromise the host when certain
conditions are met let me show you how
it works and then we'll discuss what's
going on behind this thing okay so as
before we start already within the
container what you see here is we
downloaded a special kernel module I'll
discuss this in a moment to the
Container and we also enumerated the
processes running at the moment in
within the container again though those
are pretty limited and it is a pretty
significant indicator of it that we are
within a container and we also see that
there is a docker container the process
running which means there is a docker
within a docker situation here which is
a very significant indicator of
something I'll discuss it in a moment
all right so first thing that we do once
within the container is enumerate in the
namespaces the IDs that you see here are
the ideas of the different namespaces
assigned to our container these are the
walls that I discussed before these
namespaces will be our target we try to
escape those from those namespaces now
if we try to use the NS enter command
which allows us to change namespaces
enter another namespace and what we try
to do here is change our namespace to
the system namespace the host system
namespace now obviously if we can do
that we can change the context of our
process to the system context meaning we
own the host but obviously we got an
error docker prevents us doing so so we
are going to bypass that
we are we're gonna use here the Anna
sticks that you see here is actually a
special kernel module now let me quickly
explain explain kernel modules are an
extension of Linux kernel it allows us
to load any functionality to the kernel
without rebooting the machine so for
example if you plug in a new hardware
into into a linux server or machine
instead of having to reboot the machine
a Linux kernel might below it and allow
us to use this new hardware so this is
what we are going to do here we're going
to load a new kernel that will
manipulate the NS enter control
this is a great question I'll answer
your question okay
so again we're in numerating in the
namespaces the idea is that we are
targeting will be simply changed we're
using in small insert module to the to
the current kernel module to the current
kernel no error so same successful now
we are enumerated the namespace IDs
again within the container and we find
something interesting the IDS of the
mount and the network namespaces has
changed so this is a good indicator that
something good has happened for Houdini
at least we are still within the
container this is the process the list
of processes that you see here but now
if will try to use NS enter again and
change the context to the system context
system namespace you'll see something
funny the kernel returns with TTY name
failed success so the kernel is a bit
confused whether we fail to load the
kernel and change the namespace or
succeeded in doing that TTY name is a
typewriter which basically means that we
just connected our input and output to
the system context this is what TTY
stands for so now if we try to enumerate
again what processes are running we have
a completely different picture and also
if we look at the file system we'll see
that we have the host file system so we
broke out of the file system
installation we broke out of process
isolation using this type of attack we
can compromise the host completely not
just having a read access to it now
let's demystify the mystify the attack
and answer to answer your question so
will allow us to
for the shocker in numerate inodes
and in read file that we shouldn't have
and what allow us to load a new kernel
module this is something called
capability or capabilities these
capabilities are essentially against a
distinct permissions that were broken
out of the root user in the Linux root
user meaning that instead of having user
or processes in Linux instead of
granting users and processes full root
permissions you can we can assign them
specific capabilities for further tasks
or processes to run so it is actually a
pretty good list privileged
implementation and same applies for
containers containers also can be
assigned specific capabilities and it is
needed in in many cases it is needed
when running container within a
container to do that the containers Nick
needs to have certain capabilities to
run this virtualization one inside the
another also containers that run a file
system jobs that run configuration
management jobs also require
capabilities kubernetes if you have
kubernetes within the within your
environment many of the management
containers that come default with with
kubernetes running run as privileged
containers with with capabilities so
what capabilities were used here for the
Shocker
for the Shocker case the chakra needed a
special capability called Cape duck read
search the read search allowed the
container to enumerate the file
descriptor to change the I nodes and the
duck which stands for discretionary
access control allowed our container or
Houdini within the container to read any
file on the system while ignoring the
discretionary access control on the file
so we could easily enumerate any file on
host file system this is the capability
required by by shocker for our escape we
use two capabilities one is cap C's
module and this is answers your question
which allows us to load new kernel moly
modules into the kernel and the other
one is cap sea slug which allows us to
read information from the kernel and I
should say here that writing new kernel
modules is very painful because you have
to you have to make sure that the
version of the kernel module complies
with the current kernel version at the
CRC and the Mac's are are equivalent to
the current kernel modules there are a
lot of stuff going on there this is why
we needed the cap syslog to read some
information and get the idea of what
they can expect from from our new kernel
module so capability is where the trick
here and containers that are assigned
capabilities are actually called
privileged container now I should say
here that this is not something that we
coined or invented this is something
that was known when containers laners
containers were developed and then
docker containers were developed but our
contribution to it was to see how
attackers or in our case Houdini might
be able to leverage those capabilities
to escape the containers this was our
our our contribution here and we
extended a bit definition of privet
container saying that a privileged
container is the container providing an
attacker with a direct or indirect
access to the underlying hosts this is
what we've seen here and capabilities
are just one example of privileged or
just one example of how a container can
be turned into a privat container but
there are other ways to make a container
of private containers container and and
so today we talked about capabilities
but mounds can also make a container of
each container so for example one of the
most I guess
weird or uncommon use-cases is creating
a container that mount the whole whole
host file system so we have a container
that just owns the whole host file
system so this is obviously a privileged
container another example of it would be
ii know ii know a parma now linux has a
very effective and efficient security
controls
Sekhmet armor that implemented
defense-in-depth in Linux
so those security controls allow us to
restrict access to access or execution
of processes even if those processes
have certain capabilities so even if our
container have those capabilities I
mentioned before with the right second
profile or app app fr more profile the
process and the container will be pretty
restricted so container without those
security controls should be considered
privileged container last but not least
we have the docker stock I didn't cover
it today but I still thought it worth
mentioning doctor stock is a special
file that allows the CLI dr. CLI to
communicate with the doctor demon now
any user or process that have access to
the docker stock file can control the
dr. diamond dr. diamond runs as route so
this is an obvious privilege escalation
or escape or in our case when you talk
about provision container if a container
have access to the docker sock on the
host it should be certainly considered
privileged container so bridge
containers were the trick and what is
the risk
I'll just recap what is your the risk of
having privileged container within the
environment there are a couple of things
to consider for those of you who are
computer science enthusiasts I have here
a reference to P and NP I hope you
appreciate it
so there's a couple of couple of risk
that that we should consider first is of
course escaping we just discussed this
provision Tainos can be used to escape
but of course this is this doesn't stop
here as soon as our attacker or Deena
gets into the host system any other
container will be obviously compromised
any sensitive data that are stored in
their credentials and so on there's
another vector which leverages
privileged containers to escalate
privileges so imagine this you have a
DevOps engineer in your in your company
in your organization and he has access
to an on route access to a container
host now with his access he does able to
launch or deploy new privileged
container if you can do that you could
just launch a new privileged container
access it and then escape it as route on
the host this is another vector or
another risk we should consider when we
have privileged container or the
permissions of the ability to launch new
provision containers this is the risks
what about mitigations so there are a
couple of things you should consider
when thinking about provision containers
or the risk about privat containers
first and foremost is the privileged
access to the container host any user
any developer any DevOps engineer with
privileged access to a container host
can inflate the attack surface of the
image of the environment dramatically by
deploying privileged containers to their
need so controlling privileged access
could be route or can can be any user
under the docker group is critical to
limit the ability or to limit the attack
surface of the whole environment this is
the first thing to consider second thing
to consider we talked a lot about
privileged containers and capabilities
and so on so limiting the ability to
deploy new privileged container is
obviously a good way to limit the attack
surface of the environment so the CLI
the syntax that you see here docker run
- - privilege is one way to
to deploy a container with the whole
whole nine yards the whole set of of
previous container the whole set of
capabilities excuse me I think there are
13 39 different capabilities at the
moment and this is still under
development and so docker run - -
privilege is one thing that you want to
prevent when running when allowing user
to run containers in your environment
and last but not least we should also
talk about secrets containers obviously
are used in a multi-tenant platform it
allow us the flexibility to run multiple
sessions on the same host which is great
the other side of it is that different
session might be associated with
different sensitive data different set
of Secrets different set of users and so
limiting the exposure of credentials in
such environment is super critical
because if you have one privilege
container within the environment and it
is compromised all the other containers
are obviously will obviously be
compromised all the secrets and data and
so on this is why secrets is in actually
any other environment the exposure of
Secrets should be minimized to the bare
minimum all right so let's talk about
key takeaways and here's the thing
although everything I said here today
containers can be a good security
boundary with a little asterisk we've
seen that when we launch a raw Linux
container completely isolated it will be
very efficient in limiting the ability
of the attacker to escape from escape
from the container to the host but in
many cases operation or reality dictate
dictates differently and requires us to
pokes
to poke a new holes into into the
environment and these holes
inflate the risk that that we need to we
need to deal with so what kind of things
we should consider what risk you should
consider if you have container
environment within New York within your
organization first one is privileged
access to the host this privilege exists
as I mentioned before will allow
developers DevOps engineers to learn
through this container and extend the
attack surface privileged containers are
obviously a risk and attack surface and
secrets that I just mentioned this is
the the things I would recommend and I
know that many security DevOps security
vendors and service providers usually
focus on the application layer on the
behavioral layer of the containers but
there are rare cases where I see or I've
seen in the wild people that focus on
containers themselves and how they are
configured and what permissions or
capabilities and what kind of boundaries
or how the boundaries of the containers
look like so this is one thing to
consider and I didn't have much time to
discuss all the details so I'd like to
I'd like to suggest two things first of
all you can have a look at our threat
resource block cyber-ark lab we'll find
the research the discussion is based
upon with all the details that I
mentioned before this is the first thing
second thing I'd like to suggest that
you come at our booth at Ciroc Ciroc
booth right over here where you'll find
me I'll either be there or in the Lego
station trying to break the record there
that's it thank you very much
[Applause]
any questions yeah mm-hmm okay that's a
good question so the question was here I
show the scale based on capabilities are
there any other ways to break out of
containers and the answer is is yes as I
mentioned containers that have pretty
weird mounts for example there are
several containers that are run run as
side course in many in in kubernetes
environments that wrap or simplify the
work with with the docker demon and to
do that those containers mount the
docker stock file that I mentioned so
this allows the any user or process
within this container to completely
control the doctor environment so this
would be one thing one I think one thing
to look for there are other there's
other things that I didn't mention here
today which is exploiting kernel
vulnerabilities now it's not it's not a
straightforward thing to do even pretty
simple vulnerabilities or exploits like
dirty cow can be exploited
straightforward within the container you
have to adjust it we have done some work
around it and you can find you can find
a piece in the threat research blog but
kernel exploit would be one way one way
to go thank you very much guys
[Applause]