so next up we have Martin van horebeek
his although he's come over or come over
from all the way from San France San
Francisco talking it's very good for me
today and his and his presentations got
global Commons or connected States the
contest for the soul of the Internet I'm
actually really looking forward to this
presentation so mom's gonna tell you a
bit about himself so a subject matter
I'm sure he's very very aware of so
let's give a round of applause money
[Applause]
thank you very much for the intro and
great seeing everyone thank you for
coming out so my name is Martin Van Horn
Blake and I'm a board member with the
forum of incident response and security
teams which is an association of
incident response teams outside of that
I also thank you very much outside of
that I also work as a lead expert for an
initiative called the best practices
forum on cybersecurity which I'll tell
you a little bit more about later and
I'm also the chief security officer for
a software company based out of San
Francisco called Zendesk now one thing I
wanted to give you as a bit of a
starting point is the context behind why
I'm actually interested in this specific
problem and how it actually also affects
you and I want to give you a little bit
of an intro into what's happening in
this space and something that for me
matters very very deeply is that we
recognize that as incident responders
and as members of security teams we
actually all need to work together there
is no way we can win by ourselves a
little bit of you if I go back to the
keynote from this morning from eco hippo
Ninh if you look at that Castille and
the walls that were building around it
if we're all building our own walls
we're going to lose however if we work
together and we understand from each
other what the challenges are and we can
work across those walls and actually
benefit from each other's experience
we're going to be a lot more effective
and that's really what first as an
organization is all about we have
members in eighty four different
countries actually I need to update the
slide is it's 92 today which are all
incident responders just like yourselves
people's dealing with and responding to
cyber security incidents
as an organization we have one big
vision for us as a community and that is
that we are the organization that helps
incident responders be more effective
and we want to do that in four different
ways first is by creating this community
where you can actually connect and
coordinate in a global way with other
incident responders we want to make sure
that we all speak the same language and
that doesn't mean that we all speak
English even though I really do like the
Aussie English accent so that would be
what I would be rooting for but we want
to make sure that everyone understands
the terminology that we use and the
problems that we work on we also want to
make sure that automation is easy and
that automation exists so working on
making technologies like the sword
technology that the previous stock here
was about more widely available is
really important for us and finally we
started recognizing a few years ago that
there were a lot of policymakers that
got really interested in cybersecurity
and in incident response but they didn't
always understand exactly what it was
that incident responders did so we
actually wanted to work on figuring out
how do we get them in the loop and how
do we make sure that they understand
what we do so they could actually help
us instead of sometimes maybe perhaps
making life a little bit more difficult
and we do that in a couple of different
ways this is a photo of my colleague
Audley Wahid who is actually also here
at the conference when he met with the
new newly built Incident Response Team
of the country of Bhutan in the
Himalayas so we do a lot of
capacity-building we meet with a lot of
new certs we create standards and
technologies that they can pick up and
then also you can pick up for your
incident response teams and almost
everything we do in that manner is
released as Creative Commons so you can
actually use it this is another example
this was a debate in 2012 at a
conference culty Internet Governance
forum organised by the UN when I was
discussion about whether or not
countries should be working together
only law of the Seas a very big idea at
the time that would cover cyberspace and
we provided some technical input from
the Incident Response perspective and
shared with them the different things
that would work and wouldn't work if
countries would move into that direction
and then finally we do a lot of training
in education we have open source
training for incident responders which
we teach in various places this was a
training that we did in Cote d'Ivoire
but it's actually also available for
free from our website so you can
actually go download it there now the
talk today that I want to give you is
all about whether or not we should be
pursuing a global Commons or an internet
of connected States and I want to be
really clear about it because it is
actually a choice that we have in a
sense that we can look at the Internet
as oceans as forests as things that are
communal between people between
countries and that we all have to work
on together and partner on managing it
or we can decide that we're all
countries in it for ourselves and the
only ways we really interoperate is by
trading by signing treaties by agreeing
and in reality we will always figure out
some place in the middle rather than
leaving completely in one direction but
I think today we're very much in a place
where some of the things that are
happening are not really very conducive
to getting us to a place where we
actually manage the internet as a
resource that is shared between all of
us and I'm going to use three quick
examples to actually walk you through
that and in order to do that I'm going
to make a blitz trip from Iran to
Amsterdam to the Ukraine and we'll get
started with an event that happened in
July 2010 and which I think changed a
lot of how people perceive what the
internet is and what impact it has on
States as we know them today and that
was of course a piece of malware called
Stuxnet now at the time I was lucky
enough to work in the Microsoft Security
Response Center in Redmond and so I was
very involved in the initial response
against Stuxnet when it took place but
one of the big takeaways for me was the
technical complexity of the issue so
here was an attack that actually
exploited for zero-day vulnerabilities
in various pieces of software including
Windows but also the siemens step7
software that actually had a physical
impact
the world and bypassed a air-gap network
so it made its way onto a network that
wasn't even connected to the Internet in
the first place by exploiting a
vulnerability and how specific file
types were being parsed on a USB stick
now what was really really interesting
for me about Stuxnet was how the
countries that were later on assumed to
have something to do with initiating the
attack were some of the first ones to be
really really concerned about it when
Stuxnet originally hits the
organizations that me and many other
security professionals ended up meeting
with to give them more data on what was
actually happening and how they could
actually protect against it we're in
many ways the countries that were later
perceived as being behind the attack
because they had a lot to lose they had
a lot of infrastructure they had a lot
of power plans that were connected that
could potentially be affected because
they use similar centrifuges similar
devices as what was actually being
targeted by Stuxnet so it was a very
very interesting incident that
completely spread beyond the intended
scope it was probably a state attacking
another state's nuclear program and by
simply by virtue of doing that they
actually spread across the world and
ended up affecting a lot more systems
now none of those other systems were
affected in the negative way that the
target plant was but keep in mind that
during the initial response because of
the size of Stuxnet nobody really knew
that until quite a bit later so the
initial response was very frantic it was
trying to figure out what is this
malware doing and how do we stop it
so this became a very big problem and it
actually changed the way that a lot of
countries ended up thinking about
malware and what malware could actually
do moving forward one year to 2011 there
was a small company in the Netherlands
called diginotar and diginotar is a root
certificate authority so when you look
at any laptop it has about a hundred and
fifty companies that it trusts to a test
that for instance a website is actually
owned and operated by Google now
DigiNotar was a CA that was a bit
particular because it also happened to
be a CA that provided services for the
Dutch government so it had the scam
so part of it but it also had
essentially digital certificates that
were essentially signatures by law and
were being used by the government in
many different capacities now in that
month or actually a few months before
there was a compromise of the CA and
someone broke into their systems and
used their hardware security modules to
issue new certificates for sites such as
google.com but also for instance for
Mossad Lavrov Raphael and mi5 dot-gov
the UK now there was no indication that
those certificates were ever used but
the Google one specifically was used to
man in the middle about 700,000
connections all from Iran made by
individuals checking their Gmail so the
attempt here seems to have been to
man-in-the-middle email traffic from
Iranians when they were trying to
connect to get to Google and the attack
actually worked for a couple of weeks
until it was discovered by a user in in
Iran that was using Google Chrome and a
new feature called certificate pinning
actually flagged that it was it was a
problematic connection and there was
some type of attack taking place again a
very very interesting incident because
the entire world was really affected by
this one compromised in the Netherlands
even though the target of the attack in
this case were people that were based in
Iran so again you see this attack
spreading way beyond what the original
attack was and in fact this particular
incident kick-started a whole set of
incidents then in the CA community that
were later on discovered and now we have
better technologies luckily to be able
to spot them but at the time it was a
fairly immature place and it really
pinpointed a weakness that ended up
being exploited in a number of different
ways and then finally moving forward to
something a little bit more recent in
June of 2017 several companies
international companies that had
business operations in Ukraine
downloaded a security update for an
application called Medoc or rather an
update for an application called me doc
Murdoch was accounting software that a
lot of international companies used when
they did business in the Ukraine because
they needed to have the ability to file
taxes in the Ukraine and it happened to
be
the most convenient software for it it
just so happened that these update
servers were compromised and were
actually used to provide a piece of
malware called notepad yeah to the
machines at these different companies
that were downloading updates now when
they got these updates they were
infected with not patio which was
seemingly ransomware and ended up taking
a lot of very very large organizations
including for instance the chipping
chipping giant mask now this was a
particularly interesting incident
because a both undermines the update
mechanism of a very common application
in the country it was clearly targeted
towards companies doing business in
Ukraine but because it also exploited a
vulnerability that allowed it to infect
over the network it spread out to other
offices of these companies in different
countries and there's many different
assessments of how expensive not petia
ended up being but 10 billion is at
least one number that was thrown around
in a wired article a little bit later so
it was a very very expensive attack and
in fact there was a very interesting
outcome from this as well quite recently
where a cookie manufacturer ended up
filing an insurance claim for the
damages that they had for not petia now
the insurance claim that they filed was
under property insurance not cyber
insurance so it's a little bit different
than a typical cyber insurance claim but
that particular claim was denied because
the company was according to the insurer
affected by an attack that was actually
warlike activity so the systems that we
have built to protect our own
organizations both in terms of defending
against attacks such as installing
updates were used against us to
compromise our own networks and then our
insurance providers are getting to a
point where some of them at least are
declining insurance because that's
warlike activity happening so you can
see that the impact of these incidents
is pretty tremendous and has a lot of
impact on us as organizations and really
in many ways as Internet users and
medicines so when I talked earlier about
the fact that we could be a global
Commons or we could be
a set of interconnected states there's
actually some really interesting work
that was done a few years ago by a
academic at Indiana University and she
actually got the Nobel Prize her name is
Elinor Ostrom for her work on
identifying how communities can actually
govern the Commons and many of those
things include making sure that as a
community when you heard your sheep in a
particular field you could only heard as
many sheep as you've actually been able
to care for five years before there's
many different rules and principles that
she identified that are very very
helpful but as you can see we are right
now in a dark place where things look a
little bit differently and we don't seem
to be thinking about the best interest
of the Internet and in fact we're just
trying to get short-term benefits and so
a very important question for me and
also for first as an organization is how
we actually break this negative cycle
and how we end up in a community where
we all work together on making the
internet safer and some of these
behaviors that I just talked about which
all seem to be state initiated or not
considered reasonable and some offensive
activity by States we will never be able
to exclude but the activity that impacts
very large communities that removes
trust from individuals on using the
internet and makes our life very very
hard to actually operate businesses
reliably in the Internet as we do in our
legal systems within our countries is
absolutely unacceptable and there's a
lot of work going on in the community to
get to a better state and I want to use
today to talk to you a little bit about
what is happening in that community but
before we go there I need to cover
something that is probably the driver
forward a lot of these issues and that
is our national interests now some of
you may recognize this this was a chip
that the US government in 1993 started
promoting it was called the Clipper Chip
the idea behind the Clipper Chip was
that it would become possible for
everyone to have encrypted
communications over the phone with one
little exception that was that the
government would be able to listen in on
every phone call
and this chip was the guarantee that
that would happen now the chip didn't
end up being very popular because I live
in the United States I'm actually from
Europe but people in the United States
don't always trust the government very
much so as a result they didn't
necessarily want the government to
listen in on all communications but you
can see that that same issue actually is
just part of a much wider and longer
conversation that started off with
export controls until the early 90s much
of encryption was actually on the a
munitions list in the United States and
was not something you could export then
there was a Clipper Chip there was
something called dual EC drbg which was
a pseudo-random number generator that
was widely believed to contain a
backdoor but that was considered to be a
relative standard and promoted by the US
government and finally today you see a
lot of discussion about the FBI and
Apple trying to figure out how do how
this law enforcement actually get access
to data on phones so these are very big
societal problems there are no necessary
easy answers for any of these these are
trade-offs that we need to weigh as
communities but you can see that quite
often the problems run over a very very
long period of time and it kind of
brings into context how the definition
of a state actually is being a little
bit criticized by this concept that we
have which is the Internet Mikko this
morning made a much better argument than
I ever could for why there are no more
borders everything right now is
transnational when you think about the
internet and how it works we don't
really have solid international laws we
have some work that's happening there
and I'll talk a little bit more about
that later but there is no real common
understanding what a cybercrime a really
interesting thing for me was when I
moved at a certain point in time between
employers and I went from a software
company to a company that was more an
online services provider and suddenly I
was being contacted by very much the
same people but about very different
issues which they consider to be cyber
security issues at the software vendor I
ended up working with them on security
vulnerabilities at the online services
provider many of the questions I got
were around videos that were being
posted to the service that we actually
operated and that they consider to be a
cyber security
so there isn't really a lot of agreement
there another thing that is critical
about a state is that a state has the
unique ability to engage with other
states so for instance if I get off a
plane here in Australia and I tell you
I'm here to negotiate on behalf of the
United States government you'll probably
laugh me out the door and legitimately
so because that's not something that
individuals do that is something that
elements of the state do that have that
role and with the diginotar incident in
particular where you saw digital
certificates being issued that
impersonated parts of the government
it's a very interesting echo of how that
ability to engage with other states
really depends on how trustworthy your
communications are a political scientist
from Germany also had a definition that
a state is a country is a territory and
a government that has a monopoly on the
use of force within that particular
territory
Stuxnet actually undermines that in a
way because the use of force isn't
necessarily violence between people it
can also be activities that break things
for instance which was definitely the
case with the attack on the Iranian
nuclear installation in Natanz and
finally states are also often identified
by the fact that they provides a very
critical key services issuing passwords
being able to make it possible for
people to receive mail in many countries
still is actually a state provided
service you can see that a lot of those
services are slowly also being served by
online services providers so there's a
lot of change to how states have
actually worked with their citizens just
in the last 25 years and I think that
isn't a bad thing it's also a lot of
good thing it's just change and so this
is a very difficult time where we're all
trying to manage that change and work to
it now in 1996 there was a hacker in the
United States who goes by the name
mentor his real name was Lloyd
Blankenship and he wrote this very
interesting piece of text I believe it
was shortly after he was actually
imprisoned for a crime at the time and
he makes this really compelling argument
that the Internet is actually something
different
and all the internets different rules
apply now I think today we have a very
much more strong view on the fact that
law also applies online and so a lot of
this no longer really holds true but I
think the principle behind it of we're
dealing with a new technology that isn't
just changing the way we use technology
but it's changing the way we actually
live and breathe Society absolutely is
true and when you look at how the
internet grows you see that very same
like challenge rising and becoming
bigger because if you look at internet
adoption rates first of all
congratulations Australia or actually
all the way near the top way beyond even
the United States but if you look at
countries like India and China they're
just hovering around the 50% mark which
means that many many many more people
are going to be coming online in the
next few years that are actually online
today and for them the internet means
very different things because keep in
mind many of them won't have a
background to understand what cyber
crime or cyber security issues are some
of them will be users that use the
Internet in a very specific way for
instance to get remote medical care and
won't be using a lot of the technologies
that we today take for granted now by
itself the internet becoming bigger is
always a very very good thing but it
also does make things a little bit
tougher on countries and States if you
look at 2016 it was with this tweet that
Mozilla announced that they actually saw
over 50% of all HTTP requests being
HTTPS so that meant governments were
silently going dark and when they try to
monitor for things they wouldn't they
wouldn't be able to monitor them anymore
as a technologist I think this is a good
thing but there's clearly a lot of
societal issues related to that where we
need to have discussions and we need to
have debates so as countries have these
rising concerns it's very important for
us as people that in many cases operate
a network that we realize that countries
have different tacks that they take to
look at this problem some countries
especially the ones that have issues
like domestic terrorism or that have
porous borders are always going to look
at cyber as a probe
from a national security perspective you
see the solid in Africa where they're
very concerned about security because
they have other security issues and they
immediately think of the impacts that
the internet is going to have on those
issues
there's also countries that choose to
prioritize social concerns for instance
you see that a lot with very small
countries where there might be issues
with social cohesion or even really the
understanding that there is such a thing
as a country and a national viewpoint
they may actually see the internet as a
way of improving social cohesion and
making it easier for them to bring the
country together and finally economic
improvement is a very big one you see
that especially in Asia where countries
are doubling down on the internet as a
way to increase commerce increase trade
and drive innovation and leapfrog ahead
of other countries so there's many
different countries that take completely
different perspectives on these issues
and the challenge that we're now seeing
as Atos countries often don't trust each
other because they have different
priorities and they come from very
different angles I seem to meet a
charter for this level
this might be the one let's give this a
try
I think that's it great sorry for the
technical interruption so these
countries often have issues trusting
each other and there's a couple of
different ways why that is the case the
first one I already mentioned legal
frameworks another one is that you
rarely really know which country did a
particular act or took some particular
action the incidents earlier there's a
lot of assumptions there's also a lot of
attribution but quite often that
attribution is actually based on things
that were gathered - signals
intelligence or human intelligence and
it's not always based on something that
smaller countries would necessarily have
access to and finally there's a real
problem with intent for instance if you
run a power plant and you find malicious
code on your power plant systems that
could be both to spy on how much power
is actually being generated for part of
the population and to measure economic
growth in the long run or it could be an
attempt to sabotage your power plant and
the reality is with today's malware that
quite often allows you to do pretty much
either of those it's very very difficult
to actually determine intent behind a
cyberattack luckily there's been a lot
of international cooperation so far and
this graph is just a quick view of how
political scientists see the global
cyber regime so the different
organizations that all partner together
and work together on making the internet
run the me this is always an eye-opener
because when I saw this I wasn't really
that interested in governance yet and I
was really looking at it from an
engineering an engineer's perspective
and I saw the ITF building standards and
I saw companies implementing an
operating large parts of that internet
but there's actually a lot of debate and
discussion that ends up influencing
those decisions even before they are
made when I said there's no real global
legal frameworks there actually is at
least one that is fairly global and
that's the Budapest Convention it was
developed by the Council of Europe
in the early 2000s it was actually
started being drafted in 1997 which is
one of its problems so it was developed
before social media
it was developed before all of the
online search
we use today but perhaps most
importantly the Budapest Convention
struggles with the fact that it was was
absolutely developed by a number of
states in Europe and in the West and
today they are trying to get other
countries to adopt it and because of
that distrust that I mentioned some
other parts of the world are going to be
more hesitant to adapt adopt a legal
framework that actually comes from a
different part of the world and so
that's a big challenge that the Budapest
Convention has run into which means that
today it's only ratified by about 63
countries out of about 187 recognized by
the UN there's also been voluntary
proposals and partnerships such as the
Wassenaar arrangement which is actually
an export control arrangements for dual
use goods and it's actually fairly old
but more recently they have started
looking at technologies such as
intrusion and surveillance technology
and see how they can actually regulate
and restrict some of doubts this has
been a bit of a challenge because as
they made decisions they made decisions
that actually made the work of security
professionals very difficult so the
definition of intrusion software wasn't
very clear at a certain point in time it
even included a in many ways the
burghers that could be used to trace
code so luckily there's been a lot of
work on it over the last few years with
a lot of really solid engineers from the
community providing input to the people
designing Wassenaar and updating it one
approach that was taken by the UK
government in 2011 was to start up a new
process where a single country would
host a major conference every two years
approximately and in that conference
conference settle on a set of principles
to govern behavior so it wouldn't make
decisions per se but it would be a place
for governments to come together talk
about some of these challenges and agree
on rough outlines work together towards
more agreement that could then translate
in either treaties or laws or any other
types of output now this process has
been going on for a few years and
actually had a lot of good effects an
organization came out of this called a
global forum on cyber expertise which
has been doing a lot of
capacity-building and prepare
of documentation that new incident
responders and security teams across the
world can pick up so it's been helpful
right now it's a little bit in a dormant
phase because I think we're all waiting
to figure out where the next meeting is
going to be and what the focus of it
will be there's also been a couple of
regional approaches within ASEAN
specifically the Association of
Southeast Asian Nations there's been a
lot of work to figure out how they can
really best support cybersecurity
capacity-building more recently last
year they've started picking up a lot of
more international efforts and promoting
them within ASEAN using what they call
the ASEAN way which is really all about
building more predictable relationships
rather than having hard commitments and
an agreements within the Shanghai
Cooperation Organization there's also
been a push but that push has been more
to propose a strong international code
of conduct under the United Nations that
everyone would agree on and that process
has stalled a little bit and converted
into some other mechanisms I'll talk
about in a second now the interesting
thing about regional approaches is that
technology isn't really regional in the
sense that many technologies are built
in a country used across the globe and
it makes it quite challenging when
regions take a very specific tak for
other countries to easily trust and buy
into those approaches a little bit
similar to what happened originally with
the Budapest convention in the United
Nations there's been a lot of work
ongoing since 1998 there's actually been
an annual report from the
secretary-general of the UN on cyber
security interestingly enough can anyone
guess which country has responded to
every call since this this process
actually started it's a bit unexpected
so the country that got started
responding and continued to respond
every year was actually Cuba and the
reason why they responded was because
they wanted to flag the concern of radio
transmissions from the United States and
in propaganda into Cuba now the reason
why this is interesting is because it
shows you how different states perceive
information security
and cybersecurity so something to be
aware of that we're coming from very far
and were slowly all moving a little bit
closer hopefully um the ITU has done a
lot of work on cybersecurity capacity
building they have their global cyber
security agenda but I specifically want
to dive deep for a second into the UN
group of governmental experts which is a
group that's being convened every couple
of years of UN member states where they
actually work together and try to come
up with a consensus view on cyber
security and of one of the groups that
actually managed to gain a consensus
view of the countries participating
which was 16 in total in 2015
the UN GGE published this set of norms
as they call it which were responsible
rules of behavior for states on the
internet some of these are really
interesting for instance one of the
statements in here is that a country
should never attack the national
computer security incident response team
of another country because they really
need to be available to deal with
security incidents when they happen now
this initiative is continuing the last
one that was initiated in 2016 I believe
didn't unfortunately get to a consensus
view so they didn't publish any output
but they are starting again this year
with two different initiatives actually
both endorsed by the UN General Assembly
there will be the government group of
experts which is 25 selected member
states including Australia
congratulations that will be working on
identifying more of these types of norms
more of these types of behaviors that
should be encouraged within the global
community and then there will also be a
second group called open and that
working group which is going to be
focused on identifying and progressing
the implementation of the work that's
already been done
by the UN GGE and it's quite interesting
because both of them will allow input
from a slightly different perspective
the gge well this year allow regional
bodies such as ASEAN to provide input
and the open-ended working group will
actually allow input from nonprofit
organizations businesses and so on
so there will be a lot more
opportunities to participate now within
the UN there's also a bigger initiative
called the Internet
form which is now one of the largest UN
conferences happens once a year and it's
really intended to bring together a
multi-stakeholder community so very much
looking at it from a governance
perspective instead of a government
perspective it brings together a civil
society it brings together government
private sector and international
government to debate some of these
challenges in a very very open forum and
a few years ago this group determined
that they needed to have more tangible
outputs so they started working on
something called the best practices
forum on cybersecurity
and this is a really interesting
initiative because it actually allows
all of you as individuals or as your
companies or as your organizations to
provide input on a lot of these
challenges this year one of the things
that we're doing with the group is to
review international agreements that
have been signed either between or under
signed by countries or by different
companies and government agencies or
multi stakeholder groups and actually
looking at some of the commitments that
they make for instance one of them has a
commitment around vulnerability equities
processes and then identifying what best
practices there are that others can pick
up and implement so it can really serve
as a catalyst for this type of work and
that brings me to where the industry
today is really going or the community
is going in ox norms me and my partner
drove here from Sydney and one of the
wonderful things I noticed about
Australia was that everyone on the
highway actually drives approximately
the same speed which is fantastic that's
not a lot at least I don't think it is
in a sense that you have a minimum speed
and a maximum speed but a norm is that
you drive approximately the same speed
and even if you're not speeding if you
fly past me very very quickly you're
going to make me quite annoyed and I'm
going to react to that and in essence
you violated the norm now norms come
from saw as social science rather and
the idea behind them is that they are
collective expectations that we have on
a particular actor with a particular
identity norms emerge because people
agree that something is a right thing to
do when they start expecting it they
cascade because people start reacting to
a violation of a norm such as for in
deploying a malicious software update
and finally their internalized when
people believe it's the right thing to
do and they automatically start
implementing the right course of action
and start doing the right things norms
can come from any wide set of a
community of different organizations
both governments but also private sector
for instance Microsoft published the
norm which you see here at the bottom
which was a proposal that global ICT
companies should always issue patches to
protect users regardless of the attacker
and their motives
now norms too are not a panacea they're
not a solution for everything
there's actually three big problems with
them there's attribution when you don't
know who violated the norm it's very
difficult for you to call them out as a
norms violator it's very easy on the
road because you see who it is they have
a license plate
cyber is a little bit different there's
a problem with implementation because
states may sign up to a norm but if they
don't implement the mechanisms
internally to actually live up to it
it's not really working
and finally there's no real enforcement
so that brings us to the fact that norms
really aren't a solution for everything
in fact I would say norms loss treaties
they're all just tools but what we need
to work on as a community is getting
agreement on some of these basic issues
and we've been successful at this in
many different parts of our communities
and societies we're great at this with
search and rescue there's many different
search and rescue agreements across
countries that make helping people very
very easy in sports were fantastic at
this we do global sports events where
even countries that can't participate in
anything else can go and participate in
the Olympics so we're good at this in
some areas but we really still need to
grow and so how can you contribute I
think the most important takeaway for me
having done some of this work now for a
little while is that we need to
recognize that engineering and policy
run at slightly different speeds but the
conversations between the two need to
happen and need to be in place in order
for us to actually get what we want
which is a stable and solid internet
that we can all rely on right now we're
in this really strange place where
everyone is really lucky
at each other and trying to learn what
it is that they're doing that's working
for instance vulnerability equities
processes and the ability to weigh
whether a vulnerability that you found
as a government is something you want to
use to attack or to actually defend
everyone by reporting it to the vendor
is a very very important thing and you
see that now there's two countries that
have implemented them there's many more
that are considering doing it but the
conversation still needs to happen
there's many different forums where you
can participate some of the ones I
mentioned in the UN are very state
centric there's several that are more
open to private sector as well and civil
society the Paris call for trust and
security in cyberspace launched by
France is perhaps the best example and
so I kind of want to leave you with this
slide which gives you a bit of an
overview where you as an individual can
participate and I'll also add that
within the forum of Incident Response
and security teams we have a working
group to determine what is important to
incident responders globally and feed it
back into many of these mechanisms so
I'd also like to invite you even if
you're not a member of first feel free
to reach out and send me an email if you
have ideas thoughts because right now
what is happening is a war on of ideas
and figure out what is it actually that
all of us agree on and building from
there into a better community so it's
really important that everyone gets on
board and and provides their input and
I'd really like to invite you to become
part of the process and happy to answer
questions we're pretty much out of time
but I'll be around here after the
session so feel free to reach out to me
or send me an email and happy to get you
involved in any way that's practical for
you thank you very much
[Applause]
we do have time maybe for one or two
questions if there are any no all right
thank you very much all right thank you
and I'll give you the best speaker gift
you this is a head is absolutely the
best very much cheers and thanks
everyone
[Applause]