so it's my pleasure to introduce Nick
Nick is the vice-president of AIPAC
sales at conference Nick's responsible
for helping organizations build on their
security strategy throughout the APEC
region by helping make humans part of
the solution in every company he will be
helping deal with cyber threats it's my
pleasure to introduce Nick thank you
very much just one quick correction it's
Co fence not convinced but that's all
right it doesn't look like there's a
name in there somewhere
and I know I'm the last presentation
before coffee break so I'm going to try
to keep this as light as possible and
also as fast as possible so if I'm going
too fast just tell me to slow down I am
a Greek who speaks too fast so sorry
about that now for those that don't know
we used to be called fish meat we
changed our name in February 2018 to KO
fence and we changed our name because
predominantly fish me as a company will
the first guys to get into the security
awareness program so we were the first
company to educate customers simulate
them on phishing type of tax and fish
pee was a good name that told people
what we did we fish them that's what we
were doing as an organization but we
changed in February 2018 because we have
a very large global footprint of
customers sorry too soon we have a large
footprint of global customers and those
guys were telling us they needed more
from us in what we were doing from a
fishing perspective so we really started
to develop new tools more tools to
really help people from a fishing
perspective to stop phishing attacks and
now we changed our mission when we
changed our name and our mission is to
enable the world to stop phishing
attacks in their tracks and we do that
from a collaborative and a cooperative
defense program so the CEO is for the
collaborative or cooperative and the
fence is for defense although the
Americans spell fence with an S so
that's why it's Co fence with an S Norco
fence with a with a seat so today we're
going to talk about a few uncomfortable
truths we're going to and we've gone
through these truths with all our
customers that we
globally one of the things this slide is
telling us and this is taken from the
Verizon data breach investigation report
and there's lots of reports that say
very similar things that fishing is a
number one vector for attacks into
organizations so this is saying that
phishing and protect texting represent
98 percent of social incidents and 93
percent of breaches but emails are the
things they'd get into our customers
organizations and they caused those
breaches now as measured as mentioned we
talked to a lot of enterprise customers
across the world and and because of that
we have good relationships with
different stakeholders within the
organization and our main goal is to
understand the needs of each of those
stakeholders that we deal with from a
security awareness perspective we need
to understand what their objectives are
and how we can help build them a program
to better defend against the types of
attacks that are out there and so they
can build a campaign to launch into
their system to test their users and the
CeeCee's and executives they really want
to stop fishing so their main goal is to
understand why it's happening and where
to put the resources within an
organization and obviously the security
operation teams they're the ones that
are getting all this information they
need visibility on how to control each
of those attacks that are happening in
that in their organization but we
believe there's another stakeholder that
is critical to the team and that's the
end user so that's the people the staff
in your organization we believe there
are number one stakeholder to defend
against phishing attacks that are coming
into your organization and because of
that we've started to look at some
uncomfortable truths things that our
customers don't necessarily want to
always admit to but they have over the
last few years and because they're
admitting to them we're addressing them
upfront and the first uncomfortable
truth is no matter how good your
perimeter defenses are or your perimeter
security malicious emails still reach
the inbox and we saw that 96 percent of
attacks start from a phishing email so
we know that all our companies that we
that we serve they heavily invest in
technology and and we do as well we've
got the secure email gateways we have
all our security perimeter defenses in
place and if
organization we talked to does that as
well they put those in but those
technologies really they do a great job
in stopping the known threats that are
out there but phishing attacks are
evolving and they're changing soft and
that sometimes it's not always easy to
use just technology to stop these
phishing campaigns that come in if we
were to look at the phishing landscape
that exists out there so so we run a
phishing defense center and so we have a
large number of customers that we manage
everything for them so we send out the
campaigns we look at all the emails that
they report back and that goes into a
phishing defense Center which is based
in the USA and that defense Center gives
us so much information that we can look
at and prepare ourselves to the types of
attacks and you know the phishing
landscape as it stands at the moment
there's a lot of different things out
there from a malware
ransomware trojans I mean ransomware was
very popular in Australia about a year
and a bit ago sort of died down a little
bit now but they're still attacking
organisations using malware's of
different type sorry is my here okay and
the other type of attacks that are out
there is a credential phishing and I
heard Trustwave today they were talking
about it's it's popular it's out there
credential phishing is a is a big tech
that's happening in the marketplace but
we're also seeing a huge rise in the
spear phishing or the business email
compromised phishing we're seeing that
increased quite significantly and when
we think about those bottom two the
credential phishing and the business
email compromised or BC attacks they're
really hard to defend against just using
technology so if malware came into your
system it comes with a payload it comes
with information that you can use
technology to stop but these type of
emails when they come in they look
benign they look safe they just come in
from your normal website mail servers
and and you think these are easy to deal
with so technology won't stop them but
they're actually very threatening to the
organization the other thing that we
look at when we look at the threat
landscape is there's two groups if we
look at that big circle in the middle
there's two types of groups that are
causing the most havoc in the in the
market we put them into two high-level
groups the first one is the organized
criminal groups and they're really
responsible for the large crimeware
attacks that are
I mean across the world today and
they're very financially motivated and
they really do those large botnet style
attacks and they're also selling in the
dark web fishing tips and ransomware as
a service so that's that the number one
group that is targeting organizations
today and then the other side right at
the bottom is the nation state sponsored
groups and they're really the groups
like the apts Lazarus and cozy bears and
they're more geopolitically focused in
trying to attack and maybe even some
government government espionage type
attacks and now those two groups create
the tool box that exists in the middle
so the middle of our screen there you
can see the different types of tools
that the criminals are using to type
trying to attack each of the
organization now we're seeing probably
growth in two of those areas in the
probably eleven o´clock area you'll see
five file sharing and so this is an
attack that we're seeing that's quite
prevalent in the marketplace today so
most technologies as we mentioned can
detect malware but if you sent a link to
a Google box or Google Drive or a
Dropbox or any of those type of file
sharing sites that a lot of companies
use today that link will come in because
it's a known it might be a service that
you're using you might subscribe to to
Dropbox so if it's a known link it will
come into the inbox it'll sit within
your users email and you might have
staff click on that eat on that eat on
that link therefore creating a quite a
big attack and the other one that we're
seeing a sharp increase is probably
about three o'clock and that's the IP
geolocation awareness and and basically
that's where they're sending attacks
predominately malware attacks that will
only work in the geolocation that it's
targeted to to work in and we saw an
example of that came into our fishing
defense Center a little while ago so
that's based in the US but reporters
were reporting an attack from Brazil and
they were sending it to our PDC and our
fishing defense Center we're looking at
that email they couldn't really get
anything to happen for them because our
based in the US but everything about
that email looked like a fish it looked
like a fish's smelt like a fish but they
couldn't get it to react
in the way that the Brazilians were
saying that it was reacting so then they
our analyst changed his machine to a I
think of Brazilian IP address and then
he was able to download that malware and
it was able to see the information in
there it wasn't executing so that
frustrated him a little bit but he was
able to see the malware and he then had
pulled that malware apart inside the
malware he was able to see that it was
also requiring a Portuguese keyboard to
go on on with it
so he changed his keyboard to a
Portuguese keyboard and then that
malware executed and did exactly what it
was supposed to do so there's some
pretty large attacks that are coming
into the market now the criminals know
that if they just send malware
technology will stop it well
predominantly technology would do a good
effort in trying to stop it so they're
using this toolbox in the middle to
ensure that it's not stopped and it gets
through to your users inbox so we need
to make sure that we stay on top of that
as as much as possible and that really
brings us on to our second uncomfortable
truth and that's you can't defend
against attacks you cannot see so you
know if you think about technology
trying to stop what's in the marketplace
if it doesn't know it's not a known
threat or it can't see the threat within
there then it'll get in to the inbox and
what we want to do is make sure that the
sock gets visibility of the different
types of attack that comes into the
inbox and when we talk about visibility
from a phishing perspective we're
talking about two types of visibility
and so we'd look at it through
we call them lenses so the one on your
left the blue one that's threats that
already exist outside in the wild so
this is stuff that we know about we
might work with peer groups we might be
in the banking industry or energy
industry and we're talking with peer
groups we know about different
ransomware attacks or different types of
attacks that are out there and we stay
across those and we do whatever we can
to defend against them but the red lens
is the one that we really need to make
sure that we are focused on because the
red lens is threats inside the network
this is bypassed everything that you
already have in place and it's reached
your inbox and we call those threats
clear and present danger because this is
danger that's in your inbox it's
already happening as we speak I was
talking to someone yesterday and he said
that they have an attack that happens
every time the CEO goes away or goes on
it on a business meeting and that's
because a criminal has visibility of
that they're already in your system
they're aware that got into your system
and they're just watching what's
happening and then they create those bc
attacks from within the organization to
send emails from the ce o--'s says hey
on the way can you pay this bill and the
finance department no his away and then
they send that bill so these guys have
already got in so they're the type of
lenses that we're using and when we're
using that red lens in our PDC we get to
see some interesting information from
our customers that we're managing and
have been managing over the last few
years and I mentioned earlier that we
aren't mint and managing those customers
through that phishing defense center or
PDC so in there we manage about two
million end-user
mailboxes and those mailboxes that we're
managing these customers have been with
us for a long period of time and they're
well conditioned to look for what
phishing emails are they're also well
conditioned to report that email so we
have a plugin that they can use and they
can report that email so these are
customers that we work with very
regularly they do lots of campaigns they
try and educate their staff as much as
possible if they see something they know
to report it but even those we see that
when they report it there's one in seven
emails that have been reported that
contains a malicious or malicious
content of some sort and that's quite
square even scary when we think about it
because it's a significant volume of
emails we've got two million in users
with emails coming in and they're
reporting as much as possible so it's a
pretty big volume but the important
thing that we need to remember that our
PDC is only seeing the emails that have
been reported by our customers after
technology failed to stop it so it gets
into the inbox and they need to act on
it so whilst technology is doing a great
job stopping that volume of coming in
there are still malicious emails making
it through to that inbox so we need to
make sure that we make humans more
sensitive or make them part of our
sensors within the network to help
protect against what's out there so of
those emails those two million odd users
that have come in what have we seen well
last year this is a full year that we
saw through our PDC we saw fifty five
thousand four hundred and four
credential harvesting attack emails that
have come through these are the emails
that have been reported via those two
million users twenty seven and a half
thousand campaigns leveraging cloud
services the bottom one is a bit scary
because it says 4152 but I only updated
this two days ago the number before was
at the end of quarter three and that was
only just over eleven hundred so we've
gone from eleven hundred to four
thousand attacks in that BC space in in
less than three months so it's quite a
significant number of attacks that are
hitting our customers and then coming
through to our PDC and I'm not trying to
bash any technology but remember
technology didn't grab this on the way
way through so companies they know that
there's a problem out there and they
need to understand that they need to put
something in place they need to try and
protect against the type of attacks they
need to educate their users so it leads
us on to our next uncomfortable truth
they know that they need to put
something in place but even the best
security awareness program in the world
will never deliver a zero click rate and
I want to just pause on that for a
second of our competitors go out in the
market and they say you know you take
our program and you drive you click
right down to zero percent and you're
saved
well you're not saved someone will
always click or open an email that they
shouldn't open even if you educate your
staff some stuff move on you bring in
new people you have to re-educate them
by the time you get them recognized to
get them to ability to recognize a fish
it'll still happen they'll still click
on those links but what we're trying to
get companies to understand is this is a
real statement you will never get zero
so what we need to deal with is the real
problem and the real problem is real
fish that's the real problem the real
fish that are making it into your inbox
is not the simulations that we do not
the awareness campaigns that we do we
need to deal with the real fish that
make it into that inbox and we we want
organizations to understand and agree
with us
they are being fished regardless of what
type of organization criminals are going
to fish them and when they're fished
they need to be able to respond quickly
how do I respond to the attack that's
just happened into my organization and
then how do i best mitigate that attack
and reduce the risk to my organization
so that's what we're trying to get
companies to understand and we have a
lot of competitors in the marketplace
that say you know if you drive that
click right down I mentioned before you
can get it down to zero or as low as
possible to zero and that's going to be
your savior but it won't happen you know
in the last four years we do a lot of
campaigns
there's over 50 million simulation email
sent from our company just in in the
last four years so 15 million emails
that have gone out as simulation emails
to companies that are well aware of the
problem and we see that even though the
susceptibility rate or that click rate
is reducing it's flattening off over the
last years I think we've started hue our
quarter one so January March we're at
11.5 percent so it's really just
flattening off so 11 and a half percent
of most individuals and companies will
click on a similar oh sorry oh yeah
simulation attack so it doesn't matter
what people say about reducing that rate
you will still get people click and the
interesting thing is if we think about a
company the size of maybe two thousand
so let's just take a small organization
of about 2000 individuals eleven and a
half percent means that around about 220
230 somewhere in that space we'll click
on an email when you think about that's
less than the people in this room are
clicking on or opening up an email that
could potentially be suspicious and if
they click on it they enter the
information they could cause so much
havoc to your company to your endpoints
can be compromised so that leads us on
to our next uncomfortable truth people
say if they're clicking on it users are
the problem but we're saying users are
not the problem users can be educated
and employ to be part of your network
defense system and we use this slide to
show that so the first that red slide on
the top left hand side that was a slide
we mentioned before
that's showing that the clicking rate is
coming down so it's starting to decline
and it's flattening off as over that
same period of time we've been educating
customers that they need to use or they
need to be in a position where they're
reporting so they need to understand
that the behavior we're giving them is
if an email comes through and it looks
fishy should I click on it or what
should I do you know some of the
questions we tell our customers to ask
their staff is was I expecting this
email you know I just got an email from
the CEO saying hey can you please
transfer 1 million dollars into this
account to pay for this you know is that
my level or should I be sending a
million dollars based on the CEO does it
look like the email was intended for me
should I really be clicking on the link
or opening an attachment is there other
things I could be doing before I click
on that sort of stuff and it's really
the same sentence if it smells like a
fish then need to act on it so we're
trying to get our users to look at that
email sniff it if it doesn't pass the
sniff test report it and we have a
little button that sits in a lot of
different clients it looks like that but
a lot smaller it's a little fish and all
they need to do is click on that fish so
once they click on it that'll grab all
the relevant information you'll grab the
headers footers any attachments and
it'll send it to wherever you want to
send it to is your organization you can
send it to your own IT department you
can set it to a sock you can send it to
an MSSP or you can send it to us as an
organization and we will manage that
information and as soon as we get that
information as soon as you get
visibility on that type of attack then
that'll help save and mitigate a whole
lot of issues so left hand side is
clicking right hand side is reporting
the line underneath that is your
resiliency rate and we get that number
by dividing the number of people
reporting divided by the number of
people clicking and when you divide that
it really you can see at the bottom that
you become more resilient in actual fact
if you look at it says 1.86 so for every
one person clicking that's the left hand
side 1.8 6 percent is reporting so the
more people are reporting the more
defensive you become as an organization
because the criminals know they only
one person in your organization to click
on a link to compromise your
organization they know that that's why
they keep changing that will that
toolbox they keep trying different
attacks they just need one person to
click conversely we only need one person
to report once you've reported the
problem the sock MSP whoever is managing
this for you has the ability to act on
that information so the question that we
always pose is there we always ask our
customers which trend do you think has
the greatest impact on improved security
posture do you think it's just a click
rate alone or is it a click rate with
the reporting rate which gives you your
resiliency level and that's what we
focus on that resiliency side so there's
another uncomfortable truth from our
perspective and where are we talking
about our customers most organizations
are unable to effectively respond to
phishing attacks and we know that many
organizations we work with they've got
great organ operational teams and they
do a great job in deal dealing with the
different types of attacks that are in
the market but they're not really
equipped to understand the types of
attacks that are coming in they know
there's a problem they've created work
groups within their organization to
resolve the problem but they're not
really in the position to do that and
having a good fishing defense program in
places lots of really good benefits
around there so what we're trying to say
is get that collaborative approach when
you talk when the executives and CISOs
are talking about understanding the risk
get them working with the security
awareness teams get the security
awareness teams working with your
security operation teams because your
security operation teams when you're
clicking reporting they'll see the real
type of threats that are coming into
your organization so the sock needs to
feed that information back down to your
security awareness team and then they
can create campaigns based on real-life
threats that you are seeing as an
organization it could be BC it could be
email sort of compromised and credential
information but whatever real-life
threat you're seeing the Sauk will see
they can feed that back to your security
awareness team and then they can feed
that back up into the executives and the
ceases to create the resources needed
within your organization
to drive the right response but we are a
big believer in engaging the end-user
and educating them sorry i lost my mouse
educating them to report because the
sock really can only work on information
that they see coming in to them they can
only act on when you've sent them that
information and rather than just in
standard template so here's a template
that lots of organizations have
pre-built into the awareness program
really bespoke two ways that are
affecting your company as we mentioned
before we really want to create a
collaborative collective approach when
we're looking at threats that are
hitting that inbox and if we understand
the problem we understand that there's
real fish that are coming into your
company remember one in seven in our
environment that for those managed
customers are real fishers that are
coming into your organization so we need
to customers to grasp the fact that the
real fish is a real problem and we want
to work on that so if we imagine a fish
hits that's the the red part there is
your organization ready to understand
what happens once it's fit once it's hit
are your staff trained enough to do the
sniff test to really understand is this
a suspect email and if it is a suspect
they know what am I supposed to do you
know many companies have a process in
place and some people stick it on top of
their laptop so if they get an email
they've got a copy that email and
forwarded as an attachment and send it
to someone but most users a bit lazy so
if they see something they'll just
delete it
deleting doesn't help your company it
doesn't help what you need to do which
is why we created this little fishie
button that'll sit in outlook Gmail
Lotus Notes and whatever you use and
then you can report all that information
directly straight to your sock team and
which obviously helps so if we would
look at across that journey and that the
problem is hit your staff has suspected
the email they've reported the email
then what do you do with all those
emails that are coming in we need to
make sure that the users are aware of
sorry your sock is aware of the
different types of emails that are
coming in and prioritized the right ones
so you can then move on to the animal
analytical side and understand the
problem to then mitigate the problem and
a lot of companies out there they they
pen test or they do awareness testing
once maybe twice a year to make sure
that you know do we have a problem and
nine times out of ten they do but we're
saying get a real program in place and
fish your customers as in simulation
fishes but your staff as often as
possible so they become aware of the
issue they report more and then your
sock can handle that in a much larger
system because having a system that can
cut through all the noise is critical
you know when you're reporting
information into that report button and
then it goes into prioritize are your
socks capable of reducing the noise we
have a lot of customers that will click
on that button purely because they want
to manage their inbox so it's easier
just to click on that it deletes it and
moves it on but that's not that just
creates a lot of noise for your sock and
in actual fact when we mentioned one in
seven emails that come into our PDC and
malicious that's being six out of seven
that are coming in and not malicious so
that's again a big volume that comes
through so you want to have a system in
place that allows you to prioritize and
reduce the noise so for the spam email
that does make it through create rules
within that system that rid of the noise
so you're only looking at the real
priority emails and we also need to have
a system in place that can recognize the
credibility of those people reporting so
one of the tools that we have let's say
I'm a known spam clicker and I'm only
sending rubbish through the inbox I get
a status and my status is very low so
every time I report it when you're
looking at the dashboard they'll go this
clown he doesn't know what he's doing so
we won't open that cluster of emails
that he sent through but we might have
somebody else that's very regular
hitting and suspecting high levels of
phishing your emails that are coming
through so you can have a system in a
dashboard that highlights that high and
that means you can prioritize that
cluster of all the rest of the rubbish
our system also can collate all that
information together so even though it's
one attack they might just change a few
little things along the way it'll
collect and gather all those together so
you're dealing with the problem
a cluster making it easier to prioritize
in reading 300 emails entering in that
inbox so we need to make sure that we're
building a system that can help you move
along this kill chain along the bottom
as quickly as possible to get to that
mitigation area to stop that attack
coming through so let's go on to the
next slide which is a little example
that we had recently last year of a
global customer in in the USA so it's a
large medical organization and they use
our technology they use it very
regularly they have everything in place
they do simulations very regularly I
think they're up at about twice once a
month but then repeat offenders get done
a lot more than that during that time so
they've got 12 14 programs that come out
every year they click the button very
regularly if they see something they
click on it sends all the information
through to our phishing depends at the
phishing defense so they're very
conditioned to understand what a
phishing email looks like they're very
conditioned to report that email but
what they did is a nasty fish came
through and this fish that hit the
organization that looked very real it
came from their CEO and it was trying to
get payroll information from them but it
looked really real every single person
that was conditioned to read that email
looked at it and thought this is a real
email so we need to act on it so but
there was a link within the link there
was a fake 365 office login page and
people clicked on that link actually
thousands of people clicked on that link
within a very short period of time but
what happened was with the thousands
that had clicked on it thousands had
also reported it to our PDC so at 11:48
the email came through to our PDC and
11:49 we had already received the email
and started to go through the
prioritization of it and we realized
pretty quickly well within 19 minutes I
think was a total time that that is a
real fish it was a real problem and they
were trying to get that payroll
information from and so by 1207 we were
able to go back to the customer
tell them this is a real attack and
mitigate that whole problem no money
left that organization no attack
happened to any of the cut any of the
users in that environment
that's our 19 minute one we've just
recently put on our website a 10 minute
one so it's a little bit faster but the
attack was a little bit different so
these are the types of tools that you
need to have in place to ensure that you
can shut down an attack in a very short
amount of time
I think Trustwave mentioned before and
might have been someone else sells this
thing to the average time of the
criminal is inner network in Australia
is in months
so they're inside your network for
months before organisations find out
about it and a lot of ways as we
mentioned they get any through these
emails so to be able to work through
this kill chain from left to right in a
quick period of time will get them out
of your network as quick as possible
remember you only need one person to
report something for that to be to be
worked on so I said I'll be quick so to
summary we believe that users are not
the problem we believe that with the
right campaign in place you can educate
and ensure that your staff are
completely aware of what the real
problem is and the real problem is that
real fish entering your inbox bypassing
all the technologies that you have in
place that's the real problem that we
need to address and having the right
awareness campaign creating a reporting
culture and giving visibility to your
stock in very quick time you then can
create a easily intelligent phishing
defense program thank you very much
[Applause]