well ladies and gentlemen welcome back
till afternoon session trust you enjoyed
your morning to your afternoon until
your lunch in those parallel streets
during the course of the day it is of
course just a day about learning just
accumulating your information
challenging old ideas reassessing
paradigms if I just learnt during
afternoon tea for example something I
never knew shepherd's pie and ice cream
oh what an amazing combination so what
I'm gonna get you to do here very
quickly because I know how exhausting
roles you're all here with probably one
or two colleagues the vast bulk of you
know a couple of other people outside of
that but don't know a lot of people in
the room and you're ten statistically to
clump around to be sitting next to the
person you know best here at the entire
conference so in a couple of seconds I'm
gonna get everyone to stand up quickly
spin 360 degrees the first person you
lock eyes on I think got an idea who you
are you're going to extend the hand say
who you are hello how do you fit in and
share with that person one thing you've
learned today all that's jumped out at
you from a keynote or a parallel session
so far that you went well didn't know
Wow what's one big take out you've had
from the day so far okay then when you
do sit down I'm gonna be encouraging
again if you're close to an aisle but
could move across one side and leave a
few spare ones on the aisles that's
easier for the people who will
inevitably come in late and not have to
wobble past you so let's all stand up
everyone stand up everyone stand on
let's get the energy back here for our
final session on the count of three spin
around one two three
make a friend shake hands how are you
one take out someone you've never met
before
great stuff okay everyone sitting down
now shuffling in one suit if you can if
it's easy to leave a spare spot on the
aisle that it'd be great if you could
shuffle along one suit if it's easy to
do
everyone looking back at me now on the
gone TV focus on me okay really exciting
afternoon session for you here ladies
and gentleman this next gentleman he's
going to talk on the concept of the data
breach pipeline there are few people
better qualified in the world to do so
he knows so much about the subject he's
testified before US Congress on the
impact of data breaches on
knowledge-based authentication
authentication um I think you probably
only had to watch that footage of Mark
Zuckerberg being grilled by the US
Congress to think they those guys really
know what they're talking about that
must have been a tough day at the office
for this guy who is the founder of the
data breach monitoring and notification
service have I been pwned we all know
the site that's the site that millions
of people have gone to when they have
received that email on suggesting
they've been watched doing that sort of
stuff your race off to this website and
I hypothetically I've been told suddenly
feel a lot better about yourself and
your ongoing employment prospects and
relationship with family members anyway
let's give him a big round of applause
gonna stage Troy hunts here like Jeff
and Troy this is all yours the data
breach pipeline seems like that was a
nice intro thank you
so normally I'd sort of start off by
saying that does anyone know this
website but it's probably not much point
now who has used this out of interest
Wow okay I've got stickers for all of
you too you want to come and get them
later on so this is a recap have I been
point is a data breach notification
service when we have large data breaches
Dropbox LinkedIn Ashley Madison stuff
like that data gets spread out all the
way around the world I a grenade it load
it into that system then you can go and
figure out where being exposed our
companies can go and do things like
domain searchers figure out who in the
organization has say a Dropbox account
it's kind of interesting for a lot of
companies and the the interesting thing
about this service is it started off as
something very
back in 2013 so this was like the first
tweet ever and I thought this would be
good like a few mo mates will use it
it'll be interesting not everyone
thought it was always going to be a good
idea they thought I was gonna be like
running as spam harvesting site but the
funny thing about is is like Adam said
it kind of took on a bit of a life of
its own and and became something much
bigger to the point where it it ended me
up over here and you know like he made
it sound very serious and it was kind of
serious I had to get dressed up
everything you see me wearing there I
had to buy so I'm dressed up but today
because I live on the Gold Coast but I
had to put clothes shoes on and things
like that and I kind of didn't want to
make it too serious either like it's
it's a big event but you know let's have
some fun and I thought I should get some
cool socks
and I actually tweeted out I said has
anyone got some nice socks they want to
send me so so Foss sent me these socks
says for those about the code we salute
you and I thought I'll it'll be a bit of
fun and it'll just you know lighten the
mood a bit and it turns out that the
socks were quite popular and you can
even now go and buy a stock photo of my
socks 199 dollars off Shutterstock and
that the sort of thing that struck me
the other day is like how did this like
little project somehow end me up in
Congress with people taking photos and
selling my socks so several years on the
thing keeps growing growing because we
do have so many different data breaches
happening pretty much every day like
every day I look at my Twitter feed as a
bunch of people saying hey Cece Troy
hunt have you seen for example today
it's Flipboard everyone's getting
Flipboard notifications that was canva a
couple of days ago there's always
something now thought of the Internet is
sort of have a look at who is behind a
lot of these breaches as well because I
think there's a perception which is
often really different to the reality
and I'll give you a good example of this
so this is Talk Talk now Talk Talk is a
massive UK telco and they had a breach
in 2015 that they said customs 77
million pounds like a massive massive
amount of money now at the time when
they had the incident it was a
detective who came out and he was quoted
as saying we think it is Russian Islamic
cyber jihad ease this is a true
statement and it like it just kind of
feels like he just picked scary words
and put them all on the page and as best
I know it is none of these things other
than maybe cyber which let's face it is
a little bit generic so it turns out it
was actually this guy and he's leaving
court here after having to answer for
his actions you can't see his face
because it's a 17 year old child 77
million pounds of damage 17 year old
child now he was actually 16 when he
broke in to talk talk using sequel map
freely available sequel injection
software did the 77 million pounds with
the damage the lawmakers there took it
quite seriously
they took his iPhone away which like in
fairness for a 17 year old is probably
like hell right but the thing that
strikes me is how often it is like
children who are breaking into these
systems even great big multinationals
and that the thing about kids and
hacking these days is they have access
to so much material to be able to do
this and I want to give you an example I
went over to YouTube and I thought look
all I'll pull a video that demonstrates
hacking and there's a gazillion of them
on YouTube I thought I'll pull one which
is probably shows how simplistic the
threat actor for one of a better term is
have a quick listen to this guy let's do
a professional video let's actually show
you how the concept works and I'm using
them the SQL or school method here a
school injection it's like as mayor
right is this and I don't know if it's a
squirrel or a chipmunk but I know it's
not a sequel so you've got kids creating
videos about how to break into systems
you gonna see what he does next in the
moment and they literally can't even
pronounce sequel so anyway he starts
doing this tutorial and he goes off and
he does his google dork and he wants to
find websites that
have a query string parameter in them
that he can then take and put into
automated software so he ends up on this
site here and this is a gold bullion
trading site so have a look what he does
once he gets over here okay so with this
extension what we do is put a little
apostrophe here no comma ish put it
there press ENTER and then okay so this
means that we have an error in the
database so there's an error in their
database so and their database is my SQL
Server there you so a because it to my
skill hormones go out we can target it
and grab all the info now one thing to
think about here as well is what do you
think it's like the kids sitting at home
watching this stuff right like they
don't have that moral compass yet of
what it means to do what he's beginning
to do because he's just out of parameter
tampering he's putting apostrophe in
there somewhere some are in the
application they concatenate in whatever
that crew string value is into a sequel
query obviously not doing any
sanitization parameterization he's
established to proof he grabs the URL
goes and throws in a havoc free sequel
injection software shows you how to pull
out all the email addresses all the
passwords and then he logs into the site
with them now like I was watching this
and going oh it's one thing to do this
it's another thing to video yourself
doing it and put it on YouTube as a
tutorial for other people so once he's
authenticated he can pull out banking
data and this is a child whose voices
probably just break in can't yet
pronounce sequel it's just too easy so
one of the things that I think the
industry's starting to focus on a little
bit more is how do we tackle this like
how do we start to think about getting
kids on the right pathway and the NCAA
in the UK is starting to focus on this
quite a bit as well so I want to show
you this a little short clip here I got
this advertisement of how they're trying
to reach parents it's a little bit of
fun but have a think about how
representative this is of most parents
out there whose kids hacking away in
their bedroom in the
sort of absolutely no idea what they're
doing oh he's such a clever boy boy mr.
Queen spends all night oh listen how
smart is this you know them shooter
games the other day he was losing so he
crashed the server Papa wizkid it's
amazing what kids can do these days no
darling or what did they call it
ddossing that's it I saw it on the telly
please no dasa they were only a hundred
percent in maths every single exam for
the last two years not to mention his
GCSE coursework that's gonna go down the
m11 to Cambridge Computer Sciences
degree top career in computing internet
billionaire by the time he's 25 the next
steve gates I know he's very clever but
his money too we only give him a tenner
a week doubles he robbed a bank
and that the thing is like it's very
close to the truth right most parents
have got no idea about the technology
that their kids are using and then the
kids don't yet have that moral compass
and we end up with things like what we
saw just before now cause a lot of these
breaches impact passwords we saw
passwords on the previous screen who
used them to then go and authenticate to
the app so I thought it'd be worthwhile
just recapping on on passwords briefly
in terms of where we've come from and
where we're going as well because
there's a lot that is actually changing
and on that first bit the bit where
we've come from this is MIT in the 60s
and this is believed to be the
first-ever case of having a password on
a computer system so this was a
compatible time sharing system you'd go
into this room of computer and you'd log
in and then you would have access to
whatever it is you did with a computer
that filled up a room back in the 60s
now if we think about the threats we had
then and the threat actors and the
access that they needed first of all I
had to have physical access you had to
be in the room this was not a connected
system you couldn't go home and dial in
when you got in there you need a
sophisticated knowledge I don't know
what you do when you get in there maybe
take Miko's punch card from this morning
and put it in on something who knows but
you've got to know what you're doing
which is really different to today
there's no password reuse because it was
the first system that had a password so
there's that problem gone and you could
use basic passwords because your risk
surface was so small but the way
passwords worked back then the first
time ever it's still pretty much the
same as they work today you've got two
strings in your head ones are using they
ones you password if the ones in your
head match the ones in your system you
get to log in job done but the 60s is
very very different to today yet the
same mechanism is how pretty much every
system we use today works so that was
the sixties now we move forward go
forward a couple of decades get to the
80s we start getting connected systems
so this was a press tell and press tell
was used by about 90,000 people you'd
plug this computer into your TV because
we didn't have computer monitors in the
home at the time you'd plug it into a
modem and you dial in
once you dialed in you doth entik eight
this is a little BBC clip which shows
how to log in to the press tell the rest
of computers now ask me to enter my own
personal password which I've now done
here I get that let's zoom in enhance
see what's going on right like one two
three four
so what we're sort of seeing here is
humans taking the path of least
resistance it's like ah something's in
my way how quickly can I get around this
thing not much quicker than one two
three four I assume the minimum length
of the password was four otherwise it
would have been one two three or
something like that so this is now more
problematic than MIT in the 60s because
it's a connected system you've got
people remote you've got more people
with enough knowledge to use the system
compared to the 60s we go forward
another couple of decades get to
Internet era get to the 90s we've got
millions of websites billions of people
using them and people are using bad
passwords like in the press tell so we
said all right we're going to fix this
the way we're going to fix this is we're
going to create password complexity
rules now we've got a bit of file
footage of Bob here at Bob's trying to
create an account on a website and the
website says to keep your password
secure it must have at least one
lowercase character at least one
uppercase character it's got to have a
number it's got to have a non
alphanumeric character it's got to be at
least eight characters long you can't
have used it in any of the last three
passwords and now Bob is losing his mind
because he can't create a password and
we have all been there right it is
painful so what do we do we create
passwords like this and this is a good
password cricket's okay
it is a good password by the
mathematical definition of what most
people think makes a good password
because think it through right you got
upper case lower case number non
alphanumeric that's actually 15
characters long too yet we look at this
as humans and we recognize patterns and
we think we'll know maybe maybe there's
more to password strength than just
mathematics yet still it meets that
basic criteria and any one of you could
go back to your places of work on Monday
and create this password at the office
now if you did that what is going to
happen 90 days from now got a rotator
right what are gonna do 90 days from now
you put a 1 on the end and the funny
thing is every time I do this look
there's always everyone that's going
yeah you just put a 1 on the end cuz you
all do it I know you do it I've seen
your passwords so so we do this and
again it's humans circumventing the
controls that get put in place we know
this the hackers know this like I hate
to break it to you they have worked this
stuff out and time goes by and we just
keep incrementing the number because
this thing is in our way and there's a
fun trick you can do so take the number
that's at the end of your password right
now divide it by 4 that's how long
you've been at the company works doesn't
it so this is all very very predictable
we know what's happening but what
happens is when we enforce arbitrary
complexity rules and we force rotation
people take shortcuts they do things to
try and remember what the password was
which actually weakens it I'll give you
a perfect example of this remember last
year in Hawaii that emergency response
system went off and everyone thought I
were going to get bombed because their
phone started getting all the messages
they went and interviewed this guy
afterwards and he's here in this
emergency response center and they're
kind of interviewing me know like what
happened why did the thing go off where
they're real any bombs and he's standing
in front of the screens there and
there's something alarming down here
they're still using Internet Explorer
and he's got his password paste
on-screen and this is what happens and
again is people trying to find the
shortcuts around the controls that are
standing between them and doing the
thing that they're there to do in the
first place so this is changing and
here's where it gets sort of interesting
there's a couple of really interesting
things that are starting to come out
from industry bodies about how we should
do this differently and the first one
thought we'd touch on is from nest so a
nest came out a couple years ago and
said we should not impose composition
rules for memorized secrets
so verifiers applications shouldn't say
uppercase lowercase alphanumeric
because it's such a predictable result
yeah you think about if you're gonna try
to just use a lowercase password and it
says now you got to have an uppercase as
well yeah okay so your uppercase the
first character got to have a number as
well you put a 1 on the end got to have
a non alphanumeric character you put an
exclamation mark on the end it is so
predictable time and time and time again
stop requiring this because people take
shortcuts make things worse the NCSC in
the UK around the similar time City
should only ask users to change their
passwords on indication suspicions are
compromised unless you think the
password has been compromised stop
forcing people to rotate it now they
don't just say get rid of stuff either
they say look stop doing that but there
are other things that we can do now that
we couldn't do before we have almost
ubiquitous 2fa we've got things like u2f
tokens we've got user behavioral
analytics we can see deviations from the
norm we've also got more encrypted
networks than ever as well so the
exposure of passwords is different to
what it was say even just 10 years ago
let learn 20 years so this is how
passwords are evolving and how we need
to start thinking differently about them
and over time these will start to filter
through more Microsoft just recently
updated a bunch of their baseline
guidance for Windows Server and for
desktop PCs so look we're going to
remove the rotation requirement things
are progressing
they also on the subject of passwords
we're seeing huge exposures of them in
numbers that we've never seen before
this was in January and there emerged
what was referred to as collection one
and collection one was a list of
usernames and passwords pairs often
referred to as a credential stuffing
lists someone sent this data to me and
turned out there were seven hundred
seventy three million email addresses in
there there were more than a billion
passwords because many email addresses
had more than one password and this was
an amalgamation of different breaches
from different services I was in there
including a password I'd used in the
past and people take these lists and
then exploit the victims why I picked it
up
CNET picked it up 21 million unique
passwords also do the math seven hundred
and seventy three million emails but
only twenty-one million unique passwords
what does that tell you not so good at
the passwords fortune I always find the
fortune stuff interesting because now
it's like consumer mainstream media this
is not just technical people anymore
it's the sort of thing my parents would
read here's how to find out if your
email address was one of them they sent
people to have I been part I got 10
million people come to the site in the
day that was fun I don't think I've
recovered quite yet now often you see
this sort of stuff and a combination of
the press and I think a lot of the
masses they go are must have been on the
dark web because I keep hearing about
the dark web the dark web sounds very
scary this is where the criminals go on
they distribute the data and they sell
the drugs and everything now a lot of
this is on the dark web it's also on
Twitter and this is the reality of it
most of the time when people send me
data is floating around the clear web I
know it doesn't sound as scary and I'm
so sorry for the vendors who are trying
to sell stuff just based on what's on
the dark web but a lot of it is just
floating around in the clear so this
says you can see its collections 135 I
had collection 1 773 million unique
email addresses that was about 8% of all
the collections combined so this float
around Twitter it's on mega Diane said a
lot of the
oh I see gets redistributed on mega
because it's a good file-sharing service
raises the question now what do people
do with this right so imagine you've got
let's say round numbers you got a
billion email address password
combinations what do you then do with
them I won't put a bit of a clip there's
another tutorial about how to abuse
credential pairs so what we're gonna see
is how to mount a credential stuffing
attack or what is going on with these no
welcome back to a brand new video here
on the channel now in this video I'm
gonna be showing you guys a checker of
me for Spotify account so you can check
if the accounts are valid now Spotify
really really frequently features as the
target of credential stuffing attack so
I get emails from people all the time
they go hey did you see Spotify had a
data breach because a whole bunch of
credentials have appeared on paste bin
now this is not generally what has
happened and we're gonna see as this guy
goes through the process how Spotify has
a air quotes data breach so let's have a
look at the checker he's made but before
we start I just want to say that this is
for educational purposes only and this
is obviously not made for checking
cracked accounts you guys know one of me
this is for checking your own accounts
if you guys got multiple so you guys
don't have to check one by one and this
will make it a lot easier alright so
let's just be clear about this you have
so many Spotify accounts you can't
remember which ones work any more so you
need this script to go and check your
credentials keep this in mind it will
also tell you guys if the account is a
Spotify premiums by 2phi family or a
Spotify student whatever you have so
many you also can't remember what type
of account you created but you'd like to
know it would be nice if there was a
tool to help you establish this but
before you open this actual program
you're gonna make sure you have combos
all right as we start to get to the
pointy end of it so combos are username
password combinations and we're seeing
like one tiny tiny little bit of a
snapshot of what a credential stuffing
list looks like email address password
over and over and over again a billion
times so let's have a look at what he
does with the combo
you're gonna typing combos and then
threads let's do four this time so it
goes a bit faster so as you guys can see
already we got eight hits as you guys
can see it keeps getting hit because
these accounts are high quality aka HQ
as you guys can see we keep getting hits
I don't care if you guys steal these
accounts I have about 9,000 at the
moment
well here's two it's rather miraculous
isn't it now all he's done here is his
script he's gone to his Spotify and he's
had a look let's ask the Spotify API for
example sits behind the mobile app he's
looked at it he said okay what's the
HTTP request pattern which logs on
that's a post request to this path
there's a field called password and a
field called user name I'm just going to
automate that and then I'm going to
multi thread it and I'm going to pass in
a big list go outside and play Bob's
your uncle now he's got 9,000 accounts
the challenge for us and challenge for
you guys is how do you defend against
that how do you defend against a request
coming to your site legitimate username
legitimate and password but not the
actual person that owns it and this is
becoming a really really big problem and
there are so many tutorials like this
out there I wrote a blog post recently
about the fact that most of these
Spotify breaches I say just successful
credential stuffing and I embedded a
video and then it got taken offline so I
embedded another one and I got taken
offline so I embedded this one and it's
still there there's just a heap of them
they're all over YouTube so data
breaches and passwords are a massive
thing data breaches and connected things
are also becoming a massive thing and I
thought I'd touch on a few which have
hit either have I been poned or my radar
in recent times and the first ones this
one has anyone got one of these thank
God okay so here's the value proposition
this is a cloud pet so imagine you've
got a kid in bed you know wanting to
talk to Mum cuz she's working late and
phones are boring so why not get them a
connected teddy bear with a microphone
in it and put it in their bed I know so
anyway this is what they were they're
basically dead now the company's gone
bankrupt but they're connected teddy
bears they've got a little light that
flashes when a message comes in they've
got a button in the poor they've got a
microphone I've got a speaker
now when you record a message through
this it goes up into the magic of the
cloud and it's stored up their cloud
pets stored all of their data in a
MongoDB publicly facing without a
password and then it looked like this
your database is backed up in our
service send one Bitcoin to this address
and send your IP to that email address
now there are about five hundred and
sixty odd thousand accounts and there
someone did grab them sent them to me
for ever been pwned
but then it later got ransomed like this
now we know that this is what it looks
like because we pulled logs at a
showdown and we can go back and actually
see the state of the database at the
time we also know that to other people
subsequently came along and change the
Bitcoin address to their own which okay
it is kind of alright you know you don't
have to do the crime maybe you get some
of the proceeds incidently no way it's
backed up either it's just been Newt and
the thing is is that this happened and
then the cloud pets came back online and
nobody got told
so obviously the company knew continuing
the IOT thread we're seeing IOT in all
sorts of places we never had it before
in cars for example so this is an S and
leaf the nests and leaf has a companion
app so that you can do things like pull
back the battery status it's an Eevee
you can pull back the trip history you
can also control features of the car so
you can turn the heating on I was in
Norway doing a workshop and we do this
exercise where you you take your phone
you route it through your PC you have a
look at the traffic going backwards and
forwards just by naturally using an API
and actually using an app they'd hit
take the eyes and you draw certain
conclusions about the security posture
and one of the blokes in my workshop had
one of these cars and he was curious he
said I wonder how my phone knows which
car to turn the heater on
because in Norway it's so cold you've
got to be able to turn the heater on
before you get into or you freeze to
death or something like that
so as alright this must be some sort of
API care but maybe it's a bearer token
or something stored within the app and
then when I go and turn the heater on
since the bearer token over a secure
connection turns on my card doesn't mess
with anyone elses car so he proxies his
phone through his PC he looks at the
traffic and he discovers that the API
key so the secret that allows you to
control features of a car is printed in
the windscreen of the car they used the
VIN number as the API key now not only
is it printed in the windscreen of a car
so you can walk around and start taking
photos of cars and go in my car my car
my car you can also enumerate them
because the last five digits you can
just keep guessing numbers and finding
more cars and this was another example
of how hard it is also to get
organizations to the right thing so
after we found this I got in touch with
ness and privately and said look I think
you should kind of fix your cars because
this isn't real good and I said yeah
we'll fix it this is very important and
eventually they just grew a bit tired of
it they stopped answering my emails and
it took a month before I discovered that
someone else had found the same
vulnerability and the way I discovered
this is there's a forum where people
were commenting on how terrible the
mobile app is and someone reverse
engineered it and said hey look all you
got to do is go to this URL replace the
VIN number with yours put that as a
favorite in your browser and then when
you get up in the morning you go to the
bookmark job done heaters on so that had
to go public because they wouldn't fix
it they decided it was important after
it went public amazing thing and this is
one of the issues we see organizations
having trouble dealing with security
incidents as well we had an issue just
locally only a couple of months ago
similar sort of deal there's a company
called tick-tock track and they make a
GPS tracking watch for kids in fact they
don't actually make the watch the watch
is made by a company called Gator they
make the application layer that sits on
top of it they make the mobile app they
make the api's and a mate of mine in the
UK a guy from a pen testing firm called
Ken Munro
ken reached out and he said look we've
been looking at a bunch of these watches
and they're kind of as terrible as what
you would expect a really cheap internet
connected device to be and they'd found
a whole bunch of problems in late 2017
in fact that found so many problems that
we had things like Norwegian consumer
protection council saying just don't get
these things
Germany banned them they're just like
nope destroy them they literally said
destroy them because they're all so
sharp - she's listening devices you'll
see this in a moment so he believed that
there was a security vulnerability in
these he needed someone in Australia so
he called me when and got one of these
and I had to go to the website in order
to purchase it so I went to the site and
then I saw there was a padlock and I
felt much better no not really also
noticed in that second power there it
says we take the security of your data
seriously now normally when I see
someone say that it's in the breach
notice which is explaining how they just
didn't so it's not really a good leading
statement in my experience so anyway I
thought I'll go and get one anyway
because this is interesting right like
we want to see is this vulnerability
which Ken believes is in the watch
actually there so I wouldn't got one and
I put it on my six-year-old daughter
so this is L and as you can see it's
it's branded gator it's made by Gator in
China and then tick tock Trek put there
a player on top and we started having a
look at the api's and we found an api
like this and it says yeah get users
this is going to pull back information
about the family and all you do is pass
through an ID now because Kansas smart
guy and he can count he can hack so all
he did is change the number change the
number another family like this is the
level of sophistication these are
physical devices that we're using to
look after our children so when you hit
that API response comes back it says
here's your family we get a whole bunch
of JSON back here there's my email
address name
then you can start making calls to other
eight the eyes so you can go out and
actually get yourself a child and I know
this is alarming why is this a post
request when you're pulling back an
entity this is not right
anyway also you can just change the ID
and pull back another family now that
there was off on this and it went like
this
are you authenticated yes sweet go for
it it's not like I authenticated also
are you actually trying to retrieve the
entity that you're authorized to
retrieve so that that bit was kind of
missing and for any of you that actually
tests this stuff and look for it this is
like one of the most obvious things that
you would look for one of the absolute
first things in secure direct object
references the gift that keeps giving so
you could retrieve a child you could
relocate a child and this is where it
starts to get weird because parents have
these things in order to track where the
children's our children's our kids are
so the problem there is that if you can
start to relocate the child to some
arbitrary location it kind of completely
destroys the whole premise of having the
watch in the first place so we tested it
we sent hell off to tennis just over
here in Southport and I opened up the
app and she was that tennis and me my
helicopter parent modem are good I know
she's safe and then Kem dumped her in
the ocean
because he can do this because he can
put her wherever he wants because ken
can count got worse than that as well
and that the bit that got worse is that
these Watchers do take a 3G SIM card so
they can operate as a phone as well so
the parent can call the child but it
would be weird if just any person could
call the child so there's an API that
lets you set who the parent is and by
now you can probably see where this is
going to be going so Ken gets hold of
the API and he said look we're going to
make some changes we want to give you a
call so we get out in her bed and he
gets one of his colleagues Vangelis he
said look Vangelis yeah obviously you
found the vulnerability in the API let's
let's see what we can do with this so
have a look at what Vangelis does
[Music]
and when I first saw that I was like
holy this is actually feels really
scary like our kyle is there videoing up
but just why is this possible and then I
remembered what ken can count and this
is what we are where we are
so these vulnerabilities keep popping up
again and again again and to their
credit tik-tok track did actually take
the service down very very quickly but
they had a lot of trouble actually
understanding what went wrong and
started throwing around blame and things
like this and this is one of the
problems we have as well there's so many
organizations out there that just aren't
equipped to deal with the data breach of
any kind who don't realize that people
like Ken Monroe is a legitimate
straightforward guy who's only there
trying to fix broken things like this
and I thought look we should sort of end
this on a really good example of how
companies are having trouble
communicating and I saw a recent case
involving this now this is a biometric
padlock and there's a guy called the
lock picking lawyer he's got a YouTube
channel where he does physical
penetration testing of padlocks it's
really fascinating actually gets big
locks and he's like you know how how can
either pick them or how much effort does
it take to break them so anyway he's
picked up this lock this biometric lock
and he's going oh look at that there's a
screw now the screw does exactly what
you're thinking it does right it's like
you get your screwdriver out you undo
the screw and the lock opens up that's
not the good bit the good bit is he's
like okay well we got to do the right
thing we've got to disclose this
privately so he gets in touch with them
and says look I've got one of your looks
I have a screwdriver I managed to get in
there and they replied and they said our
locks are invincible to people who do
not have a screwdriver
and this is pretty much where we are
today thanks very much
can I just ask it up fantastic
presentation one quick question before
we go cuz I judge about the Zuckerberg
stuff but I've heard anecdotally that
the stuff that got online about the you
know the guys asked me how do you make
money out of it well we run ads and all
that but it in fact that I believe that
testimony kept going and there were some
senators while some quite informed
pointed questions what was your
experience of that did some of those
people they really know their stuff was
an embarrassing how far off the pace
they work and you summarize it in a
generalization or did it vary across the
people use spokes so what I actually
learned is when they ask questions
they're not their questions so they all
have liked it in fairness they're there
they are doing like testimonies on
things like the opioid epidemic the day
before so they're going from like
serious health care stuff to serious
cyber stuff so they have staffers that
prepare all the questions and the
questions were actually pretty good I
thought so but so the questions were
reasonably point what were they trying
to get and what do you think they came
away with what did they come away with
is a benefit from the testimony that you
guys provided so the premise was what's
the impact on knowledge based
authentication so you know how like your
bank calls up and they're like we just
want to make sure you are who you are
what's your date of birth and you're
like oh crap it's that thing that's in
all these data breaches they wanted to
sort of understand how that as a means
of authentication really doesn't work so
well anymore so yeah my bit was data is
all over the web you really can't rely
on this stuff anymore and I think they
got that the trick now is to see what
actually comes as a result so this was
about 18 months ago we did that has
anything happened yet where are they on
are they moving slowly well we still got
a hell of a lot of data breaches so
hasn't changed that look I think
organizations are moving slowly because
we're getting better means of
authentication so stuff like u2f keys
and now all over the place and lots of
support for that so we're kind of moving
in that direction but it's got to be
slow cuz the one thing that
knowledge-based authentication does
really really well is everyone has
knowledge and everyone knows how to use
it it's it's week but the accessibility
are it's off the charts give him a big
round of applause as he walks past grabs
his elder chess set on the way through
as well
get your daughter playing some Zelda
chess thank you so much Troy what a
fascinating just on behalf of everyone
here I want to thank you for keeping us
safe from those Russian Islamic cyber
jihadis they are the worst our final
presentation today again from another
one of our platinum sponsors we could
not have also the way we do without the
support of our platinum sponsors talking
on threat intelligence and automating
security processes from the good people
at threat connect this is Director of
Sales Engineering at threat connect
Chris Adams give Chris a round of
applause all yours
thank you all right intelligence the
first time I really thought about the
challenges of intelligence in a
defensive perspective is following 9/11
and when you think about all the
information that came out following the
attacks if you're like me or all this
information was coming in and you felt
like how could this not be obvious right
that's the the benefit of hindsight but
if you really think about the the types
of things that were going on if we think
about the pilots for example okay three
pilots were being trained on US soil
both in California and in Florida you
had six of those pilots who were
frequently traveling between the United
States and Saudi Arabia frequently four
or some number of those were involved in
the ham Hamburg cell in Germany so
there's obvious link there and actually
two of the pilots failed their training
training for Cessnas and even though
they had failed training they had asked
to train on Boeing large aircraft and so
in hindsight when all this comes out and
you think how could they not have
connected to the dots well you have to
think that there are over 15,000
trainings per year each all the systems
independent right there is no one giant
system where all that information might
be stored you have hundreds of thousands
of people traveling back and forth
between the US and in places in the
Middle East where they might be some
cells where they were doing some type of
activity right or communicating with
people who are orchestrating this so
that's a hard problem because these are
large disparate type systems some of the
some of the critique of the agencies
after the fact were you know criticisms
on what type of processes those Intel
agencies had were their formal process
connecting all those things so in
hindsight you'd love to see that data
superimposed where it becomes clear but
there was no real process to do all that
and so thread Intel in the cyber realm I
as I like to think about things in that
grant perspective obviously it's a
different realm and cyber compared to
the traditional defense if we think
about what threat intelligence means in
the cyber realm you can look at this
definition by Gartner kind of R or D
I'll let you read that real quick my
summary definition right is knowledge of
threats and capabilities right of
infrastructure motive intent right so if
that's what threat Intel is that's not
an easy thing right that isn't it's hard
understand that deep when you see the
types of things you're looking at day in
and day out how do you know what the
real motives are what are the
capabilities what are the
infrastructures are using it takes time
to put this picture together and so
anyone who thinks about threat Intel and
everyone's at varying levels of maturity
and knowledge about it I like this this
is a an idea that you know everyone
belongs somewhere on this plot right far
left interested in it don't really know
how to engage and begin to use trying to
tell I won't read through all these
things in detail for the sake of time
but you can kind of think that you're
beginning to start to use it you might
even begin to start creating it you
might begin tying it into things that
you're seeing in incidents or in in your
sock you begin to start automating some
processes and over time you've
established a methodology right for
creating in
chain pulling that content in and so
without getting into too much detail to
moving to that left side to the right
there's I'll just talk about three key
things that most organizations can just
think about as in these are capabilities
you want to sort of bring online so to
start you know mention those being as we
go through here so to start aggregating
information aggregating phenol we got to
be careful about words right it's we're
aggregating threat data potential this
is a lot of data you don't know if it's
intelligence yet intelligence comes
through a process right but one of the
key things is establishing you know a
repository where you're putting
throughout and the threat intelligence
this is one of the first practices and
just sure everybody in the room has some
method and I'll argue that even if it's
an Excel spreadsheet that's a start
right collecting information over time
that you believe I have some some some
knowledge that you want to share and
begin to sort of enrich and grow and
analyze and so the key to that is having
a data model a data model is gonna help
you describe how where that data comes
and fits in and so those are indicator
types right IP addresses addresses email
addresses host URLs malware events just
a quite a bit there but in the end
you're the the goal would be to have if
you have multiple sources of threaten to
tell it could be from government sources
it could be Oh sent phishing emails you
have laying around the the team that you
you realize you have to aggregate and be
able to start pulling into the process
if once you once you begin to establish
a data store where you can pull that
content in and it's sort of represented
here with you know multiple sources when
you have an ability to deduplicate that
information normalize it find
associations of cross that this is when
you begin to be able to make sense out
of all the into all the information you
might be pulling in okay so I like to
say that from my experience in working
in government you want to establish a
system of records system of record and
in traditional sense means that you're
building the authoritative source of
threat Intel for your organs
a lot of government's want to you know
it's it's a it's a play to try to become
the system of record and I think every
organizations need needs one and that
way when you have analysts come and go
from your team you retain all that
information and you have that to work on
as things go forward so that's a bit
about aggregating threat information
this second thing is analyzed and
analyzing information can mean a lot of
different things it's getting enrichment
from other sources it's being able to
sort of make sense out of what that what
type of data it is that you're looking
at and there are a few models that I
think should be embraced by teams to
drive that analysis work so some one of
the more plates straightforward
approaches is the diamond model for
intrusion analysis that's the idea that
anything involving a threat is some type
of activity you have a bad guy you have
a good guy that's being you know the
victim in the situation you have
infrastructure that's used to launch
some type of capability okay that's it's
a crime scene
right there's always an actor there's
always some element of that in that in
that scenario if you begin to think
about things in that way then you start
forcing your mind when you see pieces of
information it begins to make you want
to think how do I want to organize this
data how do I want to structure it how
do I want to share it with my team and
then you get into a bit bit more insert
of the extent of you know deeper models
provided Lockheed Martin and everybody
probably knows the kill chain miters
more recently popular attack these get
into much more granular detail and we
see a lot of products coming online that
begin to support those they're all good
to me a team that establishes a
methodology a practice is really the key
thing get the team to speak in the same
language right when you're that's really
the key part is building something
establishing something so that when new
people come on the team there is a
methodology approach that's a big key
part about discovery into turning threat
data into Intel
and it's establishes a proper practice
practices for your team and I'll just
give a little for people who aren't
familiar with attack it's quite complex
but it's kind of fun to look through
here in fact while Troy was talking I
was trying to think about where do some
of these things fit in on some of those
but I like to think about your you're
looking at you know the whys and then
the house if I want to establish some
persistent type of presence
I mean Network I want to create an
account right if I can get the crown and
then I want to escalate my privileges I
might use some passed the hash technique
and start moving around somebody's
infrastructure right so there's always
sort of a mindset now when you begin to
pull information in and learn more about
what you're saying if you begin to start
thinking where do i classifies that by
this it's a lot better than just having
a lot of data in a spreadsheet that says
oh I should be concerned about these
things and and so that's a little bit
about aggregating content a little bit
about analyzing until you begin to start
operationalizing and that's a loaded
word familiar but we can think we want
to begin to start moving that
intelligence around in our
infrastructure because until I can I can
have six billion indicators with someone
telling me that's all bad it really
doesn't mean anything until I find out
that there's an indicator in some feet
that matches data that I have in my logs
all right so that's all the sudden your
eyes are widened and you think I got to
do something right because you've you
now have some proof that that resides in
your network and so I believe you know
threat Intel is becomes that lifeblood
that flows through the environment where
it's really a feedback loop between your
infrastructure and what it is you've
learned and what is you've pulled in and
that's not just from a system
perspective
I mean sometimes the fun part the
integrations and seeing how you can pull
things and get products to work together
but it's also people its people from I
are seeing something sharing that
collaborating within an environment
becomes a very important
part of that what we call dissemination
within our in within the organization
and so I'm gonna when you begin to start
you know systems can permit that type of
integrations right just from I'd say
some from central store via api's you
have this a new word that's making its
way sore right this is security
orchestration being able to automate
some type of response to that there's a
pretty graphic from Gartner making this
official technology and you have a
really a kind of a healthy cycle here of
detect triage respond responded
prioritize there's some value in this
and I thinking this is like a
traditional really cycle for analysis
right and things you want to do and
being able to orchestrate processes I'm
an IT guy I love tech right but I don't
believe you can just automate your way
out of out of problems I think what you
do is find ways to optimize what the
team is doing I'll show some examples of
this in a minute but orchestration is
really just the concept that a team you
know security is maturing right there
should be established processes some of
that of which you can automate some that
you're not you don't need to we're not
trying to turn security into something
that's you know built just be
self-healing there are reason for
analysts what's or does promise and the
automation the part of things is to give
your analyst more time to really focus
on the analysis part and relieve some
time from the things of the the things
that can be automated and so I'd like to
thank you know as a tech person right
this isn't I say down to the bottom
right this is nothing new it's not new
in the sense that in IT in general
there's been automation forever right
people are old as I back in the you know
days when Enterprise Service bus Azure
the rage and for the IT stack right
Message Queuing Web Services these are
technologies that will lets if we call
security a department in an organization
like finite like finance
Logistics operations all the different
departments you have they have grown up
stacks of products security is just
seems to be this like let the the last
to become an official department that
deserves technologies the tie systems
together many times
security stacks you know they're grown
organically no one no one typically
people don't define an enterprise
architecture and then start filling
things in right departments they get a
firewall they get an IDs proxy right
everyone knows how things grow in
Greenwich and then the fight is how do
you get these things to talk to each
other and so sore is that realization
that it's maturities cut that you know
security is now becoming a first-class
citizen that's in the end it is just
data right and having an approach to
managing that data is what we're looking
for so let's just look at a couple
examples of what I think are some of the
key examples for people just to think
about from a malware analysis
perspective in this case take malware
file be loaded into your tip there's
some context of where it came from files
then sent to an AMA tool you parse the
results of that and then maybe present
some of that information you came back
from that report so in that case perhaps
some iOS sees that came out of what that
malware did are collected they're pulled
back into your tip perhaps speeds that
you that you have pulled into your into
a central store now give us some context
of what that is and if you could then
search a sim or search something and you
can see if that had some effect on you
so this is something maybe you know a
lot of analysts will do everyday if you
can automate that so that you're just
seeing the results of anything you sent
that you're saving a lot of time and
value ever over a period of time for a
little bit more sophisticated type of
example this is something we had built
just a designer from a customer's
perspective is what if I take you fish
right everybody how could something how
many phishing emails do people get
inundated with every week if I can
automate a process where I'm sending
every fish to an environment we're
parsing taking off
petter body attachments we're running
all those through enrichment sources in
this case we're looking you know taking
something and detonating malware in a
malware analysis platform taking that
information back and it like I mentioned
earlier a few parts and then can search
your sim and find out have any of those
indicators a bit in my environment well
maybe then my result is I create a
ticket or maybe I lock the ad account of
that user just to prevent them and say
send them a note slack message that they
have to talk to IT before they can log
into their account again alright so a
little bit sophisticated use case the
key is that this is all possible these
are things that you can do you can
modify those flows to your heart's
content you can introduce a person in
the loop and say before I take this step
I actually want to be able to make a
decision here I don't want something to
follow all through this right and so the
key thing to take away with this is that
with the advent of automation in this
sense it's and I consider this where we
were talked about that maturity curve
kind of here then at far right where
we're trying to identify the things that
art seemed to waste a lot of our time
and I think I've seen in terms of
benefiting one-man teams or one-person
teams who are running security up to
having teams of 60 people there's always
a means for being able automate and
that's part of what I understand to be
very beneficial for organizations it's
so cost when I have to just mention this
real quick
part of what you want to try to achieve
in turning like return on investment
right what is all what does automation
offer well you can calculate the amount
of time it takes to do certain things if
you put a dollar a you know monetary
value on the amount of time it takes and
be able to show that return this ends up
becoming a very positive way to be able
to show back to your leadership look how
much time we're saving if we enter and
this is exactly what you've seen a lot
of different products today even outside
of security when automation is involved
all right that's all I had we're here in
the booth anything that I said feel like
I want to discuss more happy to chat
about it and thank you thank you very
much Chris and thank you for threat
connects wonderful support of us twenty
nine eight that's us done for today
guard interpreter drinks will commence
beside the pool from 6:30 p.m. the
conference rooms at nine o'clock
tomorrow morning
haha see you there but the good people
have pwned a drone outside a remaining
over for a little while if you haven't
been outside the hall go out there hack
in it's absolutely awesome like they're
having some tremendous feedback from the
people who are trying to hack their way
into PO 2 drone another round of
applause please for Troy and Chris Chris
take your chess set with you wonderful
stuff we will see you here at 9 o'clock
tomorrow or the gala dinner tonight
don't forget if you're pulling out of
the gala dinner if you're not going to
the last minute please let them know
that registration