okay ladies gentlemen we're gonna
commence our final session if you'd like
to take your seats in just a few moments
we'll be starting the annual speed
debate I'll call our debaters up in a
couple of seconds we've got a few prizes
to give out first when we swing into
debate mode you'll be voting at the end
of each debate via the app let's put
those instructions up now so people can
load up and check if they've got any
troll Mike oh there's a slide here about
to come up explaining what you do you go
to this afternoon's session Friday 3:45
in the ballroom just enter that pin and
that should give you access to voting
via the app on the topics in the speed
debate as we get to them but first of
all we've got a few prizes to give out
quickly I'm going to call out the list
of people have won the appropriate
prizes and so I'm going to pause for a
second because someone's walking towards
me at pace you can shake people's hands
I love that you come forward able to
shake your hand and can you make if you
if you have one get up and come up
pretty quickly because I want to move
through these fairly quickly and I don't
want to miss people but I don't want to
be waiting really blind here the first
couple of people don't have a physical
prize as such but you don't need it
because someone's got full conference
registration to also 20/20
congratulations Milton Marcos as Milton
still here yeah well done Milton
congratulations do I see movement from
Milton Milton is so excited he's already
left to go home and tell his family that
he's got free registration next year and
the gold pass registration of the
Australian cyber conference donated by
the good people at Acer is killer
gooo love we killer goo of we mo got
your name right there
killer kil a round of applause for
killer yeh who also is just too
emotional to be here but now going
through prizes a good people at Co fence
donated an Apple watch three to Jamie
Gillespie yeah come on forward Jamie
great stuff
I'm gonna count home with a lot of stuff
I like this okay we've got a book pack
from AWS n donated by Dave chatter one
by Dave Chapman not an item oh that
would've been a bit awkward
well done Dave Dave Chapman's won that
one I'm gonna keep giving out prizes
until there is someone here
psychotic I'm guessing you're the
gentleman from psychotic who's going to
present the prize is a drone to Patrick
McElhenney
well done Patrick Patrick McIlhenny okay
fantastic there seems to be a common
theme amongst our winners Glenn Ramsey
has won the new gen systems prize so
Robert Perrin come on forward where's
Glenn Glenn well you they might would
you like an apple watching a book back
nah can't do that you graduated - Glenn
smile for the camera there Glenn don't
be shy the photographer is very excited
for the first photo though I've got this
afternoon great okay a Google home prize
has been donated by the good people that
recorded future Colin Chamberlain has
picked that up Colin Colin is not here
we know that for a fact okay we've got
five people thanks NS focus five people
of one and m36 a wireless charger power
bank so if any of hallelu Mac and Tommy
Pierre Corral Philippe Dias pong Lim Lau
and joy Minton if any of halleluh
halleluh Pierre Philippe pong and joy
are here come on forward give them a
round of applause congratulations thank
you in its focus five charger packs and
we've got I can see three of our winners
at least take that as a more than a pass
what a cosmopolitan the named Bunch -
joy pong Philippe here and hallelu
well done joy smile for the camera come
on in Pierre off you go joy that was
your moment right there you go don't get
too carried away okay great
and the lovely Philippe as well
smile for the camera Philippe great work
okay someone's going home with a Sonos
speaker thanks to extreme networks and
that's Jonathan Levine
please enough to generate a laugh good
on Emil's she was in the duo the Kessel
run Millennium Falcon Lego boxes
Northcote productions prize Victor
Bradbury has picked it up for the speed
build
well done Victor picked up the
headphones last night and won the speed
build
always an iconic the Millenium Falcon
back there like a one-minute nine
seconds an iconic item on the all cert
challenge each year great work mate the
bb-8 lego prize thanks again Northcote
productions gee joy matthew is g joy
still here there's G Joe come on forward
Mike congratulations
and also Northcote productions are given
to the way the welcome to apocalypse
burg Lego to Jamie Keil or Jamie Keil or
Jamie's at the back come on forward
Jamie great stuff Jesus come on might a
bit of trouble the overhead luggage
Jamie but that's why guys that looks
distinctly like an empty box - at the
moment
what was he cutting costs at our
Northcote productions but I don't drop
your empty box Jamie deceptively light
oK we've got a couple of prizes here
from Pearson see this was for the
hardware hack there's a solo prize for a
one-minute twenty eight hack Mitchell
Harvey and a team prize two combined 32
seconds was all it took Scott and Tim
Scott and Tim coming for that's an
incredible hack in only 32 seconds and
Mitchell have him on the solo back in a
minute 28 you're both getting JB hi-fi
gift cards be very wary of any of these
three gentlemen going anywhere near any
of your belongings the good people at
hack ative have given us a $250 rebel
gift voucher it's been won by a name
that was written down in not the
greatest handwriting dive perceived as
Simon see a quick Simon's Co quick whoo
anything anyone any minimum called Simon
with a sir no set Sedgwick that would
make more sense there you go
so I'm in Sedgwick his time in Sedgwick
here
last call no let's move on they've got
the volkswagen t1 camper van thank you
again North co-productions another Lego
prize Andrew strong picked that one up
too absolutely no claim whatsoever
there you go Andrew if you don't mind
there we go smiling and no offense the
Volkswagen team on camper van but
stepping it up north crow productions
the Porsche 911 RSR lego chris versace
or christian verse ace is Chrissie Chris
picked up the Porsche the Xbox one
carbon black gave away a couple of Xbox
prices the Xbox one to george abraham
and the xbox wireless controller to Alex
Norman thank you very much carbon black
or either George or Alex here come on
forward if they are yep here we go
here's David from carbon black to help
handover the prizes right Xbox what is
this is this George or Alex George
you've on the Xbox one make
congratulations happy gaming
turn for the camera don't be shy George
make the yeah hi George come back hold
that mom that's a magic mother dick and
we've got Alex there's one the wireless
controller
congratulations Alex Smalley for the
camera there well done thank you so much
carbon bike big round of applause to all
our prized sponsors thank you so very
much what an amazing tribe for prizes
and we have the capture the flag po
we found Jamie good who's Jamie he's
means nothing to me more Jamie Gillespie
the Apple watch there boy he's got an
Apple watch you're gonna be like Jamie
there you go never be light again my
friend congratulations okay and of
course there was the capture the flag
pone - drone challenge I think Lucas is
gonna come forward and make someone very
happy by announcing the winner in the
capture the flag pone - drone my man
Lucas coming from the back of the room
just to build up the excitement this was
fantastic that captured the flag don't
forget to enter your name with that pin
that we had up there so you can vote in
a couple of seconds in the speed about
coming up may tell us about capture the
flag very popular little event over the
last few days howdy so we had a capture
the flag challenge over the last two
days so the team I think put in close to
about a hundred days worth of effort
into it so you know give a round of
applause to the complex team and we do
have a winner and the team members qut
you Cuba I saw them running out the door
so I'll I'll give this prize to them oh
I'll talk through the challenge it's
basically you need to compromise a IT
network like a Windows domain to then
pivot through it to an OT networks an
operational technology network so what
we do there we have series of houses we
have a water plant as well here we are
got we have a water plant and we have
traffic light system and we have a
series of streetlights as well so if
you're able to compromise all those bits
especially their houses and compromise
the quote unquote smart smart meters
that are in there it's actually
literally not literally a lot of fire
but mock light of fire and through a
series of pipes smoke actually starts
pouring out of them so it's so it's
really really cool so we are packing it
up but I think most of the people have
actually seen it some people have seen
in action as well so
we do have the team here fantastic so
that's UQ QUT team wanted a stress just
uke you know environment of QUT
whatsoever in that world our
congratulations guys great stuff thank
you so much David for organizing all
that wonderful prize for his great work
congratulation to our winners and all
the people have looked up to all the
boots over the last couple of days now
we move to the annual also its plea
debate this is a bit of fun debating
like you have never seen it before
unless you've been to all sir any time
in the last 10 years where this has
become an absolute highlight of the
event of the calendar what we do here is
we have rather than your old-fashioned
minutes each everybody at the end we did
a few years ago thought bugger let's get
through as many topics as we possibly
can in the space of one session so the
way we do that is we live in every one
to one minute
speaking one minute and I will be
ruthless on that we're going to go
through six topics six count them six
topics each one divided by three on the
affirmative three on the negative at the
end of it I throw to you guys for a vote
and we just roll on to the next topic so
please welcome to the stage our speakers
who will sit in the appropriate places
there
Kobe Pryor Jesse Erwin Jake Carroll
Mikko Hirvonen Brad at Duncan Troy hunt
Justin Steven Heidi winter and Brian hi
give them all a round of applause as
they come on forward
[Applause]
okay then so this is how we roll now
first of all it's gonna have Colby
Jessie and Jake on the affirmative Mikko
Brad and Troy on the negative there are
handheld microphones there so as I say
who the next speaker up is please make
sure the handheld microphones are
appropriately passed to them can someone
who's quick can we just grab the
microphones each just a quick word into
them and check the microphones are
working Justin's got one there is all
good fantastic you've got one there
Brian is that microphone working you
know yes fanta incorrect answer good
eventually MIGO yes okay let's see we
got our first topic our first topic for
this evening personalized ads are
morally wrong personalized ads are
morally wrong Colby Jesse and Jake
versus Mikko Brad and Troy Colby your
one minute starts now personalized ads a
morally wrong because machine learning
is only as good as your training set is
so until like every single person in
this audience goes homes and buyers a
Amazon Alexa and a Google home and kind
of straps them to their body with like a
portable power bank they're not really
gonna know enough about us so when I
bought a mountain bike about a few
months ago all it did was ask if I
wanted to buy another mountain bike it
never really went anywhere beyond that
and I think to have such a terrible
training set and still use machine
learning is pretty morally bankrupt okay
thank very much Bobby give him a round
of applause first breaker for the
opposition and negating that topic take
it away
Mikko
okay thank you very much big on taking
the position of personalized ads ah
morally wrong over to you Jesse Oh
[Music]
are you guys thinking too much Jessie
Owen arguing against the topic to
personalize hats are morally wrong take
it away Brad Dunkin uh first of all I
hired a speechwriter to help me prepare
to the statement his name is Harry I
watch a lot of porn a lot of porn how
else am I going to find out about the
newest developments in my particular
fetish without personalized
advertisements I sure as hell am NOT
going to search the internet for some of
the things I am curious about
I enjoy booths very very cheap booze
without personalized ads how can I find
the cheapest alcohol I like guns how
else can I find the quickest way to
obtain a firearm in my local area
without registration when you argue
against personalized ads you are arguing
against porn addicted hard drinking gun
enthusiast like myself which I'll go to
now a couple of days ago Brett that's
great so closing the debate for the
affirmative personalized ads are morally
wrong Jake
Carol take it away
thank you very much Jake and to close
the debate for the negative take it away
Troy hunt I don't really understand that
the Kobe argument it's like I like bikes
I keep seeing bikes like what's the
problem and you're there on a website
which you're trying to use for free
aniss like here's some bikes I don't see
the problem let us see Jesse's problem
either because I'd be very happy to get
more personalized ads because I have so
much trouble shopping I'd love to be
wandering around the internet and
actually figuring out what I should buy
by the site itself it would make my
whole Christmas thing a lot easier so
the thing is like if we want to keep
getting things for free and we need to
have some targeted information we gotta
get ads one way or the other I'd much
rather see stuff that's relevant to me
and it's gonna make my life easier I'd
be happy to have more sensors in my home
looking at more of my stuff if it will
help me get better things because I'm
just useless that actually going out and
buying stuff of my own free volition so
I'm more tracking more targeting and I
think we'll all be a lot happier there
you go you've heard both sides over to
you now take the app and you've got a
few seconds to cast your vote on this
first topic personalized ads are morally
wrong did you come down on the side of
strap-on Alexis multiple mountain bikes
and amateur a purists or adult diapers
fetish porn and guns you've got a few
seconds to lodge your vote there
a resounding wind or the negative
congratulations Mikko Brad and Troy okay
now I should have pointed out before
that our first debate I will clarify now
I've encouraged all of our speakers
today to be provocative it's the last
session of the of the conference really
throw it out there if you feel sort of
six out of ten on a topic push it out to
twelve or thirteen Brad I get the
impression didn't even need that
instruction I love your work in
particular Brad
but in all seriousness this is this is
septum with provoking a bit of thought
having a bit of fun nothing that is said
here on stage can be taken away as the
actual held position of individuals or
the organization's they happen to be
from as we move onto our second topic
apps need a code worthy certificate much
like cars require a Road worthy
certificate should apps have a code
worthy certificate just and Heidi and
Jesse will be saying they do Kolby Brad
and Jake will be saying they don't so to
commence absolute a code worthy
certificate much like cars require a
road were these difficut take it away
Justin Stephen
[Music]
Justin first speaker for the negative
speaking against code worthy
certificates take it away Kobe Pryor
well I kind of like docker hub I don't
want that to go away but beyond that a
big difference between New South Wales
and Queensland roadworthy certificates
for cars is in New South Wales you have
to get it every single year and someone
kind of just walks up kicks your tyre
ask for $500 and you see him again next
year in Queensland they just kind of
sign up once but and said you pay $3,000
and it's kind of good forever so I don't
know how that maps out to the the
practical real-world life but if you
gave a a code worthy certificate for
some of the apps which were around 10
years ago I'd not sure how long they
would live on the Internet today
thank you very much Colby now we're
gonna hear from the first time this
afternoon on the affirmative in favor of
Cobo exhibits Heidi winner take it away
Heidi so apps definitely need a code
worthy certificate much like the cars
need a Road worthy certificate because
it's definitely more things that we can
issue and make money from in the long
term
with a cybersecurity benefit so we can
afford more conferences like today but
let's take it seriously at the end of
the day what we actually really need is
to understand that the applications are
safe so that Brad can watch is out of
porn finish the sites and guns and not
have to worry about that particular
information being leaked publicly on the
internet so we understand that those
billions and billions of records that
justin referenced earlier that may or
may not have actually been leaked are
actually never gonna be happening again
so I just definitely need a code worthy
certificate but not like the cars as
Colby said because it's different in
every state we need to understand this
at a federal and a national inner and an
international level that code where
these certificates are definitely
necessary Oh
bring it in on 59 seconds well Don Hardy
guy to negate the concept of the card
worthy certificate it's the drunken
gun-toting porn fetishist himself brat
take it away my friend through an
initial misunderstanding I thought my
speechwriter Harry had graduated from
Oxford University but it turns out he
merely stated he was proficient in the
use of an Oxford comma a code where the
certificate is a nice idea but do you
know what else is nice ideal communism
both communism and these proposed
certificates required bureaucracy and
this dictatorship of the proletariat
will make all our decisions for us as
far as this issue is concerned do we
really want to mix commie politics into
the code worthiness of our apps when you
argue for code worthy certificates you
are arguing my friends for communism
[Applause]
okay well here to our finalized the
argument for communism or at least code
word is difficut Jesse Erwin taken by
Jesse well done Jesse and ooh yes please
run of course final speaker in this
debate bring it home for the negative
Jake Carol take it away
[Music]
okay thank you very much Jake give a
round of applause please
lodge your votes apps deserve a code
worthy certificate you had Justin Heidi
and Jesse on the affirmative
Kolby bread and Jake on the negative I
just wanted votes are coming in Jake I
will note that um so you've currently
got a neighbor in hospital and your
child's traumatized and common link
seems to be you my friend that's on it's
all I'm saying it it's all I'm saying at
this - you certainly do have an effect
on people okay let's see how those folks
put them in first debate was a pretty
comfortable winter the negative second
debate oh yes okay I very I do liked it
a few yeah okay no negative of one that
again quite comfortably give them a
round of applause that is Kobe Jay and
Brad okay two debates in a row to the
negative our third topic open source is
organized plagiarism opens yep yeah you
might hear a funny thing from me all day
open source is organized plagiarism
Kolby Justin and Brad will be taking the
affirmative Brian Jesse
Mikko will take the negative open source
is organized plagiarism colby lead us
off my friend
yeah open-source is totally open just
organized plagiarism like every single
time you type out curl paste in a URL
endpoint and throw in a dash K because
you're fast and loose and use pipe at
the bash that's stealing and every time
you do a get cloned you're just stealing
off someone else the only way it's not
stealing is if money is exchanged that's
why we all need to put our all of our
API endpoints and our you know github z'
all behind some kind of Bitcoin right
limited access where we're paying for
what we're getting because that way it's
it's a purchase it's not stealing
thank you very much cobby yeah given
Ronald was gonna hear from the first on
this afternoon against the argument open
sources organized plagiarism welcome
Brian or yours what a crock of shit okay
open source is a gift it's a manor it's
a part of what we thrive on in the
Internet it's the world in which we live
this myriad of ions and neutrons
bouncing around because we interplay
with it every day you imagine if we had
a gatekeeper to go through everything
and you think that there's no money
being exchanged my god have you look at
the Bitcoin the organized crime the
cyber crime that's occurring every day
it's the the underground economy of what
exists is you know blessed by the virtue
of such freedom that we express and
jealously guard I mean when you look at
the thing is open sources organized
plagiarism plagiarism a type of IP theft
we have students around the world that
thrive on plagiarism they need
plagiarism to get through their studies
actually there are industries they
support in places like China and in
India that it's the economy is supported
by the whole idea of writing assignments
for other people but you know what open
source it's unleashing free radicals we
need it okay thank you very much Brian
hit the ground running my friend
Justin Stephens going to take up the
argument in favor of open source is
organized plagiarism over to you Justin
[Music]
there you go Justin the thing I love
about this debate each year I don't have
one hour of the year as much as this
where I hear an audience laughing so
hard at jokes and I have no fucking idea
what anyone's talking about I just I
love it
you clearly nailed that but I've got I
don't understand anything you just said
Jesse your chance to oppose this topic
police open sources or Joe organized
plagiarism take it away Jesse Owen
[Music]
thank you very much Jesse okay final
speaker for the affirmative open source
is organized plagiarism take it away
Brad my speechwriter Harry must be
associated with an important government
or military organization he has the term
4/20 peppered throughout his resume a
resume riddled with Oxford commas Harry
also agrees that open source is
organized plagiarism the reason is
because all the good ideas in software
development up to this point have
already been done operating systems
applications we've already discussed
part of this already but for any new
ideas that will eventually become
open-source let the commercial vendors
market an application or a novel concept
and see if it works and then open source
can swoop in and provide an alternative
version when you argue against open
sources plagiarism you my friends are
arguing against quality there you go
thank you very proud I thought you were
gonna side there supporting communism
but anyway wrapping it up for us Miko
you're gonna close this out for the
negative police open source is organized
plagiarism Mikko to disagree
[Music]
they go okay you've got 30 seconds to
lodge your votes do you want to steal
the will from the fat cats do you think
plagiarism is art that was a cracking
debate a lot of issues thrown up there
hit the app let us know your thoughts
we'll see how the votes for Colby Justin
and Brad on the affirmative Bryan
Jessi and Miko on the negative
whoa okay the negative of crushed that
congratulations Brian Jesse and Myka
okay topic number four we need the
internet Paris Accord an Internet Paris
Accord for information pollution Troy
Jake and Heidi will take the affirmative
Kolby Brian and Justin will provide the
negative we need an Internet Paris
Accord for information pollution Troy
hunt take it away so recapping Paris
Accord the whole idea here is we're
polluting too much we've got to reduce
the greenhouse gases try and stop the
temperature's going down or else we're
all gonna choke and die and we're kind
of doing the same thing on on
information now we're choking and dying
on disinformation on the internet so
anyone being on Facebook or Twitter
lately it's like yeah exactly right so
this is the problem I'm spending my
entire time looking at things at people
at posting and it's taken me like two
seconds to fact-check this stuff you
know is it on Snopes yes okay job done
is it all in capitals yes is it asked me
to do something yes okay it's gonna be
faked so if I can do it in a couple
minutes so don't know why other people
can't I was just trying to look for some
of the worst hoaxes that have been out
there and frankly I can't repeat a lot
of the ones I just read here but think
about some of the stuff we've been
seeing lately kids reading Tide Pods you
seen this one because they put out
information on the Internet go this is a
good idea let's do this how deep fakes
we don't know what to trust anymore one
of my favorites here was how you can
charge your iphone by putting it in a
microwave this is the information that's
online we've got to kill this stuff okay
thank you very much Troy yeah great
stuff okay Colby speak against a Paris
Accord for information pollution take it
away Colby I feel like you just kind of
listed a bunch of reasons as to why it
misinformation is hilarious and I know
as soon as my nephew comes and asked me
one day what is the Great Wall of China
for I'm gonna tell him it's to keep out
the rabbits and if I can't do that I
don't want to live in that world the
other great thing about like the Paris
Accord is it's just so easily
enforceable and in the same way that any
international law can easily be enforced
misinformation will be easily enforced
because everyone's really good at
identifying
playing what satire and what isn't
satire and you know the whole thing of
Paris it you know the whole world is
being polluted but the war is only in
Paris like what
thank you very much call me Jake you're
gonna speak on the affirmative mate for
an Internet Paris Accord take it away
Joe thank you very much Jake powerful
stuff okay now Brian certainly shot out
of the blocks with his last offering I
can't wait to see what he's got on this
one even a speck on the opposition Brian
to the Internet Paris Accord for
information pollution take it away Brian
hey what a crock of shit yes have a look
at the Paris Accord it was designed I
think in about 2016 if we're now in 2019
and it's just been agreed to by the
countries so you know what that tells us
that world leaders didn't necessarily
agree with it and you know what Donald
Trump has just he's already announced
he's gonna withdraw I mean mom some may
argue if it's good enough for Donald
it's not good enough for us you know
what I'm saying and what about pollution
if we didn't have pollution we would not
have the Greenies movement we would not
have global warming think of the
benefits that yields at warmer summers
warmer winters suntan bodies there are
benefits here people now equate the
filth in the air to the filth online
pornography grew the Internet
ladies and gentlemen we should stand
proud the free spirit of the Internet
rests in the ability to actually have
not have filtering so go for it okay
[Applause]
Heidi would you like to close out the
argument for the affirmative pleas in
favor of an Internet Paris Accord I need
this to be regulated we really need this
to be regulated we need to have less
flat earthers and more cat memes
I need more cheeseburgers I need less
flat earth I need less propaganda and I
need less tweets from Donald Trump so
really in the end this sort of things
pretty easy to enforce and all we need
to do is to put up some really big
firewalls what is it we also need to do
make sure people are actually fully
curating posts we need to make sure that
we're all checking these things and oh
wait yeah cuz that's not hard at all but
really at the end of the day as long as
I can make sure that my Twitter feed has
at least 80% shitposts to 20% actual
factual chrome content I'm ok with that
ok thank you very much Heidi our final
speaker for the negative arguing against
an internet Paris Accord just and
Stephen take it away
[Music]
thank God there you guys toss burner
okay so Lodge of votes in favor the
affirmative microwaving Mobile's
psycholytic sand cat memes we do you
support the negative emperor nasi goreng
the benefits of global warming and the
Adani data mine you had Troy
Jake and Heidi on the affirmative Kolby
Brian and Justin taking up the negative
ten seconds to lodger votes the negative
one all three debates so far
[Music]
so now starting to worry if there's a
Fault in the system not in terms of the
merits of the device but if the negative
one or six that will be interesting
right so the negative again get the
round of applause Kobe Justin and Bryan
now this is going to be interesting this
next topic Valen researchers can do no
wrong they need diplomatic immunity
appellant researchers can do no wrong
they need diplomatic immunity exciting
for a couple of reasons on the negative
we'll eventually hear from Brad Jesse
and Troy but on the affirmative seconds
big is gonna be Mikko third speaker is
gonna be Heidi given the way that brian
has started
both of these speeches so far by
referring to everything that's happened
previously in the debate as he's gonna
be the very first speaker in the debates
it's gonna be varying to see how he
leads off possibly any I'll leave it up
to you take it away Valen researchers
can do no wrong than a diplomatic
immunity take it away Brian this is not
a crock of shit we need volatile
researchers vulnerability researchers
okay hackers we need the luck right
they're vulnerable to you know don't
welcome they should be enshrined as
national treasures Putin had the right
idea he announced that but one of the
national treasures the great treasures
of Russia they've got their greatest
assets was their covert hacking to
forthright we should actually consider
them a protected species we need the
freedom of liberalism to be order to
make a difference to give us the cutting
edge in the world that we love today
everything of course should be subjected
to rigorous testing and review you start
testing by virtue of guidelines would we
actually have the solutions to the
common cold well we don't have that yet
but other things like you know that the
advances in medical sciences they if we
followed strict protocols without
testing and testing the vulnerability
researchers that they do give us the
advantage that puts us on the edge on
the roadmap of things good that are good
yeah I think I'll just made shit up then
but there you go thank you much Brian
hey Brad's gonna laid us off on the
negative speaking against Vaughn
research is doing it no wrong tackled by
Brett my speechwriter Harry has a wide
variety of life experiences that have
hopefully informed my statements tonight
for example
he lists and part of his experiences
medical testing medicinal testing which
is always for some reason included in
quotation marks in 1984 Libyan embassy
worker in London opened fired a mob of
anti-gaddafi protesters outside of his
embassy this killed one police officer
and injured eleven others the embassy
staff are eventually kicked out of the
UK and no one was charged with a crime
this my friends is diplomatic immunity
additionally diplomatic immunity was
abused by criminals during the movie
lethal weapon - which I think resulted
in more deaths but I don't really know
because that wasn't a good movie and I
can hardly remember it anyway an
argument for diplomatic immunity is an
argument for murder and vulnerability
researches should not be encouraged to
murder
thank you very much Brad coherent as
always Myka you're on the affirmative
Molinari searches can do no wrong
[Music]
[Laughter]
[Applause]
[Music]
hey you guys thank you very much me
Jesse oh and you're gonna take up the
negative saying that valen researchers
do not desert diplomatic immunity take
it away
[Music]
thank you very much Jesse
Heidi wrapping it up on the affirmative
rollin researchers can do no wrong they
need diplomatic immunity take it away
Heidi look if they don't get to come out
of community
how are they gonna actually go to DEFCON
get drunk and brag about everything and
not get arrested like but really this is
a job imagine going into work one day
and you've just gone and the day before
reported some of the stuff that ended up
and one of your spam traps or whatever
and people come in after knocking on the
door sit you down and go you know it
you've done you know why you're here
today it's because you've been knowing
your job
and we don't have diplomatic immunity
for you because you've been doing your
job
look we need people to do these
particular pieces of work we need to
actually have these vulnerabilities
uncovered and we also need to have them
reported responsibly
they're responsible ones are the good
ones of course but at the end of the day
we really really need to make sure that
we actually treat our vulnerability
researchers with the respect they
deserve because they can't do any wrong
thank you very much Heidi final speaker
for the debate on the negative take it
away
Troy stop finding bloody bugs and
everything look at all the problems
we're having anything I think about even
the eternal blue stuff it was like two
years ago this thing is still dishing up
the goods if no-one found that it would
be fine we wouldn't have the problem in
the first place
I really don't want to see all the sorts
of vulnerabilities people finding I
don't want to say like compromise teddy
bears and cars and watches and things
like this I mean who really wants to
live in that world if they just let the
software developers do their job
stop mucking out their code leave it as
it is would be a lot better off stop
finding vulnerabilities and sucking data
out of systems as well because the last
thing you want to do is have more data
making ever been poned even bigger and
bigger and frankly I would like to break
from all that as well so if you could
all just stop doing that shit for a
while I think everyone will be a lot
happier thank you they're you God well
there you have it compromise teddy bears
but pain bug bounty hunters and Luther
weapon two versus hackers as national
treasures and protected species log your
votes valen researchers Bolen
researchers can do no wrong they need to
keep the money community
Brian amico and Heidi on the affirmative
at Brad Jessie Croix on the negative
plus away there you go
I went for the affirmative ever mickr
party Brian congratulations this brings
us to our final topic of the day topic
is cyber security is not very important
cyber security is not very important
Justin Brian and mica will present the
affirmative Troy Jake and Heidi will be
arguing against this our final topic for
the day cyber security not very
important take it away Justin
[Music]
okay nice sinister ending from Justin
Troy you're gonna lead off the
opposition to the topic of cybersecurity
not very important well it is that's why
you're all here this seems like the easy
side of the eggman to be on in a bunch
II you got here because you went online
to book tickets and you kind of hope
that you could book tickets where the
cards being sold and then you got on the
plane and you came here and it's like ah
to be really nice not to crash on the
way here and then you got in the car
that had cyber things and it'd be nice
if the brakes worked and no one else was
only my car or anything like that and
then you hear any check into your room
with the electronic card and you're kind
of hoping that other people don't get
into your room as well and you come
downstairs with your phones and you take
your photos and you hope that other
people aren't in that and then you're
going to vote on our side of course just
after this and you're hoping that all
that works and someone hasn't gotten
into there and oh in that system and
even the lights and the microphones and
the screens and things here all
dependent on this stuff actually working
it is important that's why we just spent
two days of your lives away from your
family here listening to it thank you
very much there you go Troy Bryan to a
firm the topic that cybersecurity is not
very important what he thoughts Brian
cybersecurity is a crock of shit the
biggest fraud perpetrated on the human
world let me take you back in a little
bit in history ladies and gentlemen
panel members y2k no matter how many
billions were spent on the millennium
bug that didn't exist it set the seed
cybersecurity is a conspiracy by the
vendors to extract money instill
paranoia and leech the lifeblood out of
the human race in the economy of this
planet let me give you an example man
did not land on the moon it's a myth
myth I tell you Elvis
isn't dead did you not watch men in
black aliens did land in area 51 at
Roswell it's proof fake news does not
exist
cybercriminals and misunderstood they're
just free-spirited youth
and Brad is hairy and he's not disturbed
Jake is gonna be the second speaker for
the negative the topic is cybersecurity
is not very important you disagree take
it away Jake thank you very much Jake
great stuff give me round of applause
final speaker for the affirmative his
final speech no Micko cybersecurity is
not very important take it away
[Music]
[Laughter]
thank God and wrap it up on a spike a
final topic final debate take it away
Heidi Wendell what are your thoughts
okay so cybersecurity is obviously very
important but it's such a new area that
we can't even decide how it's spelt so I
want some audience participation here is
cybersecurity one word or two words
raise your hand if it's one word all
right and ready hands if it's two words
alright cool so I've got a bit of a
problem
he'll anyhow so it's that of oh it's
that in its early ages in the moment
that we've not even sure as to how it's
actually spelt correctly and we've got a
lot of options moving forward as to how
we want to actually shape this
particular industry whether or not you
actually want to go back to the
traditional cyber can we not that was
really bad whether or not we want to
actually move forward and make this
industry the best place that it can
actually be because we're all here today
for a reason and it's because we
actually believe in cybersecurity
there you go hardy thank you very much
call to arms to finish it off okay your
call item what do you think you come
down on the side of the biggest fraud
perpetrated in humanity and Mikko cyber
sex life or are you fine with anarchy
and really side with the grammar police
you've got 20 seconds to logic votes on
this final topic and it will determine
our most successful individual debaters
of the day
I've got to give away those prizes and
also we'll be giving away a couple of
prizes for the high scores registered in
the various retro games that were played
over the last few days but lock those
votes in now oh the affirmative actually
drastic dr. Brian and Mika okay so
totaling about that I just wanted to say
[Music]
okay so we had we come to the end of our
hour now debates today the way we did
this we had six topics six people on
each that's 36 speeches in total divided
by the nine speakers they've all done
four debates each this year we had no
one finished on zero which is great
you're all winners though strictly some
of you want a bit more than the rest of
you
we had one win each to Heidi Troy
Jake and Jessi give them a round of
applause world out over the win two wins
each to Justin Brad and Colby
congratulations
but our joint winners with four wins
each Mick oh and Brian congratulations
now I'll get I'll get a brief statement
from each of you I'll start with you
Mick Oh what would you like to say on
the fact that you won four out of four
there okay
Brian your thoughts on winning four out
of four in the speed debate what a crock
of shit there you go I was hoping some
budget so they give them all a round of
applause one of us stuff and we have two
other quick prizes to give out the high
scores on the retro gaming for his score
of forty five thousand two hundred and
seventy on the 1982 Atari classic
xevious like devious but with a letter X
congratulations Mick oh it wouldn't be a
prize giving ceremony at all sir twenty
nineteen without Victor Bradbury winning
something at half an hour since he's won
anything the poor bastard he won the
headphones last night just won the Lego
speed build
he also won one of the retro games so
come on forward Victor
come on parent tell which ones which one
were you on there I'm naughty 43 we do
the plan going through the edge great
stuff what we remember your score was
46,000 congratulations great stuff a
misspent youth give him a round of
applause well done mate our two gamers
and so now my pleasure to call David to
the stage to wrap this all up
just quickly David sure I'll let the
speakers go back to their yeah that you
have you gone for like ten seconds a
couple minutes tops you can stay there
coming up David say few words don't
forget to mention how wonderful I was
during that over the last couple of days
just drop that in there no trouble at
all opening night thank you very much
thank you Adam okay well I'll start 2019
been a great conference it's dangerous
going alone I'm not quite so sure now
I'm not sure which side to be on I might
just go alone I think but anyway thanks
for no but seriously the panel it was
really entertaining thank you very much
I hope you don't feel like you are alone
after this conference I hope that you've
built some new networks and and Amster
networks over the last two days it's
been great leaves all leaves for me to
do is to thank our sponsors these events
wouldn't happen without especially our
gold silver bronze and innovation
sponsors but our platinum sponsors emt
mine cast and pssc like to thank you
[Applause]
I'd like to thank all of our speakers
because again you know this event really
is because of our speakers so thank you
but especially to Mikko Troy and Jesse
for hours keynotes I think being great
thank you very much for coming all this
way especially Troy I know it's a big
journey for you hope you have a safe
journey home rain I'd like to also thank
the the conference chairs because they
have sort of our volunteers who help out
in these events and then make everything
run smoothly as well and of course the
wonderful Adam Spencer thank you very
much Adam I mean I was always gonna
actually have a quick straw poll to see
whether we preferred the real Adam or
the virtual Adam from last year but you
know I think you know having here has
been great thank you so a special thanks
to my team at assert the operations team
who move everything down all the
operations down to the Gold Coast and
they continue the great service which
takes a lot of doing and also to the
business team who brought this event
together and especially to bec cheb
so please
[Applause]
so just these would say thank you to all
the delegates if he didn't come we
wouldn't have the event either so thank
you to everybody who came it's a big
commitment at four days or two days we
I'd like you to to invite you to join us
at Oscar 2020 on the Gold Coast sometime
next year probably about the same time
and finally just want to say have a safe
journey home thank you very much
[Applause]