ladies and gentlemen good morning it is
on the stroke of 9:00 a.m. so we are
often flying that is the accuracy for
which assert is renowned my name's Adam
Spencer and welcome ye to the 18th of
cert cybersecurity conference
2019 Australia's original and best
cybersecurity conference we're gonna be
packed to the gunnels today people gonna
keep walking in for a little while so if
it is easy for you to move across
shuffle across one seat and leave any
vacancies on the aisle feel free to do
that because you don't want people
clamoring over you for our opening
session it's a thrill to welcome you
here but I want to start today I'm
really excited to welcome to the stage
to welcome us on behalf of the
traditional owners of this land an
emerging leader of the Gold Coast we
police have a big round of applause for
the wonderful Stacey Fogerty I would
like to begin by acknowledging and pay
my respects to my elders past present
and emerging good morning my name is
Stacey Fogerty and I'm a Mullen Jolly
woman from but is it which is about 60
kilometres west of where we are today I
am a traditional custodian of these
lands and I'm connected to these lands
to my blood birth and my ancestors this
is my land in my family's land and on
behalf of myself and my family I love to
welcome you all here this morning
jingrui minyak go junkie wallow down in
your is Stacey
jingrui you can bear jogging now what I
just said to you all in the local you
can bear language is welcome hello how
are you my name is Stacey and welcome to
you in bear country it is tradition for
indigenous people to welcome other
people into their land and in doing so
pay your respects to the elders on whose
land you're standing on we do a welcome
to country because we over we have over
400 tribal boarders sitting with inside
what we call the Australia you see today
respectfully we would request permission
to travel into another mob's country
permission to travel into another tribes
land permission to travel into another
family's land and this tradition still
continues today with my welcome for you
all if I can explain how this works in a
non indigenous non traditional sense I'm
hosting a party tomorrow night
and you're one of the invited guests the
way you would come to my party is you
would open you wouldn't just come to my
door you wouldn't just
you wouldn't just knock on my front door
and you wouldn't just walk into my house
you would have to wait for me to invite
you in you wouldn't just open my fridge
just start eating my food and start
drinking my drinks you wouldn't do that
that would be disrespectful so welcome
in traditional sense it's how we operate
today which is when we go to someone's
house which you guys are in my house
right now you would come and knock on my
door I would answer the door and choose
whether or not to let you win if I
didn't want you to come into my house
you would have to turn around and go
away but this morning I'm going to
welcome you all into my home so now that
you have permission to enter my house
open my fridge and start eating my fruit
and drinking my drinks if we hold that
thought of what a welcome to country is
it is me opening my home and my lands to
you in an indigenous sense in Aboriginal
stance in days gone by not by us we have
a similar fashion but we didn't have a
fridge we didn't have a door and we
didn't have a mobile phone or anything
like that so you would go to the edge of
your country and try to get the
attention of the neighboring people next
door one way we would get the attention
of the neighboring the neighboring
people next door would we go to the
border the border between my land and
the next person's land could have been a
river a stream a set of trees or just a
rock and we would get to that rock and
would light a big fire the fire would
produce smoke and that smoke was a
signal to the custodians the owners of
the land or which you wanted to gain
entry to to say hey there's some people
at the border I think we should go over
and see who it is so the Warriors or
some of the men would go over to the
border and light the fire it would
basically say hello what do you want and
you would say hey I'd like to fish in
your river
we know that the mullet is running now
and we would like to come and hunt the
mullet to feed our children do you give
us permission to do this
the Warriors would then take the message
back to the leader of the tribe and pass
those words on it was up to the elder
whether or not to let you in so in this
case we've said yes
then the Warriors would return to your
fire and say you have a mission to gain
entry into our land and to fish the
river for the mullet but you must adopt
our rules and our laws have for you to
come in to and hunt our mullet you can
only bring in two worries to come and
fish whatever
Karrie is what you get to take home to
feed your family respectfully we would
have 100% pay the law thought there were
ten men waiting at the fire only two men
would gain entry and the other eight
would wait the other two men would go in
and fish and hunt until they got enough
mullet they could carry and they would
all leave together so when I say I
welcome you and I welcome you to the
land something you can bear people I
welcome you to my home I'm giving you
permission to gain entry into my home
but they are under my rules and you
respect those rules so today I
respectfully welcome you all to you can
bear country and to my family's country
thank you for listening and enjoy the
rest of your day
nunya breeze see you soon thank you so
much Stacey for that wonderful welcome
to country for our international guests
in particular I want you understand
that's more than just a quick chat about
the rules about fishing for mullet in
Australia where we're exceptionally
proud of the fact that our indigenous
culture stretches back tens of thousands
possibly sixty thousand years so we
thank our indigenous forebears for their
custodianship of the land upon which we
meet today for this as I said the 18th
absurd cyber security conference my
name's Adam Spencer really excited to be
here with you again this year at this
time in human physical form some of you
will remember last year I appeared as a
robot some of you'll remember the bit
where I didn't quite understand what
it's doing in the robot fell off the
stage very funny stuff tough crowd had a
move on but obviously some of you
weren't it some of you were here for the
very first time quick show of hands if
this is your first Oscar Congress give
our newbies a big round of applause
great to have you here
ladies gentlemen really excited of you
you're up the back of the room please
come and find seats plenty of seats down
this into the room in particular a
couple of little bits of housekeeping it
has to race through before introducing
our first speaker in the unlikely event
of an emergency remain calm follow the
instructions of the well-trained staff a
public address announcement will happen
in conjunction with the evacuation tone
whoop-whoop
beep-beep the primary evacuation
assembly area is in acacia Avenue near
the southern side of the hotel bathrooms
exit the room turn left and left again
halfway down the gallery side phones out
of respect for the presenters please
turn your phones to mobile off or on to
silent I like to say at events like this
we've got enough breaks during the
course that I just look up free yourself
on the screens and soak
what's going on here on the stage I
accept in this group that's a bigger
challenge than it is in some but if you
can break away from the screens the
presentations we got here today are
quite amazing most of you should have
installed the conference app by now use
that for writing the presentations check
in at each booth during the passport to
win prizes and all that sort of stuff
and we're particularly excited the good
people at context are hosting a pone -
drone challenge now the objective of
this challenge is to allow participants
to try their skills in controlled semi
representative industrial control
systems which include a fully
functioning Scott and network including
controllable traffic lights smart meters
pump water storage simulated smoke fire
effects once players have compromised
the network from the IT DMZ propagating
through the operational television
network possible to compromise and
capture I've got no idea what I'm saying
as often happens for me it also most of
the individual words and that paragraph
makes sense to me they have been placed
together in an order that render them
gibberish but I'm told it's a rocking
challenge get along to the s10 context
booth have a chat with them make sure
you go to the registration desk and
collect your shirt and bag the
interactive zone as always goes off at
also the Lego booth where you can build
your own minifigs and the lock picking
village one of the real highlights of
also try and pick up a lock picking set
and try and bust some of the locks down
there throughout the next couple of days
our hashtag for social media is oz cert
two zero one nine take photos get images
quotable quotes everything that's going
on capture the conversation and get it
out there on your social media of choice
we don't care what it is Facebook
snapchat Instagram tinder we don't care
get it out there and let everyone know
how much fun we are having it also at
2019 this event is completely sold out
so can we have a round of applause for
the organizers congratulations guys this
is just wonderful
it does mean that tonight's gala dinner
is absolutely packed to the gunnels with
an extensive waiting list so if for some
reason during the day you realize you
can't now make it to the garlotte dinner
do us a massive favor go and tell them
at the registration desk that your seat
will be in because there's someone else
who desperately wants to sit in that
seat we're moments away from our opening
keynote but now to welcome us on behalf
of us and let us know about the next
couple of days have in store please
welcome David stopped-up and Mike home
thank you very much Adam and thanks very
much to Stacey as well for the welcome
to country and I too would like to
acknowledge the traditional owners of
the land on which we meet and pay my
respect to elders both past present and
emerging so my name is David Stockdale
I'm the director of assert it's
dangerous to go alone what do we mean
what are we doing well it is dangerous
cybersecurity is a it's a phrase that's
coming out as a team sport
we need to act together so what's assert
doing for you there's a lot of diverse
cyber threats that are emerging it's
it's evolving very quickly what does all
cert actually do for you well we're
investing we're investing big time we're
investing in your people in the
processes and in the technology as well
and what do I mean by that it's
investing in empowering your people
through the training that we're going to
be offering it's investing to enhance
your capability through our defined
processes that's our threat intelligence
and that and that's our Incident
Response services and we're expanding
your capacity through the through our
technology integration with our Mis
platforms with our integration with that
with vendor products from our services
so that's what we doing to try to make
sure that you're not alone to hear more
about this I'd like to introduce Mike
home the Operations Manager across cert
to talk a little bit about this thank
you thank you David welcome everyone
really excited to be here now that theme
that wasn't actually chosen just for its
retro-gaming coolness where we were
actually trying to
encourage a balanced information
security program
hence the you know defense and depth
strategy everything that we've all
learned but it sort of ties in really
nicely with don't go it alone
so what does that mean for us it doesn't
mean that we're here to replace any
government departments or anything like
that
government agencies it doesn't mean
we're here to replace any of those
vendors out there it's quite different
we're actually very passionate about
delivering world-class cybersecurity
services that are unique and we want to
do it at a not for profit rate so that's
why we're all here that's why everyone
works in awe cert the we're actually at
the moment we're very excited about
planning what we're doing next year so
you know you've got to look ahead so
what we really want from you from our
members is we want you to come and visit
our booth so our booth is sort of at the
intersection of the the two aisle ways
and throughout the whole conference in
next two days and our wonderful
Membership team Nick and Megan will be
there so they've actually got a short
survey that we would really like you to
to complete it's it's just asking you
know what are you using in our services
what do you want from our services going
forward so we'd really love it if you
could if you could participate in that
during the breaks also our analysts will
be at the stand so if you want to
actually talk to any of the analysts
just come and find us at morning tea
afternoon tea and lunch okay speaking of
our members we're actually really proud
to say that and quite a number of our
members have been able to integrate our
services into their business processes
that's what this is all about obviously
it's not just technology anymore with as
David said we've got to think of people
process technology so one of the
examples of that is the information
sharing and analysis center that we
we've operated now for a little while
for the universities we actually just
got a finalist at status in the quarter
Awards last week for that we're
extremely proud of Nick's oysters one of
our senior analysts who's who heads up
that Isaac but we're really proud of the
whole team because to actually get that
recognition for that Isaac was just
wonderful and the Victorian government
had already put all of all
membership services into their business
processes for their information security
management program but the next thing
they did is they've rolled out our new
training across all of their state
departments so that everyone can benefit
from all sets expertise and we were
really excited about that too um so I
suppose it's really good to see that
it's it isn't just about the tech
anymore it is about the people and
that's where that training came in all
right so that brings me to something
I've been really looking forward to
doing and that is launching a whole lot
of new products so David has already
hinted out it I just hinted at it we're
now doing training again so what we're
going to do is over the next month or so
we'll launch that officially and we'll
get all the information out to our
members about the courses that we're
offering so there's things like
obviously Incident Response that's kind
of a cert teams bread-and-butter so
we're obviously very keen to impart our
knowledge on that but we've also done
some courses on planning your incident
response now that's that might sound
like a bit of an overlap but it's
actually not you've got to plan these
things in advance so those courses will
be announced really really soon so over
the next month or so the next thing I
wanted to announce is something that
we've all been very excited about
internally and we've got a few of you on
the pilot for this and that say our AUSA
daily intelligence report I found before
I worked in also where I was surrounded
by analysts that know everything that's
going on all the time in cybersecurity
news I felt like when I worked in a bank
I felt like I was in a bit of a vacuum I
didn't really know what was going on in
the world so it was really refreshing to
see all the analysts talking about all
these infoset news articles and we sort
of looked at that and we went well and
members probably want to hear that too
so it's now a daily report that you can
subscribe to in a couple of weeks we'll
just be able to switch it on in our
member portal at the moment if you want
to enable it immediately if you can't
wait for that you can just see our
membership team and they'll turn it on
in your in your email subscriptions and
it's just a daily report of some curated
news articles that our analysts thought
would be relevant to you
so that was exciting and the very last
thing I want to mention I mentioned
we're doing a nice act for the
university so the Isacc is information
sharing and analysis Center
that was something that we stole from
the US a lot of a lot of good ideas come
from there in the cybersecurity space
and they're miles ahead of us so we
we've actually used we've got it done
done a little bit differently we are
using Mis for the technology behind that
and those of you that have looked at the
program you'll notice that we've
actually got the guys from circle which
is the team that that writes the the
software behind Mis we've actually got
them here at the conference again
there's a couple of them here did some
tutorials in the last couple of days and
there's presentations today and tomorrow
from them as well
so we wanted to be able to get that
expertise out to you so that you can
learn from it but most importantly we're
actually going to for all of our members
we're going to launch the MIS Pervis so
that you can subscribe to it and you can
receive the giant flow of indicators of
compromise that that comes out of a
missed feed so over the next couple of
weeks we'll announce we do have to
charge you for that I said that we're
not for profit but it obviously there's
that there's an internal cost to us to
producing that information it's a very
highly focused curated high confidence
feed of information and that obviously
doesn't come for free so we'll announce
what the pricing is for that over the
next month or so and we're very very
excited about launching these three new
products so I'm going to stop talking
now and hand back to dr. David we're
going to go a little bit further through
the journey of people process technology
thank you everyone
thank you very much Mike is really
exciting I feel very M very lucky to be
director of assert but I'm quite
fortunate also to have to foot into in
or two feet in different camps also it
is part of the University of Queensland
but I also have a role within the
University Queensland
so the theme not going alone what is
also doing for you well we've covered
some of that there's some of that to
that stuff today with our pros to people
processes and technology but it's not
just about what University what else
earth is doing but also about what the
University of Queensland is also going
to do and it's my great pleasure to
invite professor Ryan Coe the chair and
the director of UQ cyber security to the
stage to talk about the up-and-coming
cyber security initiative thank you I'm
very good morning to you it's an honor
to be here amongst all these
cybersecurity experts here I want to
find out how many of you are from the
industry can you raise your hands and
how many are from the government and how
many of you are currently not a wing and
need some coffee right now yeah I'm very
honored to actually be part of this UQ
cybersecurity program the whole goal of
this UQ cybersecurity program is that in
a few years time all of you who have
raised your hands are going to be part
of this UQ cyber security network why am
I saying that it's because one of the
problems is that we always have industry
academic research and education and
training in silos or in different parts
of the ecosystem and one of the
challenges is actually to bring them
together so as you can see from from
this perspective the University of
Queensland has invested in program which
actually brings everyone together author
and its members uqs IPS with its sock
the industry government and
international organizations like the
Interpol is owned East and so on
together with all the researchers from
our different faculties the engineering
texture an IT faculty with the school of
IT EE the signs with the math and
physics you know the mathematicians and
the physicists who are working on a
quantum computing the post quantum
crypto and so on the humanities arts and
social science faculty who are working
on the different social aspects and the
challenges of cyber security and the
Business Economics and law faculty
working on the business governance the
economical decision-making the legal
aspects of cybersecurity medicine coming
together to understand from the
psychology perspective even for the
health information systems the data
privacy and so on the Center for Policy
futures covering the national security
and the policies and we have the
Institute for social science research
which supports the H a SS and also of
course yeah coming together and as Mike
alluded to it's dangerous to go alone
and David as well mention that so we all
coming together and together we've all
set we are actually offering a lot of
continuing professional development
courses the master's program PhDs and so
on so that's in a nutshell how we are
proposing to work together and it is my
dream at least to see all of you as part
of UQ cybersecurity if you come by our
booth you might get a UQ cybersecurity
sticker right so I'll see you at a booth
then thank you very much
you