hi everyone my name is Jamila I work as
a security researcher at 11 pads 11 but
it's the telefónica cyber security unit
the idea of the stock came to us because
we usually think of Sims as defensive
tools or blue team tools and during this
talk we will see them from the point of
view of the attacker or the red team yes
I came from machine Tina very very long
it's 27 hours of a trip of 27 hours to
get here so a very very very long trip I
think you might know my country for some
of the things messy who knows messy you
raise your hand may see all of you knows
messy I know that dulce de leche anyone
oh just one three three people next time
I have to bring some dulce de leche for
you to try and asado
it's like Argentinean meat it's it's
delicious it's great well starting with
the talk seems a stand for security
information and event management sim
solutions combine security information
management management and security even
management security even management
carries out low analysis of flawed data
on on real-time to to detect straight ID
to provide even correlation thread
monitoring and incident response and
security information management is used
to analyze
the deadlock data in order to generate
reports of these microphones
well any of you knows plan okay
Splunk is a sim solution that use it has
a web interface it can search sorry
Esther
okay Splunk is a commercial seem that
that's important that allows you to
capture analyzed and and search for data
and within a web interface any of you
knows the other one drill of the open
source one okay
Greg log is an open source seam the the
uses is like the this blank one used to
search and monitor data with a
centralized console and use MongoDB and
elastic search in order to store and
search for the data well who use this
this type of system these seems in
general sim solutions are mostly used by
large organizations and public companies
compliance with regulations remains a
very strong factor in the use of this
technology however from the point of
view of the attacker this is the
attacker hacker cut I allow it I love
hacker cut well the permission that
seems have on the server on which the
seam is installed the other components
on on the infrastructure are very broad
so you can use administrative access to
a seam it can be used to compromise the
server on which the seam is installed
and in some cases the declined equipment
from which the seams collect the event
well we are going to talk a bit about
blank versions and features I can see
anything there so I just here the three
more important versions of explaining
the most use it's a light version but
but it's not it's not very used so we
are talking about it
free is blank enterprise and sprang
cloud the first one is plank free I
don't have any type of access control or
authentication any user who knows the
URL and it's not a very difficult URL
you can search in insulin for that and
you can access with administrative
privilege to the to the scene a Splunk
enterprise can use several
authentication methods like LD IP proxy
SSO sam'l and scripting but in general
user name and password that's blank
internal authentication method it's the
most use and is the default
authentication metal M in a splendid
enterprise you you could configure
password policies the the only one
mandatory password policy for force
planning Enterprise is they ate they'll
launch the length of the password it's a
it's mandatory to have a password from
eight or more characters length in new
versions you can configure another
things like password complexity I can
look out after a serious or failed login
attempts but this this password policies
are not applied in the same way in all
cases so we are going to to see that
later in another slide well about the
permissions explained free and sprang
Enterprise are usually installed as as
root or with administration
administration privilege you you can
stall it with an unprivileged user but
it's not the
the common case in general and the the
important thing is in a Springfree and a
Splunk enterprise
you can upload custom applications or
that is to say you can brought your own
your own application and upload to just
blank application or script a Splunk
load is different because it's blank has
all the control on the environment so
you can you can configure s plank by
changing configuration files by the
command line command line interface and
you can't upload a custom applications
and Ana script and the authentication
for Splunk load could be sam'l user
password or LD IP also okay it's blank
loud sorry
it's usually published on the internet
because of course is blank loud but why
would someone expose to the Internet is
plank free or Splunk enterprise I I
really I don't see any reason for for
that you can search children for forest
planks the first search is by a TTP
component and these are it returns all
these planks that have their web
interface published on the internet the
second one returns all these planks that
have the management port that is a 8089
with explained e you can search for all
all the these planks on the internet
well that is the s Planck law in page
analyzing the source code of the S plank
login page we know this
that this is happening to access the
explained REST API endpoints is
necessary to be authenticated first but
in this case the spline login page the
API call is made directly from the from
the Splunk login page before the
authentication process and the result is
loading in JSON as as you can see the
first endpoint service session indicates
with the property has logged in in in
the top of the of the screen and
indicates whether someone ever logged
into the sim if anyone ever has logged
to the sim it's very very likely that
the sims still still has the default
password that is changed me in in other
versions in new versions you can choose
your own from 7.1 you can choose another
password if at the installation time but
in Nollan versions the the default
password was changed me and in the other
[Music]
in the other API call that is its
service server info this this has the
information of the of the blank license
and you can see there is if is blank
a free explain Enterprise or explain
cloud and the version of s plank all
this before authentications just looking
at the source code of the blank login
page with this information and and the
shell and search for all these blanks
with the web interface exposed to the
internet I wrote two scripts to Python
script to detect a s planks at risk of
being compromised big
of default password or because they are
the free version with no authentication
the first one that takes all the blank
free exposed to the Internet and the
second one that takes all the blanks
with default password previous version
to 77.1 that has no no more default
password the result is this this country
an and 69s planks exposed to the
Internet at risk of being compromised of
being compromised for the full password
or because they are the free versions of
his blank who has no authentication well
but what's the case if s plank
displaying that we are going to attack
is not free and it has not the default
password you can you can do a brute
force or a dictionary attack on the on
the password of the user admin in
previous version was admin now you can
choose another name for this user if you
want but in most most of the time the
user is still admin the DES plank a
brute force or or dictionary attack
could be performed on the web interface
or in the management part you could use
a very same Metasploit to to carry on
this attack and you can use other tools
such as Hydra on the web interface but
the problem is in newest version you you
can configure a akan lookout but a
series of failed login attempts so our
approach is different
we made the the brute force or
dictionary attack on the management
interface not on the web interface
because they account lockout policy
doesn't apply to the management
interface you can try all the all the
password that you want and you won't be
looking the the admin account well I
will explain attack vectors 2 3 & 6
because you are going to see the others
in the demos that I brought today
number 2 being a low analysis and
collection the first thing that we can
think of is use it as an intelligent
source to identify users in the
environment roles and usage patterns
that's attack vector 2 for attack vector
3 you can use the explained
functionality that uploads files -
indexes to read any file from the from
this from the server where Splunk is
installed for example the the shadow
file on on Linux or Linux systems and
attacked 6 is deploy malicious
applications Universal forwarders
well-explained has a functional itical
deployment server this functionality is
used for deployment of applications our
configuration in distributed
environments and also for configuration
of the M explained Universal forwarders
that
the Splunk collection agent the Asians
installed in the clients like in the
database server in the Active Directory
server for for collection of information
from Reuters or firewalls
about the applications it's very easy to
create this blank applications and s
Planck provides a template called
bare-bones that builds the entire
structure you only have to worry about
the directory being the directory bin
and this is the directory which contains
the actual code of the of the
applications or script and this files
the file up comp this file contains all
the information of the of the
application configuration I forgot to
say this you come Splunk has native
Python support so you can build
applications in Python Perl a bash
PowerShell and even an executable file
all all that could be could be
application or or scripts in use in a
spelunk with blank base ASP language is
like the Play Store in Android is it
contains applications designed by Splunk
or by different providers to integrate
their products with with blank here the
list is ordered but the most downloaded
applications on the ones blank base you
can see the most use applications are
for Windows Linux Cisco database most of
these applications request credentials
to connect to the to the device they
monitor and these credentials are stolen
is plank and if we have admin access to
s plank we can access this credential
and an decrypted and unused in in our
attack to compromise other systems in
the first structure not just this blank
server
well now we are going to see the demo of
the attack vectors 1 4 & 5
first I I will perform a brute-force or
dictionary attack on the admin user of
Splunk and then obtain all the explained
stored password of of the applications
at first we are going to scan the
network in order to attack seems active
on on that network
that will detect it too - seems to us
planks now we are going to choose the
the last one for in order to attack it
and launch the attack model first we
need to use the option one because we
need the credentials that does the Bruce
for for dictionary attack now that we
have credentials we can use the other
attacks we are going with option I think
is for two to obtain all the blank
applications credentials we need to use
the credentials that we obtained before
okay and that's the credentials store on
on this blank it's the last version of
blank the first one is the are the
credentials used by Palo Alto firewall
in order to administrate the fiber and
the second one is the account used for
LD IP wines and this account generally
is a privileged account because it's
used for obtaining the logs of all the
windows hosts on the infrastructure so
generally it's it's a very privileged
account and for the attacker is it's a
very important that going to to have the
credentials for well now we are going to
install a malicious application to
obtain a reverse shell from the blank
server we are going to attack the same
seam as before
lunch they attack model and in this case
we are going with option seven upload
malicious up to a spline server or
Universal forwarder it could be used on
both the server or the universal forward
it's a Linux esplen server in this case
so we are going with option one we need
to enter the credentials and our local
IP address for the reverse for receiving
the reverse connection the application
is so ready install our shell and we are
going to start listener on port 1 2 3 4
5 in order to receive the the reverse
connection
now we have to wait a few seconds and
Splunk will connect to us that's it
Splunk connect to us with root privilege
the application that we install in this
case is a python reversion because it's
a lino server and on windows M Universal
forwarders you you can't use Python and
you you need to use PowerShell or or
another a a bi T file or another another
payload this this tool is developed by
us in in 11 pads ok
recommendations for hardening Splunk
first we need to start
Splunk the server and the universal
forwarders with and privileged users
change all the default password of
course use another authentication method
not Splunk internal and if it's possible
a second authentication factor you still
yes TLS please don't use this blank free
in production environment I I see so
many flanks free in production
environment I think it's because the
cost of blank and and all that but
please it has no authentication it's
it's the worst don't expose the explain
server on the internet of course except
cloud that do you need to to put it on
the Internet and the same day web server
if there is no need most of the attacks
choose planks are based on the web
server so it's an attack surface
reduction disable the web server when
when you don't use it update and purge
Splunk in a regular basis and enable a
Splunk outlet it's the in
X underscore audit now we are going to
talk about grello same case as before
who published the grello web interface
on the Internet I don't see any reason
there is no great load cloud or
something like this so it's I I don't
understand this the most important
Trello components are MongoDB
elasticsearch the web interface and the
rest api the attack vectors you will
notice that the attack vectors are all
different this is because Greylock does
not allow us to upload code through the
web interface so you just can customize
inputs/outputs another so we need to use
other attack vectors different than the
than the splines ones the first one is
the the brute force or dictionary attack
in order to perform this attack we need
to do a post request to this URL API
system sessions and the username is
admin you can change it and icons are
not lookout for fail access attempt
that's attack vector number one you can
configure it it it has the policy for
for configuring the logout it is not
there in in gorilla
well great log virtual machines
appliances relevant on machines
appliances OVA
or am i m has those password by default
the first one for the web interface is
admin I mean a very difficult
combination of username and password to
guess
and I want to won't do for the for the
console and additionally in grade level
tone machine appliances elasticsearch
MongoDB and the web interface are
listening on all the interface I think
that's the reason by that we're why
there are so many great looks exposed on
the internet I thinks it's not
intentional it's people that just
install the built well machine appliance
and didn't notice that that it's going
to publish these ports on on all the
interfaces as attackers we could chase
those default credentials to see if they
are valid that's attack vector number
two same same cases as Splunk
and greg log store credentials but in
the database in MongoDB in MongoDB you
can find some store passwords not like
not like this blank ones but but some
password for example they LD IP one this
this password these credentials can be
decrypted using the sick the secret a
store in the gray log server and that's
attack vector number three
recommendations for Greylock hardening
please please please don't use a virtual
machines grail of virtual machines in
production environment I seen it so many
times a lot like is plank free provide
please don't do that limit the interface
on which MongoDB and elasticsearch
listen for incoming data a set up
authentication for MongoDB this is
important because in the installation of
grail of
by default the MongoDB is installed
without any type of authentication so
you need to configure it later enable
the access log and use another
authentication for the web interface not
user name and password and any field if
you could please use another a second
factor authentication method well here
you have some resources and downloads
and for more information based on the
results of this research we developed
these tools that we show us before the
name of the tool is Simms framework
allows to automate all these dimension
attack in commercial and open source
seems and the tool is open-source and
will be released on August blackhat
Arsenal and it will be include Splunk
Trello for sim and other seems that that
we are trying to incorporate to
incorporate sorry incorporate to the to
the tool and thank you very much for
your attention and special things to
assert for inviting me to this really
really great David thank you
[Applause]
thank you very much for that it's
fantastic
do we have any questions from the
audience oh one off the back ah great
get my steps up so just a quick one it
run his long into this is an imperfectly
privileged position did you think about
actually deploying something so that
when they log in you harvest their
credentials or you something sorry I
didn't understand the question so Iran
whose logins and admin uh-huh
could you exploit that could you have
that as a module so it drops a shell or
drops a bit of malware so that then when
they log in your RSA attack they log in
and get popped it's it's very
interesting at that vector I didn't I
didn't think of that
but but it's it's really it's a well we
don't do illegal things do we are there
any other questions
nope well in that case thank you very
much' Miller round of applause guys
[Applause]