anyway yeah so it's a normal hackathon
we have to go through usual stuff the
URL champion the client-side validation
sequel injection XML injections were
kind of new to me see XSL you're gonna
form cryptanalysis to two bit and then
brute-force attacks and even go to a
dossing an application to unknown
vulnerability in that app so normal
normal hackathon stuff at the end of the
day or rather half day alex and i
finished in the top two of on the
scoreboard for the entire class which is
awesome or so we thought yeah we said so
what's the perfect score and they said
oh the perfect score is 1000 you guys
you know just barely scratching it and
and they also said nobody ever got to
the top score sorry yeah security
innovation was also kind enough to leave
the environment open for a few more days
and they basically told us go home and
keep hacking and keep learning and
that's what we did we went home and kept
exploiting finding and exploiting those
vulnerabilities in this web application
and both Alex and I separately and
combined we got you 9,000 plus points
much better but yeah still we still
didn't hit the tops and I was like come
on you've challenged us we got to get
there and we're sitting there it's
Sunday night it's like eight hours left
till they turn off the service and we're
like let's let's just you know try
something else they just keep scratching
our hasn't said we're gonna turn it off
on Monday morning yeah what do we do so
we decided that you're probably gonna
waste a lot of time trying to find the
those vulnerabilities that they code it
and we should look for some
thing that was not intended there for
that to be so we started in prompted
hacking and you know from your textbooks
on hacking and that's what it looks like
you know reconnaissance research try
exploit profit repeat but in reality you
know it's a lot of frustration trial and
error some alcohol involved
maybe maybe other substances yeah you've
heard on today's talk if you were in the
keynote I mean it's it's rarely this
textbook example is just a lot of
bashing and drinking so I'll give a
quick for into how Hulk hackathons are
built so for those of you haven't been
on the other side of things can
understand by the way there's a talk and
thirty minutes two o'clock right topper
is talking about how he put together
this CTF for this conference so if
you're interested in actually learning
how it's done then go to that talk to
but they in reality it's billed by
hackers for heck cuz right so obviously
they know all the other vulnerabilities
and they they're not just gonna leave
you with a pre Vasque there so you shut
everything tight and obviously the
training company they wanted to make
sure that they keep it all closed and as
to realize much later what we were doing
with it was a bunch of hardened
aw Linux boxes and have no normal tools
no you know you can't just on that cat
and be happy there so no extra all the
challenges everything was hard-coded
into the app and compiled there was no
databases no text files nothing to
tamper with and no public and bond
acceptor for port 18 no outbound either
so it's like oh man
that's really tough yeah so we looked
for those things like open ports
nothing and finally we realized that
some of the URLs have this dot action
extension and I think Alex said yeah
this looks familiar
better the use of Apache struts okay
awesome
anybody here stirs recently no well yeah
so we'll have to slide on there was
earlier but obviously you know it was it
was in March you know
April right no we were doing this like
end of March so you know we were going
out after the exploits and looking at
certain exploits and we come up against
this thing that's you know CV 2017 and
remember this number five three three
eight apparently it's five six three I
can't read English
all right sous-sous it's a it's a CB SS
score town it's like alright and it's
fairly recent so how about we try it
looks like stress is there yeah why not
maybe they haven't passed yet so it's a
couple of weeks after the they actually
release of the so we ran a tool called
Metasploit framework and they already
had an exploit for that I mean they just
searched for strats and they had six or
seven and this was this one was the most
recent and we just put the parameters
the the host name the port
yeah and we're like hey we're gonna have
some time to sleep today - yeah okay
Metasploit is gonna do it for us and it
kind of did so when we hit when we put
the check command it set yay target is
broader ball awesome not quite yeah well
it's said vulnerable but then when we
tried creating such as nothing happens
like you can't get out we can't
communicate nothing's like so the only
little piece of information we had is
like a it says it's smaller and once it
hopefully it's not lying to us it's
promising but we cannot get shell or
remote command execution so we start
looking into that yeah so we could be
first of all we trying to understand how
the how Metasploit was checking that
it's vulnerable so we ran the traffic
through intercepting proxy and we used
burp here on the top you see this is the
request that that Metasploit was sending
and on the bottom is the response the
request is looking kind of funny but the
the highlighted text is what's important
if you look closely at this you can see
it's
looking like Java it's calling a certain
Java method to get proper system get
property with OS dot name parameter and
that it puts the result into just a
random header and on the response here
is this header with the value so it is
running a Java method to get the
operating system name and returning back
to Metasploit that's how it knows that
it's vulnerable and you can see it's
using this funky language that's called
OGN l which we just least recently
learned people in Java world called
agonal so it's using agonal all right so
so the next thing pop off one you know
finally exploit open up the ruby exploit
the Metasploit is running and start
reading the code and it's like what well
how does it work how is it checking you
know you can see in this ruby code it's
putting together the agonal thingy and
it actually is what it's doing
internally is it goes over and starts
setting up this symphony agonal as a
library that apache hasn't developed for
internal language processing but well
sousou you'll see later to it also goes
into setting up excluded classes
basically it removes all the security
precautions that agonal has internally
just basically calling sink clear clear
clear this stuff out and and go and pop
the OS name system property into the
header and then return that hatter now
this thing worked the check works the
exploit thing didn't so we were tasked
with now we need to make this thing work
somehow yeah if you wanted to get
something too useful running the server
so we tried a few things and of course
we we do not intend to write something
in Ruby no well instead we use the
cieaura come out of curl which is a
really nice little tool that can send
any kind of HTTP request and show you
the response so in this case we built a
curl command to send to send requests to
our vulnerable server and this is the
header that that is custom and as you
can see we're trying to run a remote
command basically with the reverse shell
right and that's a bachelor's show if
you've not familiar with this this is
the thing to have like you know if you
don't have that yet that's the way to
get a reverse shell if if you have
oddball Network any good network alright
so the next thing we've tried all right
let's try to just find a filing we'd
from the file so we're built in some
Java code and so that and put a file and
and we were able to actually get and
read and put something into into one of
the headers to return the content so
like all right so we're getting there so
we could get the bits and pieces we also
tried to write a file so we sent two
headers instead of one then one header
contained that base 64 base64 encoded
file content and then the code here got
that header if I can read it it's
difficult to read here is and then it
would decode and then write to file and
then we're hoping that he would just
execute it on the server and get
something I don't know maybe torque we
had no way to check right it was the
server was always silent to us and then
and it took a little while and that dawn
on us yeah yeah so we realize that it
over complicating things and it should
be easier than that and after a couple
hours maybe three four hours we came up
with this and this is the end result of
our hecan't and what this little script
does is it does some prep work there are
some variables
you know it's server name and and B path
to do the application on the server it
creates just a file name with the
timestamp and we use that file to so via
Roenick so we know we know we can run a
command on the server
the problem is how do you get the result
of that command because the server
cannot communicate back to you so you
thought okay this is a web server why
can't we just run the command redirect
its output to a file and then just
retrieve that file from that web server
and that's what we tried and
surprisingly it works so here we just
the dollar one is the command that we're
on and it redirects to our output file
and the blah blah blah runs the process
and we don't care you know about the
process anymore
we just want wanna wait for it to finish
and then on the bottom the this little
command on the very bottom is just a
plain HTTP GET for that file the name of
which we know because we created it
ourselves and then we want to out so
once we got this go on yay let's exfil
everything we we can it's like hey let's
go out after you know get get it see get
off to get a user get you know all the
content from the server we can get and
got everything yeah basically we run
commands to read everything that the web
user was able to read yeah and the most
important thing that came was the
content of the actual hackathon that was
the war file the web application you
know Java compiled code and obviously
what do you do when you get a compiled
code and while you decompile it and JT
goo is an excellent tool to compile look
at it see those at completed challenges
and see those unique identifiers for
those completed challenges that are sent
to their CNC server and it's like all
right I think we got there yeah so we
basically we just took the D compile
code and looked for all these at
completely challenged occurrences with
those unique strings and we built our
own java class that we were hoping to
run on the server to just execute all
these methods and by doing that it would
send the commands that commands but
messages to to the main to the
scoreboard server to register that we
finished
and since we've got all their libraries
too we just compile against their
libraries I can't wouldn't care and then
the next thing was how do we upload all
they were on it but thankfully they also
they had an upload vulnerable upload
page that we have used an intentional
yeah actually that was intentional
vulnerability but we put put it as a
text fake text and renamed it with our
command and you know next thing was hey
timestamps no see how fast we hack it's
like getting 2,000 points in four
seconds or something yeah thank you so
so that was those fun and games and
everything and alex is gonna talk a
little bit about the responsible
disclosure we didn't land and you know
all that common you know good feelings
and stuff but we wanted to talk about a
little more profits so here's another
example he's this is a training program
this is another sort of a hackathon
training program and it's awesome it's
it does pretty well it's it's from my
sac its cybersecurity and access and it
what it does it also you complete a
challenge and then it also reports your
sea pees like any time you spend on
hacking it and and submits on your
behalf and I thought that's an
interesting way let's see what I can do
with CPEs so I did a little more so that
was another hackathon it was a different
blog it was a shell injection it was
actually yeah shell injection then into
an map but there you can do something
else when people submit you know see
Pease on your behalf you can submit a
little more so I thought yeah it spent a
lot of time thinking about it maybe so
for two hours of work you've got 20
hours of CP yeah nice profit yeah but
you know if it were smarter
so when the equifax thing came out they
they kind of hinted right away that it
was my cheese frosting and then a week
later a few days later they actually
confirmed officially that it was the
same Apache stress vulnerability that
they get hacked through same one that we
exploited in that hackathon you see the
number you remember that number right
into 638 so real-life consequences it's
it's not fun anymore
I'm sure I'm one of those 145 million
people and my information is out there
if you ever doubted that your
information was out there it's out there
now
you know it was happening about the same
time essentially all right so so you
know quickly what what does this whole
thing mean to you if you're not you know
putting together hackathons obviously
you know you got to know what's deployed
in your system you've got to watch for
the recent series and you got to
understand your application you get a
scan for vulnerabilities this is I'm not
breaking anything new here it's new you
need the usual cybers you know hygiene
and perform pen testing but the other
thing that's kind of important here and
that's in the light of the Equifax I
mean they get they got hacked pretty
fast too and this you know the security
innovation we were able to get in fairly
fast - there's a certain period of time
before it comes out in somebody hacks in
where you can't really do anything so a
second level of defense would have
definitely helped if they had a Wafaa
plication firewall that had signatures
at least you know filtered out the
freaking whole thing you don't need it
why who does use it and it's like when
we were looking at there's almost no
documentation limit either it's like
come on
use use some other method of protection
know that you're gonna be hacked at some
point what's the other thing that's
gonna stop or it will slow them down and
if your developer meaning you develop an
application or a website or just a
company that has a web presence you got
a watch you know you
know what libraries you using you got a
if there is an issue with them you need
to release your patches promptly as well
and all responsible disclosures meaning
somebody comes to you and says hey your
website is vulnerable and here's how I
can hack it don't just turn them into
your FBI you know work with them because
most people they're trying to help and
that's what we did also we reported this
to security innovation they handle the
situation very professionally they told
us exactly I mean they were respectful
they told us what the planning to do
they asked us to wait on publishing this
until they fix it we complied of course
and it was a very good experience I
think we we said we sent a report like
at 1:00 1:00 a.m. and we got a response
ten minutes later or yeah from a
salesperson their salespeople don't
sleep it was our only point of contact
at the companies
[Applause]
you