that you guys could hear that in the
back okay so a toothbrush that plays
music in that video you know imagine
having somebody replace it with like
death metal or porn or something like
that sorry if you're underage yeah so
you know it's it's it was a constant so
people are like oh I want to I want to
make it play whatever but nobody ever
did it so my whole thing was like this
is a cool concept but it needs a little
bit of finessing these a little bit of
help all right yeah so plays a
two-minute song clip of the the world's
most popular artists according to
somebody probably not in this community
though yeah so originally came out in
2007 and then was re-released in 2012
which is when I found out about it what
the real kind of thing is is based on
bone conduction which I guess is called
a denta mandibular sound transmitting
system where the the element that
vibrates kind of runs the vibrations run
through your bone you can actually hear
it in like your inner ear which is
awesome and this is dated back a long
time I was talking to rob earlier who
just gave the talk and he was saying
something about a retainer that you
could do something to play music I had
seen once like some swim goggles that
had something on the back that would
tell you how many laps you've run so
there's been attempts at doing consumer
electronic stuff for a while in this
space and if you look at at this main
patent which is the arm and hammer now
owned by Armand Hammer patent it has
some references and prior art and ideas
of like spoons that play music and this
and that and anything you put in your
mouth will play music there are lots of
options and but the toothbrush is the
one that stuck it seems like so here's
what the packaging looked like yeah it's
great if you're 12 it which is probably
why you need help brushing your teeth
anyway but this is you know interesting
concept but definitely not targeted
towards people like me and I wanted that
targeted towards people like me so I
mean I think the toothbrush is good but
the main problem is that all the songs
just you know just totally sucked it was
lame so the process is I'm gonna replace
the circuitry with something that allows
me to play whatever music I want
here's the timeline so ya talking about
spending lots of time on projects this
was a five-year endeavor and I probably
spent I don't know maybe two twelve or
twenty or forty hours on it total or
something way way more than you would
expect for like hacking a toothbrush but
yeah so I bought it right when it came
out and I was like this is so cool the
music sucks and I'm gonna fix it I did
build a prototype in 2013 which I'll
show you the pictures of then I moved
here thank you and thank you for
accepting me and everything was in boxes
for a few years and I just totally
forgot about it like I sort of knew in
my head I had wanted to do it but it
just like was not something that could
find and I wasn't really like I'm gonna
hack the toothbrush now so I eventually
found it last year and then finished it
this year so yeah a long time that's the
death dedication right dedication to the
cause of making tooth brushing better
for all of you okay so here's the
teardown first thing that I like to do
is I get the product take it apart look
at the circuitry and figure out how I
can manipulate that so normal toothbrush
looking at the top this is all like a
one-piece molded plastic and there's
some rubber built in but it needs to be
water-resistant and it's probably pretty
waterproof the batteries which are down
here are not replaceable I don't know
how long the thing is supposed to last
but if it's a two-minute song clip but
you know some it's three triple-a so
it's probably gonna still last a few
years
maybe with self-discharge I don't know I
didn't do the calculations but it will
last long enough until the kids get sick
of a song and throw it out or buy a new
one but there's like a overhang around
here to keep everything pretty well
sealed up so it wasn't something that I
could just open up and take the stuff
out it took a little bit of kind of
breaking I broke quite a few of them
which I bought them all on eBay and to
try to figure out like how can I get the
circuitry out in a way that when I put
my new circuitry back in I wouldn't
break everything and figure out how I'm
gonna attach the element so that was one
tricky thing his hat figuring out how to
get access to this back part which was
like glued in and there was like a post
and everything so once I got like a neat
little method of like some you know nose
pliers and just some finesse to pull
that out that worked okay the other
trick was getting
to the element which is here and it's
all molded in the actual head I don't
have a picture of the head here but it's
up here it's sort of a round thing
that's not directly connected to the
bristles it's just in that housing and
the wires come down to here and then
their heat shrink to some wires that go
down to the circuitry which actually so
they kind of continue along here and
then over to here
so I couldn't figure out any easy way to
get that out without doing some
modification of the of the area around
here which I'll show you later on this
plastic piece you see here if you pull
that out it's this plastic how this
little carrier here which has the space
for the batteries so now that I know how
to open this I can replace the batteries
which is good this is the circuitry here
which there are some discretes there's
nothing on the back side and so there's
the button to start and stop the
playback you can you can play the song
and it will continue to play all the way
through or you can stop it if you're
done early which is cheating because
they're supposed to brush your teeth for
two minutes right but who actually
brushes their teeth for two minutes
really okay I have a dentist
appointment on Wednesday so maybe I
should start yeah I always say I do and
they know I'm lying I didn't realize
that people actually do good for you
guys that's amazing okay so don't come
close to me I guess so this is the main
circuit shows here so you have a button
here and then this is a chip on board
type of device so if you if you think
about like a normal integrated circuit
that you see in a circuit board it's
like a black plastic housing with wires
with leads coming off or maybe there's
leaves underneath you can't see them
this is the silicon underneath here
actually an integrated circuit or just
just the chip wire bonded with little
tiny wires to the circuit board and then
coated with epoxy on top Blagh with
epoxy this is like a really hard coating
that if you want to manipulate devices
like this you could either get the
coating off with chemicals or scrape it
or more likely just look for other
places to tap on to it so it's a
possibility that you know I like I could
maybe monitor some stuff here and see
but it's really just looking for the
button press all the songs stuff is
stored in here and that's this stuff the
chip on board is really common for high
volume low cost stuff where things
aren't gonna change at all
but I wanted to be able to change the
music and have control of the music so
my whole thing was like alright just get
rid of this build something that looks
exactly like that that can take an SD
card that will play songs
I don't like recreating the wheel and I
like you know being able to share my
project so other people can build on
them and in the same way I don't mind
using other people's projects to build
on my stuff so this just happened to be
I did some google searching of like
audio player wav file microcontroller
because I didn't want to have to design
the whole SD card interface the fat
filesystem all of that so this person
named Chan there's not I don't know much
about that person because there's not a
lot of information but there's tons of
great projects on the website and this
was one of like this project that that
he or she came up with that was a tiny
wave player for an 8-bit 80 tiny AVR
Atmel AVR microcontroller that also had
support already for the fat filesystem
so you it would read a memory card and
play the song so it's great that was
like a perfect starting point so I
didn't have to do like all this crazy
reverse engineering or crazy engineering
to get this stuff done so this was the
starting point for the for the project
let's see so yeah he has or she has a
bunch of code in here two two-bit bang
through over SPI so software spi control
to read the SD card which is a standard
kind of SPI interface and then there's
some module fat FS that that people have
been using I think it's for at males I'm
not exactly sure at some C library so
well well fat Oh fat FSS is that generic
library what's that oh okay cool yeah so
that's still the standard so he wrote or
she wrote a petite fat FS which was just
sort of a carved out version too you
know for what for what's gonna fit with
this particular microcontroller so less
than 512 bytes of RAM which is cool
so if you take nothing else out of this
if you ever want to play WAV files from
a microcontroller of an SD card you just
use this stuff yeah so standard WAV
format in RIF 8 or 16-bit files and then
it's mono so yeah all that all all that
starting point was there
so I built up a prototype and just had
it working without the toothbrush right
so eighty tiny microcontroller little
circuit and SD card with a little
carrier board from Adafruit
over to a speaker and it worked fine as
expected right because the project that
part of the project already worked I did
have to make some firmware changes to
get the code to compile because the last
time it was worked on was 2000 between
2009 2012 so I had to get some stuff
tweak some stuff to get it working to
compile in 2017 but that was not too
much of a problem we also build the
prototype up and this is again part of
the standard process for me anyway is
when I'm starting to design a circuit I
will do something on a breadboard like
this where you can plug stuff in take
things out change values get everything
working here before you kind of hard you
know code it into circuitry on a circuit
board so that worked so then I went and
built my first version of the board
which doesn't get a lot of respect in
this presentation because it didn't
totally work the way I wanted it to but
I will mention so I got the board back
through OSH park of course because
they're awesome and local and here and
here in the front row so yeah got the
board's back built it up just like the
prototype and which was just like the
version that Shan had written or had
made but it turns out when I hooked it
up to the actual element
it was way not loud enough and I had
actually tested that with the prototype
at the beginning but I it just didn't
occur to me that it wasn't loud enough I
heard it and I'm like yes it works but
then I didn't I didn't test it as much
as I should have before I built the
first version so I built it and realized
it wasn't loud enough and I tried to
convince myself that it would be okay
I was like well I can kind of hear it as
long as there's nothing else going on
around and like but I just couldn't
bring myself to actually call that
complete and I was like damn now I have
to go and find an amplifier and build
another circuit and hack on that and try
to get it a little better what I ended
up doing is using a little little level
meter to measure the sound of the
original and then try to match it a
little bit to see you know okay let's
let's add my amplifier and see if I can
jack up the volume and make it work
because with the speaker with my
amplifier it was suit
was really loud but then with the
transducer it wasn't because whatever
the you know however the construction of
that thing is and the the resistance and
I mean I don't even know so I figured I
would just do like some test once I got
it close enough I ended up using a LM 48
64 which I'll show you on the next slide
just a standard kind of audio amplifier
to take the output of chance of chance
design and then amplify that so here's
the final look of the circuitry fits
right in place so ya button micro SD
card slot let's see the battery
transducer and then the backside had the
micro controller the amplifier and an
on/off control which I'll talk about
when I show you the schematic and then
the voltage regulator so power comes in
goes the voltage regulator gets
regulated down from the four and a half
volts to three volts to power everything
micro controller has the code the on-off
control again I'll talk about later and
then the amplifier takes the sound in
amplifies it and then sends it out to
the transducer and it just so happened
that like the board I'd already design
you know for the first version it looked
exactly the same except without the
amplifier there was nothing under here I
might have had a big bypass capacitor or
decoupling cap or something over here so
it just happened that this was like just
the right size so you know I didn't want
to have to like go to smaller components
or anything like that so here's the
final schematic sort of you know assume
Chan's design is this and then I have
kind of the simple stuff added to it so
yeah SD card goes in here with the wav
file gets communicated over SPI to here
and then this will output PWM to the
audio amplifier which will amplify it
and then play the sound a cool thing is
down here we have the voltage regulator
here and then remember at the beginning
I mentioned you can play the song you
can also stop the song halfway through
for people like me who don't brush our
teeth for two minutes I needed a way to
do that sort of have on/off control of
the system and there are ways that I
that I had thought about using
transistors you could have two two
transistors and do some stuff with
discrete components but that would have
been way too big to fit on the board it
turns out that Maxim has a chip this
sixty no 54 which is an actual on-off
controller so
typically the the setup is you have your
on-off controller with an input on a
button and then the output and the
inverted outputs you can choose you know
depending on your system feed that
directly into the enable pin of the low
dropout linear regulator a lot of
designs you know normally the enable pin
is just pulled high so it's always on so
this is like any actual use of the
enable pin so now you can push the
button this this will always stay on
this has like a pretty wide voltage
range so you power it directly from the
batteries and this will always stay on
and I think it sucks like seven micro
amps or something it's it's small enough
for for most battery-powered systems and
it will eventually kill the batteries
over time but I thought it was a good
compromise so it stays on waits for an
interrupt and then we'll set the output
will toggle the output so when I want to
interrupt to the playback I can push the
button again it's gonna change the state
of that disable the voltage regulator
and turn it off alright so that's cool
what I also did is modified the firmware
to change one of the pins so there's a
reset pin normally that with this chip
this eighty tiny 85 three set pin is by
default a reset pin I disabled that
change the fuses to turn it into GPIO
pin and then modified the code so once
the song stops playing the way it turns
itself off is it will set this pin high
normally it's low set the pin high which
clears sort of as a secondary input into
this part and then toggles the output so
it will shut itself off so now the user
can manually turn off the unit and then
the electronics can manually turn itself
off also aside thought was sort of cool
and then the amplifier bridge siloed
output and it's pretty loud with a
normal speaker but not with this but
louder than it was before the amplifier
so yeah just a list of some of the code
changes this stuffs all on where did I
put that code I think there's a link to
it on my website I think it's on my
website I don't know but you can see the
code modifications on there but yeah so
fix some of the stuff that that would
that wasn't working the way that Chan's
code was is it would play every single
file in the directory like one time and
then it would keep keep repeating it you
know yeah I would play each one one time
and they repeat and keep playing sort of
constant stream so I just changed that
to just play the first file it found on
the filesystem and play it once and then
turn it
and then dealing with the with problems
of that because when you disable the
reset pin that lets that prevents you
from doing any subsequent in circuit
programming so you can only program it
and I think it's the high voltage
programming mode or something I had to
use a device programmer to do that
instead of like the you know standard
wavelet whatever the Adafruit um oh the
USB you know tiny isp stuff sort of in
circuit serial programming so it's a
little bit of a problem when I was
modifying the code and then testing the
code because I couldn't just do the
typical iteration of make code changes
program it tested it was like make code
changes put it in the device programmer
program it stick it in the device
you know socket and go from there
there's just a longer process but
luckily the changes weren't like that
crazy but if you wanted you know compile
your own you grab the code use these
things with these few settings and you
should be good to go so here are some of
the pictures of the final board now that
I knew that board worked you know again
I want to make it look as stock as
possible but I just couldn't figure out
a good way to get into that transducer
so I took a little um little little
drill drilled in use some dental tools
to like fish out the wire so cut them
with one dental tool and then use
another one to fish out the wires and
just left enough that I could strip it
off add some you know blue wire 30 gauge
wire yeah it was like it was like
laparoscopic without a camera right so
you just sort of sort of guessing and
you'll maybe I could do a smaller hole
with better tools or something but that
was fine what I didn't end up doing is
putting like you know silicone in here
and I probably could if I was actually
gonna use it but after all this work I
didn't want to use it because it's like
I only had the one that actually works
well and looks good and I was like I
just want brush my teeth yeah so this is
what it looks like so final things
circuitry you know the transducer gets
extended out to here and then SD card
here slides it in put the batteries in
and and that's it so with that let's
give our demonstration so I released a
video about this online I don't member
when if you want to go or something and
the original intent so I grew up in sort
of that kind of punk hardcore scene in
Boston
and listen to a lot of straightedge
hardcore so kind of positive message and
drug free and all this stuff and there's
a band called Crucial youth that had a
song which was a spoof of like a lot of
the positive bands at the time and they
had a song called positive dental
outlook which I thought would be like
totally fitting for this toothbrush
because there's a lot of songs about
positive mental attitude you know and
being positive so I thought that would
be funny so I made a video and showed
that song and realized pretty quickly
that like most people didn't know what
that was and could barely understand it
because it was loud and fast and
everything so when I got accepted to be
sighs which thank you to everybody who
accepted me because I wasn't expecting
to give a talk on packing a toothbrush
and to Chris and staff for convincing me
to also submit it I figured I should do
something more portland-based right
because we're Portland and it would be
it would be pretty silly to just play
the same song so I have a special song
for you that nobody has heard yet and
well at least not in toothbrush form and
I'm pretty proud of it I think it's
pretty hilarious and hopefully somebody
will recognize it let's see so I'm gonna
do this alright so I'm gonna put this
microphone over here and oh I should
mention so I have two different speakers
because if I just held the transducer to
here you're probably not gonna hear it
so I have the paper cup which were a wax
coated paper cup which works pretty well
and then there's this kind of metal
Mancala box which this sounds a little
bit tinny but this is what i use for the
other videos i think i'm gonna try it
with the with the cup first and we'll
see if you can hear it I have a backup
video just in case anyway so but let's
see what happens will you be able to
hear that wiggle around too much
all right so I might have to do this a
few times I don't know let's see if
let's see if you can hear it ready don't
count down three two one the whole thing
[Music]
[Applause]
that's now officially my favorite song
and I've listened to it like a thousand
times as I was getting the volume right
and everything and that was actually the
remix so if you watch the first episode
of Portlandia that's where this tune
came from and this was a remix version
so somebody took it and made it sound
even better so yeah that's one thing you
have to do is you're gonna have to fine
tune your audio for the transducer cuz
it just has a much weirder response but
yeah you know then you can have awesome
songs like that so possible enhancements
I think none I think it's fine the way
it is but of course people have opinions
so when I originally posted the video
they're like well you have Bluetooth and
you can play it from your phone it's
like because I don't want to have my
phone in the bathroom when I'm brushing
my teeth for less than two minutes
anyway
uh-huh so I don't know and then
inductive charging maybe we don't have
to change the batteries and then
actually the one thing I would say is
some easy access to to the to the SD
card cuz getting to it you have to
unscrew the screw on the back of the you
know where the batteries are pull that
out pull the housing out and then change
it so that's sort of a pain especially
for for testing but works fine for my
purposes of giving a talk and putting it
in a box okay so final slide yeah if you
want to build your own everything's on
my website and you can go directly to
ash Park if you want to order the bare
boards I have them shared so you can
just go there order them get your
toothbrush and you know have better
sounds so with that yeah thank you and
remember to keep that positive dental
outlook
and this by the way was another
inspiration this is called the youth
brush that's like for the youth of today
yeah so thank you oh do we have any
questions no kind you're not allowed to
ask questions but I'll be outside if you
have any
you