what are some of the types of social
engineering attacks that we've seen so
you've seen all the traditional attacks
right you've seen the impersonation
tailgating tailgating is still a problem
today right we haven't fixed that
problem yet shoulders surf reading
dumpster diving and then some of the
stuff we see more today right the
fishing machines machine anything that
ends with ing basically and then you
know I did my own little branding here I
don't know why it's doing that it is
yeah I'll push on my connections and see
if that helps at all I got a lot of
connections up here
well if you could see that that would
say you know it's my special branding
for what we're gonna expect in the
future
and you're seeing some of this already
and one of the things is social media
impersonation so we're seeing the bad
guys are out there they're creating
Twitter accounts and you know you go to
a company maybe you experienced some
poor customer service and you're in the
lineup for an hour and you tweet to them
you say hey this is no good I really
don't like this you get a tweet back
from who you think is them and they say
hey no problem just send us your account
name and we'll give you a credit and so
they start harvesting your credentials
so they're really setting up fake
accounts in the anticipation to to get
that customer service interaction
software-as-a-service
for se everybody else is doing it you
can get dial of service attacks now as a
service so we're really going to start
to see that ramped up I would expect on
the private side we see that already on
the nation-state side you've seen the 50
cent army in China and in every other
country really gravitating in that
direction and you know I think you'll
see that more and more in the private
space as well
virtual kidnapping so where your
accounts get taken over and there could
be various ways to monetize that maybe
they're just going to held you for
ransom
one of the areas that I think you're
really going to see huge developments is
whaling and the reason I say that is
because this is these attacks now have
moved for
you know it's cool to do this I can tell
my friends I did it now it's monetized
this big business now right so who holds
the money while your executives right so
they have the authority to transfer
large sums of money so there are gonna
be really bigger targets and I think
there'll be a lot more effort put into
that so what's the origin story for this
social engineering stuff right it's it
didn't just occur it's not a new thing
I'm pretty sure the people who built the
pyramids you know I think they're pretty
good at social engineering if you want a
crash course in social engineering just
walk oh no a used-car lot and and wait
and see what happens and that experience
is pretty interesting right you'll have
someone come up to you and they'll go
through this certain script and it won't
be oh what kind of car would you like to
buy it'll really be how much money do
you have to spend right and so it's it's
a very interesting approach they're not
concerned about giving you the best car
they want to extract as much funds as
much money out of you as possible and
give you the least value in most cases I
love doing that I love talking to those
guys so why should we care about social
engineering what's the big deal so read
the this charts taken right out of it
that's really distracting I'm glad I'm
not looking at that
come on I got to give you something
hello okay don't touch it all right so
please say so yeah the Verizon report so
this is a chart and I like to look at
charts and I think of charts as stocks
basically and I extrapolated this this
is not what it's really gonna look like
over several years but just for
visibility you know if we take a look at
this
social engineering right that's the
superhot stock right now if this was a
stock you'd want to buy it we compare
that to some other things right we see
that the physical right that's doing
pretty good probably an ETF maybe not a
big dividend right but you know it's
still not bad not as good as social you
know and then malware that's probably
bonds it's leveled off a little bit and
then what they refer to is hacking I
don't remember the definition it's kind
of generic that's the stock that your
friend recommended which is never a good
idea right so you just look at that and
vendors are saying well it's going up by
20%
whatever that percentage is you could
just eyeball that and you can say that's
pretty steep right and when whatever
attacks you're looking at most of them
have started off at least as a social
engineering attack whether it be fishing
or fishing or whatever it was right so
it's usually and especially the oesn't
is usually that first stage of an attack
if you see people looking at all your
stuff doing Osen
well that next step is probably going to
be something a little more serious so
that's why we should care the OSI model
I always like to poke fun at the OSI
model any of you have done an exam
lately you're probably pretty familiar
with this we don't typically look at it
on a day-to-day level but the
interesting thing is it only focuses on
the technical right so the joke is let's
add that user layer on top of that
because I'm not gonna spend a ton of
time trying to hack your firewall if all
I have to do is phone your user base and
say hey what's your password and they
will give it to me right so five minutes
later all right
so kevin Mitnick had the pleasure of
meeting him in Vegas this year amazing
person his books are fantastic you know
he had this great quote the weakest link
in the security chain is the human
element I believe in that personally
after my experience is there anybody in
the room or do you all feel that maybe
that's not the case do you think that
maybe social engineering is really not
that big of a deal
not that big of a threat
are we drinking the kool-aid yeah okay
do you want to do a quick demo to see if
you could be socially engineered yeah
it's worth the time two minutes okay so
let's do a trick real quick this is a
cheap trick you will not like me
afterwards especially if I trick you so
you know full disclosure okay so let's
do something real quick let's pretend
we're a company we're all working in
some big company we're awesome we're
making widgets and I'm the info SEC
persons just one of me so I'm just full
out and I got to do some policy on stuff
you shouldn't be doing so my executives
said they're sick and tired are you
doing this thing like I'll say something
easy like let's say hand flipping right
you're not allowed to hand flip hand
flip is a fireable offense okay
everybody got that
don't flip your hands okay don't do that
I'll gonna do something like dancing but
I don't think anybody you're gonna want
to dance so so no hand flipping that's
the rule it's in policy okay you've all
read the policy of course right because
everybody reads all the policies okay so
let's do this all right
and I need full participation for this
okay let's put your hands out in front
of you like zombies yeah thank you very
much I appreciate that okay so we're
gonna start with our hands up okay
busted
see I told you I told you it was a cheap
trick but that's basically how social
engineering works right like you're told
not to do something and then I kind of
put you in this weird position you know
where you do it right maybe not the best
example but it just kind of shows that
everybody can be socially engineered
everybody ends up clicking on that link
and those emails are not even that good
yet wait til they're good right they're
getting better for sure so I'm sorry
okay I'm sorry about everybody has that
different look at this point in the
presentation I'm sorry that idea I
ripped off from somebody so if anybody
remembers where I got that idea from
I've tweaked it a little bit I think
I've made it better but let me know
because I have no idea where that's from
so if you're still doubt the power of
social engineer and just go google it
right most of most attacks start at that
place either OSINT or pho NSC all right
so a little bit about DEFCON who's been
to DEFCON
holy smokes okay who wants to go to
DEFCON okay good I was really hoping
there'd be as many hands on the second
round they're good okay so I've been at
DEFCON twice first year I went there you
know you buy your ticket for blackhat if
you're going through a company and you
could get kind of DEFCON on the side and
you avoid the lineup and it's kind of
like you know when I first did that it's
like okay well I'm a good blackhat and
then oh yeah maybe I'll go to DEFCON so
I I went through the first year and you
come out of blackhat and it's you know
you wake up you go have breakfast you go
to some talks you have a lunch you go to
some talks you go and party and then you
just rinse and repeat
right DEFCON is not like that they don't
have lunch right so no one's holding
your hand
no one's going over this way sir right
it's really you just do whatever you
want to do there's talk so you can go
out in the desert and shoot guns
there's the villages CTF there's
whatever you want to do so it's really
whatever you want to make of it people
call it a conference I don't think it's
really a conference anymore I think it's
a series of conferences and a whole
bunch of other stuff and you know I got
the feeling when I was there it's more
like Burning Man and in a conference
right if you read the ten principles of
Burning Man you kind of understand what
I'm talking about but definitely worth
your time it's a couple hundred bucks
great value but it's whatever you make
of it I brought a guy from work this
year he went there different experience
because he didn't really know what to
expect and
it can be a little bit overwhelming so
if you're gonna go kind of plan what you
want to do so I saw the su village when
I was there I spent a few minutes at
every every little stationed at every
CTF or every village and I went in there
and saw these people phoning these
companies phoning actual companies and
getting points so well that's pretty
cool I'd love to do that
so I thought okay well I'll apply for
that right that's gonna be my plan of
attack for this year I'm gonna apply but
hundreds of people apply so how am I
going to get in there well and they're
the people that apply are really skilled
there's a lot of talented people at Def
Con how am I gonna get in there so I
thought well okay I'll make an
interesting video right and like
everybody life gets in the way I didn't
have a lot of time so I made a video I
don't know if I'd call it interesting it
was really creepy you can go and watch
it it's not great it's just really
spooky crazy weird but I get I guess
that's what they were looking for
because they said yeah Rob come on in so
that was good for about five minutes I
was pretty excited and then I realized
holy crap I'm gonna be in a room in
front of hundreds of people for 20
minutes and I have to perform
so goodbye weakens weekends and evenings
I spent about a hundred hours prepping
for this which sounds ridiculous and I
guess it was it was quite addictive I
was a total novice so some of the areas
for me that burned a lot of time was how
do I collect data how do I store data
how do I organize this data because if
you have a thousand data points and
you're trying to make sense that and
you're not really used to doing that it
takes a bit of time to do that so so
that was interesting I learned a ton so
if you want to learn if you wanna go
take a course or something and and get a
crash course in any of these areas
things like this at these conferences
the CTFs are a great way to do that I
can't emphasize that enough
so the CTF is basically two stages you
have your first stage which is three
weeks at home in your pajamas doing
OSINT there are sixteen people that
could participate so 16 competitors and
you start following them on Twitter
looking at what they're doing everybody
has their own target so what's a real
company and it's part of a common
industry so this year it was the gaming
industry and which was cool because I
have some of the games of the company
that I targeted which made me feel a
little bit weird but but it was alright
I got to know them
really well and you have 29 flags to
capture and work different points
depending on the quality of the flag so
what's your SSID is worth more than oh
how long have you been working for the
company no engagement so you're allowed
to phone the company but I'm not allowed
to talk to them so I just can confirm
the phone number works and that's really
prepping me for stage 2 which is your 20
minutes phishing live at DEFCON and
there's echoes over two days they're
gonna either go to Friday or Saturday
and the winner really is the one that
captures the most flags or the most
points hence CTF so you can get the same
points that you collected during the
OSINT and you but for the vision you can
get up multiple times depending on how
many people you phone so if iPhone
person a and get all the flags that can
then do the same thing on person B not
person number letter but anyway so you
can repeat it over and over again and
some people just go for the big flags
like please go to this website and they
just keep doing that over and over again
all right this is the flags I don't
expect you to be able to read that but
basically there's things like you know
do you have a cafeteria
what's your VPN janitorial service OS 10
year how long have you worked there for
so those are some of the common ones
then starting my OSINT because it's a
corporation LinkedIn was your my friend
right it's just amazing how much you can
just collect from that alone for
individuals you want to go a little bit
differently but since my target was
corporate great starting point because
not only is it very well laid out but
they've given me some really key
indicators right tenure what they
specialize in
what department they're in so you can
start to kind of group those departments
I had multiple offices and locations so
I could find out what location these
people were in then also there's links
to their other social media which is
great too I don't even have to go
hunting for it right it's all there with
LinkedIn if you send me an invite on
LinkedIn say hey Rob can you join my
LinkedIn
I will accept why because it just
expands my search range right which is
which is fantastic LinkedIn will try to
make you buy a membership at some point
and as you limit out
your search capabilities on there and
you could do that I was determined not
to do that so there's a tool called
Linkedin x-ray which is a great tool and
it will allow you to kind of search the
whole area get much wider results
without having to pay so I'd highly
recommend you take a look at that so
once you're going through the company
you're gonna get a lot of people that
you could go deep on kind of the 8020
rule of course though it 20% of those
people are gonna be the social
butterflies that are gonna put
everything out on the internet right
they're gonna be putting your VPN
information out there so really I
focused on those people and also their
friends because they go out with their
friends and their friends takes pictures
of of their stuff right of their laptop
and things like that so really focusing
on that go into their personal websites
which were just fantastic they'd have
their resume you know home home address
cell phone number what technologies they
use so that was really really helpful as
well so you don't want to look at
everybody because that'll just burn way
too much time so I was a novice when I
started this I'm you know I still
classify myself as a novice compared to
many of you but so when I was out there
doing my OSINT hunting these people
unlinked in you know when someone looks
at your profile you you wonder who was
that why are they looking at my profile
so then you go and look at their profile
well if you do that to a few hundred
people and they all start looking at
your profile so I noticed that after
about a week into it in which which
point it was too late so then I was like
oh dear that could go really bad right
because all I have to do is say hey did
rob say look at your profile yeah he
looked at my - and then you know could
be game over there so many of you
probably already have some of these
solutions in place if you're doing this
professionally there's a lot of options
to give you a little more privacy but
yeah don't make the mistake that I made
all right so pretext development and
pretext is really kind of your story
that you're going with so to develop
those talking to a lot of people over
beers hey would you believe me if I did
this or said this so I got rid of a lot
of pretext through that because at first
you're like okay I'm sneaky I'm gonna
have a really sophisticated pretext
right it's gonna have all these bells
and whistles and no get rid of those
right just super simple as simple as
possible I started talking to
receptionists receptionist's are golden
for this right because they probably
have kids so they're used to you know
that sort of stuff they used to say no
very politely they're usually super
professional because they deal with cold
calls all day long right and so they
were fantastic I spent hours talking to
receptionist's you know at the end I was
so happy I was buying them chocolate
just for all their help and really your
receptionist's are are kind of your
firewall to your organization right as
far as se attacks so I was really happy
to develop those relationships even more
but a lot of my pretexts were vetted
through them and when i went to vegas
they you know the they really helped me
to make sure that I had ones that worked
so so then you're going to Vegas and if
you haven't been DEFCON before some some
ideas you might want to think about I
choose not to stay in the hotel that's
hosting Def Con this year it was Caesars
they just changed I can't imagine you
know people that are showing up to Vegas
you know that the sweet couple you know
the in their 60s they come in and they
don't know that there's three security
conventions going on at that time and
they've got their laptop with them you
know I just feel so bad I actually
talked to one couple I said hey by the
way you may will not want to get on the
Wi-Fi why and then I started to tell
them and they just kind of slowly moved
away from me so you know I tried right
so you know just you may want to figure
out where you're gonna stay there's the
three conferences right besides the
black hat and DEF CON and you might want
to go to all three or one and but you
got to figure out where you're gonna
stay so that's always a challenge
comfortable shoes so Vegas is brutal
that way right I was doing 10,000 at
least sometimes towards 20,000 steps per
day
everything is through the casino right
so bathroom food whatever you want to do
is through the casino so you're doing a
lot a lot of walking famous Def Con real
rights so three hours of sleep two meals
a day and one shower you know it's a
room like this but even more packed
sometimes so there's a level of
stinkiness involved sometimes so they
ask you to do the hygiene part of it
so how did I prioritize my marks right
then this is an important part right
you're gonna have a lot of people to
choose from when you're there I only had
20 minutes and real attackers are gonna
think pretty similar to this right they
have a their they have a business that
they're running so they don't a waste
time right there they have a lot of
things to do they want to get points
that you want to score right so same
with me so I took a look and I developed
kind of an algorithm for my marks I
wanted like low connection scores on
LinkedIn because that was gonna tell me
that this person's not really
well-connected
they probably don't know a lot of people
in the organization and they probably
don't know the industry that well either
so they're not going to be able to go
tell somebody hey this weird guy's
calling me um very easily right so
that's what I'm looking for they're not
gonna know what normal looks like
probably rights so this seems kind of
weird they may not detect that then the
next thing is I'm looking for people
that will actually talk to me because
it's no good if I phone you and you're
not gonna tell anybody but you're also
not gonna talk to me so I need somebody
who is expressive so those if you're
taking a lot of selfies and stuff like
that you know I'm going after you and in
your ability to share so if you posted
the VPN configuration on your Facebook
then yeah I'm putting your name down on
my list right so basically high charisma
low wisdom scores which actually quite
often translates into interns and
contractors and you know I think that
it's part of the transient transient
nature of their business but but that's
pretty much who I was targeting that's
what the room looks like and I just
thought I'd show you this in case you're
planning to do this it's really exciting
being in the booth and when you're in
there like any high-pressure situation
you realize that sophistication and
complexity is your enemy
and it you just kind of domed out things
down it's like okay this this is simple
and it's gonna work and I highly
recommend that sort of strategy and
you'll see attackers do that too right
there their attacks are pretty pretty
straightforward and pretty simple in the
booth the clocks the enemy right so as
you're dialing that takes time voicemail
takes time no answers take time so that
killed 10 minutes of my time right off
the bat and so I fell down to my sure
bets which was reception so I there was
a couple different offices reception at
both of them so I spent my time talking
to them some other people had more
sophisticated pretexts where they would
talk for a couple minutes to introduce
themselves and to talk about why they
needed your information and those were
doomed to failure because it gives the
the mark more time to think about it
right does this is a sounding normal is
this weird
should I ask questions right so I find
good attacks are quick and concise and
direct unbelievable right so you want to
have something that that sounds legit
but don't waste any time on any fluff
right you want to really boil it down
some some of the general rules right so
pictures were okay but no video because
they were worried about the audio you in
the state of Nevada you have to actually
tell the person on the other side of the
phone that you're recording and that
really would have kind of given it all
away and even though the booth is
soundproof you know you can actually
hear the audience so they try to make
you stay quiet until it's over and then
if you do really well everybody jumps up
in screams and yells and shouts which is
pretty cool so now we're gonna get into
some of the more interesting stuff some
of the tricks that I used and some of
the tricks you'll see attackers use the
spirit of the SCC TF is really to not
victimize the person so a lot of my
tricks were really focused on the good
side right the you know making people
feel good as I'm tricking them as
opposed to the more aggressive
intimidation approaches that you'll see
real attackers using I think they could
do better if they use some of the softer
approaches actually but they I think for
them it's more of a time thing so the
first one is the confirmation if I know
you're using Dell laptops based on my
own scent I'm not going to ask you if
you're using them I want to build that
we
poor by saying well how do you like them
right and then in your mind you're
saying well okay he knows I have them so
that kind of legitimizes our
conversation so that'll help that whole
conversation wheels start turning if I
don't know and I use this technique and
it worked it could go wrong so you have
to be a bit careful but you could do the
the reverse conformation so I say oh so
you're using Dells are you but you're
using lenovo's so some people will take
great pride in correcting you right
which is great no no no no we're using
lenovo's right okay good thank you
Chuck you know name-dropping I've used
this and this worked and real attackers
don't really use this one too much yet
for fish and fishing but I think they
will so oh mr. or mrs. Smith your VP of
HR or recommended I talk to you if I
know who that person is I know their
title it sounds legitimate if the rest
of my story sounds good you're probably
gonna go for it blowing smoke this one
as well works great I use that as well
you know you were recommended to us
right and you know you feel special as
soon as someone says those words right
up me yeah thanks yeah I do have some
good information for you so you know and
that they're you're making the person
feel good some more tricks impending
doom and so this sounds negative I use
this trick it worked and it's really I
used this HVAC example where I said you
know we've won the RFP Larry's going to
come on-site tomorrow to do an
inspection of your HVAC hey I just want
to call and see if there's anything we
need to do to get him set up to do that
what what are you talking about yeah
don't you know like we were working with
the property management company he's
gonna be there tomorrow and can you use
your cafeteria how about your washroom
does he need to get it use a card to get
in hey can you use your Wi-Fi to upgrade
the firmware as well right so you can
start going in those directions and for
things like physical pen testing this
might be good intro aloud to vent
everybody likes to vent right and so
this can work pretty well you know my
boss is yelling at me he wants me to get
this done you know can you help me out
and sometimes if you can get them to
vent a little bit you can start to build
to develop that relationship smarty
pants you know how did you ever figure
oh thanks so much this works great too I
try to work this in to every pretext
right to really thank them to be very
courteous people tend to respect that a
lot I find zero-sum okay agreed this is
used by the bad guys quite a bit right
you've probably seen this quite a bit
very usually it's that time sensitive
thing so somebody's gonna get this thing
of value it might as well be you so you
know quick click the link right giving
you that pressure we did a phishing
program and we found the time sensitive
ones worked actually quite well it
triggers people to take action so
whatever you can do to get them to stop
thinking about it right just do it you
know sympathy this works great as well
real attackers don't use this very much
but I think they should you know I'm new
at this you know can you help me out you
know I've been trying to do this it's my
first day on the job my boss is gonna be
so mad if I screw this up
right who's not going to help that
person right and I find so that worked
quite well as well so now we'll get into
my pretext and so these pretext use a
lot of those tricks um and because a lot
of times you'll get stuck at reception
if you don't have the people's dids
direct inward dial and so I anticipated
getting caught up in reception and I did
not because I didn't have their D IDs I
did I took all of that other PBX but but
it was good you're gonna you're probably
going to hit reception and and and there
are masters at detecting BS right so I
want to really make sure I was ready for
them so these were designed to kind of
get through that front door you know so
spoofing the university or college that
some of their employees go to their
interns specifically I'm calling in a
reception saying hey can I talk to
so-and-so he's your intern I'm calling
from the U of whatever and you know we
really want to talk to that person to
help develop our intern program sounds
legit right so then once you're in the
receptionist has probably said oh it's
you of whatever they'd like to talk to
you that builds some legitimacy right
and then I introduce myself as that and
then I go through my questions boom boom
boom boom and then at the end I ask them
hey can you transfer me to so-and-so
because they're also a former student or
an intern as well
so now I'm inside and now I'm getting
routed through without having to go back
out and come back in the blue-collar
disco so I really like this if you have
any knowledge of areas kind of outside
of yours
for me I work with data centers quite a
bit historically so I know a little bit
about HVAC so it'll be able to talk that
language and say you know this is where
Larry's going to come in and do the
servicing I can talk about HVAC s'right
and and the person on the other end you
know it sounds legitimate to them right
so if you can throw out those industry
words that really helps as well I did
this one in Vegas and it worked pretty
well some targeted methods right so
these are the pretext where you're going
after a very important piece of
information which is probably going to
set off some red flags if you're not
extremely careful Mitnick does this
really well you know if you read some of
his books he talks about how he layers
right he goes after the first one and
it's relatively easy it's relatively
benign it's something that you would
look and go why would he need that
information but then you use that for
the next call and then you use the
content you got from that call for the
next call and you're just building this
snowball of knowledge right and then
when you get to the you know let's say
the fifth or a sixth college you've got
tons of information to make you sound
like an authority or an internal person
so that's what this is all about so the
first one was the enemy of my enemy you
know so I'm calling as a potential
tenant and I'm asking you hey how is it
working in your building what's the
property management like and they're
gonna start to tell you about the
different things within their building
and there's a ton of information out
there if you want to learn about a
property to take that approach it's
surprising how much is available special
delivery
I use this one it worked pretty well the
script for safe FedEx or any of the
couriers is pretty well known and so you
can get the receptionist to talk to you
a little bit with that sort of call yeah
can I tell you a secret
everybody likes secrets right I've never
ran into anybody who said no to this
question so I'm calling as a recruiter
my company's gonna lay off some people
and I'm trying to find a new home for
them and you don't
to help them out and so I'm calling
companies like yours because they'd like
to you know work at a company like yours
and I just need to answer you'd answer a
couple questions they have like you know
how's your cafeteria you know stuff like
that and they usually get a bonus for
recruiting and so they're probably
thinking about that so this question is
usually pretty exciting for them because
you're gonna give them qualified
candidates um so this is another good
one right it's that that greed emotion
greed factor the full dumps these are
great if you can get somebody lined up
to do this right you're gonna go in the
radio station contest I mean any sort of
contests it's so overused now real
attackers gravitate towards this you
know how many times you get the call on
your cell phone congratulations you've
won a cruise right it's so I didn't use
that one it was on my list but you know
it's just so overused the upgrade
opportunity so many of you probably work
with vendors right when you have a new
account rep how does that work right
somebody just calls you out of the blue
and says hey I'm your new account rep
how you doing right there's no real
formal approach to that quite often so
if I phone in and then I say hey I'm
your dell account rep I know you have
Dells I know what models you have right
I can call in and sound pretty pretty
legit go through hey I want to send you
some free demos how's that sound it
sounds pretty good right I just need to
know how is it how's it working out with
your VPN client right so I can start
digging get a little bit of content that
way you're so special the engagement
survey I use this one this one worked
really well and it's really fast too
once I get the person you know I do some
name-dropping I do that trick hey I'm
working with the VP of HR they gave me
your name right and they said you could
help me develop this engagement survey
and as soon as you get them to say yes
and I don't even the person said yes and
then I moved into the questions so
quickly I barely heard it just so you
just get that little bit of commitment
and just start rolling right boom boom
boom boom and they're answering
questions as quickly as they can and so
that's that's a really good one for a
lot of content the final one there okay
you caught me a lot of people say well
if you get questioned you should never
drop your pretext the joke is even when
you're going into the police car with
the handcuffs on you should always stay
in pretext
and I kind of didn't want to do that I
wanted to put a twist on that a little
bit so it never happened I was really
wishing it would happen hopefully in the
future it will or they say hey you know
what like Rob I'm not really buying this
I don't think you're my dell account rep
this actually happened in Vegas to
somebody else and it was hilarious
because they knew the person they were
impersonating it's like I don't think
that's you and they were arguing for
about five minutes no it's me it's me
it's like okay where do you live and it
just went downhill but it was it was
hilarious so so my pretext was okay you
know what congratulations you caught me
you're the only one in this whole
company that caught me right I'm gonna
give your name to the executive and
because you're an example of the type of
employee that they need to have so you
know I'm making a note of that and hey
if you've got a minute can I just roll
through the rest of these questions just
to develop a baseline so so you know
I've made them feel good right nobody's
victimized he well they kind of are but
they feel good about it right so I'm
just kind of like flipping it over and
keep on rolling so I thought that might
be more effective so I was I really want
to try that in the future now this is
the reflective moment that I promised
you okay some questions to ask yourself
you don't have to say this out loud
because some of these might be
uncomfortable you know what you know
when your staff especially your exec
have been socially engineered right you
know if some executives will come to you
and say hey yeah I've been emailing this
bad guy back and forth and you know they
think that's funny
other executives may not say anything
because of embarrassment or something
like that so do you have a mechanism to
trigger that feedback to you right
because you probably want to know sooner
than later
how bad would it be if your CFO
transferred you know millions of dollars
there's companies out there that have
wire transferred 50 million dollars
right or more I remember the one 50
million which is seems like a lot of
money right I would be in a lot of
trouble if I transferred 50 million
dollars from my bank account if there
was that much in there so you know so
that's that could be embarrassing does
your insurance cover that
right that would be interesting to take
a look at if you give away your money
are you insured right do you have the
internal resources to manage that risk
right so if that was to happen what
would you do would you start doing some
sort of forensics on that to figure out
what exactly happened would you have
visibility would your InfoSec staff have
the skills to do that and then finally
you know can you navigate through
Equifax paradox what I mean by that is
who's getting fired right so and if you
don't know the answer to that question
it's probably you so it's good to know
that all right so some recommendations
understand your exposure first of all
right so always sent yourself that's
always fun
oh isn't your company find those social
butterflies so who are who are the
people that are publishing your VPN
information out there now that's
probably a good thing to take a look at
what's at risk
right is it proprietary information is
it source code is it big buckets of
money right so what are you protecting
these attacks are monetized so the end
of the day they want to make money so
build up some defenses against phishing
some things you can do you can do a
phishing program everybody's doing this
these days you want to measure the
clicks but I would also say you probably
want to take a look at how people are
reporting it as well
I did a phishing program it was a lot of
fun it looked really cool and I was a
novice and I released all the emails at
the same time so everybody got at the
same time don't do that because people
got it and they're like oh cool what's
this right and they're clicking on it
which they're not supposed to do just to
see the splash screen then they're
telling their friend to click on it
right so just don't do that and I didn't
measure reporting which would be a good
metric to have right how many people are
actually telling you they got this this
weird email you can create an ext tag on
your incoming mail that's coming in from
the outside so when the president gets
the one of actually the CFO gets the
email from the president that says hey
can you wire transfer 50 million to that
other company over there it's an
emergency if they see the ext and they
realize that oh maybe it's not the
president right because that's coming
from the outside in you won't do this
but you know you could stop allowing
active links in the email so they
actually have to copy and paste and they
would actually see that okay it's it's
not going to amazon.com and then provide
some other channels other than email
right and we're starting to do this
quite a bit we're realizing that we're
overloaded with emails right and the
amount of time you can spend reading any
particular email is probably seconds
right so some other channels there's and
there's so many of them defense against
phishing right so your executives are
the the highest target the the big value
target right so if you could vish them
ask their permission first be very
sensitive use that as a learning
opportunity but tread lightly right they
may not find this as entertaining as you
create choke points so I talked about
the receptionist's a little bit and
really they do such a wonderful job of
protecting our business and do they ever
get any info SEC training or awareness
training other than they say the the
annual click-through stuff right so that
might be an opportunity on your PBX you
probably have dial by name do you still
need it I love that feature because I
can go in there at night and I can get
everybody's number I can get everybody's
title and then I go through their
voicemail and listen to their voicemail
I get so much information do you need it
probably not maybe your sales department
needs it maybe your marketing needs it
but your IT department other people that
probably not right I don't want it dids
you've directed or dials most of your
staff does not need di DS
give them extensions have it routed
through reception they're probably
calling out a lot or some but they're
not getting a lot of inward calls right
so why have that and don't match your D
IDs with your extensions either oh
that's that's not very good stop
answering the phone I got in trouble for
AB for putting this bullet point on
there right so take that with a grain of
salt that's one of my opinions you know
if you recognize the name and it's your
boss you probably wanted to pick up the
phone I did this this talk internally
and a lot of managers looked really
badly at me so I had to put that in
brackets they're always answer if it's
your boss
get on the offensive right so I write a
lot of policies that nobody reads and we
do the annual training as well the
awareness training and the joke is how
fast can you get that done right
nobody's reading policy in it you know
what you have to have it so I'm not
saying don't have it but a majority
people are not reading them right when
you fire somebody you point to it right
but instead I'm saying we need to create
a culture change right of continual
challenges so take those people that are
doing the right thing and make them into
heroes communicate okay we're doing this
this goal so InfoSec is doing this
advertise that right we don't have to be
the bad guys we can say hey we're doing
this this is exciting you can be part of
this give stuff away give out Starbucks
cards right be the good guy yeah right
you'll get so much popularity just by
giving out Starbucks cards put people's
picture on on your sharepoint or your
confluence site and say hey this person
did this it was fantastic that's really
what we should be doing and then
ultimately we want to get to culture
change right so one of the problems we
often complain about is oh the bad guys
only have to get lucky once or you know
I don't have budget to really and make a
difference and to protect all the things
I need to protect yeah that's that's
that may be true right but and we can't
scale if we don't scale we can't we
can't really win that that war right so
if all our employees care about security
and we always say they should but they
don't right they're not rewarded on that
so they won't right we have to reward
them and we're not at this point putting
that on their yearly review right that's
not one of their goals necessarily
hopefully one day it will be but we can
do other things right we can make them
into heroes and and then you can based
on that you can scale you can make them
into mentors right so then they're
teaching on your behalf
alright some of the tools that I looked
at and you look at this is like well Rob
I use those tools every day yeah it's
really how you use them and then what
your target is using right so you kind
of roll down this list LinkedIn if it's
a corporate target that's where I would
start use x-ray it'll help you out a lot
to bypass the page service twitter is
great for images very fast you can do
that you can do tools like all my all my
tweets to get everything all at once
Instagram if you want to do geolocation
it's not bad there's better tools out
there where you can fence off an area
set a time and then get multiple
multiple channels of of that so there's
what's one there's another tool out
there for emergency management I can't
think of it right now but if you're
curious just let me know I send it to
you Facebook's not bad SlideShare
surprisingly good right I don't know why
but people put their reference letters
on SlideShare and that gives you tons of
information personal websites are gold
and job postings I can learn all about
you know your Cisco firewall that you
have and you know what you're hiring
people to look after right just go
through that Google Maps you can get
your picture of the building entry
points stuff like that
signage sometimes you can read that
which is very nice if you're gonna do
physical pen testing that's a good
starting point and then once you're
through that move into more specialized
right so you know your wearable Strava
is great I can see where you ran showed
an IOT right pastebin I can set up an
alert on your company Spokeo at an
individual level I'm gonna get a ton
information from that and then more
specialized which is even more fun right
so I can look up people's you know
criminal record or their taxes property
management is a really nice area that
I'm focusing on a lot lately there's a
ton of information out there for that
some resources so one of the best
resources is Michael bezels in Intel
techniques you can go there there's a
ton of tools there it's like this big
menu system of tools so if you want to
do some OSINT on somebody or a company
just go there and it's kind of
simplifies everything for you
he's got training he's got a podcast
tons of information if you live up my
way tottington does something similar he
trains most of the government agencies
he's a great resource as well again
online training articles and stuff like
that and then of course the social
engineer right he really is the one that
organizes this sec TF both at Def Con
and Derby now so he's got tons of
information great podcasts as well if
you've got some money you can buy plural
site if with your company cyber e is a
free resource online as well and they've
got lots of great tools I'm a big fan of
them alright so I rock through that
pretty quickly if you've got questions
we can do that now I just want to tell
you this is my latest project here my
it's kind of an OSINT project so if you
have if you have any interest in ocean
you can take a look at that let me know
what you think always looking for
feedback on that if you want to reach me
those are the ways you can do so now
twitter is your best bet so we've got a
few minutes
questions yeah the very back
yeah so I didn't cover that but that's
one of the places where I started you
know just doing a who is there's a lot
of good tools out there that provide
information on that I like to look at
who registered the domain and then I
look at the IPS go on to error and look
at who owns those IPS that's great as
well that'll tell you a lot of good
information I got emails I got phone
numbers and the phone numbers nice
because even if you get the pretext that
helps you with the bank of numbers
because then you know at least I've got
that far right and then it's narrowing
down the suffix of those phone numbers
so definitely want to look at that
yes sir yeah it's yeah yeah yeah yeah I
don't really need that right like if you
gave me someone's name or a company's
name all you need then is time there's
so much out there right it's it's you
know it's it's amazing how much is out
there so just need time and you can
start gathering everything
yeah so I'm sure there's a lot of good
tools out there unfortunately I'm not
using any of them if somebody has
recommendations on that I'd love to hear
that because that burned a lot of my
time and I'm still struggling with that
so right now I use Excel right people
use Excel for everything they probably
shouldn't including myself so I would
have links within Excel to the to these
different channels and then I could sort
and stuff like that in Excel so that's
why I use that and I knew how to use it
so but I wouldn't recommend it
yes sir
yeah
yeah yeah I saw people use that and I
think that's very effective you know the
joke is you know people put their there
they're going on holiday on Facebook and
then their house gets robbed right same
idea
my out of office I'm very careful with
that I simply say that I'm not available
that could mean anything but as an
attack or the minute you see that you
could then you know you could leverage
that for sure
so the I don't like to put a lot of
detail in that if I say I'm in Hawaii
then they'll use that right oh hey yeah
I'm calling cuz Rob's in Hawaii I said
yeah he said I should give you a call to
get this so for sure that's a good
technique yes
so it wasn't on Facebook it was on
Twitter and yeah yeah there was there
was myself and there was another person
who talked about that where they found
it on Twitter and I don't know what
people are thinking I think that that's
you know as we do our self-promotion
with these social media channels and we
build a brand as a night as an
individual we have to be a bit careful
about what we're putting out there right
so we're proud of the companies we work
for and we want to talk about the
companies we work for but I don't think
it's appropriate to - it's post or VPN
configuration so yeah it's that's a
really interesting area right is where
do you draw the line with the
self-promotion and branding right so
it's VPN was definitely across the line
so yeah I recommend go out and take a
look at that right see if any of your
employees have done that that's one
example of things they probably don't
want to do and then you can build
awareness around that yes sir
yeah so all of the information is
open-source and so you put references to
all the information that you collected
so you have links to it so one of the
bits of one of the bits of evidence that
I found was a YouTube video a tour of
their office which was incredibly useful
yeah so I did that frame by frame and
you could see the in the mirror there
was a reflection of somebody bringing up
their badge like that and so I
screenshot of that I had the second in
the video and sent the link in for that
so yeah there's yeah that's how you do
that yes sir yeah I think it was about
50 pages and yeah you know you could
have gone more and more and more and
it's funny because you start going down
that rabbit hole and it's so fun right
like oh yeah I got this one right and
yeah it's just you feel like a private
investigator or something right so it's
a real rush so almost I was so
frustrated because I there was one or
two that I didn't get and it was who
does their garbage and who does their
bug extermination and I was trying I was
working so hard at that and you know
trying to get different camera angles of
their office and I could see there was a
truck in their parking lot oh maybe
that's it but I couldn't get it quite
right using all sorts of different
satellite imagery and yeah that was fun
but missed those two
you