[Music]
CAIR percent speakers with all season
ones they kind of work together to help
the new speaker because at their first
talk so community involvement really
important to me I also do work with Def
Con in their workshops group and I'm
excited that because I hate free time
and money in industrial and
organizational psychology so what I do
is instead of focusing on social
engineering and stuff like that I try to
think of ways to help other users be
more secure using so this talk just you
know is more of a high-level strategic
talk than a low-level technical talk so
that's nice
title well what does that mean in my
group as we work for fragment 7 a group
of us called the strategic advisory
services we have and what we do is we go
out to a different customer each week or
so and try to get an idea of what their
overall security maturity looks like we
look at things like penetration testing
is it a response application security
asset and software management all that
kind of good stuff and what we see time
and time again is that there's a
disparate focus on priorities a lot of
times executives directors of security
things like that focus on compliance and
wanting to be compliant instead of
security a matter of fact I would say
easily 9 times out of 10 what gets us in
the door in the first place is a
compliance need this could be HIPAA PCI
Newark sip what have you and it's kind
of an uphill battle that we need to talk
about you know why they need to be more
secure instead of just being compliant
just so I get an idea of who's in the
room how many of you all are in a
manager or higher Kappa work capacity
all right cool
how many of you work in compliance all
right more technical or all right cool I
know there's several of you who are like
raising your hands for everything and
that's kind of how our field works right
we have to wear many hats and another
question I have is what is the most
significant driver behind your security
program and you're spending raise your
hand if it's protection of sensitive
data all right regulatory compliance
reducing incidents and breaches of fewer
hands okay and protection of
intellectual property ish yeah so this
doesn't really surprise me it's pretty
in line with what the sands spending
survey in 2016 found about 65 percent or
so respondents said the protection of
sensitive data was their biggest concern
and biggest driver for security spending
quickly followed up by compliance and
then after compliance there's about a 20
percent gap between that and everything
else and I would say this is really
typical for what I see when I go out to
a client most of them in the boardroom
are going to say yeah you know you say
that I need to get rid of administrative
credentials but that sounds like a pain
and I don't want to do it they don't
understand why it's important or they
push back and they say well I never
heard of any of my peers and other
companies get breached by that and on
the other hand when I tell them oh hey
you know PCI says you need to get rid of
administrative privileges they're like
okay let's do it but PCI says we have to
do it and it makes them it made me stop
and think when I started writing this
talk or thinking about doing this talk
why
why do they do this and I'll get more
into it later but it's mostly because
compliance is our path of least
resistance right it's the easiest way to
get things done and best of all they get
a little piece of paper that they can
take to their customers and say we're
secure we're protecting your data we're
doing a good job
the auditor came told us we're doing
really well oh crap
29% of survey respondents from that
survey spending said that they were
still compliant or they were not yeah
29% were still compliant after they
received their attestation so what that
means is about 71% of those folks who
are taking the survey they got their
paper and then maybe they forgot to scan
for a couple of extra months or maybe
their developers have access pull access
to production dev and test and that
brings us back to that path of least
resistance thing it's nice and we see it
as a necessary evil but we need to
change the way that we do things
specifically how we report metrics to
the folks in charge a lot of times and
you know I work for rapid7 so I'm gonna
get some like laughs and jabs over this
one a lot of times salespeople when they
talk to see so CEOs or people who have
purchasing power is they rely on FUD
fear uncertainty and death in order to
make that sale they're like oh if you
don't buy our product a hacker will get
in and hell will break loose it'll be
awful right and that works for a little
bit but then people look at numb to that
they don't respond to it after a while
so what we need to do instead is come up
with meaningful metrics that we can take
to those c-level folks to our directors
in order to justify our security
Oh Graham and the spending that we're
making and we need to do so regularly
and going back to that sans annual
spending survey they asked them what
metrics do you use to evaluate the
effectiveness of your security spending
and number one is compliance they're
like oh well you know we spent this much
money on security but we're PCI
compliant
we're HIPAA compliant Ian KPMG isn't
gonna come knocking on our doors fewer
look at things like reduce breaches or
Incident Response a lot of them are a
lot of folks who are compliant with a
lot of these frameworks they don't know
first of all if they've been breached or
how to react when they've been breached
and that's a huge problem that we have
in our industry so we need to find a way
to explain why we need security spending
how we can track it without relying on
fear uncertainty and death and one way
to do that is using something like a
security maturity model so this is a
sample of one that we use it's loosely
based on the Carnegie Mellon maturity
model I'm sure some of you guys are
familiar with that it goes from
preliminary all the way up to innovating
and honestly I have never had a customer
in the three years I've been with this
company that I've reached predictable or
innovating I would also not expect any
of my customers to reach that level
unless they were defense contractors a
lot of times it's not necessary what I
want them to be at or where I want them
to be at is that a managed or
standardized level I want them to have
skills and training maybe some tools in
place that they know how to use
effectively maybe a third party that
they're leveraging to supplement what
they lack good processes and policies
that they're actually following I've
seen some really good documentation that
sits on a SharePoint somewhere and then
they're never looked at or seen again
even by them
Bocek folks and standardization
centralization everybody needs to be
able to do the same thing the same way
every time in order to help reduce risk
where compliance stops is about the
initial level so I get a lot of
surprised looks when I go out to
customers and I tell them you're about
at a preliminary or initial level and
they fight me tooth and nail how can
this be
we are HIPAA compliant we've been HIPAA
compliant for years we meet all of the
requirements the auditors tell us we're
doing well how can this be
well you don't send your developers to
training right you fight them for PTO to
go to things like OPSEC or their local
OWASA meetings you buy all of these
shiny new tools but nobody knows how to
use it or they're poorly implemented and
they don't know how to effectively
respond to an incident so an example
that I like to talk about when I do a
discussion like this is I had a customer
one of my first customers when I was in
this when I got into this group that I
could named all in the family so we used
code names in our group because it's
easier to talk with each other about
customers without seeing the actual
customers name so all in the family was
a really tight-knit family run and
operated or owned and operated business
and what they did was they handled sales
calls for other larger companies and one
of their larger customers said that they
had to be sock to compliant and PCI
compliant and they're like oh well we're
PCI compliant we've filled out this
questionnaire thing for years we're
doing great
we just need rapid7 and to help us with
sock because we don't understand it so
about three of us went in started
talking with their people read over
their documentation or lack thereof we
asked them for a data flow diagram
kind of looked at us like what you're
talking about what's that so we had to
do a whiteboard exercise and we found
out no you're not PCI compliant in the
slightest you're nowhere near being
socked to compliant and you're basing or
you're missing some of the most basic
security controls that we would expect
you to have with an organization your
size so we got together and sat and
talked and try to find a metaphor that
would work for them because essentially
what we were finding was they can't see
the forest through the trees
they're so hyper focused on compliance
that they're missing some of the more
basic things like knowing what assets
you have and where they're located
what kind of sensitive data do you have
what date is important to your
organization how does that flow through
your network what kind of basic
permissions do your applications have
that sort of thing and they just weren't
in a place where they could start
creating a comprehensive security
program so we needed to kind of start at
square one for them even though they
were they've been around for twenty
thirty years and what we did was we
talked to them and we were like okay you
need to focus on security and by
focusing on security you will also
become compliant with these things it'll
just kind of naturally fall into place
because what a lot of folks don't grasp
is that compliance tells you you have to
build a gate and this gate has to be
made out of this sort of material a
certain type of material it has to be a
certain height and width and it has to
have a lock on it but what security
tells you is you have to have a fence
attached to the gate and that fence has
to wrap around the entire perimeter of
your organization so what does that an
attached gate look like for most of us
who are trying to attain PCI compliance
well in the latest version of PCI it
says any administrative non non console
access
as well as any remote access into
cardholder data has to have multi-factor
authentication and it seems pretty
straightforward right if you have Suzy Q
and HR or whatever needing to remote in
and access the cardholder data
she needs to authenticate twice you know
but a lot of people don't really
understand what multi-factor
authentication is and they think well if
she has to log in twice with her
username and password that's good enough
that's that's two factors no that's one
factor twice right so you have to
explain to them multi-factor is like
something you know and something you
have and that's why or something you do
yeah so that's why 39% of compromised
companies will breach through unsecure
remote access they might have
multi-factor in place they might have
they might have bought tokens for
everybody to use or say hey you have to
use the Google 2fa app but it might not
be properly implemented or they might do
the to password thing and they use the
same password for both accounts and
that's how they get breached and this is
why things like Target happen why
somebody can be compliant at one point
in time and check the box and then later
on be at the center of a major breach
because what a lot of people don't
realize is that there's no easy button
in security there's no quick fix that we
can implement that will protect all of
our data with one fell swoop and it'll
be cheap and easy to implement and
nobody will need to fix it or update it
or yell at the vendor or anything like
that so we buy these tools we make these
investments but we do so poorly and our
easy button becomes a self-destruct
button
so we talked about and I'm talking
really really fast so if you guys have
questions in the middle yeah absolutely
and I couldn't agree more it's kind of a
culture shift right it's kind of like
when you go from saying oh we can have
six character passwords and you can
reuse it for after two or three times
versus you know strong secure passwords
you have to explain why why is security
more important than compliance
how can a lead to be and it really
depends on the person that you're
talking to I find that I have more luck
with the CIS oh when I talked to them
about compliance versus security the CFO
and the CEO oh and actually a lot of
times the CEO will fight me because they
will be like oh well no because if I'm
not PCI compliant and we get breached
it's my name in the paper what they
don't realize is well even if your PCI
compliant and you get breached your
names still going in the paper so if you
spend the time effort and money on
security first the likelihood of you
having to go through that and it's a
response scenario of you talking to the
papers is greatly reduced and
also a lot of them don't see how
security helps the business a lot of
folks view us as a cost center and leave
it at that what they need to realize is
we're kind of like in an insurance
policy we're here to help them make sure
that they don't get reached chances are
you know based on everything that comes
out they are gonna get breached so we
also have to let them know well yeah we
might get breached but we also have
processes people and tools in place to
quickly address that yeah so that's
another problem we have in security we
kind of have a people problem we're kind
of like the guy in office space where
we're like we're a people person damn it
but we're not weak we've it's hard to
find a way to express our jobs to a
person who doesn't get it so I think
that's something that we as a community
really need to work on an address is how
to more effectively communicate with the
business even though it's hard and it
can sometimes suck a lot of times sucks
any other questions no okay but yeah
just a reminder again I talk really fast
so if you do have a question want me to
go back just let me know it's fine I
won't be offended but yeah a lot of
folks focus on the compliance tree
completely ignore the rest of the forest
end up to the path of destruction that's
why you know the gingerbread house
Hansel and Gretel kind of cutesy little
dramatic but I think it's a really good
metaphor for what I see a lot of times I
had another customer who I code named
Red Rover and what they do is they house
data for a large number of companies and
they also provide a reward provide
security services for a lot of
organizations things like log management
in Agra
an incident response to a very high
degree things like that but they were
also too busy looking at compliance and
they had a network diagram that looked
very similar to this
it's scrubbed and also a little bit
higher level than what they had yeah
very flat network but the cardholder
data environment separate but the
problem was let's say they have
customers in Louisiana Missouri Arkansas
South Carolina Florida and Colorado well
they all VPN in and since their network
was pretty flat any customer could
theoretically access the file and print
servers for any other customer but since
their CDE was separate they were
compliant so that's great we got our
paper customer feels great because we
have the paper papers awesome people
protect us but were they secure if we
look at it from a different way let's
say they housed voter data okay they
didn't but let's just say they did we
have a bad actor in Louisiana who wants
to get motor data for Florida they know
Florida kind of sucks at computer vote
voting stuff and they want to do some
damage so what they do is they VPN in
through their state are able to get in
to the file print server for Louisiana
but since they don't have good
permissions in place and everything's
pretty flat they're able to traverse the
network and pivot and get into Florida's
data and chances are the customer isn't
able to detect this let alone respond to
it another way to go about would be to
put in a VPN so they would have to
ideally have multi-factor to get in in
the first place and then all of a sudden
if they get in through the ERP of
Louisiana it's a little bit harder to
get in to
Florida file server because it's
segmented off so it's both secure and
more compliant so kind of like I've been
saying through this whole thing
security is going to trump compliance it
needs to trump compliance we need to
find a way to communicate this to our
leadership so that way they can shift
their focus from getting the checkmark
and getting the piece of paper and
instead focusing on actually protecting
your sensitive data and actually knowing
what your sensitive data is and I know
that the previous example focused on
networking but it's still pretty
applicable to things like application
security and development so another
common thing that I see is trying to
think segregation of duties that's
probably the easiest one they say oh
well this guy can't transfer this code
to this place because they have
different user IDs but what they don't
realize and they have separate no let me
back up I got too excited recently
actually I had a customer say they had
segregation of duties in place because
even though the one developer that they
had had full access in both environments
there was a firewall between prod and
dev but what they didn't know was that
they didn't have proper ACLs in place so
it was kind of pointless so what we need
to do is take an action beyond
compliance because it's important for
our security decisions to be focused on
being more secure and informed by
compliance instead of relying heavily on
compliance and saying that's the only
thing we need to focus on
so how many of you all are familiar with
this
that's pretty full dispersed okay a
couple of you for those of you who don't
know what this is this is Microsoft's
secure life lifecycle development cycle
it's pretty good right it has a lot
instead of relying on the traditional
security gates towards the end it has
security built in to several steps and
while this is a good goal to reach I'd
argue that the majority of development
shops out there will find it impossible
to do all of these things they don't
have the people the knowledge expertise
tools what-have-you
in order to do this and implement it
fully and so it's important for us to
stop and take some time to think about
okay well we can't do everything and we
shouldn't be expected to do everything
but what makes sense for our
organization what does our application
need to do what data traverses through
it and what can we effectively get away
with so first of all you should always
look at training right that's kind of
like the first step you don't know what
you don't know until you know it and
then bring in your audit folks we need
to get a little bit better as security
practitioners working with other teams a
lot of us are so used to being siloed
and being pitted against others but one
of the greatest things that I see is
when I go to a customer site and I bring
in HR and they get that moment where
they're like oh I can be helping
security and security wants me to help
them and they're not here to tell me how
to do my job but they can make my job
easier and this is how so just trying to
make things more I'm sorry make things
less adversarial and bring in other
departments there's no way that we can
do everything by ourselves nor should we
expect ourselves to
so it's really depressing and I've been
a lot of this is horrible things are
awful people won't listen to us oh god
the sky is falling so basically
everything I told you not to do to your
execs I kind of did to you so what's the
next step well what I would recommend
you do is maybe Thursday or Friday after
the conference take about five minutes
instead of refreshing your email or
Twitter what have you and look at the
Microsoft secure development lifecycle
and try to identify one or two things
that you think your organization could
realistically do or implement in one to
two years and then how you're going to
implement it or achieve that goal in
that timeframe and then once you do that
try to push it out a little bit further
okay so what do I do for the next one to
two years and so on and so forth and
then before you know it you have more
you you're better off than you were when
you first started we're so used to
fighting fires constantly and trying to
boil the ocean but what we need to do is
try to take things little by little and
try to delegate a little bit also to
other teams so try to talk to your HR
folks see how they can help your
developers a bay and his talk he made a
really great point about sorry I'm
picking on you Center right there he
made a really good point in his talk
about security reaching out to test
engineers and QA analysts and teaching
them about security so that they can run
some of the scripts that we create any
questions
all right if there's my contact
information I sometimes go on tweet
storms about psychology and security
stuff some food pictures - that's fun
and then there's my email and LinkedIn
information yes so my first point would
be like ok oh yeah that was a great
question actually do you want him to
repeat the question
ok oh you want me to repeat it ok so he
basically asked how do we respond to
developers when they tell us why would
we want to change what we're doing we've
never been breached
well my first argument would be how do
you know we've never been breached can
we prove that we've never been breached
and then also I would argue maybe it's
not about preventing a breach maybe it's
about improving an aspect of the program
by implementing some of these security
controls because a lot of and then
there's there's so much to talk about so
I'm like ah how I freeze this okay so
also we need to talk with them earlier
on in this life cycle once it hits
production it's too far it's going to be
more costly for our organisations in the
long run to secure things or patch
things once it hits production when we
could have done it in development or
even in the requirement gathering
process so if you can start talking with
them getting them training about things
like the top ten wasp top ten right and
that's usually a lot of times that's
enough for them to go oh people can do
that oh there's people who do this on a
regular basis for fun that kind of like
freaks them out a little bit and they're
like okay can you talk to me a little
bit more about this or if you can't
afford a wasp training or any
they're training a lot of organizations
especially the smaller ones that I've
worked with they have lunch and learns
where they invite a developer to sit
with them for a day when they do a
webapp test and they can say oh see this
is how I was able to login as user one
and then open up a session for user
three yeah anyone else all right cool
well thank you for your time
[Music]