[Music]
thanks to Oh Austin apps I Kali for the
invitation to speak here thank you for
your time today I hope you're all
enjoying the wonderful weather we were
blessed with I originally started
modeling this presentation with some gag
jokes about the National Lampoon's moot
movie a European vacation but then I
realized I might be dating myself and
many people wouldn't get it so I kind of
limited those I contemplated showing you
bunch of pictures of my European
vacations but I thought that might just
be rubbing things in or something at
some point so I kept them to a minimum
but not zero so two of these things are
true ones one's a blatant ripoff from
Tony Stark I'm not a lawyer so
everything I tell you here don't you
know don't don't try to defend yourself
in court with anything that I that I
tell you today and I don't want to be on
the hook for it either I'm the director
of security at tinder we're here in West
Hollywood you're all welcome to come and
hang out with us sometime we are part of
the people who run the dc-10 group that
where we're getting started getting off
the ground here in LA so you know you
can follow us on Twitter or wherever if
you want to get involved with that that
supposedly says Who am I in French I
just trust Google Translate did a good
job there so what does GDP are in
essence it's a u.s. sorry it screwed up
the first thing you privacy law that
goes into effect where they're actually
enforcing it five twenty five of this
year so if you don't know what it is and
you have anything considered like
personal information in your
environments for users you're probably
behind the eight ball in times in terms
of time it applies to any third party or
any parties who are processing data on
EU residence I'll leave it up to your
lawyers to define residence it's
actually kind of a hard thing to do
from a product standpoint to ask to
derive whether or not someone's a
resident of a certain place like you can
do you can do geoip you can do look at
their GPS coordinates or you could pop
up a box and say are you a EU resident
but most products don't want to go that
route right
the penalties for non-compliance in gdpr
are severe you could say it's roughly 4%
of your global revenue for a company and
the one thing about that it's pretty
quantifiable so unlike PCI or Sox
compliance you literally can say you
know here's our budget that you know we
can work in to say like we don't comply
this is the number that's we're going to
potentially lose right my understanding
is that Member States can also go after
you independently so it could actually
get higher than that but it's something
like 20 anyway it's roughly 4 percent so
as as stated in the regulation it's an
attempt by Europe to standardize the law
across all the EU countries and it
basically creates sort of a privacy bill
of rights for use at residence quick
overview of the rights there they're all
detailed in the in the regulation but
basically the idea is to give people
greater control over their data and how
it's used we'll get into what their data
actually means in a moment but
essentially we required as processors or
users of their data to put in blame in
terms to inform them what we're
collecting from them why we're
collecting it how we're using it who
we're sharing with who are sharing it
with if we are and for what purposes
we're required to allow them to request
that the information be corrected if
they find a some sort of error in it
that they ask they can ask us to delete
it and we have to respect that they can
opt out of certain parts of how we use
the data like I don't want to be
marketed to right the other thing that
they do I'll get into it more about the
data portability but essentially you
have to be able to provide them with all
of the data like literally give them a
file with all the data that you have on
them that has a good impact from a
privacy perspective as a consumer but
bad impact or potentially bad impact as
a creator of an application maintainer
of an application especially when uh
when you're factoring the security
implications of that
so GDP are you're all used to saying PII
right like personal identifiable
information they generally you have two
buckets of PII right you have things
that are clearly PII right I'm Anthony
trummer my social security number is X
or or whatever maybe it's an email
address whatever falls in that bucket
and then you have this other bucket of
PII which is basically things that I can
put together to figure out who you are
right if I could say like you know the
bald the six close to six foot tall guy
in this room and I can put together that
I'm probably talking about me right I
don't need to know all those other
personal details to isolate me and
online is the same kind of way right so
they have this expanded view of that
that goes beyond personal information I
into what the considered personal
information so it could be things that
aren't necessarily identifiable but
they're about you right this could be
how many times you've logged into the
app for example like who you've
connected with maybe you're a fictitious
made-up example might be like your score
in your video game right now might be
information about you there's all kinds
of things Purchase History and
application where you logged in from
over time those sorts of things might
all be personal information but not
necessarily PII so one question we had
when we were going through this is what
constitutes your data right so if I
message you right and then you message
me back is your response back to me my
data or is it your data right and if
it's your data then then then that means
that the receivers it's the receivers
data right but then that means that the
message I sent to you is not mine
anymore right which is true right which
which one I'm not I'm not saving I'm not
saying that it's true I'm saying I don't
know which is true right that's
something for your lawyers to kind of
iron out also a tender we have internal
like mechanisms of how we sort of like
lack of a better term rate people in
different ways and you might have some
proprietary algorithms that you use to
process people's data and you might feel
like you're compelled to divulge some of
that information to the public now
because it's their data right
you might arrive at a let's say a a
likeability score like you had something
like that in your application right they
may be it's a messaging app and a lot of
people like start talking to you so you
seem to be a friendly person and they
rate you very highly because you seem to
be a friendly person you might have to
divulge some of that information in this
process or at least you're gonna want to
get clarity over around whether or not
that's something you have to divulge
again I'm not a lawyer I just throw that
in there as we're done and see so while
Europe is pushing for greater privacy
controls for their residents the
internet looks like this right it's just
a mess of everybody's trying to you know
they've got the big data stuff we've got
all the analytic stuff going on half the
sites you go to anymore your Facebook
feed or something like that or just
nothing but clickbait to show you a
thousand ads and all those ads are
sucking out your user agent your IP
address your your ID fa or your Apple
equivalent yeah your ID FA or your
Android ID things like that if you're on
mobile so we're in a world where on one
hand privacy laws are getting stricter
but on the other hand like everybody's
trying to monetize all of your personal
data right so it gets annoying and it's
it's messy when you look at an example
like this where you know there's just
all these ads we've all seen sites like
this so what we're moving towards though
is something that looks like this which
is sort of in Reverse right now we're
gonna have opt-ins if you've ever
traveled to Europe we're used a European
site they all have cookie banners right
we use cookies and we're like as
technologists we say yeah of course you
use cookies how would your site maintain
state if you didn't right but they're
required to put that on there and if
they ask for your GPS location they're
there you got a message pop pop up for
that but we're gonna start to see more
and more I have to explicitly opt-in I
have to explicitly opt-in and so it's
gonna impact usability from a from a
consumer standpoint but instead of being
like annoying ads it's going to be
annoying things asking if we can show
you this ad or if we can collect this
data
about you you're also going to need to
track potentially which private which
version of your privacy policy or Terms
of Service did this person opt into over
time so if there's ever a dispute over
that you can say well you opted in you
you agree to version four and that was
covered in version four and maybe like
in version six it's not or something or
there were some modification to that so
as primarily security practitioners you
may be saying like how does how does
this fit with the security world why is
security obviously there are from
encryption standpoint there's privacy
sort of angles of we want to ensure in
security wenonah share privacy of
encrypted messages but you'll notice
that most of this overlaps with like
your GRC policies and procedures already
right it's not groundbreaking stuff in
terms of the requirements but there are
specific yet vague gdpr requirements
around security as stated it says
something to the effect of considering
the state of the art you should take
reasonable measures in relation to the
risk associated with the data that
you're trying to protect
all right that's a summarization by a
layman but it's vague and what vague
does for me is telling me a I can't go
to my engineering teams and say hey I
need you to do this absolutely because
this is a requirement I can say it feels
like it's a requirement it feels like
that's gonna meet that bar but it's also
sort of a trap right because when the
auditor comes in and says were you doing
sufficient security to to protect this
data it's it's subjective right they
could say you know I don't think you
were because I have an extra grind with
you right so that's sort of a trap for
us as security folks and lastly if if
you if your company doesn't have a
dedicated privacy team guess who the
privacy team is it's going to be you
right they're gonna your your executives
are gonna look and say security privacy
same thing right right that's probably
what they think now right I can tell you
from our from our company's perspective
I now have a lawyer on my team right
something as a security person I never
thought would happen although I was
actually quite I advocated for
previously because I'm like I don't
really know the law you know I'm and
that's not what I do right but I
actually have a privacy attorney on my
team now which is interesting along with
people who specialize in privacy so
there are specific security impacts and
that's partly what I wanted to talk to
you guys today about how this is going
to impact the the general security
practitioner and leaders and security
organizations so some of the things
we'll talk about are the the win of
gaining maintain a sort of complete and
maintained dataflow mappings so you know
where all your stuff is that and what
all the stuff you have is that that
implies proper change control because if
that ever changes you need to know that
right what happens to the vendors that
you integrate with right and what are
their requirements under gdpr right how
that affects your overall security
posture and in the sort of cloud first
world that we're in most companies how
data I'll just say it's data lifecycle
right like how are we going to manage
the data from the from the moment we get
it till the moment we get rid of it what
the impacts of GDP are are on the value
of you as a target and what happens if
you get breached right and then lastly
the download portal that I alluded to to
satisfy the portability requirements
I put yikes there because it's a scary
thing as a site operator to have this
thing that I'll get into it a little bit
later but it's sort of like a one-stop
shop for hackers right it's like if you
can break that one thing it so it's
pretty much game over so when we talk to
dataflow mappings we're not talking
about I know I don't mean to confusion
with this we're not talking about
necessarily how the data moves from
country to country although crossing
borders is definitely part of something
you need to account for under GDP are
what we're really talking about is when
you're ingesting this data I got it from
this site via that cookie it went into
this repository which is or is not
encrypted right so basically mapping
your application from input to storage
right all the way through your
architecture
did it get kicked off into some
analytics or big data pipeline somewhere
right so don't now do I have two copies
of it or do I have ten copies of it
right well it's in this database did
some other service pull it out of that
database to use it for something else
and now there's and more copies of it
right pardon me
many client-side applications will send
data directly to third-party partners
right if it's an SDK or JavaScript or
something it's just going to send it out
there into the world never even touching
your servers and you have to be mindful
of that and then we're physically or
geographically the the data is actually
being stored not only that but you may
getting back to the second-to-last point
you may actually have back in things
that share data as well right you have
partners or whatever maybe your CRM
systems or something like that are
populated by a back-end data store in
order to get any sort of as security
practitioners you know this already
right you can't do anything if there's
not proper documentation and proper
change control because it's just hurting
cats at that point right so in order for
me to maintain data flow mappings right
I need to know if you add a new piece of
JavaScript I didn't need to know if you
add a new cookie and what that's used
for I need to know if you add a new SDK
into our mobile application I need to
know if you're adding some sort of
back-end a data sharing pipeline with
another company or with the analytics
teams or whatever right the data
scientists all those things now force me
as a leader to say you have to do change
control it's no longer an optional thing
for you right I need at least these
minimum requirements for you to even do
my job if I can't do my job
company loses four percent of revenue
right it's not even a passionate
argument at that point right it's a
factual statement so knowing this and
knowing how hard this can be luckily
we're an AWS shop so some of the things
for us are easier than maybe in the
conventional infrastructure I can go
into a web console and I can say show me
all the databases that I have cool
there's all the table names right done
to a degree right but then I have to map
the input to the table name and figure
out like okay so if I get rid of this
does that mean that data is divorced
from from its input source and no longer
needing to be retained right things like
that so luckily I have a couple
hard-working people on my
who we basically got together and Johnny
and Vishal were both hanging out here
for some reason I worked with the I
worked with these two guys to to kind of
how are we gonna how are we gonna map
out all of our applications right so
it's similar to a static versus dynamic
code analysis problem where basically
you can say okay well I have the
front-end application I can run burp
suite and with Johnny's help we modified
this parameter analyzer library to
basically be able to say here are all
the quests and here are all the pieces
of data that went in that request right
so we can say every path and every
parameter now that comes out of one of
our applications right and we can store
that and he's going to be doing it
anyway right it's not even really much
more burden on him to collect it right
because he's gonna be testing out all
the new features and everything so he
runs that he creates a CSV that's
basically what you're seeing there right
of all the paths and all the parameters
secondarily I say okay well that's
similar to like doing dynamic testing
where unless you exercise all the code
pass under all the variants you're not
going to get a full picture of it right
so then you say okay well I could do
static code analysis drawing an analogy
to that which would be me going in and
reading the code parsing the code
somehow and saying let me see every
route and every get post put parameter
that that might be there right and I'm
gonna map those out right so if I put
those two together I might have a
reasonably good picture of what the
application looks like right but again
there's still possibilities like when
you parse out a code there might be a
late loading code or there might be
you're not for some reason you're not
getting everything that you need to for
some reason something's dynamically
generated and you don't see that in the
static code whatever the case may be
so you still run the possibility of
missing things to give you an idea of
what we did so we took like our
developers use something called swagger
which is basically an API testing kind
of validation thing where basically they
say if I send a request to this endpoint
I expect to get something back right and
they basically map it out say I want I
send this request I should get something
that responds that looks something like
this right so I say okay there's a third
point
that's what the developers think should
be there right so I said okay let me
take this and create a sec machine
parsable files out of all of them right
and merge them together and see when I
come up with right so I basically just
used a custom written Python script it's
not really that hard to mash CSVs or
json together or whatever right so we
came up with something this is just a
partial list and redacted right because
I don't want to map out our full API for
you guys but you can see here there's a
couple things
so I zoomed in a little bit but the gist
of it is this is API to go tinder comm
that's the thing that powers all of our
back-end right like that's where all of
our client apps call to that right so
you'll notice there are different shapes
in different colors right generally
speaking that the roundest shapes are
actually paths path elements right the
squares are actually parameters that are
passed in so I can look in here and I
can say like you know I can follow paths
from the from the API and and the thing
the colors are actually a melding of
colors so basically like yellow and blue
make green kind of thing right so I said
if it came in from the work that Johnny
and Vishal did to map out the
application it's one color if it was in
the if it was dynamic or if it was
statically found by reading the routes
files or some other way I add those two
colors together right so it's like
inherently I can look at it and say well
if it's green then that means it was
yellow or yeah if it was yellow and blue
at one point right so that that's the
only way Green would have showed up if
it's not in that file but it's another
file it emerged that color together and
it would come out with a different help
of color if it was all in all three then
I would have yet another color right so
it's sort of inherently I know how much
I can trust that that's a thorough
representation of it so another sort of
side win is I can go back to the
developers and say hey your swagger file
is out of date right I have proof that
it is because of dynamic I'm going to
test in the app it doesn't look like
that's supposed to right or vice versa
right so anyway so this is just using a
library called graph is it's pretty
common library but this goes on for my
I can't I can't even get it close to on
one screen right the the the breath of
possible routes is just is too wide so I
zoomed in here and basically kind of
give you an idea like in tinder you have
the idea of like you left swipe or
passed on somewhere you right swipe and
you like them right so in the past path
then we can drop down and you can see
like these are from obviously from code
or something because they have
placeholder values or variables there
right so they're saying it's gonna be a
user ID well there was another path that
actually showed that the user ID was a
numeric value of 24 characters or alpha
sorry a hex value of 24 characters right
v 2 would actually merge those two thing
together and say it's a user idea of
this length but right now I treat them
separately anyway so the parameter being
passed in on that path of the user ID
and then the X auth token which would be
the authentication and stuff like that
there will be a body for that and then
there's a super which is another
parameter it's nerve-racking with people
taking pictures of you you don't know
like should I stop and pose a model up
here or what
anyhow so that's how we did it right we
basically were able to merge all three
of these things together that we
basically already had with a little bit
of scripting and and now I can auditor
came in and said show me how show me
what your API looks like I just shown
that and say there you go it's done
right
and I can automate that if I want to and
say like hey well it's automatic to me
because I can say hey Johnny or Vishal
next time you guys test this application
make sure you run a parameter Eliezer to
collect all of the all of the input and
I'll just merge them back together again
with very minimal effort right so what's
not shown here and because partly
because I'm not crazy is the actual
version of this includes all the
back-end data stores right so if I have
I don't know let's say it's a your first
name right
I will actually map your first name into
each of the data stores on my back-end
everywhere first name is stored taking
that to the next level you say ok I know
that the first name isn't in all these
data stores because of this request
directly right what most likely happened
is it got came in through this request
it ended up in that data store and
something else copied it out of that
data store so I can actually map it
laterally as well right and say ok well
it wasn't directly dropped in there but
it was moved around in my environment
and I can start to actually do and end
data flow mappings right when things
change I can say well change
what does that mean can I get rid of
that piece of data now because we're not
collecting it's not being used anymore
whatever the case is right also I can
see when somebody slipped something in
there that they didn't tell us about
right it's reinforcing the change
control paradigm of having visibility
into what what your environment looks
like lemonade third party exposure
obviously don't have you over exposed
here like Bora
basically because your partners are also
almost guaranteed to need to be gdpr
compliant just by the fact that you
might be sharing data on EU residents
with them automatically draws them in
there right so you're gonna have to make
sure all your contracts have GDP our
privacy addendums included in them
saying yes we will be gdpr compliant
with your data right this means that all
of the wins that you get from GDP are as
a security leader or part of a security
team you inherit from them as well or
you place on them as well right so they
have to do the same things that you do
which include limiting data encrypting
data that sort of stuff right tracking
it so hopefully they'll watch a
presentation similar to this and they'll
they'll reduce the data they're
collecting and take care of it as a good
data stewards obviously if you find that
they are not compliant at some point
it's an automatic contract breach now
you can leverage that however you want
right but it's clearly stated as a
contract term and if they are not
compliant well you know it may is
insulate you from a liability standpoint
to some point but you might use it for
other purposes well I don't really wanna
use that vendor or something right it
also depends on how much leverage as
most of these contract things do how
much leverage you have in the in the
relationship right like if Google is not
going to care if I stop using the most
nine times out of ten right but some
small dev shop in San Francisco is
probably gonna care if they lose our
business right data cleanup so one of
the things as a as a security
practitioner I always hate would be to
lose data that I didn't need to have in
the first place to have to do a data
breach notification on data I didn't
intend to use anymore anyway an example
of that
one time I had a
as a young application security tester I
had the CTO come over to my desk and I
said hey I want to show you something
right and it was a login page for an
application and I proceeded to dump a
credit card base database via sequel
injection right there in front of them
and I said he's like what's that I'm
like that's the credit card database
because no that's the old credit card
database I said why do we have an old
credit card database oh I don't know we
just never cleaned it up no would you
want to suffer a data breach over data
you were never even using like it just
was of no use to you anymore I wouldn't
want to write the pr is still gonna be
there right the potential for legal
liabilities they're still there but you
didn't want it in the first place right
so you can enforce that again with that
sort of threat of the 4% loss of revenue
right also data retention policies right
so there are specific guidelines that
you'll have to go through with your
legal teams to figure out what the right
numbers are for you but what what do you
do how long do you retain data after the
user closes their account right in a
purist world we say the day they closed
their account it should be gone right
there are technical limitations to that
right some systems are just so big and
diverse that it might actually
physically take more than a day for all
the batch jobs to run to clean all that
stuff up right nothing happens
instantaneously so is it a day is it a
month it is a week as of the year right
there are also competing interests that
we'll talk about later which might force
you to retain data that you didn't want
to but you need to iron all those things
out and communicate them to your
developers right also makes things like
retention or reactivation tracking
difficult right if you signed up with
this email address or this phone number
and you cancel your account and you come
back six months later I can't tell that
you're a reactivation now from a
security standpoint nobody cares about
that from a business standpoint they
absolutely care about that right oh we
were able to you know get this guy to
re-subscribe by sending them an email or
whatever right well we don't have the
email anymore I can't even remark it I
may not be able to necessarily market to
my previous customers anymore right like
oh hey we understood you didn't like the
pricing we changed the pricing now here
sign up again if I can't retain the data
I can't do that sort of thing right
again we want to try to eliminate
data that we don't need minimize the
data that we keep in effectively try to
eliminate the unnecessary losses right
we also want to limit the number of
places that we store data the number of
partners that we shared data with right
to minimize our exposure because of the
requirements of sort of taking
reasonable means or you know state of
the art blah blah blah to protect user
data if you're not doing things like
deleting data that you're not supposed
to have if you're not anonymizing data
that you're storing if you're not doing
what they call sudo a pseudonym ization
which one example of would be like
hashing of something like a hashing
their phone numbers instead of keeping
the raw phone number that would be
suited minimization or something is
basically pseudonym right so something
that is representative of something else
but not a direct you know tie or
encrypting data if you're doing these
things if somebody does break in right
there's a good chance that that breaking
is going to be less impactful right if
I'm properly encrypting the data and I
can somehow protect the key used to
encrypt it then guess what it's not even
data breach under gdpr I don't have to
send out notifications if I somebody
stole a bunch of your encrypted data now
pseudonym ization is sort of like a
compromised position where you can't
quite protect it the way you want to but
you need to do something a good case for
that might be when we delve into this we
realize there are data bases that just
don't lend themselves to being encrypted
at a field level right so like if you
think about elasticsearch or a fully
indexed database right I want to search
on every field it's not theoretically
but it's practically impossible to
search on encrypted data you just can't
do it right the the efficiencies of
storing data in those databases all go
away if you start doing things like that
right and your developers will just like
I'm not doing it doesn't make any sense
right so the less data you have the less
motivation obviously there are for
people to break in right and the better
the better job you do of storing it
internally the the less that the impact
would be if they do break in
getting to this down download portal so
basically if you think about it if you
have any kind of scale at all you're
gonna need to create a portal so people
can say I want you to show me all the
data you have on me under GDP are you
have to be able to do that
right in most places are gonna want to
make it like nice and presentable but
there's a requirement energy to be our
GDP our that it's basically machine
readable right it's it's subject to
interpretation and what that means like
we initially had an HTML form and I said
well technically machine readable most
developers would say no all right if you
try to parse HTML everybody knows
there's it's a pain in the butt right
but JSON you know might be a better
option for that right and you could
actually use a you could create a pretty
JSON or a pretty HTML page based off of
the JSON blob that you're gonna give
people as well the idea is that like I
could go let's say let's say Friendster
was still a thing or MySpace was still a
thing and I said I don't want to be a
Facebook customer I'm supposed to be
able to export my data and give it to
MySpace or Friendster or some other
social network and they're supposed to
be able to ingest it and basically make
me a consumer there that's that's how
poor that's the portability aspect of it
right but anyway it's a portal that lets
me download all of the data that you
have on me so as an attacker if I can
break one thing in your in your
environment I'll take the thing that
gives me all of the data that you have
on your users right access control
problems here are just it's it's game
over right it I can sit there if I can
if I can somehow break access control at
this portal I can just get all of the
data that you have on all of the users
so again you have basically you know
more or less two choices but three
choices of how you store your data right
you can store it in plain text which is
no protection at all you can encrypt it
or pseudonym Suter than that I can't say
this word pseudonym as a pseudonym eyes
it which offers some protection right if
you if you realize that database
encryption is flawed and the fact that
generally speaking at some point you
have a server talking to a database and
at some point that process running on
that server that's walking the database
has to access the key in memory so if I
break in there and I have suitable
access to the
I can if I have RC I can probably read
that key out of memory anyway so did you
actually accomplish something maybe
maybe not right
but anonymization under GDP are true
anonymization means there's no way to
get from A to B there's there's
literally no linkage there anymore right
so you have to think about how you map
users data across different data stores
and maybe you put in sort of a as an
example like a pseudonym table where you
have the external user ID and an
internal user ID and as soon as they're
gone you delete that connection and now
I can't tell user a on the inside was
the same person as user a on the outside
right
that's up to you how you want to
approach that but those are your three
options basically as I said gdpr lends
itself to better vendors because they
have to apply these same standards to
their environments they also need to be
able to purge the data that you give
them upon your request right so I say
I'm no longer doing business with you
you must get rid of this they have to
tell you what what they're doing we your
lawyer should already cover this but if
they're sharing the data with other
third parties as well they should
equipped or anonymize the data right
obviously because that's part of their
GDP our requirements as well because
they now inherit those security even be
it that they're vague they inherit those
security acquirements you could have
forced those on them as well right and
say what are you doing to reasonably
meet this vague standard right there are
some exceptions so one example that we
ran across was Brazil so apparently
Brazil wants you to keep data for a year
after people delete it and I think this
is generally for servicing law
enforcement requests or something like
that but that's obviously in direct
conflict with GDP our that wants us to
get rid of data as soon as we no longer
have a you know legitimate business use
for it right and then subject to some
other criteria if you have a platform
where abuse between like IRL like in
real life abuse between two people might
happen and there's actually going to be
investigations and you want to be able
to help law enforcement with that you're
gonna have concerns like well can I
retain their data what if the bad guy
just deletes their account am I supposed
to get rid of it
neatly right now I can't help law
enforcement right or maybe you maybe you
don't want to help law enforcement
that's up to you right as a company how
do you ban a user if you can't retain
their data I can't say Bob Smith that
gmail.com was a bad user we got rid of
him now we want to ban him forever
how can I ban him if I can't keep his
personal information right or his IP
address right maybe he changes his email
address but now I need to know that Bob
Smith was at that IP that's most likely
Bob Smith's house that sort of thing
right luckily gdpr does have what they
consider greater good exceptions right
as a sort of a blanket statement so if
it first of all you can't be compelled
to break another law to meet gdpr
right so if it's a law in Brazil and you
can say hey I couldn't do that because
you're EU residents you know we're also
subject to Brazilian law for whatever
reason I guess I got to keep your data
I guess I can keep the data right also
things like anti-spam and abuse
retention is allowed right so that would
be for the greater good to protect the
the community as a whole right so again
not a lawyer but these are the kind of
details that you need to iron out with
your legal team or seek outside counsel
about if you don't have lawyers at your
disposal that's about it I hopefully I'm
doing alright on time this is my contact
information and as with any company
we're hiring in security so does anybody
have any questions mr. green jacket I'm
sorry I mean yeah
thank you you are referring you using
AWS and like if you take any snapshot of
your audience or stuff like that if I'm
a you like EU citizen so I can come to
you and yes are you in the EU resident
not anymore but I can maybe we don't
care about how your channel anymore so
how will you do
because basically my information are
also in those backups and it's really
hard to get rid of them that's a real
fun question yeah what do you do with
backups right that you're gonna backup
data from somebody today right and
they're gonna delete their account now
what do you do you have to mount a
backup to delete a row right there are
things like that that there are real
challenges from an engineering
standpoint like what do we do right I
think there are things that you would I
think you I'm not a lawyer I think you
would try to make the argument that that
was a necessary necessary thing and an
undue burden on your company to make me
go through there right but as an added
step I would say encrypt it tightly
protect the key and say you know we did
as much as we could we needed to retain
the data we put this special key I took
it offline or something it's it's it's
on the you know it's on the CEOs desk or
something like that right you can take
the approach like with most compliance
things of compensating controls right
what could I do to make the argument
that although I had to retain this data
at effectively in violation of this
directive or regulation I've taken
extraordinary steps to make sure that
that wasn't going to be an issue that's
that's the approach I would suggest that
most people are going to take yeah
suppose because like same thing if you
come back from a disaster recovery if
you had like such requests during just
before the disaster recovery so
basically like you lost the last two
hours you'll probably put online back
some data that you are supposed to raise
right so so if you think about it you
could if you did daily backups you could
say okay they delete it today I'm gonna
make a backup today and everybody's data
prior to today is lost right if you
weren't in today's back
but we all know how backups can work
some times that you get corrupted back
up you don't know it until you try to
load it and then you have problems
depending on the formats that we're
talking about but yeah that's that
presents a real problem yeah I have no
sort of shin I would go the compensating
control route would probably be the best
I mean as with any legal thing I think
that it's up to your legal department to
figure out what is the right way to meet
with the spirit if not the letter of the
law so I had two questions so number one
you talk a bit more about what the
dependencies are for four companies that
are based like in North America visa vie
this dysregulation obviously they do
business in Europe or they have you
citizen data then even though they're
based in the US they have some some
impact is on them right and the second
question is you mentioned in earlier in
your presentation about how you're kind
of the combining dynamic and static
analysis and building out these these
nice graphs I was wondering what you use
to actually drive the you're basically
capturing all of the requests right and
the responses and saying okay here's
what we touch but how do you actually
make it actually exercises the entire
application so that you get the full
code coverage I hope that makes sense
but you have to have an engine to
actually click on every particular
button so that you can actually do your
graph building so if you could talk to
that that's an interesting topic as well
so two questions so if you process data
on EU residents you you must comply with
GDP are theirs that's the scope it
doesn't matter what country you're in
it's a matter of where the people are
residents right the second part I try to
apologize if the explanation wasn't
clear but basically we used different
sources so they come in different
formats but essentially I have a have a
URL right and I parse out the different
pieces of it and I say make this a
hierarchy of this make this a child of
that right and just till I get down to
the point where I say okay this is this
is a parameter now the library that I
use to draw the graphs dynamically is
called graph is
spelled as you would imagine graph plus
viz oh you know the you know thousand
million variants that that application
can encounter so I say Johnny and Vishal
could you please make sure you exercise
every possible path on our application
now what I tried to allude to earlier
was that you can't write you're not
going to realistically you might even
have a B test that pretty you know you
signed up as one user you're signed up
another user guess what they don't see
the same experience and you don't even
have that other button to click right so
you have to combine both static and
dynamic analysis of the client software
or maybe even the backend to put
together a more complete picture that's
why I said we also incorporated swagger
which is what the the or the API
documentation even right that the
developers maintain and we mashed all
those things together we looked for
conflicts resolved conflicts and then
try to fix the conflicts at the source
and then we said okay this looks like
the cleanest result most thorough result
we could find right so there is no magic
answer to that yeah so I I like the
approach that you have mapping your API
and that kind of stuff but as far can
you talk to about continuously
monitoring and and and getting the
updated changes regarding that and then
what on a follow-on of that of is when
the auditors are I don't think they're
really going to be auditors they're
gonna actually be investigators come in
to investigate that you're
non-compliance or you've got up or you
got a breach or whatever do you think
they're going to care about how how you
mapped it out and that you have these
pretty diagrams are they actually
getting these forensics tools to tear
your place apart to find where your data
is at and because it's it has to be
presentable to court if it does go to
court so you have to have those type of
ways of preserving and to finding that
data so I just want to talk about
kind of key points continuous monitoring
and forensically finding the data so
because I'm drawing on different
information sources to complete the CSVs
what the CSVs might be better for them
to use anyways in the graph but I like
having the graph it makes me happy the
the because I'm drawing on those and
different sources some of the sources
are in github so I can literally just
watch that file and see if it changes
right or I can just pull it periodically
uh maybe you Johnny Vishal or someone on
our apps tech team is is testing the
application and I say okay every time
you're done you drop that drop your
output from the dynamic test into this
folder and I'll just have a job that
runs up and mashes them all together
automatically and generates it for me
right there's a little bit of
showmanship in the graph in in the fact
that you have this information you you
do eventually need to have data flow
mappings how you get arrived at that and
what tools you use to store that I was
kind of showing away you could do it on
the cheap for free right we there are
products like one trust that actually
are professional products geared around
storing these type of data mappings but
this is something homegrown and I think
if it if an auditor comes in and they
don't have an axe to grind right they're
not specifically making trying to make
sure that they find something you know
you show them that I'm doing due
diligence right here's a process that I
have that shows me all this and I'm
watching and monitoring for changes in
our data collection and storage right I
think that's a big win and it might get
them to stop looking right it's kind of
like hey our house is in order you don't
need to go looking under every every
nook and cranny or under every Rock for
a problem right is it is it enough that
remains to be seen
can I talk to my legal team and say hey
this is what we're doing does this is
this a defensible position for the
company to be in
they may say yes they may say no you
need to you know put some more work into
it right I think an an auditor of
anything can find a problem if they want
to right isn't it is it a gross
negligent thing or is it a you did due
diligence you did your best and you
still fell short that's a different
standard right and I think what ends up
happening I think historically
if you're grossly negligent you face a
much harsher ramification you may still
face something even though you did best
effort right but it generally minimized
right they you they the company took it
seriously their obligations they tried
to meet them and maybe they fell short
but you know they take that into account
I think general ease you had a question
right yeah so are you gonna the burp
parameter that you guys wrote are you
gonna open source at or anything like
that to help other companies so I can
show you the slide again just so if
anybody wanted to use that we actually
did a custom modification to this we
didn't actually we took this because it
was a very good starting point it was
like 90 percent of where we wanted to be
or so right and we just wrote some some
custom stuff in there to make it fit our
purpose I think it was probably around
the output if I remember right so all we
did was tweak it so we could actually
get to CSV output because that was
easier to to munch but out of the box
that's ready to go for you more or less
if you can take the JSON or XML that it
was already outputting right and then we
and then we wrote some custom code that
I'm not ready to like I don't even know
how useful you would find it but to
merge all those things together swagger
files and API documentation and CSVs and
mash them all together and resolve the
conflicts and create the tree I could
probably talk to you and give it to you
if you really want it's not a major
large-scale project I don't know if
anybody who's really interested in it
but if so I can talk to me I probably
give you a good start on it at least any
other questions
am I being kicked out yet quick one say
company a I'm a user of company a using
Salesforce
how do I request data purge from company
a and Salesforce who has the liability
and how the flow votes that's number one
the comment one comment is the banking
industry they need to retain over
records in personal info for seven years
or so so they don't even right now they
don't even start working on GDP L they
have a few more years before they start
eating date more than seven years old if
they have so thanks so it's a chain of
responsibility right so if if I'm
company if I'm company a and you and I
and I've shared sorry if I'm a user and
I've shared my data with company a right
the responsibility on from my
perspective is on company a right they
need to delete my data or give it to me
when when I requested it right from
company s perspective company B has that
obligation to them right so they have to
to treat that data in accordance so it's
sort of a transitive responsibility like
they inherit that responsibility by the
fact that they're processing data for
you they have two specific terminologies
of user of companies or entities in GDP
are ones processor and another is an
aggregator right and a controller sorry
is that a third or just I miss quoted
one of them okay so it's a processor in
a controller right and so in a in so so
yeah and so they have different spelled
out obligations for each of those entity
types was there what was the other was
there something else
Oh banking I mean again if you're
legally compelled to retain data they
can't make you keep it beyond that right
nobody can force you to be a criminal
that's entrapment okay right at least in
this country anyway now there probably
will be some undone thought of conflicts
that will come up like that right like
earnings reports that I guess those
shouldn't really have stock market data
probably shouldn't have personal
information on the but but an
interesting point that we came across
was vendors the vendors that we use we
have to purge some of their information
because it might have personal
information of the vendors I'm like so I
have to delete emails from vendors from
you know n years ago or whatever because
I have to met meet gdpr
or employ data right it has HR employee
implications as well I I would suppose
that mean that that is only if they are
an EU resident I would assume right and
I guess the same would go with your
with your vendor although good luck on
figuring out whether or not your vendor
is an EU resident or not so so my
question on that would be I am the
company right I am if it's if it's Tony
trummer and I'm holding your data that's
one thing right but as an employee of
tinder I'm now tinder I would assume
right because otherwise my data science
guys right cool I can hold all the data
for what because I'm Bob and I'm gonna
hold all the data you know it's it's my
data the big issue is that is not
defined in gdpr and any other working
groups is I'm a salesperson I take
customer data from the company database
put it in my contact information I
collect the kids birth date so I can
call the customer to say say happy
birthday to your son
now does that data fall under Judy PR
and what happens if that guy's notebook
or you know laptop is stolen and it's
not encrypted it's a whole can of worms
that nobody knows about because there's
no precedent yet yeah we already know
salespeople are lawless Bunch right so I
good luck with them but yeah I mean it
raises interesting questions about like
tracking the data that employees might
put on their laptops and you know take
on vacation with them and not come back
or something like that right there's all
kinds of interesting questions about
that right so as a model right we try to
push everything so like if you're
someone who's pulling data out of our
production systems that needs to stop
right first of all we have kind of a
policy where it's like we don't want
engineers to have access to personal
information as much as possible anyways
realizing that some people like and
maybe the analytics or data science
teams maybe it's unavoidable and some
things I was like how they have to do
their job right but when it's not or if
it is and we can find a better way for
them to do it that doesn't you know
maybe we can change the you know you
change the client server
in some way we're more of it can stay on
the server and less can come down to
your client right test data as an
example like developers I got a whole
bunch of test data it's sitting right
there in the production database I'll
pull it out right like we got to stop
doing that so that you know that doesn't
walk off you know oh it was just I had a
bunch I had a million or so people had a
personal information my laptop cuz I was
running a local instance and I wanted to
test it there that can't can't persist
right okay I guess I'm done oh sorry do
I have time for one more
yeah well squeezes in last question I
just had a question about the your very
exhaustive data maps so you're trying to
identify all the data you use and how
the data flows through your applications
are you intending to implement gdpr
controls on all that data or just the
personal data subset and if it's just
the personal data subset how are you
identifying it from that huge map so
it's probably more easily identified on
the CSV to be honest with you right so I
can actually I could pair it out right
so I could I could literally say like
for things that I know for example like
the auth token on the mid that's not a
great example somebody might say that's
personal information or something but
like I don't know uh let's say there's a
clearly non hypothetical clearly
non-personally identifiable or person
personal if there's a data point that's
not personal information it's clearly in
there I can literally just squeeze that
out and minimize that actual graph to
just be that information the problem the
one problem is about like you might say
okay I'll take a whitelist approach if
it's a date of birth if it's this this
and this you're gonna miss something
eventually because someone's gonna
misspell date of birth or they're gonna
do date underscore of underscore birth
or something like that so it's probably
easier to eliminate parameters once you
know they're not personal information
than it is to having to manually inspect
the output for things that look like
personal data and then you go back track
and look at the flow and determine which
databases are involved in that flow and
those are the ones that you have to
apply controls to is that what you're
doing well yeah if you want to if you
want to minimize the the graph and you'd
need to do that yeah for sure I don't
know that there's an easy way around
that you could you can try regex parsing
and stuff like
bad to say like does this match a phone
number there's certain structured data
elements that are that are going to be
easy to find date of birth and phone
number potentially right there's a
limited range of what those are gonna
look like
whereas someone's names a little bit
harder and then our other addresses get
a little bit looser you know things like
that so good thank you all for coming
have a great day
[Applause]
[Music]