[Music]
I love apps Akali it happens to be my
favorite show I live in California and
so it's really convenient I mean Santa
Monica couldn't be more beautiful today
I'll be talking about how to use a
software-defined networking which is you
commonly see in a lot of private clouds
how to use that technology in to satisfy
OS top-ten controls
[Music]
we're out here because we have the
fastest application testing out there so
we are we're racing
as sec is always amazing you know some
of the best speakers and best topics and
well of about apps a cos is extremely
technical design requires art and
analysis as much as science and so
that's what threat modeling opens up is
the art of the secure design
[Music]
this conference really like like two
thumbs up really for myself because it's
really it's about the people you know
this is also me coming back this is a
this is the best conference I've been to
in a long time thank you
and those for those of you at home if
you can follow me I just want you to see
something over here look at that you see
that background this is what we got to
deal with so come on out next year if
you're not here now
[Music]