[Music]
this is the hours top 10 talk this will
be probably the second last time that I
actually ever given almost top 10 talk
until 2020 because everyone's seen the
hours top 10 talks and I hope to
actually talk about something slightly
different today and we'll get onto that
so Who am I I have been here forever I
am part of the furniture
I did not start oh us I know who did and
I know who was in marks apartment and it
wasn't me okay so at the end of the day
basically I was a early executive
director it was a volunteer position at
the time I worked on the developer guide
from 2003 into 2005 literally until two
hours before I got into the plane to go
to blackhat to present it that was
interesting
there I was top ten 2007 and I'll get
into the reasons why I didn't do the
2010 and 2013 ones in a little bit Ellis
is happy for at PHP and I apologize in
advance for that one or actually
apologize for 2009 and for that one PHP
does not do unicode and so therefore it
will never pass unit tests and so
therefore it had to be abandoned that's
just one of those things and of course
I've been working on the application
security verification standard since
2009 in until now and hopefully we'll
get 3.1 out the door soon and of course
the our top 10 2017 I'm gonna board
member so if you've got any issues
regarding governance and leadership at
OS please come and see me I think I'm
one of the only board members here today
I will be here today and a little bit
tomorrow morning okay so this is
probably the being the rockiest release
we've ever had to put it mildly we've
we've had a bit of a Genesis we can't
stop here this is back country so this
is actually how not to interact with the
project there was a lot of social media
that was very very negative and it
actually ended up with the founding
leadership leaving the oels top ten and
to put it mildly this was not a good
time
honestly the social media pylon was just
extraordinary continuous and extremely
aggressive and
for the most part completely useless
because it was basically saying yells
top 10s sucky and blah blah blah
these guys are conflicted blah blah blah
it's a failure to buy a tool blah blah
blah the reality is it was the worst
thing I've ever seen it was so please if
you're going to interact with the
project provide decent constructive
advice even if it's the sort of advice
that says I think you are completely
wrong and these are the reasons why and
I'll show you the reasons why that's
actually really important it's not
almost like the original rc1 came out we
had a lot of feedback some of it valid
some of it not a seven from monitoring
an ape a ten for API protection board
many people felt it boiled down to you
didn't buy at all which by the way one
of the I was top ten founders by the way
had a product along that line honestly
who here thinks it's okay in this time
and age that you wouldn't monitor an
application I don't see a single hand go
up okay so they're valid are they valid
the way they were written
constructive criticism might have got us
across the line however now we did have
some really good feedback both from John
Stephen who turned out to be in the
organization I joined in June so my
second day was John Stephen and I on a
phone call he's saying I've got a blog
entry you're not going to like it and so
he had to agree to disagree but the
thing is is that his blog entry was
really constructive it actually let us
go forward to figure out what we needed
to change to make it good and so that
was actually a valid piece of criticism
it was long
it was huge he used difficult words but
at the end of the day basically it was
the best thing we could possibly have
because it provided us this is what's
wrong this is what you need to fix did
we accept every single one of those
suggestions no we didn't but we
basically needed that sort of help we
also had problems with data quality and
Brian glass one of our co-leads he
actually provided a two-part blog entry
that did more data analysis
than the original I was top ten rc1 had
and it was really good analysis at
delved deep into the data that was
available it showed that the data wasn't
sufficient it also showed us the way
forward and you know what Brian ended up
as a co-leader of the project can you
see the difference between saying this
is crap and now you're a co-lead this is
what I'm trying to say we really need
people to you know we're a volunteer run
organization I really need people to say
I'm gonna help with projects I want to
volunteer for that it's not you know
we're not just about chapters or
conferences I mean they're great but
we're also about projects and if we can
get more volunteers for projects to make
them better okay so I'm gonna skip this
we've got so many slides unfortunately
as I said Dave and Jeff the original
Ross found is not most founders but the
top ten founders stood down and I got a
call really late at night I was still in
Australia at the time and I said look
I'm gonna step down and I really want
you to look after it and I knew that at
that point I needed help so what I did
is I looked through the contributors
who'd been helping that I was top ten
forever Neil Smith line has been
participating since 2004 so if anything
him being elevated to a co-lead was well
over to you Torsten has been during the
German translation and if you've been
reading the wiki version of the August
top 10 since 2010 that's best Torsten to
work okay so those folks no-brainer easy
to actually justify and as soon as they
got appointed they we basically worked
out that we needed Brian because we
didn't have the data analysis skills to
really figure out what we needed then we
had the project summit the project
summit was still going to happen Dave
was very kind and was a moderator of the
project summit and so one of the
criticisms that was leveled at the I was
top ten prior to rc1 is that it sort of
popped out of nowhere and that's only
true if you don't follow the development
what we tried to do with the project
summit was actually help mitigate some
of those issues so how do we actually
develop the old top ten what qualifies
for getting in
and so there was a couple of outcomes we
aimed for a release in 2017 and we did
that we also agreed to reopen the data
caucus we didn't have 2016 data so
essentially if we'd gone live with the
2015 data I still think it would have
been a bit wrong so we needed more data
and Brian really helped us get that done
we also reopened we opened a new survey
and the survey basically decided that
was going to be too forward-looking
issues and some people are really upset
with us because they really want us to
talk about the impact based upon
breaches but the reality is I stuck in
serous F into the OWASP top 10 2007
because 100 percent of applications had
serous F in 2007 100 % so we stuck it in
because it was important so we're going
to always reserve up to two spots one or
two that aren't supported by the data at
all and we've got those we're also
agreed to work completely in the open
and github and you can see that you can
see who contributed you can see actually
those folks who submitted a ticket to
get something fixed so instead of
providing silent feedback and then it
suddenly changes and no one's got an
idea what actually happened there
everything's completely open so if
you've got a problem with the OS top 10
2017 logon issue and we'll fix it that's
as simple as it gets
so the data call we talked about that a
little bit we've got five hundred plus
four responses to the survey we've got a
whole bunch of data and I really really
really really appreciate everyone
submitting their data we had over 43
submissions of which 20-plus were
actually had enough data points for us
to be able to use we had some problems
where some of the folks who are doing
automated assessments and those who are
doing static code analysis had different
things and so many things it was
overwhelming some of the other inputs
from say for example small boutiques and
the small boutique consultancies the
quality of the findings is incredible
the breadth of the findings the number
of cwe's hit is incredible and so we
didn't want to lose that data and so
Brian's job was
actually to try and get that balance
right so if you are actually wondering
how we came up with the weighting we've
got the Excel spreadsheet there if
you're wondering what the source data
was it's in github you can download that
data and so if you run a security
consultancy you can actually use that
data compare yourself against 114
thousand other applications and you can
say am i doing a good job or am i doing
a bad job and then up up those skills so
it was still analyzing all this data and
that's probably going to go through to
2020 just realistically we need to have
a different design for 2020 historically
the URLs top ten has always looked
backward these are the things that
security researchers found last year but
that's actually not important because if
you think about it in 20 in 2012 was all
about hacktivism in 2016 I was all about
credentials and automation attacks
basically credential stuffing and what
not if we were designing the hours top
10 to be about you know more or less the
things that happen last year it would be
out of date the second we published and
that was always the problem with the
methodology of the hours top 10 and so
we've tried to fix that and when we do
the 2020 version I would really
appreciate it if you guys could actually
start doing some sort of automation
around your you know pen test results so
you can actually submit as well ok
now we can make it an anonymous
submission we didn't have time this year
to do that but I would certainly suggest
I would like to have more than 114,000
apps as our sample size so anytime that
I get information back from someone who
says the OS top 10 is not valid because
we don't have enough data is wrong this
is the largest sample of data out there
at full stop and more importantly just
before we actually started to finish up
the I was top 10 bug crowd submitted
their data and that was a huge thing I
was so brave of them because it actually
gives you a little bit of a clue about
their business but important thing is
bad crowd has triaged every one of those
bugs the customer of
but crowd has actually paid out either a
t-shirt or some money to get those
results and it agreed with our analysis
that is an amazing like you know you got
the best people in the world working on
bug bounties including you know some
folks who do nothing else but look at
one class of bug so a friend of mine who
now works for Apple he basically found
nothing but X axes and and 250 K in a
year getting X X YZ so the reality is we
had real specialists who were you know
back crowd thank you thank you so much
and we also appreciate everybody else
who contributed data ok what does it say
well the reality is passive findings are
overwhelmingly towards the top but is
that going to be a one we had to think
about that because you know
realistically signal injection is now
less than 5% of every of the total
number of findings but it really comes
down to the impact so things you can
find through SSL labs or passive
findings and burb or security headers
that i/o those things are you really
going to get hacked by having a weak
certificate or a self-signed certificate
probably not if you had no certificate
yeah maybe so we actually looked at this
and we tried to actually work out what
is it we're going to say because the
data and you can see there that X X C
which is one of the new URLs top tens
had enough data by itself to get in by
itself you didn't need help
ok so we'll talk about that in a bit but
this is actually really interesting
because you know we we've selected the
number of cwe's pretty much at random
based around what we felt were the most
popular 40 cwe's and in the MVD data and
we were worried that we hadn't asked you
for a cwe that could be really impactful
and that's the problem with the
methodology and that's something we'll
have to fix in 2020 how do we make sure
that we get all the cwe's to see whether
or not it's impactful because this is
not the list you'll see there and so
the things that did come up and you got
to remember when we were doing this the
Equifax hack had just happened and I am
aware that a couple of people from Yahoo
are here today and I apologize in
advance but also the the fact that every
single account at Yahoo was breached not
just some of them and obviously this is
not great so this was on top of people's
minds but the reality is finally people
are testing for access control and this
is a really important thing so we need
to make sure that we've covered that off
and so we basically started weighting it
and the number of responses that
occurred and it started becoming a bit
clearer that once you actually seemed
these things up we started to get
certain categories of findings which
sadly in some ways is the old Hoss
top-10 sequel injection didn't move
access control moved up a beard but
cross-site scripting went down a bit but
they're still in the ovals top 10 if you
think about the I was top 10 as being
this is the bare minimum you can do then
essentially it's a 10 things that you
really need to fix and does it matter if
it's in 1 or 10 no not really
so one of the problems we've got here is
that this is about what to do you know
what not to do you can tell developers
there's like a thousand things not to do
but there's only really about 13 or 14
things that you want them to do and
Enterprise Architecture still roll has a
role to play there but also leading
practices so if you're actually
interested is to how come this has ended
up in this way and then for what is the
order of the hours top 10 you've got to
realize that we've got to talk about the
ASVs and proactive controls if you're
after a security standard you really
need to use those other actual standards
this is an awareness piece of the bare
minimum to avoid negligence there's a
big difference there so the OS top 10 is
used on a regular basis because it's
easy there's only ten things most of it
is surface like you
you can get it through a pen test most
of it and so that's an important element
and so ordering Dave really wanted to
keep the same order and this is an
actually an interesting point do we keep
the same order if it exists
so keeping cross-site scripting at
number three or whatever it was and the
answer is well I didn't know and I
wanted to find out so I asked on Twitter
how to actually work it out and the vast
majority of you wanted to have risks in
fact risks outweighed all the other
responses put together so it was an easy
decision but what's a risk a risk is
likelihood which we had times impact
which we don't and so this is a bit of a
problem I mean we're we're coming up
with a risk rating here that's not a
really a risk because we can't guess how
you use it someone who uses SharePoint
for like a wiki or something that's
internal has no sensitive data that's
like if you compromise that SharePoint
no big deal many share points are
actually on the Internet in read-only
mode and that's fine but if you
sharepoint to store health data and
that's a heavily protected part of your
ecosystem that's usually a big deal so
sane app very different risk ratings so
we want to understand that a little bit
more and I think that's actually
something we need to work on in 2020
there's something we couldn't get to
this time around so the road to release
we basically had a lot of things going
on we basically had two more releases
the rc2 which is the first version that
actually exposed what we're going to
have as our top 10 list in the order
that we're going to have it at that
point we were basically really certain
of our data the day that we had that is
the wording how we expressed ourselves
the recommendations that was all up for
grabs at that point we needed to make
sure that the community was on board
with it and so it was an interesting one
so everything was in github you can see
it there the data call has all the data
if you want to reanalyze that data go
for this is how we get to a place where
we start to be reproducible we want to
make sure that you can disagree with
this if you like but if the data is
there hmm okay
can have opinions but facts don't care
about your opinion we want to get to
that place we need to be reproducible we
need to be a bit more scientific about
this because we only have 10 spots we
need to make sure that we use them
properly the other thing is that we need
to make sure that the issues are
traceable so say for example someone
logs at issue and we actually take care
of it so how does that get into the text
we actually worked in markdown that made
it really easy to actually identify what
text has changed and that made a lot
easier to translate so you can already
see that we have English French Hebrew
Japanese and Korean and now we've got a
few others as well this is amazing we've
never had so many translations finished
so early and that's because not only did
we make sure the translators know that
there was something coming up we also
work with them to make sure that
markdown was available to them so they
could start the translation effort
before we got going and because they
could see what changed they could
actually with confidence do the
PowerPoint version of it which by the
way hopefully in 2020 would be using
PowerPoint for the actual final version
it made it really simple for them to say
well that text change in the English
version I need to update my translation
of that one sentence instead of re
translating the entire page and that's a
huge benefit for them I see - we
actually closed 125 issues in four
months but you can sort of see it spiked
roughly around September to October it
was more of a rewrite than and then
anything else where you looked at every
single word where he basically read
jigged it we reordered it slightly we
included a difference the exposure of
sensitive data has often been
misconstrued as ah you tell us that the
header here is the running Apache that
is not sensitive okay so we'll talk
about that a little bit more xyx II got
in there by itself D serialization is
chosen by the community and it's a
worthy inclusion it could have it might
be the root cause or one of the root
causes behind one of the biggest hacks
of 2017
insufficient logging and monitoring
we're basically saying you need to bring
down the number of days that you're
compromised and you need to detect it
now it seems pretty reasonable so if you
look at the Vera's on
data breach report it's been basically
static for the number of years it has
gone down from less than like just on
two years down to a hundred and ninety
two days but 192 days is not great and
the vast majority of people who tell you
that you've been breached our external
parties and so that's also not great so
we really need to get to a place where
we're actually in charge of our
destinies and that includes logging and
monitoring and we'll talk about how to
actually do that in a tick the garden
master we did 121 issues in three weeks
I didn't sleep much my sleep is terrible
at the rest of times but that is a lot
of work we actually closed out very
substantial issues and in fact we
actually got a complete rewrite of a a
the D serialization from Chris fro Hoff
and Gabriel Lawrence the guys who came
up with the D serialization attacks and
why so serial so those guys actually
wrote that section which is fantastic we
want more of that we're a specialist in
that area help peer-review it all
rewrite it okay so that's awesome
we also did a test fit PowerPoint
because it's really easy to write 2,000
words it's really hard to write 600 so
we actually had about 140 words per
section of the of the document and
getting there distilled essence of what
we wrote and marked down into PowerPoint
yeah in the final release we did 82
issues in one week yeah I didn't sleep
there neither we definitely moved we
moved from markdown to PowerPoint at
that point cuz we didn't allow anything
other than essential typos to be fixed
at that point we also kicked off
translation and then it was released and
it was awesome the timing could have
been better
it was the Thanksgiving week that is a
good lesson to be learnt for 20/20 do
not release in Thanksgiving okay that is
like number one don't release in
Thanksgiving I would actually like to
see it released adapt SiC USA in 2020 I
think that's a good time it actually
coincides with a bit of press and I
think it coincides with people being
around I think honestly it'll be good
good to aim for that
it's too early in the year it takes time
to do this properly no I agree though
it's awesome okay so what's new okay so
these are the things we're going to
basically skip this you can get it we
have a slightly different format than
previous years we've really concentrated
on how are you vulnerable so this is if
you're a pen tester you need to test for
this if you're a developer you need to
write tests around this how to prevent
this is for developers how to fix it so
it's not about folks basically getting
in there and putting in waffles or
anything like that we need people to fix
the code and so that's basically our
best advice at this very moment on how
to prevent we've provided some attack
scenarios there and I'll let you know
there's an easter egg in there and the
first person who finds it I will get an
iTunes voucher for them so let's just
say those who it's a quite a good one
anyway and then we've got references and
for the first time we actually link to
cheat sheets proactive controls and ASVs
as well as the cwe's so this is actually
really important the vast majority of
security tools have now settled on CWA
has been the index
okay so ISPs will actually start to
relink will actually linked with CWA
even though we're a positive model on
the CW is a weakness the top ten is all
about weaknesses so you know what if
you're a pen tester and you're wondering
how do I update my skills and whatnot
make sure you cover off every one of
those cwe's and then call it that CWA
when you write your reports and then we
can figure out if you comply with the OS
top ten or not
honestly this stuff here is interesting
so you want to know how we ended up
scoring things this is basically the top
bit here exploitation of deserialization
is somewhat difficult blah blah blah and
then prevalence of detectability like
how easy is it to get and then the
impact and the impact can be anything
from we've made you reboot your server
to we can port scan you inside or we can
use internal document reflection to get
things out of you I've talked about the
application
and Prevention that's awesome attack
scenarios and references this is
actually one of those areas where we
basically help you figure out how to do
it with different views so the proactive
controls is like the negative of the OS
top-ten except for it's a completely
positive way of dealing with things so
if you want a simple quick standard to
comply with proactive controls as your
job if you want the ASVs
that has three levels level 1 2 & 3 you
can choose whichever one you want
we also encourage people to fork it and
then basically make it its own we also
provide some background information and
that's actually really helpful so say
for example you don't understand even
after we've written all of this you can
go click the links and there's some good
links to presentations or background
material ok so a sequel injection no
surprise that it's number one it's just
the impact is off the charts we've seen
a lot of no SQL injection primarily in
encrypting complete databases so most
people are actually now on top of that
because they've had their databases
encrypted once yeah but you know we've
included it so I'm just going to show
you the demos come on you can do it oh
it's done it as a little tiny thing on
the corner there its sequel injection
everyone said sequel injection this is
the o oz juice shop by the way which if
you haven't played with it yet it is one
of the best for neural apps it's written
in angular and has an odious background
has 50 odd exercises all of them modern
and it has a CTF mode and it actually
has a learning mode so essentially you
can teach yourself the five different
levels of attack it's actually really
cool they've they've done unit tests
it's actually the most bug free
vulnerable application in existence
it passes all the unit tests okay so in
a two we are now talking about anti
automation so credential stuffing we are
talking about NIST 863 so stop testing
for password complexity please sub you
now need to test for the length of
passwords they should be a minimum of 12
if they have to factor and the minimum
of 16 if they don't have to factor and
you're probably going what the but
that's NIST 863 to give you an idea how
little they think about passwords it's
in the second book on page 260 in
Section five point one point one point
one and you know what it was it took me
a while to find out when they're
actually going to talk about passwords
and the entire three-volume set is a
better syndication they don't want you
to use passwords anymore please stop so
two-factor authentication pretty much
mandatory at this point and he
automation so because we've got four
billion credentials floating out about
there with the username and passwords
you don't need the dictionary attack you
don't have to GPU crack anymore you look
up a person's password like password
directly and login so passwords are done
they are dun dun dun dun dun
and so what I really needed to do in
fact it's going to do this again isn't
it it's going to put this little video
here in that little tiny window that's
terrible
so yes that's a dictionary attack that
video there
the reality is dictionary attacks are
interesting but I'm much more interested
about credential stuffing so you need to
bring it up you need to actually look at
the way that we've rewritten it our top
10 to 30 and start testing for those
better things
also think about two-factor
authentication in terms of business
logic can you use a token to identica to
a different account can you actually
bypass two factor authentication can
password resets bypassed two-factor
authentication you need to be testing
the functional aspects of two-factor
just breaking in because you have a very
fast connection to the server yeah okay
so sensitive data exposure is about
sensitive private health financial data
pretty much anything you can get in
trouble for regulatory wise compliance
wise or legal wise we care about okay
so s3 buckets get a mention here now
Amazon is well on its way to fixing that
problem okay
but even anyone who actually explicitly
shares a bucket with the wrong
permissions because they think that the
bucket name is somehow magical and
special that can still be a problem and
there's other cloud services as well but
Elvis did we talk about s3 buckets we
also talked about ways that you can
actually do the attacks so essentially
we're looking at exposing records let me
just get my mouse pointer yep so
effectively what trying to do here is
we're trying to get to a place where
people are testing for access to other
people's data and we're not just talking
about read access if you can change an
account like you can update someone's
password and then login as them that's
terrible - okay if you're in a Health
System and you say this person is crazy
because you're allowed to update someone
else's record that's terrible so we want
to make sure that we get to a place
where we are testing the functional
aspects of access control for creation
read update and delete and anything else
that might expose bulk information okay
so it's way different so this is
basically an account takeover because
the password can be reset for someone
else's account okay that's terrible
you shouldn't be able to reset someone
else's account so xxe got in by itself
one of the biggest things though this
was only in SAS data wasn't in DAST
which means no one's testing for it okay
so what we really need to do is and
interestingly enough this bad crowd
actually had the most amount of x'q see
findings of anyone and so what we really
need people to do is learn how simple
xxe is let me just kick that off because
this is one of the shortest videos in
the entire compilation yes I prepared
the file earlier but anyone can
prepare an XML file and just have it
handy so effectively you know file
upload features would be probably be
testing for can we run an arbitrary
command like put over you know a JSP or
something but you know we're gonna
submit an XML and see what happens so
it's going to try and get the password
file out of it and yeah went well we've
accepted that exit ich Euler thing and
then we can look at the response and yep
so the request is all good what's the
response say yep there's the password
file that is how simple it is to exploit
xxe if you really want the file from it
you might need to set up a victim server
like you know an intact server but you
know what that's not a high bar okay
broken access control we're now
extending it from just idle and
functional level access control ie
controllers we need to go to perforce
browsing presentation layer access
control particularly model layers so
essentially do I have permissions to
create read write and delete this
particular record is owned by someone
else when I see code and I do a fair a
number of code reviews I often see the
models being one line long and those
lines don't often have a join in there
to make sure that the ownership of the
record is enforced we need to actually
start testing for that because what
happens is that when you go to micro
services they're now exposed and it's
like having a sequel server on the
internet because you know how to drive a
restful api to get all the data out so
please
model i/o access control and domain
access control business logic one of the
things that I tested for in 2015 was a
is anyone here from Oracle I'm going to
apologize in advance there was a really
interesting app and I'm not going to
tell you which one it is because I have
3,000 apps and so you're gonna leave
your guessing because I don't know if
they fixed it
this app is used by infrastructure let's
call it infrastructure it's 16 years old
at that point in time it would have been
pen tested hundreds of times and I could
access admin functionality without being
logged in yeah I it blows my mind that
so many people would have pen tested
that because
it's infrastructure if you get my
meaning
that no one tested access control we
need to step up access control testing
you know it's not automatable so we need
the developers to do this we need you
guys to help their developers write good
integration test because it's functional
testing and we need to get on with that
okay security mist configuration this is
the bucket list for everything that's
passive and I would actually like it
very much if everyone stopped reporting
these with a risk rating because it may
you yeah you're running Apache hmm big
deal it's actually much more important
about a nine which is running vulnerable
components okay it's not really
important about what you call it because
plenty of people disable that header and
you're still vulnerable okay so every
passive finding is a six and I honestly
think you know we need to actually just
simply say here's some hygiene things
you should fix don't risk rate it just
simply say here's the bucket list here's
the ten or fifteen things that's wrong
because we should be spending our times
in pen test reports in actually doing
consulting helping our people be better
at security the only reason it's this
high because its impact is negligible
it's because it's the most common
vulnerability it's so much more than
everybody else make success everybody
knows exercise but we've talked about
Dom XSS explicitly we need you to start
testing for Dominic success if you don't
know anything about Dom XSS learn it's
not hard it just requires better skills
you need to know what it sources are you
need to know sinks you need to get
yourself a plugin that I actually do
some little bit of JavaScript inspection
to actually understand how it works and
to find those sources and sinks and then
learn how to actually do it it's not
that hard
and the problem is Dominic success
doesn't go through a firewall it happens
on the browser and so you don't even
know it's happened and yet it's got
exactly the same impact as either a
reflected or restored cross-site
scripting depending on how it's actually
invoked okay insecurity serialization I
have talked about this already let's
just click this this video
what we're talking about it and so this
is an API and basically we're going to
have a serialization attack anyone who
leaves their swagger in production is
all good and so this one's just going to
do a do s to stop the server from
responding for a period of time and so
we're going to steal an authentication
header from a good request and then
everything it's going to do the xxe
sorry there to see serialization you're
not going to find it very often I
actually think the serialization is
going to be with us forever once people
learn how easy it is and how often folks
who are writing back in code they don't
want to have state on backend code
because then it becomes not functional
programming anymore and so what happens
is they ship that state around and that
state is actually very sensitive and so
once you learn what serialization looks
like and how to attack it it's actually
really interesting because now you go
remote khoomei a command execution on
the remote server and that's not the
only thing if it's an object it's not
necessarily exploitable in that way you
might be able to change yourself from
being a user to an admin or
get to be someone else so these things
are actually rather interesting so just
in the interests of time I will make
sure all of these videos uploaded so you
can watch them all they're mostly
between 10 seconds and 40 seconds long
and so in this case it's going to
require me to do some cutting and
pasting to get this right and yeah this
is why I think this I that want to be
with us forever may not necessarily be
always exploitable because you have to
get the syntax right so if you remember
the days when syntax was a real big deal
when you're doing sequel injection like
15 years ago and you had to do it by
hand
yeah blind sequel injection was
basically known but you couldn't really
ducks there were no good tools we're at
that point right now with D
serialization because the gadgets that
why so serial producers are very
specific to certain builds okay so we
need to learn how to do it okay I'm just
going to go forward because we are
running out of time
okay known vulnerable components
unfortunately is still with us and this
is actually really surprising we really
need the CIC deeper folks to step up and
say we are going to break the build if
it has a vulnerable component we are
going to warn the developers that there
is a problem if there's an out-of-date
component what happens is that if you
leave this go and you don't you know
this is a problem but you don't actually
update it
it creates technical debt I went to one
client late last year and they have
components that are like three or four
years old and it's got security
vulnerabilities up the wazoo and they do
two or three releases a year and the
problem with this is is that they're
going to basically do nothing for like
three or four months but update their
components and then they'll still be out
of date at the end of that unless they
fix the process so we need to start
fixing the process I really want this
out of the old top ten because it
shouldn't be a thing if we're doing
agile devops whatever it is this should
not be a thing that is dependency
checker is really good for those of you
who have never seen an in action this is
basically looking at the juice shop for
nodejs
now there is an NSP check which you can
also do but it's not as good as I was -
dependency check even though this is a
bead of function experimental function
of dependency check it does it for PHP
it does it for node it does it for Ruby
it does it for Java it does it for
JavaScript please start using it it's
really impressive it's really awesome
and you can see there if I saw that
particularly report coming out in XML I
you can actually ask dependency check to
put out an status code of fail above a
CVS s level so you can say is it is it
above 6.0 break the build absolutely we
need to get to the place now where we're
breaking the build so NSP check which is
another thing you can do with javascript
with no js' only found like one item and
yep thank you
so I really want to make sure that we
can retire this in three years help our
our industry out by getting rid of this
there problem I really want to see like
sequel injection went downhill really
fast as soon as people's did frameworks
properly when you really need out our
folks to start building in an
engineering fashion okay
insufficient logging and monitoring I'm
going to spend a tiny bit of time here
because it's important because it's it's
a control in fact it's a missing control
so in auditing circles is the idea of is
the control present is it in use and is
it effective so even if you have Splunk
if your security things aren't saying
I'm a security event I can be searched
for and create a dashboard
you've got logs you don't have
artificial agreements to get rid of all
the other logs you need to be able to do
something it allows your tools that you
have to highlight the problems that you
definitely have so it's not a matter of
if you get hacked it's when you get
hacked and then can you detect it so the
way that I want to go forward with this
is basically if you're a a security
consultancy when you do a pen test ring
the client up I know this is shocking
you talk to the client did you detect me
if you didn't detect me you need to fix
things if you did detect me with that
I've actually started your incident
management process and then more
importantly does your incident
management process allow you to continue
even though you're being hacked because
imagine if Amazon turned off every time
that someone tried to hack them it's not
ok we wouldn't we wouldn't accept that
today so as much as we try to say that
we want you to have an incident response
framework NIST 861 ref 2 basically says
turn it off I slayed it forensically
image it yeah that's not going to happen
we need to have a modern version of 861
okay and you need to be realigned with
your business translations please we've
only got those ones right now I'd really
like to see a Vietnamese version I'd
really like to see your local language
here ok as many translations as possible
even if only one person reads it then
that makes a difference that's awesome
and as I said almost every
you'll document I ever have ever done it
always has a cat related Easter egg this
is the cat related Easter egg in this
particular deck but the OS top-10
actually has a different cat related
Easter egg and a you to find it okay so
time to upskill and continuously improve
honestly I want you to start thinking
about the hours top 10 as being the
minimum list to avoid getting sued for
negligence okay it's the absolute bare
minimum if you need to do something more
you want to do an AB set program it's
not the right choice I'm saying that to
you as the ellice top 10 leader you need
to choose the ASVs you need to choose
the cloud security alliance you need to
choose their proactive controls because
you cannot review yourself to security
and I'm gonna apologize again security
needs to become part of the development
team ok if we sit to the side and say
that we're somehow better than everybody
else when we've signed the exact same
employment agreements as everybody else
though we can't be approached if we sit
on a different floor the developers
don't have the choice of talking to you
about something they've noticed or they
want help with if you actually make
yourself the person who communicates bad
news to them in such an offensive way
they don't like dealing with you then
your other computer says no we need to
enable secure business in 2005 I worked
on a corporate internet banking project
where we basically had a business
requirement - if they had two billion
dollars in the account they could
transfer 2 billion dollars if we had
40,000 transactions for a pay run it
could had to allow that to happen and
this is the Internet in 2005 and so I
came up with a solution for that and you
know what we evaluate a whole bunch of
products we did transaction signing
which is something you don't see very
often but it's really important the
thing was that was such a huge
competitive advantage that we got a lot
of other clients to come to us because
we could do things that other banks were
still accepting nine-track tape for like
pay runs you know this is like 2005 so
it's a while ago so we could do things
on the Internet
with billions of dollars because we
invested in security that enabled secure
business it is a competitive advantage
and to be there you need to be part of
the development team we cannot be there
right at the end we cannot be telling
people that their baby is very ugly if
you're a separate security team you're
doing it wrong please get embedded you
need to update your skills you need to
update your test plans because obviously
we've retired a few things I know
unvalidated redirects and forwards was a
very popular item but the reality is
that the data is just not there for it
anymore and that's probably because the
frameworks we now use don't have it
really anymore and so one of the
problems is though if you're still
testing for the old top 10 2013 you're
not really testing for the impactful
things and I need you to start testing
the impactful things ok and updates
Karen policies if you write tools if
you're a tool vendor please create an
owl's top 10 2017 policy please don't
tell everyone you do the entire top 10
because you can't 810 is untestable from
a tool perspective unless you have some
way of hooking in with your seam that
reports back to your test tool which is
a way forward
but I don't see it happening ok 20 20
please I please please please think
about right now getting to a place where
you can get statistics for your own
needs but then share it with us because
if you know where your problems are
because you're collecting statistics you
can say well I've been investing this
many millions of dollars a year in my
security team and I don't have anything
to show for it
standing at metrics helps you start
building that that thing what's actually
effective and what's not effective and
what I'd like to do is once you actually
do that for yourself you can share it
with us and I'd love that
I want more than 114,000 apps next time
I want a whole lot more than a hundred
and fourteen thousand apps and I would
really like more bug bounty folks I
would like the internal security teams I
would love to get more data even if it's
anonymous data it's going to be
fantastic we didn't have the option of
doing anonymous data this time but I
would love to be able to do that to be
able to share more with you ok thank you
there's any questions it's great thank
you so much
[Music]