[Music]
good morning everyone welcome to my talk
my name is Swapna and I'm here to
present about packing your Android this
particular presentation itself is going
to focus around how can we extract
malware genomes from hardened
applications within Android itself we
saw three main categories of hardening
one is office keishon another one is
packing and third one is a combination
of both called protector so the
techniques that we have would statically
extract malicious genome so that we can
do a research around it and identify its
a if it's one durable or not but Before
we jump into the presentation itself
there is a quick disclaimer so the views
and opinions that I have expressed in
this particular presentation itself is
purely mine and I would be really
appreciative we don't associate that
with any of the companies or individuals
that I'm associated with so now that we
have that out of the door a quick Who am
I so as I stated before my name is
Swapna Deshmukh I have co-authored
hacking exposed series of we within the
book itself we basically talk about
various avenues of how we can exploit
let's say mobile for example or web
application itself what are the other
what are the various attacks that we
have and how can we defend against those
attacks as well along along with that
I'm currently leading the security team
for emerging technologies for a company
called visa as the moonlight projects
I'm also working on a poppyseed project
this is an open source that we have that
basically talks it's an abstraction
layer of all the different malicious
applications that are out there so we
found millions of samples for it for
various verticals itself and we want to
create a framework that will identify
all the different malicious applications
that are already out there for various
verticals it could be right from Android
to iOS to Windows so so we started with
Android at this given point itself
because of the cost of deployment itself
and the ease of use of it and we have a
running instance at this given point
itself on malware repo which is right at
the end
so now that why exactly are we here why
does it matter at this given point it's
off and the sheer reason why we started
with this engagement was because we all
are very easy targets
a lot of malicious applications are
already out there in our trusted play
store itself it could be Google Play
stores
it could be Chinese play stores as well
they already are installed in there in
fact there was a report that came out
from suppose that stated out one in
three application that was installed in
2017 from an Android app store itself
was malicious in some degree it will
collect our user data itself or it could
be a ransomware so imagine one in three
application that be installed in 2017
itself can be malicious that's a huge
number
in fact they continue reporting that
there is billion-dollar industry when it
comes to ransomware there is one that we
would be looking at there was 33 million
dollars that they collected as a as a
result of that ransomware itself so very
very easy target and they're earning
millions and millions of it so the
biggest challenges why is it so
difficult for us to evaluate and
hardened Android application and and
there are four different reasons or five
different reasons that I can come up
with I am very sure there would be more
than that because of which is very
difficult for third-party app stores to
identify it the first in the list is
office keishon so office keishon makes
an application very difficult to read
what it does it it manuals the class
names at mangled stuff the function
calls itself it will add java
reflections that will do api hiding
itself which makes it very difficult for
someone to read through the code anti
emulator is another one that makes sure
that it's not running in an sandbox
environment at any given point so if
they will do something called sprach
info just to identify if it's running in
a qmo environment itself or a sandbox
environment and if it's running in an
sandbox environment itself they will
deflate the malware genome a good
example of that is Google bouncer which
is used to identify
malicious content and Google Play Store
itself heavily uses an T so it uses
emulator itself to identify a lot of
applications and they have two criterias
they run in a sandbox environment and
they only test that application for five
minutes
so as an malicious author itself what
would be the workaround that we can come
up with it's very simple right have a
delay of five minutes or if it's running
an anomaly in a sandbox environment
itself do not inflate your malicious
content and you pass through your Google
Play Store so it's as easy as that
along with that there is route detection
checks that make sure that you're not
running in a compromised operating
system so Google coined the term called
route to make sure that if it's elevated
privileges that you have then it will
again look for those look for certain
conditions itself if it satisfies that
then it will make sure that it's not
able to execute the malicious part
malicious content itself or you also
have anti debugging as well so as a
security researcher a few prerequisites
that you have to even analyze any code
dynamically is that you have to first
route the device that's the first thing
that you need to have and the second
thing is you need to have some sort of
debugging controls in place to hook into
a gdp for example or do some method
sizzling to just do a dump a log dump of
what exactly is the application trying
to do at any given point what are the
calls that they're making what are the
function functions that have been called
out of it as well right so you start
logging that just to analyze as well
right so by having route detection
checks and anti debugging checks as a
security researcher they are not able to
to analyze this application further in
2017 itself we saw a huge trends of
there is anti tampering solutions which
make sure that Derek each code blocks
would have their check sums and if you
modify any of those check sums at any
given point itself or so any code blocks
at any given point itself your check sum
would be different which means that the
application is tampered with right so as
soon as it detects that the application
is tampered with now they will make sure
that the malicious part of the
application is not running there is also
a new trend in later half of 27 that we
observed called white Boz cryptography
it what it does is encrypts a part of
the Android code itself and the key that
has are encrypted this data would be
completely office gated and that office
kitchen piece would be spread across the
heap itself so if you want to decrypt
the data or if you want to statically
analyze the code itself you first need
to identify what the key is and then you
can do a dump of that part of the
malicious file whatever has been
encrypted so it makes it a little
difficult for us to like even analyze it
further along with that white box
cryptography has also been used for
ransomware as well so they will encrypt
your entire SD card and they'll say you
have to pay 0.5 bitcoins in order to
decrypt this data and if you try to
decompile an application to identify
where the keys are it would be spread
across the memory itself making it
difficult for someone to like gather
that right so if malicious authors are
finding avenues like these to to bypass
a lot of checks that we have in place by
the third party products or by Google
Play Store itself to publish that in
Play stores as a result of that we have
seen a huge surge in malicious
applications itself been out there so
now that being said this is not the
first that is talking about this
particular topics itself there are bunch
of them a few listed there there was a
talk in Def Con last year talking about
how to hack into Android itself when
it's been hardened when the application
is hardened itself unfortunately the
tools that they have released as an
after of aftermath of that itself of
aftermath of their presentation it's all
been obsolete at this given point or are
not been maintained as a result of that
there is no concrete evidence of us just
downloading something from github and
decompiling and harden application
itself right so that's where the
initiative came and from for for the
poppy seed project we are certainly
looking for contributors itself there
are a lot of data that is already a lot
of research that is already out there
which would all consolidate that in one
place and then use that to identify the
application itself so we we talked about
the premise so far around the hardening
of applique
let's quickly take a take a look at the
first hardening technologies that we
have seen for Android which is office
keishon as a stated before office
keishon is basically scrambling of your
data a good good example for that is
let's say if for an Android class you
have comm wasp dot password validator as
a human inspecting it it's very clear
that this could be a password validator
class files right so office keishon will
change that it will just change that to
comm dot H dot s so as a human it's
little difficult for us to understand by
just reading that last name itself and
you have to inspect that class name
class further to understand what that
class is actually trying to do so
obfuscation would basically mangle those
things there are a few other things that
the scramble they also scramble the
variable names the function names now
they can also do a control flow office
keishon as well so if you have try/catch
if you have FL statement itself they
will change that into a switch and that
switch would have a dead code so you
have to go through each cases itself to
understand what are they're trying to do
there there could be a variable that has
returned back that can be used for by
some other case statement itself to
execute certain payload of it so since
because of that dead code injection
itself it becomes very difficult for
someone to like read through that code
the third in the office case in
standpoint third in the office Keshan
that we have looked at is called string
encryption so it will encrypt the string
and in order to decrypt the data itself
they will have some logic inside the
file on how you could decrypt that
string so as a human when it's reading a
jargon jargon strings itself it's very
difficult for us to understand what it
is right so now you have to go through
the entire call flow itself to
understand how you can decrypt that file
decrypt that string itself to get a
human readable string so office caters
would do all of that along with that
they also use Java reflection either for
an API hiding itself or adding more
complexity to the code the only good
thing about this is they are not
encrypting any of them
Jeanne omits of the malicious genome is
along with the code so if you want to
read through the code itself statically
then you have to read through through
the code itself and the first in the
example itself is ProGuard so this is a
example of a very lightweight office
kitchen technique it comes out of the
box from Android standpoint itself and
as you can see this is one of the
ransomware so the the first part of the
code itself is basically used to lock a
computer or lock a device so it will
lock a device that will set a passcode
for it in order to decrypt the data you
need to enter the same passcode passcode
so if you D compile the application once
you get it it was it was very evident
that the passcode is set to one zero
zero eight from a malicious author
standpoint itself they were coding 0.5
bitcoins for this and when we did some
stats around how much they earn over a
period of time at last till last week
they earned thirty four million dollars
from it so by just having addy
compilation of the application itself it
was very evident that the passcode is
right there
and we could have helped millions of
people who paid for the ransomware
itself to unlock their device so that's
one example of let me just talk about a
quick office caching technique as well
so if you look for classes dot for name
of which is comm dot H dot s that is a
kind of an office keishon for class
names so it's not very trivial as you
can see to read through what exactly
malicious author is trying to do at this
given point even if they're using some
sort of obfuscation but then it gets
complex the second in the list is Dex
protector Dex protector is a combination
of packer and office cater at this given
point itself we will just look at the
office keishon techniques and how their
office cating it so if the one that is
highlighted is basically a Java
reflection where it call calls on create
with certain arguments that have been
passed this on create when you look at
the file itself that there were nine
different instances of it with various
arguments being passed and each and
every argument was called so each and
every method was called bypassing
various arguments to it it will collect
a small bit of code and we'll pass it to
the other one itself by collecting all
of this you basically have a decryption
key but if you have to go through nine
different methods to understand how to
decrypt the data itself it's very
time-consuming so as a result of that we
created a Python script that will
basically go through the entire code
start dumping the data bits in the data
bits and then collect the decryption key
and use that decryption key against
entire decompiled class files itself to
first remove the dead code and also give
you a decrypted string so as a result of
that we used that Python script to just
understand which method has been called
by that function so it's it was colic
and collected calling a text protected
dot name which is which was one of the
loaded libraries that they had and they
were passing an argument for run along
with the small hash and that hash was
collected through the string encryption
mechanism that we have along with that
it was after it calls that it looks for
certain attributes for route detection
checks or for anti debugging checks
itself if it if it passes through that
it basically calls the next function so
as as a person who's trying to research
on malware itself I know that the next
jump that they would be having provided
all the conditions are satisfied is this
the activity splash itself so now I
don't have to go through nine different
method calls to understand what they are
trying to do all I need to do is I just
need to know the next jump that they
have very similar to how we have it for
the assembly language as well right we
just go through each assembly language
we know which the next jump would be
provided certain conditions have been
met so we try to do the same thing
itself so index protector this was the
the next one that was called and they
had a function that was called from the
malware genome itself so now we know how
to reach out to it right so if you
basically have a
items group that can help you out with
this the next in line was for a premium
SMS malware application so this
particular of malware application itself
would send out SMS to a premium SMS
numbers itself and it will send out
various data it could be right from your
geolocation or whether you are close to
home or close to office all the time
whenever you just leave home so it will
send all of this information back to an
premium number itself and when we looked
at the code itself as you can see we
cannot see where the premium number is
to right because they all are been
encrypted the method names have been
encrypted as well however for each and
every calls that they have they were
importing a file and they were importing
this h h h h dot w h HW of that
particular class name itself had that
logic of how to decrypt the string or
the function calls so now for us the
next step would be just to jump to jump
into that call itself right and that's
exactly what we did
jumped into it and we saw that they're
basically passing three different
arguments to it they are passing a
string that needs to be decrypted
they're passing a number and they are
passing another character and the
function if you further inspect the
function itself they're doing three
things they are doing an and all or
based on the number of numbers that have
been passed in the middle argument the
second argument and and they're
decrypting based on that so we mimics
that entire call function itself into a
Python code and we said okay let's just
do this all the encrypted functions that
we have or the string just pass it to
this particular function call there are
four different results that it will have
and one will have a human readable code
so if if we get one human readable code
itself we know that it's that's the
logic that they use to decrypt the
string so without even understanding the
entire logic itself without even
spending a lot of time into how they are
trying to do it we basically just mimic
that code and now we are able to extract
all the code from the now that becomes
very easy for us to like read the code
through right at that given point so
that
another instance where you have in file
encryption mechanisms to to pull the
data out
now the second hardening technology
technique that we have seen is called
Packer a packer would basically encrypt
a section of the code and it will keep
that in the memory if all the conditions
are met then it will decrypt that data
and pull that information from there it
could be malicious content or in many
different companies that's been used to
like you it's used as a secure storage
of the data or where the IP is very
important they use Packer to encrypt
that data itself so in case of Packer
they are doing it in three different
ways
there's the dynamic code modification
where you're modifying the code itself
on the fly based on the certain
conditions whether they are met or not
then you load that file in the memory
itself or in certain cases within your
data drive or there could be an envelope
conceptually this is how it works you
basically have a APK file which is
before signing it you upload that on a
website somewhere and it will modify
your manifest file and it will modify
your classes dot text which is which has
all the logic around how it actually how
the code would actually work and it will
give you a new classes file which is
called a stop that
so the first Avenue of calling an apk
itself is that it will go to the
manifest file it will look at where that
stub has been loaded it will load that
stuff in the memory first look for all
the conditions whether it's satisfied or
not if the conditions have been
satisfied then it will load then the
main classes dot Dex that was written by
the malicious author so the first in the
example that we have was released out in
December 2017 and this was a packer
called jum j2 I'm just making up the
name at this given point itself I don't
know the name of the Packer but we've
found this one where
the the class name and the header size
if you look at it's normally close to
forty six or sixty two bits right and
this was close to one hundred and thirty
six kilobytes so that's that's like a
huge chunk of data right so we started
inspecting why exactly does it stores
that huge of a file and it was dumping
that from our header bytes as well it
turns out that they were storing the
classes by classes.dex the malicious
classes dot next in clear inside the
header files itself so now the next step
would be just to dump that file store
that as a class s dot text and D compile
it right and that that's what we did and
we were able to extract all the files so
security through obscurity itself but at
least we were able to pull the data out
without doing without installing it on
any phones or doing a lot of analysis
around it the second is more dynamic in
nature
it's called outcry infiltrate again we
are not very sure on the file name
itself all of these names are named
based on the class files it loads so as
I stated before the first step in the
process is to modify the manifest right
and the first injection point that you
have for Android is your application tag
so that's exactly what we did we looked
at the application tag itself and it
turns out that they're calling the one
that is highlighted it's calling Android
support multi decks and multi decks
application itself the multi text
application that it's calling has the
call for the stub now again another
classic case of security to obscure
security they are making it sound like
this is an Android SDK that they have
downloaded that was in the case this
particular file that they have is
actually something that they embedded
along with the Android SDK itself that
has the call for the stop as a result of
that if you so we went to Android sorry
multi decks application file itself and
we saw that it's it it's calling out cry
it's calling out cry with a hash to
decrypt the data the one that is
highlighted below
so like any sane person we followed the
trail and we said we let just go to the
load library that they have and the
infiltrate call itself basically uses
that as a hash and it's sense to a
dynamically loaded library called second
hand the second hand again does all the
checks and balances to make sure that
it's running on a secure environment
itself it's not running on a rooted
device it doesn't have the anti
debugging check itself and in order to
decrypt that classes dot text it
provides you with that hash that hash
was the key to decrypt that data so we
created all the knobs for for all the
different conditions that we have for
route detection checks or anti debugging
checks itself and then you are left with
the files and how to decode to decrypt
it right so we found an easy avenue of
it we patched the the secondhand dot so
library that they had and then we
finally ditch out to the main classes
dot text that was loaded in the memory
itself and we said rather than you
loading in the memory itself store it
here so that we can grab it so we
grabbed the classes tour decks from
there itself and once we had it we just
decompile it and we just get the code
and the malicious code right there right
so that's the second one that we saw
from a packer standpoint the third in
the list was called Vicky this is
another one that was encrypting SD card
so it will encrypt your eyes take heart
itself and the logic of encrypting the
SD card was within the file itself so we
used the same process we looked at the
manifest file first we saw where the
injection of that stub actually is and
we found that the injection of the stub
was at a VG application which is
extending the Android Zac application at
this given point and it was calling to
different so files the first so file was
to make sure that it's checking for all
the different conditions that we talked
about before and the second one what was
a wrapper that would basically decrypt
your data so we said we can use the same
techniques that we used for outcry where
we bypass all the different conditions
to check whether the files have been
validated or not and then we use the D
corruption key to decrypt the classes or
tax but the interesting thing was there
was no code to decrypt that data so as
you can see there's no hash function so
if I go to the previous slides itself
this particular function was calling the
load file along with a decryption key so
that was the decryption key right there
right so conditions satisfied used this
decryption key to dump your classes or
text in Vicky sorry I'm going the wrong
way
so in case of Vicky itself there was no
decryption key at this given point so
and we said bye if we'd run the elf hook
dot so obviously the conditions would
not be met so we would never be able to
get the decryption key but they were
doing one interesting thing what they
were doing at any given point itself was
they were storing the file the classes
dot txt in files folder and during the
course of the application whenever you
are running it it will stay there and
when you run the application again so
when you read on to the application
against the cell it'll delete that file
again and then recreate it so we said ok
let us learn this application on and run
non-rooted phone itself do a adp backup
which does a backup of the files folder
let's just take that file folder out
there would be a classes dot for classes
dot decks in the files folder itself we
can use the same decompilation
techniques that we know of to get the
real java code that has the malicious
code and that's exactly what we did and
we were able to get their classes text
the malicious classes.dex so if so there
are avenues like this that basically
helps us out pull that information from
there so the last and the hardening
techniques that we have is called
protector protector is basically a
combination of both a packer and an
office keishon so it uses the encryption
of classes dot X and it also offers
gates the logic of how you can reach out
to the stub itself so as we saw in the
office kitchen itself it makes very
difficult for us to like read the code
it's of many different ways so that's
exactly what happened with us
so this is how it works under the hood
you have the same techniques that you
have for packing exactly the same
process the only distinction that they
have is that they have obfuscated that
stop and how they are calling it so now
we come back to the ex protector we
looked at it from when we are looking at
office creation itself and we use the
same techniques that we used for Packer
to decrypt that data so the first thing
that we did was we identified the
application and where it's been called
so we identified that it's calling comm
android GMS comm API application and we
know this for sure that it's security
through obscurity they're just injecting
their code in the android sdk that they
call etcetera Android STK kind of thing
right so we did that and now we know how
to decompile so the d office gate in a
way the code that is already office
gated right so we did that and we do
office gate at that code and we
identified two variables we said okay
they're calling this load library itself
very similar to how they're doing it for
Packer and after that the next step that
they call is a different file so we said
okay skip the first two steps where
you're doing the validation part of it
and lightly come to the third part where
you're basically launching that
malicious content and and that's how we
were able to identify what that
application is trying to do by running
it on a device by doing this particular
control by doing this particular check
itself we identified that there is an
malware called TZ which was impacting
Android users and in fact Google came up
with the finding itself in August or
September of last year so that's various
techniques that we have seen from a
militia standpoint itself
so the the poppyseed project that we
have has identified 46 such different
office caters Parker's or protectors and
as you can see each and every protector
is treated differently right or the
office caters or the Harding
technologies are treated differently and
we are creating use by use Python
scripts
can be injected so the first face that
we have within our project itself is to
do a discovery phase of it
so after discovering or rather after
discovering itself we identify whether
they are using an office cater protector
or a packer once we have identified
through that itself once you do the
discovery then you call that particular
files that we have created for for the
office cating decoder so a good example
of that is let's say for TZ application
they're using Dex protector by now that
we know that they're using Dex
protectorates off we now know techniques
of how we can do office get the code to
make it more human readable and now we
know how to decrypt the data as well
right so we use that logic in a Python
code so that you can decrypt that data
completely and understand what genomes
are they're using so during our during
the the start of the call it's the
presentation itself we talked about
various samples right and that's where
the samples are so important for us by
identifying all of the samples itself we
were able to find 456 different Android
genomes that are being implemented in an
application at this given point so he
said that's awesome but how is that
beneficial for all of us right so we are
going to create a static engine for the
same so that they can do a static
analysis for you and after that the next
process is to is to scan the entire Play
Store all the places that are out there
and identify this malicious content
itself and reported to Google so that
they can do the right thing after that
so that's all from an Android standpoint
itself there interestingly enough there
is an IOT application that we all must
have heard about for sure and we are
looking at the security posture of it
and interestingly enough we found that
they're sending sensitive information
from our home devices itself to a
particular server and again we haven't
inspected a lot in it it was just day
before yesterday that we found it so
maybe we will have some more details
soon but as you can see is basically
calling home with the username the port
the password and it basically sends out
your information a user information
about certain activities that we're
doing at any given point so once we have
and we have done the inspection around
it I'm happy to release it out so that
we all can understand the security
posture of it so that being said time
for questions I want to open up the
floors for for what we have seen so far
or any observations or any feedback that
you have though so I'm curious about the
obfuscation tools are their makers on
the black market building these and
evolving them and selling them so from
an office Gatien standpoint it's a we
haven't seen anything off someone
creating it but for backers We certainly
have liked the outcry that we saw or the
jp2 that we looked at those were created
by a black market for sure for office
keishon they're using off-the-shelf
product at this given point we have seen
decks card we have seen decks protector
there is a guard guard square one of the
vendors that we have we have seen that
you been used for malicious contents as
well but we haven't seen any new thing
from an obfuscation standpoint coming
out yeah from the obfuscation point of
view like there are different levels are
there like one two three four so the one
that you have tested is it like level
one or which level is it or if I am
using the highest level I'll be more
secured so I'm not sure what different
levels are but there are different
techniques that you have for office
keishon like you have class name office
keishon which is like the bare minimum
that ProGuard provides you but there are
class name encryptions there API hiding
there is java reflections so what we
have looked at is like a combination of
all of them used together yeah because
when I was doing office questions so
there is like easy or medium a very
strict or very high level there is so I
just want to know like which level you
have done
so if I'm if I do like very highest
level then will I be secured
I see so as I stated before I'm not very
sure about the different levels itself
we have seen two different things we
have looked at all of different features
being used from an encryption from an
obfuscation standpoint and there's
iterations so he can do it one time or
you can do it 50 times or you can do 600
times and it will office Kate based on
that right so that's all that I have
seen so I'm not sure how to map that to
the level one or level four that you
talked about I try to office get it and
then I try to analyze how it is doing it
is it like similar that kind of research
if we do it or a period of time would I
be able to know like how they do it so
true we can certainly do that so from
our engagement standpoint is what we try
to do the same thing with text cards
because we are not able to crack decks
card at this given point itself so we
wanted to know how exactly are they
trying to do it and we used right from
one round to like 600 rounds to
understand how the code would change
based on that so yeah that that's part
and parcel of the research as well thank
you I was just wondering if the level of
obfuscation be an indicator of high
probability for containing malware true
so it's actually not even we the apps
that we use on a regular basis as well
they do office Kate it so anything that
has like an algorithm or an IP that they
want to protect they would normally
would go for office caissons they also
so there are few companies that I know
of which are also using white box
cryptography to just give you a secure
container as well and they all are legit
applications so that should not be the
parameter of like assessing whether it's
a malware or not is there any tool to
compute level of obfuscation so out of
the box a lot of applications do that so
as I stated before techs card for
example gives you avenues of how many
times you want to office Kate it so that
kind of has a level of difficulty
associated with it there is few others
that we talk to as well
that provides you with the same option
as well but can you measure it like we
can get a certain pile court
once you have compiled the application
itself it's very difficult for us to
measure it from a security research
standpoint it's off but if you are
developer then you can certainly have
quantification around it how many of
these applications are actually using
white box cryptography and have you had
success in you know attacking these
implementations so in last year itself
we saw three different applications
using white box cryptography they all
were under the ransomware category
itself and they are trying to implement
their own white box cryptography in many
different ways which is making it little
easier for us to like understand what
they are trying to do but I'm very sure
it will get sophisticated as we go along
awesome so that's all that I had thank
you all for attending
[Music]