[Music]
so this is my first dog actually talking
about this stuff I did a small sneak
peek of what I'm gonna be talking to you
here at Def Con last year and I plan to
do it a lot more larger stage this year
as well in you know in different ways
with different tools so first of all let
me give you a quick introduction of
myself my name is AB hi I work for a
company called we 45 where an
application security company I started
off in PCI compliance I also wrote a
book about it then I kind of moved
towards application security entirely I
fell in love with application security
did a lot of pen testing then I realized
that obviously pen testing needed to
evolve a little bit more so we I got
heavily into dev psych ops which is
essentially how do we achieve better
application security outcomes in a
continuous delivery pipeline how do we
ensure that as companies are as
organizations are going at rapid scale
or deploying very quickly how do we
ensure that security is part of each and
every deployment or each and every
release that they do so that's that's
been my chief aim for the last two and a
half years I also developed a product
called orchestron which is a correlation
and orchestration tool I speak at a
bunch of conferences do a bunch of
training that's a quick introduction of
me I got a lot of demos today as you can
see and one of the things with demos is
that they seldom work so I am just
praying to the demo gods to make sure
that all my demos work perfectly fine
today I have two or three demos and some
of these demos were a little but we are
till this morning so I'm just hoping
that they go OK right now so just before
I start so don't don't blame me if
something goes wrong I've tried my best
alright so today I'm going to be talking
a little bit about deficit ops in the
sense that I don't think I need to sell
you on dev psych ops anymore right
pretty much everybody in this conference
is aware of DevOps is aware of them
to a certain extent even if you're doing
it or not doing it you're aware
something called FC cops and you're
aware that it has a lot of value for
your own organization for your own
product whatever right so I'm not gonna
sell you on dev checkups but I'm gonna
talk about a few key issues that we keep
facing with deficit cops as well so just
as we had issues previously where
application security was not moving with
the pipeline application security of not
keeping up now we're having a different
set of issues so in many cases I've seen
these issues and they've become pretty
pernicious issues I'm going to talk
about these challenges and then then I'm
going to try and give you a solution to
these challenges in the sense that it's
not obviously a silver bullet solution
but I'm going to introduce something
called the robot framework so I'm going
to talk about why I believe it's so
great that this framework exists it's an
open source framework all of you can use
it in fact I've built a bunch of API
that you guys can fork on github and use
it as well
so I'll talk about the recipe part of
this in a little bit and then end with
some examples and demos so if you look
at any security in DevOps pipeline it
kind of looks like this right so you
typically have all of these different
security checks that you're doing in the
pipeline or you should be doing in the
pipeline you start off with threat
modeling then you have sassed and source
composition scanning you have vast I
asked in obviously in configuration just
you before you deploy you do a bunch of
security checks and then once you deploy
you have your monitoring kick in your
threat intelligence threat detection so
on and so forth you're logging so on and
so forth that kicks in so this is great
and a lot of organizations have taken to
this over the last two years very well
some of them better than others so
that's why we started doing security at
different stages in the pipeline
different stages in urs DLC so we have
threat modeling we have sass we have we
have a bunch of process obviously
different organizations do it
differently but this is sort of broadly
how most organizations do it at least if
they're trying to do things in a
pipeline this is great right so
everything is great so what we're doing
is at least trying to find and fix
security bugs as early in the lifecycle
as possible that's something we want to
do because before
goes to production we want to be able to
identify security issues react on
security issues and at least solve as
many as possible we also want security
to integrate with your sdlc so if you
are doing agile or whatever version of
agile or souped-up agile that you're
doing you want it to integrate with it
and obviously you want security to work
seamlessly with your continuous delivery
pipeline so if you have a CI pipeline
you want your security tools to run as
part of that CI pipeline give you some
results at the end of the day some of
its good some of its bad but it really
depends a lot of organizations have
started at least working towards this
goal if not being complete compliance
with it but then security folks are like
this this is what security folks say
when they're presented with something
like this and how many of you are a part
of an application security team within
the organization how many of you feel
there are enough application security
folks in your team ok only one you are a
rare exception but most places you would
see that there is a massive shortage of
application security teams right wrong
application security folks within the
team so recently I was speaking to this
company which had 50 agile teams and
they had two application security folks
so which means that it you tend to get
very quickly overwhelmed with the amount
of work and the applicants security with
you need to test continuously for
security that's going to be a really
really big problem right so so let's
let's get real let's look at some of the
key issues that I've seen with abstract
teams and some of you might you know
might relate to this as well we have
some very serious issues let's talk
about some of the serious issues that
we're facing especially when it comes to
all this sounds great when you're
talking about pipelines and automating
stuff in the pipeline and making sure
that your - your SAS your scanners all
of it runs very nicely within the
pipeline smoothly within the pipeline
what we have some major issues right now
application security tends to get
overwhelmed very quickly simply for the
reasons I stated before right because an
application security team is usually a
small group and yes they're they've got
great skills they've got a lot of
periods they do great jobs at pentesting
but they get quickly overwhelmed simply
because you have to do all that you will
doing as a gatekeeper process
continuously across all your products
life cycles so let's say you have five
products you have one application
security team that is working with all
five products to make sure that they get
released on time and they're
continuously released so you have a lot
of these deployments happening
continuously you have security reviews
your threat modeling you have to triage
bug bounty results as well a lot of
application security teams today are
spending a lot of time triaging bug
bounty results and saying ok this is
real this is not this is just some
random you know junk that we've received
but this is really a high-value finding
all of these things are happening and
application security is at the epicenter
of many of these issues so security
assessments just to name a few
so you really have a lot of tasks that
used to be you know once in a gateway
yes that was a different problem but now
you have it continuously and a lot of
application security teams aren't able
to scale with that and you're finding
that and especially with the shortage of
talent I'm sure all of you know this
that application security teams are not
able to scale they're getting quickly
overwhelmed by a lot of this stuff
automating application security is
challenging as well right now has any
one of you try to automate some tools
like any tools with an API you'd see
that different tools have different
challenges right if you work with zap
you have one set of challenges you work
with Bob or you work with some other
tool X Y Z you have different sets of
challenges you really have yes these
tools do a great job when you are a
manual pen tester you're working with
these tools or these tools were great
job in one sphere or in one type of a
check that they do or one set of checks
that they do so you really have a lot of
tools that you need to automate and you
need to get working in the pipeline and
some of this is a little complex so for
instance I don't know I mean if you have
dealt with you know some of these tools
API some of that is not very well
documented some of it is very well
documented but doesn't work quite as
what they've described in the document
some of it doesn't work with your
platform some of it does not work with
you know
with a bunch of things so you really
need to kind of scrounge around on the
internet try and figure out okay this
works this works this is somehow not
working so let me ask a question and
then comes back a lot of time later so
application security automation is not
as easy as you think
yes in some tools they made it easier
but in some products they made it more
difficult the other problem is with
custom security flaws right now yes your
zap your burpee are all of these tools
they find some great flowers sequel
injection xsrf or SS RF for XML external
entities they find a lot of these great
security flaws but let us say you have
this custom authorization button or
which is essentially an ID or bug or
some other kind of bug which is very
very specific to your business logic to
our platform to our application then
these are not really in there right and
these are also pretty important so you
have all of these things coming from bug
bounties or from internal pen tests or
external pen tests and they essentially
become PDF reports or JIRA tickets that
may or may not get solved depending upon
what kind of engineering team you have
so custom security flaws are hard to
weave into a fabric especially because
these tools do their thing but custom
security flaws are still not
incorporated into that common fabric of
security automation so in short we are
essentially looking at this right so we
have application delivery which is going
at a really rapid pace and we have
application security constantly trying
to catch up so yes previously we were
not being I mean we were trying to catch
up in a different way but now we're
doing different things to try and catch
up so we're still kind of short on this
so let's look at what do we need so
let's look at some of the potential
solutions for what we need to solve some
of these problems yes obviously I'm not
saying I have all solutions but
definitely some of these solutions we
can tackle today so let's talk about
these three things Engineering run
localized security and engagement with
security teams and QA teams and I'll
talk about make security a first-class
citizen and I'll talk about how to do
that so ideally you want your
application security teams focused on
finding the really more complex big
stuff right in the sense that if you
have security tools that can take care
of all the low-hanging fruit you really
want there are security teams focused on
finding that big crypto flaw or that big
authorization flood that thing that
coming comes up from your bug bounty
which is you know P one kind of a flower
something major so you really want your
pen testing teams to find more complex
flaws and instead of taking those
complex flowers writing up PDF reports
and sending it over convert them into
security regression scripts right so I
would be great right just imagine if you
could create a security regression
script that would run the same way and
then hand it over or run it as part of
your CI or give it to your developer and
say run this if this script still works
that means you're not fixed the bug if
the script has not worked then you fix
the bug so it means that you have some
kind of a regression capability and get
engineering involved in application
security automation now this is easier
than it sounds because engineering
already has a large set of tasks that
they need to do so let's let's see how
we can do this the other thing that I
feel we should also be doing is get QA
or quality engineering involved and that
I think was discussed in this morning in
the keynote as well that QA it does a
lot of automation already right now if
you have a QA team they're probably
doing a lot of selenium they're probably
doing a lot of software test automation
they're running a bunch of tools and
they're there they already have some
great expertise with automation
unfortunately security teams do not
leverage this capability a lot of times
security teams kind of just sideline
adoro they don't even think about this
is I don't see that these two processes
kind of meet in the middle so it would
be great if we could kind of get them on
board simply because if we get them on
board you are increasing your
capabilities at the same time you are
making it a part of the engineering
process because right now security is
seen as a kind of a separate process in
itself by engaging with QA and quality
engineering we can make them part of
that same security test process that
would be there so it would be great
it would be even better if we give them
like a single fabric in the sense that
oh I don't have to run this script for
this tool I don't have to run this
script I can run everything as part of
the same framework or as part of the
same you know as part of the same fabric
so you look at the test frameworks out
there you have a bunch of them right
you have selenium you have of course
these are extensions many of these are
extensions of selenium
except maybe puppeteer which is a Google
Chrome specific test automation
framework you really have a lot of these
frameworks that your QA teams are using
and some of these frameworks are a
little hard to understand especially for
security folks because you are focused
on different things some of these
frameworks are easy to understand but
you really have a lot of frameworks
today so I want to introduce a framework
that essentially would try and create
this single fabric so what I'm trying to
say is you run software test automation
and security testing on a single
framework on the same fabric weave it
into the same fabric so ideally speaking
create test Suites that combine the
capabilities of test automation which is
your selenium or any other test
automation tools that you have with
security testing tools so just imagine
being able to run your selenium script
with Zapp which a lot of organizations
are already doing but in a much more
simplified in a much more easy to scale
way right to provide coverage and use
spent test results as security
regulation so ideally what we want to do
is create repeatable and reproducible
you know automation that can be you used
by engineering teams so essentially
create canned recipes right so we create
a canned recipe that we can use to just
run again and again and again and it
will try and find as many flaws as it
possibly can so that's where I ran
across robot framework and in fact how
many of you've used robot framework here
before nobody it's it's great you should
definitely consider using this now robot
framework is a generic acceptance
test-driven development framework a TDD
framework and I'll get into that in a
little bit now the way it works is that
you have a
library which is essentially compatible
with the robot framework and you have
keywords and all you need to do is
invoke those keywords in a simple line
of English something like run zap on is
a keyword
so our nmap scan is a keyword so all of
this these complex tasks of running zap
active scan or spy during a site or
doing XYZ that you do in a security test
is typically broken down into simplistic
keywords and you have a libraries for
Python and Java and it's pretty modular
I'll get into it you'll you'll see a
bunch of demos as well that I'm gonna be
talking about so a TDD it's not really
important but I'm just giving you a
quick example of what an 80-degree is
essentially you write an acceptance test
before you write code that's what a TDD
is you write an acceptance test then you
write code and you test your code
against that acceptance test so a TDD
frameworks you do have many of you
probably heard of BDD which is the more
popular one because it has a very
specific set of syntaxes syntactical
annotations what a TDD is is quite
useful but what we are doing today is
not really going to focus too much on
this it's going to focus on what this
framework can do from that perspective
so the way robot works is essentially
you have your test libraries that robot
runs and then you have your test suite
so essentially what robot does is that
it converts all these functions in your
test library into key words and you can
run these keywords so for instance I
have a keyword called
start zap that means it would
essentially start the app in a headless
mode or GUI mode and then I say spider
run zap spider on this particular target
now the reason that this is so powerful
is simply because you don't need the
lower line of code in order to actually
do this you don't at least the barriers
that you need to run for this is very
very low you just need to know those
keywords or you can find these keywords
and you can just run these keywords as
part of your fabric of security testing
right so and it automatically gives you
results in both HTML and XML it gives
you all the artifacts that are required
it gives you a pass/fail status of
whether this test ran did not run all
that stuff I'll get to that in a
so why we like it essentially it's
simple syntax right this can be given to
anybody and they can figure it out very
quickly and that's great simply because
you can give it to your quality teams
you can give it to our engineering teams
and say just run this if you want to
invoke it just use this keyword you're
gonna be invoking security that's right
out the gate so it's pretty simple right
easy to develop the API it's modular it
comes with reporting out of the box so
it gives you a nice HTML report out of
the box you don't really need to do
anything much for it you don't need to
write the reporting model on your it
gives you right out of the box it also
gives you a base Lee it supports two
very popular languages that a lot of
security tools have support for so
Python in Java a lot of security tools
have support for these two platforms so
it's great to use this so for instance
this is an example of a robot test case
right now this as you can see is not
come this is selenium by the way now if
you know selenium of you have written
selenium code you would realize that
selenium you need to invoke a lot of
functions to do all of this stuff but
here you are essentially expressing this
as natural language syntax you're saying
input text email in with this particular
class ID or this particular name of that
particular parameter input password
password this particular password click
button submit wait and make sure that
the location is dashboard that's it so
it really comes down to breaking down
these complex otherwise complex test
cases that were code into simple easily
understood syntax that you can use for
your own testing efforts and you have a
bunch of libraries already you have
selenium your RPM your SSH Android and
iOS automation they already have
third-party libraries for all of these
different products so let's say you're
testing a web service you can directly
use the Python request module out of the
box for the for you know running
parameterization on the web service diff
liable appium in selenium and so on I'm
going to quickly get into a demo of this
and show you how it works
and then come back to the slides so
let's look at one one of the robot
scripts that I have of going to oh yeah
so this is one of the robot scripts that
I've written for an API so I have this
really simple API that just invokes some
customer functions just so what I've
done is broken down each of these things
each of these operations into test cases
so what I've done first is say
authenticate to the web service then get
customer buy ID get request this
particular API slash - so that would
give me one customer ID with these
headers right and then I say post
customer ID then I start running zap so
as you can see what we're trying to use
is a single fabric we're not separating
the zap and the selenium bit our zap and
the functional test automation bit so
what we're doing is essentially running
the functional test automation with zap
as the proxy and we are proxying all
this traffic through zap and once that
the test automation is done we run zap
against the target and we get our
results the good thing about this is
that you don't need to have two three
different things that you're dealing
with you're just dealing with one script
so what we're doing here is we're
essentially running all these test cases
when we finish running all the
automation bits we start running zap we
run the active scan on zap once the
active scan is run we generate a report
and we kill both processes that's really
as simple as this so and zap if you look
at the the Waze app is invoked it just
says app start scan so it's really not
that complicated for anyone on an
engineering team to be able to figure
this out so all you have to do is just
invoke to three different specific
keywords and they are up and running
ready to go right so let me just go back
to the presentation and then run the
demo
so the QuickStart is essentially you
have variables you have test Suites you
have keywords I already mentioned the
keywords and you saw some of the
keywords you can import a bunch of
libraries as well so let us say you have
a generic Java library or a Python
liability that we want to use you can
import it into that particular script
and start using it if it has a robot
framework integration already what we
have done already is these two are ready
to use and they're on github you can
download and use it
zap integration is called robos app I've
also written an in map integration
called Robo and map you can start using
this right out of the box you can just
download it runs app with it and you
have all the documentation burp suite
I'm almost done I should be done very
soon web suite
sometimes is a little cantankerous when
it comes to Jatin API but it's it's
almost done I've we've almost finished a
sub lister integration as well for our
directory brute-forcing so let us say
you want your a pentester you want to
run a bunch of automation and then only
focus on the big stuff you can run all
these tools as part of a pen test
pipeline of salts and then you know run
your custom stuff do your manual pen
testing so that you save a lot of time
instead of running all these tools one
after the other so you can just run that
as part of one fabric now the future I
want to definitely work on stuff like
this which is the dependency check or
acne and some of the other tools so this
is this where I am with these API so
some of the use cases obviously is
getting engineering teams to run their
own security testing lower the anti
barrier for security testing is what I
definitely want to achieve at the end of
this let me just run a quick demo for
you guys and then come back to the
slides so this is the robot script that
I have written that would essentially
run some functions on the web service
obviously we know that with web services
you can't use a spider with any
traditional scanner you can't use a
spider you can't do any of that so you
kind of have to run through the
parameters specifically one after the
other so let me just run this so what
this is going to do is going to run
those it's gonna authenticate to the web
service it's going to call invoke a few
functions
and kickoffs app to run an active scan
and you'll see the app it's I've
configured it to work on the GUI mode
but you can run this headless lis as
well and then once app runs it's gonna
write the results to a JSON file that's
simple right so let's just run this and
you'll see how it works
so it starts zap and zap is running on
another desktop that sucks just give me
a minute
yeah so yeah this is the app and I'm
gonna just bring this in as well
probably just going to reduce it so the
app is started up and now all the
traffic as you can see is being proxied
through SAP so I'm logging in and I'm
calling three or four different
functions and once I'm done with this I
create a context with zap and zap is
going to start an active scan very soon
so it's gonna start an active scan and
you can see that each of these steps are
represented as modular entities here so
you can see that get customer ID I've
done all of these different functions
contact clear does app context run an
active scan once the active scan is done
it's going to write the report and shut
it down that's it
so with this your actual automation is
pretty much done right so you really
have you've lowered the entry barrier
for your QA teams to get into security
testing simply because you've been able
to give them a repeatable process and in
fact robot framework if you ask your Qi
teams that you'll be surprised to know
that a lot of people are already using
this because it's heavily used in the
test automation world but unfortunately
in the security world it's very
little-known so it's it's pretty easy to
get started with something like this and
obviously by providing them a simple API
all they have to do yes right right now
this gives them a report so this gives
them a JSON report so let me just try
and pull that up so this would be the so
generates a report at the end of the
script so as you can see here this is
the report that it generates generates a
JSON report for the tests it ran at this
time and it just gives you all the
details of that right now but you can
use you can use it however you want you
can send it off as an email or you want
this to be triage by the security team
to remove false positives or whatever it
is all of these flows can be worked out
but typically right now the API is that
I've implemented either write it to our
product which is the correlation tool or
just generate a JSON file which you can
use you can slice and dice and use it
how you will write so so really if you
look at the security use cases there are
quite a few use cases that I would go
with one definitely to empower
engineering teams to run their own
security tests simply because
engineering teams you don't want them
coming to you for everything
ideally that's what you want them to do
right have their own security practice
run a set of security things by
themselves and then obviously for more
specific more value-added type of
services approach your application
security team or your security group
functional test automation can be so in
fact this was an interesting story we
were able to convert a selenium script
for a pretty massive product to robot
within two and a half hours which means
that the ability to scale with this is
pretty easy so let's take a massive
selenium script you just convert all of
that over to robot because robot has the
same selenium API so it just has
keywords for those selenium scripts and
you can just convert that into robot
framework pretty easily for pen testers
it's great because you can kind of
automate all that low-hanging stuff
right okay I'm going to run this I'm
gonna run nmap I'm gonna run sub lister
I'm gonna run the app I'm gonna run Bob
and only after that I'm going to look at
the product so if the if the pentester
gets a test automation script from the
QA team all the pen tester has to do is
to run all of this stuff and only start
to look at the more specific more
critical flaws in that particular
environment so the idea is to break down
all of this stuff that used to be a
friction driving process and make it
something like this which is very easy
very simple very intuitive for people to
understand right so yeah so let's look
at some of the use cases and patterns
and I'll run you through another demo
and a little bit as well so automated
print test activity is creating a pen
test pipeline so one of the visions that
I had for this when I started off with
this was for our own internal team one
that was running pen test was that you
know what guys instead of running all of
these tools manually why don't you have
you know test automation script run it
through robot and therefore you actually
run it through all the different tools
you would otherwise use in a pen test
and then write them back for you to see
what it found what kind of security
issues it form what kind of flaws it
found and essentially creating a
pipeline so you can run nmap find all
the port scan results and the
vulnerability scan results from nap in
fact we even wrote a neces integration
at the time when message use to have an
API and we used to actually automate
that whole process of running messes
then we used to run a directory brute
force tool runs app run Bob and then
come out with the results so we had all
of these results in a database that we
could triage and then figure out what
were the security issues that we
actually found so creating some sort of
a pen test pipeline kind of enhancing
the capabilities of security teams the
other thing that we also have been using
this for is parametrized application
security testing right now one of the
things that I'm sure some of you will
know is that with security tools like
Zappa burp or any of these other tools
one of the big challenges you have is
doing authenticated scanning especially
against Web Services or single page apps
all of these different products which
are not easily Spy durable you don't
have spiders that can do a very good job
of this so ideally what we did was use
selenium scripts or
other test automation scripts use that
as input for these scanners these
scanners capture all that proxy all of
that traffic and then you you run your
security tests after that so that's
another use case and obviously one of
the other things that we also started
using this far was let's say your pen
tester finds an amazing authorization
flaw that is very specific to your app
to your environment or to your
particular business logic instead of
showing that as a bunch of screenshots
convert that into a robot script though
and run it and say this passed this
failed great right you can get much more
immediate feedback from that particular
process in a much more easy way so now
this is a pen test pipeline so for
instance this is what I'm talking about
so run nmap first print the results run
zap get the results and you're done so
you have some of these patterns that you
can merge so let me just show you a
quick demo of this as well and I don't
have too much time so I'm going to kind
of run through this demo so this is
actually if you look at the script and
I'll show you the script as well is a
yeah this is selenium script what I did
now was just a web service it ran some
web service request with an HTTP client
but this is actually a selenium script
so what this does is that it runs an
nmap port scan against that particular
vulnerable app it's an intentionally
vulnerable app on my system it runs the
port scan then it starts zap then it
creates a browser in this case I'm using
phantom j/s you can use firefox you can
use chrome in headless in the headless
mode so it starts phantom jeaious which
is by default a headless browser and
then it logs into the application visit
some random pages start Subs app runs
app and terminates the scan after
writing a result so let's just run this
script and show you how that whole
pipeline process works
so this I just need to invoke the script
and it starts with an nmap ports can
obviously I'm not running a very more
powerful and map ports Kay I'm just
running the default then it starts
zap-zap is started up again as you can
see and then it runs all of the other
stuff so it's gonna login its going to
open up the URL pretty soon it's gonna
login to the app very soon and it's
gonna start the active scan very soon
yes it opened up the login URL it's
going to login with those particular
credentials so even if you are testing
single page apps or you know web
services or something a little more
complex that your spider is not going to
be able to ever catch you want to run it
with specific inputs that give you
specific outputs that you can use for a
more efficient more effective scanning
process you can use something like this
because it becomes very easy very easy
to scale and you can give this as a
recipe write it and just put this in the
CI pipeline in Jenkins in fact robot has
a Jenkins plugin so you can just put
this in your Jenkins box and just say
invoke the robot plug-in and say run
this particular script every night
that's it so it becomes a lot more easy
to do so as you can see it's it's still
walking through the app I should have
eliminated the GS but I don't know why I
just spidered everything anyway so so
it's running all of this stuff and it
should now start the active scan as well
so while this is running I'm just going
to finish up the rest of it because it's
going to take a little bit of time so
yeah so you are on that so if one of
these activities fail it would it would
essentially throw a fail and then it
would give you a report with the fail
notification now the reports are pretty
good they look like like so I'm going to
show you how the default report looks
and it's pretty intuitive so this is
what our default report looks like right
so you have all of these different tasks
that I've run and you can see the Zap
scan results if you want I think it it
gives you each of the test keywords that
you've run so each of the keywords has
so if you are logging stuff within the
keyword you can get a detail of all of
the different keywords that you've run
again so you see that it gives me a scan
status and then it's generated a report
so it's generated a report and then it's
killed zap kill the browser etcetera so
it gives you all of these it's it's
pretty useful because you get running
status of what's happening and what's
happened with that particular script you
know whether something is failed let's
say a UI component is changed
you you you limit it your obviously it
would fail it will tell you that this
particular script fail the good thing
with this is that since it's modular
failing of one of these test cases is
not going to result in your entire test
case or your entire script failing so
it's just going to say that okay that
failed but I'm still going to continue
as much as possible and run right
yeah so that's the idea what I
eventually want to do is create a
pipeline of tools that can be used with
robot framework right now Zapp is
something that I already have a bump is
pretty much done I think I just need to
put some final touches on that
Arachne and all of that stuff is still
not done yeah so parameter is the
application security testing so you can
run even your custom scripts so instead
of creating them as PDFs create them as
regression scripts run the entire thing
as part of one single test case or one
single test suite where you say that
okay run all this automation first then
check for these securities
you know these particular security flaws
that have been found by my pen testers
to say okay this authorization fly still
open this crypto fly still you know out
there in the wild whatever so you can
still run the entire set of events so
some questions that I kind of preempted
one
why not BDD BDD was definitely an option
that I was going with but I did not like
BDD so much to be honest I'm sorry if
I'm gonna offend a lot of people in the
room ability restricts you to a syntax
right given this when this happens then
do this now with this you don't you're
not really restricted to any syntax is
just saying call this call that it's
more data-driven whereas behavior BDD is
more behavioral I did not need something
as complex as that I just needed
something simpler so I went with this
all tools easy to integrate it depends
if the tool has good API france's app as
amazing api so it's easier to integrate
yes but typically if they have some kind
of integration point some kind of api
some kind of flat files that you can
work with you can even do something with
that parallel execution is possible so
let us say you want to speed up
execution parallely so let's say you
want to run and map separately wanna run
this separately one of them that
separately you can actually do that
there is a integration to robot called
pay bot the PA b OT pay bot allows you
to run in you know in as a multi-process
kind of thing with parallel execution
the next thing i want to do is run all
of this in darker
something that I'm really working on
because we're darker you really are
achieving all of this without all the
unnecessary dependencies having to be
installed on every single machine so
that's something I'm going with the
future obviously my team and I will be
working a lot on robot framework we've
seen a great deal of value with a lot of
our clients as well and we've been
working on this API I highly encourage
you to go and download some of the stuff
that we've put out definitely happy to
have more people contribute more people
us ideas that we can go obviously be a
part of this whole journey with us with
that thank you very much
I really you've been a great audience
thank you I hope you guys found this
useful yes yes I forgot to put it on
that but yeah you can just go to my
Twitter and you'll find a bunch of
github links tweeted there I can give it
to otherwise it's not on my presentation
sorry any other questions thank you so
much
[Music]