[Music]
hi my name is tae ship and welcome to
security after death so how technical is
my audience really quick on a scale of
one to five how comfortable you are with
technical stuff okay so about half the
audit that's fine
so this whoops wrong way got to push the
right buttons I'm a security auditor I
work for compliance point I've been
doing this for a number of years before
that I was an IT and security and he
commerce and mobile and stuff like that
so I have a lot of different skill sets
and I love to scuba dive so you'll see
some things about that this talk is
dedicated to my best friend Eric Jacobs
who died last March and his widow asked
me to break into his computers because
she needed files that were on his
systems to do stuff specifically
passwords to manage his digital life and
close it down so this is a direct result
of that experience so in the past
[Music]
okay so my clicker here is not working
so just give me a second sorry about
this
so the problem definition that we're
gonna fix is how many passwords do you
have I've gotta turn this off this is
really bad
so in the past when you died your spouse
only needed your a death certificate and
a marriage license and maybe your
mother's maiden name and we're able to
close down all the accounts and manage
everything at the bank and stuff like
that today that's not necessarily true
because there is no way to recover
passwords from like Facebook or Google
or Yahoo and all the dozens of other
digital environments that you currently
have
so the problem space that I see is how
many passwords do you have one show
hands one just one password two
passwords three passwords 10 20 30 50
100 200 4 ok so 400 passwords yeah I'm
about 385 so how do you store these
things that's what we're going to talk
about in the first half and the second
half talk about how to share them and
then a third third part of the talk
we're going to talk about how to recover
from a catastrophic problem so where do
you store your passwords well your brain
it's very safe but like me my brains
like Swiss cheese I forget a lot of
things on sticky notes they get glue
black books files on your computer may
be encrypted files on your computer how
about on your phone well that's really
great now they're with you but you can't
copy/paste your encrypted on a phone
that's horrible because now you have to
type in some big long password to get
something that you can't copy paste so
single passwords it's called super
Federation it's a really bad idea
we'll talk about that in a little bit so
you fix that well you kind of combine
all these things to get the best of all
the worlds and that's called a password
manager and we're going to talk about
that super Federation how many people
have seen these things show up super
convenient they're really dangerous if
somebody cracked your facebook account
they own you
there are better ways to achieve the
same convenience one of them is called
the password manager or password vault
or keyring by multiple names these are
applications that are specifically
designed to hold your digital life
behind a super password that only you
know and then you can use those to
access your digital sites that you're
going to Facebook Twitter Google AWS all
those things not all key rings or
password managers are created the same
lots of features so you really need to
understand your feature set that you
have to have browsers have password
managers built into them they're not
protected by a password and they're not
encrypted in Eric's case that's how he
recovered his digital life he was using
password managers on his browser so I
was able to get all those give them to
his widow and she was able to close down
all the accounts so to find out more
about password managers go to google
search for password managers try them
out before getting one get the free
versions there are a multitude of
functionality in these password managers
you have to figure out what you need
look at the open source products if you
go by a password manager only spend what
you have to because you can update later
all of these password managers have
export functions and import functions so
you can move between password managers
as your requirements change you want to
look at things like good password
randomization force complexity of your
site passwords so uppercase lowercase
all those things password length
automatic rotation if they've got that
functionality ms a multi-factor
authentication support some are
automatic capture and sign-in so you go
to a new web webpage you sign into it
you have to create an account password
manager will in fact in fact grab that
password data and store it and then you
can use it later on for auto submission
there are other systems that support
auto submission and the shells for an
SSH terminal and applications the vault
many of them have choices for algorithm
support maybe you don't want to use
Blowfish you want to use an ASC 256 or
512 if the master master password
expires maybe you want naggy to help you
rotate it on a consistent basis so that
it remains secure some of them have
differences between the admin user and
the user for the site passwords those
things are happening so here's an
example of good randomization in my
password manager that I use so you can
choose the number of characters you can
choose how many digits how many symbols
that you choose in these things these
are really nice so you don't have to
figure out the patterns your human brain
will manifest on a pattern if somebody
figures out your pattern they'll able to
crack your site so use random passwords
if you're not using a multi-factor on
the site twenty characters or more you
don't care how long it is how complex it
is because you're never going to
remember these you're gonna storm your
password manager your password manager
is going to keep them so multi-factor
authentication there's the Google
Authenticator which is a one-time
password it's free it's in this level to
addition to security this level one is
just the password in this level two is
the one-time token generators like the
RSA and the Google Authenticator and
Yubikey is NIST 3 so that's for
high-security sites so think about the
multi-factor authentication systems you
want to use
sharing passwords features that are
necessary in a business it's great for a
home
it allows you to share passwords safely
I use them to share bank passwords with
my wife I've created a group she gets
the bank password if I change the bank
password or she changes it it just goes
into the password manager I don't have
to worry about the update in a business
you have a support team that needs
access to you know remote site you can
have one person control the password
everybody else can just use it those are
things that happen in the password
managers LastPass is an example that has
this kind of functionality they actually
have a feature called use only where the
person who is entering it on the website
can only select it to say insert and it
just fills in the username and password
fields they never actually see the
password in clear text and then the
normal readwrite and use so what
features might you want you might want
to store other things in your password
manager beside your digital credentials
passport IDs driver's license credit
cards pictures PKI keys all these things
should go into your password manager
anything that you consider that you want
to be secret other features tags so you
can group them multiple URLs are handy
if you're going to different sites that
you're using some kind of Federation
maybe like a company internal site you
can do all these things with auto submit
versus wait is really important some
systems have the ability when you choose
it that it will go and insert the
username and password and click the
submit button for you others are
username password and it waits because
you're using a two-factor authentication
system you have to put in the two-factor
system one-time password and then you
have to manually click the submit button
to make it all happen
hack alerts are very nice in 2017 there
were 230 million passwords leaked on
eight sites that were hacked that we
know about in 2016
539 million passwords were leaked as
kind of shocking when I started adding
up all these things so it's very likely
that your password on one of these sites
has been leaking you probably don't know
about it the password managers maintain
publicly disclosed hacks and disclosure
lists and they'll alert you to the fact
that your password has been leaked on a
site so you can change it before the
company does a revocation on your
password and forces you to do it you
need integration into as your AWS handy
things to have other policies IP
restrictions I once set a password
restriction that said you can't use my
password manager for my business if
you're in China you have to be in the
United States or in Canada I assumed
anybody who went to China and we had an
office in China they used it in China
the Chinese army would get my password
to my AWS system and I didn't want to
have that so I just said you can't use
it so the things to think about audit is
a really important thing if you're
running a business repositories where
should your vault live on your local
machine or off in the cloud if so in the
cloud where in the cloud what country
important things to consider or both I
like it that way both local and remote
browser integration you want to make
sure that the browsers that you use
support the password manager that you're
going to integrate with not everybody is
equal there multiple vaults and api's
user management functionality so here
are some open source password managers
key pass has been around for a very long
time I think 2008 2009 as when they came
out they have hundreds of features and
they work on just about every
form known to man it's an open source so
somebody if it's not there somebody
writes a plug-in donates it and then
it's there tons of features some of
these things are very very minimalistic
some of these systems are minimalistic
that you need to deal with so you need
to choose your password manager
carefully commercial systems dash line
LastPass those are ones that I have
experience with I'm not endorsing those
it's just I can tell you if they have
some functionality that's very nice
there's a cost of these the way you read
this data set because it's kind of
complicated is zero dollars for one user
or 40 dollars for multiple sites and
platforms 48 dollars for an enterprise
version of dashlane or you go all the
way down to Zoho for 84 dollars for an
enterprise license so choose the
password manager based on the feature
set pay the price these are all the
features they have and all the platforms
they work on again figure out your
requirements get the password manager
that meets the requirements and then
change if you don't like recovery the
master password so in Eric's case he
never told his password to get into his
computers to his wife and then he died
and that's where I had to break in so if
you become incapacitated how are you
going to deal with how is your spouse or
your executor on your will or your mom
and dad or your significant other gonna
deal with that how are they going to
recover the password to get into your
digital vault we'll talk about that in
the latter this last part of the talk
how should the recovery happen dual
control sometimes you want to have your
master password split between multiple
people you want to force collusion in
this case usually collusion is thinking
of a bad situation
in this case you want collusion so we'll
talk about dual controls and you want to
make it easy for non-technical people
some commercial platforms have password
recovery systems in place dual control
seems to be an issue on the ones that I
reviewed they don't have a duality
requirement so it's just a single person
get your password you know what about
your updates your master password how do
you tell these people you know your
spouse or your who your executor is
gonna be if you change your master
password my master password changes
every month it should remain secret
until that's a really good requirement
in the recovery process and we'll talk
about that and again as I said collusion
should be a requirement you trust a
single person you can trust a single
person these are good for businesses you
tell your boss or your manager or a
lawyer but what if they become
incapacitated now you're kind of in
trouble especially if you're traveling
in the same car and you get hit and both
of you pass away you're now that there's
two clean ups to happen so now you go to
two people so how do you sync those and
how do they come together what happens
if one of them gets incapacitated you
know it's an on and on and on problem so
there's a way to solve this it's called
generic secret sharing excuse me what
you want is a recovery system that
requires multiple people to come
together that have part of your password
to recreate the full password so you
know it's a it's a cooking class that
has to come together and everybody
brings their own little part of the cake
these systems need to be highly
available and they need to be
confidential they're storing sensitive
information typically they store launch
codes bank accounts and
the password to your personal stuff so
all important things we're gonna focus
on one specific sharing scheme called
Sameer secret share there's another one
called Blakely's which I'm not going to
cover today I am gonna give you are ELLs
at the end of this presentation that
will point you to all these things and
you can look up all the math behind them
if you care to do so or more about them
so Sameer secrets share a decent from
RSA Fame publish this solution in 1979
so quite a long time ago basically
you're taking in a polynomial you know
it's like X to the second or plus X to
the third plus X to the fourth to solve
a problem which are points on a graph
which turn out to be parts of the
password you can look at the website
that I'm gonna reference at the end to
really understand this it's the most
efficient algorithm one of those key
factors is that the shard or the share
piece is no longer than the secret
itself which is important for input
control so if you have a 20 character
password the piece that you're gonna
give to your lawyer is gonna be 20
characters long the number of trusts and
the number of shares can be large or
small and we'll talk about that for
instance if you do a two of three scheme
which is two people have to come
together out of three shards you have
three combinations to recover that
password a two of five is a recovery of
ten different ways a 305 is also ten
ways but you need more collusion so it's
a more confidential system so here's an
example of an input of sameer share this
is the site that I referenced I'll give
you the at the end so I type in my
favorite password not really
and I'm doing a two or three split so
I'm ending up with this gobbledygook at
the bottom because the length of this
gobbly gook is equal to the input size
so it's quite large and now I'm gonna
recreate the password so from the
previous page you saw that I did a two
of three so I need two pieces to recover
the password at least two pieces so if I
have just one piece I just get gobbly
gook which means the shard itself
doesn't lead to the password there's
nothing the shard that tells you the
password you need to put two or three
pieces in there so it's very nice
because now you've got multiple people
who know different parts any of them
individually is useless coming together
they recreate your password so here we
do a 1 of 1 this is nice if you just
want to hide the clear text password you
can use the same system to create just
one single shard so the person doesn't
know what the clear text password is
it's just a bunch of gobbledygook for
them to type in
okay
so in this case what I'm doing is I'm
saying I'd like to shares but I only
want one person to come together so it's
a nice way of just splitting the
password what's your scene at the very
bottom of the screen is the passwords
are almost identical except for the
first three characters so it doesn't
really provide differences it's just the
way the the mathematical model works but
now each one of these pieces work as a
password to find your password so it's a
really convenient way to have two person
share with the same password each of
them thinks they have their own secret
but it's really just one password behind
the scene okay so where are you gonna
use these anyplace where you want dual
control so here are all the use cases
that you might want to think about so
we're gonna look at a in a minute we're
gonna look at something here so now what
do you do at the end of this
take a breath
this afternoon go and get a password
manager install it if you don't already
use one pick any one of them put the
repository on the cloud there are a lot
of options there you can put them in
Google you can put them on as your
Dropbox any of the file sharing systems
Microsoft let's save your existing
passwords into them try it out you can
always switch later especially because a
lot of them even the commercial ones
have free trials for one user and then
use the Sameer secret share to create a
recovery path it doesn't have to be very
complicated
so take and write some instructions put
them into a folder use a zip that
creates a encrypted file take that file
and put it on a file share system take
the password use Sameer secret share to
make two of three or three of five
whatever your combinations should be and
share the passwords but give the people
that you're sharing or you're custodians
access to the shared file so something
happens to you and tell them the names
of the other people right so now you've
got a way to recover the master password
should you become incapacitated so in
conclusion I was able to break into
Eric's system and recover the passwords
only because he was using a non secure
password manager I was very lucky I was
very bummed that I lost my best friend
but I was very lucky in that sense so
how do you store passwords securely well
the obvious answer is use a password
manager you should get away from writing
passwords on a piece of paper or trying
to use a pattern all of those things are
breakable password managers are very
easy to use
they're free to share passwords use
groups or different vaults to share your
passwords with people that you have to
share them with for sites not your
master password but your site passwords
and then before you become incapacitated
use Sameer Sheikh secret share to create
a recovery system so if something
happens to you somebody has the ability
to get in there and clean up after you
any questions yeah Richard you know for
the multi-factor yeah can you use to you
be keys associated just in case you lose
one or one the stops functioning most
you be keys have the ability to clone
the certificate data and those are
submitted that those are either outside
the password managers or they're built
into the password managers to clone them
some have that support built in and some
of you just use a tool to clone your
Yubikey you can also have multiple ub
keys control access to different vaults
so you can have you know a low security
of medium security and a high security
and then those things which you just
want to die and take to your grave with
so you know i use to you be keys
so thanks we had one more question over
here and then up to the front okay
yes sir i use the password manager
myself but they make some themselves a
very juicy target because of
centralization of your entire life how
do you recommend limiting the risk if
your entire password manager is
compromised
choose a strong initial secret key so
that it doesn't happen if your if your
entire password manager is corrupt you
know taken and broken at least you know
the site's you have to go and change
very quickly you know you're not going
to forget something the password
managers typically are storing the
passwords in a in a file that is
encrypted with you know a SC 256 or 512
or Blowfish so the work factor to you
know twist those out is pretty high so
you have time if you know that it's been
compromised
the whole idea is you know to choose you
know like use two-factor right that's a
solution use a one-time an OTP like a
Google Authenticator or RSA key or a
Yubikey for access to your password
manager that helps a lot but then just
choose a good strong password along the
way you know 16 characters or 20 and
realize your master password doesn't
have to be completely random it can be a
phrase that you can remember so one
second we've got to get the mic to you
aside from securing your master password
to make sure they can't break into the
overall key management store what kinds
of things should you be looking for in
terms of the security practices of the
password management that's the company
that produces the software for the
password management because there are
various attacks that can disclose
individual site keys or you know once
you're signed into that password manager
other exploits against the browser
extensions etc like that so you know
most of them use JavaScript to be able
to inject things into the fields there
have been exploits found against some of
them
you know there's other possible ways
that I know that some browser makers are
talking about API is in the future to
make a more secure way of dealing with
that instead of exposing through
injected JavaScript just what what are
your thoughts on that part of the
equation so basically the question is
how do you stop some kind of injection
attack on a browser from getting access
to see the site password or you know in
the worst case scenario back into your
password manager there are there's a
there is a project underneath active
development now between Google and I
want to say LastPass to create an API so
that at least on the Android phone
there's a back-channel to get the
passwords instead of going through a
browser I suspect that you're gonna see
something like that on all browsers in
the future for better integration to
specifically stop that exploit but I
don't know what's happening the other
way that I would say to do that on
highly sensitive sites is use a
combination on that site of a one-time
password along with the password that's
in the system because then you have to
crack both you have to crack you know
the password manager you have to inject
and you have to take over the phone or
get you know the one-time password
master system do you know if any of the
password managers support a flag that
says whether or not that password can be
auto-filled versus something that you
have to copy and paste manually yeah
yeah yeah that's the idea that you
basically set it up not to auto submit
and so you can just you know go and
disable the URL so that it doesn't
recognize the site so it doesn't do an
auto-fill and then you can go and copy
you know
the passwords from the system into the
page if you want to do that so that's a
way to achieve those that goal in the
back we'll come back to you in just a
second go ahead all the way back you've
recommended two-factor authentication
for using sites however if you say
disappear and your two-factor
authentication is located on your phone
providing a password and master password
to access your password vault is a
little bit incomplete to access sites
that might be guarded by two-factor how
would you recommend somehow being um
provide - if they are MFA Keys - those
people you've trusted - you're
recovering the case your disappearance
front timely demise I'm sorry I didn't
fully comprehend the question sure so if
I disappear and I have left phone with
me and I provide my password to recover
for those people Duty right there is
they can't access say my Facebook site
which is guarded by two FA with Google
Authenticator on my phone okay how does
one get around that or somehow provide
another entrance for sites that are
protected by two-factor perfect so the
idea is that if you're using a one-time
if you're using Google Authenticator you
have to initialize the Google
Authenticator when you first enroll on
that on the site and there's a gift that
shows up take a screenshot of the gift
put that in the password manager doesn't
that expire once it's used the first
time though no does no no okay that gif
initializes the clock with a random
sequence so that the time and this
random check formed the sixth digit
token and so those never expire I've had
to go through that exact it was a
learning experience I lost my phone I
got stolen actually and my Google
Authenticator was on it I had nine
Google authenticated systems I had to
have another administrator login removed
the two fastener administration and I
had to go through the whole reinitialize
ation process and then
at some point my clock got out of sync
for some reason and one of them stopped
working so I just went through and just
did the reinitialize ation so it was a
learn sequence for me so I can tell you
it absolutely works yes upfront wait for
the mic please how do you apply this
Shamir group because I know I noticed
you just shown that how to generate but
how do you apply it to like keepass or
stuff like that so the the Sameer share
is the recovery process it's not inside
of key paths it's an external process
okay so once you set up your password
manager and you put in you know your
password to access your password manager
let's say it's just password one you
take password one go to the site
generate the two shards share the shards
write some instructions to tell people
this is my access password to my share
to my you know password vault and you're
done so it's not an integrated step it's
an out out-of-bounds step we can take
this offline I'll explain you know any
other questions okay thank you for your
time all these slides you can take a
picture of this slide here if you need
to it has all the relevant information
and I'll leave that up and then this is
on my LinkedIn page and you can just go
there as well as the wasp is publishing
all the slides when they publish the
video take a picture of that page my
LinkedIn will have these slides in about
two hours and you can go and get them
and you're always welcome to email me
and ask me questions about this stuff I
don't have a problem sharing any other
questions we're done enjoy your lunch
thank you very much
[Applause]
[Music]