[Music]
my name is Justin Collins welcome to my
talk thanks for coming you can find me
on the internet at president beef most
places on the internet this is a picture
that I took in California up the coast
somewhere there's no towns nearby so I
don't know how to describe where it is
but I'm very proud that I got the bird
in the picture oh it's not working
well anyways I'm very proud of getting
the bird because I saw it coming and I
like try to take the picture I'm very
proud of that anyways you know they used
to like show like people would get mad
because people invite you over and then
they'd have like a slideshow of their
vacations like no one does that anymore
so I put my vacation pictures in my
presentations so you get to experience
it so today I'm talking about injection
vulnerabilities in general but first
about me I'm this guy over here I
realize this is my eighth year of
application security and right now I
work at Survey Monkey and I also work at
my own company building break man pro so
if you need a static analysis security
tool for Ruby on Rails check out brick
man Pro if you need to take surveys
check out Survey Monkey
so I'm actually like a little bit
nervous about this talk because it's
more of a a thought talk than a nice
concrete talk about things that I'm very
sure about so I hope it goes well and I
did not pick this picture because of
Survey Monkey I I just thought I was a
good thinking picture but maybe it's
like something that just gets stuck in
your brain when you work at a company of
it has monkey in the name anyway so I
looked it up and it is claimed that 1998
is about when people started talking
about sequel injection and it is now
which means it is 20th birthday of
sequel injection yes the interesting
thing about that is it means that it's a
very well understood problem and we also
have a very prescriptive solution to
sequel injection more so than we have
for most other vulnerabilities which
we'll talk about a little bit more but
happy birthday to sequel injection so if
we look at the wasp top 10 and we look
at injection and also cross-site
scripting which I believe is also an
injection vulnerability but more
specific one they both been on the list
since 2004 injections started kind of
low and then it jumped up to number two
and 2009 and then since 2010 it's been
the number one spot so again sequel
injection been known since 1998 it's
been at the top of the a wasp atop 10
for about eight years and then
cross-site scripting is like bounce
around but you put those two together
that's a lot that's 20% movie loss top
10 is essentially injection if we look
at the 2017 new wasp atop 10 this is
what they say about injection and I
couldn't remember what these numbers
mean
so hello cheat sheet so exploitability
easy if you know what's there it's easy
to exploit it in fact search the
internet and you'll get all kinds of
nice payloads and again especially
sequel injection very well understood
and people have thought a lot about it
and written a lot about it
prevalence is middle of the road
according to OS top 10 it's common so
not widespread and not rare but common
detectability easy relatively easy to
find in an application and then the
technical impact is severe so of these
for metrics three of them are the worst
they can be and ones like kind of in the
middle so that that's telling us
something about it and obviously this is
why it's at the top right so let's look
a little bit like prevalence versus
impact i found the hacker one report and
this is information from 2013 through
may 2017 so maybe like about four years
worth of data cross-site scripting is
the most common vulnerability found
which i think most of us would agree
that makes sense and then the more
specific injections down here are not
very common command injections you know
it's really tiny command injection
sequel injection code injection or like
this is by industry like two percent
three percent a little bit scary based
on yesterday's keynote in healthcare
industry six percent the highest of what
they measured so you can't get the
feeling like whoa it's not like super
common cross-site scripting is but other
types of injections aren't really super
common but again it's at the top of the
list right if we look at the book crowd
data this is the 2017 report these are
critical vulnerabilities meaning their
top p1 category this is what makes up
that category and sixty-three percent
were sequel injection so last slide is
like not very common but when it happens
it's bad and cross-site scripting is
number two with 18% because and I think
XSS is often categorized not as a p1 so
sometimes sometimes not and they also
said that sequel injection got the the
highest average payout a little over
$2,000 so you it's not super common but
when it happens it's bad and I think
that probably reaffirms most of our
intuition about it
okay now let's talk about what I see or
what an injection vulnerability is and
this is maybe for some of you like I
know what an injection vulnerability is
this is so we're all on the same page
and you know we're all together on this
so this is I think my definition may be
someone else has said this but is my
succinct definition it's when we have
data that gets interpreted as code we
have values that should be data and data
you should not be executing data but
instead it happens and then we have an
injection vulnerability and that data
could be things like query parameters
values from a form they could be values
that come in as header values files that
are uploaded stuff that comes out of the
database these are all things that
should be data and somehow they get
interpreted as code instead as sequel or
HTML or JavaScript or CSS or basher a
specific programming language that's
when we get an injection vulnerability
and it kind of like visually it looks
like this we have some code that's like
from the developer that the developers
intending to be interpreted and then we
have some code from the attacker and
then they both get sent to an
interpreter of some kind and executed
although actually it usually looks more
like this
like the attacker code is kind of in the
middle and we'll see kind of the
examples of that and I think again it
gets sent to an interpreter in this case
what I mean by an interpreter is like
anything that's going to interpret that
and sort of execute it right so that
could be the database it could be a
browser XSS just generally going to be
the browser
it could be the web server or mail
server it could be a shell it could be
the templating library or XML part you
know you get the idea it's something
that's going to execute this code or
maybe you know someone's just calling
eval on some code
all right so here's our classic sequel
injection example we're creating a query
and we're putting some data into it and
then we're going to execute the query on
the database and so just to be like
super explicit here we expect that email
address to be data right and we have
this stream which kind of looks like
data like in the program that's data but
actually we're gonna execute it as code
right and that email is probably going
to be user input so in this case like a
request parameter and if it's user input
that means it can be attacker input so
we have again sort of the classic sequel
injection where we're gonna in that
string and you know do or 1 equals 1 and
in the query and what ends up happening
is we had this code that a developer
wrote write the the seek I'm talking
about the sequel code that the developer
rode and we have this data coming in but
now the data is interpreted as code and
what I think is really interesting is at
this point we no longer have a
distinction between what the developer
wrote and what the attacker is injecting
so at this point we've lost right we
have no idea which is which so here's
some more examples in different
languages where we're building queries
and then we put values into them and we
have sequel injection opportunities here
so if we look at this we see like we're
building strings and we're like putting
values into those strings and then
executing them right here's more
examples wow I don't know what happened
there lots of white space and not top
row in there so again we're like
building strings and this time we're
gonna hand them off probably to a shell
or sometimes it's like a pseudo shell
and it's going to execute so here we
have command injection and just in case
you didn't get it on the first two
slides here we're building more strings
and this time we're building actually
templates that we're going to execute so
if you caught it
jayson's talk yesterday server-side
Templin injection is becoming more
popular among bug bounty researchers I
think the rails example on the top is
actually very sneaky because there's
nothing that really indicates what's
going on but when you do render in line
it actually treats it as your default
template Ameri which in this case would
allow you to put in essentially any Ruby
code and it would be executed on the
server so what we get from him like
building a template now we have remote
code execution and again we're like
putting the other these strings putting
user input into them and then handing
them off to something that's going to
execute them all right what about this
one so is this like opportunity for a
cross-site scripting probably but you
don't actually know because there's like
a whole bunch of templating libraries
that use this exact same syntax but what
I want to point out here is we have at
least four different contexts that
require different types of escaping to
avoid across site scripting at the top
we're just kind of like in an HTML
context here we're in a CSS context
you're in a JavaScript context here
we're in HTML attribute context it's
very unlikely that your templating
library even offers the correct escaping
for all in these four contexts in there
they're like five or six that can happen
in HTML right so even if you wanted to
do the right thing probably not going to
be able to and of course expecting
people to always use the correct
encoding for the correct context is very
difficult this is like a simple example
but most of the time your templates
aren't going to be this simple okay
we'll come back to this
so here is my thesis for the talk web
programming is actually meta programming
and in this context what I mean by meta
programming is you're writing code that
writes code there are other parts of
meta programming but in this context is
what I'm talking about this is what
you're doing when you build a web
application if we look at that the the
black box with the glowing blue lights
that's our web application on the web
server and if you think about what it
has to do it has to take in some stuff
from a browser we get HTTP requests
opportunities for injection there may be
some JSON some XML form data query
parameters all that's coming in and
maybe it's talking to some back-end
micro services may is talking to a
database and then from all of that it
has to generate something that gets sent
back to a browser it's going to be an
HTTP response and you're probably gonna
have HTML and JavaScript and maybe some
JSON and CSS so it's essentially taking
this and generating code and that code
is going to be interpreted actually you
know it's interpreted in the browser
there's also like things along the way
right there's the web server itself
there may be networking devices along
the way all of that and then you have
the browser itself and in the browser
you may also be like having JavaScript
that generates HTML and CSS and maybe
it's even generating other JavaScript
that it then interprets so there's a lot
of code generation happening here so
really what programming is compiler
construction we're building a compiler
that's going to take in inputs and it's
going to generate code that's going to
go and get interpreted and evaluated
however unlike a most compilers we're
doing it with untrusted values that are
coming in
and that just makes it even harder so we
have this like complicated system where
we're building this compiler and we also
have to worry about people giving us
values that are untrusted in unsafe and
handling those all correctly to generate
safe code for our users and for our
back-end and so on and I like you just
like kind of take that in for a moment
because this is the route of injection
vulnerabilities is that this is what you
have to do when you're building a web
application and that's a lot to deal
with so if we look at how you would
normally build a compiler you would
start off with some source code which by
the way is probably trusted source code
and at that point you take it in you
turn it into a stream of tokens then
that gets turned into an app check
syntax tree then you kind of turn into
like another tree but it has more
semantic information then that gets run
through a bunch of iterations of
intermediate representations and then at
the end you have compiled code either
you know binary or some kind of source
code that gets interpreted so I just
want to point out that at the top we
have text and at the bottom we have text
or binary that comes out in the middle
when you're making a compiler you don't
deal with text you're not manipulating
strings unless you're really
inexperienced at writing compilers like
I did once and tried to do it with
string manipulation and it's a mess you
don't want to do it it's very hard but
that is what you do when you write a web
application you're actually building a
complex compiler and most likely you're
doing it all via string manipulation we
have our templates we have our quiz that
we send to a database it's all strings
string manipulation that's why I show
you all those code examples it's all
building up strings that you hand off to
an interpreter
and again we're doing it with untrusted
values so that seems like a great way to
get vulnerabilities and it is that's why
injection is at the top just to
reiterate we're building these complex
systems using string manipulation with
untrusted values alright so back to the
real world how what what are the
suggestions for preventing sequel
injection you could use an ORM and if
the ORM is good right it should help you
avoid sequel injection however first of
all you have to have like the object
mapping and not all applications make
sense to have an object mapping not all
queries make sense to have an object
mapping and at some point developers are
going to want to write just like a
normal sequel query that doesn't again
have this mapping so even if you use an
ORM there's probably going to be a
method somewhere where you can just
shove in some sequel query
parameterization is generally like the
most commonly recommended way of
preventing sequel injection right and it
mostly works except first of all you're
still doing string manipulation and it
tends to be limited on where you can put
these placeholders if you put them like
in like a column name or a table name it
made mess up the query and not really
work all right
and again we're like doing stream
manipulation and then of course if we're
just manually escaping things first of
all we have to make sure we call the
right method to escape the right data so
now we're back in like XSS land and
we're building strings so I think I
probably like hammered that point home
enough right like we're building strings
and that's bad so here are my
suggestions and this is where we get
into the like thought part of like you
know a little bit vague so here's my
first suggestion let's stop providing
unsafe interfaces right so you're
building an ORM and then you say okay I
have all this great like object-oriented
stuff that you can do but I also have
just like you know execute sequel and at
that point what how are you going to
execute the sequel it's gonna be like a
string that you pass in and now you have
you're basically saying like yeah I
offered you all this good stuff and
here's the way of like introducing a
vulnerability again so some examples
stop providing you know execute this
query
maybe stop providing hey like you know
here's your shell-like execute whatever
you want and in these cases I'm talking
about like where you can just pass in a
single string and that's it will execute
rails HTML safe is not safe
a lot of templating languages like
ginger they have like safe again
it does the opposite of what you mean so
let's stop providing those kinds of
interfaces in fact for templating
languages in particular one thing I've
noticed is often missing is that people
want to compose templates right you want
to reuse templates and if you don't have
a good built-in way of saying like okay
here I'm going to combine this template
and that template in that template then
people do stuff like this where like the
template value comes in as a string and
then you throw it in something like this
anyway well it has I I can't escape it
because I just generated a bunch of HTML
from this other template so now I have
to mark it as safe and it's just a poor
way of composing templates so provide
better interfaces
you know enter HTML
just stop doing that another thing I
want to mention is that any library that
you write is probably going to end up
being used on the Internet at some point
and I think we've seen a lot of examples
of this where especially older libraries
someone goes oh well I need this to you
know process this file or maybe I'll
shell out to it because it's handy and
it's useful now
the original library author probably
didn't even consider that hey maybe this
might accept untrusted input at some
point so as we're writing libraries we
have to think about like hey maybe the
at least the default interfaces should
assume that it could be dangerous input
this coming in okay number two stop
providing string interfaces to libraries
so if it makes sense as like the first
pass right but sequel injection as
mentioned earlier been around for 20
years maybe we should stop building
database squeeze by putting strings
together here's an example from the
rails world I'm not saying this is like
the best way to do things I'm just
saying this is kind of give you an idea
instead of manipulating strings we're
kind of making these method calls and
everything that gets passed in is going
to be treated appropriately in the query
so we can pass in an untrusted input
here and it'll be properly escaped and
it will generate the query for us so
we're not working at the stream level
anymore we're like at least one step up
from there
but developers I'm gonna write stuff
like this not just developers everybody
every way wants to write code like this
we're like whoa look I am an expert and
I need to do this complex query and you
know I want to be able to generate it
dynamically so one thought that I had
and I think this is I think this is a
very good thought which is why I'm
sharing it with you so I'm sorry we're
getting like rails heavy here but it's
like where my experience is if we have
query parameters and our framework knows
that it's a query parameter right and we
try to put a query parameter into a
string well maybe our query parameter
shouldn't be a string type it should be
a query parameter type let's say and if
we try to even put it into a string we
should get an exception so this kind of
is like hey if you try to build up
strings using unsafe input we're just
not going to let you do that and I think
this has a lot of promise because again
the framework already knows the types of
these values right it knows that this
came from a query parameter so if we
just say well you can't add query
parameters to a string and don't offer a
to string method okay then we kind of
eliminate this and instead we have to
offer a safe interface for composing
quick parameters or form values or
whatever and database queries it's just
a thought but I think it has a lot of
promise this is ancient does anyone
remember does anyone know what Mark
could be is no cuz you're not you're not
huh no sorry
so a long time ago there was a guy in
the Ruby community named why the lucky
stiff and there's like you there's like
a I can't remember the publication but
they did like this whole big article on
him when he disappeared
anyways he had this library and I don't
that this is a great idea I didn't
really catch on and it's it's very like
heavy but the idea is like I'm composing
HTML but I'm not working with strings I
have data values and I have method calls
that I'm making and then that will
generate the HTML for me and again not
saying this is a great idea but the idea
is that what what can we do
that is not manipulating strings but
still gets us to generating those values
safely at some point so it's a thought
and like I said it's a thought talk so
it's just the thought I'm sure some of
you can come up with like a better way
to to build this kind of interface but
the idea is to get away from like
strings right number three if you're
going to be accepting code let's say a
database query or even like a shell like
shelling out somewhere do you need like
the full power of a programming language
in that particular scenario like do you
really eat a Turing complete language or
can you restrict that language in some
way because the more you restrict the
language that you accept the more you
eliminate potential vulnerabilities I
think a good example is HTML if you only
had HTML but no JavaScript no flash
anything like that you're kind of
limiting what you can do you can do like
some content injection maybe you know
but you're not you can't really execute
code you know how the opportunity to
like have a Bitcoin miner in an ad right
it's just you can't do it or if you can
you should probably give a talk on that
because that would be really impressive
again it's just like a thought that if
you're building an interface it you know
if you're building a library or
interface generally you're thinking like
I want to provide the programmer all the
power that they could possibly need and
then it's their job to figure out like
how to use it safely maybe think about
it the other way right what do I have to
expose and what can I leave out another
good example is if you're creating a
database library do you need to allow
multiple queries to be executed in one
call because a whole lot of sequel
injection payloads rely on being able to
get a semicolon or a new line in where
they can end your current query and
execute a second query those kinds of
things are ways that you can limit the
impact if a vulnerability occurs okay
number four provide context aware
escaping so now now we're going back and
we're like hey we're going back to
strings because honestly you're building
an HTML page it's a whole bunch of you
know text it's a lot easier to just like
write the HTML and then put dynamic
stuff in it
right so okay giving up on the other
ideas let's go back to okay I'm going to
build strings but how can I do it safely
so going back to this all those
different contexts what we want is to be
able to hand this to our tip floating
library and again we're like writing our
HTML we're even doing things we cry a
and do like inline scripts and
inline Styles
you know and dynamic URLs and so on all
right look I'm just going to write it
the way I want to write it and I'm gonna
hand it off to my templating library and
it's gonna do the right thing for me
because honestly remembering all this
and doing it correctly in all cases is
just it's too much even if you have the
libraries available to do it which is
also not often the case
okay so there are at least four
libraries that do this the HTML
templates that come with go do this
there's C templates from Google
I'm not is anyone familiar with C
templates no they didn't seem like super
well maintained to me but they're out
there also if you use them the auto
escaping is turned off by default so
you'll want to turn on
Wattay looks really cool because it's
PHP which PHP normally you're like
here's a bunch of HTML and I'm going to
put code all over inside of it so it
will actually like do the right escaping
for you unless it's a script context or
maybe CSS but for the other context so
you have like your PHP tags it will
automatically pick the right escaping
for the right context which i think is
pretty amazing
and then there's secure handlebars which
was presented actually a OPSEC USA
I believe 2015 and it same thing like it
looks at your whole template parses the
HTML and does the right kind of escaping
for the input that you're putting in I
think this is fantastic and it's great
that there's and there's probably more
you might know it more but these are the
ones that I found so what if I wanted
sequel context-aware Auto escaping I
couldn't find anything like this
and I think if you watch the talk about
secure handlebars the majority of the
talk is just like how do we parse HTML
how do we parse the templates that
people use in a way that you know we can
do the right kind of escaping and people
aren't too restricted on you know they
don't have to use like XHTML or whatever
if you go look
sequal parsers you will find that it's
also a very hard problem because every
database has like different syntax and
different commands and different ways of
escaping and what I found is that it
seems like this sort of accepted
approach is just rip the parser out of
the database itself it's like if you're
using Postgres like just take the parser
out of Postgres and try to use that and
if you're thinking like ok well i'm to
modify the parser so that i can put you
know question marks or brackets or
something in so that i can put the
values in like we saw in the other
templates that's really hard like that's
a hard job so it'd be great if any of
you could tackle that problem you can
come back next year and give a talk on
it would be awesome well shell
context-aware Auto escaping you will not
find anything about that
of course every shell is like a little
bit different and just like no one as
far as I know no one is even like
approach this problem right and again
it's it's like it's a hard problem
it's a parsing problem it's a how do I
escape properly problem all kinds of
difficulties to build these auto
escaping templating things right so I'm
I'm hoping that some of you in here are
thinking hey the framework I know does
this and that is cool which is also a
town in California if you didn't know
like I didn't know but so that's great
like it's awesome that there are
frameworks that are doing that correctly
or I shouldn't say correctly but that
are offering that kind of functionality
to prevent injection issues however what
really we need is that every framework
needs to provide this so can you imagine
somebody today is like okay I'm gonna
build
web framework and they build it and they
don't provide any kind of HTML escaping
that would be ridiculous right everyone
would kind of like laugh at it right
because that's that's just silly you
know that you need to have some way of
escaping values if you build a database
library and you don't provide at least
query parameterization people are gonna
be like what is this right so we need to
move to a space where things like
context-aware escaping is just expected
I expect that my templating libraries
will do this for me I mean not in a way
I don't mean that in the way of like you
don't check and you just blindly use
things I mean like this should be the
level that we're expecting from these
libraries as well as like I said you
know the context-aware stuff is really
cool and it's great because you can kind
of continue doing things the way you're
doing them now but even better would
just be moving away from the strings and
having a higher level interface that
we're working at just like I said with
compilers you're not going to be working
with string manipulation so we need to
be moving to some kind of libraries and
I you know again it's a thought talk so
I'm hoping that you have thoughts on
like yeah what like what kind of
interface do I want to use that's it's
not strings I don't want to like be
putting strings together but some kind
of data structure or some kind of
programming interface that's going to be
safe and still allow me to do like
complex queries that I want to do and
again we want every framework to do this
so I I have some thoughts about how I
think there's a really good model with
like the lib NaCl and the lib pasta
library that came out recently where
people spend a lot of time building a
secure by default library that does the
right things that's simple in terms of
its interface and then everyone else
just wraps that library I think that's
like a really cool model because you put
all the effort in one place and then
everybody benefits from that as opposed
to like okay well now every framework
has to like go and implement
their own whatever context-aware
escaping again like I said sort of like
expecting better things from our web
frameworks expecting that they're gonna
provide really good security and in this
case like context-aware escaping or a
better interface for doing sequel
queries that kind of thing and then my
thought is like so Google created go
right and now like a whole bunch of
people use go because go is so awesome
maybe or maybe because Google has an
awesome marketing machine and they can
promote it and people trust it because
it's Google and and then it catches on
right or think about like rust with
Mozilla getting and I think those two
examples are great because getting
people to use a new programming language
and getting community around it and
getting people using it is like a hard
thing to do and yet we've seen really
modern examples of that happening so and
same with web frameworks you would think
like maybe the web framework market is
flooded but no people still keep coming
out with new ones and if you have
somebody with the money and the
influence and the incentive to get
people to use it
I think there's opportunity for change
there so who here works at Google
Facebook in any of those like Amazon
like any like nobody alright well tell
your friends who work at those companies
to get on this and then you know just
applying some shame to frameworks that
are not doing it right right they're not
providing these security features I
think could be helpful
all right so who in here is like this
sounds a lot like lame sec were you
thinking that a little bit yeah so I
spent some time so links X stands for
language theoretic security it's a
research area and I spent some time
looking
and so if you're really familiar with it
you can correct me but I got the feeling
so the early work has definitely focused
on like parsers and building safe
parsers that can accept unsafe input and
so on I didn't see so much around what
I'm trying to talk about which is like
the programming interfaces that will
allow you to do things safely if you
want to check out I know it's not a
great URL you could just search for Lang
SEC there's a bunch of papers and stuff
and maybe you can come to your own
conclusions I feel like this is a
related area of sort of formalizing you
know parsing of languages and also
output encoding but I feel like maybe
it's like a little bit off from what I'm
talking about specifically but I needed
to mention it because it's definitely an
area that's it's nearby
alright that's all I wanted to talk
about but I I it's a thought talk and I
think you might have thoughts so I think
we have plenty of time I think I don't
know but I would love to hear people
talk about I think libraries you know
that are doing this or like thoughts
that you have on this not necessarily
they don't have to be questions I'm not
a programmer developer I come more from
the security side right and many times
it's difficult for me to believe how
many mistakes I find and so forth but
then when I watch how like I took the
picture of the four different ways you
would have to escape characters and one
little template and that's really
ridiculous
yeah Wow yeah that's quite enlightening
thank you very much okay yeah again
they're more than four contacts even in
a you know in an HTML page
so you again coming from the security
space your example on query
parameterization yes um I can say it was
definitely sequel injectable because
you're doing string building right and
you you focus a lot on string building
being the problem with injection when
the idea behind proper per query
parameterization and parameter binding
this one yes this this is safe is it
yeah what language is that it's Ruby on
Rails actor okay yeah but you hadn't you
had another one that was in Java no I
had a vulnerable version could be okay
yeah maybe that's what I'm remembering
yeah could be but the problem that we
see a lot is even with building query
grammar s queries right without
separating the parameter itself right
the the the variable from the query you
still have entirely injectable queries
right doing doing parameter binding is
that exact thing of not building a
string you're feeding the object into
that query right rather than the string
of the object yeah I see what you're
saying yeah I do
you're right the it's separating like
okay I have this string and I have the
values are over here and then the
database driver will put those together
safely is that what you're saying yes
and I that's true but I think two
thoughts on that one we only get query
parameterization for seek like database
queries we don't get it for templates
usually and we don't like we don't get
it other places so it's great that we
have it here but we don't get other
places and really what happens is like
people sort of get into this like yeah a
query parameter ization and then they
want to do something like a
dynamic column name and most core a
parameterization will not properly
parameter I as a column name or a
database name so so you still end up
with people like building dynamic
strings on this side and they'll also do
query parameterization in the same line
of code right so it's not I'm not saying
like this is awful I'm just saying like
we need like maybe we need something
else things where you need to understand
the limitations of what it provides
right and that you know the the thing is
you know I am a security professional
yeah okay I am a security professional
and it's still like confused like you
still have to like spend some time to
understand like what are the safe ways
to do things and if you're a developer
I'm not saying you wouldn't do that but
when I'm writing code I just kind of
like Google for like the first thing
that comes up and I kind of trust that
like it's doing it right right so so
yeah it can be tricky even if you have
the tools available to do it the right
way and yeah I'm like okay I'm gonna do
query parameter ization and then you
find like well but if I do the parameter
in like the wrong part of the like a
particular part of the query like it
doesn't do it right and it breaks my
query and now I'm stuck with like well
how do I do it right so that's why I'm
kind of suggesting like even then you're
still kind of like putting code in
strings and then trying to manipulate
them to have dynamic values and so on I
think that those examples are really
great up there but a lot of the issues
that we had at my company were that
people started writing sequel functions
inside their Java code and they weren't
necessary like sequel statements that
these functions had these statements
inside them so they added parameters
from the request into the sequel
functions and not a lot of developers in
even security folks in this conference
knew that you can actually create
callable statements and so that was very
interesting to figure out that we had to
create a wrapper that did parameter
statements I think I would like to see
more examples of that in the future like
people stay that you mean statements
like prepared statements they had sequel
functions under okay no worries but
these functions for like plc role calls
I don't think you can stored procedures
I mean I mean you mean like in sequel
you can call certain functions that are
more like executing code than they are
yep certainly and also stored procedures
can have dynamic bits to them too which
is like if you're looking at the code
you're like well it seems okay and then
you look in the database and it's like
oh actually you know it will just like
accept things and like put them in
dynamically so again another another
problem wait for the mic please thank
you I would like to agree with the first
statement we heard that there are a lot
of maybe what I call cases of over
trusting input I know insecurity with a
lot of the development teams I've worked
with people basically say there is no
injection prevention but it's okay
because we trust our source I guess
maybe I'd like to confirm explicitly
that what you're getting into with the
don't just DB execute whatever don't
whatever that that's kind of like a
library with our protections it's a what
is this case we sort of agree with the
sentiment yes absolutely and I you know
the and the if it might can go back
there yeah that that's absolutely true I
can give you an example at a former
employer they so they had external data
that they bought from some other company
and then they took that data and they
just put it in their database and then
when they started rendering it on the
webpage
hey here's like a bunch of sequel
injection that came in from that so they
they may have been doing or they
obviously weren't escaping things
properly on output but in terms of you
know maybe they're managing all the data
and the date in their database
everything going in
out there yeah we're doing this right
we're like very careful about what goes
in maybe I don't know maybe they were
like sanitizing it or stripping whatever
they were doing but then they have a
third party source of data which they
just put into the database and now I
mean that's untrusted input it didn't
come in through a query parameter from a
user they literally bought it from a
third party so what sorry yes I have a
question here in the back I first of all
thank you so much for your talk a
college students sudden CS and security
and just correct me if I'm wrong but
from what I'm understanding these like
libraries are kind of a way to prevent
these injections from happening at the
code level from the development level is
there a way to somehow use these
libraries to maybe run a scan on on code
that would you know catch these you know
unpromising savings that are not
prepared properly as maybe like security
testing automate security testing or is
it mostly this is just like we're trying
to stop it from the development
standpoint with the language with the
framework yes so certainly I mean I have
a lot of background in static analysis
which is what you're talking about
and if you remember at the beginning
wasa top 10 categorizes injection as
easy to detect and actually it is one of
the easier things to find via static
analysis looking at the code the problem
is not every you don't have we don't
have a hundred percent coverage on every
language and every framework in every
database library that we can have that
kind of assurance and really we should
and you know is every company gonna get
the tool or buy the tool that's going to
cover their particular thing and maybe
they wrote their own who knows so yeah I
think you know fixing it at the library
level well and actually let me back up
just a little bit again the 20 years of
sequel injection we've also had static
analysis and dynamic analysis tools and
they yeah they can find this stuff but
it's not solving the problem completely
it solves it in individual cases and the
idea here is like let's
just kind of try to solve it in at the
base layer no other there are other ways
of solving it yes there's question here
there plenty of other ways of solving
and this is just some thoughts so quick
question I had is for libraries secure
control interfaces we have the wasp
isapi right yeah so does that like you
talked about Google or Facebook coming
up with libraries but how are auspey
sappy libraries we use that a lot or
with reference implementations so my
understanding the way I will look at it
is libraries like a sappy should be like
that's something you can build a better
interface on top of right so if you have
stuff like a sappy or there's another
project I know Jim Manukau has been
working on I don't remember the name of
where they basically providing the
building blocks in terms of these are
the methods that are going to do the
correct escaping but you have to wrap
those up and in a better interface so
like talking about like the context of
where escaping you need to have good
escaping libraries to do that but you
don't want the developer to have the
responsibility of choosing the correct
method in some cases if you look at like
the OAuth XSS cheat sheet and so on
sometimes you have to apply multiple
coatings to the same input to make it
completely safe and if remember that in
all cases like you'd have to like print
out the cheat sheet and like have it on
your desk right so the idea would be to
take potentially to take a library like
that and then build something on top of
it yes
it's just more kind of a it goes back to
our keynote yesterday in the morning you
know whatever you've talked about is
great and I think we need to put that
more into the mindset of the generation
that's through that pipeline of
Education and get these I know concepts
into their heads to write code more
securely or and kind of share these kind
of thoughts with them right yeah I think
that's part of you know if you think
about I want because one thought I had
was like okay so like if you're building
a new framework you should do this right
and I thought well who's building new
frameworks and I was like well actually
people build new frameworks all the time
and it's surprising how rapidly those
new frameworks can be adopted so yeah I
agree
or I mean I don't know how to implement
exactly what you're suggesting but
definitely these sort of like like I
said like hey this if you're building
something if you're building a web
framework you have to provide these
things and you see that for example with
C surf protection most new web
frameworks are going to provide that out
of the box they're gonna provide that
for you and so that's something that we
should just expect like hey you're
building a new web framework that's
awesome do you have C surf protection
you have XSS protection do you have
sequel injection protection you know and
so on and that should just be what yeah
it should be given that you're building
web framework this stuff was provided
okay I think that's about it but I'd be
happy to talk to anyone afterwards if
you have thoughts all right thank you
[Music]