[Music]
how's everybody doing today duh it's
like it is just like gonna be one of the
best conference venues right because
they're just like hanging out at the
beach like okay maybe we'll go do this
and then it's like if the talk gets
boring you can just go outside and go
and say save it at the beach okay you
read my mind yeah well I got the good
good task of like the post lunch talk so
hopefully I hope to make this like a
real you know real smooth you know using
the afternoon I have had people fall
asleep talks before and I'm just like
I'm sure that they're coming from like a
really far away timezone that's why you
know that's you get when you speak you
got to psych yourself up with stuff like
that right and you know it's always
really good to go home to your wife
she's like I had people like it you're
like yeah a couple of people fell asleep
yeah so it was hopefully we won't do
that today if you if you do like think
you just want to hit the beach or
whatever you can hit me an email and I
have an autoresponder already set up so
it'll like Auto give it all to you right
now and so you could just you know leave
with with no regrets you know at that
point and you you would have it have it
all so if you send me email there it
should auto respond and if you if you do
it and you don't get an auto response
right away like give me a shout and then
we'll I'll check that or whatever so
okay so I'm done I'm in from Texas I'm
from Austin I work over at signal
sciences I think signal sciences has
been around I think we got a party
tonight that should be good if you're
interested in checking out after party
hit me up if you don't know anything
about it you want to come we'd love to
have you
also I have some courses on DevOps over
at lynda.com also linked in learning and
sometimes and I've been kind of bad
about it lately but me and a couple
buddies we blog over at the agile admin
and and then a lot of us have put
together to the courses over at
lynda.com so I kind of thought I'd give
you a summary up front too so we kind of
know like where we're going and we kind
of see the roadmap for the the path for
today I think we see that DevOps is
changing and there's there's a big risk
I think that security is in a little bit
of a crisis but I think we have some
some good things coming out I see a lot
of like forward
means security shops that have seemed to
have found the way and we're also going
to juxtapose some of the old ways in the
new ways of security especially in the
context of DevOps
ok so I've also had like these sort of
existential questions on my mind lately
I'm asking like ok can security as an
industry really rise to the demands of
DevOps and and are we able to like is
like is DevOps able to actually handle
all of the cultural baggage that
security is bringing to it right and
maybe one pack a little go what that
means but like I mean you know there's a
lot of security stereotypes right and
like they're therefore somewhat of a
reason and our industry is traditionally
kind of a little bit more difficult and
are we gonna are we gonna mess up the
whole DevOps thing along the way with
that and you know and basically I'm like
worried I'm like this this DevOps thing
has been really beautiful it's done a
lot of really good things and it's been
built up and is secured just gonna come
in and like smash it like they seem to
do we seem to do right does that
resonate with anybody or you guys is
that sound good I mean the beaches still
available so I don't feel too bad about
it so my journey I started out working
at right out of college at this big
billion-dollar company we had these
brutal on-call rotations we did these
crazy 24 hour go live deployments and it
was all waterfall and then but some of
my greatest friends were kind of born in
that job and there's that was the that
was the the place where we came from and
in O seven I went to a startup and we
were doing stuff in Amazon Cloud I
learned at that startup a little bit
about failure and about what actually
makes me happy then later I went back to
the that same big company and I I guess
I don't of it but then we were just kind
of said alright hey like ignore the rest
of the company go cloud and go all-in
and we had a really great time a lot of
us that kind of I lived that old style
of those 24 hour painful you know
deployments and you know weekend's it's
like we would now are like deploying a
lots of times per day we were you know
not having crazy on call and it was
really great and we sort of saw the kind
of saw the future we started you know
back in 2010 we had a case study
written on us and we were doing
infrastructure is code and and we kind
of did something really neat at this
company we delivered four SAS products
in two years which is like a really big
thing for us back in Oh ten and 2011 and
then around that same time I found the
rugged software movement I live in
Austin and I was lucky enough to meet
gene Kim in a bar and so that was that
was great I was like so if we just read
visible apps you know that was before
Phoenix project and all the other books
he's written and and we you know we had
a good time there worked on a project
working on a project called gauntlet and
then later I joined signal sciences but
I kind of came to the realization
through all this and probably many of
you all have as well as like in our
careers like what's really important
like and I think this is one of the
things that that I think sets DevOps
apart from a lot of other movements and
things we've done in our industry is
like our insistence on culture and we
always say DevOps I like the idea of
like DevOps is friendship it really
started out with a the idea of having
compassion for operations because you
know we would start and would be like
cookie to have ten developers for one
operations person there's this whole
throw it over the wall mentality there's
that picture of the developer girl
that's got the building on fire it's
like it's office problems now right
that's that's the that's the that's the
that was like our our life and images
and but we have seen that labor inequity
actually permeates all of the IT
organizations and security we we live
this as well so for every 100 developers
you would have 10 operations folks to
like one secured and this is really a
quarter of magnitudes but does that do
those numbers resonate with anybody yeah
yeah it was like yeah it's time the one
right or I was like I'm just a half like
I'm supposed to like do have half of my
job is something else right and and so
even with all that and in kind of the
baggage that comes with that I still
remain pretty optimistic but then I and
I'm kind of optimistic type of person
but then earlier this year I started
having some doubts and my first one was
I was at RSA and there was a bus that
drove by and it's a you know DevOps and
real big letters and it was for a
company that's like very much not DevOps
and I was like oh geez we're just a
marketing slogan now right
and sort of like and so I claim that as
like security beam security right that's
that's what we do that's what we do
right it's like you can rewind like five
or seven years ago and it's like cloud
finger quotes and then you know three
years later it's like cloud security
that's what we do you're like with
nothing has changed but you know just
we've just rebranded right and that
seems like what we do and then then
later that year so it's I'm not just
blaming on security but I was at the
expo floor a docker and there was a
booth it said like the DevOps tool chain
and it was like oh I can't remember what
it was is like put your you know you
know automation in a Windows box on a
VMware and a docker I was like it's like
that sounds like a nightmare like you
don't want to do that like that's
something that you're not interested in
running all this stuff and so I sort of
felt like have we have we allowed this
to become a slogan or a gimmick and and
what really had DevOps become what would
have what have we kind of built over the
years and if you're new like that this
is where I started kind of coming with
those questions that I posed earlier on
and I think back about two of the the
main folks that actually like really
helped DevOps get started so do you guys
know who these folks are no okay so the
guy on the left is Patrick Dubois he's
he is the guy who coined the word DevOps
he lives over in Ghent in 2009 he him
and Andrew Schafer and some other folks
had had sort of used the words like
agile infrastructure or whatever but
then he he decided to host the first
DevOps days and he was like we just need
a conference where developers and
operations can come together and and
meet the the guy on the right is John
Willis John Willis along with Damon
Edwards they run the DevOps cafe podcast
but John's done a lot of good stuff he's
worked from chef to docker he's doing a
lot of cool stuff now but you know like
a lot of the industry you know like I
know if you guys are familiar but like
you know a lot of the communities that
kind of a rise in like in a programming
language or a practice area like they
kind of take on like the the however the
kind of personality of the main founder
well like Patrick is extremely extremely
nice guy you can tell he's he's very
friendly there
but that's like one of the things why
we're DevOps really is always kind of
insistent on culture and a lot of push
towards that it's because Patrick really
helped us like especially in the early
days coming out of the agile stuff
saying like let's let's build the right
culture and that's the big push behind
this and you know and I get it like I
see like in my in my own story like okay
I teach DevOps classes and you know I
work at a vendor that does kind of some
stuff in the DevOps space in the dev sac
ops space I help write articles about
DevOps and security at signal Sciences
but it really helped me to start
thinking about this as I was kind of
kind of having these existential doubts
and this this idea of like what am I
really doing here is to sort of go back
to what patrick said all the way and
this i think this quote came from
patrick back in probably 2010 or 2011
but he was kind of posed with the
challenge of like devops is great
because like a lot of startups can do it
i mean if you're like if you got 20
people like sure fine everybody is like
one happy family team but it's not gonna
work in the enterprise setting and he
said you know culture is the most
important aspect to devops succeeding in
the enterprise and I think when we kind
of rewind rewind and really think about
it what is it we're doing and we kind of
get stuck thinking about tool chains and
all this other automation and others
others other business we kind of lose
lose kind of the focus of what we're
what we're actually trying to accomplish
and you know what DevOps has already
accomplished so far I I think about this
personally in my family I like to say
that we have a moon culture and my
family or not it's not like it's not
quite as mystic as you might think but
when my daughter was like 2 or 3 she's
five now my oldest is five and and she
she would always say like oh the moon's
out tonight she really like was really
excited about seeing the moon and I
started realizing like something in me
started to shift right like I got
excited when I saw the moon
I started downloading apps to like
figure out the phases of the Moon then I
could like tell her like honey it's like
a waxing crescent moon did I write you
know it could be like oh yeah it's like
that's gonna rise up over this way or
you know whatever and you know it so I
started thinking that like I I started
having
and it hit me one day on my drive home
and I saw you know the moon and I call
my wife I'm like you gotta get Lydia
outside cuz like it is like really you
know big and and and it was great but I
realized like I was actually starting to
change like my own personal desires in
my personal opinion and like I developed
this new understanding I had a shared
language shared views and and then I was
even putting like those apps on my phone
right to have it the two lanes so I
started thinking about and this is our
original team that kind of put this
together and I've given a version of
this talk to
I should also preface the whole thing
with I've given I've only given this
talk like a couple times but mostly to
DevOps audiences because I'm trying to
be like hey how are security people
actually going to move forward so this
is I'm kind of hoping that like that we
as security people agree and we can kind
of like you know deliver on some of the
promises I've made to these very kind
DevOps people that was a joke so there's
that's where though there'll be more of
those I'll try to cue you next time okay
all right so anyway so I hope you can
make a connection and may I go make a
friend through your journey today okay
so let's go back to our main our main
point here is like I think security is
in crisis so there's a great book Steve
Logan he wrote the firewall book like
that was like the book on firewalls in
the late 90s but recently he released a
book called thinking security
he says companies are spending a great
deal on security but we read a massive
computer related attacks and something
is wrong and the problem is twofold
we're protecting the wrong things and
we're hurting productivity in the
process so I think we can see that like
there is there is a there is a problem
does this resonate with anybody does he
feel like security kind of this is the
it's okay
good I'm glad you know sometimes like
that one doesn't even get a laugh I'm
like oh geez
we're in you're in for it if you tell
ins not funny to you all right so
so there's a great book on browser
security called the tangled web but in
the first chapter there's a there's kind
of a walkthrough of how the security
industry and where it's been and been
going over the last 30 40 years but in
it it says security by risk assessment
introduces a dangerous fallacy that
structured inadequacy is almost as good
as adequacy and that underfunded
security effort plus risk management are
about as good as properly funded
security work does that does that bother
you
yeah yeah yeah you know what what is
what are they saying here right say
they're saying by doing risk assessment
that we don't actually have to do
engineering we can be actuarial do
actuarial stuff and buy insurance
policies and that we we don't actually
have to fund it anymore and that that we
can just say hey like it's adequate it's
good enough stop insurance policy on top
of it right now does that is that bother
you right and I read that and kind of
threw this that first chapter he kind of
walks through how you know over the over
the years how like we used to spend a
lot of money and time and in you know on
engineering stuff and then over the
years we kind of got compliance we got
these insurance policy things and we
stopped doing a lot of like actual
engineering work and we started doing
more as more like this often I see that
security is the cultural outlier this is
a book that came out last October called
agile applications security they say
that many security teams work with the
world view where their goal is to
inhibit change as much as possible does
anybody have a friend who experiences
that right and and I have experiences
personally I've have like I've had a
developer friend tell me this I was kind
of working as a security guy on the kind
of in the DevOps team and they were
saying you know you guys just prefer to
have a system unplugged and powered off
and I was like well I mean I'm not an
idiot like we got to make money like I
was like that you know that you know but
it's sort of like that's their point of
view is like that we are so disconnected
from reality as an industry they're like
we would just rather have all the all
the computers
turned off and then I hear a lot of
security folks say this like those
stupid developers right it's like oh you
got you know some sort of injection or
some cross-site script or whatever
problem with your page like you must be
stupid right like one small flaw equals
like you know character assessment of a
person right and we hear here that kind
of cascade through our industry as well
and a leading security industry industry
publication recently sent me this and a
flyer it says hey it's 30 times cheaper
to fix security defects in dev vs. prot
so we've known this but the sad part is
we've known this since 2002 and and I
got it on a flyer like I'm not joking on
a flyer last year right so like in 2017
so that's like pretty disconnected from
reality
so I actually tried the MapQuest joke
with my father-in-law the other day and
he was like yeah MapQuest I'm like god
no no no okay
so hopefully doesn't watch this video
recording I'm sure he won't okay so it
was I think that the premise is like
Security's in crisis we must change or
we must die
so I work at signal Sciences we provide
kind of a laughs like type product when
I first started I was like I'm gonna
research certainly like there's cool
stuff out there or whatever we're going
on and and there's this is just to show
like the disconnection of the research
here but one of one one laugh provider
says something like averaging every
aspect of managing this is an ongoing
process blah blah blah and you got to go
if everyone's eyes open and effort
required to get and keep the laughs
running productively and they go on to
say you need like two headcount and I'm
like in an industry like where we don't
have enough people to fill all the
wrecks that are open and like you're not
gonna get two headcount to do that like
we you don't even have you have half a
headcount at best you know for anything
right and so it's just very disconnected
rich mogul also says that we need to
change or die or that we are gonna do it
he was talking about he was looking at
the RSA floor and said a lot of people
that are here now they're not gonna be
here in five years there's another so
the business is also saying that we need
to change or die this is from Fortune
magazine I guess about a year year and a
half ago
well I guess almost two years now time
flies but this is the average time to
deliver corporate IT projects is eight
and a half months and it is risen for me
to have months to over ten months in the
last five years but why is that and it
goes on to say it's the growth of
security functions which are too poorly
coordinated and they often arise from
doing stuff like compliance privacy and
data protection and all the legal stuff
that we're doing so again not actual
functional engineering work but just
like more you know tasks and compliance
driven type stuff you're probably like
okay I think we've got the point right
but I think that we just live in this
world where security folks are having a
hard time keeping up and now that we've
kind of shifted into this like post or
post waterfall and like an agile or
DevOps place where we're able to not
keep up with with everything that's
going on and and a long time ago or like
six seven eight years ago
there is the rugged software development
movement I liked it at the time and I
still think there's a lot of value here
and just thinking about how in security
we always think about absence of events
we have costs it's negative we have a
lot of fear uncertainty doubt that we
use to kind of promote that but in the
the rugged since like we try to verify
quality there's a there's a value
proposition here it's often pretty
affirming and and and even just I guess
like in November John Willis oh I
mentioned earlier he's like security
didn't really get an invite to the
DevOps party so he actually was was
saying it from a sense of like hey
DevOps people like we did this wrong
like we we pulled in that we fixed the
ten to one to have two ops but we didn't
fix the rest of the problem like we
still have this divide so it's not it's
you know the blame doesn't purely sit on
this security side and and he goes on to
say like you know read-only containers
and servers shift the security story to
almost 100% application security and
we're shifting everything around I think
that also really spells a lot more
future for wasp inand kind of our
application and security space to run as
well ok so I think I think so DevOps um
that kind of will say is that we think
DevOps is the way for security really to
survive here the state of DevOps report
says that you know people spend a lot
less money whenever they're on security
whenever there
when they're doing DevOps right and that
high-performing org achieve quality by
incorporating security and security
teams into the delivery process here's
that here's a talk on this if you're
interested you can get the link from the
slides but I like to I like to propose
like what I think is like our new path
and we're gonna juxtapose kind of old
paths and new paths and kind of see if
there's some ways forward and this maybe
I'll give you some ideas and I'd love to
hear if you have any other ideas of
things that are that are going on
because I mean part of the idea is here
like you know DevOps has done a lot of
really great things Security's in crisis
some people have already picked up on
this and some people are already kind of
leaning into this and doing some really
cool things and I think we're now sort
of like accumulating a long enough list
of new things that we're doing that we
weren't doing as a security industry
five five seven years ago then now we
can start up start looking at this new
list and say hey like we we actually
have something here like this is
something that we think there's
worthwhile and this is something that we
add as a value creation or value to the
business as we're kind of moving forward
so let's well go through them one by one
and our first one here was say like the
old way was like we like to embrace
security or a secrecy and the new way is
to create feedback loops so rich Smith
former security director over at Etsy he
also helped write that agile application
security book that he says a security
team who embraces openness about what it
does and why spreads understanding so
the idea is creating runtime loops for
runtime feedback loops and so you want
to look at parts of your site where you
can say alright like are people trying
to take over like certain accounts for
my users what part of my site is
actually under attack
what kind of vectors do people normally
attack like these are sort of basic
there's like there's kind of like I hate
to use supports analogies but like like
tackling and blocking right it's like
are do you do you know where where the
attacks are coming from and you know if
there are they being successful or not
right kind of like kind of basic kind of
stuff oh yeah this is my this is this is
the only gift I got in here I think
but but be able to answer that question
of like are you under attack do you feel
like right now you can answer that
question pretty well right like no we
can't right we don't even have like that
kind of that simple feedback loop in our
industry and then the we're you know we
would really like to hope to know that
as well
okay so Zayn who is the CEO and founder
for signal Sciences he does this nice
little thing like we used to
we used to do this and kind of like this
isn't horrible this is a feedback loop
right like having logs and like emitting
kind of events and stuff like that but
then it's better if you can actually put
visualization in in front of folks as
well for like what kind of attacks are
actually happening what kind of
anomalies and part of part of this story
for us was you know Zayn built that over
at Etsy and then now we launched into
signal Sciences and just putting some
sort of instrumentation in place whether
it's a wrasse for a next generation
laughs or whatever you want to put in
there but like put some sort of feedback
and telemetry back from from runtime
I liked this John all SpA who he was he
was a leading engineering over at Etsy
but at the time he was leading Flickr
but at the time of rise of DevOps if you
don't know who John all Spy is he he did
the the talk that was like that is the
talk that everybody thinks about when
they think of DevOps and it was called
like doing ten deploys a day and and
everybody at the time in 2009 they're
like we do four deploys a year and we
pray that there's not any more than that
right and so like why would you redo ten
deploys a day but he's kind of been
talking recently like we and it kind of
really good into more like how we're
working with incidents and and helping
operations folks think differently about
how we think about incidents and I think
it's also this applies over to and it
crosses the chasm over into security as
well like everything else security
incidents even you know Equifax or
whatever like they could actually be
worse and so at the surface like we want
to ask these types of questions like
what went wrong how did it break how do
we fix it but we actually need to get to
this deeper level of understanding of
what are the things that went into
making it not as bad as it could have
been what what types of stuff did we do
right you know and like that helps you
kind of juxtapose the two in your mind
as you're kind of doing this incident
resolution it helps you also not stop
doing the good stuff that you've that
you've been doing so having the
instrumentation in place like at least
be able to answer these level of
questions like that's really helpful
okay so the next one will zip through
but like sorry should have said so the
old way was like just past audit right
the new way we're gonna say is
compliance adds value policies and
procedures you know that's what that's
what auditors live and die for and
having an effective execution of those
is what you know let's the business keep
running but a lot of times you don't
understand that we sort of just sort of
put like an us-versus-them scenario and
you know I don't know like most of the
PCI and all the frameworks I mean yeah
they're they're actually not horrible if
you can remove all the waterfall bits so
you just got to figure out like how to
work with your your auditors on doing
that and you really want to get to this
point where your training deploys as
standard or routine changes that they've
been pre-approved by management and
they're don't require a heavyweight
change review meeting or anything like
that and I like to think of like
separation of duties that is considered
harmful you know you know it's like a
lot of times we treat our software like
we're like launching a nuke and I think
when I first found this we weren't in
like a nuclear war scenario so it was
like more funny you know now it's like
oh I hope I hope that works so but you
know we we kind of treat it like this
thing that's like a really you know a
big thing but but if we read like even
something like simple like PCI six for
two it says hey it's not it's not like
the same person can't do it it's like
he's the same account to do it right and
like otters have been dealing with this
for a while yeah so basically you just
need you just need to work on putting an
independent check points in place if you
need some resources on this like here's
here's one and I think I got another
link here so some sometimes I just like
try to add slides in here that I think
might be helpful for folks so that's
that's kind of what I'm doing here
but there's the dev ops out of Defense
toolkit so if you find yourself like
fighting the dev ops battle and you need
to fight the auditors on it like this is
a good place to start and so hopefully
that's a helpful for you
all right so old way is in for stability
and a new way was create chaos
everybody's familiar with Netflix's
chaos monkey right right well why why
did like a hundred lines of shell script
like capture the heart and mind of our
industry why right it's because they
said we are going to apply actual chaos
to our system and we're gonna try to
break stuff and everybody's like that is
genius right and and and we've sort of
seen a movement like this where people
are doing their own chaos monkeys a lot
of variation there there's anti fragile
book release that just came out with its
second edition and there's a whole
chapter on chaos engineering this is
Michael Knight guards book I think I
have a link to it my buddy Aaron Aaron
Reinhart is working on a project called
chaos slinger if you're interested in
doing that but they're doing chaos
experiments
it adds miss configuration to your stack
checks to see if it gets detected it
runs in as a lambda and serverless but
you know part of the idea here is like
we're trying to validate our system and
make sure that it can handle chaos and
we do this through chaos experiments and
and and I liked in Nygaard book he's
sort of like really brings it all home
for you if you're if you're trying to
think about this and how to do it in
your organization but building like a
culture where like you have to opt out
of the chaos and like your management
teams always saying like okay like well
how come like is your stuff not harden
you know like hardened enough to like
actually survive like you know the chaos
monkey why not right and they they kind
of build a culture of it so it actually
is more of a cultural thing than a
technology thing right because like
deleting some servers or turning stuff
off like that's really not that that
part of a thing I'd recommend that book
release it's a really great great book
also you know I think another thing that
we think about creating chaos like I
think bug bounties are another good
example of that another another way to
do it I have a friend who's not really
in security at all but he's like oh yeah
we get pin tested all the time and he's
like he told me like he's like he's
really proud about it and I thought you
know bug bounties again right like it's
it's more of a systemization of a thing
that we've been doing for a really long
time but like it is a shift and it is a
shift that has crossed out of just like
security pin testing and kind of like a
smaller domain knowledge to like the
wider development audience in general
and I think that's that's pretty cool
okay old path build wall a new path zero
trust networks so I do like the new OSI
model I actually can memorize this one I
feel good about this and and I like it
and I think that we see like the
auricles have moved off the network over
to the application layer and we see that
we're no longer thinking yeah I mean we
still do it at some but like as a whole
like we've kind of shifted into this
idea like okay there is no perimeter
don't you know don't have anything like
that we're gonna assume compromise at
all layers we're gonna instrument
everything that we can and we're going
to control our endpoints and all the way
to our customer accounts and just sort
of you know instrument as much as we
possibly can I help run the modern
security series and we have windy day
they're joining us from duo security
this Thursday so in two days and if you
can check it out like it's a good like
post conference event maybe you can come
come join us and it should be a really
good time I really enjoy just hearing
wouldn t talk about anything so like
it's going to be even better now we're
talking about zero trust networks okay
next slow validation versus fast and
non-blocking so I think we we had fast
and non like like when we think about
fast and non-blocking like what do we
really mean like we're saying don't slow
down delivery still do continuous
testing but you don't always have to be
like in the middle of the pipeline you
don't have to be like you know Pat it
doesn't pass so like I'm gonna head and
break the build and maybe doing
penetration testing on the outside or
like in a sidecar fashion at signal
Sciences we do about ten fifteen deploys
per day we've done roughly 10,000
deploys in the last two and a half years
and when we first started like I I
pulled off Jess humbles book on
continuous delivery and jezza's and he's
a former thought works guy and I said
alright it's like how am I gonna thanks
how are we gonna do this like how are we
gonna build this in a pipeline way so if
you're if you find yourself like needing
to build a pipeline or need some like
best practices like I really enjoyed
this book and jazz talks about it now
he's like I don't know it's kind of a
dry book I don't know how it's done so
well or people would liked it but it's
really really helpful so and one of the
things that he talks about in the book
is like how little can you deploy at a
time like how long does it take you your
total cycle time from you know checking
in the one one small line code commit to
to have it running and this is something
that we really have kind of obsessed
about over at signal sciences like we
optimize for total cycle time and that
was that's that time from code commit to
running and production we built a deploy
system and let everybody run it and
everybody has the access to push thrown
thing we have a culture it says like if
you write it you must deploy it you must
make sure and support it in production
you know all these things are like
cultural type stuff they're not just you
know a they're not just a push to say
like well let's just add a new tech for
the sake of doing that we're also a
security company so like we couldn't
just do this without putting security
into it so we put security as part of
our CI CD pipeline and we mostly folks
so if you look at the five phases or
some people call it you have six
whatever but you look at these these
three phases these are where I like to
think about where we can put some
security in our pipeline so what have I
bundled into my app that leaves me
vulnerable so all the libraries and
other stuff and all the junk that I've
inherited whenever I run and my building
acceptance tests an integration test
carry catch any security issues before
release and then in operation you you
want to say am i that same question I
was asking Ori they're like am I being
attacked now is it working but I like to
think through those steps the other two
steps are also very you know important
as well but these are kind of arrived
I've kind of put all of our our effort
in focusing on something so lastly we
are another one we have a certainty
testing versus diversity testing and old
way was or the new way I say is like be
mean to your code and so in this the
book agile application security they say
the goal should be to come up with a set
of automated tests that probe and check
security configurations and runtime
system behavior for security features
that will execute every time the system
is built and every time it is deployed
this is kind of
our standard of what we're trying to do
but security tools are like kind of
noisy they're difficult to use we needed
a way to like collaborate between
developers and operations security we
needed a way to spanned you know across
these across these groups that would
make sense to folks so I worked on I've
been working on our project called
gauntlet and but there's other stuff
like security BDD or like just using the
robot framework or other types of
testing but this comes with pre-canned
hooks it doesn't install any tools but
fits in your CI CD pipeline you can
check it out a gauntlet org and our
really stunning graphics are you know
running these tests and and it passes
out the back it looks for anything
called an attack file and kind of a
plain English scenario I you can get it
from the gym but I really prefer to like
running a docker container which I have
a link for that next but it's it's real
simple of like what am I trying to test
given I have this this setup here and I
run this this test then I expect the
output to be this and you this is a very
simple thing you can put in like a
Travis or Jenkins or whatever and run
with your with your site
Aaron Reinhard over at UnitedHealthcare
he says yeah we use gauntlet and we've
used it a lot and and he said they saved
millions of dollars it's like well how
do I get any of those millions of
dollars that would be really great
parent so I use just sort of being
pretty excited about it but kind of that
was our original hope like really to
build something that would help folks
both whether you're in security or
development or operations to kind of
build this kind of point-x thing so
imagine Hanson and I did a talk on this
and the workshop has some labs for
gauntlet and if you want the links like
they're all they're all in there as well
okay and I have some like some demo
stuff we'll kind of skip through this
because we're kind of run a little lower
on time and we also have a way how to
set it up inside of a CD system and I
really prefer to use in a docker
container and you can get that over at
gauntlet - docker so you can put the
tool with all the or the the gauntlet
with all the other tools that you have
inside of the container and just execute
it straight out of that okay so another
thing we like to do is in security we
would always just like say we're going
to do our testing when we're done
and that's a real waterfall type
approach but the new way is to shift
left I like Shannon Lietz as you
probably have noticed by now I just I
find a bunch of things that I like and I
just assemble them all into a deck it's
oh sorry sorry I do that but that's kind
of the kind of way beg borrow and steal
I guess but she talks about a software
supply chain secure software supply
chain and thinking about where we have
all these these phases and then the
questions to ask notice she has four
phases for for her pipeline but thinking
through like okay well in design like
how am i adding security and build like
are the components do they have the
right security applied to them for
deployment how am i securing secrets and
managing my config management system or
operation is my app getting attacked but
thinking through these different phases
and kind of breaking this down like I
think that's a real helpful approach and
and even stuff like the culture add into
it's really cool because okay we're
going to do we're going to do
Red Team Mondays and so the security
team just gets around a big conference
room and like tries to attack the the
sites in different parts of the system
and and it's made a culture where like
people will come and say hey you know
we're makin some changes to our
application next week can you can you
guys put us on your your Red Team Monday
list and you know go out the list and
and again that's it's one of those
things like as a security person like
crossing the chasm into into developers
and operations people like people that
we were really kind of like separate
silos from for such a long time now
they're kind of engaging security and
excited about it and through through
stuff like this and and I think that
this is a power to kind of be as
cultural so culturally significant is
like chaos monkey how it has or was you
know several years ago you know and and
I think you know sometimes we think like
well okay I have to worry too much about
my testing far-left because you know
inheritance and all the stuff in
containers and it's all you know
isolated or whatever but like Gareth
rush Grove as a talk on like what's
inside that container and you know like
a good chunk of containers have
vulnerabilities but surprise surprise I
know none of us in here are surprised by
it but like just continuing to think
through that whole pipeline and like how
to how to break that up is real
helpful for us the last one you know we
used to take a real process driven
approach and Jason Shannon over Netflix
II uses the words the paved road which i
think is really helpful it's making
making it easy for people to do the
right thing you know whether it's like
using gold images or having blessed
bills and dependencies or saying like if
you kind of go with the standard
processes like you're gonna get security
by default again like I think these are
each of these areas like I've just seen
like our are evidences of how like as an
organ distri like security has shifted
and I'm pretty excited about that and
that's why I still remain pretty
optimistic so I guess in the in like my
last charter is like hey let's not be
let's not be blockers but let's be
enablers of the business and I think
that's that's it so if you send me an
email if the slides and we can have time
for questions if you all want so thanks
you