[Music]
do this so it's called threat modeling
toolkit like I said my name is Jonathan
Marcille a small summary so I will go
with my background a bit of myself and
not that much but more about what is
threat modeling as well like we just
said we'd have some actual questions
because this talk is literally ten times
better if you ask anything so about in
the middle of their presentation you
will see slides about those questions so
please jump on it because we need to go
quick I have a lot of content ready to
go through and so our helper will be in
the middle of the room and it will just
jump at you with the mic it's important
because we are recording so the core of
this presentation is really like all the
toolkit components as you basically can
see so data flow diagram and attack tree
so I will jump right into it and so my
background I'm actually right now
application security engineer at twitch
I'm the OS major project leader that is
the project that will distribute this
kind of recording contents actually I do
have sixth sense eight-years blah blah
blah other years and stuff what you need
to know is that I'm really paranoid
about threats since all my life so that
those are all these three creds I need
in order to do that dog like right now
and we're out the exits or take out the
classes and stuff or far is the sea and
everything so so my threat modeling
experience it's basically like working
in a SDLC and doing application security
activities so I'm like kind of brought
up second-gen years that does everything
mostly because most of the time I don't
know I was alone doing it sniff and so
what you see right now it's basically a
drawing that I made it's boxes that says
those are the act the steps that you can
do it in your sdlc even if you're agile
it works and the arrows are the
application security activities that you
do during that so I'm really like super
practical I'm frontline and do all the
stuff myself always at my birth window
open and I'm actually very time
constraint as well so threat modeling
for me it's just one part of the thing
that helps me in order to be more
efficient and so it's not all that I do
when I do it it's always part of maybe
something else this talk is really
earned to share my enthusiasm about it
so it's not like a sales pitch oh you
should do modeling and stuff if you like
what I will be presenting then just try
to you
and then you will see by yourself so
what is threat modeling it's an
application security activity to analyze
the security in software development
that's exactly what I just told you
before I think it's there to really
system at least strictures the attacks
the bad actors that are the actors or
the bad persons and the actual contours
or are the so-called let's say security
controls there's another thing that we
call train intelligence and my own
definition I really tend to take it out
of the threat modeling part because it's
off of it but it's not really modeling
it's much more knowing about the threat
actors and what they have to gain it's
like a knowledge base of threat while
modeling for me it's more just the
methodologies and so the tool and this
talk so when why do threat modeling well
it's a common method for the security
practitioners as well as the software
engineers you sort of doing you sort end
up doing it by doing resign review as
well or at least that's a bad project of
when you do threat modeling you sort of
do are doing a design review at the same
time so it can be like like the same
activity almost in many cases is there
to us to clarify what the system is for
the reviewer so when you're trying to
understand a design you know to make a
review out of it then doing threat
modeling in some of the actual component
that I will show you it helps you a lot
on the understanding and then you can
use the model that you're building in
order to highlight the ameliorations or
also set requirements so it helps you to
catch important things even if like
everything it's messed up around you
like there's like the fire burnings left
and right and you drive like your small
tiny model of your understanding and
your like I do understand I am fixed
like I have a point of reference really
to go with and so that's all at least I
use threat modeling so it must be
collaborative because I think that most
of the projects they fail because lack
of let's see communication because most
of the people I've met in this industry
are like super smart the only thing that
they might lack it may be like how to
actually communicate with others
smart people and so when you do threat
modeling if you do it in a corner and
you're not talking to anyone then you
are doing it wrong because I really
think it's a communication tool so you
can still start the modeling alone and
again to see other people and say hey do
you think that this is good and then it
will engage the actual compensation
because people they love actually
correcting you when you're wrong and
that's actually a good thing when you do
threat modeling because the more wrong
you are the more they will be engaged
and the more the people are engaged the
more they will communicate and then you
will have some wins so there's a bunch
of existing methodologies because I'm
really time constrained right now and I
want to show you the bits and part as
you can see there's Microsoft SDL tool
there's a graph there's the pasta at the
bottom I will have some links that are
attached to that presentation so those
will be the actual tool kit components
so what you actually came for after 10
slides it's not that bad so the first
tool kit component and this presentation
is the DFG diagram so it's a way to
analyze the target system that you will
be threat modeling it's a data flow
diagram but not in my case I don't use
it that way I use it as an actual
connection flow diagram writer because
it limits the amount of visual every
time that I try to do a data flow
diagram it's always run a row in that
direction and other I ruin the other
direction and because of that it doubles
the number of arrows and most of the
time I ended up not needing it so I was
like okay I need to limit the amount of
actual like of what is on my screen so
because of that it's not really a data
flow diagram it focused on the attack
surface and vectors and so the way I'm
doing it is that when you have a port
that is open as a simple example you
have an arrow that points into that port
and then you know that that's the
direction of the network interaction so
it provides the dfd diagram or the flow
diagram as I might call it in area like
a security oriented view of the system
so it's a representation of let's say
you are the security reviewer in this
case it's a representation of
your comprehension of the system and of
course it will evolve with understanding
of the system design or architecture
changes that are attached to that system
and one thing that is really important
and I have to stress this is that it's
not an architectural document it's not a
thing that that really should be part of
the main the main set of documentation
that you might have because it's really
part of what you need in order to do
security so it focus on the details that
are relevant into security and it might
omit what is important for engineers as
an example you have a very complex
system and then you know that the
attacker face is much more up front
there's a lot of stuff at the backend
that you don't care when in your case
will you you won't just model it you
won't graph it you won't have any
representation of it and so this is
wrong
Architects are wise because it's not
complete but for a threat model like one
of the way of winning at this when you
are time constraint and everything is to
scoop it at what you think is important
at what is upfront and everything so you
might have met a lot so there's the
actual basic step and don't worry we
will go with example step by step that's
the core of this thing so there's a
square for actor there's a cycle for
process there's a double circle for
multiple process there's the arrow for
the connection flow like I said there's
the double line for the data store I
won't blame you if you're using like a
cylinder instead like everyone else
there's a red dotted line for boundaries
or any fronts here this is all by the
way Microsoft as the notation so the
example that I'm going to use in order
to trace a flow diagram is actually
kwhitaker NC so it's my own setup I've
at home when I deal with Bitcoin let's
say and so I'm the user I guess that's
me and I use the electron wallet that is
a software wallet that I have on my
machine that is used to store send and
receive bitcoins right so super easy
right now right then we add the other
components out
to use a browser and I have a mobile app
on my phone in order in order to get
some more information that are related
to let's see bitcoins and all that stuff
I also made like a small training but
it's not doing much right now but one
day I might be rich you know I also dig
and I look up electron Wallet as a
server side component that is electron X
so I graph that and then I also work
with an exchange so the exchange has a
website there's a back-end as well with
the website that I see then I can it it
has an exchange API and so those are the
the main let's see components of my flow
diagram or at least the processes as I
as I can see and like a trace right now
you have the Internet boundary right in
the middle so in my point of view on the
user side everything on the other side
is like it's in the cloud it's on the
internet so that's why I add the libel
so one other thing that I normally do
when i graph like this is that if I want
to expand something because my electron
wallet as I looked into it I realized
there's a GUI and the daemon that goes
with it so it's not just one single
process and in this case and what I
wanted to model I realized at the end oh
no I need to expand this really to make
it clear because it's an important part
of what I'm doing so many times you will
end up at the end graphing and then
saying okay I need to expand that in
order to make it more clear right now
you have it more at the beginning
because I just want to be consistent
with the steps other thing that I had is
the blockchain integration like I said
before if I don't really care about what
is on the backend I might just abstract
this I literally totally made it up and
so I assume they do some blockchain
integration
ere's the database as well this is all
made up but just as an example it fits
you have the my sequel database that is
for the user plus the configure the
exchange and then I assume there's a
MongoDB for the exchange IP is and all
the transactions and everything into it
so adding the let's see connection flow
arrows as you can see now the enter
action becomes clear between each and
every processes and so at this point
that's my comprehension of the
interaction of all the actual processes
altogether and you should be able just
to understand the same thing as myself
if you just look at that as an example
you know that my browser actually
accessed the exchange website and also
the backend as well because it's a
front-end back in architecture I have
also a weird thing that my browser do
connect to a demon on electron wallet
why that's curious
and you see that the exchange IP I my
mobile app use it as well as my let's
see trading but so this looks really
clean it's really simple but I might
need more informations into it when I do
threat modeling and so that's why I have
an extended set this is adding mostly
some colors and note I like to use a
text act label on let's see processes in
order to make it clear that this thing
is in Java this thing is in Python
because it might help me do some
decision later on because the stacks
might be important I also add a lot of
labels on flows because as you saw
before this is on labels so you don't
know why it is and so I really found it
really useful to document the flows in
the diagram so with that I'm just hiding
label on top of it you can add the state
you can have like a sticky note anything
you want actually like you can have like
a cloud 4 abstraction any color circle
for logical links or any special meaning
the domain real life is to keep it
visually pleasing and as minimalist I've
let's see possible you don't want ready
to look at a thing that is way too big
one of the reason that I say that is
that if you end up doing it and you see
this is what I'm working on it means
that you're working on too much at the
same time you need to scope yourself you
need to be focused there's a another
component that is at a table of the
security control and mitigations will
see it at the end so here's the graph as
we had it before and then I'm adding
some labels on the connection flow so as
you can see there's a
whew HTTP links there's a it's G Center
PC for the demon so I wanted to add that
there's one thing that I'm not sure
about between the mobile app and the
exchange API is it HTTPS I'm not sure is
it is HTTPS well implemented I I don't
know so there's a lot of notes and as
you can guess right now this is
literally my working document as I try
to work on the security of all this as I
try to understand and so I'm really
using it in order to organize myself as
well in this case it's a made-up example
so I did it by myself but in a normal
case I will GU see I don't know the
exchange the exchange people and I will
ask them is that right do you have this
as a database and so and they might say
oh by the way yes went to great with
blockchain but it's secret so that's why
I did as a cloud and so those are the
labels that I had so i've Electra mixes
in Python and then I have some react GS
and Ruby for the exchange website and
back-end no GS it on the exchange API
and my trading but isn't Python I
actually skip electron Wallet for this
either because I actually forgot about
it or I don't mind much it really
depends one thing that would you need to
understand is that a model like this
will never be complete we'll always have
errors most of the time if you remember
the rules that ad before that to
actually keep it visually pleasing so if
there's thing that is are not on your
scope let's say that I would just focus
on my life on my client side stuff with
electron wallet then the labels on the
exchange back-end and everything doesn't
make any sense and so you kind of have
to literally target the visual that you
are adding into your flow diagram that
way you will have a way clear of you and
it will be pertinent to what you're
trying to do speaking of which I was
literally I did this first and I was
like maybe there's a vulnerability
maybe there's a thing interesting in my
electron wallet and I ended up finding
that there's a JSON RPC vulnerability an
electron that has been not
release but raise one week before I
round that so it's basically if I at the
end point and I ask for a few comments
errors all the things that I can do
without being authenticated on it so
it's super easy and you just have to
make a request to that part it's a
random part that there's a way to find
it so that's kind of a real variability
that I found and I was like oh this is
interesting so that's why I'm adding a
note and I say well there's no
authentication Wow and so that way when
you see that model one thing that
actually stand out is the note that I
have about it even if I'm not making any
recommendation yet I don't know yet how
to do it and of course this is a step by
step process and so as you build your
flow diagram you will add some stuff you
will change it in this example I knew
where I was going because I went
backwards from the end to the beginning
right but normally you don't so you just
recognize and so there's a lot of let's
see playing around to organize
everything to keep it visually pleasing
because you don't want the arrows to be
like all messed up and so and you might
remove and have some stuff and multiple
process abstract other parts so as long
as you play with it and you're at ease
with what you're seeing I would say that
you're making like a good flow diagram
so the last thing like I said at the
bottom left there's the let's see
security control checklist so I like to
use that when I engage teams and I'm
like Ayers man the standing is what we
actually corrected about that
understanding and Ayers what I think
should be done in the scope of that
project or right now so I always try to
keep that least that list under maybe
seven items that way it's easy it goes
with the diagram you know visually where
they are so as an example I say number
one is in my electron wallet I need to
encrypt the wallet the wallet file what
is while it's at rest and right now I'm
not doing it so you see the X and
there's a green checkmark when you do
something right like number two my API
key is read-only when I use it on my
mobile app so this works great with team
because they love the green checkmarks
they just want to
ready to squash this it has a visual
representation of the system and plus
you don't come with like maybe 20 items
you're forced to be really keep really
concise and what you are modeling
because you're using that graphical
thing on the actual top left you can see
there's like notes about what this is
about who's the author version date so
that might be useful so that looks a lot
like many of the flow diagram models
that I did like I did actually quite a
few of them and they all look more so
like that so now's the time for the
questions like I said you need to ask
because if not this talk would not be
that good to encourage you I've made the
small progress bar to say yeah please go
on
I have a couple of questions for you
mm-hmm do you mind going back to the
diagram you your abstraction for HTTP
you kept just one arrow but we know that
a request and a response are very two
very different beasts that come with
different threats yes like I yeah so
that's always a challenge right how much
resolution you want to give and things
like you know writing and reading from
the database that's another transaction
that is very different and then how do
you go about the arrow direction because
those are the three things that are
mollys talking with people how many
arrows do we put on the diagram and the
directionality of that yes so what is
your heuristic yes my answer for that is
that when you find something that is
that absolute pertinent for what you're
tracing because right now I hope I've
been clear with this what I'm trying to
trace first is ready towards what part
one process is actually connecting
toward what I like to do is to use
another color let's say like blue and
then I graph in this example I don't
have it there I think in my other
presentation I did but it's literally
you have a data flow because I like
cheating on my own rules because I said
it's not a data flow doesn't mean that
you cannot add a data flow if you need
to and I think that you will often see
that you don't need to add data flow
every
we're because you don't need to focus
everywhere one of the good example was I
think with a callback that I had on one
website and then that callback was
actually redirecting after and so then
add a natural representation of that
callback directly on it so you can yes
you can totally do that my rule of thumb
ready to it is that is it pertinent do
you think there's a threat that is
around it is that in scope of what I'm
trying to model is that like a part of
the feature more than often it's when I
have a release sample asked about a new
feature that we're adding into a new not
a new system add an existing system with
a new feature and then I want more
details on that feature in let's say
particular I use an arrow that is
another color like that another funky
thing I like to do is to do arrows that
goes through a process go underneath
them and then it another thing that we
you can see that oh it's passing through
that process but it's not that process
was making a cow so you can be original
with it as long as it's clear normally
when I the data flow back and forth like
this add the notes like I have more
notes that goes with it that explain
that this is the flow of this really
coming back so you're not even saying
that it's the protocol at this point in
some of the things I don't know if I
have it in this example but you can have
also some details on the labels and you
basically can say oh this is the piece
of information that grows to that part
and so that might be a but you have to
be really careful like that like I said
be aware of not doing a data flow
diagram that is complete because if you
do that it will get super messy cuz you
will have a ton of arrows hope that this
answer your question right thank you
very much
another one so I got a question about
your data flow put your data flow your
throw model if you were to hand this to
a different security person in a
different company would they understand
your throw model I hope so I did
that that's a good answer actually I did
one example with like oversea people and
that was of the best threat modeling
team because as you can see I'm kind of
rambling when I talk I'm not easy to
understand this is because it's simple
words it's literally the system it's I
really keep it like super short and
sweet I'm what are my recommendations
and so and I also clear like a lot of
things because like I said very bright
people might say this is HTTPS and then
we call yes this is encryption and it's
also doing verification of the O's and
then somebody in the room say and this
is a true life event it was like no it's
there's no encryption when we do HTTPS
here and I was and we were all like like
what and then we understood that no no
we just like we said the cipher to email
and Ella laughs so I added a note on the
threat model just for that because it
happened to be like an actual
clarification so I think yes it does a
great job and I think that's one of the
main way that I'm using it cuz I
basically could keep all that in my mind
and then just send an email hey guy is a
encrypted file at rest use API key
read-only blah blah blah enter so all
they add is a boring email with just
like a list and they might say okay this
one they look at that it's kind of
appealing ready to say all that I wrote
and and I really really cannot stress
that enough
if you're too good at doing this please
make mistakes on proposed because it
will engage people they will correct you
and that's the stuff that you want so
yes I think it is like let's say if you
understood what I was trying to explain
about my own setup with electron and
everything then it proves that it works
are there places for exercising you know
working with them exercises for threat
modeling so you know since this is this
the first time I've actually seen it
demonstrated yes I'm not gonna be able
to go away and just go like oh yes you
can you know why because this is just
circles and arrows right if you cannot
get that from my talk it's because I'm
super bad at really conveying that but
you could directly start doing it
yourself like I did like I said don't do
it alone for real but ready for practice
you can just say okay I'm gonna I'm
gonna threat model that thing and
I will try to make like that diagram and
then I will think about the twist that's
basically by the way that's not all of
threat modeling that's just like a part
of it so it's a part of understanding
the system so it's the thing that you
can try like yourself and then you go
talk with a friend and you you just
continue on that right we are they
another question at the back I will try
to answer it really quick if we get to
the guy before that thing goes down
challenge go quick microphone please
okay
yes ohit's you okay okay going on okay I
would like to ask what would it be a
better approach for a sam'l based
authenticated application would it be
necessary for me to place a trust
boundary between the browser and the
service provider and then another one
between the service provider and the
identity provider another one between
the identity provider and the Active
Directory database another one between
the service provider and the target
resource URL or would it be sufficient
with just place one between the browser
the application and another one between
the application and they and the sam'l
provider my take on this is that if you
have a lack of bread at the end of
naming all those boundaries maybe you
are graphing too much of them I know
that the network people they love making
boundaries and stuff me normally I would
see that at the top number that I've
seen is maybe three or four boundaries I
really tend not to do that much because
when you're doing that it might be
because you're not decoupling enough
what you're doing right now oh it's just
a literalness
if for you you really care about it and
you want to cross it and you want to
make sure that by the way the boundaries
is supposed to be every time there's an
arrow that goes through it that arrow is
supposed to be more at risk right and so
if you think it is important yes do it
if you don't have any arrows going over
them or the thing that you might not
care you can actually mostly keep it
lighter with that I just want to answer
the next question because we're sort of
actually like let's
time constraint so I hope that this
events or the boundary questions thank
you really quick this is all fine and
dandy but what exactly is going through
your head when you're setting this up
are you doing this just solo what kind
of research was put into it to actually
get the overall pick yes that's a great
question in this case I was alone at
home and sad and I was just looking at
the system and I was doing some
reversing right so I was like here's the
electron wallet I did a google search
and then the rest I just made it up in a
real case scenario I will look at
architectural documents I would have
interview with people you can even have
like an activity that is you go with the
developers the architects and everyone
in the room and you make a big party
that you are graphing this and it works
because they love doing graphs and stuff
and yes they might have an architecture
already other document but then it's
there as a let's see presentation to you
and so they will just jump in and do it
so as long as you make it like let's see
collaborative I think you will have like
a good win and that will be a way that
you will find your existing
documentation existing system you can
reverse them but more importantly you
have to communicate with people so I'm
gonna jump right away in the next actual
component because we're off an hour in
and this is the youngest part so the
attack tree is the next component it's a
way to organize the trade intelligence
so you will see now that there's a link
that we will do between this and what we
had before so an attack tree is
basically just a simple tree where the
root goal is the root node is a goal and
the leaf nodes are the way to reach it
and other nodes are the sub goals it can
be flexible and have some logic gates
you have a small example here but we
will go with again super quick to
currency as the next way of doing it so
like I said this is a real goal what
okay you have to ask yourself when
you're making the attack tree what are
the attackers goal right that's the
first thing when you build an attack
tree that you do so you're like okay the
attacker want to steal go to currency
easy you might want to manipulate the
market as well because you can make
money out of this and it can use it to
invade your privacy right so those are
to example a ver as you can see it's not
complete maybe you have other ideas but
then we're time constrain we need to
focus so I'll just choose those let's
dig in to steal cryptocurrency I'm
adding an arrow mostly saying I'll do
you steal cryptocurrency well you can
gain access to a wallet and that way
it's like regular money if you just go
in the wallet and you steal it right but
then how do you gain access to a wallet
so you can either still a physical
wallet and the password with it you can
gain access to the local software wallet
like add with electron before so it's
just the software that runs on my
machine but then you can ask yourself
how do you gain access to like a
software wallet well you can find a
while let's see the city is basically
just a secret that you can recover the
wallet with it so if you find a secret
you can basically cheat and have the
wallet by yourself how can you find a
while let's see well maybe if it's using
a weed-like let's see sitting algo you
can brute-force it that's just an
example again I'm branching down as well
on the software wallet how can you get
access to a software RL if there's
malware on the system that might be one
way to do it and then gain remote access
to local API might be another way so if
you managed to find a way to get access
to that local API that the daemon was
answering as you saw before maybe that's
a way so I'm already breaking down right
now what I think it is and every time
I'm asking myself ow ow until I am at
the bottom and this is a good example of
a NAND gate and the bottom of it really
should be a let see security
vulnerability so in this case if we look
back at the actual Verity that I found
well if you have a town station bypass
and you can do DNS rebinding attacks
that are basically a wait to go through
a lock hello sport using a browser then
with both of those you can gain remote
access to local API at some point you
have to stop and be satisfied because
you know when you start asking all this
is made all this is made now it just
goes like infinitely so at some point
I'm okay with that I think I dig it
enough I don't want to dig on malware
more there is like I'm happy with that
so I will continue another way that you
can gain access to the wallet is that
you can gain access to a web-based
wallet this would be great right to
expand because it's like regular normal
day web backing right but we don't have
much time right now so I'm just gonna
skip it and also that's another great
example on like I said before with the
flow diagram with the attack tree if you
can scope yourself on the threat that
you want to organize let's see then
that's a good way of mostly saying oh
maybe this have already another attack
tree elsewhere that do it I don't need
to do it in this particular case because
it's not particularly - a wallet in
cryptocurrency another thing that you
can do to do let it to steal an equal to
currency is to run an Internet Khan
operation it's an IC o---- look it up
it's another thing that I don't want to
dig because it's not really app set it's
basically can use all normal operations
and do it so this is kind of a bridge as
you can see in the attack tree that is
really like risk base it's not just apps
X so that's a great way I think to link
like the attack tree with other things
that just have sex you could basically
dig it without any technical stuff in it
and it will actually give the same
result another way to steal
cryptocurrency is to gain access to the
exchange like we saw in the flow diagram
so right now just for the sake of being
clear for the slide and also when I work
on it
you can basically just take a part of
the branch and then they get on the side
so then I say okay how do I gain access
to the exchange well I can have access
to the API because we saw that there's
an API how do I get access to that API
well I can steal an account I can steal
the API keys or I can have an
authentication bypass on it another
thing then that I realize is that if I
steal an account I can gain access to
the exchange right away so I'm just
adding another rule like this and then
it means that how can I gain exchange
access by the way by default it's a
whore so it's like or you can steal an
account or gain API access
and I could consume like this most of
the time when I'm very time constrained
and I don't want to dig further but I
know that I should I'm just adding like
clouds like this or that thing that says
this we'll get along later so I did this
part of the attack tree on one side
that's the side that we had before so
all you need to do is basically plug in
in and add it and then your tree grows
and grows and grows of course make sure
that it doesn't grow too far again you
need to scope it you need to be focused
on what you need to do another is
manipulate the market well how do you do
that you can do a denial of service or
you can gain exchange access so this is
literally the same action that ad before
when I was doing the steal
cryptocurrency so that's an easy one
because I bet we can just say okay I
want this in the diagram that I have
before I'm just beginning in so I'm just
adding on top air when you play the
market and then it's done so you have
like your route go on top and you don't
need to do it that way so there hey
usability of what you're doing with
attack trees is awesome
another thing isn't very privacy if I
dig into that I can expose the spending
a bit of people okay and how do I do
that well I can view their actual
transaction on the blockchain did this
one I'm like I don't know if I'm super
tempted to linked it with anything so
I'm just adding it there on the side
ready to see look I won't probably dig
on that because that's not the focus
obviously right now the focus is the API
is around the access and maybe the
software wallet on my local machine so I
keep it like that so the way that I'm
actually doing this and here's the trick
right now is that I'm using plans UML in
order to code the actual tree so
everything that you're seeing here is
actually just like definition with
arrows and - one and another so that way
it's really easy to recopy pays to redo
and undo your stuff it's really a great
way of building it as an example I have
the spy one is basically like just like
the name for
the invite privacy right so I'm just
adding this at the end of my code and by
the way this is like alpha or one third
of it it's not all the code but I had
this at the end so add that before and
so that's the link that I'm so maybe I
should link and very privacy and then I
try it and then automatically when I
regenerate the graph it will realign
everything so of course you have to play
with it to have the right order and
stuff and maybe you won't like this cuz
I don't like when line crosses like I
know that I should embrace that but it's
kind of mostly triggering me so I like
having it like that because maybe this
is true that this is clearer again it's
the same rule of thumbs as before and
it's just a matter of are you focusing
are you conveying the right thing that
you want to talk because when you're
building this you're basically talking
with I don't know the business owner for
the goals you look at the pass at the
variability that you can have and so
it's really like a great way to organize
the top goal or the top things that you
might care about risk wise plus the
vulnerabilities at the bottom so again
another bunch of questions the one
before we're great so I hope we have
others let's go with the progress you
guys are too fast my progress Lawrence
we found that as we start doing threat
modeling and it becomes really important
to the business that people want to be
able to look at sort of metadata about
those meals or comment on them track
them and that kind of stuff the plant
UML looks really nice for having it sort
of as code but have you had any success
or any suggestions on helping other
teams collaborate comment refer to link
to aspects of the threat model so we can
help drive even more change with that
artifact yes again with that the actual
alternative add with that and this is
driving me insane
it's bullet lists that are infinite and
it's like you scroll you scroll on a
wiki page and when you have it as a tree
you can basically extract it and have
like a view of one part or you can just
browse through it because you can
actually have a story about all the
I steal cryptocurrency and go down and
explain everything but you can also do
it in an other direction so this helps a
lot with communication you can say oh I
have DNS rebinding attack right what can
I do with that if you go up the tree you
see that DNS rebinding attack goes up to
steal cryptocurrency and maybe it's not
as easy to manipulate the market when
you are having that so we can sort of
make a link with that so it helps you do
I would say maybe a cognitive links
between everything and because of that
when you will interact with other people
it will make it easier I think than just
a list or just talking about it you
could have like a meeting with people
and they are just talking and they say
oh this and that
and then you note everything and then
you do your homework and the homework is
let's trace it as a tree one thing n is
great is that you have to balance the
tree of course this I don't like my tree
I never liked my trees ever because I'm
like it's not balanced enough it's not
good enough but at some point you have
to say no stop because you will go
forever but it helps you a lot mostly
saying oh this is actually the same
thing here and then you refactor and go
through it so that this answer your
question
thank you any other we have time just a
question so you mentioned that you're
working with developers they love
drawing things and I think that's true
we've tried a lot of different kinds of
tools and really been satisfactory so my
question is basically working with
distributed teams teams that are located
in different geographies WebEx is
obviously kind of unsound drawing tools
or unsatisfactory so how do you you know
how do you get this so people can can
interact and it can all kind of
participate and adding to the threat
model than the attack trees what real
practical like what tools you use and
what do you do and what do you tell
people with the flow diagram as we saw
before you know it was more like a free
way of doing the diagrams right so you
could use a whiteboard and everything
this when I did it with my friend John
may go in the room maybe we did it on
paper in like coffee shop and so it was
like super awful I just thought about it
but I was
washing because it looks super bad right
but then anything that you might have
remotely maybe you have like a graphing
board dream or that you can do the times
that I didn't do remote were more like I
did my homework first and I came with
the things we just like did a review of
what I made and so I actually present
the team remotely but I could see it as
you can just work the thing you say
though about developers I don't think
they like making graph those are
architects developers they like to write
code so having plans UML it's actually
like I stole that from a developer
because they are using it for a like a
sequence diagram every sequence diagram
I see I think it's made of that plant
UML and so it's very popular for that
I'm just asking it right now in order to
I think like a tree so when you write
the code it goes so fast when I did this
and I was doing it myself
it took me let's see two hour to make it
proper and one hour to refactor after
and it goes so fast because you just
kept space you do like undo redo and so
I think that you can do it like in a
pair programming way and that could help
a lot and so it really goes with what
you're at ease with but most of the time
attack trees are ordered to do on paper
because of the refactoring the flow
diagram is easier because it needs to be
a natural flow it needs to look natural
so of course you're doing freestyle you
could generate it and then we organize
all that stuff really freestyle but the
attack trees normally they do really
well by code so I will encourage you to
try it at least to do it like in a pair
programming of it because there's it's
literally just labels and arrows right
and then you add one and automatically
it actually goes faster when you do that
well at least in my small brain it is
faster when I wrote it and I just
refresh the graph then I try to think
what will happen with the change and so
we can basically prototype as you go any
other questions
so let's what's add to that let's say
you wanted to roll out like attacked
remodeling to a group of developers it's
just had no exposure
modeling at least in my experience like
okay honest first time looking at using
like plant UML for this is really nice
but I am i myself have pitched threat
modeling exercises to developers that I
know and I've just told them straight up
look even if you do it on a napkin in a
coffee shop during lunch like if that's
all you do scan that and put it to the
wiki at least or something
what's your I mean you talked about this
you talked about getting developers to
possibly embrace this may be overdoing
it on paper know if you wanted to roll
this out to a new team what would be
your preference getting them to do
something at all or getting them to do
it the easier way so to speak with who's
a curious Mosel with attack tree as you
might see there's not much about what
the actual system is there might be
because there are some of the goals that
you can do with that system but I feel
that the attack trees are more coming
from a security background and then the
floor exam is more coming from an
architectural background so because of
that you don't introduce the same and I
think that this one is really useful
when you're brainstorming about what can
go wrong and it's also very useful when
you want other people in security to
review and add their stuff because
normally they will jump into it and they
will see you missed this disease and
that and you don't have a way to
organize it this will gives you like a
way to organize it and if you come in a
new team and frankly I did this like I
don't know but near like 100 times right
and flow diagram is like 100 percent
right this is like 20 percent it's like
I'm not doing attack tree as much
because they are servicing the security
stuff more than the actual architecture
itself so I do it less but I still did
it with a few things that were wondering
and we were brainstorming and it was
like not organized so many of the item
that we came up with were like oh you
can do this this this and that but I was
like but that's not at the same level so
depending on who you are engaging
because in your case if you're engaging
the developers first you might dig and
go down and start with already like the
top of the tree about the threats that
you met with maybe some of the p.m.
executive or the
like like other people depending on what
organization you are in and then you
come in with that and you're like okay
guys what do we think that we can add
that is like the technical layer so I
see a line in this that some people will
stop understanding what is going on and
I see a line that it's kind of the
guidelines of the actual like business
that will go to the bottom so at some
point if you don't want to waste time
maybe you should come with an attack
tree that is already made at the top and
then with the dev you dig him this can
get super messy cos if you want to add
other variabilities that you know and
then you just add out the cwe you will
end up with the mother of all three
that's the end game by the way it's the
end game but the end game will never be
useful for you because you will have to
scoop it and what you care right now so
we have to parse about it so I can see
like a system when you basically have a
list of all the bottom stuff and then
you just branch it and then you link and
so you might just do as an exercise the
top stuff because this is
business-related and then everything
just plugs itself in and so there's a
lot of things to do with that but
normally when I do it I'm just like
we're just trying to organize in order
to not miss or when there's another
person that adds into the threat model
you just say okay I'm adding you in a
tree it's way easier to parse the tree
when you add new stuff then when you
have a list of multiple pages that you
need to scroll down so I'm getting out
of time a bit so I will go ahead with
the lessee conclusion and after I will
take another question offline if you
want so there's a synergy in the actual
toolkit that is a link between the
attack tree and the flow diagram so if
you remember the actual security
controls that I show you while doing the
flow diagram they can actually be used
to be a way of mitigating the sub-goals
and so mostly preventing the explanation
so it's not like I'm breaking it it's
just like I'm mitigating it so this is
what it looks that I haven't done it
much it's kind of delayed stuff that I
didn't and I think it makes sense and so
in this one the end goal is to have all
the security controls that you might
like have in your thing have it to every
arrows that go to the sub goals so the
game in this
gays is to say okay I want to add a
control into everything and to all the
owl's that are actually possible in my
attack tree so that way you have a way
to organize and map the security
controls and stuff
this map might do better if you want to
be super concise not concise but more
broad because it may be you will need a
list of maybe 20 things and so maybe you
just do it for yourself as a review
that's just a thing that I'm throwing
here and I think there's a value in it
but I haven't had like much hands-on
experience so in conclusion if you need
to review the security of a complex
system the connection flow is your tool
because it will help you understand and
actually communicate with the people you
can use this in order to link other
activities in AB set say you want to do
code review well you can use a flow
diagram in your graph and then just say
okay here we need accurate review on
this component and it shows on your Ted
graph that diagram it's like your flow
diagram I'm used to do that all the time
I mean it works because of people like
you're just basically communicating with
them and that's the goal of the diagram
if you try this in a meeting and then
the people ends up really clarifying and
or improving the system while you say
nothing you just want a treatment and in
congratulation because it's just like if
they are self-aware of the
misunderstandings and then they actually
correct it and they make the security
better because of this that's the goal
of the actual toolkit companies and I
show you is to enhance the communication
so if you want to know more this
afternoon we have modeling panels with
experts
I'm also on it at 2:00 p.m. with Brooke
Adam in Azure so please come and I would
like to talk about I would like to
thanks all do wasp actual chapter as
well as twitch and I've said California
for inviting Mears so and big thanks to
you for all the actual questions it was
great if you want the links and to my
talk they will be in let's say ten
minutes on let's say Twitter right now
you have already the plan to your ml
stuff you have my source code right now
if you go on Twitter it should be there
you can eat me up my DM might be open
and this is my last email so big thanks
for your time
[Applause]
[Music]