[Music]
cool so yeah I'm they're excited to be
here today
and I'm gonna talk about kind of a
research project a co-worker and I have
been working on for a few years now and
has to do with basically us trying to
figure out if mobile devices all around
the world are being targeted for traffic
interception or man-in-the-middle
attacks and if that's the case why and
where and trying to figure out what's
going on again in the world and to do
that we've had access to a set of ten
million reports about SSL incidents
around the world and I'll explain why
this is but this is basically where all
the data we have is coming from just as
a quick intro we have obviously a lot of
data coming from the US and I'll explain
but basically analyzed many the
militants all around the world to try to
figure out what happened was it your
employer or was it something else again
looking at 10 million reports or 10
million attempts so first of all I'm
gonna talk about how we were able to get
access to these all these reports is
that data set and then I'll talk about
the data set of very high levels so
something like where where the data
coming from which countries what does it
look like at a high level and also how
we analyzed that data and then of course
I'll talk about the result of that
analysis which is really trying to
install the question who what where is
mobile traffic getting intercepted and
why and then of course a quick
conclusion but first of all so you saw
that map with all these dots and
well did they get access to 10 million
you know reports about manual attacks so
it all started a few years ago when we
released an open source library called
trust kid and actually somebody in the
room have worked on it and what it does
is it makes it easy for developers to
make the apps network connections more
secure using two mechanism that I'll
explain in a minute
SSL reporting in is happening and so
I'll quickly explain what risk it does
just so then you can understand where
all the data and I'm going to be
presenting it's coming from so the first
thing the library does is it's an iOS
and Android library is a sharpening and
logins spent too much time on this but
the idea what's happening is when your
app is connecting to its server using
TLS or HTTPS it's going to check the
server certificate make sure this
applicator is trusted make sure it was
issued for that whose name that you're
trying to connect to so that's the
default OS validation itself pinning is
when you want to add an extra step to
add validation at the very end and that
extra step it's basically hot coding the
key that you know is going to be used on
your server so if you look at that
certificate chain for the last remark um
if an app is trying to connect to that
server first it's going to all the
default audition and if you do pinning
you're also going to be requiring the
certificate chain to contain the key
that you know is used for the authorial
comb or some intermediate certificate in
this case and so you get that extra step
to validate and the real ultimate dream
is to hash the public key data you get a
hash like that and that's an SSL pin so
in your app or when using Kreskin you
have very straight validation which is
okay the sub gate is trusted it's all
good but now does the chain contain that
one key that we know is being used on
production because if it doesn't then
that chain might look like it's valid
but it's not the one that's on a server
so what is it and that's happening a
very quick intro the other thing that it
does and as this is these rates to our
resource is SL what we call SSL
reporting which is
if something goes wrong with the TS
connection the circuit is wrong in one
way or another it might be wrong because
the default was the addition failed so
the subjugate is expired or the name
doesn't match the CA it goes all the way
up to isn't trusted that's when the d4
validation fails and then when pinning
validation fails which is all of this
was fine but once you get to that extra
step
pinning validation fail and so as that
reporting is the idea that you want to
send a report learning you know about
this that this just happened for one
user are using their phone somewhere in
the world so that's what we've
implemented just kidding so it looks a
report it looks like this that's some
data about the app so we know which app
it is but mainly the host name the app
try to connect to and then the
certificate chain that the app received
when it was connecting to that server
which clearly is probably not the right
kitchen it's probably not the one that's
on your server oh it's something someone
the middle that's trying to mess with
your connection and you know we're going
to the details of that but that's
basically a report you can get again
when something goes wrong with TLS and
so the idea with that is that you get a
report so you can see what's going on
across all of your user base you know
how many users are getting the traffic
intercepted and why so we think is
pretty valuable and so when you enable
that interest kit you have the option to
send the reports to a server which is
hosted by deterrent for free and if you
enable that as a Raval you get access to
a dashboard that shows you some details
but the whole the whole idea of its
telepon is that you can you able to tell
when something's happening and how many
of your users are getting problems with
their RTLS connections and even spikes
you know give an example later spikes of
report meaning something is happening
it's somewhere in the world so I'll do a
quick demo just so it makes more sense
it's a recorded demo and so on the left
you have an real iPhone and under and
that iPhone has been configured what
sorry this here okay so on the left you
have a real iPhone and on the right so
that iPhone has been configured to have
all of its traffic go through a proxy
which in cases in this case is Berg
which some of you probably have used
before yeah so the lateral iPhone's not
the simulator and then I'm gonna build
an app and running on this phone and
what the app does all it does really
it's just connecting to a domain to data
from using the normal IP eyes but that
app has just you configured so I'm gonna
building in launching it doesn't do
anything that you can see in the logs
some errors and it's probably probably
hard to see but I'll read pin validation
failed for the Orinoco so trust key is
complaining because bean validation
failed and then it says report was sent
to something so that's basically
everything I just described and you're
gonna see in Bob the ripple that was
trying to get out to a server that has
all the data I just described including
the certificate chain that caused the
problem and in this case the certificate
chain that caused the problem is the
certificate chain that caused the
problem sorry is the one that's used by
Bob to try to intercept the connection
so this is basically the verb
certificate chain and so the ad was
unable to connect because Bob is sitting
in the middle and yep can connect and
this is our internal dashboard and so
once the ripple has been sent we receive
it and then we see all the data in that
report so when it was sent the domain it
was trying to connect to and then the
certificate chain that caused the
problem in this case it's portugal's
here which is the certificate chain
that's used by the Bell proxy
and then we do some analysis which I'll
explain later where we say okay this is
clearly a testing tool and this is the
proxy basically so they just kind of
summarize everything I just talked about
and now back to the research so the data
said as I said we received 10 million of
these reports and so they come from all
the apps that are using Triscuit and I
have enabled that feature what I send
the reports to us so we receive reports
from about 2000 different apps mainly
from iOS not because iOS is getting more
targeted or anything like that it's
because we have a lot more apps on iOS
that are using the library on Android
and we will use the library a lot later
so we have less apps that are using it
and there's like maybe 2 TV iOS apps or
something using it so 2011 apps all
kinds of apps banking shopping news and
if you look at proc countries again it's
not this doesn't that the US is less
secure there's more there are more
attacks it's just how much data were
getting from each countries and so
mainly the apps that we are seeing and
their user base on main in the US which
is why I was saying more data coming
from the US but one single school is
we've received at least one report from
every single country in the world but
most of the data comes from the US we
have a few big apps in Taiwan so we're
also getting that's why Taiwan is
stirred but yeah so just a high-level
overview of the data set and then all
the interesting things we've seen more
than three million unique certificate
chains so again that sort of key chain
that caused the problem that wasn't the
real one probably and also among all
these reports 22 percent of these
reports in the the soft key chain was
bad did not match the server hostname
so it wasn't actually an attempt at
decrypting atrophic or interesting
traffic it was just either miss
configuration or some kind of captive
portal and I'll talk about that in a
minute
that's what we call non
man-in-the-middle incidents so that was
22% of the reports so that's basically
the data at a very high level and so the
way we analyzed each report we used
different things but honestly usually
all comes down to the certificate chain
and so we look at the certificate chain
and all the fields like the issuer or
the subject and try to figure out okay
what what is this is this verb is this
some network device is it someone's
employer and we have a basically huge
rule set trying to figure out what this
certificate is based on again field or
you can add a rule for specific
certificate like known that CA like the
one that was used for the Pegasus attack
we never offer that we haven't detected
it but we have a rule for it
so anyway you can do all sorts of rules
but to give an example that's the rules
some of the rules we have to detect
tools like pen testing tools and
developer tools so it's just a Yama foul
it's pretty simple the first one is the
one you so live but we guess it's the
one that detect the world proxy and so
it just tries to look for Portugal CA as
the subject of the root certificate
fiddler is the same fellow is another
tool you can use to proxy apps except
the the subject is always called do not
trust fiddle root which makes sense
because you shouldn't trust it then
Charles proxy is slightly more complex
you have to use a regular expression
because the content of the subject
changes one thing you have to be careful
with with Charles Fox if you're using it
is that it's sometimes puts here your
name and then then it's kind of obvious
who it is because I think it uses the
computer's name and on Mac OS the comes
your host name can be your first name
and last name
that overall the rule is pretty pretty
simple
and then other tools so that's kind of
how it works
looking at the subject the subjugates in
the chain that was received and trying
to classify them I have another quick
example so this is a report we've
received almost server although the data
I just talked about the Abney and the a
package name the host name but again the
main thing is the certificate chain and
if you pass the certificate chain you
get the certificates and in this one the
common name the issuer is fortigate CA
so it go through our set of rules and in
this case that's a that's the all the
rules
there isn't one for four tickets here it
doesn't want for Cisco umbrella which is
another type of appliance but there
isn't one for four degrees here so then
it just the several flags the report
from manual review so someone has to
look at it and try to figure out what he
sees and then someone looks at it see
that says four tickets here it's
probably only going to be googling
photogate and then we know it's actually
a branded appliance from 49 which is
pretty easy to figure out and then we
just add a rule and then all the next
reports I'll come in with this get
automatically flagged as a corporate
appliance and the brand is 49 so that's
how the analysis work you know very high
level and we have I don't know how many
rules like that we have but probably
hundreds that we've built over time as
we kept getting more and more reports
from new devices or new things so that's
how we analyze the data now of course
what did we find
that's probably why everyone's here so
in weave as I said we realize yeah about
nine million reports and we've grouped
them into different categories and these
are all the categories and I'll talk
about each one of them in details and
that I'll talk about this one last it's
probably most interesting one but and
among all these categories we split them
into two groups
something I mentioned earlier
what I call the non man-in-the-middle
categories which are for SSL incidents
when the hostname didn't match the
sovaldi i was trying to connect to in
this case whatever happened it wasn't
trying to decrypt the connection I was
proof to silver or do anything it's just
the kid was just completely wrong for
that server and that happens that there
are values reasons why this happened
number one reason its captive portals
which I'm sure you know about so it's
when you're a living person here it's
when your other hotel at the airport and
you haven't logged into the the portals
page to get connectivity so you're on
the Wi-Fi but you haven't done the login
flow so you have like some connection
but you don't really have the internet
and some of these potholes they do
everything they can to redirect you to
the login page but if you're using TLS
they they just put your push certificate
that's just wrong and it's and then it's
just causing failures that's whenever
one category that nothing too surprising
we have some reports we haven't had time
to look at yet so we'll get to that but
again it's non man in the middle so the
host name didn't match so it's not it's
not going to be a huge deal it's not
going to be something that was trying to
spoof the server the next one which is
interesting Silver Mist configuration so
in okay is it's mainly one thing it's
when this the server certificate expired
and that's four percent of the reports
and we saw that happening live actually
for one app while everything was fine
and then the subhead expire and then we
start getting turns of reports because
it subtly was wrong and the app
basically couldn't connect anymore and
stopped working so it's a pretty big
number activity of several that are
misconfigured
unknown that one is interesting unknown
is four so as I was explaining most of
the analysis we do is on the certificate
chain but sometimes we get a certificate
chain that doesn't really have anything
we can use to
it is sometimes it's a subjugate issued
for localhost and it's soft sign and
there's nothing no company name no
nothing so then we have no idea what it
is and this is that category right there
it's when we don't have enough data
enough information to make any
conclusion which is sad but there's not
much we can do about that and the last
one client clock Miss configuration it's
when your phone doesn't have the right
time when the time is wrong then you're
gonna have TRS failures because maybe on
your phone it looks like the certificate
is expired but it's not experiments just
your phone time is wrong it's a very
small number as you can see which is
interesting because a few years ago
Google released some similar stats for
Chrome desktop and google.com and the
client called Miss configuration was the
number one reason why chrome moon wasn't
able to connect to google.com not too
surprising of course I think phones are
much better I figure out what time it is
then their stuffs but still an
interesting difference and that's all
for the non-manual category so again
these things when the such gate was
wrong so whatever device are kept if
Paul was there wasn't trying to spoof
the server it was just a failure and the
next group is what we call man in the
middle categories which in this case the
such keychain was I had the right host
name so it was definitely trying to
pretend it was the server the real
server enough stuff for the from the
bottom the first one dev will call dev
artifacts it's the one you just saw in
the demo its developer up interesting
tools the most popular one is just proxy
it's the one that most mobile app
developers use but osp's app is here
Fiddler's Oswego if you've done any kind
of weapon testing you know about all
these tools and obviously we see them in
the reports when they are used to try to
manual an app but it's more like
developer tools and again nothing too
surprising here and then the next
category corporate networks nothing too
surprising either it's basically your
employer who has set a traffic
interception to try to manage all the
data coming in and out and so we can see
all the you know the brands all the
different appliances that are used and
that's that's two percent of all the
reports we've had and so for for this in
this case basically what happens is
maybe you know at work you were given
some kind of phone like that's on the
corporate network and that phone has the
cop the IT teams private CA in Spri
installed x4 we also using a VPN so the
phone has customs here which is probably
see I used by the device that's being
used to intercept the traffic and then
so then your device traffic is getting
intercepted but again that's I mean your
employer would have notified you and you
would know about it so nothing too
surprising here again so that's for
corporate networks one thing that's
interesting about this category so
sometimes called lawful interception
so one thing we looked at was okay so we
have these devices that are intercepting
the traffic and they're probably your
employer and you know about it and so
it's again lawful interception but one
thing we've seen and there's been
previous research about that from
Facebook and cloud fair I think in
manjira devices the lines put in the
middle they actually tend to downgrade
the security of the connection and so
for 30% of the reports when the real
servers key was 2048 bits the key that
was used by the interesting device
was only 1024 or less so that device
sitting in the middle where your phone
is here was downgrading the security of
the connection so that's that's not
great and also I won't go into that but
there's a big debate about that around
here's 1.3 but I think we'll just want
my tweets about to be is I think so but
anyway it's a big thing with lawful
interception and then the next one pin
means configuration 34% that one always
kind of scary so penis configuration
means that you miss configured trust kit
in your app and so you set up pinning
but the pin that hashed I showed meaning
that use used it's not the one that's on
the server so the app tries to connect
the app is wrong about you know the
service key so it sinks it everything is
failing and when you ask it you can
decide if you want a pinning fail to be
a heart failure where the connection
just gets cancelled if you still let the
connection go through and so if you
haven't enabled enforcement for pinning
you up steelworks but it's sending tons
of reports because every time it's
connecting the pin it's expecting isn't
there and it syncs the server is wrong
or something so we get lots of reports
and if you are enforcing Toninho and
then you are just stops working because
it cannot connect anymore so sorry 4%
that number is kind of inflated because
again as soon as the the app is
misconfigured we get lots of reports for
every single connection however we
looked at a different number which is
among all the episode we can see how
many didn't have at some point
opening Miss configuration and that's
22% which is huge again if you have
misconfigured your pins I mean your app
will probably start working so the
reason for that I mean there's a lot of
pressure on mobile developers to to do
this thing opening and be secure when
everything from all sorts of reasons the
security in the grant is the truth is
most apt only need like pinning and
pinning and forced and there's a huge if
you decide to do it there's a huge
overhead and you have to be ready for it
because again as if the ski on the
server changes not the one you think it
is your object ops working and it's not
just an AI abstract idea it actually
happened it was pretty bad it happened
to mobile app from Berkeley the bank the
mobile app was their version of square
register so it was an app for stores to
take critical payments so you'd have a
phone and you would pay with your credit
card and they would use this app to
process your payment so if you read the
title so it was the end of 2016
users have been left without the
possibility to pay for purchases due to
legacy intermediate a sell certificate
which sounds kind of odd but let me
explain so the the back layer was
configured to do pinning on this one so
that's the certificate chain for the API
and the back layer was configured to
depending on the intermediate
certificate which is this one so it had
everything set up correctly everything
was working fine the app connects to the
server gets the certificate chain sees
that this is the right key and
everything works fine however the team
the the server team renewed the
certificate for this one because it was
going to expire and when they renewed it
the CIA gave them a new certificate but
also with a new chain so this one
changed with the news of keychain and as
soon as I deployed it then the app would
connect and this would be wrong
according to the app so they have been
anymore so the result was going to be
several thousands of customers of small
and medium-sized businesses will not be
able to perform any transaction during
Black Friday and during the holy
shopping period this will affect
hundreds of thousands of customer
transactions until the application is a
data and then released again so yeah
that was pretty bad and got even worse
because but they didn't want to go
through that obviously so they asked
their CA to do a special to issue a
special certificate that was still using
the old intermediate but to do that the
CA I want not going to details but to
really see I had to break a bunch of
rules so then the CA was in trouble and
now I don't think they exist anymore but
I'm not gonna you can figure out who it
is
yeah so anyway all starting from this
idea of win was do pinning and now this
so you have to be careful and again
we've seen 20% of the apps we can see
getting it wrong at some point so I feel
like this is not something that's
well-known like a huge I mean it's
better now there's a huge overhead and
risk when you want to do pinning and
then finally the last category which is
probably most surprising one as it was
to me spyware 39% and we split that into
three subcategories and I mainly talk
about this one market intelligence which
is where most of the reports are more
than three millions and then parental
control and AdvoCare you can probably
guess what this is
but Frost market intelligence so it all
started when we were getting any reports
other ways and these are the names in
the see a mobile expression digital
fiction all these ones but it's mainly
one company called mobile expression
which I'll talk about and then the next
one digital faction it's actually the
same company so that's
mainly who we looked at who investigated
so again mobile expression is the name
in the CA when when we get to rebut we
see mobile expression and we get a lot
of reports across yeah about 20,000
devices and it's only on iOS we haven't
seen seen it on Android again we have a
lot less data on Android so so as I said
before when we get a report about
something we don't know about
we just google it and so if you google
for mobile expression you find that it's
an elite market research community
dedicated to improving the mobile
Internet and mobile users are invited to
join our panel and help shape the future
of Internet simply by sharing your
mobile surfing activity with us
so it's act pretty clear actually that
there's something going on here it was
still surprising to me because I wasn't
sure how that technique that would work
how do you share your surfing activity
with them or anybody and so I'm gonna do
another quick demo to show you guys how
it kind of works I don't know which
screen ok yeah so don't look at what's
behind let's see all demo I'll put in
the middle so that's an iPhone again and
so if you go on the epsilon you search
for mobile expression you find them as
an app and inspire this company called
voice 5 and they actually have three
different apps TV check India is
actually digital reflections of
expression and my mobile secure which is
like a VPN at three proxy VPN client one
thing that's interesting is that users
become members of the mobile expression
research community
and as something you're gonna see in
every other app but pretty good reviews
actually dears it's digital reflection
members to easily participate in your
community and other things and then the
main one mobile expression same thing
you can help improve the mobile internet
in rewards and prizes including cash
gift cards and other things so if you
install the app and then you open it so
you have to activate it and when you do
that you get kind of a they tell you
what you're supposed to do and then you
might be able to win a prize in only one
week Amazon giftcard speaker of HGTV's
and so if you click on start now one
thing you didn't see is it does show
privacy policy just I had already
accepted it be following the demo so
there's a pricing policy but if you
cannot sell now it goes into that screen
that says install profile and it says
profile propels your device for
participation in the more expression
community and says contains email
account VPN settings and two
certificates if you look at that yeah so
there's a VPN the mobile expression CA
which is the thing we were looking for
in the first place and then even an
email account it adds an email account
to your device will username and
password and everything and actually use
that to send you notifications so if you
click on install then does give you a
warning so I will add the certificate to
the list of trusted certificates on your
iPhone and with the VPN the network
traffic of your iPhone may be secured
filter on our monitor and then once you
install that you have to pay attention
to the top of the screen because
something's gonna happen okay profile
install and then you can see the VPN
icon showing up and now I'm activating
and so know it seems like a not a VPN
right
and so then
going back to the app I showed in the
first demo which just connects to data
for Malcolm if I run it again this time
you're not going to see anything but
I'll show you in the next slide it's so
I just launched it and then it wasn't
able to connect and going back to the
slides on also that's receiving the
reports we could see one report for data
from welcome and the mobile expression
CA which is the thing we've been looking
for this whole time
and obviously we and I classified as
spyware so basically that app try to
connect to data for an outcome and then
run into an unexpected certificate chain
which is the mobile expression is here
certificate chain yeah this so what
happened they're sleeping on how
familiar you are with iOS so a
configuration profile was installed on
the device a configuration profile is a
very powerful tool that lets you
configure on an iPhone basically an iOS
device and it's mainly used by IT
departments to enroll your device your
phone into the corporate environment and
the VPN and email so it had access to a
lot of different things and in this case
the profile installed an always-on VPN
so that all your phone's traffic goes
through the servers and then you also
installed a custom root CA and if you
have these two things you have
everything you need to decrypt all of
the difference network connections
because all the traffic goes through
your servers and then here they have the
key for s here so they can decrypt all
the connections yeah so that's what's
kind of surprising to me
and then so you might be wondering why
is probably whose mobile expression and
why are they doing this so it's actually
pretty easy to find that they are not
hiding anything so it's they say it's a
service of comScore global leader in
measuring the digital world providing
insights into customer behavior and
attitudes so they're owned by comScore
and kumkum score owns a bunch of apps
including mobile expression in digital
reflection and what we saw there was
they promised there was some kind of
reward like a gift card or an HDTV or
something if you install the app in the
configuration profile and so some users
you know they have I don't know how many
users they have but they definitely got
people to install it but then they don't
get very good reviews so there's this
review which is pretty telling they
spent four weeks collecting data from my
phone first week I want an Amazon gift
card which I never received then they
never gave any more rewards when they
say you get something each week
contacted customer support and they
never replied I gave them a week and
still nothing but you're the final I
like the final sentence which is pretty
they got my data for free don't be like
me so yeah pretty sad ending so but
that's basically how kind of the model
of these apps and it's not just come
score but I think they are the biggest
one and so if you look at comes called
website so yeah they say they say like
this cable is based on a massive global
cross section of two million consumers
who have allowed comScore to collect
their online browsing hard on
application usage and processing
behavior so basically the business model
is they sell to other companies
information about app usage so if you
are company who's building some app
maybe you want to know more information
about your competitors how well they are
doing are people using them or you know
which apps is going like exploding right
now and is getting tons of traction and
they also you know sell things like
measuring how well your ads are
performing so all sorts of things but to
do all that you in basically need to
recruit install the applications traffic
yeah so we uniquely combined massive
scale which is not on method to turn
data into value so there are measurement
companies so that's I mean yeah that's
there's nothing illegal I guess I would
say is still kind of shady at least a
gray area you may be wondering okay how
can we do anything about it and it's
kind of tricky actually because so you
could one thing you could say is okay
let's get rid of configuration profiles
because they are so powerful and you
just you're just one click away from
installing something crazy right but
it's it's difficult because they are
used again by IT departments to set up
devices so you can't just get rid of
them because there's a real use case for
them it's just that are getting abused
in this case but it is pretty bad
because if your normal user not
technical I don't think you can really
understand the warnings and what you
know what it means and what you can
really installing and all the things
that are kind of confusing for example
the profile it doesn't get uninstalled
issue and installed yet the profile has
actually nothing to do with the app when
you're in the app and you you install
the profile it actually opens Safari to
install the profile so the app is
completely disconnected from the profile
and all these things cannot make sense
if you understand how it kind of works
but for a normal user next no sense like
if you uninstall the app the the
profession be there
but yeah so getting rid of profiles is
not an easy thing to do and you could
also ban the application from the store
but again only you need to install a
profile is safari so if you just open
one in Safari you can install it I still
think it should be it would be better to
ban it so people can't find it but it
doesn't prevent this whole scenario yeah
so I'll talk about it again at the at
the very end but I was market
intelligence so pretty interesting and
then the two last subcategories ad
blockers so I'll briefly talk about
those it's very small numbers compared
to that as you can see the one we've
seen so it's technically it's the same
implementation it's put you on a VPN
with a custom CA we've seen one on
Android called defend my Wi-Fi
automatically turns public Wi-Fi into
safe and secure private Wi-Fi I don't
know if I would agree and the company
doesn't exist anymore so the app I think
the app is still on the store I don't
know if the app is honest about still
seeing reports of people who still have
that installed but I don't think the
company exists anymore so that's one
thing it's once you install that unless
you know where to go and like it's in
the the settings pretty like pretty
hidden it may not be obvious how to get
rid of that if you are not technical and
another one we've seen on iOS is adblock
mobile but what's interesting is
initially around iOS 8 again you will
install it the same thing pretty on a
VPN installed this year and then it
would man in the middle all the ad
domains so not all domains but just just
the advertising domains but then they
got removed from the store I don't know
why I don't if it was up all of them and
then I got back on the store but this
time they don't install a customs here
anymore which makes sense because to
block ads you don't really need to man
the middle of the connections you can
just block the connection if you know
it's an ad domain
so yeah I don't know if Apple was
involved but it's pretty interesting and
then the last one parental control
yeah it's mainly one called cue studio
it's just tools we install on iphone 2
if you want to kind of spy on them or
just monitor what they're doing on the
phone so we have parental control one of
these tools I don't know which one I
like it because they call the person
spying on you is called an
accountability partner which i think is
pretty funny but basically it's just
tools to to monitor our device and that
was all the analysis and the categories
we had we've found so far so to conclude
so something we knew already before
looking to that is of course traffic
interception does happen you know at
scale anyone in the world at least we
knew about the employer use case right
and so usually it's not null issues
again if it's your employer it's not my
shoes we've seen a lot of reports where
user winningly share the sharing the
data for the world and we one maybe
again a gift girl something or maybe the
promise of security or blocking ads or
stuff like that for me this area is
again kind of a gray area I don't I
don't like it a lot but there's nothing
we haven't seen a lot of anything from
Apple Google on this and mobile
expression is still on the store right
now
you can donate if you want and so I
really think it's a great right and even
there's a privacy policy that everything
is there but I don't I'm not sure it
makes sense and I don't think users have
a chance of really understanding what
they get into and that App Store review
I should kind of prove that yeah and
then
another thing you know I talked about
which was the spinning miss
configuration which was the second
biggest category and and so it goes back
to all these that these examples of
traffic interception and I think as an
app developer you have to ask yourself
the question is the data in with my app
is it so sensitive that legal or lawful
interception is okay and it is fine if
the users employer can see it and if
that's okay I mean if it's a game or
again an ad that actually needs to be
used on the copper network then are
you're probably fine you don't really
need to do anything but if you feel like
the data is so private that even the
employer shouldn't be able to see that
and a good example is mobile banking
then that puts you up in a different
category and if if this is the case one
way to technically enforce that is
happening but if you're fine with you
know lawful interception you don't need
to worry about this I think but if
you're there and so you want to do a
star pinning you can use it it's do you
have more option on mobile compared to
the web so on the way their words expect
to do pinning which i think is pretty
much dead now because it was very tricky
and very easy to make you know a big
mistake
but what we've seen that works well is
you know using this thing we call as
cell reporting probably has all the
names well you can see how many of you
are getting a scene man in the middle
attack so getting that traffic
interested in and see how big of a
problem it is and who's doing it and
based on that data you can make an
informed decision on whether you
actually want to go ahead and do pinning
or you think it's probably okay again
you should only do it inning if you
really feel like you're unneeded
it's a huge overhead and there's a huge
risk of catastrophic failure like what
happened to Barclay so you really should
think twice before doing it and if you
want to do it it needs to be planned
carefully the server
it's fine it was the Foley and the
server team needs to be needs to be
involved because they are going to be
rotating the keys and the certificates
so they need to be a lot of
communication happening for this to
succeed and one thing I've seen a few
times is well the main reason for doing
pinning is to prevent reverse
engineering of your app if that's the
main reason you're going to run into so
many problems and it's not very
efficient at preventing reverse
engineering anyway so this is the only
reason it's not a very good reason I
think so something to think about and
that's all thanks Aaron
[Applause]
any questions yes you have to wait for
the phone do any of the mobile app
security checks like you know mobile
safe or anything like that
pick up the insertion of CAS to detect
this because any application could
install a CA so I don't own the Android
I think yes I'm more familiar with iOS
on iOS but I don't think an app can
detect that if you're if you're set up
as an MDM so you have like a special
admin privilege on the phone so it's
like again your IT department they
probably can detect that but an a by
itself trying to see the list of CA
that's it so that you can't do that only
ways yeah okay so in your research were
you able to find out who exactly was
purchasing that information from mobile
force and whatnot because it's really
Shady what they go about it and you know
as a business a business owner would you
be like well do I really want they took
it from very unethical means I really
want to purchase data for that is it
even viable at that point so I think the
buyer of the data is only maybe half
aware of where it's coming from they
kind of know but not really but if you
think about it
tech companies they are probably buying
this so yeah do you see any apps using
like the public key pinning to like do
different things once they see like a
like an interception like maybe like a
big warning bar across the top or like
maybe now you change data yeah so I've
seen different ways to handle that
honestly if it's happening in the app
again the best thing you can do is send
a report so you are aware of it showing
something that the user can't do
anything about it so the best thing you
can do I think you'd say the app is
unable to connect try again later or
something because they're not gonna be
able to do anything long do you take a
view on using certificate transparency
instead of pinning as a way of trader
tracing and finding out when someone's
man-in-the-middle in your app yeah I
mean I think self-forgiveness message is
great it has proven already multiple
times that it's super useful I think you
can use both because certificate
transparency well right now this it's
too early to use it so that it would
block the connection if something is bad
with the subhead chain to do that to
block the connection you you need right
now this unit pinning I think there are
mechanisms event to that you'll be able
to use where if the circuit is not in
the transparency log then it doesn't
connect but I don't know how like I
don't know if this is already available
and yeah oh yeah it's it's amazing yeah
for sure
so two questions one do you know of any
tooling to help track changes to the
certificates to help you update your
pinning and second do the libraries for
doing the pinning validation support
checking against multiple public keys so
that you can transition from one cert to
another yeah so I'll start with the last
question froze yeah so all they're
pinning like were all good cleaning
libraries should let you in multiple
keys yeah that's that's something you
read so and it's part of the
the strategy you should follow if you're
doing this because you need to pin one
key that's the one that's being used
right now you need to also be in another
key which is a backup certificate if
something goes wrong with the one you're
using you can quickly swap and the app
already knows about it so by design
you're pinning I must be able to do that
if it's if you only suppose one key then
that every is know should you should not
use that your first question monitoring
when the certificate changes I don't
know but probably there has to be some
service that does that well yeah if you
want to do it yourself you can I like
always I don't I'm not sure but does
HSTs help prevent this assuming that
they've connected to you once
successfully the first time so that that
connection is cached I'm not sure if
more than don't use port 80 is cache
then beyond that such such that it might
have the key or the hash rather yeah so
it's just yes it's more it's does
something similar but it's more in the
browser office if you're in Safari or
answer the mobile apps yeah so on iOS
the mobile lesson do support it is yes
but it's very I'm not even sure what it
really does because there's some level
of support but it's not like in the
browser so HSS is mainly for the browser
yeah
all right I guess cuz that's all thanks
[Music]