kibou up a hooter manga called taka Puma
wanna Tim wanna know out here or a hope
I found out my uh Howie II Kitty kill
Aurora IT boom a kia ho eat a marui
called Tamaki Makaurau and know who and
a ho na na cannot a Pakeha te we coach
on Harris can I repay who is my Mountain
the hierarchy golf is my scene I am from
New Zealand I am born in Hamilton I grew
up in Tamara Louie I live in Oakland now
my people are not I Pakeha I am Shan and
I am here today to tell you a security
tale I've worked in information security
predominate in the financial space for
the past ten years and external or
internal roles and I was the Equifax
information security officer for New
Zealand pre breach and post breach
so this talk covers the experience I had
as working in that role which is the
equivalent of being a security
consultant here in New Zealand the time
period covered in this particular talk
is from August 2017 and to 2019 when I
left the business I was not powder the
technical IR I am in no way shape or
form able to talk about that but when I
can talk about my experiences that I had
and responding to the breach from here
in New Zealand working with the global
team and if you're a customer of Equifax
you can be confident and then meeting
your needs and then supplying what you
need I've been know a little toomai to
my former employer and this talk is
purely educational so needs to begin so
in 2016
I joined Equifax Equifax purchase feeder
reader became it perfects I was there
for a year and then 25th of August 2017
I traveled to Atlanta Georgia to meet
the global team there was a week-long
conference
amazing group of people it's one of the
best security teams I've worked in this
was this was a global information
security officers so consulting the
business non-operational they just their
compliance all of that type of thing
I was there had a fantastic week jumped
on the plane came back was ready to get
involved in a whole bunch of different
conversations and initiatives when on
the 8th of September the breach
announcement came now as you can see
when I came back from Atlanta on the 5th
September no one than that team had been
notified that was a bit of a shock
because when the announcement came on
the Thursday night US time no one knew
I've heard stories from teams that were
there at the pub and it popped up on the
news that affects had a breach and
they've had that they found out by the
by the pub Lord coming over and saying
hey you guys are from Equifax right I
see your bags well you know about this
breach so that cells some other teams
found out for me what happened was I
came into the office on the Friday
walked and passed the team of New
Zealand's addictive assistant and she
said ah so Shan what do you know about
the data breach and I just go you know
okay what what data breach haven't seen
anything sit down at my desk and in the
in the email start in my boss who lives
in Sydney contacted me and said buckle
and something's going on and off we went
so that's not the ideal way to find out
about a security breach in any way shape
or form my first reaction on that was
just total utter shock and despair
because what do you do there's been the
breach once at your parent company
you've gotta know you've got no idea
what's going on they're not telling you
anything you would just fear in the
middle trying to answer people's
questions add to the fact that the New
Zealand company knew that law was in
Atlanta and everyone started coming to
me for answers and I had to purely go I
I don't know so I get pulled into the
GM's office and the first thing you do
and that situation is that you go well
how secure a we you know we've got our
yearly assurance exercises where you get
a reputable firm and to test everything
there happened three months ago but you
start doubting everything and I'm
forever thankful for the fact that the
company that we use I got on the phone
called up and said here shown here from
Equifax and they're able to pretty much
give me a slot that Monday to help and
just redo an entire entire web facing
environment and for about two weeks
after that I'm just I'm just depressed I
don't know what's going on I'm not
getting any information I've got a
one-liner from from HQ saying hi you're
don't worry you're not you know you're
not involved in the breach Australia in
New Zealand are separate and for New
Zealand that was kind of enough because
people would call me and just say are we
you know how are we involved in this no
we're not okay can give me something
official no not yet okay please give me
one as soon as you can but this is where
I guess my my journey started to change
from my peers as the other countries
they had a lot more assurance activities
my manager for the next three months
after this I think he had 282
client meetings and three months during
during the work side of things so I kind
of lost check with him because he was
looking after Australia and New Zealand
there's only two of us to cover the
region at this time whereas for me what
happened was transformation activities
begin where to the three weeks it to the
three weeks after the breach
announcement there was a global company
white communication saying right we've
got this big body of work I need you to
help scope this okay but for that to
occur because they're a global company
you had the main side the things in
Atlanta which was pretty much just being
told what to do by the US government
various regulations and compliance
bodies over there saying right here
here's these number of streams which I
think got up to 28 and then they would
communicate it to Australia in New
Zealand and you're expected to kind of
tow the line and prioritize
what's going on now I was in an office
of 60 people of those 60 people I had
two development teams at the time those
two development teams were on required
compliance activities for New Zealand we
couldn't stop to do that so the security
remediation team became me I was it I
was promised contractors that would
start up soon but because we are still
going through merging activities we had
all these people lined up to start in
December and steered what happened is
that our you can't use I can't use those
agencies anymore here's a new one which
meant that I didn't get my resource
until April which means for me for six
months I was pretty much on this project
along with the head of QA and the head
of solutions architecture for New
Zealand so these three people trying to
work out how to attack all these complex
problems so I stopped being a consultant
and more back into operational
activities you know I over this period I
was be a Solutions Architect p.m.
helpdesk just anything anything that
needed done that would come to me and
that kind of put me in a weird position
because I was now the I was now the
focal point for all of these activities
going on around New Zealand reporting to
Australia that went back to the states
right this big long giant reporting
chain and so what would happen is that
my name would be just dropped into
everything so I beginning emails and
phone calls and things all throughout
the day because I was the main contact
point which meant my day at this time
started like this and this is how it was
for a good nine nine to twelve months
from memory I kind of wake up at six I'd
see what they'd come through from the US
because if something had changed
overnight you need to go for the project
across in estream I knew today I was
going to have to fix something or work
with the team to do that I'd get into
the New Zealand office from there I'd
have about two hours to myself to figure
out a plan of attack for the day and
what was going on and then from there
Australia would come a line come online
around 11:00 and they'd suddenly have a
whole bunch of more information so any
plans are made during that first five
hours we now changed
prodigies are changed no please don't do
that you're doing this now I've got this
doesn't matter go on to this then from
there I'll work on that till about five
o'clock in the afternoon then I'd go
home I'd done my bit but then you'd get
the end of a messages from people saying
or hang on I don't have this information
I need this now we need to report this
this is going in a report bla bla bla
bla bla needed next day at Congress like
all this type of reporting information
which I didn't have to bug my that the
New Zealand team to find information on
now one of the core pieces was that the
infrastructure so other things was
mended out of Australia and I can tell
you now if anyone here is supported from
a team in Australia and a breach happens
they are looking after their own do not
for a second think that because you got
in the SLA that they look after your
company in the time of a breach because
all resources are just being chucked
over there it's it was a really trying
period and essentially I deserve to lean
on or the political capital any
friendships or anything to get done out
of the Australian team because they were
wrapped up in Australia everything else
I had to kind of do by myself in New
Zealand with an outsourcer and there was
only so much I was able to do during
that time so that brings me onto these
slides which is just some when you are
call that in a in a post for each world
security is very different because it's
no longer he's our strategy here's our
long-term goal we want to do this in
three and four years that's now high
we've got eight months to implement an
array of controls that are very complex
let's go do this and you're no longer a
technology function for me and felt more
like a product and the product you're
trying to get out is security and your
customer is regulators and compliance
authorities and the the cost of doing
that is not it's not loss of sales or
anything like that there's huge fines
and potentially going out of business
that's a Glee different environment to
work in and if you're in a multinational
company and you're doing all these type
of activities make sure all your
territories are on the same using the
same project methodology
also happen at this time is that we
transitioned from with our waterfall
projects to agile agile safe I thought
okay this was going on worldwide so
there was a period of six months we also
became an agile coach scrum master
because of the fact that I get the Syst
of 28 28 different activities and I had
to prioritize that put them in Sprint's
all of that estimates do all of those
things because that's what we were using
down here in Australia there in New
Zealand and when we were reporting back
to the states I kind of just just didn't
feel right be like what you're doing
this where's this priority why aren't
you doing all of this in parallel but I
later found out like every like a year
later that they were still using
waterfall methodology so if you're
reporting on agile to area which is
using waterfall we've got a mess of all
the communication massive loss of
communication and that just makes things
harder which is why carrying on with
carrying on with with my day you know
I'd go to bed ten eleven o'clock at
night with what the phone at the side of
my bed and then you know at the time I
had a fourth my daughter was four years
old but she should be waking up at night
so I'd wake up the porter back to bed
and in that spinning up two or three
hours or she's asleep responding the
changes and things going on I'm trying
to figure out what's going on - whatever
contractors picked up the ball whatever
PM's testing me just trying to find
information so I can be prepared when I
wake up make sure wake up and like an
hour or two that I know what the next
steps were the next day and what works
in your country or territory may not
work in another fight for what you know
is right by your people one of the
biggest challenges which I had is that
New Zealand is pretty unique in the fact
that there's no local cloud presence in
New Zealand that's all in Australia and
with that comes all types of data
sovereignty issues so when you're
looking for moving things to the cloud
as a pattern and the global company cool
that works in every other territory
because they either don't have any data
sovereignty or they're hosted in country
but with New Zealand that's tricky
because if you want to take advantage of
AWS a juror or GCP or moving stuff to
Australia and there are specific
contracts and clauses
and regulations which require certain
amounts of data to stay in New Zealand
and it was kind of funny from the fact
that Here I am I'm down in this little
corner of the world two reporting layers
deep to to the states and I'm the one
kicking up the fuss about moving data
anywhere offshore unlike coke that's a
global patent doesn't work for us can
you please support us in other ways and
the biggest fights I had wasn't with
other parts of the business it was with
the security team saying why can't we
use the spec and why can't why can't use
this pattern why can't we deploy why
won't you just do this can we do
something like just put it in there and
ask for forgiveness later and I just had
none of that not having any type of
thing happen on my watch to New Zealand
data just so things can get fixed right
because I was comfortable with the
environment
I still am no need to change it so
there's that side of things and then
post breach business incident response
personal the people with the most
knowledge in your organization that you
rely on the most the one to two people
that know everything about the company
have been there from day dot they are
the ones that suffer the most they are
the one that's pulled in every direction
imagine having 28 different projects
dreams come to you for information
because I need to for that this bridge
sheet there form anything like that in
order to get things moving though that
person becomes squeezed they're going to
become unhappy I'm unhappy because that
person is unhappy and it just ends up in
the giant just a giant pit of despair
because you see them being hammered
they're being hammered along with you by
all these are the 28 different project
teams and whoever's on dick that day and
that's in it's tough it's very tough
because I liken the situation I was in
to if you think about the project that's
going live a big project then you've got
those three or four days where it's very
intense everyone's on board everyone's
fighting to get it done fixing any
issues imagine doing that for over a
year and the toll that would take on
anyone inside your organization in the
loan a company of 60 people
we're only probably 20 I think it was 20
the 30 where IT staff right that is a
mess of toll mentally and physically
you can't fake who you are under stress
now I mentioned this am I my purple
contour where you know who you are
and if you're trying to put up some type
of front will be something you're not
when you're in one of these situations
you're going to be found out because if
you're doing this for a year
something's going to give so this is
where I found out that empathy is my
biggest strength I may not be the
brothers technically but I know exactly
what's going inside the business how
people are feeling how I can get them to
work I just need to protect them from
what's going on so they've got the
confidence and the time to do what
they're paid to do and your mental
health food deteriorate this job broke
me I've got no shame in saying that this
broke me and this broke other members of
my team I know if two people they got
Hospital hospitalized for stress and
anxiety and exhaustion there are a
number of people who missed family
events holidays school events anything
and everything because something needed
to be done I'm pretty sure the team in
the states worked 18-hour days six days
a week for this whole period because I'd
come on a come on on Monday morning he's
a whole team working Sunday night sort
of like midnight in Atlanta right and
that's that's the hidden cost that means
we're health of people that they are
working on this project that's hidden
the hidden behind the window success
stories the high we did this and look
this is amazing it's hidden behind stock
price it's hidden behind we spent this
amount less security because the real
cost is as to the people now this became
apparent to me because after a year of
doing this going back to Atlanta and my
whole team was still there no one had
left apart from one team who managed to
or get transferred like a certain place
a year afterwards in Argentina but I'd
been there for a year I was absolutely
empty and our between of the after
Atlanta the go for a go on holiday with
my family for a month and Greece in the
UK this picture is me with my daughter
at the Olympic swimming pool in London
now I used to love taking her swimming
and this is the first time on dinner in
years and kids that you know when
something's up because this photo was
taken just after she told me daddy I
miss you take me swimming and that's
because while I was involved and
although this work
I wasn't prison motion emotionally or
mentally I was there but I wasn't my
mind was elsewhere or my energy or my
emotional energy had gone and the people
I'm working with to make sure that they
were protected that they had the space
to do these things that I felt oh yeah
it was me it felt there's other if my
family down and my daughter down so
thanks to Equifax for an experience no
training suit or anything can either by
and thank you for listening
[Applause]