- Hello, everyone.
My hair has been causing
problems with the microphone.
So hopefully this all works fine.
Access control on Sesame Street.
Yeah, so Matthew Daley, Matt Daley,
Principal Research Consultant
at Aura Information Security,
and general weirdo.
Without further ado, let's begin.
Now two things.
We're doing this live.
I've only seen this talk once.
And so I've seen it one more time
than everyone else in this room.
You'll see why soon,
but I lost access to my slides
rather late in the process,
and had to redo them all last night.
So if I seem a bit out of it,
and I have no idea how much
my time limit is going,
it's 44 minutes still, great,
then that's on me.
And this is also a information
dump on a bunch of research
that I've done over the last few months
on Gallagher Card Systems.
A talk is not the best format
for here's list of op codes
and here's a list of data
types, and stuff like that.
So after this talk,
I'll be releasing information
in a more usable format,
bunch of documentation and source files.
But for now, you get this melange
of bad art and information.
So let's start with what the
average access control system looks like.
So you start with a controller,
and you usually have,
on each door you'll have a reader,
and an RFID reader,
a lock, so like one of those magnet ones,
and an input which will tell
whether the door is actually open or not,
so it can beep annoyingly
when you leave it open.
And these are all connected
to the controller, usually,
and they can be connected
directly to the controller,
or they can be connected
to an IO breakout.
But either way, you'll have
lots of those three items,
connected to the controller or a breakout,
and they will connect to the controller.
And you might have more
IO breakouts as well.
And then you need some kind
of administration tool here.
So Officer PC is a terrible name,
It wasn't the Officer PC, but
this is meant to represent
the P.C. that the security guard would use
to see who's on site,
who's trying to break
and what needs to be attended
to, that kind of thing.
And then you'll also have
a administrative console.
So this is where the site installer
can install, add new hardware,
set up new cards, fix
faults, that kind of thing.
So it's pretty obvious, really,
the idea is that a user
will will scan their card,
hold up to a reader,
reader will send that information to
the IO breakout board,
sends it along to the controller.
The controller has a think.
To see whether that
person is A-okay or not,
says, "Yes."
And then usually the IO,
it's the IO break-out board,
it's that board's job to
unlock the door and make the
reader say a happy noise.
So how does this badly drawn diagram
fit within the Gallagher
brand access control system?
Their marketing material
is a lot better than this, for starters.
So let's look at the controller first.
So the Gallagher state
of art controlaghar,
controlaghar?
Wow.
(audience laughs)
I just gave you a new brand name.
Controller 6000 is the current
state of art Gallagher controller
This chunky brick size
thing, about this big.
And it's scalable, intelligent
control, blah, blah, blah.
All you need to know is that
those green blocks on the side
are where you can
connect in other devices,
using protocols that
I'll talk about shortly.
And the ethernet cable on
the right hand side there,
for talking to the
administrative consoles.
Yeah, okay.
And then you also plug in a,
you can also plug in
additional plug-in boards
from the bottom, to additional,
have more doors for
example, it's configurable.
The idea is that this
is just the top part.
Then you'll have to slide
this big chunky thing in the bottom.
And then you can have this
customizable basically.
Before this Controller 6000,
there was the Cardax FT controller 3000,
which comes in green
and also a fetching red.
Now Cardax was the previous
name of this technology.
And, I will admit, I don't
know the business background,
but I believe they were
bought out by Gallagher
at some point.
So you'll see references
to Cardax and Gallagher,
kind of interchangeably,
especially from me,
because I don't know which
one is considered which,
but the idea is that
they're interchangeable.
It's just brand name changes, basically.
And yes, on this chip, on this board here,
that is an Intel i386.
So that's the era that we're talking about
for these Cardax technologies.
I think I'm the only
owner, and I don't know,
but it took me so long to get this book.
This book helped me,
helped me reverse engineer
some of the firmware on these things,
which uses an embedded DOS based...
Well it's embedded kernel
that pretends to be Windows.
And it runs on 386 CPUs,
and the book is from the era
where ARM is a up-and-coming technology,
and soon we'll have 32 bit and 64 bit.
So that's very cool.
Okay.
So now that we've seen
you got your controller.
Let's have a look at a reader.
So this is the current
state-of-art in reader technology.
T-20, it's like the
Terminator or something?
It does all the things.
And then you've got all the other crews.
So we've got long boy,
bigger boy, square boy.
(audience laughs)
But there is reasons
to use different ones.
T-15, for example, is
very weatherproof, yeah.
So these are what Gallagher
wants you to be using.
And for good reason.
Unfortunately, what
you'll see out there still
is from the Cardax era.
So this teardrop reader,
it's called and by the way,
all the readers have this
trademark green squiggle.
Which is not an S, it's
the opposite of as S,
as I figured out alarmingly
late during all this.
But, yeah, Cardax reader.
Then you got this bad
boy, it's got a keypad.
Does the same thing, but
it also has keypad input,
and nice LCD display.
And then you've got
the formidable, chunky,
good old fashioned, I don't
even know what that's called,
Prox Plus, I believe, Prox Plus 125.
Now I got, just as an aside,
I got all of these pictures from fccid.io,
basically they take the FCC,
The Federal Communications
Commission, or whatever it is,
takes their god-awful website,
and turns it into a usable format.
So you can look up companies registration.
So, for example,
here's all of the things
Gallagher had to register for FCC.
And for each of these things,
you'll see a bunch of useful information,
including user manuals,
input, user manuals, photos.
Most importantly, you get internal photos,
which can be really helpful.
Yes, I couldn't be bothered rotating it,
and I'm very thankful to
Dave, Dave, Dave of Dave
(audience laughs)
for doing these things.
I don't know why I bothered
blanking out the email there.
(audience laughs)
Okay.
And then the Officer PC,
for lack of a better name, monitoring PC,
that takes the form of
Command Center with Gallagher.
I do have an installation at home.
As you can see the only events I ever get,
is that I've pulled out the controller,
and plugged it back in again,
because I'm trying to break something.
So there's not much
interesting to look at there.
And Gallagher will probably
be annoyed that I don't show
a nice, much more meaningful,
interesting display.
But this thing can do some
pretty amazing things.
It can, yeah, it can
turn on and off your AC.
So when someone walks in a room,
it does all the, turns
everything off and on.
You can have it so that people's lockers
are controlled by these T-20 devices.
You can even have a breathalyzer.
So people aren't allowed into a room,
or they are allowed into a room,
if they're drunk.
(audience laughs)
So there's lots of amazing
things that this thing can do.
But, you know, 95 percent
of the installs you'll see,
it's just annoying people with
cards to get into the office.
And then the administration
PC looks like this.
Administration console looks like this.
It's a... It's that.
And you can configure everything here.
There's a giant menu called configure,
and it has literally everything.
So, yeah, the Gallagher
system, same thing.
Controller, then you
have breakout modules.
And then you have all your readers.
There's actually a lot more,
as you can see in this
diagram, that we could go over.
Considering it started off from
very basic things like this.
Now, yes.
So why Sesame Street?
Might as well get straight to that point.
And I only know the top eight
of this group of people.
I don't know the last four,
orange dude, red dude,
freaky brown thing, and blue one.
The reason is,
it's because those are the
code names that they used.
As I discovered,
Gallagher uses these code names,
or Cardax did, and Gallagher
still does for their products.
So, for example, the Controller
6000 that I talked about,
well, meet Grover.
The Cardax FT 3000,
meet Bert.
And Command Center control
platform, meet Elmo.
And for the F-, I didn't go over these,
but the F-Series fence controllers,
these are used for electrifying fences,
and telling you when
someone's touching them.
or when you're giving them a
nice free bit of electricity.
That is code name, you know this guy?
That one.
It's Frazzle.
I thought Frazzle is a
very good name for that,
but I'd never heard of it before.
So there's a lot of technologies in use.
And there's just a bunch of
information, like I said,
that I've scraped so far.
You can see that a range
of technologies and uses.
I now know more about ARM
Thumb than I did before.
And I know now more about Intel 8051
and Phar Lap embedded kernel
than I ever wanted to know before.
But there's a whole
range technologies there.
It's pretty cool.
Even the T-20s that you see,
those are actually running QT web browser.
And they're using WebSockets.
So when you press this
little JavaScript interface,
on the front screens,
so you press something,
WebSocket goes to a
native WebSocket client,
and then that does more stuff.
So real range of technologies
all the way back to DOS era stuff.
Okay, so as you saw,
there was a lot of technologies there,
and in the interest of time,
and me only having a certain amount of it,
I've restricted myself to
basically things that are
accessible by an unauthenticated
idiot out on the street.
So unprotected stuff.
So this is stuff like readers, cards,
and the connections
coming out of the reader.
So intercepting cards.
That's cool.
Playing with the readers,
you'll see that's okay.
And pulling the readers out
and playing with the connections directly.
That's probably a more intense
job, but it can be done.
So, yeah, you could go through the cloud,
or whatever you want.
And try and attack those
administrative console PCs.
through their corporate network.
Good old fashioned network level hacking.
But that's a whole other talk.
I didn't really look at
the consoles that much,
but to be honest,
a lot of sites out there just have them
domain joined PCs, with
some crap password,
and that's the administrative console.
So lots of jobs I've gone
on, done a pentest and,
"Oh there's a PC called Cardax,
I wonder what that does."
So, Yeah.
Okay, so now let's look at
these outlying technologies.
The stuff that we can actually play with.
As a person trying to
potentially get our way in.
So let's start with the
reader, it hungers for a card,
but which card does it want?
So there's two main kinds of
RFID technology, low-frequency,
which runs at 125 kilohertz,
and high frequency,
which runs at 13.56 megahertz.
Let's start with low frequency.
So the implementation
of low frequency cards,
in the Cardax/Gallagher system.
I guess it's going to
be Cardax these days,
they're called Cardax Prox.
I mean it's hard to tell
what they're actually called
because it's not really
brand name or anything,
but I've called them Cardax
Prox and they look like this.
So there's no point in me
showing the cards because you
can't reliably determine the
type of card from how it looks.
Just to show you, here's
my collection of test cards
and see they all look the same.
Totally different cards,
apart from the writing.
Now if you excuse me for a second,
I'm going to steal some
slides from a previous talk.
So if you see the art style change,
from one style of bad
hand-drawing to another,
that's because this is the talk I gave at
OzSecCon last year on RFID.
Just some generic slides that I can use.
So there's four ways that we
can look at RFID technology.
Physical, data, protocol and system.
So physical, all you
really need to know is
these cards use the Wiegand
effect, which is a cool thing.
The reader can provide energy
through a oscillating magnetic field.
And basically it's just like a induction.
So one side is a magnetic loop,
with current going through it.
Moving current in a wire
makes a magnetic field.
And then moving magnetic field.
And then a coil in the card
does the opposite thing.
Turns it back to energy,
rectifies it, turn it to DC
and use it to power the card.
And then the card can also
load modulate that RF field
which sends data back to it.
How heavy is it drawing
power, can be a zero or a one.
It's quite cool.
And there's different ways
of modulating information.
So you can take a bit stream,
you can then modulate it different ways.
Digital level, so Manchester, for example.
And then you can modulate
it at a different level,
at the analog level.
So the Cardax Prox system
uses Manchester encoding.
So that's the bottom one there.
Basically all zeros turn into 0 1,
and all ones turn into 1 0.
And it runs at clock speed RF/32,
which means blah blah blah.
So it looks like this
when you plot it using
the Proxmark software.
If I hold up an LF RFID card to my reader,
I can plot the wave form it
outputs, it outputs this.
And so, yeah, let's talk
about the data layer now.
So from looking at the
administrative console,
when I want to, if I wanted
to encode a new card,
I can see that there's four
elements that a Cardax card has.
So that I know from open source research,
by that I mean looking at manuals,
and figuring out that if
it says there's 65536,
or if it says there's 65
thousand of these things,
that probably means there's
a 16 bit value, for example.
So it has a 24 bit card number,
a 16 bit facility code.
So that's the idea is that card
numbers might not be unique,
but the combination of
facility code and card number should be.
Actually I lied because it
should be the combination of
region code, facility
code and card number.
And then you have an issue
level, which is basically,
how many times has this
idiot lost their card,
and how many times I had to reissue it.
You start with zero and you
move upwards from there.
So I know that somewhere
in this stream of zeros
and ones is this data.
So here is that streams of zeros and ones.
There's clearly a repeating pattern here.
I wrote this out for some reason.
So when we look at the best
way to do protocol analysis,
it's like a scientist, right?
You think of an experiment.
So you take a sample
and then you change one thing and redo it.
So that was a terrible explanation.
Basically, you take a card,
encode a card with some known parameters,
get the bit stream,
and then you change just one
of the fields, for example,
and then look at that bit string.
The idea is you want
to see what difference,
in what field, makes to the bit stream.
So what we end up seeing is
that this is a common prefix.
So this is like a training sequence.
Just to help the reader realize
that there's a card here
and you should pay attention
to the following data.
So that's always 7FEA,
I think it is in hex.
And then we have the last eight bits.
Which turn out to be,
well I haven't said yet,
they turned out to be something, Okay.
So what happens is,
Sorry, slides remember.
So if we change one of
the fields, for example,
this is what happens if I change
the card number up by one.
Okay, we see eight bits change.
That's actually incorrect.
It should be nine.
But the idea is that we see
quite a bit of difference.
So what's going on there?
So after a bit of head-banging.
And not the metal kind,
more like head-desk banging.
You see that every ninth-ish bit
is the opposite of its previous bit.
So here you can see if
the previous bit was zero,
then the next was one, and one zero.
So there is some kind of parity padding,
but it's not really parity,
because it's only parity
over the last bit.
But it's definitely doing a
good job of padding it out.
And then we can actually
see that, eventually see,
that this last eight,
the last eight bits,
is actually a CRC of all the
data, excluding that prefix.
So it's got a slightly
unusual initialization value,
and a slightly unusual
polynomial value, at least to me.
So we now know that the
yellow part is some data,
the un-highlighted part is the prefix,
and the pink part is the CRC.
So let's remove all these things
that we know what they are.
And we're left with this still.
And now let's convert this to Hex.
Now we start to see some
kind of stuff happening here,
There's A3s is all over
the places and A2s.
So we do the same thing.
We take a bunch of cards,
we change some things and
notice the difference.
Okay, even longer later.
And I'm not going to explain how.
But basically, we can figure
out what this actual data is.
So again, there's eight
bytes, it turns out
that the card number is
splayed across all of these.
So for example, bits 0, 1
and 2 are in the third byte
3-10 are in the second and so forth.
And hopefully 0-2, 3-10,
11-15, 16-23, yes, okay.
So all those card number byte bits,
are spread across those eight bytes.
Facility code is here.
Region code is here.
Issue level here,
and stuff I don't know or care about
but usually always 0 is here.
But there's a twist.
So what they've done is
they've done a simple.
I'm not a cryptographer,
not the old style,
But a substitution cipher
basically in this box.
So basically, for example,
you can see here, just,
that the byte 00 gets mapped to A3.
So A3, all those A3s we were
seeing in that input data.
The bits in that data are actually zeros
and that's kind of a good sign,
zero is probably most common thing
that we're going to see
in the underlying data.
So we can now decode this.
From that bunch of data
into its underlying fields.
So we have the card number.
This is actual actual
data and I'm very sorry,
Facility 456, region code 0,
But user 123 now has
their card data there.
So card number 123, facility
code 456, region code 0,
which is usually written
as A, and issue level one.
So this is card number 123, for site A456.
That's how you might
see it in the consoles.
So what do you do when
you have the ability
to take an existing card,
decode it, modify fields,
and then re-encode it?
Well, you take your work card,
and try and get onto the
roof of your office building.
So, I miss you laptop.
So we have this thing called a Proxmark.
And this is the POC version, right.
But eventually it does work.
So what we can do is, we
can take my work card,
our office uses a more secure system
than the rest of the
outside of the building.
You know, landlord versus tenants tenancy.
But sure enough, this works eventually,
if I increment the card
number up enough from mine.
That works, cool, yeah.
(audience applauds)
Cool.
So basically low-frequency
cards are busted.
Have always been busted, in
that we can always clone them.
There's always ways to
easily just clone them.
But now we can go a little
bit above and beyond,
and actually modify the
data that's on them.
So you might have a boring
plebeian employee card.
Now you can turn that
into administrative card,
something like that.
So, okay.
So for high-frequency.
High-frequency, there's
different kinds of technology.
But they're all Mifare brand cards
that the Gallagher system uses.
So Mifare Classic, Mifare
Plus, Mifare DESFire.
So let's start with Mifare Classic.
Looks like this, which is
an ISO 14443 card, type A.
Because there's also type B,
because they couldn't decide
which standard they wanted.
So they just called two
standards, one standard,
and called them Type A and
type B, which is ridiculous.
Physical, yeah, it does some things
but so it's still Wiegand.
The card gets put into the reader,
reader gives power,
and the card can start,
but there's a twist.
The reader can also give
data now as well as the card.
And so this allows for, basically,
a more interesting form of communication.
So Mifare cards don't just spit out
some sequence of bytes over and over.
They actually have blocks and sectors.
Just like a little tiny flash memory card.
So Mifare 1k, for example,
holds one kilobytes of information.
So you've got your blocks over here.
Blocks and sectors.
Block zero always has manufacturing data.
And in each of the blocks, for example,
this is sector one,
the last block in the
sector contains two keys.
Which keys are allowed to
actually read that sector.
And the access bits, which is kind of like
the read write executable
of the Unix world for this.
So basically what key can do what?
Can it read this block?
Can it write this block?
So, for example, you might
have your access control data.
in block 0 of Sector 2 and in
the key sector of that block,
which should actually be 3 not 2,
you'll have the keys set,
so that you can only read with key A
And you might need
administrative key with key B
So this is the first taste of
real crypto for some reason.
For some definition of real.
Both the card and reader
must prove knowledge of the
shared secret, namely that key.
And this cipher is called Crypto 1.
Basically, the way it
works is, the reader says,
"I would like to read block B."
The cards gives a nonce
back, a number used once,
n_t, and the reader in
turn decrypts that nonce
which has been encrypted
by one of those keys,
to prove that it has it.
And then it does a
little modification too,
and then re-encrypts it.
So basically it can prove
that it could decrypt that nonce,
fiddle with it, and re-encrypt it.
Which proves that it knows the key.
And then, in turn the reader
also sends a nonce, n_r.
And the card does the same thing.
So it takes, decrypts that
nonce, fiddles with it.
Just rotates one bit to
the left or something,
and then re-encrypts it.
So these two nonces get modified and sent.
The idea is that this
prevents replay attacks.
You need the card to actually be there.
Is that correct?
Moving on, sorry.
So Mifare Classic, so sector zero.
So let's look at a Gallagher card now.
Gallagher Cardax Mifare card.
So Mifare is like a generic technology.
Let's see how Gallagher is using it.
So sector 0 has manufacturing info,
which is why you have to have that there.
And then a Mifare access directory,
which is just some Mifare
stuff which is there.
Sector 14 is a thing, but
that's not of importance to us.
Sector 15 is the one that you can't read
with publicly known key,
you can't read, with no keys,
it's locked, so this
is the interesting one.
Now, this is nothing new,
it's been known for a while,
that Mifare classic cards are busted.
People did some maths and figured out
that if you know one of the keys,
you can then using magic maths,
brute force all the other keys out.
And luckily for us,
usually at least one of the
keys is a well known one.
So, for example, the read key
for the Mifare access directory is,
which is highlighted in blue there,
it's essentially A1 A2
A3, something like that.
But basically we know that,
And so we can easily
get the key for 6 to 15
using this technique.
Those are the keys there.
Now, before everyone gets
all blah, blah, blah.
Like I say, this isn't,
it's already in the public.
So people already know this.
And like I say, the technique,
if you have a Mifare Classic
card, anyone can do that.
So, for example, this person here has,
we recognize that squiggle,
he's also noticed those keys before.
And this is the only other place
that I've seen them printed in
a research sort of document.
But you'll notice here that
he's got that Cardax key thing,
And he said, "these keys while
unique to each individual
"are generally incomprehensible
"and a series of various ASCII characters.
"Without access system
to the system back end
"it can only be assumed
how these keys work
"and what meaning the characters have."
Okay.
So let's look sector 15 ourselves, right?
This is what sector 15 looks like,
and that lock sector now
that we have the keys.
So you can see there is what the keys
that were in that sector
to tell which ones were allowed to use.
We cracked them.
So we can read this sector now.
Here is the access control bits.
I'm not claiming a prize for figuring out,
that that's ASCII, and that's
www.cardax.com space space.
And that just redirects
to Gallagher these days.
But what's this?
Sector very start is, well,
we recognize this, right?
This is the same kind
of eight byte encoding
that we saw for the LF cards.
And the last eight bytes
are just the bitwise inverse
of those previous eight bytes.
So you've got the eight bytes
and then you've just
got the inverse as well.
So basically we can do
the exact same thing.
We can take the top of that sector
decode it into the card
number, facility number,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
Same thing.
NXP, the creator of Mifare,
tried to resolve the situation
by removing the Classic from production,
Introducing the Classic
EV1, that got broken,
so they introduced the Plus,
and then they introduced the Plus EV1
This is a giant mess.
I'm just gonna skip all over Mifare Plus,
mainly because not many
people, that I've seen,
actually use them.
And it's very similar to the next.
And the way that it works
in a Gallagher system,
it's very similar to the
way of the card technology,
which I'm just about to talk about.
So this is the Mifare DESFire.
This is the best current
state of art of Mifare cards.
For some degree of best.
So DESFire, this isn't a
block based card system,
this is file based.
So you can have multiple applications,
and each of those applications
can have multiple keys,
and then each of those applications
can also have multiple files.
So you can use, the idea is that
you can use one card for a
vending machine, payment, door.
Of course, it never ends up like that.
It just ends up being a single use card.
But good intentions, right.
So this is what a Gallagher
Mifare DESFire card looks like.
So there's card application,
which is always there, and it's boring,
Card application directory,
which is the one on the right.
That's boring.
Cardax card data application,
which you might have multiple of.
This is interesting.
There's three keys there
that can be used to
access this application.
And there's two data files there.
These are all readable by default.
They're not interesting.
And you'll find out what they're about
if you read my stuff later on.
But these are,
these we can't read without
using one of the keys.
So what's in here?
So when we look at the configuration
settings of the Cardax,
sorry, the Gallagher
controller set up system,
we noticed a thing,
that it's doing a thing
called key diversification.
So you can input a Mifare site key.
And what it will do.
I'll just explain key
diversification real quickly.
It takes an existing key.
Some other data represented
by this database icon.
And it merges them together
to create a new key
indicated by the different lines.
So key diversification lets us
take a key, some other data,
I'm just repeating myself,
and turn it into another key.
The reason you might want-
And the protocols that
they're using for this,
that Gallagher's using, it's
well-known public AN10922.
Which is recommended by
NXP Mifare themselves.
I did notice Mr. Gallagher,
Mr. or Mrs. Gallagher,
a developer, that I think
you broke one of the steps.
So you've got a bonus step,
instead of using the standard.
But that might just be me.
I'd be interested to hear about that.
But basically the Gallagher system
lets you enter a Mifare site key
that will then diversify that
site key with each card's UID,
and those diversified keys
are then the ones that are
used to lock the application.
So to lock the master application,
to lock the cad application,
the one that's not important,
the UID discovery key
and read Cardax read key.
So the idea is that these keys are needed
to read blocks and files
on the application.
These ones you use to write.
So in theory, the reader should
only need this single key.
Okay.
Now, but hold on.
Let's go back and look at
that diagram one more time,
because you probably saw it.
There's a big giant check box
that says use default Mifare site key.
Now, I know that Mifare default site key,
basically through reverse engineering.
So given that we know the Mifare site key,
and given that we know
any given card's Card UID.
A Card UID is a number
that it will spit out
without questions asked
as a serial number.
We can then diversify those
and grab all of the other keys.
So if a DESFire card is
using the default key,
it's possible to, you have
read/write full access again.
So you might ask what is the key?
I'm not going to tell you or show you it.
You'll see why that would
be a bad idea later.
If you're going to ask
me how to find the key.
The answer is still no.
Because I don't want Gallagher to throw me
into a room of frazzle units
as a product tester basically.
But we can now read what's on those files.
So assuming that the default
Mifare site key is used,
we can then diversify the
key and read those files.
Turns out that Cardax standard thing
just has the usual 8 byte
thing, and the inverse again.
So you can see that this
8 bytes thing is used,
is a very weak protection
on the underlying data.
And then it's put a different container,
depending on what type of card.
But once you know how to decode these,
and once you know how
to get the keys you need
for the card that's holding it.
It's game over.
Am I going to have enough
time for this? No, I'm not.
So I'm going to skip right over this.
Okay.
Now, what are we talking about?
Oh, yes.
Now, let's look at the protocol
between the reader and the controller.
The most there's three in use, Cardax IV,
which is the ye olde one, GBUS and HBUS,
GBUS is medium olde and HBUS
is best current practice.
There's apparently one called localbus,
but I've no idea what it is.
So HBUS is the current one.
And these ones are the
backwards compatibility ones.
Let's start with the Cardax IV protocol.
So this is used for these
bad buggers, these old ones.
It's serial pulse wave modulation.
Sort of- very simple,
there's two card, two wires,
one from the reader, one to the reader,
and depending on the length of the pulse,
it's either a zero or one,
and it's five volts.
Very simple, looks like that,
except that that's got inverted
polarity, because, reasons.
So the Cardax IV protocol
is pretty simple once you decode it.
There's one byte opcode
and then a bunch of data.
So from the reader, the reader
can send a bunch of opcodes,
indicating that it's got a card,
it's had a keypad press,
or it's still there.
And from the controller,
there is a lot more opcodes
that the controller can send,
To do the fun things that
we love these readers do,
like play the unhappy sound,
or play the you're allowed sound,
or flash the light, or do whatever.
So there's a lot more as well.
So what we can do is,
We can build a tool to
man-in-the-middle the protocol
between a reader and the controller,
just to verify, and this is
how you find this out, anyway.
So we've got, from left to right,
got a power supply thingamajiggy,
a Raspberry Pi, a GBUS IO unit,
which is basically just
there because reasons,
and then a reader. So
basically all you need to know
is that the Raspberry Pi
is intercepting the comms
between the reader and the controller,
which is one of the cables
going up, into the Controller.
So It's just good old
fashioned Python on there
using pigpio.
And that's pretty simple.
Is this video going to auto play?
Please?
Okay, yeah. So you can see there,
Press button, get that thing.
Get the card data through that.
Right, simple protocol.
Nothing there.
So what would happen
if we were to replace,
for example, the reader?
So let's try sending
our own Cardax IV data,
instead of letting the
reader do it for us.
So, after all, it's the controller
that makes the access
decision, the yes-no,
not the reader.
The reader is just
there to gather the data
and to annoy you with sounds.
It doesn't actually make
the decision itself.
So we moved from,
I moved from Raspberry Pi to Arduino
That is the only picture I can find.
That is my carpet. That is an Arduino.
But basically, this is designed
for a specific kind of interesting attack.
A timing attack.
Timing attack is basically
where you take advantage of differences
in the time it takes
for a device to respond
to a certain request.
And that's a generic technique.
So what the Arduino does is
it uses interrupts and ring buffers
to make message receiving and sending
efficient and accurately timestamped.
So what it does is basically
it outputs a bunch of JSON.
And what it does is it sends
a bunch of messages saying,
pretending to be a reader, saying,
"card number 1, facility code 1"
And then it checks to see
when it gets a response
saying yes or no, it checks and logs
all of the responses it
get from the controller,
and accurately timestamps
them to the nanosecond
or something like that.
So a bunch of messages being spammed out
of different card numbers,
and facility codes,
and different messages coming in.
We can then take some
more wonderful Python.
And we can create a giant mess.
And what this giant mess
is actually showing you is,
for example, how do I explain this?
So at every gray line we were sending.
Do I have this thing, no.
Every gray vertical line,
we were seeding a new
card information message.
Only, and I know from the way
that I set up the controller,
only one of the facility codes is valid,
and we've sent that valid facility code,
when it's the green shaded box.
So looking left to right at the top,
you've got one, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight invalid cards.
Then you've got a valid card.
And then eight more invalid cards.
And what the colored dots are,
are the response messages,
color coded by type of response
message from the controller.
You can see that when we are
spamming out invalid cards,
you clearly see that there's a pattern.
And then when we're
outputting a valid card,
you clearly see that there's a big gap,
right while it's busy thinking.
That's because the controller
is doing a two pass thing.
It's checking, is the
facility code even valid?
If it is, then there's more to do.
But if there isn't, I can just
instantly say, "No, go away."
So this is basically a
generic timing attack.
We can send out card data,
measure how long it takes
for the controller to say yes or no.
And then from that, make a judgment call
as to whether that was
a valid facility code or card number.
And then once we have
a valid facility code,
we can start brute-forcing
the card numbers.
In theory, this would work, well it does.
It enumerates the entire
facility code card number space,
that's 24 plus 16 bits.
Does that in four hours,
which sounds like a while.
I won't disagree.
There's the list of
messages, the color codes,
and different classifiers.
It's hard to, basically this different,
I didn't go full machine learning,
but I tried different ways of detecting,
given this bunch of messages,
was this a valid message or not?
And it turns out, the red
is a very simple predictor
of whether it was or not.
See if it sends back a message saying,
"Turn on your red LED."
So that's the orange one,
that works in a 100
percent true positive rate,
97 true negative rate.
In a 3 percent false positive rate.
So that was 0 percent false negative.
So basically you can see, hopefully,
that yeah, basically,
every time that we've seen the bad cards,
we always get a message saying back,
"Turn on your red LED." in
within a certain amount of time.
But when we send a good
card that we don't,
we have the facility code
for, but not the card number.
It will not send that so quickly.
So we can use that as a predictor
of whether that card was a
valid facility code or not.
And then start brute-forcing card numbers.
So the intent, well, it is how it works.
This is a Bluno beetle,
which is a very tiny
Bluetooth Arduino thing.
The idea is that you connect this,
pull out your reader, connect
the two wires you need,
three wires you need to the pins.
And then it will, and then
you can put the reader back.
And this then reports
back through your phone.
An Android phone as it
reports back progress.
How is it doing?
Has it found the facility code yet?
If it has, has found a valid card number?
And if it has, cool.
And then you can just press a button,
for it to replay it, and open the door.
Unfortunately, this does work,
but I don't have the video for it,
because of that
aforementioned slides issue.
But it works, trust me.
Yeah, weak clap, okay.
(audience applauds)
Okay.
Moving right along.
GBUS is another protocol.
It's protocol, I wrote a decoder for it.
The...
Come on.
Moving right along.
GBUS as another protocol which is in use.
You can use this to control the,
Oh, it is playing.
Okay, right.
You can use this to
control the IO devices.
So, for example, you can
read and write messages
to the devices that handle the door.
The actual locking and
sensing of window open
or door held open too long.
Is this going to play?
Yeah, okay.
So, Python script.
That's a bit more less
janky than the other one.
But you can see here that it's
detected a bunch of devices.
It's given me the input of all of
the status of all the inputs.
I pressed the key, I swiped
the card, that sort of thing.
So we have that too.
Now let's very quickly look at HBUS.
HBUS uses RS-485.
Which has a differential serial thing.
The protocol runs at
1 megabits per second.
It's pretty fast for serial.
It's very simple.
There's just 2 voltages.
If one is higher than the other, it's 0,
if that's the other way round, it's 1.
So it's very noise tolerant.
The other nice thing
about HBUS, like GBUS,
is that you can have star configurations.
Instead of having to have
each single reader connect.
Sorry, not star configurations,
we have bus configurations.
So instead of having every single reader
having to connect to the
controller in directly,
you can have them all in
a daisy chain, basically.
And this is also good because it prevents,
if I was to go and try and
introduce my own reader,
it gets no attention from the controller.
Because it has a special protocol
for assigning new devices.
So basically any new device
that's connected will say,
"Please give me an address."
And that's where it stops
until a manual event occurs.
Where administrator on
one of the admin consoles
manually says, "Yes,
this is a device I trust,
"and I want you to start using it."
So you can't just go in, jack in a reader,
jack in a dodgy looking box thing.
And expect that you'll be able
to talk to the controller.
You need to, there's more to it.
It first needs to be
approved by a administrator,
and then there's also more.
So let's say it did get
approved by administrator.
It gives an address.
That's cool.
Next thing is new devices,
what protocols it supports.
In this case, if it's new.
The controller needs
some new pre-shared keys.
So it asks for that protocol.
They exchange public key certs.
So, yes, each device basically
has a public key certificate.
Nothing sensitive here,
it's just public keys.
The these are all signed by Gallagher.
So basically each device
you can see there,
the serial number is
actually the ASCII version
of the serial number,
actually of this reader.
This is a reader's device
certificate, I believe.
So basically there is a
authoritative train of trust
basically between
Gallagher and its devices.
More things happen and we
end up with a set of keys.
And then those keys, now
this device is registered,
we can now say that we want to start
an actual data transmission protocol.
We can then use these keys
to prove that we can
respond to a challenge.
And then we can then use all of these keys
to then exchange data.
So.
That was out of order, anyway.
So you're asking where the
fun vulnerability in HBUS?
Well, there isn't one, for now.
Why did I tell you about it then?
I want to prove the difference,
but show the difference
between the current tech
offered by Gallagher versus
the ancient Cardax IV and GBUS,
which are very broken basically.
Of course, I would like
to look at HBUS more,
and I will be.
That's all I got up to
in this current time.
So we've looked at the cards,
the readers, and I didn't
find anything in the readers.
Nothing that I can tell you about yet.
So I did look at the readers.
So I've looked I've talked
here about the cards
and the connections past the readers.
And I looked at the readers myself.
There's one missing element here.
That's the actual RFID data transmission.
So there's two forms of RF based attack.
There's skimming.
So skimming, and that is not a balloon.
That is a magnetic loop antenna.
So, like I said, magnetic
loop conduction, wonderful.
So the loop, if we're
doing a skimming attack,
that's when we walk past someone,
power up their card and
retrieve the data off it.
So our antenna powers it.
We exchange data and grab
the data off the card.
Now, this works fine
for low frequency ones.
Because as soon as they're powered,
they all start screaming
out that magic number,
over and over.
There's no access control.
There's no protocols.
It's just power and then it
starts modulating the number.
So we can put our antenna into that field.
And then spit that out to any old reader,
save it, or do it on the same spot.
That's a replay attack.
But this doesn't work for high
frequency, 13.56 megahertz.
Because of a little thing called physics.
Basically, the power required to,
the magnetic field strengths required
to power a high frequency
card is a magnitude.
Well, I'm talking stuff
I don't understand.
But it's a lot more power required
to power one of these cards,
from a reasonable distance,
than it is for low frequency.
You might have noticed that old readers,
low frequency ones, will accept the card
from quite a bit a further distance,
than the newer high frequency ones do.
How it is.
So instead of skimming
for high-frequency cards,
let's try intercepting them,
and intercepting is similar,
but basically we're
intercepting a transaction
between a real reader and a real card.
Kind of like how the
agency has its spy bases,
looking at down coming satellite
traffic, kind of thing.
We're just sitting alongside
an existing transaction
and taking advantage of
the fact that the signal
is actually going further
than it should be.
So this is a terrible picture,
But this is what a
long range reader looks
like when I'm poking it.
These only will read RFID 13.56
cards, about 50 centimeters.
So they're used for
carpark kind of situations.
Just to show you that these
do try to pump out a lot of power.
They try to make the
distance as long as possible.
There is a completely,
I've just put on my sofa,
a completely unconnected
long range reader.
And there's two other different
kinds of long range reader.
There on the right.
I power the two ones on the right,
and that's enough to
power the one on the left.
So they're trying, right.
When you open them inside,
it says high voltage.
And I trust in those capacitors everywhere
and stuff I don't understand.
So it's not through a lack of power
that these things are low.
It's just physical limitations.
So what can we do?
Well, normally, readers,
what they'll do, is they say,
"Please give me block 60."
The one with the magic 8 bytes in
And the card will give the block data.
The reader has to treat
all the blocks the same.
Because the reader
doesn't necessarily know
what the content of the data is.
It just needs to pass
it on to the back end.
Can't make any assumptions about the data.
So, for example, if one of
the bits in that response
gets munged because of RF noise,
the reader basically has to
throw away the whole message.
The parity gets corrupted,
checksums gets corrupted,
whatever, it just can't figure it out.
But we know the format of sector.
Well, we know the format
of the data, for example.
in a Mifare Classic.
So, for example, if this bit gets,
this byte gets trampled on
by my neighbors fridge, or whatever,
sending out RFID spam, RF
spam, hopefully not RFID spam,
we can correct it using
the conveniently placed,
and this is why it's there,
we correct it using the
data on the other side.
Just flip that bit, and
now we know what it was.
In addition, we can go above and beyond.
We know what the
underlying field should be.
And we know that, for example,
if we've lost the bits
that would represent the facility code,
the high order bits,
we know that those are
probably zeros anyway,
because there's only
so many facility codes.
So what we can do, is
we can just replace that
with data that we all ready know.
So using HackRF, that's
a software defined radio,
and GNURadio,
which is software defined radio framework,
we can make an unholy mess again.
But what this does is
basically read some data
from the software defined radio antenna.
And puts it into, does a
bunch of pre-processing,
and then puts it into a
custom written block there.
What this custom written block does,
it can look at only the bare
minimum amount of messages
that we care about,
just to get a valid
Cardax access credential.
You know the reader normally has to say.
"I want to authenticate."
"Okay"
"Blah blah blah blah."
"I want this block."
"Okay."
"What's your CSN?"
"Blah, blah, blah."
All these messages
We don't care about that.
All we can want to see
is the magic 8 bytes in a transaction.
So we only care about the two nonces
that the reader and the card give,
and the block request from the reader,
and the response from the card.
And we can also do things like,
we can take advantage
of an off-line attack.
Normally readers have to be quick.
They have to try and figure out
what your cards said very fast.
Because otherwise you're
waiting there holding your card.
We can do off-line attacks.
We can we can sniff traffic.
And then spend longer time
trying to resolve any errors
in the RFID signal, trying to flip.
So what this does, for example,
is it flips all the bits in
a bunch of various patterns.
Trying to fix the parity, for example.
And here is more code.
So this is what it looks like.
You can see there,
that's how strong a
reader signal looks like.
And that weak signal on the right there,
That's a response from a card.
Card responses, are very lot
weaker than the reader signal.
And so you see there the
reader said 60 00 F5 7B.
Which is, "I would like to do something."
I can't remember what 60
is, but I'm sure it's great.
So what we can do is we can
take the software defined radio,
put an antenna on it.
There's my magnetic loop antenna holder,
in front of a reader.
And basically we can
see how far can we read?
How far can we see card
reader interactions?
This works only about 30 centimeters.
So well-done Matt, you did worse.
But in this case, physics
actually has an answer.
Bigger is better for RFID antennas.
So with that in mind,
introducing,
(audience applause)
Yeah, so,
RFID,
near field RF technologies
are usually just brute force.
You don't have fancy
antenna configurations,
and weird patterns and grills.
It's just more metal
basically, and bigger.
So in this case,
one square meter of copper
tubing from Bunnings,
and a lot of burnt fingers later,
and solder mess,
we have this.
Oh, okay, you're showing that.
Yeah, that's just the cables.
This is taken out of
the HF antenna cookbook,
from Texas Instruments.
Here's me and Valentinas.
A friend who let me borrowe
his man cave, I guess.
Looks like this.
Yeah, multimeter for scale.
This gets up to three meters.
Now, I know what you're thinking.
You can't walk down the street with this,
and then, you know.
There is a happy medium.
And the other thing is,
there is the opportunity to build
a slightly more reasonably sized one.
And I'm not an RF engineer,
so there's a lot of shit
that I had to guess here.
I think I got it right.
But there's a lot more tuning
and stuff that could be done.
So if you're an old ham,
or you work in RF fields,
give me some help.
That would be awesome.
Okay, so we get to the very last,
second to last part, because
that's telling me time is up,
so I'm gonna go real fast.
This is a danger zone.
So don't do anything.
That's what I did.
Don't do any of this.
So I wanted to find out what
are the number of technologies
in use across actual readers, right.
Do a field survey.
So I wanted to find out how many 125.
How many readers accept 125 cards?
How many readers accept
Classic, Plus and DESFire?
Now Plus is, like I say,
the bastard child they don't care about,
it's effectively the same as DESFire.
So I'm just going to
pretend that doesn't exist.
And more importantly, I also want to know,
are people using default
keys, or non default keys?
Because as you figured,
the only secure configuration
is not to use low frequency,
not to use Mifare Classic,
not to use Mifare DESFire
with the default key,
But you have to use Mifare
DESFire with non-default key.
That's the only chance that you have
of keeping your credential secure.
Or Mifare Plus, with a non-default key.
But like I say, it doesn't exist.
So I wrote a, I wanted to know this.
So here I am debugging some code
out in the middle of the street.
I wrote a little, you
can't see it unfortunately,
It's just a Proxmark that
connects to my laptop
and tells me what card
technology is in use on a reader.
And are they using a
non-default key or not.
Important.
It does not tell me that
key if it's non-default.
Because of the way the
DESFire protocol works.
I can tell if it's using the default key.
But I can't-
if I can tell it's
using a non-default key,
I can't tell what that key is,
but I can tell that it's not the default.
So in my opinion, no damage done.
I just get to see what I'd be able to do
by holding up my cards,
seeing if they ding or not.
And the results.
So there's, I did a sample
of ninety five readers,
10 of them are the old big boys.
11 Prox Plus, 10 Teardrops,
5, 28, 9, 20 of the big ones,
and 2 probably where I forgot
to record that information.
Low-frequency is in use on 35 out of 60.
I really probably should have
put percentages, but whatever.
35 out of, not out of 60.
35 out of 95.
And that's a lot.
And high frequency is
accepted by 80 of them.
And not by 15.
So one of the things you can tell
by just having low frequency enabled
is that it accepts 125
kilohertz Cardax Prox.
That's by design.
The reader doesn't emit
a low frequency field
unless it's willing to accept those cards.
So just by the presence of that field,
you know that it's accepting those cards.
Whereas, for the high frequency ones,
you have to actually tell
what kind of card it accepts.
And that's harder to tell.
This is the thing that I skipped over,
so I'm not even going to show you that.
Okay, so now we get to the big thing.
How many sites are using a
non-default Mifare site key?
This is the key thing that is required,
Gallagher acknowledges it, knows it.
This is the thing that is required
to have any form of card security.
Put your hands up if
you think it's above 20,
Above 10,
Above five,
Above one,
Zero?
Oh, ye of little faith.
Okay, there's one.
And this one particular
government department
does not want me scanning their readers.
And I understand. This is
the second time I've had
a laptop confiscated by
the New Zealand government.
(audience laughs)
So in my not defense.
Yes, it was late.
I'm a night owl.
So walking around in near black,
at midnight, scanning readers.
It's not the smartest of
ideas, just one of those,
thinking without actually
thinking too far ahead things.
But, yes, I would like to
point out that, during,
if you did see me or,
and that agency that
does know who they are.
No card data has been taken.
There's no way that can be done.
And to be honest,
congratulations for the
only non-default site key
in all of Wellington.
And that's what pisses me off,
it's only because of
the non-default site key
that I stayed around.
I was like, wait a second,
that can't be right.
And that's when the security
guards show up, and the cops.
So, yeah, okay.
That was all about attack.
Now let's talk about defense.
So migrate to a secure
card technology, right.
That that currently is
only Mifare DESFire.
Gallagher does support
Bluetooth credentials
and PIV for you yanks,
and also people who do use
those kind of technologies.
But for most of us, it's
gonna be Mifare DESFire.
Disable unused card types.
You can do this.
You can go to the control
settings of each reader and say,
"I only want you to accept DESFire cards."
It's very simple. You know
how to use checkboxes.
Use a non-default, Mifare site key.
Uncheck that box.
Press the handy dandy, to generate things,
don't just type in zeros,
press to generate the keys.
Now this is where it gets sticky,
because you do have to
reissue all your cards.
And yes, like I was talking
to a contact at Gallagher.
And he said, "Yeah,
this can be a problem."
And I was like,
"Yeah, you're issuing 100
cards must be quite a bit."
And he was like, "Try 10000."
And I was like, "Yeah, okay."
So we're pretty small, our sites here,
but some the biggest
sites that Gallagher do,
it's that there's actually,
there's a bit of stuff
that needs to be overcome there first.
Use HBUS, not Cardax IV/GBUS.
And make use of all the
functionality in command center.
Now you might be asking,
"How do I actually audit all this?"
Well, lucky for you.
There is the Gallagher
Security Health Check.
This as a concerned person looking at
his Gallagher Security
Health Check report.
Basically, you run this
tool on your machine.
One of your admin
machines, it collects data,
you send that to Gallagher.
They run the secret sauce, and
they send you back a report
that tells you what your set up is.
So basically, this puts
me out of business, right?
Industry first automated method,
to check your security system.
We all know Nessus, we
all know all other boring,
checkbox standard things.
This is for first one for
actual physical security control systems.
Which is really great to see.
This is what one of the
reports will look like.
And you can see here, clearly,
that it's talking about the things
that I've already bugged everyone about.
So reader 125k.
You have low-frequency
enabled, disable it.
You have Mifare Classic
enable, disable it.
I believe there's also one's for,
you have a non-default
key, don't use a default.
There is also the Gallagher
controller 6000 Hardening Guide.
And the Command Center Hardening Guide.
You should read these documents,
or your installer should
have read them for you.
Okay, so that's it.
I am well over time.
Now, as I said, this
is just a short summary
of the more interesting
parts of the research.
There's a lot more out there
that I need to gather
my notes for, literally.
The best form to find this is,
I'll probably have this on
my GitHub at some point.
I'll just make a repo and dump
a bunch of information there.
Also my Web site, and
it's plain and I2P there.
And yeah.
Thank you very much to
Daniel Underhay, best friend.
And he's given me lots of
ideas and support through this.
Robert Cowsley at Gallagher.
I've put Gallagher through a
bit, and this is Gallagher-
Gallagher really wants
to be the anti-HID, okay.
Everyone knows AmmonRa, or whatever it is.
The guy, leaked the HID iClass master key,
moved to China, apparently.
They don't want to be that.
They want to be supportive.
They offer licenses.
They offer hardware.
They offer training.
So this is really good.
I'll admit that I wasn't
able to keep my bargain.
Good side of the deal quite so much
because these slides, this
will be the very first time
that they've seen them as well.
Apologies, guys, but hopefully
there's nothing in here
that didn't already get mentioned.
But yeah, Robert's been great.
The whole Gallagher team's been great.
Oh, there they are.
Tom Moore, Aura Infosec.
I've been disappearing into a black hole
quite a bit the last few months
instead of doing my work.
And it's Tom's job to
whip me back into shape.
So thank you very much, Tom,
for keeping me on track,
and also for reaching out to that agency
to see what could be done.
And Aura Infosec.
And you.
Also Vales for letting me
borrow your logic analyzer
for the last one and a half years.
I still need it though.
Thanks.
(audience applause)