this talk is defense against rapidly
morphine DDoS with Mikhail Fedorov and
muta Tyagi yes
it's an honor to be here thank you very
much for being with us let me just begin
with the the acknowledgement that young
people the younger generation is very
very sharp they're very smart they
figured out how to take over IOT devices
and make botnets and they're selling
DDoS services this is an ad from paste
bin and if you notice for 10 bucks you
can get 500 second attacks with
60-second cooldowns
right for 10 bucks that's cheaper than
pizza in New York City probably here
also here in Vegas right so all of us
need to be ready to deal with DDoS
attacks the what do you do to get ready
well we should be testing our DDoS
posture and we should be running Red
Team Blue Team games to make sure that
we are absolutely prepared when doss
hits us right now if you get ddosed who
do you call those busters so I used to I
mu de t oggi architected f5 networks and
that's how I used to look when I was
younger my name is Michaela fedora
I'm engineer at f5 networks and the
Academy Harris before started to fight
those attacks yes fighting DDoS you lose
your hair so the you now know who we are
how many of you hands please how many of
you recognize this character ok good now
please help me out here I'm a bit
nervous so help me out why is it so
difficult to fight this guy why is it so
hard to defend against moral t1000
what's so special about him
liquid-liquid he can change his form he
can morph one moment he looks like a cop
another moment he looks like Sarah
Connor right and just when you think
that you figured out all his shapes he
moves again he can even become a tile in
a hallway in a building right so very
difficult to figure him out because he
can just continuously keep morphing
right now this is exactly what happened
to our friends at proton mill in June
2018 they were hit by sustained DDoS
attacks the vectors that got got used in
these attacks they were run-of-the-mill
vectors you know UDP floods syn floods
etc nothing too special about the
vectors but what made the attack so
complex to defend against is that the
attacker kept on changing the attack
they kept on morphing the hf attack
right so as the salt deftly would go and
figure out what's a good mitigation for
the attack and place that mitigation in
in in mitigation mode in some device the
attackers would simply morph the attack
change the attack so the mitigation that
got placed in order to defend against
the attack was no longer useful
now protonmail we are huge fans of
proton mail we truly appreciate what
they do for the community so for us for
me shine me when protonmail got attacked
we took it as an attack on the community
on ourselves and we said alright let's
figure out how to defend against these
attacks what do we do to catch the
morphing attacks and just you and defeat
them right the other thing I would say
about protonmail that we really truly
appreciate is that that they were
actually transparent about the nature of
the attack so researchers like us could
actually study the attack and figure out
ways to defend against it
now when you begin to research the first
thing we needed was a tool that could
actually stimuli
morphing attacks and so we looked around
and we didn't find any good tools so we
had to write one so Misha wrote a tool
be sure you want to take it up and
describe the tool you wrote right so we
are sure that everyone in this audience
is smart to write your own to to launch
more in flux but we decided to save you
some time and Road soda so soda is able
to launch those plugs on them on the
various levels on the network level and
application layer it uses the existing
tools to generate traffic but scale them
to the multiple cores in order to
increase traffic volume and of course it
allows you to morph attack pattern
continuously so so that can be used in
order to put down any part of your
infrastructure firewall application
services everything so so there is a
tool for a red team right so soda is a
tool for the red team for the blue team
what we did is we came up with an
environment we were just talking to
Nathan who who's discussing with us that
you know he has to do some DDoS testing
and doing DDoS testing can be complex
because even DDoS in your dev
environment touches your network right
so you need a safe environment where you
can do your your testing against DDoS so
we put this together and the the
blueprint that we show you here you can
use it as is or you can customize it
further now let me explain the blueprint
to you a little bit so we've got clients
which are running as docker containers
you need those because you want to see
what the end users experience looks like
when soda begins to attack and then on
the very right hand side you've got the
dam vulnerable web application running
in containers that's the target and then
you've got pfsense which is an open
source fireball we wanted to create an
environment that looks like your network
so typically you're defending the edge
of your network with a firewall so we
picked an open source firewall
now it's all of these elements the the
client containers the dvwa containers
pfSense they're all instrumented with
Telegraph if you don't know what
Telegraph is it
it can Telegraph metrics wherever
whichever host it is instrumenting
instrumented on so it's sending
real-time metrics into in flux DB which
is collecting these metrics and then
with Griffin ah we can show dashboards
you need all this because you want to be
able to see what is happening to my
clients what is happening to my servers
and what is the state of my firewall as
soda attacks so we put all this together
and now what you can do is stick your
ddos defensive mechanism just before the
firewall keep in mind a DDoS device is a
default open device unlike a firewall
which is a default deny device and you
open a pinhole DDoS device is a default
open device it's got the hardest job in
the world it's got to let everything
through right do not drop anything
unless there's an attack and then only
drop the bad packets and today the
biggest challenge that DDoS defense
faces is they're open to many false
positives so what happens is people
create they use what we call static
vectors and set thresholds for them so
for example they'll say I'll only allow
10,000 20,000 UDP packets per second my
normal load is 10,000 my firewall can
take 30 South thousand so I'm gonna
allow 20,000 UDP packets per second when
the attack comes you might see 200,000
UDP packets per second right and you're
gonna have to drop most of those because
you set a threshold at 20,000 so you're
dropping a hundred and eighty thousand
UDP packets and the chances are the
10,000 good ones are part of those
180,000 that you're dropping so you end
up causing a lot of false positives
now thus the sake analysts were
experienced they know this so what they
do is you know they're put systems in
place and best practices in place they
look at packet captures and other
indicators and try to find very specific
characteristics of the attack back 'its
and then make a regular expression and
program that in some mitigation device
and and try to be very specific about
what they draw but this takes time and
doesn't work or morphing attacks by the
time you figure all this out your
mitigation is no longer useful because
the attack is already morphed so what we
figured is okay
a machine is coming at us so we got a
defend with the machine so we
investigated some machine learning
algorithms the algorithm that we tested
it baselines the the traffic and then
when it detects an anomaly triggers on
that anomaly and it begins to mitigate
whoa careful because what if your
marketing team there's a massive
wonderful campaign and drives a whole
bunch of new traffic to your site and
your infrastructure team does a great
job and prepares for that new traffic
right nothing is going to go wrong but
the anomaly detector is going to see
anomaly and start dropping you don't
want that you just spent all this money
driving traffic to your site
so you don't just want to drop because
the anomaly detector is unhappy right
another example you have a store
developer and you know your your
customers want a brand new feature so
she codes rapidly checks it into github
she then pushes it out through CI CD the
code is in production the applications
nature has changed a little bit
traffic patterns have changed a little
bit whoa the anomaly detector says
attack right and you don't want that you
want your users to be able to use the
new features so what we discovered is
that you need a second mechanism a
second machine learning mechanism which
is watching the state of the service
so is the service degraded or is the
service doing well that's what this
second algorithm is watching and it's
supervising the first one so if if if
the end-user experience is good the
service is doing well it tells the
anomaly detector don't do anything just
keep learning and as soon as it sees
that the service degrades the end users
are unhappy then it tells the anomaly
detector find the anomaly start the
mitigation and then it keeps on checking
how effective is that mitigation so if
after mitigation is deployed the service
becomes better and better and better the
user experience goes back up to normal
it will say great we found the right
signature but if it sees that after
application of the mitigation the
service is degrading even more it's not
helping it will tell the anomaly
detector you found the wrong thing drop
this one and look for another anomaly so
when you have these two things working
together you have the anomaly and proof
of harm together when these two things
happen together then there's a great
chance that the two are correlated we
found this approach to be the most
effective approach Misha ran a lot of
tests with soda and he's now going to
discuss the results Thank You mood so
the main goal of our experiments was to
check how good machine learning add
mitigation of more hand or splats
as you all know there are two main
victims in your network which can die
when those who has come it's your
infrastructure and your application
services your infrastructure usually
dies when network layer flood comes to
the network and bring a huge amount of
traffic and your application service is
usually bad and usual day when
application layer that comes it's
important to note that we've used two
kinds of anomaly detection mechanisms in
order to find the unnormal E and install
it and main difference between them is
subset of beta kids they use in order to
identify an anomaly
and build this signature the first one
uses all available fields in the packet
to build anomaly pattern and the second
one uses application payload in our case
it was HTTP in order to extract
predicates from and build the signature
the way we run our experiments was busy
attackers and clients on the left then
those protection device then firewall
and then application services and I
would like to cover two experiments
first one how does machine learning
defense against network level floods so
this is a peacetime and the user is
happy the latency jumps between I mean
near zero there is no attack traffic now
just 20 packets per second from attacker
machine firewall doing well it doesn't
see much traffic because legitimate
traffic usually much less than firewall
can do back and CPUs are relaxed and
they happily handle all legitimate
requests which come to them then BOOM
solar started to launch Network level
floods and you can see that level attack
pattern changes every two Millions there
is a syn flood UDP flood NDP flop and so
on and firewall CPU is so busy dropping
this traffic it is not even able to pass
the geometric quests towards the
backends so backends don't see traffic
at all you see this amount of traffic is
near zero and this is complete disaster
for a user
these are barely able to access the
service this is a mostly outage what do
we do we apply network level anomaly
detection
what happens here so that keeps more
than attack water but now where was if
you has enough power to handle all the
traffic which comes to the firewall so
the backends
handling the same amount of legitimate
traffic as they did before and most
interesting graph on this slide is a
huge user latency graph as you can see
at the beginning of every single
interval there is a small spike in the
utilization this is the only amount of
time which machine learning takes in
order to identify an anomaly and apply
mitigation so few seconds I believe is
unreachable result for a human human
cannot compete ok this is a case we'll
never clear all floods
what happens if application layer
attacks come to the network in this case
amount of traffic is much less than 4
never flood and fire will easily handle
all this traffic but the back end cpu go
crazy they're overloaded and the amount
of requests is much more than we saw
before and this is also disaster for a
user so now latency jumps between 2 and
4 seconds this is an acceptable quality
of service now let's take a look what if
we leave only network layer anomaly
detection on the church in this case
amount of legitimate requests which can
two backends reduces so back and CPU
feels more relaxed and from socket the
rater point of view everything
everything becomes fine but attacker is
also happy and the reason for that is
user traffic is also affected this
happens because on the network level
good packets and bad packets too similar
there is no way to differentiate between
them so that's why network level anomaly
detection generates false positives for
application layer attacks what do we do
in this case in this case we can apply
anomaly detection on the application
layer to use application pillow to
extract predicates and build an anomaly
pattern if we do that
so so that keeps morph in the
application layer attack but the amount
of I mean CPUs sake cycles comes back to
normal pretty quickly just after a few
seconds the same and well about the
about of amount of legitimate requests
and the user latency graph is exactly
the same as we saw for Network level
flus there is a small spike at the
beginning of every interval and it takes
just few seconds for machine learning on
application layer to detect an anomaly
and stop it
excellent so thank you Misha so I just
want to point out to the audience in
somewhat of a more animated fashion is
look attacker attacks I find the
signature attacker attacks I find the
signature hacker attacks I find the
signature morph all you want I'm gonna
catch you right so Misha we now know
that if the re people in the audience
use soda and they can beat soda right
there DDoS defensive mechanisms can beat
so that they're doing well but what what
is one piece of advice that you want to
give to the audience what do you want to
remind them of you know an important
point of course we have more than one
piece of advice so the first one is the
first one so more can do squats are now
the keys protonmail kiss showed us so we
should check our DOS posture against
Morgan those Plus this is only how we
can say we are protected Misha we talked
about layer 3 layer 4 attacks layer 7
attacks getting all which together and
coming at you right so what should we
remember to do in this case right so
anomaly detection mechanism on the
network level is not accurate enough to
stop application layer attacks without
creating false positives so in order to
block anomaly at application layer
attacks you have to use a normal
detection on the application layer so
Misha and now
detection can also cause false positives
what should we do about this issue right
so traffic volume does not always mean
an attack so those devices should only
go mitigate when there is a stress on
your back end so there is one more
mechanisms required to supervise a
normal detection so move it you've been
doing those fighting for for a while
I've been what the best practices you
would like to share with community look
I would like to leave room for questions
but here's what I would want the
audience to just memorize when you think
about DDoS attacks you have to focus on
intelligent mitigation the job of the
DDoS device if you look at the graphic
there red packets are bad the blue
packets are good the job of the DDoS
devices drop the red packets and let the
blue packets go through you cannot just
say I'm going to set a threshold and you
know and and just only allow so many
packets per second because that
mechanism is also going to drop the blue
ones right so you gotta be intelligent
about your mitigation and of course you
see there the t1000 cannot hide the
machine learning mechanisms we can catch
all his forms right but here's if you
can somehow without dropping any packets
drive off the attack that's the best
policy so the first thing we should try
is just tell all the clients that are
coming to your service slow down a
little bit so each user is not going to
feel that but the collective impact of
everybody slowing down could take some
load off on the infrastructure in the
backends not easy to do but
theoretically speaking that's the first
thing we should attempt only after that
fails should be getting to the business
of dropping and when we drop we should
use these very precise signatures that
the machine can figure out so that only
the bad packets are being dropped right
and do it only when you have proof of
harm so that you don't cause false
positives
and if you are still struggling then you
can start doing you know heavier things
like let the humans through drop the
bots but be careful because there's a
lot of legitimate machine to machine
communication nowadays right so if you
if you break that you might break your
end users experience and after that what
you might think of doing is look at
special connections that are indicative
of attack slow connections someone might
be hitting you with a variant of slow
read slow loris etc right or someone
might be hitting your heavy URL the URL
that does a lot of computation in the
back end and when this doesn't work now
you drop the hammer so now you start
doing your rate limiting even this you
have to do carefully if you rate limit
based on source IP the most active
source IP careful it could be a mega
proxy and you might be killing a lot of
good users behind that mega proxy if you
rate limit your most heavily used your i
well that's what people are coming to
you for anyway and finally if you if you
raid limit based on packets per second
it will there's no intelligence there so
really you want to achieve intelligent
mitigation and your strategy should be
something in that order with this i want
to thank people who helped us out mark
Campbell Rachel Sarah and Lydia they
helped us practice and prepare for this
we want to take questions and as we take
questions we want to tell you that you
can download soda and here is sort of
doing its magic you see the soda is
creating the attacks this is a live demo
while we recorded it so it's not live it
was live but we were recording it of war
of soda attacking and the machine
learning catching the attack
so with that questions there are mics at
the edge this is the last session so we
are happy to stay here but we don't want
to keep you from your beer
any questions question yes sir
yeah you guys didn't really discuss like
which machine learning models you use
gas is what you used for speed and if
you'll be open sourcing any of this if
you'll be open-source again in this code
are you gonna hold it back for your f5
products or and how did you come up with
the signatures for the attack yes yes so
the question is we did not really
discuss the machine learning models
which is true but let me give you an
idea of how they might work right so and
we don't want to really talk about
products we just want to talk about
research so the the you can imagine at
layer 3 layer 4 Mitch I mentioned layer
3 layer 4 predicates so you can imagine
you know an IP packet and it has all its
you know headers options source IP DES
type e TTL checksum etc etc in the
payload you have your UDP Datagram in
your TCP data gram and they have their
own fields so every single field that
you can imagine that that's present in
this in this IP packet TCP UDP payload
it has a universe of possible values so
take TTL one to 255 easy one so what we
do is we're looking at all the packets
that are coming in on the fly and we see
how many of them are TTL - how many of
them are TTL 3 so we're building a
frequency distribution a histogram now
TTL is easy
what about source IP so the you you have
a lot of source IPS so we hashed them
into segments and then we build a
histogram against each one how many
packets are hitting which segment right
keep in mind that we don't have the
luxury of storing these packets and then
running models on them so our analysis
is a lot more statistical we have to do
this in situ as packets are flying
through we have to figure out is the
next one which we see good or bad is
that anomaly or not anomaly right so we
build these histograms during the
baselining phase and you need that
second algorithm which is you
implemented using various techniques you
can say I'm gonna monitor my synthetic
clients latency and based on that I'm
going to declare a my under attack or
not you can say I'm gonna monitor on the
DDoS device what the round-trip times
are from the server is the server
slowing down and based on that I'm gonna
declare whether I'm under attack or not
so they're different mechanisms but you
need it because in these statistical
methods you can have false positives you
canyou we will absolutely detect any
change in the current network pattern
compared to what we saw in the past
absolutely we will detect that but is it
a normal change or not you need another
mechanism to inform the anomaly detector
to consider it in anomaly or just keep
learning it so so we use statistical
methods we don't end up using the the
typical models that you run on data that
you have the luxury to store we got to
do this in flight and we're not going to
open-source the statistical methods
there are lots of papers yes they may
show up in products etc but we are
absolutely open sourcing soda so you can
download the kit and also our friend Ken
is busily writing down as we speak here
the instructions for putting together
the the rest of the lab environment so
you can test your DDoS mechanism
whatever it is in your case you will
still have the clients instrumented with
Telegraph servers the pfsense firewalls
take your own DDoS device in your own
DDoS mechanism and test so all that
we're going to open source any other
questions I have one yes so we've been
talking a lot about layer 7 or
application attacks and early on there
was discussion about volumetric attacks
which are typically asymmetrical so my
question is is where
would the mitigation actually be placed
in the network infrastructure yeah so
that's a good question so and it's it's
a I can go on and on answering that
question because you bring up several
points right so if I'm seeing attacks
that are stateful right so I'm seeing a
request I'm seeing a response going back
it's useful for me to see both the
requested the response so that my my
mechanisms can be precise in discovering
anomalies and my mechanisms can be
precise and discovering attack condition
you can do that at layer seven and you
can for HTTP and you can also do that at
layer 3 layer 4 if you know if you
cannot see the HTTP traffic if all
you're allowed to see is layer 3 layer 4
now typically if if the DDoS defensive
mechanism is placed at the edge of the
network you only see the layer 3 layer 4
predicates you don't end up seeing the
layer 7 predicates and if the DDoS the
mechanism is also placed near the
servers in often at the data centers you
know there's not a lot of depth in the
network you come to the edge and you go
straight to your application servers
then you will end up seeing the layer 7
predicates if the traffic is asymmetric
the mechanisms will still work but the
precision of the signatures will go down
a little bit I want to show you you know
that's an example of a signature that's
a layer 3 layer 4 signature that you're
seeing there so you see it we're looking
at the IP header size flags proto source
IP TCP flags DES type e et cetera and
here's an example of a layer 7 signature
right so you you're seeing now you're
seeing HTTP payload level information so
asymmetry makes the fidelity of the
signature a little bit less strong but
the mechanism will still work
right the maths but this this
statistical model doesn't change and
typically you place the DDoS defense you
know if you're an enterprise you get the
ISP routers giving you a handoff to the
enterprise routers which then go to your
firewall you can be in that in between
the ISP routers and the enterprise
router so the edge of the network or you
could go just in front of the firewall
which is what I'm starting to recommend
because if you're just in front of the
firewall between the enterprise router
in the firewall you are more likely to
see both the forward flow in the reverse
flow of the session because firewalls
are often stateful yeah that makes sense
for the application layer attacks right
can you hear me yeah it makes sense for
the application layer attacks to be
close to the servers and in fact in
front of the firewall but for volumetric
attacks you'd still be overwhelming your
last mile from your provider edge or
router yeah yeah look if the pipe is
completely filled right if it's a
volumetric and so volumetric attack what
does it contain it contains a whole
bunch of bad packets right and
potentially you're really truly clarify
you can have a scale a volume of the
volumetric attack which is so high that
the pipe that that you have from the
service provider just getting billed
right and and no no I can't fit another
packet in there because the pipe is
built right so now my details device
which is sitting right at the edge what
it's going to do is it's going to stop
this traffic from making it into the the
enterprise but it can't do anything
about the pipe the pipe comes before the
DDoS device so in this case what you
have to do is call a cloud scrubber and
have the ISP transfer your traffic to
the cloud scrubber so that you get
appropriate amount of volume that your
pipe can handle now if the case is
slightly different where the pipe is not
completely filled so your pipe gets
we'll take another few gigs but the
volume of traffic is much larger than
normal normally what you used to see I
can handle that on premises now this
device the one of the examples which I
showed you is the layer three layer four
signatures so in that volume I don't
need to look inside the payload I will
figure out what the bad packets are just
by looking at the layer 3 layer 4
predicates thank you yeah but thank you
for asking the question
and I think oh there's more questions
yeah hi
so the story that you guys have pulled
here is really compelling I've heard it
from some other from some some DDoS
defense appliance vendors have you guys
done any kind of bake-off in your lab to
look at performance for your solution
versus their solution I mean I I know
you guys are still in sort of research
and exploration and that sort of thing
so but just curious to hear if there's
any anecdotes about how you're doing
versus what you might see on like a
defense Pro for exam yeah yeah no we
haven't done any bake-offs
but you know you now have soda you do
the bake-off right you do the bear you
we'll help you set up soda it's for it
this is you know look we don't care what
you use protonmail got attacked and we
got really charged right and we want the
community to be able to defend against
these types of attacks and you know the
the strategies that I showed you
regarding intelligent mitigation they
don't change whatever bender you use you
write your own code that's fine too but
you know focus on intelligent mitigation
a/b tests your posture and and we
understand that testing your posture is
difficult therefore we give you the kit
use the kit test your posture in a safe
environment and then you know if we can
help you happy to help you as
researchers right and if you want to
call the vendors go ahead and call them
but if you can't want to call me Kyle
and with it you know let's let's flash
our
call us there oh yeah it's my f5 email
so he doesn't get help right he doesn't
get up sounds good thanks guys I'd
probably let me all sad so the idea
behind open source in the solar that we
will have a tool the standard tool to
test the dust protection so everyone
will do will do the same tests and this
is how we can compare who is doing good
who is doing back let's lay it behind
the soda sounds good thank you guys
other questions I think that we're
supposed to yeah we're way over there's
gonna be a rap room over there for
additional questions yeah we're gonna go
to the rap room and drink of water and
take a sigh of relief and so you know
happy to answer questions there thank
you and thank you for letting us go
[Applause]