good morning welcome to finding our path
how we're trying to improve Active
Directory security in South Seas a b e
with an d Robins will Schrader and Rohan
Berserker before we begin a few brief
notes stop by the business hall located
in Mandalay ocean buff side and
shoreline ballrooms on level 2 the
blackhat Arsenal is in the business hall
on level 2 lunch will be in Bayside a B
from 1:00 to 2:30 and don't forget the
merchandise store on level 2 and the
session recordings from source of
knowledge they I have a desk on every
level before we begin please put your
phone on vibrate it makes it easier for
the rest of us to ignore the ringing
while you wait for your voicemail to
pick it up alright let's give a hand
round of applause to our speakers hello
everyone dude doing awesome today we're
gonna be talking about the greatest tool
of all time bloodhounds power review
data power view actually all right so
our talk is called finding your path how
we're trying to improve Active Directory
security this is us
I'm Rohan I'm will I'm Andy alright
introductions done alright so first of
all we're gonna talk about a little bit
of background here we released the
Bloodhound project about three years ago
now and we had some very significant
problems to solve when we did so I do
want to acknowledge some prior work
these are really really cool stings
especially like Metcalf's blog here and
check all these out here is where we
kind of started when we were trying to
build bloodhound so we're standing on
the shoulder of giants here whatever
been possible without that all right
what is bloodhound bloodhound is the
tool we wrote and our goal was to apply
graph theory to Active Directory we
wanted to simplify privileged analysis
in Active Directory which if anyone has
tried to use built-in tools and Windows
knows
that is not easy it's very very arcane
and not very easy to navigate so we
wanted to visualize relationships in
Active Directory and essentially build
what we call Google Maps for Active
Directory so we had a bunch of problems
we had to solve one of them was how do
you go from one place in Active
Directory to another our background is
pentesters and red teamers and often we
drop it in a network and we were given
an objective
go get healthcare data go get da
whatever happened to be and our original
process would take a really long time so
this was kind of our solution to the
problem other problem we wanted to solve
is how do you escalate your privileges
without the scanning in the network many
many many times I'm gonna demonstrate
what I'm talking about in like the next
slide here but we hit the network a lot
when we used to operate and also how do
you analyze permissions more efficiently
than built-in tools so we're gonna tell
the tale of two api's the two API is
that Microsoft's have graciously
provided to make our lives much easier
but also was the basis for everything
we're talking about here the first one
is net session enum now the built in
Windows net command has lots of juicy
stuff in it and one of them is net
sessions and underneath net sessions
just uses the net session enum API call
what's fun is that the actual API call
has a nice little field for the server
name so because it the API call is a
little bit more complex than whether
than that session binary does by
implementing it directly we could
enumerate remote server sessions so now
we have a way to tell who's logged in
where the second one is net local group
yet members lets you retrieve a list of
members of a local group the one which
we were almost always most interested in
being the administrators group
administrators are awesome good lets you
do whatever you want on a system get rid
of all those pesky DDR solutions so
again this one has a server name
parameter so this allows us to renew
marae remotely and check who's a local
men on remote computers so let's let's
tell a little story here we have a pen
tester named Matt Nelson and he is pen
testing the corn hub bio domain this is
a nice little tiny office in Indiana
gotta make sure that they're really
secure so they have about nine computers
that Nelson fishes and gets initial
access on the computer in the middle
right there so this is our old
methodology here first thing you do you
run find local admin access and Power
View and now you've hit every single
machine once we're gonna put a little
number under each underneath each
machine here so you guys can keep track
we've found out we have admin on the two
machines that have flags on them now so
next thing we do is we run net session
enum on those we try to see who's logged
into those machines so we can get some
kind of idea of what kind of creds we
might get so we look at the user names
that come back and we find absolutely
nothing of value they're not domain
admins they're not an any like super
privileged group so let's just like
blindly pick one computer here we're
gonna go to the computer number four all
right so now we're over here what's the
next thing we do hey we hit the whole
network all over again we're going to do
find local admin access one more time
because now we have a new credential
that we've taken from this computer and
we want to know where we have admin so
now we've found admin a few more places
and again the number increments we now
we have to get net sessions on those
computers so now we're up to three on
those and we decide all right let's go
to the bottom computer over there and
this one looks juicy I think it's a da
and we go over there sure enough we're
domain admin yay we won but at this
point we've hit every computer at least
twice some three and this is a very very
very small network this is just nine
computers as the network scales up this
number just keeps increasing as each
step increases there's more and more
network in numeration that's being done
that's not good it's very very very slow
to do this process when we used to run
this process in larger environments this
would take us weeks or months to execute
weeks spent doing approvals escalation
is a lot of time that removes post
exploitation from your assessments as
you get more and more Network hits your
chance of getting caught also increases
and if you're on a red team getting
caught is no bueno
and as you get bigger and bigger
networks keeping track of what your
enumerated gets harder and harder we
used to try and solve this by using like
Excel pivot tables which is like the
worst thing you can possibly touch so we
want to do it better and as it just so
happens an entire branch of math that we
all fell asleep during math class for
exists to solve this problem so why are
we doing this ourselves so let's let's
do the new way so we drop in on the
network right in the middle here and we
run data collection for bloodhound we
hit every computer in the domain twice
once for that session once for local
admin but instead of just blindly
latently picking something we feed all
this data into our tool and then we say
let's make educated decisions where we
need to go so instead of having to go to
one computer and do an enumeration again
we know exactly where we need to go and
what we need to hit in order to get to
where we need to be so there you go you
do two steps you get the DA no more
networking numeration no more extra
steps you're just happy now sure all
right we're gonna swap out our table
here but wait there's more when you run
sharp out you're not just getting basic
local admins or sessions you're also
getting lots of other things like are
there any Kerberos misconfigurations who
belongs to what group and how is that
unrolled
are there any abusable East ACLs in the
environment that you could use which
might even prevent you from needing to
move laterally to another computer is
there MS sequel servers that you might
have admin to because of service
principles and if you do can you use
those to get where you need to go so in
the real world we actually created
bloodhound because we were in a massive
massive organization with thousands of
endpoints hundreds of thousands of
endpoints as it were getting domain
admin in a single domain in this network
two weeks now the organization have
literally hundreds of domains
this was definitely did not spark joy
knowing that getting to the top of the
root was gonna take months potentially
we built bloodhound as a proof of
concept and we ran it data collection
took no 48 hours about 48 hours and it
showed us a path that went through seven
different domains to compromise the
forest route so 48 hours to go from
beginning to end versus one week to get
just da in one single domain so it's
kind of the history of bloodhound the
genesis how it came about we've been
doing some new work in the past year so
that means some new attack edges adding
some cool new features so we wanted to
go through an example attack path and
show some of the more kind of niche cool
like new Kerberos abuses that we've been
able to implement it so as we're going
through this attack path think to
yourself okay
these misconfigurations have been in the
network or might be in your network for
years would you have had any way to
actually analyze and execute these
things or actually realize the
implication of the risk that some of
these components would have but first
we're going to talk about Kerberos
there's an element in Kerberos called
resource based constrained delegation
where the the general motivation for
delegation in general an active
directory is a way to impersonate users
just do user impersonation from the
Active Directory context resource based
constrained delegation as opposed to
unconstrained or classic constrain is a
modern so Server 2012 plus way to safely
allow this type of user impersonation in
the active directory context why is this
needed for delegation in general so the
classic example is if a user is
authenticated into a front-end service
say a web server that web server may
need to impersonate that user when
they're authenticating to a different
back-end service say a sequel database
so we've had some people say like why
does Microsoft allow impersonation or
delegation at all there are legitimate
use cases for it the first take edit the
Microsoft did with unconstrained is very
dangerous for different reasons
the second take they took it it would
constrain had its own kind of elements
potentially domain takeover depending on
things so this is a their third take at
delegation and overall it's a good
system but it has unintended
consequences that we love is pen testers
but diving a little bit deeper for
resource base how it actually works I'm
not going to spend you know 10 minutes
going over all the Kerberos internals
and all that but resource based
constrained delegation is implemented as
a security descriptor a discretionary
access control list on a target resource
or computer object so this tackle this
store is a serie of binary bytes and the
msds allowed to allow to act on behalf
of other identity it's a bit of a
mouthful property this is just a simple
ACL that defines who is allowed to
impersonate any user to that target
system the impersonation itself is
executed through a series of two
Kerberos extensions called s3 to self s
or youtube proxy why does this matter so
we had known about this for a while and
one of the things we really cared about
when we started bloodhound and doing the
ACL based injection components is we
wanted a computer ACL based takeover
attack operative what what do we mean by
that so for a user ACL based primitive
we could if we had generic all or kind
of edit rights admin rights over a user
object itself we could reset their
password that doesn't work with
computers because they'll become
disjoint from the domain so we've been
waiting for an ACL based primitive for
this and in spring of this year Evod
Shamir or at least his really really
awesome wagging the dog post on resource
base constrained delegation abuse and
his big finding is that non-portable s3
to self tickets will still work for s4
youtube proxy specifically in the case
of resource based constrained delegation
so what does that mean if you're not
person Kerberos is this grants us a
generalized ACL based computer takeover
per image
what does that mean in English in
English if we can modify this one
particular property on a target computer
object we can completely compromise that
computer and take it over we're going to
show this an attack that so first any is
in the show what this attack path would
look like and bloodhound so here's the
bloodhound interface whoa here's the
bloodhound interface and we're saying
the domain object in the contoso dot
local domain
give me the shortest attack paths to
there and the graph will find all the
shortest paths that exist from any node
in the domain to that object
this attack path starts at this desktop
0:01
computer as a session for Bob accounting
that user belonged to this group called
accounting support accounting support
belongs to accounting admins so through
security group delegation accounting
admins has epidemic accounting 0 0 1 and
so does Bob this computer in accounting
has generic write over an exchange
system which belongs to the exchange
trusted sub system group and AD our
favorite ad group favorite ad group that
group has tons and tons of privileges
including right tackle on the domain
head so we're gonna execute this attack
path in these video demos we're gonna
skip part one just because it's a very
basic thing it's local admin on a
computer so PS exec WMI whatever you
want okay so we're assuming that we're
going to be on this accounting box we
compromised that first hop we're gonna
show the verification of the ACLs that
bloodhound was able to find but first
we're on the system or on accounting
we're gonna escalate to the system user
context but showing like ok even
whatever context were in we do not have
we do not have rights over that target
box
so we will escalate up the system
because the system user context will use
the Machine account from whatever box
you're on see access denied
because we haven't actually executed
this resource-based constrained
delegation attack better yet so we're
gonna load up Power View to do our
active directory analysis we're also
gonna load up Kevin Robertson's
power-mad which abuses the machine
account quota component of active
directory to provision new machine
accounts in a way that we can control
so our target computer in this example
is going to be the exchange server this
is the machine that our current machine
has edit rights over we're going to pull
our actual attacker Sid so this is the
SID of the computer we're currently on
this is who has edit rights over that
target system then we're going to show
the ACL base we're just gonna pull the
the dackel the ACLs for that target
computer on the exchange box if we
examine the ace we see ok there's a
generic all right over the exchange
system by the security identifier what
happens which happens to match what our
current computer security identifier is
so this is just simple verification of
the actual ACL information the
bloodhound was able to enumerate the
next steps we want to actually execute
this this attack that we are going to
first use Powermat from Kevin Robertson
to provision a new machine account with
a password that we control this is
because we need an account we need
complete control of an account that has
a service principle name set to actually
execute the resource based constrained
delegation path we're gonna grab the
computer set these this is the this
computer says is going to become the
principal in the ACL that we actually
construct the general approach is we
need to create this ACL set it to a
particular property on the target and
then we're going to execute the s for
you to self and proxy component for
resource based constrained delegation so
create the ACL very easy to do in
PowerShell
we're gonna get the binary bytes that
ACL and we're going to use that and set
against the MSDS a lot to act on
Oh what can never burn off the whole
thing it's a little too long so part of
the axe
grab the binary form we're going to just
use a simple l dot property set against
the target and after that we're going to
pull the ACL to just verify that we
actually did the correct LDAP set on
this component the puller all raw bytes
we're going to transform that back into
a security descriptor and pull out the
discretionary component of the ACL for
verification but still you can actually
do this we're not gonna have
administrative rights against the target
system because we have to go through a
fairly complex Kerberos ticket exchange
process to actually get the final
service ticket that we want against the
target verification everything matches
up everything's great still don't have
admin rights ok the next bit we're going
to do is use a tool that we wrote called
Rubeus which is a Kerberos abuse toolkit
that heavily heavily pulls from benjamin
deltas kikyo project we're in a hash of
our password then we're going to use the
s4 you module our command and Rubeus to
actually execute this whole process
which will first get a TGT for this
dummy system account we created it'll do
that for you to self to itself to
impersonate an administrators or
pretending to be the domain admin then
it'll do this for you to proxy protocol
transition ending with a full ticket for
CIFS or the file system we're then going
to apply that ticket to our current
logon session and after this we're able
to compromise the exchange box awesome
there we go alright let's step one of
that whole path that Andy outline in the
bloodhound analysis component step two
we're moving to the exchange server
itself so now we're on the exchange box
see exchange o1 and this is the computer
account that because of the Nestene in
exchange trusted subsystem is gonna have
right deco rights over the domain root
this means that we can grant ourselves
DC sync privileges DC sync is a the
reimplementation of the DC replication
protocol by Vincent Lee - and Benjamin
so we're gonna run this and because we
have these edit rights we can't just DC
sync immediately we have control rights
over the target we don't have the DC
sync rights itself yet and you can do
any of these like a CL bias
modifications you don't have to use
Power View anything that has just LDAP
property modification can be used to
execute this PAP so we're going to use
the C import power view we're gonna get
the we need to get the identity the CID
of the chain trusted subsystem we're
verifying this okay that's one 603 then
we're gonna verify some of the ACL
information for the attack that but
because this we know okay exchange
trusted we can add and modify an ACL on
the root domain object where the
principal is the extreme trusted
subsystem itself we're gonna grant
ourselves DC sync rights everything's
gonna execute through and now we're
gonna have now we can synchronize and
retrieve the password credential
material for any use in the domain so
say krbtgt we get our hash we can create
all of our awesome golden tickets so
that's a fairly complex path with a lot
of moving pieces that even as of like a
year or so ago we would not have been
able to enumerate and find but these are
miss configurations that have existed in
domains and existing domains and have
been around for years we just don't
realize the full risk and implication of
it okay so
what are we trying to do about this do
you hear a lot of feedback from my voice
okay
I'll just keep on so our answer to this
as far as what can we do to efficiently
and empirically understand enumerate and
remediate these attack paths in Active
Directory is this it's our adversary
resilience methodology a lot of this is
based on this quote from John Lambert in
his blog post with this tile right here
attackers think in graphs defenders
think in lists as long as this is true
attackers when you would think that
we're contractually obligated to have
this quote in every talk that we have
but really this is a timeless and
extremely insightful quote from John
this is what our methodology it looks
like so starting at the top left we
enumerate attack paths that's using
bloodhound we analyze the attack paths
to understand what patterns we can
ferret out from that data and then the
most difficult part of this methodology
is in generating and validating those
remediation hypotheses and then finally
we deploy our prior talk to prioritize
fixes and start all over again we're
gonna focus here initially on analyzing
these attack paths that bloodhound shows
us so our objective here we want to find
critical low-hanging fruit we want to
generate basic descriptive statistics
and measure our overall security posture
in Active Directory based on these
misconfigurations and user behaviors so
before bloodhound was created it was
very very difficult to take any given
principal and Active Directory and
determine what privileges are held by
this principal because of the nature of
Active Directory permissions they are
discretionary so they are inbound on
objects and outbound privileges there is
no native way in Windows or Active
Directory to enumerate that with the
bloodhound data we can so this is a very
basic
descriptive statistic that we do for our
customers by the way everything we're
talking about this in this talk is free
and open source so there's nothing in
here that is like private or secret or
anything what we're looking at here is
just in descending order what are the
most privileged groups in Active
Directory and from this chart you can
see some very immediate insights that
would launch you into a little more of
investigative process to figure out why
these why this is the way this is an one
example is the domain admins group you
would expect that to be the most
privileged group an ad in this data set
which is based on real data the names
have been changed to protect the
innocent the domain admins group is
barely even in the top five of the most
privileged ad groups sometimes it's not
even in top ten so Shawn Metcalf has a
fantastic blog post about how domain
admin is you know just the tip of the
iceberg we should be going far beyond
domain admin but still da is like the
most obvious target something else you
can look at is there are these helpdesk
tier 1 2 & 3 groups that you would think
they would have a different level of
privilege in AD but for some reason they
have all the exact same privilege which
kind of defies our at least privilege
goals so in this chart we can we can
understand what the privileges are
they're held by the most sensitive
groups what those miss the most
sensitive verbs actually are and start
digging into how we can protect the
users and other identities that belong
to these groups so what about the other
way around
what about computers in my domain sorted
in descending order of the most admins
that exist on each of those so this is
based on fake data that we created with
our blood on DB creator script and you
can see like very obviously at the very
top there are these four computers that
have way more admins than any other
system and the network does in reality
this chart looks exactly like this in
real environments but the numbers are
astronomically large and sometimes
that's because the domain users group
gets added to the local admins group but
sometimes it's also because a different
all-inclusive non default
built-in ad group has been added either
to a privileged group or has been
directly edited local admins group on a
system with traditional auditing tools
you really can't determine this
information easily what that makes it
super easy so we're going to look at
another video this this slide right here
at the very top we can see that this
comp 0 0 0 3 computer has way more
admins than any other computer does it's
a part of a group of 4 other computers
that have that many admins so in the
bloodhound UI we can look up that
computer and we can figure out what's
going on any asset that's tracking
bloodhound you can just like just like
Google Maps you search for it we'll
click on the computer and then under
this local admin section we can see that
there are six principles that are
actually added to the domain evidence
group but then if we unroll that out
there's actually 500 different users
that have evan rights on that system and
it's all because of that right there
that domain users group has been added
to the local admins group on that
computer so as far as finding
low-hanging fruit an ad on the
assessments that we do we find this on
day one and usually eyes are kind of
like big and like people are terrified
to see this kind of stuff all right what
about Kerberos Kerberos sting
fundamentally changed how we operated as
red teamers because it gave us a
capability to do password cracking
attempts on usually very high privileged
users in AD from any domain
authenticated context and do this kind
of offline brute-force attack against a
curb 5 TGS ticket but how do you
prioritize as a red teamer what users
are actually interesting to go after so
in the Bloodhound data we can again look
at any principle and determine what
privileges they have and on red teams
this is exactly what we do
we'll find ok here are the ten you
kerberos table and one of them is a
domain admin or one of them has admin
rights on 50% of the boxes or whatever
so they can be kind of interesting and
that can be very helpful to chart out in
a way like this so we can kind of have a
hit list of okay you should be
remediating these users first because of
the level of privilege so that's one
thing that's kind of interesting but
what if we also add another element to
this what if we say alright these are my
Kerberos table users but the Kerberos
attack being successful depends on that
user having a weak password that can
actually be broken okay well let's try
to break all of them so here's all of
our users that our Kerberos LaBolt that
also have a weak password that we were
able to crack a password within some
reasonable time frame 24 hours 48 hours
whatever so when you're looking for
remediation strategy you're looking for
low-hanging fruit which is exactly what
we're talking about here this is like
zooming in and saying here is your
extreme risk you need to fix this
immediately there was a customer that we
did this for recently and there was a
user that had admin rights on 97% of
their systems password has changed let's
just say a long time ago we showed them
this chart and they deleted the user
within the hour a huge amount of attack
surface was removed basically
instantaneously so pretty big win what
about this so when we're looking at
strategies to figure out how can we
reduce attack surface and AD it's useful
to have very basic statistics that will
apply to any domain and so we hone in on
this we hone in on what percentage of
users in Active Directory can compromise
a domain admin this is a very simple
concept that we can actually empirically
measure thanks to this tool what do I
want to say I want to say that is very
common that this number is a hundred
percent in Active Directory so let's go
back to our overall resilience
methodology and now we want to look at
how we can generate and validate these
so to save your mediation hypotheses and
our objective here is to eliminate or
mitigate as many attack paths as
possible using practical and measurably
effective strategies before we actually
attempt to deploy them in production so
when we say practical we mean we don't
want to go in someplace or you don't
want to do this yourself and then come
back and say well you just have to re
are protecting entire forests it's easy
and everything will be fixed everything
will be solved don't more tourists
tomorrow yeah I will do it we'll go
tomorrow it's not practical for most
organizations to go through that process
that process can also be extremely
expensive as a lot of people know so
what we're looking for are the so to say
surgical and precise changes that we can
deploy within days or weeks and not
years so here's an example of what you
might see in bloodhound this is a user
over here on the Left called er more 0 0
1 1 and what we're looking at here are
all of the shortest attack paths to
domain heaven and that word shortest is
absolutely vital
so in graph theory it is very easy to
find a shortest attack path or a
shortest path from any vertex to any
other vertex there are several different
outcomes that can solve that problem
instantaneously effectively like think
about Google Maps how long does it take
to calculate a route from Los Angeles to
New York less than a second it's very
very fast Google message that because
they use a graph to track all that data
so something without we want to help you
with is avoid a very common pitfall that
we fell into ourselves and then we also
see a lot of other people falling into
when they start trying to apply this
data in a defensive way and that pitfall
is looking at this information right
here and believing or thinking that this
is the entire attack path possibility
from one user to the domain admins group
it is not we are looking at the shortest
attack paths so
here's a longer attack path that goes
through one other group membership step
that we couldn't enumerate because it
was not part of the shortest attack pads
here's another here's another attack
path that was not enumerated at first
because it is also not among the
shortest attack paths let's go just a
different way very common question we
get is how can I see all attack paths
okay this is a good question and it is a
question that we asked ourselves when we
started trying to accomplish more
defensive centric things using this data
so we're going to look at all the tech
paths that are possible from this user
this is one user and this one we're
looking at this is length zero so link
zero of an attack path here's one here's
two here's three here's four here's five
here's six seven eight nine didn't need
to be derive any kind of insight from
that I can but for one user outbound
attack has that are possible of length
nine this also took approximately three
minutes for the database to return the
result of this query why is this this is
because finding all paths means you have
to include the longest path finding the
longest path in a graph is a very well
studied problem in graph theory and it
is understood and known to be non
polynomial hard visit is an np-hard
problem this is true for directed
acyclic graphs which is what the
Bloodhound attack graph is if it were an
a cyclic graph then you could solve this
problem in linear time which also will
be a very very very long time so
shortest attack paths we look at in
customer environments and this is how
many attack paths we found in one of
those networks this network had 8,000
computers all of the possible shortest
attack paths from any user to domain
admins the domain route the domain
controller whatever twenty million three
hundred forty six thousand three hundred
and eighty five I don't know about you
but I don't want to go I don't want to
go to reach one of those it's like an
average Tuesday I'm in we have 15
minutes left though so we running we're
gonna start with number one okay sure
this attack number one stupid joke so
the bottom line that I want to try to
drive into your mind is that Active
Directory is not a maze was a red teamer
as a pen tester you start off with
access under one system some kind of
like beachhead system and you find your
way through Active Directory until you
finally get to your objective domain
admin or whatever don't think of Active
Directory as a maze Active Directory is
a map it is a extremely complicated it
extremely complicated map that doesn't
follow the rules of two-dimensional
geography so consider this if we're
going from Washington DC to New York
this is the shortest path
here's another path here's another path
another path another one so don't think
about trying to look at all the attack
paths you can't I'm sorry to say so what
if instead of looking at all the attack
paths what if we change our thinking
from you know trying to find like a
sparse cut edge into a strategy of
isolation well they were trying to
isolate New York and Washington DC from
the rest of the country well we would
start with zoom in on that city and we
would understand what are the first and
second-degree connections that get us
there
all right let's replace that with domain
admins and domain users so forget about
analyzing all paths
focus on isolating sensitive principles
and focus on understanding what the
outbound privileges are they're held by
the built-in security groups also
privileges are held by more or less
all-inclusive security groups in Active
Directory as well that are not default
and built-in so how can I do this for
domain admins well let's look at how
domain admins are exposed there are
several different ways that we can
understand a domain admin exposure or
exposure for the group itself so we have
credentials in memory we have abusable
aces we have GPO abuse harborough's AS
prep roasting there's a thousand ways to
skin that cat let's focus on GPO abuse
first
so with GPOs
if I control a GPO that is linked to an
object that descends down and affected
domain admin if I control that GPO I
control that domain admin I can do
anything I want with GPO possibilities
are absolutely endless so with our data
we can look at any user who belong to
the domain Evans group what are the GPO
that apply to any of those users
regardless of where they exist in the OU
you tree also
nine times out of ten we see that domain
admins don't actually belong to the same
oh you
so whatever GPO is applied to a domain
admin is basically anybody's guess so
what we want to look at is show me who
has control of any GPO that applies to a
domain admin where that user is not a
domain admin and I don't really care if
a DA can pop another da I can trust them
to you know protect themselves sloop and
run that query and it looks like this so
there's a domain object there and teal
and then the GPO that are linked to the
domain head then we have four different
security groups that have control of
different GPOs that apply to those das
those users are not domain admins so
what if we remove those permissions or
what if we change the owners of those
GPIOs from some random
group back to the domain admins group
you would think that this would cause
some remediation like maybe this will
reduce the percentage of users that have
an attack path and maybe it'll reduce
the overall number of attack paths or
what if we're not talking about GPO
whatever talking about deploying pause
and making domain admins log into paws
or we're talking about ACLs can be
abused when we started doing this we
thought I am so brilliant you are not
gonna believe this I'm gonna I'm gonna
make it so that domain admins only log
on the domain controllers and we're
gonna see a huge reduction in the attack
paths of Av so we stipulate that change
in our graph I'll say we remove those
permissions and change the object owners
and the GPOs
so before it was 100 percent of the
users that have passed the DA we changed
the data set we simulate that change
before we have to put it into production
and after anybody won take a guess what
the stat is after just how effective my
brilliant strategy is gonna be I never
sent made absolutely no difference why
is this because the graph is extremely
highly connected and there are other
attack paths that we weren't seeing
because we were looking at all paths
because you can't
what about abusable aces what if we also
say okay well I'm still gonna trim those
permissions in the GPOs because I want
to have this strategy of isolation from
my domain admins when they still have
all these other attack paths now that
rely on abusing aces on the domain admin
users of the domain admins group itself
so here's an example we have our domain
admins group we have those users that
belong to the group inbound object
control if you look at the very bottom
there you can see that there are three
principles that have explicit control of
the domain admins group but if you
unroll that out there are actually 47
different identities that have control
of the group or a user in the group and
here they are
so we can unroll this out and visualize
what groups can control a domain admin
or control the group itself so let's get
rid
that let's focus on that strategy of
isolation
okay so we've simulated changing gpo
control for GPIOs that apply to domain
admins or computers that are used by
domain admins and we've trimmed
permissions inbound on the domain admin
users and on the domain admins group so
before we had 100% of the users when
attack path domain admin after it's 82%
we're actually making some forward
progress these numbers by the way are
real these are real numbers from a real
environment this is what's possible is
once you once you understand this this
strategy of isolation both on the end
point of the attack path and on the
possibilities for where the attack path
can begin these are the local admin
rights on domain users or Kerberos table
users or domain users that have RDP
access on systems that are escalated all
or there's a local previs combo systems
you can whittle this down so that your
attack surface is reduced all the way
down to 1% or less than 1% of the users
in the directory being able to take
control of a domain admin sometimes we
can't get this number this low I think
the worst that we've done so far is
being able to take it down to about 6
percent which is still pretty good once
you have that once you have those attack
pass whittled down and you say well we
can't get it any lower because there are
some business need for a domain trust or
for some kind of configuration instead
of having to deploy some kind of non
scalable security control so that you're
you know kind of like surveying every
single computer in the environment no
good because you have no idea where the
attacker is gonna go you're kind of
funneling of the attacker so that they
have to go through this one system they
have to go through this one user and
those controls that cannot scale if it's
5 computers that I have to deploy the
Windows Firewall on and configure
inbound whitelisting rules I could do
that in an afternoon if I could do that
for a hundred thousand computers join to
AD
it's not gonna happen everything in this
talk is free and opensource
the tools we talked about bloodhound the
book on analytics tool pie review
power-mad in vogue DC sync and the
methodology itself is also free and open
source if you look at the bloodhound
analytics URL there you will be able to
create these charts yourself and then if
you look at this blog post in the top
right you'll see even more detail about
understanding the difference between all
paths shortest paths and all that kind
of good stuff thank you very much for
your time I think we have about six
minutes left if we want to take
questions here and then otherwise we're
gonna be out in the breakout room to the
right over here
thank you guys thank you