good morning this is legal Geo
narcissist GNSS spoofing and its effects
on autonomous vehicles breakers GHI with
Victor Murray before we begin stop by
the business hall and Mandalay Bay
Oceanside and shoreline ballrooms on
level 2 during the day for the Welcome
Reception 5:30 tonight at Arsenal join
us with join us for the pony Awards in
lagoon GA China at 1830 our 6:30 if
you're an American and thanks for
putting your phone on vibrate it makes
us easier for the rest of us to ignore
the ringing while we while you wait for
your voicemail to pick it up so Victor
hello everybody I'm so excited to be
here
happy to tell you about some of the work
that we've done global navigation
satellite systems these are
constellations of satellites that orbit
the earth broadcast a signal down and
our receivers or our phones are able to
calculate their location within a
certain error and this is used for all
kinds of things
I took an uber from the airport to get
to Mandalay Bay it uses GNSS it's also
used for things like time stamping stock
trades so they know exactly when a stock
train went through it's also used to set
the frequency of power lines one of the
issues with GNSS is it lacks integrity
mechanisms this means that all of our
receivers are susceptible to spoofing in
addition to lacking integrity mechanisms
Genesis is also transmitted at a very
low power so the PI actual power
received by your receiver is gonna vary
depending on the altitude the atmosphere
of things like that but typically for
GPS the power that's received is between
minus 120 DB M minus 1 30 DBM my
software-defined radio that sits on the
bench very low power is able to
broadcast at plus 15
that's at least a delta of 135 DBM
it's huge difference very easy to
overpower the signal that comes from the
skies the signal that your receiver sees
is actually below the noise floor
they're also susceptible to interference
so things if the signals reflected off
of a building or a mountain it can
affect the localization estimate if you
drive under or through a tunnel or under
an underpass it can block out some of
the satellites or it can block them out
altogether similar effects with weather
so how could systems respond to spoofing
there's been a lot of good work in this
area by a whole lot of people but I'm
gonna highlight a couple here
dr. Todd Humphries he's from the
University of Texas at Austin his has
had several publications that I've
enjoyed reading and this is just one
example video from YouTube of them doing
a live over-the-air spoofing of a drone
so what happens is the drone goes up
it's flying on its own they spoof the
GNSS signal they get it to latch on to
it as soon as it latches on to the
signal they've run the altitude through
the roof the vehicle responds by coming
down Team Unicorn did a great
presentation at DEFCON on their low-cost
GPS simulator all they needed was a $400
software-defined radio and a laptop and
they were able to spoof GPS over-the-air
or Genesis one of the cool things that
they did was exploitation of geofencing
so the drones today come with
pre-programmed areas that they're not
supposed to fly such as military bases
things like that so what they did was
broadcast a signal making it think that
they were in one of these spaces they're
not supposed to be and causing the
drones to come down out pretty neat
another interesting case is the Iran
hack so Iran claims this is back in 2011
Iran claims to have hacked the Genesis
for an rq-170 drone causing it to come
down there's a whole lot of things that
would have had to have been set up in a
very specific way for that to have
happened it's certainly possible I don't
know if it's true or not I'm going to
tell you a little bit about my
experience with drones and it in in in
my experience
it's it's just as possible that they
just jam the signal and it could have
had a similar similar effect so what can
happen if systems aren't tested for
Genesis issues I was hired at my current
company in 2002 to work on drones as a
student I built our autopilot system and
ground control station this picture the
one on the left is me in 2006 and on the
Wrights angel Rivera we were project
managers for our flight control system
part of my duties was to oversee field
operations and we had around 50 drones
that had been built and we're flying
regular so we had a whole lot of flight
hours accumulating so when when the
customer would have a problem the the
company that owned the drone when they
had a problem they would call me they'd
send me the data I would look at it and
do a root cause analysis try to identify
what what caused this issue simple
things from the kinds of issues that
they would call me before were just a
warning popping up or they should deploy
these there's a small chute in this
drone and ended the mission early or in
a couple of cases the the drone was went
down and crashed or or was lost so when
I was looking at these problems there
were two primary causes the first was
mechanical issues so this is a wire came
loose or an antenna came loose or a
motor stopped working those kinds of
things the second most common issue is
with sensors we saw issues with all
kinds of sensors but the most common was
GNSS there were instances where the GNSS
would move to the right by 200 meters or
the altitude would jump by 50 meters or
we would lose it it would drop out for
three or four minutes or we would lose
GNSS permanently the system always
responded in a little different manner
sometimes appropriately sometimes not
sometimes the system would it would it
would fly low like it lost Eunice's to a
flight a little higher to try to get a
better signal receive that signal and
then go on its mission but sometimes we
lost the aircraft so these corner cases
are kind of key to improving the
reliability of autonomous vehicles and
so
what we thought was let's build a system
that allows us to test these corner
cases these things that you're gonna
have to go out and drive your car or fly
your drone for for you know thousands
and thousands of hours to see just once
but be able to repeat it over and over
again so this concept in mind we applied
for and receive internal research and
development funding from our company all
the results that you're gonna see we're
100% funded by our company so I'm going
to tell you about the the smoothing
system
it's got hardware and software
components I'm going to tell you about
our autonomous vehicle fleet and
specifically the vehicle that was tested
then I'm gonna highlight some of our
testing results we did a whole whole lot
of testing but I've got three key ones
that we're gonna highlight here today
position translation velocity
manipulation and halting the Jeana
system and then I'm gonna provide our
recommendations and takeaways we have an
entire department that focuses on
research and development of autonomous
vehicles all the vehicles shown on the
screen here are owned by my company and
they have all been outfitted with our
own autonomy kits so the Lincoln MKZ in
the upper right would was also outfitted
with an autonomy kit and it's what we
use for all of our testing all of the
testing it was configured to drive by
GNSS Waypoint for the purpose of these
tests all the attacks that we're gonna
show were performed remotely and in
real-time so the first word in my title
is legal haven't talked at all about yet
so to be legal how do we comply let's
start with what's illegal spoofing RF
signals not limited to GNSS any type of
RF signal is illegal in the United
States further Communications Act of
1934 so what's legal well the FCC has a
couple of routes that you can take to
get special permission you can either
get an experimental license or you can
get a waiver of the FCC's rules for all
of our testing we did not use either of
those we did not get special permission
from the FCC the next two items we did
use your a louder a broadcast inside of
a fully enclosed Faraday cage and the
key word and the regulation
fully enclosed you're also allowed to
broadcast on the isn bands your 900
megahertz to point four or five point
eight gigahertz as long as you keep the
power below one watt so the system that
we use throughout all this testing is
100% legal this is the hardware outline
we start by putting our own RTK
high-precision GNSS receiver on top of
the receiver that we want to spoof that
way we know it's actual position in real
time that signals that that sensor sends
nemeth sentences to the computer and the
computer is able to manipulate those or
pass them through and modify that
modification that manipulation is
controlled remotely over either a Wi-Fi
or cellular link the modified or
unmodified signal is then sent to the
software-defined radio which generates
the analog signal that's sent to the
receiver under test and the way we send
it to the receiver under test we did two
different methods one was inside the
fully enclosed Faraday cage and this is
we put the actual antennas inside of a
box we'll put some RF dampening material
in there and would broadcast its
over-the-air but it's completely
contained and second was just connecting
directly in line with the antenna all of
the testing results that I'm going to
show use that approach use this hardware
outline we also demonstrated the ability
to use frequency translation with that
what that did was we added two boxes to
this block diagram one at the output of
the software-defined radio and one on
the receiver under test we focused on
GPS l1 band which has a carrier
frequency of one point five seven five
gigahertz we didn't mix that with a 660
megahertz signal filter amplify and it
shifts it to the ninth 915 Center
frequency we send that signal
over-the-air this is in the unlicensed
panel we then have our own box on the
other side that receives that that
signal shifts if it does it does the
opposite again mixes it was 660 slightly
different filtering and amplification
and sends that signal to the receiver
under test and it worked and the benefit
of this was going to be we could take a
lot of equipment off a vehicle and have
a lighter package the problem was when
we took it out to the field we had
severe range limitations we could only
broadcast this method it injects a lot
of noise into the signal and when we
did this we could only broadcast staying
under the one wah up to about 200 meters
and so all the results that you're gonna
see use the Wi-Fi or cellular link this
is our controlling software the software
on the right is ours it's written with
Python scripts the concentric circles
you're allowed to click anywhere the
operator will click anywhere on that
screen and instantly insert an offset
that offsets scalable it can be a
thousand meters hundred thousand meters
there can be one meter at the bottom
there's a bunch of buttons those are our
TAC scripts that do the other the other
manipulations missing with velocity or
timing or those kinds of things the
software to the right is commercial
off-the-shelf its sky del s DX we use
that software to take a latitude long
longitude altitude position and
translate it to the signal that goes to
the software to find radio all right the
fun part the attacks alright all the
videos that I'm going to show the car
first drives the path that it's planned
to drive for the offset attack we were
able to manipulate the vehicles position
up to 10 meters at a time for this demo
we offset at 4 meters to the right and
you can see the vehicle responds by
moving four meters to the left we didn't
remove it it comes right back to the
right now understand the signal that the
car is receiving it's driving straight
on its path that it's supposed to and
then it jumps over and it immediately
corrects so if you looked at the at the
path that it's growing it sits down the
it's straight down the road except for
when we inject those manipulations now
we can we can modify this multiple times
we can move it 4 meters to the right
then 4 meters to the right that 4 meters
to the right if we moved more than 10
the receiver lost fix and understand
this car is relying on the GNSS receiver
to guide itself so if it loses the
signal for more than more than a second
or so it kicks out and asked the
operator to take over which is which so
for us that killed the test we got to
that point now where might as well just
jam the signal right all right besides
moving it left and right we could also
move it forwards or backwards and cause
the vehicle to either turn early or turn
late
alright next we dork with the velocity
in this demo the car comes up it makes a
right-hand turn and it comes to a stop
for the attack as the car is coming
towards us right before it starts to
make the turn we increase the velocity
so the car it's GNSS signal keeps
driving straight past the camera now the
car still turns because that's what it's
control system will do but it doesn't
see the turning and it's feedback so it
turns harder it drives itself off the
road so had we modified it earlier we
for this demo we modified it right
before the turn and we modified it
earlier it would have made a similar
turn but we could have made it turn
earlier turn late so if we sped it up
the car would have turned before the
turn oh we slowed it down it would have
turned after the turn when it's driving
straight and we changed the velocity it
had no immediate impact and the reason
is because the car governed its speed
based on wheel speed not GNSS velocity
which makes a lot of sense we the wheel
speed is super constant where the GNSS
velocity is a little more squirrely all
right now the halt for this scenario the
car drives straight through the
intersection and past the camera
okay now for the attack as it's coming
up to the intersection we quickly
stopped the GNSS signal the car swerves
right then it swerves left so what
actually happens is during that slowdown
period of slowdown periods about two
seconds it goes from about 25 miles per
hour down to zero and when it's doing
that over that - and this is the genus s
speed not the vehicle speed when it's
when it's making that transition the
vehicle has no notable noticeable effect
it keeps driving straight but as soon as
it stopped the control system becomes
unstable again the the cars driving and
it has no feedback it doesn't know which
way to turn so we did a lot of other
testing and we had similar results if we
when we did one of our timing attacks
where we pass through the real GNSS
signal but we delayed it by a couple
seconds so we'll do in doing that the
car set the control system again became
instead stable and had similar results
so these are our recommendations to
enhance safety critical systems now I'm
not making these recommendations for for
your navigation system on your car if
you get if you're driving down the road
and your navigation system gets spoofed
what happens it's annoying you might be
late you might not be able to find your
wherever you're going - but you're okay
there there's no harm that comes to you
there's no harm that comes to your car
so these recommendations are for systems
that are making safety critical
decisions that can have the ability to
either harm a person or an asset so
first recommendation is easiest that's
to use multiple constellations most
receivers already do this it's just good
practice if you take it a step further
you can also compare the localization
estimate between the different
constellations with each other and look
for a divergence the downside is also
the easiest to overcome or able to spoof
most multiple constellations as our most
security researchers that work in genus
s alright next
don't rely solely on GNSS for safety
critical systems all right it's not it's
not if but when they will be spoof the
can be spoof the cost of these systems
is dropping every day you can't rely
solely on it our third is to monitor the
signal there's all kinds of data that
comes from it you get position velocity
acceleration signal noise ratio
levels all these things they can all be
characterized and monitored if your
civvie annoys ratio for a satellite
jumps from 35 up to 55 that might
indicate a spoofing event and your
system should respond accordingly
specific to autonomous vehicles there's
a number of different localization
systems there's vision based source
lidar based combinations thereof and
there's GNSS these systems have got to
be used together and compared to each
other we've got to use those to identify
divergence in the estimates and the
system needs to be able to respond when
that occurs and finally we need to test
these systems to make sure when these
corner cases come up if the GPS jumps or
or if it's spoofed and somebody's you
know rather as we saw in the demo runs
the runs the altitude through the route
for a drone how's the system respond and
in my experience we did we tried to do
all this we had a simulator tried to
make sure the software would do all
these things but we were when we went
out in the field the system didn't
always respond as we expect it and so
these things need to be tested on the
final systems longer-term we need to add
integrity verification methods to the
GNSS satellites and this applies to all
the public versions
GPS GLONASS Baidu Galileo they all need
to add integrity verification mechanisms
either digital signatures public private
keys some other form of encryption some
way to know that the signal that your
receiver receives came from the
satellites in the sky not from an SDR
sitting on the side of the road all
right
key takeaways all right we we
demonstrated as you saw in all the
videos that you can legally spoof GNSS
in a field environment we did it using a
fully enclosed Faraday cage and the is M
broadcast one of the key things so we
were able to do a lot of cool stuff we
could move the vehicle right move it
left we could speed it up slow it down
delay the timing to it cause the control
system become unstable but that's it
there were severe limitations when we
started this I had thought well hey
maybe we'll be able to have the car
think it's it's driving down the freeway
while it's parked in the parking lot it
just wasn't the case and that's because
the car uses other sensors so Genesis
isn't
raising sensor and I and I I'm an
optimist I think it should be used for
autonomous vehicles and it's I'm not
advocating otherwise but we need to be
careful we need to do it in the right
way so as I said on the last night
specific for autonomous vehicles we've
got to combine the genus s with other
localization estimates and make sure the
vehicles respond accordingly
so I had a lot of help on this project
bin Abbott co-created the idea for this
with me and help me get the internal
funding Vinland al wrote most of the
software and supported all the tests
that you saw Jimmy Lee did our RF design
he designed our Faraday cage provided
support when we brain it annoys issues
and things like that and mat Brees who
didn't make my slide but he helped with
the autonomous vehicle support and
that's my presentation thank you guys so
much for coming out and if there any
questions you look welcome to come and
ask I'm gonna warn people ahead of time
I do not hear very well so please try to
speak clearly
no questions all right
[Applause]
oh there's one you want to go up to the
microphone you want to go up there it
said they said everyone can hear hello
yeah it was one I was wondering if you
had given any thought to what kind of
the arms way his race would look like as
red teams would inject spoofing and
people would try to harden and then what
that might look like is that kind of
feedback loop starts up understand I I'm
gonna shy away from responding to a
nation-state style attacks I don't so it
so most of my recommendations and you
know we're using for nation state there
are military versions of GNSS which
should be used for their systems so all
of these comments are geared towards
public versions keep you to discuss a
little bit how you implemented the
Faraday cage in the open field
sure so the the Faraday cage we bought
it's a cast aluminum box very small
inside of there we put some RF absorbing
material this is which makes it very
heavy it says this is the the box has
some significant weight to it and inside
there we put the receiving antenna and
we also put our spoofing antenna so
these they're the antenna if you were
doing spoofing you take those two
outside it's gonna have a similar effect
but we just put both of them inside of a
box so that the signal that's being
broadcast is contained so you put the
broadcast antenna on the vehicle as well
next the brachot the broadcasting
antenna is also inside the cage dr. you
got it yes just threw out my question so
with with like the spoofing of the gns
like do you think that there are like
what are some other different aspects
you think besides genus as spoofing that
could affect the autonomous vehicles
I think they could what like different
different attacks that could could
affect them besides GNSS spoofing well
there's there's a lot of interesting
work out there on sensor spoofing in
general and it's not limited to just
Genesis that's what this presentation
focused on but it's a problem for most
sensors especially those that get
received attic people have demonstrated
spoofing of cameras of lidar radar
ultrasonic they've all been spoofed part
of my at least my my logic and thinking
is that spoofing all of these in
coordination is
incredibly difficult if not impossible
with today's technology and so I
advocate for we need to take we need to
have all this sensor data and it needs
to be compared with each other to do
sanity checks in real time do you think
it would be possible if somebody put
together an attack specifically on
autonomous vehicle that affected not
only just the GNSS but also like other
sensors it's possible but a lot of the
times and and you know and I've spend a
lot of time working on this you can
characterize a lot of these attacks and
to coordinate the characterization
between different sensors simultaneously
in in my experience would be just
unbelievably difficult to do is it
possible yes and certainly if technology
gets better if you had now somebody has
access to the data bus and you can do
data bus injection and replay and maybe
those things become more likely a lot of
our work has focused on the remote
access to these things thank you oh we
got one minute yeah just real quick you
mentioned at the close of your talk you
mentioned two other describe if you
could other localization methods could
you give us some examples of that please
sure I so we have one that's vision
based that points down at the ground and
from the ground it's able to estimate
the position that it's at there are
other ones I'm less familiar with but
you have way mo and you have the Chevy
Cruze those guys have their own versions
I believe they're all camera based but
I'm not sure way mo may integrate lidar
as well lidar thank you so I've got two
questions one do you think that Amazon
or any of the larger companies are
looking at mitigation techniques for
their drone delivery systems so say that
again do you have you heard of any or no
of any mitigation techniques at Amazon
or any larger commercial companies are
doing for free I do not I do not agree
and then the second question have you
and your peers or have you talked to
anybody about maybe looking at doing
some similar testing against automated
landing systems takeoff systems for
commercial airliners or
airplanes of larger sizes have not when
we were doing the research we talked
about putting it on a larger drone at
which which would have more and and
drones have different control systems so
when we're talking about the ground
vehicles they do have to use other
localization methods simply because the
GNSS by itself isn't accurate enough but
drones drones you can be can fly almost
we have to have an IMU with it but a
drone with an eye on you can fly pretty
well so it would have different
responses than the vehicles that you saw
here