without any further ado I'd like to
introduce the speakers for today we're
going to do monsters and middleboxes
I'm introducing Gabby and Luke from
CloudFlare so please give them a warm
welcome thank you thanks for the little
introduction and thank you to everyone
for sticking with us throughout the a/v
setup turns out it takes a lot of
engineers to make AV work and with that
let's get started so hi everyone thanks
for joining us today and we're excited
to share our work on detecting HTTP
interception and to show you the tools
that we've built to detect the monsters
in the middle we observe on cloud
players network so hi everybody I'm Rick
valensa I'm a recent PhD graduate from
the University of Pennsylvania and I'm
now a systems engineer on the cloud
player cryptography team and I'm Gabi
Fisher I'm a recent masters graduate
from Stanford University and I'm also
now systems engineer at CloudFlare on
the workers team so today's talk will
start with an overview of what HTTP
interception is in common sources of
monster in the middle activity next
we'll cover a technique that we use the
detect HTTP interception on inbound
traffic to cloud players network and
then we'll end our talk by sharing the
tools that we built to detect HTTP
interception and observe these
interception patterns on our global
network to make sure everyone is on the
same page let's quickly do an overview
of how a monster in the middle could
intercept HTTP traffic let's start with
the default case that a lot of us are
familiar with a normal HTTP connection
here a client first performs a TLS
handshake with a server negotiates a
shared symmetric key and then transmits
HTTP encrypted contents using the
symmetric key before the client performs
a TLS handshake
the server must prove its identity
through the client by presenting its
certificate which is issued using the
root certificate of a widely trusted
certificate authority
now let's see what happens when a TLS
connection between a client and a server
goes through a third party this third
party in the middle is either Hardware
called a middle box or software called
middleware it sits between the client
and the server proxying traffic between
a client and its intended destination in
this case example.com the middle box
cannot read encrypted HTTP traffic
between the clients and the server
since this traffic is encrypted with the
symmetric key that only the client and
server know because they are the only
two to have negotiated it during the TLS
handshake if someone wanted to set up a
middle box or middleware to intercept
HTTP traffic the following setup is
necessary first the middle box needs its
own root certificate so it can issue its
own certificates if the interceptor
wants to intercept traffic from the
client to the example.com server the
Interceptor can present its own issued
certificate for example.com and try to
trick the client into thinking that its
certificate corresponds to the real one
for example.com
the client would hypothetically perform
a TLS handshake with the Interceptor not
the end server such that the Interceptor
could negotiate a symmetric key with the
client and then be able to decrypt the
clients traffic this approach fails
however because the client will not
trust the interceptors root certificate
by default instead a client would likely
receive a warning which says that the
certificate that the middle box
presented was not issued by a trusted
root certificate like that of a
certificate authority to prevent this
morning from happening something seeking
to someone seeking to intercept HTTP
traffic must make the client trust the
interceptors root certificate this
practice of getting the clients a trust
and install the interceptors root
certificate is the crux of most HTTP
interception practices now the
interceptors self issued certificate for
example.com appears to be trustworthy
and the client will perform a TLS
handshake with the Interceptor meaning
that the Interceptor can decrypt the
clients HTTPS content
the Interceptor typically then Rhian
crypts the clients content by performing
a TLS handshake with the real server and
re encrypting the clients HTTP content
when sending it to the server now the
middle box can inspect and modify the
inner HTTP content between the client
and the server with the out errors
showing up on either end now that we
know what HTTP interception looks like
we're going to cover a few examples of
these monsters in the middle commonly
seen on the Internet
our first monster in the middle is this
rather bureaucratic looking one it
represents proxies like antivirus
software in corporate or government
proxies these proxies of several goals
including protecting clients by
detecting malware or command and control
traffic or protecting a corporation by
detecting and preventing data
exfiltration these types of proxy is
also have a nefarious side and can be
used to censor or spy on clients even
when these middle boxes are meant to
improve the security of connections they
can increase the attack surface of an
HTTP connection some examples of this
are vulnerabilities and Kaspersky
antivirus software and blue code one of
the most popular corporate proxies these
proxies can also be used for malicious
means in recent news the Kazakh
government forced the Kazakh ISP to make
clients install root certificates so
that they could intercept HTTP traffic
to social media websites like Facebook
cosmic ISPs encouraged users to install
this root certificate by saying it would
protect them from fraud or hacking
attempts or illegal content but really
the set up allows the Kazakh government
to potentially spy on citizens is
everyday online activity our next
monster in the middle is this grifter
over here it represents adware or
malware and these intercept HTTP
connections to inject ads into webpages
or even try to steal and exploit private
data one example of this is search
awesome adware especially a well-known
example of adware is superfish whose
root certificate was shipped by default
with many Lenovo devices
the third class of interceptors are
poorly implemented and often unnecessary
proxies that increase a connections
attack surface strap there we go so an
example of this I find really oops this
is what happened to me of av troubles
right before you give a talk but it will
be fine
cool so a third class of interceptors
are poorly implemented and often
unnecessary proxies that increase a
connections attack surface any TLS
terminating forward proxy whether it's
well-intentioned or not risks leaving
private information and opens the door
the spoofing an example of this if I
really interesting is Sennheiser
headphones whose head setup software
installed a root certificate on
computers as part of a syncing protocol
between headphones a computer the
private key for this root start was
weakly protected using the passphrase
sign Heiser CC so guessing it was almost
as easy as 1-2-3 and literally rhymes
with it if an attacker learned this
passphrase
they could use the root certificates
private key to issue fraudulent
certificates for any web site so these
headphones is bad software dramatically
increase the attack surface of a
customer's computer a final type of HTTP
interception is through reverse proxies
unlike other forms of proxies reverse
proxies don't require a client to
install a new root certificate
since clients connect directly to the
reverse proxy reverse proxies are
usually deployed to improve the security
performance the reliability of their
customers and sites by providing
features like load balancing and modern
TLS however they're not also immune to
of ulnar abilities as examples over
recent years have shown cloud beat
against CloudFlare was one incident that
had the potential to expose private
customer data and other major CD ends
like Akamai and f5 have had their own
share
of incidents now that we have a good
sense of the different types of monsters
in the middle on the internet and the
risks that they pose Luke was going to
explain how we actually can detect when
HTTPS interception occurs so that will
hand us over great so now we'll describe
how a server can detect when an incoming
client connection may have been
intercepted using a technique described
by tumeric and others into 2017 paper so
in this example we have a chrome client
connecting through a middle box to the
server and the middle box is using open
SSL as their TLS library to intercept
the connection and read the plaintext
HTTP content the middle box acts as a
server and terminates the TLS connection
from the chrome client and then it
establishes a new TLS connection using
open SSL to re-encrypt the HTTP traffic
to the server the first thing to note is
the chrome CLS library leaves
differently than open SSL does so from
the server's perspective it looks like
an open SSL client is connecting to it
however the inner HTTP contains a user
agent header claiming that the traffic
is originating from a Chrome browser so
if the server sees a chrome user agent
paired with an open SSL TLS connection
the this is an indication that the
connection might have been intercepted
so let's dive into these mismatched user
agent headers and TLS parameters
in-depth so we can easily fingerprint
HTTP clients by reading and parsing the
user agent HTTP header so in this
example the user agent header indicates
that the connection is from Chrome
version 75 generated generated from Mac
OSX Mojave well this header can be
spoofed by bots or or other browsers
most popular browsers can be identified
with this header
[Music]
mmm-hmm identifying the tls client
behind a connection is a bit more
challenging since there's no fuel than
TOS that identifies the library however
there's been a great deal of work over
the past decade and doing TLS
fingerprinting based on the TLS client
hello message so ristic started looking
at finger at TLS fingerprinting a decade
ago and the state of the art has been
improving sense so in 2015 Lee brother
s'en collected and published hundreds of
key last fingerprints for various CLS
clients Blake Anderson and others at
Cisco have done some really great work
in automatically generating TLS
fingerprints from data observed on
Cisco's networks and as of 2019
they've started publishing a subset of
their observed fingerprints weekly the
ja3 project from Salesforce developed a
TLS fingerprint there was succinct
enough to fit inside a tweet and the TLS
fingerprint project collects and
publishes fingerprints from TLS clients
connecting to the UC Boulder campus
network and they provide an easy
interface for tracking clusters of
fingerprints so let's look at all at how
all these methods fingerprint TLS
clients so RFC 52:46 describes the
typical TLS 1.2 handshake so the client
starts the handshake by sending the
client hello message which advertises
the list of parameters that it supports
and is willing to negotiate for the
connection the server responds with the
server hello message indicating which
parameters it chooses along with its
certificate and key exchange value the
client responds with its key exchange
value and the finished message and then
both sides can send an encrypted
application data so we're interested in
TLS fingerprinting based on the client
hello message so let's see how that's
structured so this message contains
fields including the clients protocol
version the set of cipher Suites and
cryptographic algorithms that is willing
to negotiate as well as various
extensions so while some fields of the
client hello are random like the session
ID and the client random nonce many are
static and they're never changed for a
particular version of a TLS library so
we can use these fields to a fingerprint
implementation
so let's take a look at the fields of
two client hello messages one generated
by Chrome and the other by open SSL so
if we look at the list of ciphers which
sent sent by you to client we can see
the chrome sends 17 cipher Suites in
open SSL sends 48 the list of supported
groups that they send are almost the
same but chrome sends this extra value
the grease value at the start of the
list a grease value is also prevented
prepended to the start of the list of
cyprus tweets you notice so chrome sends
these grease ciphers which don't
actually represent valid algorithms to
ensure that servers and middle boxes
don't break when they come across values
as they don't recognize so if we see a
client hello message with these 17
cipher suites in this exact order along
with this set of groups and extensions
with the grease cipher suite prevented
to each list then we can reasonably
assume that it was generated by Chrome's
TLS library and not by open SSL so now
that we know how to LS fingerprinting
works we can get to the HTTP
interception detection process so the
first step is the constructed database
of known browser fingerprints these can
be constructed manually by operating
both a client and a server and then
logging the connection parameters
including the HTTP user agent and the
TLS fingerprint next for an incoming
request from a client we can check if
the user agent matches anything in our
database if not then we can't say
anything about whether or not the
connection is intercepted and we should
collect more fingerprints if we do have
a match then we can compare the TLS
fingerprint of the requests to the
expected fingerprint in our database if
they match then it's unlikely that we
have a monster in the middle here
however if the fingerprints don't match
then it's likely that either our
fingerprint database is incomplete or
outdated or the connection was indeed
intercepted so we have a likely monster
in the middle we can go a few steps
further and actually try to identify the
responsible middle box too so we're
finally ready to talk about the tools
that we've built a cloud player for
doing HTTP interception detection
so we built an open-source library
written and go for this purpose which we
call monster in the middle engine some
of the initial goals we had when
developing this project are first for it
to be maintainable so fingerprints in
the database quickly go stale as
browsers are updated and it's time
consuming to generate and vet new
fingerprints manually so we hope to be
able to automatically generate and
fingerprints that we trust from
connections observed from cloud floors
network much like cisco is doing now we
also wanted the fingerprint format that
we use to be flexible to model a variety
of browser behavior for instance some
implementations change the order of
cipher suites based on available
hardware on the device so we'd like to
capture that we also plan to support
alternative static TLS fingerprint
formats like jaw 3 and TLS fingerprint
that are already widely adopted in the
community and we also wanted the library
to be fast so performance was a priority
so we wanted to be able to deploy it at
scale so and we actually showed that we
can do this by deploying it on a 5%
sample of TLS client hellos on
CloudFlare so this probably makes you
wonder ok what is clouds are seeing when
it comes to https interception on the
public Internet
so aggregating data from this 5% traffic
sample we've also exposed a public
dashboard that gives insight into the
practice of HTTP interception as
observed by our network this dashboard
is called Malcolm which technically
stands for measuring active listeners
connection observers legitimate monitors
but really this is Loki a chance for us
to reference our favorite favorite
2000's family sitcom and Bryan Cranston
this dashboard allows for filtering over
a number of fields including browser
operating system and the type of HTTP
interception tool out of those that
we've been able to identify so let's see
some examples of this dashboard in
action
so here we show the overall HTTP
interception rates from the traffic
sample over a 30 day period so the
orange shows a percentage of traffic
that we do believe has been intercepted
based on our heuristic so this shows
that just about 17% of traffic has been
flattened the green shows traffic that
we do not believe to be intercepted and
the blue shows traffic that we're not
sure about because their fingerprint
database is incomplete or out-of-date so
you might be wondering about this large
spike that you see here so this is
actually from when I updated the
reference browser fingerprints that are
we're using in our production database
and then the gradual increase of the
blue bar as time progresses shows that
our fingerprint database is going out of
date so we have more and more unknown so
making these updates automatic is a big
to-do for this project so that we plan
to do soon our dashboard also allows for
filtering by fields like browser and
operating system so here in this video
we're gonna first filter by traffic that
we do believe to be intercepted and then
we'll see the breakdown of intercepted
connections with a chrome user agent we
see that out of all the chrome traffic
Android and Windows phones tend to be to
have the most intercepted traffic and
you can also clear the filters and
started into an investigation of HTTPS
and reception so we encourage you to
check out the dashboard and we plan to
add more features to the dashboard soon
like filtering by country so you can
examine Kazakhstan and in depth if you
want to so let's conclude with some
takeaways from the talk the first
takeaway is that TLS terminated up
terminating middleboxes pose serious
threats to network security even if
they're not inherently malicious the
best case for Enda and connections
security is to avoid HTTP interception
altogether
whether you're ality the reality is that
it's sometimes unavoidable in these
cases middleboxes
performing interception should be held
at the same security standards as
browsers the second takeaway from the
talk is that heuristics based on HTTP
and TLS fingerprints can be effective at
protecting HTTPS interception detecting
women exception occurs is the first step
to holding middleboxes accountable this
is especially important for clients who
may not even know that their connection
is being intercepted as in the case of
the citizens of Kazakhstan finally we
encourage feedback and feature requests
for our open source tool in public
dashboard so please check them out
PRS are welcome PR is welcomed and with
that we can take any questions and feel
free to ask us in person or to tweet at
us thank you
[Applause]
how our questions handle here do we just
pick them do we choose your audience oh
yeah and I guess we have a mic everyone
should go up to a mic and line up and
ask questions there hear me yeah
a question like let's say you have a
like a Firefox browser right and it has
got all the root certificates already
stored in the binary and it can be
modified so in that case when you have a
how do you how can you exploit this MIT
M if all the well-known certificates
already in the binary and you can't add
anymore you can't go and add above in
our root certificate or something like
that
so then as long as people get CS and
certificates so how can the attacker
still like to MIT M understood this if a
binary has a preset list of trusted root
certificates like that of certificate
authorities how could an interceptor
encourage a client to install a new root
certificate that can issue fraudulent
certificates was that the question is
that let's say you don't take any other
set of care so Firefox would only look
at its own certificates and then the
roots are decayed list we do not look at
any other place in that case somebody
cannot just claim to be example.com
right because it has to be signed by a
well-known CA
tastes like on browsers like operating
systems you can actually just change
whatever root certificates you trust and
you can actually add your own and
typically applications will follow that
trusted root certificate list that is
implemented as part of the operating
system so it's derived from that ok next
question over there so in this case I
think you are to talk to an interception
between browsers and servers so how
about server-to-server communication how
do you detect that that's a really good
question
so detecting server to server HTTP
interception yeah so you should be able
to do something similar if it's a TLS
connection then then one side has to
operate as a client and one as the
server beginning if you gather
fingerprints for the client in that case
and you should be able to do something
similar if it's yeah if they're using
yeah if it's HTTP yeah okay thanks okay
I'm gonna go in this order so is there
someone at the mic over there you're
good hi yeah is there a client ad in
front of the browser so the user can
detect that their connection that's been
man-in-the-middle so so this this could
be I mean one easy thing to do in the
browser would be to to just say okay
we're seeing a certificate signed by
something that isn't in our default list
of root certificates sort of display a
warning then so that would be that would
be one thing or the server after it does
this this detection could send something
back to the client
but right now yes so there there are
some ways to do this we also have a site
called man in the MIT MDOT watch that a
client can connect to and just and then
the server displays whether or not it
believes intercept or the connection has
been intercepted thank you yeah hi
where should we deploy the detection
tool
I mean I feel like we're we out at least
okay the question for small ism where
should we deploy the detection tool that
we built at least for us where we
deployed it was in our infrastructure
that collects like a basically a sample
of all of the requests inbound to our
network we use it for internal research
and like anonymize it of course but we
use that we actually use the library
there if it detects any patterns that
could correspond to inbound connections
to cloud players Network being monstered
in the middle so something that you
could use it for us if you'd like to see
what inbound traffic to your server
looks like and identify if it's ever
been intercepted that could be a useful
place for using this tool and I think
this tool is best used in a data
analysis context right and just just add
so caddy server which is an open-source
server implementation has a version of
this man in the middle detection built
into it so it's different from the
library that we built but it's an
earlier version based off the same
research paper so so if you're deploying
caddy server you can enable this this
feature as well so hopefully we'll we'll
develop this tool to the point where
it's just easy to incorporate into
normal server software Thanks
next question do we have anyone left
microphone over there okay so if this
microphone first off congratulations on
graduating loop high so the graphs that
you showed about percentage of
interception was the denominator
connections or devices and assuming that
it was connections do you think that
that's more or less or equivalent
li-like interesting two devices like do
we know if the behavior of the devices
that are being intercepted leads to
perhaps more TLS connection so it's
really like a small number of devices
that accounts for a large amount of
bandwidth or so so you're so you're
asking if if we think the the breakdown
of connections is is for like of all
they're all the requests that we get
yeah well where the graphs was their
breakdown of connections or a breakdown
of devices like what's your denominator
at that graph
oh it's breakdown over total connections
yeah over total connections is assuming
that do you think that the devices that
are being intercepted have basically
similar number of connections to non
interception devices or is this perhaps
inflating or deflating the relative
actual like amount of devices or people
being intercepted by looking at it at
connections instead of devices yes it
does
yeah correct me if I'm wrong yeah it
does it does look like certain devices
are intercepted more than others there's
a lot of variants here and you can you
can check it out on the dashboard we
haven't we haven't done a lot of digging
to see exactly which devices are the
Moose intercepted and stuff so that's
some future future stuff that we think
would be really interesting thank you we
have connections in all three
microphones so go on this cue again are
you asking so please come find his
absolute tweet of us talk to us to be
happy to answer them in person thank you
thank you
[Applause]