welcome to the last talk of the day in
Islander ofg you are about to see and
listen to moving from hacking IOT
gadgets to breaking into one of Europe's
highest hotel suites with Ray and
Michael Hubler if you have questions
afterwards they do have some time for
some Q&A there are three microphones
throughout the room so we are recording
this please step up to the microphone so
that everyone can hear your question and
it can be recorded thank you very much
hi okay so welcome to the ending of this
conference I hope you enjoyed blackhead
so far as much admitted and are ready
for the grand finale our presentation
about hacking IOT gadgets up to hotel
suites so who are we
I'm ray an active member of the German
heckler Association Chaos Computer Club
for like 20 years or so I've been
researching lock-picking I mean
technology enthusiasts and by work I
happen to sleep a lot in hotels so
that's what brought me into researching
this topic hello
I basically have been playing with locks
all my years all my life about 40 years
ago they were on mechanicals of course
and I got into lock-picking and
competitive lock-picking and lot sports
but then electronic lock started I
became an electronic engineer I
continued to do that a few years ago
Bluetooth Low Energy came in to all the
locks and that we looked into these and
that's what led to this presentation
okay so what we're going to talk about
we're going to talk about smart devices
so the devices using Bluetooth Low
Energy connected usually to a smart
phone and of course you will learn how
to analyze and probably hack cell
systems or if you're on the other side
of this business how to improve lease or
build better ones and of course we show
how we applied those methods to various
products and the vulnerabilities we
found in that from cheap padlocks to
hotel door systems out of curiosity
array of hands who of you has used the
mobile key system offered here in the
Mandalay Bay Hotel ok so I see you
wanted to free first this presentation
which is very good but to make sure to
clear the Mandalay if not see hotel we
successfully attacked so you might well
have good we're using it so the agenda
today is bluetooth LE eco system so
what's in such a system involved because
it's hot at reduction to bill itself
how to analyze such ble systems then
Asset tell you of the vulnerabilities we
found in our prior work and then what we
recently searched in billy hotel keys
and the one system that we broke and
also talked a little about the
responsibilities close the process we
had this avenger and the challenges
involved the such disclosure in a real
life systems as has real impact in the
real world so as a billy ecosystem what
you usually have our examples are mostly
locked so we have a smart lock or
so-called smart lock connecting using
billy to a smartphone app which is
connecting over the internet to a
back-end API servers so if you have such
an ecosystem there's a lot of attack
vectors one on this side of the
electronic log you can read out probably
firmware or other secrets from the chip
you have side channel attacks like power
attacks to get out keys you can insert
the wires into the device and get to
debug ports power a motor activated some
way in a way that wasn't intended and
also the mechanical attacks like
vibration or hammering to it or magnets
who manipulates interactors to defeat
the lock on a mechanical array on the
smartphone of course things like malware
stealing secrets
so probably don't use a mobile phone he
if you have malware on your phone and
there's also possibilities to relay
which is called distance short so you're
not at your device but somebody relays
the data and still uses your phone to
open your device then there's the
internet and as we all know this
back-end web services they have
vulnerabilities so this is not the main
focus on our talk but they have been
multiple found in this field or server
systems had flaws and the backend for
will be looking at first is the
connections involved so between the lock
and the smartphone and between the
smartphone and the Internet there are
connections where you can sniff the data
you can man in the middle and you can
impersonate one of the two sides if
there's no verification so altogether
there's quite a lot of attack vectors
you will learn about
today but to understand that first
introduction to Bill II so that the link
between the lock and the smartphone app
so bill is Bluetooth Low Energy it was
designed as a cheap low-power
alternative to classical Bluetooth so
that things that run on a battery can
used for a longer time it is part of the
BT for the DOE specification so it has
been out for quite a while already and
it's quite different from classical
Bluetooth so if you know that some
things may be different it's mainly used
for these so-called IOT devices those
are usually not in some cell phones
internet but using B and E connect to
something that is online so it's
communication between the device and
your smartphone and there's lots of
things like locks what we talked about
but also light bulbs even sex toys heart
rate sensors all of these things
connecting using B and E to a smartphone
so what's the security of groups of low
energies there has been a very good
presentation already in 2013 on the good
conference this low energy comes low
security and what the basically showed
is that it's very easy to listen to
build connections and we somehow have
sometimes the impression not everybody
implementing this stuff is aware of that
there are secure options to make secure
Billy communications like out-of-band
he pairing where you have to provide a
key on both devices in an other manner
or for point to elliptic curve
cryptography but those are very uncommon
ly used in those devices for various
reasons so what you'll usually find is
an unencrypted link layer and the
application layer has to make sure to
provide the security and if that doesn't
work you find the things that we are
going to talk about so how actually to
analyze this ely layer if you want to
analyze an app you're doing it usually
on your own device so is there you have
control over the data going in and out
so the easiest way is on an android
phone to enable the debug mode and
activate the so-called HCI snoop lock
that makes your phone record all the
data coming in and out on real e so you
can later analyze it the same as
possible on iOS so you install the F
Bluetooth debug certificate you can
download it from Apple and for a few
days you have like a debug functionality
giving you the ability to dump the data
your own communicated verbally it's a
little more complicated way so we would
recommend if you have an Android phone
you can use for try this first so if you
have done that just use the app as
normal what we have found out useful is
to make timestamp so note down at this
point in time I open the lock at this
point of time that and that happened so
later if we analyze your data you know
what what we what was which action then
download the lock from the phone and you
can analyze it with very common analyzer
tool like for example Wireshark it's a
pcap file so I'm not sure if everybody
here knows why a sharper to the network
and others tool and it gives you a ways
to look into such a dump
so you see here it's a search
communication is a destination in this
way local house always is your phone and
the other thing is here in this case and
Texas Instruments device so an IOT
device using nti chip it also will
decode the Bluetooth protocol
information for you so various shark is
aware of ble and knows which kind of
packets that are and will show you what
kind of package you're looking at you
usually will at the filter to find the
patterns you want to look at mostly it's
writing or reading from so called
handles and at the bottom of here you
see the value that is actually the date
have written and most of the things
you're looking for so you're trying to
look into the data so this is if you
want to analyze a protocol for attacking
a real system you have to sniff the bill
from the air so there's basically three
channels device advertisers on and you
have to listen to the right one to catch
a connection but those cheap sniffers
who can do that or listen to touch a
channel and get your connection the
classical tools for that are the other
food bluefruit le sniffer or the uber
tooth one there's lots of presentations
about these they can easily bought like
on every online shop you'll find in this
field and they support live feed in to
Wireshark so like you have Wireshark
running on Ethernet you then have by a
shark running on a bill a link so
disadvantage of those devices is they
sniff only one channel at a time so if
you device pops
sequence you don't know it works
approximately a short of the time so
it's okay for proof of concept but it's
not reliable for a real-life attack so
our favorite tool is the called little
Jack by Damien cock Willis has been
released at black addressing and it
supports a firmware for cheap devices
you can buy like the BBC micro bit death
port you can buy for $15 from Fry's or
whatever we only 400 the other food
sniffers so your flash firmware or
actually the tool will flash the
firmware for you and then you can use
three devices at a time and watch them
in parallel and it's much more than
sniffing the options are men the middle
and lots more so if you build such a
setup I did it by putting together a few
creative comments some duct tape so that
was my first working sniffing setup
Michaels and might a little nicer set up
with a Raspberry Pi so that's a compact
set up running on the battery pack
sniffing Billy on all three channels you
would probably even be able to fit
through a smoke detector or deposited
somewhere hidden to record data so
that's how to get the data from the
gling between the device and the phone
now we also have to look at the link
between the phone and the back end and
this is usually HTTP or HTTPS only very
few apps today use HTTP we actually
encountered one so it still happens
today but usually it's hdds so if you
want to man the middle of that you have
to install a fake root CA to intercept
the traffic but that's possible there's
tools doing it basically automatically
for you they created fake CA and this is
something not to break TLS for other
people but to analyze your own traffic
there's not an attack on TLS it's
something everybody knows you can do so
you analyze again the traffic of your
device so on iOS it's easy the middle
middle tool creates a certificate of CA
for you and you just declare that
attracted that was also possible in
Android up to version sixth on X the
sixth of X in newer Android versions you
need a rooted device because you have to
hard code it change the
in certificate store otherwise it won't
accept your certificates if you can't
use the route of such a device there is
an option to modify a specific app you
want to analyze by changing the manifest
in the apks or stocks on that online
that we have linked in the slides there
are lots of links in our slides so be
sure to download them after the
conference and check out the link that
will give you lots of information about
the topics we're covering here in a very
short time but this way you can change
the manifest and change the network
security convict so it trusts also the
user store so even if non-rooted device
if you modify the app which is not a
very complicated thing to do
you can get the CA to trust and to amend
the middle your data the only thing is
there are some apps who have
countermeasures and Micra will tell a
little about what you can do then
sometimes the application itself wants
to protect the user as well from a rogue
CA which is a good thing in this case
sometimes the apps even tell you what
they are doing
sometimes they just stop working but
what can you do then there's a few basic
ideas
the first one is rather trivial but
helps quite a lot of did help often
usually there's more than one app
there's an older version potentially for
Android or there is an iOS version
basically sometimes only one of the app
testers
that's this it slightly more involved
would be the second option you can
modify the application that's of course
you have to find out how to modify and
so on there are some tutorials on the
internet for that the third one is very
powerful tool what we called the tools
called Frida and there's a framework or
objection this is extremely powerful you
can do a lot of things with that you can
modify all the calls within the app it's
beyond the scope of this 50 minute
presentation to go through all of that
so we just look quickly through this you
would run and for example in the case of
a rooted android device you would run
server there if you get lucky you can
then just run this objective framework
and there's pee defying commands like
this Android as ascertaining disabled
this will try to disable some known as
its opening frameworks and again if
you're lucky then the app will work
afterwards if that doesn't work it's a
little bit more complicated but again
you'll find good tutorials you would
have to write a JavaScript file for
freedom that can basically change or a
lot of things within the app and in this
case it would just return the
certificate which you run this and then
the bottom you see a screenshot this
time of another two and this shows that
in this case T is opening TLS pinning is
disabled so our advice for vendors is
yes
TLS certificate pinning is a measure to
protect your users from rope CAS but it
doesn't protect your traffic from
analysis by hackers so do not rely on
that
okay the tools that we then can use to
analyze the traffic on UNIX command line
we use mitten proxy if you want to have
nice user interface you cannot use other
tools like the charts proxy there is
also the pursuit of fiddler available it
will take this on the command line you
get a lock of all the transactions you
can zoom in to one of them and in this
example and you get already one of the
piece we wanted to extract from the
traffic a nicely printed out chasing
file right so our advice to use this
would be do it right from the start
because sometimes you get a system that
updates itself immediately and you would
obviously miss this and would be
difficult to get back to the old stage
yeah and it is very useful to have
dedicated rooted device like all the
Android devices also expensive to do
this okay
then now that we talked about how to
collect the data on these two interfaces
let's have a look into real world
example how to analyze this data this is
a easy example it's like a nice puzzle
you can do like on an evening or weekend
it's a small really padlock one of the
really cheap ones we should note this is
research from last year
meanwhile the manufacturer has improved
the system but in 2018 it was like this
the first one is we wanted to analyze
the backend connection turns out we
don't need any rogue CA for this because
it just used HTTP traffic you can see
the password right there you can also
see a 16 byte array called lock key so
that was in this case you but maybe
could assume it's a s 128 and basically
when we decrypted the Bluetooth traffic
that's the link between the app and the
lock again it was random look really
random so we just took a chance and
decrypted it using AES 128 and it
doesn't work on diem anymore as you can
see there's a lots of zeros and
obviously this is properly decrypted the
next thing you will do is you look for
patterns compare several sessions you'll
see things that are the same in this
traffic and from a few sessions then you
can use the protocol you see there is
like session IDs and things like that
apparently there's a replay protection
implemented by a session ID but you then
can do what we actually did is verify
this look for weaknesses so one of the
approaches we do in this case is the
writer script using loop I also this
other food library and mimic the
application and then talk to the lock
and explore the protocol use parsing
techniques yeah so that's the usual
approach how to to look at this
this was the spot a call was not so
difficult as I said the nice puzzle for
an evening something like that what if
it's not that easy to understand
you just get encrypted traffic it's all
random you don't understand what it's
doing there then it makes sense to look
at the thing in the middle what
smartphone application yeah that's
obviously something that holds all the
information how the system works we just
wanted to note that some legislations
prohibit decompiling applications except
for specific reasons so please check
local legislation before you do that
okay there is two systems and use today
Android and iOS for Android it's not
that difficult to obtain readable source
code because the applications are
typically written in Java and that's
compared to bytecode you can recompile
it back to Java using tools that are
available online as well sometimes you
get compiled C++ code you need different
tools for that like for example at NSA
either up what we heard about today or
of course EDA for iOS it's typically a
little bit more difficult but also
possible you have to get the decrypted
application file first these days you
would need some jailbroken device for
that but then you get armed binaries and
there's also choose to decompile this
like again vida or copper and so on once
you did that it's typically a good idea
to look for what does the application
with Bluetooth like you have search for
a term like Android Bluetooth or AES or
crypt and the first example you see that
that's yeah you find the place where
it's actually talking to the lock the
second part is an example where we found
a key and an application and
yeah the key was one two three four five
six seven eight and so on so basically
if you see something like this you think
ok maybe let's look at this a little bit
or there could be other vulnerabilities
in there one more point regarding
looking at applications specifically
also Android code is really nice that
you can decompile it to Java but often
it's obfuscated that means area the
symbols are readable but you don't can't
make any sense of it it's really hard to
read so there's for example
yeah it's called be err something by
Terry for then again if you see like a
string that's not obfuscated access key
data is no and yeah just replace it
using refactoring tools like another
studio and you get there we have a very
strong opinion on application we we say
obfuscation makes analysis harder but
it's not impossible
so it slows down us we cannot help you
as a vendor then it does not stop
criminals that will attack you and your
customers so don't do it instead these
are new protocols in a way which is
secure even and they are known right
well yeah so now let's look at few
things that we found us using these
methods as promised we will show you a
few examples of vulnerabilities that we
actually can find in IOT devices using
the message you just have shown you and
you hopefully will apply in your
research in the future so first what we
looked at is a typical cheap padlock
which are around on Alibaba on various
sites blew a bill a padlock Bluetooth
padlock if you look for those those
might show up so they have a sim proof
mechanic so they are better than most of
the cheap locks to get at home deeper or
something but it's transmitted pass code
in clear text over-the-air and for this
lock to our knowledge disclaimer we
haven't bought it last week or something
this is still unfixed so we considered
O'Day but on the other hand the vendor
for sure knows he didn't put any equip
chain in there so that's nothing like we
could disclose to him he already knows
he just didn't care obviously but it's
but so if we have such a look you look
at the traffic we find this one Roderick
fest it's basically the one we showed
you earlier and if you look in that we
find an asserted to a bit 16-bit hex
string here which we convert to decimal
and it turned out that's exactly the key
he sat in the app on the lock so oh one
or two or three was a key I said on the
lock so when I sniff it on the air with
some vanilla says look I can just use
this he enter it to my app and without
any hacker tools open his lock using the
code I sniff on the air so this is
really just a poem system by design so
it's not the only locks at way already
two years ago at Def Con there was a
nice presentation by rose and Ramsay
they tested a broad range of Bluetooth
locks for this simple vulnerabilities so
12 of 16 locks imagine that they tested
had simple vulnerabilities like replay
like getting the key like fasten them
and getting them open and stuff like
that two of the padlocks they tested
remained unbroken as they said all there
might be a little better so accidentally
or independently from those locks at one
of these locks the master lock bluetooth
padlock is like in 60 to 80 dollar lock
we figured you could attack mechanically
so this lock now locks you basically
it's locked and instead of using the app
we now use a high tech hacker tool
called a magnet and we attach it from
the back and by this movement from
moving it over the side and turning the
polarity from time to time he actually
turned the motor inside the lock so what
usually you would have been activated by
the electronics now are stand by the
magnet and the lock opens
[Laughter]
so actually we disclose that to
masterlock right on DEFCON because in
the Q&A I mentioned it and someone
approached me hey I'm with master lock
and showed it to him basically on the
conference so there hopefully did
something about it but we never had
contact I'm not sure if they if they
changed it or not they have a bigger
Locker it's not said easy but probably
they did something I don't know so the
other locks that remained unbroken by
the erosion tremors research foreseen no
keypad lock and that's actually one of
the first peony padlocks ever created it
was a Kickstarter campaign in 2014 which
raised much more money than they
expected so a typical thing going
through the roof so they had quite some
money to to develop and the note here
the research I am now showing you is for
the original firmware which was in place
2015 to 2017 and our responsible
disclosure process in 2016 after quite a
while I must say led to a firmware
update in 2017 fixing this to a new
protocol which we haven't looked deeper
into but the note security wasn't as bad
as a lock we shot before it must be a
reason that Ross and Ramsey didn't find
it it uses actual AES 128 bit encryption
using the reference implementation so
that something would say okay it also
uses different secrets for the owner of
the lock and friends new share as a lock
- so it's not like your friends could
use a key to change your lock or
something what we find out very early by
analyzing the backend traffic is the
time restrictions were enforced in the
app which of course is not the best
thing to do you could just many put it's
a back-end traffic and circumvent the
time restrictions basically if you share
this lock you could open it any time but
the main vulnerability so that's a real
thing you had to disclose
what's the secret transmission of C of C
code to the lock it was transmitted
using individual AES session key 4 for
each session and new key was generated
so that's also good but the session key
generation was done in a secret
handshake so something like Oh nobody
knows how we do it so it's secure using
the hard-coded AES key that we saw
before
one two three four five six but that's
not the problem every hard coded key
would be as bad as it is
so it basically was security by
obscurity as long as it didn't know the
protocol how they exchanged a session
key it's okay but if some evil hacker
comes and uses a disassembler he can
find this part of code which actually
does the calculation of the session key
so we looked a little bit into it
finally this was actually in the binary
as alpha so we really had to disassemble
we couldn't use the java decompiler
shown earlier but once you understand it
you saw it's a very simple principle the
app sends none so number used ones of
32-bit to the lock the locks sends the
second number back to the app so now
both parties Nobel Mouse numbers say X
or these numbers together so they get
this first value here in the red corner
it's a certain bit to value which is
added to the pre shared key so we
changed shirted to bit in an 128-bit key
I'm not sure what that's supposed to do
in security and then we get a new key by
adding it up to the center of it and
this new session key which you could
derive from Catholic you just sniff was
used for all further communication so
let's thought about cryptography but did
it wrong so if it is closest like the
end of two thousand dollars in the
beginning 2016 at the end vida de for
disclosure and in 2007 17 they finally
fixed it but so this shows also
something important even if a vendor
claims to use AES that doesn't mean it's
secure it's probably better than viewing
home build protocols but still look for
vulnerabilities look for key exchanges
there might be things like that so
that's the previous things what we are
going want them to hear is ble hotel
keys so what we're looking here at is
the ble layer and T back-end so but
let's first ask why BL e for hotels so
this is really a clever idea to have a
very less outer key the main purpose of
course the self check-in you don't need
a key card anymore
your mobile phone is a key for the hotel
that means they can probably do staff or
UC staff at more valuable locations and
everybody of you who stood in line at
the Mandalay at a high traffic volume
will appreciate the ability to check in
yourself with your phone and skip that
line right so it could looks kind of
attractive
but the challenge is such a system poses
is that sexual pairing unlike in the
device you own where you could like pair
from accuAir code you get as a package
or something is hard to do here you walk
to the door and you want to communicate
pairing know then they have usually
deployed see hardware in the hotels for
quite a while so they have a retrofit
probably old hardware with new modules
and not have the most recent
cryptographic chips in there and then
it's a complex ecosystem of a hotel
chain somebody building their app
somebody building their lot probably a
short party integrating the SDK from the
lock vendor to the hotel app so it's
many people do have to work together but
if it all works how does it work out I
have a booking somewhere and I have the
app and an account in the app and
somehow I have to get the booking into
the death so that actually might be the
first weak spot here because in the
system we had a look at you could add
the booking by things like your booking
number your beginning end and stay and
your name so that's not something
everybody knows but this is data
somebody could get by social engineering
and if he manages to do that he can get
your key on his app so that's the first
point where there might be a weakness
that you could think about but things
like this I've found lots of in hotel
systems if you have good social
engineering skills you'd probably get
into hotel room anyway then you do an
outer hatch online check-in in your app
and the mobile key is transferred to
your app so what you do now is here we
showing example actually if you're
wondering vibrate in the black hat hotel
this was man in the middle replaced by
our proxy we started to funny to replace
the company logo by man the middle
replacement and then you can use these
the app to approach the lock say
unlock you see it's communicating now
the lock is blinking yellow green and
your hotel door is open so that's a
normal use case so this is how something
like that would work we looked at two
different systems the first one we're
looking at is not the one we bro we call
it the hotel age so because we don't
have to name here hotels we didn't break
and it worked after figuring out in that
way the back end to the app sends a key
so there's a little bit complicated here
a key K as well as an encrypted
version of this key which we call K star
only an K star is encrypted version of K
by the key KS only he back-end which is
under control of cylinder and the lock
which is under control of cylinder noses
he KS so your app doesn't know it the
app sends now the encrypted key to the
llama
so the lock knowing the key KS can
derive the unencrypted key k and now the
lock and your F can communicate using K
but you haven't you as a user don't have
to know KS so now the bill it traffic is
encrypted with an AES key that the
passive eavesdropper doesn't know so
there's actually a good twist a good
thing so we didn't find an obvious
attack vector on that except if you
manage to obtain KS so you could
probably do it by taking a Part C lock
and finding vulnerability in the chip
user but steps of pass we don't got into
because we don't take apart other people
lock for research at least that not if
we're not allowed to do so we do it of
course with locks we own but in this
case we didn't research his father and
also with when we tried to do more dumps
and everything like that the system was
down so first arsenal ok this hotel
probably in the early stage we don't
research it anymore
so we came to a second system as a
manufacturer we call em like
manufacturer and that we found in a
system in early 2019 and acquired upper
class hotel I happened to to live in and
the lower key is used to basically
everywhere instead of the normal human
you can use it like in the elevator in
your rooms in the fitness center so we
got the mobile key and analyze the TNS
and being in traffic as we have shown
before in various cases so here's a dump
from the mitten proxy tool and you can
see there's something called a mobile
key insulation data and it starts this
DT and Zander some bytes this is only
the beginnings of like 40 bytes of this
following and when we compared the key
we received from the back end in this DT
field but the key we saw on the area
immediately noticed oh it's the same key
so would it be that simple that it just
sends the key over-the-air so you could
replay so we looked at the full
recording and realized no there's much
more going on so in the middle of
actually the full key we got from the
back end so that of course was an
indicator this will be fishy there is
something not so good if the only secret
the app has is going over the air there
must be a way to break it but looking at
the rest we saw there's lots of data we
don't understand so we had to look into
that further my career tell about you
how we did it yeah exactly so um there
seem to be some we play protection in
the protocol as well as you can see here
there's that seem to be some kind of
checksum there was also the MAC address
of the lock transmitted and some values
have changed all the time
at that time we assume there will be
announced and the CRC or some type of
checksum or an edge mac maybe but yeah
we tried COCs if you want to do this
there's some tools available on the
Internet
for example this CSE reverse engineering
tool we just used a custom Python script
and then we assumed that 16 bits may be
the nulls and 16 bits maybe ECOC
have a script that matches that searches
for match and at least two of the
messages we got yes and basically it was
exactly like this
we found the Panola polynomial we also
saw that seat value the seat value
that's the initial value when you
calculate a CSE that was something that
was transmitted over the TLS session and
that's something that's constant within
the hotel's called SCE think it's
something like system code for the next
CSEE on the other hand they use the
previous value as a seat so we were able
to transmit the first packets but then
there's the packet that contains the key
and that was a little bit more difficult
we did not initially find the two bytes
that are the correct two values for
these two bytes to transmit this key
correctly basically we had one block
where the CSE was obviously not at the
end some constant bytes some some zero
bytes and three previous year C values
and yeah that was a little bit of a
puzzle but basically it's not that
difficult they use the previous values
and calculated again at the same
algorithm as you see and over wrote this
with zeros so yeah now we knew how to
create this credential packet we could
verify that with a lot of choices we had
taken before again we created a Python
script to send this I put just take the
device name it would take these
credential bytes that we could sniff out
of the air and I calculate the CC and
using Boop I go talk to the lock we
tried this this shows how we actually
got the key out of the air so I was
nothing set up you see the three surfing
boards and in this case I simulated
customer purse on the inside of the door
because that's a little bit suspicious
if you set this up in the hotel floor
and outside in the hall but anyway yeah
you can see we we got the bites our skip
would take these bytes then we tried it
we like yes so we had put sea bytes we
sniffed on the air into our tool and
then we thought okay let's step out of
the room
take our laptop and try to run our
script against the real thing this is
actually real our Python script running
on the laptop and the actual hotel door
person mates not getting too suspicious
because we are in very quickly as you
can see and it turned out oh we actually
reached quite a nice acceptable 37th
floor 500 dollar hotel suite with our
CSC
to attack so this system basically must
pound by reversing CICS and this again
is showing that security by obscurity is
not the way to go for these kinds of
things so once we have this running we
sort out let's analyze a little bit more
go deeper into it and we did again what
we did earlier write a Python script as
a test target so instead we're having a
script now to open the lock we also
build a script to emulate the lock so
with this script we could play with some
real app and our simulation now at home
and analyze this version so we wanted to
know how big is this problem so it's a
such this one hotel that we found out is
it more so with some digging around he
found us a few more hotel change which
were starting to deploy this product
because we always has to see this is
very new we're very lucky that we got
set this early because it wasn't
deployed like in a thousand hotels so
far sorry for that if you expected that
but it's very emerging technology one
thing was very funny or interesting for
us is that you could actually see it by
the names of the locks the locks
announced the 60 base 64 names that you
could decode to binary and then found a
certain pattern so we could actually
from the outside check if a hotel uses
the vulnerable system or not so imagine
us for going around with Bluetooth
sniffers and checking hotels for for the
system and we found actually a few human
rooms and then we booked one of the
rooms in one of the hotels we identified
as also vulnerable and found an even
simpler variation of the protocol which
did the first handshake and not this
last CSC variation so there's variations
of that and at that time we also
realized the manufacturer which actually
is a company messerschmitt in Germany
and say so there are no wrong
expectations that they have like 2000
hotels that apply locks to but they're
also going for quite upper-class hotels
and those upper-class hotels are not so
much interested in Bluetooth locks they
want the customers to comes on the desks
so it's in the lower level change or mid
class change because they don't really
provide lower level so in those mid
class change the beginning to roll it
out so
it's not so many hotels currently and
luckily we informed them but we thought
about okay is this real real problem can
you really do this in in real life so we
tried about how would that look in real
life doing an exploitation of course one
thing you don't have to do is to sniffs
the key using the bill ejects at work
try to find an hour in room setup it's
the only thing you have to know in
advance is the Bluetooth address of the
lock you want to sniff so you have to go
to the lock before identify this lock
I'm going to sniff so probably if you
follow someone to his room that wouldn't
be so good you would have to know all
the MAC addresses of all rooms so we
start about other places where you could
sniffing if you thought about the
fitness center if people go to the gym
and then we start oh there might be
options to hide a hider sniffing device
somewhere you see a lot of options there
we went for something quite near to the
door there's a plastic trash can liner
and you couldn't put a sniffer set up
right to the bottom of it so we thought
okay let's put it there go to the other
wise other side of the store and try
this out and we figured the fitness
center does not support ble we later
found out in communication we see hotel
which was very good by the way thank you
for the general manager who we've
replied good to our research it was
vandalized for some reason it was out of
service right when we wanted to try it
oh my god so we were where else could we
do it oh that's the elevator everybody
who lives in a hotel like you all
currently do knows if you go to an
elevator you have to activate the
elevator so people will do this visitor
app of course and unlike a rumor fitness
center if there's someone standing next
to you in the elevator having a backpack
you wouldn't think he's currently
stealing your key so that's very like in
a possible attack and one thing we even
found out we realized this if we use our
simulator which imposes as a lock in the
elevator and just by heavenly Bluetooth
advertising the app of a user would
probably connect to our a paisa script
instead of the real lock so this attack
actually could be carried out without
any special hardware at all you just
need a standard Linux laptop or other
laptop with Bluetooth capabilities runs
a person script on it so here we run our
person simulator script tell him
imposed this lock and it really happy me
record as it seems the bottom the key
for us so this key again then can be
used to break into the room so that was
the point we said okay this is a real
thing we have to do a responsible
disclosure process because it could
actually harm people if it's getting in
a wider use so like in early April or
mid of April we contacted the vendor and
we have to say very luckily he directly
responded we know people who had other
communication with disclosure he had
really immediate response we put some
research into finding the right person
who to contact but he said yeah I'm the
right person please tell me more
we sent technical details to them they
thought about it said our technician
says that can't really works that way
but he somehow understand what we're
doing so we said ok believe me we did
within the real hotel it's not
theoretical and we sent our proof of
concept code so then he said ok obvious
a real Singh and started very well with
us beginning to discuss how do we work
on that and we really thankful he never
tried to prevent this closure and even
so this vulnerability currently is
unfixed so this is real all day here we
think it's not so dangerous because the
real user base as we have shown in a
show of hands is not so big so the real
danger is not here yet because they got
it very early so we can still discloses
here and the fixing is on the way I
think in the running of this month
probably hotels we have been in will be
fixed because the vendor very well
reacting to our disclosure but it's not
that easy the locks in the first hotel
we have been in there can be updated
online because of the very modern
high-rise hotels where a 6000 rooms or
something so they are online and can be
updated remotely it's a smaller hotel it
was like here's the hotel locks are
individually in the door they are not
connected so someone has to go from door
to door to door to upgrade them and that
only can start after the fix is
developed so this will take a little bit
more time and of course as we said
earlier there's multiple app vendors who
have to integrate this SDK it's not such
a vendor who's building the apps as
multiple parties involved so one lesson
we learned from the responsible
disclosure
and that is really important is that you
have not to only identify the vendor but
only see who is else involved in the
thing we found out there's multiple
parties building the apps there is
multiple hotel chains those hotel chains
around the hotel groups and our
responsibilities closure to the vendor
didn't immediately react in all of them
identifying those other parties actually
there we found out just last week that
there's another vendor who built
basically on the original design of the
sing another lock so they got a quite
short notice now but as we said it's an
early early stage of development so
that's really the lesson learned through
this communication do the research and
so our I would takeaways for this event
here is you should really know the Billy
link layer can be smooth reliable with
cheap tools so I'm not sure if the
people who design such protocol knew but
many probably did not really consider
this Bruce is really a saying to
consider it can be Smith don't rely on
the link layer do application crypto the
other thing is don't hide any secrets in
your app neither the algorithm nor keys
or anything like that if it's in the app
people can get it out you earlier seen
our reverse engineering possibilities
so whatever clicked try to build it in a
way you could publish everything just
the secrets key which I only notice the
user should secure it and to sing for
the research community or whatever also
as a security into this year being e is
not just padlocks or Chinese toys it's
more and more used in real world
applications and all of you and
hopefully you now can with following our
presentation should audit these things
that look into this more and I can just
say it again the slides will be online
there's lots of links in it so if you
couldn't follow everything now in this
very short runs through lots of various
concept look up the flights look up the
methods it's really not so hard to get
into we have multiple ways to attack sis
multiple layers you can go there
so it's really worth doing it and we
hope you enjoyed it and are going to
have fun with blue and P elements and
that our presentation so he actually
have like three minutes for questions so
please the people leaving now be quiet
so people wanting to ask questions can
go to the mics they have three minutes
for questions please feel free to cancel
or contractors yeah you have an email
letter C so if you're involved with any
vendor or anything if you worried so
just email to us this address probably
the next date or a Def Con so don't
expect an immediate answer but first the
direct option would be to go to the mics
and ask some questions it's hard to see
but just open slots so think we
overloaded you all at end of blackhead
here but it's the last slot so probably
that's acceptable or you couldn't also
just free close this here come to the
stage and we walk over to the developer
room where we can do some private
conversations okay thank you everyone
but some more questions