good morning everyone welcome to rogue
seven rogue engineering station attacks
on s7 somatic PLC's we're in breakers
GHI we're here to listen to Ariel Malin
and Sarah Bataan couple announcements
before we begin stop by the business
hall located in Mandalay Bay ocean sides
and shoreline ballrooms on level 2
please also join the blackhat Arsenal in
the business hall on level 2 last but
not least of course turn off your phones
and he asked me to announce that they
will be having a white paper up on the
blackhat website at some point in the
near future with that turn it over to
them
good morning goal the title of our talk
is rug 7 rogue engineering station
attacks and somatic s7 PLC's this is
joint work with Professor Ellie behan
aviod Carmel and a long dunk nerf from
the Technion a professor of vishay wolf
from the tel aviv university Oriel and
me will be presenting my name is Sarah
I'm a senior researcher at the Technion
who she Fujian cybersecurity research
center and I'm the founder and CEO of
Cyclops secure system design an audit my
name is Wilma lean and I am a master
student at tel aviv university advisor i
professor of a cheval I am also a
security researcher at mitigate health
care IOT security so we are going to
present to you in this talk several
design vulnerabilities we've exposed in
the Siemens proprietary s7 protocol and
we are going to describe and Dennis
demonstrate an exploit the performs
remote cells programming on an s7 15 PLC
those of you are familiar with game of
strong will in particularly enjoy this
talk others don't worry I'm going to
introduce you to the three characters
that going to appear in this session
gray warm the man of action the man in
the field is going to represent the ICS
operator look he even wears a Hamlet so
it's safe for him to walk on the
production floor Tyrion Lannister the
main of brain design and vision will
represent the ICS engineer an Arya Stark
the assassin the faceless girl will
represent the impersonator the attacker
so critical infrastructure system we
become more and more dependent of them
in our daily life most of this
things such as electrical grids water
facilities and transportation system are
controlled by industrial control systems
these are distributed computerized
system that many times span across dozen
of even hundreds of mile they operate
and monitor physical devices the PLC is
the core of the ICS it is a robust and
reliable device designed to work under
extreme environment conditions since
many times it is installed outdoors the
PLC is connected to physical devices
such as sensory fog
wind turbines and generators and it runs
the control program bit samples sensors
and triggers active device according to
the results the PLC constitutes a bridge
between the virtual and the physical
words this makes it in particular
interesting for attackers and it is
indeed the target of our attacks I've
described the PLC physical interfaces
it also has multiple virtual interfaces
the control program running it in it can
expose its variable to an age of my
software that the operator can use to
monitor and modify value of control
variables in the PLC the engineer
returned lanister can use the
engineering workstation to write its
control program and he downloads the
control program to the PLC through an
interface with a software layer that we
call the PLC operating system the
interfaces with the HMI in the
engineering workstation are most of the
time vendors proprietary however the PSC
also has standard interfaces where
server and SNMP server in the Siemens
word the PLC that we're discussing is
the s7 1,500 simisage in my software is
called wincc the engineering workstation
software is called step 7 and the
proprietary protocol that Siemens used
for communication between the age of my
engineering workstation and PLC is
called the s7 protocol both packages are
packaged into a software that's called
here and this is the package that we're
trying to impersonate the focus of this
talk is on the offset 7 protocol this is
the protocol that we are trying to
exploit most of the ICS product most of
ICS systems are separated to physical
several physical production floor the
typical structure of a production fir is
a layered structure you see in that
lower layer their active devices the
middle layer consists of this PLC's the
control layer and the upper lake on
triste most of the time of local aging
mind several production floors are
connected to a main manufacturing zone
where the control the Queen and the
command center is located
they're also located their server
central application a servers and an
historian in their main manufacturing
zone we also see the engineering
workstation in a minute it will become
clear why we've emphasized it but not
for now that it is somewhat isolated
from the rest of the servers in the main
manufacturing zone the main
manufacturing zone is usually connected
to the corporate network that many times
has an ARP server in it and this network
many time connected to other external
network sometimes even to the internet
this connection to the rest of the world
is the source of troubles and the source
of attacks
the most famous attack on ICS is Stuxnet
anybody heard about it no so it was
discovered on September 2012 and it
targeted the previous version of the
Siemens PLC the s7 300 it infected a dll
that was common both today HMI and the
injury engineering workstation packages
what stuck said that this DLL is the one
responsible to communication with the PC
what Stuxnet did it replaced the dealer
with its own malicious version /
practically taken control over the full
communication with the PLC which enable
it to inject control program and do
whatever in it once the protocol the
protocol that was used by this please
see is a previous version of the s
seventh protocol now the engineering
workstation on the one hand if one takes
control over it then it is in complete
control of all the peers is in the ICS
on the other hand it's a highly
sophisticated software package with many
features running on general purpose
operating system this makes it
error-prone and vulnerable and typical
ICS effects exploit vulnerabilities in
the engineering workstation such as the
first vulnerability that enabled Stuxnet
to replace the DLL with its own
malicious DLL or a vulnerability that
was discovered less than a months ago
that enables an unauthenticated user to
take control over the Tia through its
web servers by now users realized that
the engineering workstation is the
soft-bellied of the ICS has in most
production deployment users disconnected
from the product
network keep it somewhere safe and take
it out only when needed for
troubleshooting or maintenance our tech
unlike typical ICS attack exploit
vulnerabilities directly in the plc
specifically in the plc operating system
in its implementation of the s7 protocol
the implication is that we can use any
vulnerable machine or device on the
network as an attack machine anyone
cares to speculate how many ICS
deployments contain vulnerable outdated
operating system all of them right
anyone said Windows XP in most of the
ISIS deployment I have been to this you
know when you asked yes there's some
windows it's been some deserted darkroom
the transom application that is not
supported on any other operating system
connected to the deployment network and
we can use it as an attack machine so
the victim of our attack is the L is the
s7 1500 PLC it is one of two new members
in the cymatics PLC product line s7 1500
is the high-end PLC the other member is
the s7 1200 since toxnet was discovered
Simmons makes significant investment in
security enhancement of the somatic
Pearce's they came up with a new version
of the s7 protocol which applies
cryptographic integrity protection to
the messages this is the protocol that
we discuss they provided know-how in
copy protection to the control program
and they also added the PLC access
control mechanism this is based on
password this mechanism can be used to
meet
it's the download' attacks that we are
going to demonstrate however it is not
used by most customer and we consider it
infeasible it might be feasible for
small ICS deployment that has dozen two
dozen species but it's impractical to
protect a deployment with hundreds of
thousands of pieces with passwords the
s7 protocol it was originally running in
the OSI communication model has since
runs on tcp/ip port 182 which is is a
transport over TCP it is a session
oriented protocol the session begins
with a four-way handshake
during which the parties agree on the
integrity protection key that they are
going to use the version of the protocol
that they are going to use we've
detected several worship version all our
discussion is focused on a version that
we call p3 in the second message the PLC
sends a session ID to the client which
is most of the time the engineering
workstation the client must return it in
all subsequent messages hence the
session ID server the cookie the
protocol and ables the client to create
modify and delete objects in the plc
internal memory here for example we see
creation of an object that is called
server session in the plc internal
memory it will be used to hold all the
attributes of the session including the
cookie the integrity protection key and
so forth the key of the vulnerabilities
that we are going to describe is the in
the s7 p3 handshake protocol this
protocol is
based on public key cryptography the PSC
has a private key the client must have
the respective public key the session is
initialized by the client that sends an
alone message we've shot with some
random ad the PSC generates a challenge
random challenge and it sends it to the
client together with a session ID that I
already say serves as a cookie and the
model and the ephemeral version of the
plc these will be used to determine
which protocol version to run the client
then generates random key derivation key
and sends it together with additional
keys encrypted with the PSC public key
orielle and the second part of the top
will dive into the details of the
handshake protocol for now in the third
message the client sends the session ID
the king material encrypted with the PSC
public key and a response that should
match to the challenge that the POC sent
the POC verifies the response if every
scene confirms it sends an
acknowledgement and both sides derive a
symmetric session key which is a
function of the challenge that appeals C
generated and the key derivation key
that's the client generated now in order
to analyze the properties of the protis
protocol I'm going to compare it to this
to the protocol you all know which is
the SSL protocol so in both protocol
there's only one way authentication the
PLC is authenticated and the client is
not authenticated here the plc server is
a server in both protocol the client
generates some random keying material
and sends it to the server encrypted
with the server's public key however
there's a huge difference between the
SSL protocol and the s7 p3 handshake and
the difference is that in SSL each
server has its unique private public
keeper whereas in the s7 p3 handshake
opions is from the same model and the
same framework version share a single
private public key per the implication
is if we know which public key to use
and if we understand the details of the
protocol then what we have is one ring
to rule all the s7 1,500 pieces in the
word but unlike Gollum's precious ring
that was unique in the word this ring
can have multiple forged copies and all
of them work perfectly well and this is
the key to our text so now we are ready
to describe our attacks on the p3
problem download exchange first let me
describe to you how does the object that
represents the control program look like
so it's name which is not that important
is the program cycle object block and it
has three attributes that I want to
point to you the first attribute is the
object code this is the code actually
running in the PLC the second attribute
is the source code that represents the
source matching the object code and the
third attribute is an object Mak taking
over other attributes of the control
program now the whole message that
creates the control problem object is
protected using age Moksha 256 with the
integrity protection key that was
established by the handshake
in our examples we are going to use two
simple programs the yellow program is an
innocent program written by tear on the
engineer which does what is supposed to
do in the ICS the blue program is a
malicious program written by area the
attacker
note that they structure them is
identical we have the object code the
source code and the object marker now
our goal is to run the malicious program
the blue malicious program in the plc
while concealing it from the operator
clearly there is difference between
these two program KDAY the yellow
problem sets LEDs number zero and one
well the blue program sets LEDs number
two and two and three in real life time
attacks of course the difference will
not be that apparent for example you
could have the blue program increase the
rotation speed of centrifugal
while manipulated HMI variables clearly
it will not be as noticeable as here
before going into death Tech flows let's
look at legal flow of a program download
so Tyrian sits at the engineering
workstation and programs the yellow
innocent program it then hits the
download button and the four way
handshakes takes place in Tegrity
session key is established and shared
between the engineering workstation and
the plc at this time the control program
creation message is constructed it is
integrity protected as indicated by the
yellow by the little
Red Seal and it is sent to the PLC when
the PSC receives and verifies the runs
it runs the program the LEDs are set and
if and the problem is running Simmons
also provide the engineers with a
program out on a upload feature we
already say that the TIA is disconnected
from the network so if you have to do
maintenance or troubleshooting you can't
with Atia that you took out from the
cupboard kinetic to the deployment
network and then press the upload button
to retrieve the program running in the
PLC Turan presses upload again handshake
takes place integrity session key and
the source object is retrieved from the
PSC internal memory it is integrity
protected and sent over of course this
is the right source program and it is
sent to the engineering workstation now
let's start with the description of the
attack finally so we already said that
there's no engineering workstation in
the in the production network so let's
bring it with us
so the attack system that we constructed
we call it rocked here in consists of a
legitimate TIA
version 15 and an attack proxy that that
consists of two phases a setup phase and
an attack phase let's describe first v
the setup phase so are you can run the
setup phase anywhere in the world
provided that she has an s7 1500 PLC so
here she does it in my lab in the
Technion in Haifa she programmed the
blue malicious program and in this set
of phase their malicious proxy is in tap
mode it only it only lists
she presses the download button
handshake takes place integrity session
key is created the control messages
integral is integrity protected and
delivered to the PLC the only thing the
malicious property does is it records
the whole flow of the messages into a
pickup file and save it for future use
now of course if you attempt to upload
then you will have the blue program in
memory which is what is supposed to do
now the attack phase the attack phase
happens in the victim premises
here you see Aria located in King's
Landing this time she brings in the
needs workstation and programs the
yellow innocent program she presses
download again handshake take place in
integrity session key establish but
since we have the Tia under our control
this is a rogue Tia so what we do we
share the integrity protection key with
the malicious proxy the many ways to do
is we chose to do it by extracting their
integrity session key from the tears
memory and sending it over to mail it to
the malicious proxy now the control
program messages created is it is
integrity protected with the session key
and the malicious proxy intercepted our
first attempt was to replace the yellow
object toad with the blue malicious code
when we try to send it to the PLC it
detected something in wrong and
entreated rejected it
we highly appreciated it since it means
that Simmons are making some precaution
measures our second attempt we
substitute also the mac object to the
blue mask mac object
we applied integrity protection since we
have the integrity protections key and
we sent it to the PLC what do you think
happened well you should know by now
otherwise I wouldn't we wouldn't be
standing here talking to you from this
stage so we send it to the PLC he
accepted it
which problem was running the malicious
bill problem that set let's number two
and three so Simmons did very well when
they added MOC protection to the
attributes of the control program
however for some reason which I cannot
understand they choose to apply it only
to the object code and not to the source
code so we have the situation with the
blue malicious problem is running in the
PLC and when you hate upload you get the
yellow innocent program since this is
the source code and clearly they are
different are we done yet almost Tia is
the use of a package it weighs over five
gigabytes so it's impractical to use it
as an attack payload and carry it to a
production ICS this is the reason we
came up with our rogue engineering
station attack so the raw engineering
station is simply a Python scripts that
impersonate a TIA
it gets as an input repeat the victim
PLC IP address and Topeka files yellow
and blue that were prepared during the
setup phase what is does aria is again
at the victim premises she chooses the
innocent and a malicious program she
wants to to inject then she creates this
hybrid program with the malicious object
in the yellow source and Shira and
presses download at this stage the
handshake take place and integrity
session case
directed now unlike the previous attack
where we were men in the middle sort of
here we have to fix all the cookies that
the PLC sends to the client so we fix
the session ID we fix all the other
cookies that are planned there we create
integrity protection sent to the plc
malicious program running innocent
problem uploading again we did first
injection of a control program so to
wrap up this part if arya can control
the plc in my lab in the Technion she
can also control the plc in the gate of
the wall to open it even though she's
not John Snow and she can also control
the PLC in Qinglin dean's gate although
she's not Cersei Lannister
now I'll live I'll give you a wheel for
the fun and juicy stuff of the reverse
engineering Thank You Sara
so I am a real moline and I will show
the p3 handshake details then I will
give some tips for a better reverse
engineering process and then we will
show a very cool demonstration of our
attacks the technical part won't be so
long so brace yourselves
ok so recall that the session key is
derived by the challenge and by the KDK
so the challenge is sent from the PLC
from the PLC to the client and the KDK
is sent through this encrypted keying
material thing to the PLC but what is
this encrypted key material so first of
all let's list the cryptographic
primitive which in use so there is
public private key based a symmetric
encryption which is done with elliptic
curve L gamma there is also symmetric
key encryption which is done with AES in
two mode ECB mode and counter mode there
is a key derivation function
KDF
and there is also a non cryptographic
checksum tabulation hash so how did Thea
share the KDK generate 20 bytes free key
encrypt it using elliptic curve el-gamal
encryption with the plc public key and
edit to the king material calculate KDF
on pre key and gets three buffers the
checksum encryption key the checksum
seed and the key encryption key then
concatenate the KDK to the challenge
that was received from the POC encrypt
them using AES encounter mode with the
key encryption key and add to the King
material initiate the tabulation hash
with checksum seed and calculate
checksum over the AES output encrypt it
using AES ECB mode with the checks and
encryption key and add to the King
material now the Tia can send the king
material to the PLC when the bills he
receives the king material the PLC and
only the PLC can use its private key to
decrypt tricky and extract the KDK so
now the plc is able to derive the
session key to the public keys are
stored in compressed key files at a TI
installation folder each key file
contains some metadata like version key
type key + key family and also key data
which is the PLC public key for the
elliptic curve El Gamal like encryption
for example this is a real censored key
file it's version is 1 it's order number
is s7 1500 connection its family type is
s7 1500 and the kita is the PLC public
key but if we take a better look we will
see that the film version is empty why
the reason is that this plc public key
is good to connect to any s7 1500 PLC
and this is our ring this is the ring to
rule them all with this public key we
can connect to any s7 1500 PLC so now
that we have found our ring we could use
it with our with our rogue engineering
station in order to establish the
session key so first of all pre
calculate 3 key encryption and check
some encryption key check some seed and
key encryption key this step could be
offline in our setup phase in our lab
then when the attacker is on the product
environment and start the handshake let
Python do the symmetric encryption and
the checksum calculation to build King
material 2 & 3 based on the challenge
that was sent from the PLC
now our rogue engineered station can
send the king material to the plc and
the POC will extract the KD k and
derived the session key but we need to
derive the session key too
so the Python script rocks the session
key derivation function from the
relevant DLL we didn't reverse the
session key derivation function f due to
lack of time but we know that this
function is a static function and it
doesn't and it doesn't depend on any
external information ok now I'll give
some tips about reverse engineering the
Thea handshake so here is yuge first of
all find your target files in our case
the target file was a MSP core managed
dll this is the main
7 communication DLL this is a mixed
model which means the part of the DLL is
written in C sharp and co and is
compiled to manage CIL bytecode and the
other part of the
is written in C++ and compiled to native
and managed x86 awkward's then choose
your tools when we want to analyze the
managed code we can ignore the native
part of the DLL and load the DLL in
reflector or the inspire and read its
code when we want to analyze the native
C++ code we can ignore the manage part
of the DLL load it in either pro or in
Hydra and analyze the native code then I
recommend to improve your reverse
engineering starting point so how can we
do it ok ok so tip number one identify
native code entry points so this is a
snapshot from om speak or manage the ll
managed part open in this Indian Spy if
if you look at the bottom of the
snapshot there is a call to a OMS client
session set server key public key set
several public key function okay so
let's click on this function okay so we
barely can see the prototype of s
several public key but where is the
function body so the inspire us and
parsing the P header file and it can
tell us that this function is an
unmanaged function we open it during the
analyzing of the manage part so it's so
clearly we won't see the source code of
this function but how can we found it
its implementation so if we take even a
closer look a closer look we will see
that there is also an AR AR v a year so
what is this our VA this R b/a is the
relative virtual address of this
function in the native part of the DLL
we can load it in either take the image
base
this OVA and we will reach this function
now we know that this function is s set
several public key and we also know it's
prototype because we see it in the
manage part
tip number two C++ and RT TI are TTI is
runtime type information this is a very
cool feature an optional feature that
allows C++ programmers to examine object
types dynamically the article
information must be inside the binary
and we could use it
so find our TTI object this could be
done by looking for the string our TTI
complete object locator with Ida and
then after we find an object we can see
the name of the class here there is the
OMS parser the reason that this of this
object is interesting because every
virtual table of the classes has a
reference to this object so locate the
relevant virtual table by using the
cross references of this object after we
found the virtual table we could rebuild
the structure which represent the
virtual tables and also changing the
name of the address like this then
combine the wall scan the dotnet
metadata and grab the native entry
points also scan your ID be and grab the
relevant our PTI data use either Python
to add this information to your ID be
and then this ugly function which I
guess that most of you can't understand
what it does because of all these
dereference with a very few efforts
could transform to such a nicely and
readable function
much better isn't it
okay so now let's see them on the
demonstration volume
this is our attack setup here you have
our victim PLC the s7 1500 below you
have a screen connected to a Windows
workstation on the left hand side of the
screen you see three windows realize
that I'm going to use to run our attack
screens on the right-hand side of the
screen you see it Tia in a read-only
mode that I'm going to use to query the
PLC as to the program loaded in it first
I'm going to run an detects creep that
stops and starts the PLC the PLC is
currently in run mode is indicated by
the green background and we have a
single LED that is sets I'm going to use
the script to send a stop instruction to
the PLC the piece is switched to stop
hold the background color has changed
and the LED is cleared now I'm going to
send the start instruction to the PLC
the PLC is switched to run mode the
background color is green again and the
lab is set next I'm going to run an
attack script the download downloads a
program to the PLC the problem that we
are going to use is the yellow program
from the examples the yellow program
sets let's number 0 in one so indeed it
is running in the plc now I'm going to
use the Tia to query the PLC as to the
program loaded the Tia gives a
notification that the source of the
program loaded in the PLC has changed
which is indeed true because before we
had a program with like one LED set and
now we have a program with LEDs number
zero and one set the yellow program now
we are finally ready to show you our
Stealth's program injection attack I'm
going to run an attack that downloads
the blue binary and the yellow source so
the blue binary let's number two and
three are set we added another LED for
your convenience so it will be easier to
distinguish between the yellow program
and the blue program now I'm going to
use the Tia to query the PLC as to the
program loaded in it the yellow source
was previously loaded to the PLC and now
I loaded it again so the source program
hasn't changed so the Tia doesn't send a
notification so we have the blue binary
running in the PLC we have the yellow
source loaded to the PLC so indeed our
stealth program injection attack is
successful and even if they're easily
connected to the production environment
it will not be able to detect our
stealth program injection attack
[Applause]
so to summarize we introduced phone
number vulnerabilities in the s7 p3
protocol here is not authenticated
towards the PLC and there is a one ring
to rule them all a one PLC publicy we
also introduced a Python a tackle that
impersonates Tia download a recorded
program to any a7 1500 PLC we also
introduced a stills mod injection attack
thank you very much for listening any
questions yes we did contact Siemens we
found some other vulnerabilities that we
didn't describe on this presentation but
there are described in the white paper
so Simmons società CV in number but
apart from this the main reaction was
use password protection access control
to mitigate this attack any other
questions thank you very much
[Applause]