good afternoon welcome to selling zero
days to governments and offensive
security companies in South Side a de
Bie Mallory Schwartz before we begin a
few brief notes stop by the business
Hall located in Mandalay Bay Oceanside
and shoreline ballrooms on level 2
during the day for the Welcome Reception
at 5:30 tonight the blackhat Arsenal is
in the business hall on level 2 join us
for the pony Awards in lagoon JKL
at 18:30 thank you for putting your
phones on vibrate it makes it easier for
the rest of us to ignore the ringing
while you wait for your voicemail to
pick up and with that let us welcome our
speaker thank you very much for having
me here
I'm super excited it's my first time
here in blackhat then is a speaker as
well and today we're going to talk about
selling zero days to government and
offensive security companies a little
bit about myself I working as a
vulnerability broker in the past four
years started my way at beyond security
SSD project a great company highly
recommended to work with and after a
year and a half I opened my own company
this focus slowly on government and
offensive security companies called
Kuryakin and I also work today in the
insurance industry as a security
researcher in one of the largest
insurance company in Japan what we're
going to talk about today so we're going
to talk about we will start with who is
the who is this talk for a little bit
about my story who is selling zero-days
what is the process of selling them how
to sell it and of course tips for
beginners this talk is not a technical
talk and not the deep deep dive into the
zero day market industry this talk is
meant to give you guidelines for
researchers that want to step into the
market they take part of it
and of course I'm going to share my
experience and deepen tricks that I use
gather along the along the way so my
story as I already mentioned I founded
my own company called Curie con started
small and started to get more and more
attention had some quite effective
successful deals helping researchers to
find jobs or selling their products and
also started to work with the major
clients in the industry after a few
successful moves I've been approached
with one of the biggest players in my
industry and basically I got threatened
to stop what I'm doing because this is
not my main source of income I decided
it doesn't worth the risk and closed the
company but it's not the end we'll start
with an overview about the tsardom
market in traditional software companies
there is a there is a technological
problem but if you invest enough time
and money eventually you'll have a
product it doesn't matter if it will be
the best product but you will have a
product but but vulnerabilities behave a
little bit different it's sort of an art
other than something that you just can
put money on and you will get the
results so from vendor perspective they
can put a lot of money into it but they
will not find the core vulnerabilities
in their product so it behaves a little
bit different a little bit about the
history here in the past five years the
serda industry changed drastically if we
are talking about increased number of
players a brokerage company conferences
bug bounties budgets are basically
unlimited another really interesting
thing that happened in the past five
years is the fact that I call that
stepping out of the shadows in in the
five years ago if you want to sell
something it was something that you
talked about in the dark alley or
something like that that no one knows of
but today we see more and more companies
and players that actually publish it
that they are
are looking to buy vulnerabilities and
exploits on the free market so there is
starting working with invoices and
companies and contracts that things that
we didn't see five years ago but okay
who is interested in this you're the
industry there are different players in
the community and they're all interested
in zero-days but they're in the target
in the end is a little bit different I
kind of conservative here and I put
three different groups that we all
familiar with we have the white hat the
gray hats and the black hats again it's
more historical than other represent the
nature of the zero day today but let's
start with that so who is buying what
because each come each community has
different needs and different
perspective about this year the industry
will start with the white hat because
it's the easiest and we need to talk
about them a little bit the lucky one
reporting from 2018 shows they're more
than 166 thousand registered hackers and
they submitted more than 72,000
vulnerabilities as you can see the
majorities and web vulnerabilities
meaning XSS CSRF
I call them low-hanging fruits easy to
find and quick money and we can see that
it's not only in 2018 in 2019 is the
same thing we have more hackers out
there but the results are the same
more than 73% are focused on web
security low-hanging fruits easy to find
easy money it's not just the hacker one
we also see that in background also 2018
the higher pay was for XSS and in 2010
the same thing so what does it tell us
about the white hat community that it's
a huge community that there is a lot of
vulnerability submitted to the different
bug bounty programs but in the end the
majority of web related and not they are
the core
high-end products but there are also
high-end the researchers that contribute
to the security of different vendors
they're either a geology motivated or PR
motivated and we can see them in the
acknowledgement of every major company
that publishes like new versions here's
those just some of them that just pick
up randomly but there's a lot of them if
I'll try to summarize the white hats
because we need as I said we need to
talk about them so there's a lot of
vulnerability researchers out there they
are looking for low-hanging fruit and
easy targets because it's quick and easy
money and the high-end researchers are
focused like a motivated either by PR or
they want to make the ideology motivated
and we want to make the internet more
secured so we talked about the white
hats because we should talked about them
but the other two different groups are
slightly different and they looking for
different things so what are they
interesting they're interested in the
high-end market again I this is how I
phrase it so we can see here that we
have traditional browsers and OS related
vulnerabilities but on the right side
you can see the fat unicorn and I love
this picture that's supposed to
represent different kind of
vulnerabilities something that is quite
unique even in the zero day industry
we're talking about zero clicks we're
talking about RC - oh I am for example
what's up or telegram with signal or
whatever those are quite unique and each
and we'll talk about it player looking
for those vulnerabilities but again the
majority is focused or either the
browser's or the OS of course no user
interaction prio etc this is what the
zero the industry all about about from
researcher perspective they need to
understand that the service map they can
offer is not just an imminent product
they can sell different things we will
start with the unproductive
as a researcher you can sell a full
vector meaning a combination of
different vulnerabilities that in the
end will allow you to get a persistency
about your target we're talking about
remote code execution local privilege
escalation and persistency but you can
also sell each one of them individually
meaning it can sell the RC alone the LP
alone etc but much but most of the
researcher do not know that you can sell
you can also sell part in the chain Ming
info leaks and the medication bypass
doors are really common in the industry
and it can make two decent living out of
them but other than end product we also
have services and I will touch them in
the following slides but to give you the
idea you can sell it at a dedicated
researcher meaning that a company or a
government will outsource the
vulnerability research to other like
companies or individual to find things
you can also provide workshops but
workshop here meaning that each really
big conferences have workshops black get
included but there are also workshops
that are only specific to government and
security region security companies that
are specific domains and you know what
like for example if a company wants you
step into a new domain they will hire a
workshop that someone that you already
familiar with that to close the gap as
soon as possible
consulting is another way of services
that the researchers can offer for
example validate other researches
vulnerability or just like answering
questions for the research team from the
government or the offensive security
company and of course support and I will
talk about it a little bit later because
it's really important bullet what is the
difference between governments and
companies I mentioned them quite a lot
but there are different groups inside
those
is that desire those basic groups the
first let's talk about the offensive
security companies because they are the
easiest one to understand we have
security companies that are focused on
products meaning they're selling to
governments organizations here the
company actually sell the entire
infrastructure they're not just selling
the zero-day themselves meaning that
they sell their vulnerabilities the
mellah where the infrastructure the
proxy the intelligence the intelligence
the intelligence infrastructure that
comes along with that and on the other
hand we have knowledge based companies
meaning they are selling 0 things that's
what they're doing that's what they're
there for
on the government side we have two
different government entities let's put
it that way
the incapable countries incapable
countries incapable countries and I will
take an made-up example I'll take
Antarctica just not to offend anyone and
Antarctica want to acquire foreign
abilities but they don't have an
internal research team meaning that if
they you will offer them even for free
and RC for one of the platforms are
interested they would not know what to
do with that meaning they do not
understand the value of it they don't
know how to chain it then they don't
know how to write new exploits to older
or newer versions so those are incapable
countries most of them will abide the
end products from the security companies
on the other hand we have the capable
countries with a strong internal
research team they can actually value
the item itself and they can do things
with that
for example chain it to other
vulnerabilities and create different
vectors from researchers perspective you
want to focus on those on all the
offensive security companies and
incompetent government that has a
internal research team because they will
understand the value of it and willing
to pay more so let's start how do you
get those 0 days right from the
researchers there are different kind of
groups in the researchers we start with
the the biggest one called researchers
and I already showed you there are more
than hundreds of thousands of
researchers around the world but they
are not high-end researchers they not
capable finding vulnerabilities in the
product that you I show you earlier so
if we go step one layer down we have the
high-end researchers that I already
mentioned that there are either ideology
motivated or PR motivated and then we
have the work that high-end researchers
that work in the effective security
companies or governments and in the end
willing to sell meaning that there are
individuals or companies that finds or
days and sell it in the open market
roughly around 400 people worldwide this
estimate I have if you have any other
best figure out I will be glad to hear
this chart is based slowly solely or
based on my experience each researcher I
met quite a lot of researchers in the
past four years I can pinpoint where
they are in this chart how does it chart
works usually when you're in young age
around 20
you don't really familiar with the sewer
the industry didn't view and you don't
know that it your item worth money so
that's why you basically publish it for
free online you report the vulnerability
to the vendor and then you got to start
to get attention then you start you step
into the second step and the second
column here that you've got you get you
get offered to work in offensive
security industry companies or
governments at that point you make a
really decent salary but you understand
that your boss making a lot more on your
items so at that point you decide to
open your own company because you are
the researcher you know exactly what to
do and you said okay I have the
technical capabilities to find
vulnerabilities but what those
researchers don't know it's how to
manage a company because the findings
earlier that zero day is it's only a
technical part but you
also need to have a company that means
that you need to work with the legal and
accountants and find clients and it's
really hard work to do and usually you
get paid only slowly on your items that
you sell so if you didn't find a
vulnerability for four months in a row
you don't have any income and probably
you are in the age of 32 and you want to
make your own family so at that point
you start to get stressed that's why we
go to the end or - right hit the right
side of this slide we can see they
started to take more and more projects
that are not vulnerability research for
example pen tests or they you really
want to study income so they go going to
work with one of the major vendors in
the market so again this is solely on my
experience but I can input each one of
the researches that I work with based
upon that from the researchers
perspective those are the two timeslots
that you have to sell your
vulnerabilities and this lecture will
focus on them so what we learned so far
what kind of products and governments
are looking into what is the different
products and services that you can offer
what is the difference between
governments and companies and of course
the researchers hurricane courage
infinity sticks oh I hate that word okay
so what is the process
selling zero-days that's why we here
there the process is relatively
straightforward
we researcher find a vulnerability and
you want to market it so it contacts a
potential client it provides an overview
about the vulnerability and what the
capability of the vulnerability is
there's the negotiation period there is
a contract QA and of course payment I
will start with those four bullets but
eventually each one of here the audience
I think is interesting in the payment so
payouts by default is a researcher you
are your expect to get paid more than
more than the van
bug bounty because if it's the same
amount of money I think the majority
will go to the vendor and try to do from
their perspective the right thing but
from a researcher there is no single
price list there is no www-what how much
my vulnerability worth com
so today researcher based there like
pricing on those three bullets
first of all competitions if you can get
paid from point one eighty thousand
dollars for an LP so this is your
benchmark are there another example as
rumors when researchers sell they
usually talk about that and you have the
idea of how much things worth and of
course we have hacking team like
incident that we actually saw how much
they paid for the specific vulnerability
the one company that changed the game
after the rules basically are zero diem
because they just published the list
around three years in a row this this
was the benchmark like researcher when
they try to sell vulnerability the first
thing they do went to this there this
iridium website and see how much they
are willing to pay for it but in reality
things are much more complicated there
is the matrix for each vulnerability
there are different parameters that we
need to understand before we can provide
you an estimate of how much the
vulnerability is actually worth I will
go over them but there are two things
that you need to understand before the
first one is different entities will pay
different sums for the same
vulnerability and the second thing is
warranty and the model the client works
is really matter but the majority of the
like how do you do pricing for
vulnerability or for an item its supply
and demand because if there is if you
have a vulnerability for example for an
iOS and all the clients are on the
industry and already have a solution so
mean that no one will buy it from you
or the price will be lower than expected
exclusive a non-exclusive is really
important as well if you ask me six
months ago this price died just a second
it's the second site there is a price
list that are going to show you and all
the prices were for only exclusive but
today the majority of the pricing is
going to non exclusive and the price is
really high because as a researcher you
want to maximize the amount of money
that you can get for a single
vulnerability so I said warranty and
sell model it's important why is that a
company can offer you one and a half
million dollar for vulnerability but in
their terms it will be it will be
splitted over 12 months and they will
give it to their customers on day one
meaning that I'm not sure a
vulnerability will last one full year
and you will get the full one point five
million dollar so it's really important
to understand the terms that you are
selling your item this is the priceless
that I talked about and what you can see
here its prices for non exclusive items
in again six months ago I told you it
was for exclusive vulnerability but in
today reality we're talking about
non-exclusive as you can see on the
dollar then like in the left side of
this of the slide assuming that is 95
percent reliability or something similar
to that and up to 5 second execution
time so we are talking about not just I
found the crash and I think I can
actually explain it we are talking about
exploits that are really easy to
understand and are all ready to put in
production as already mentioned just
because you have an item doesn't mean
there is an active buyer that's willing
to buy it for you so it's really
differentiate between times and again
market demand changed regularly I show
you the like the big list of products
that offensive security companies in
government are interested but it's
changed from time to time for example
two years ago we saw
that one of the one of the
vulnerabilities that we're trying to
find oh I forgot the name sorry for that
I'll get to it later but there is the
high-end vulnerability that I'll show
you already there are in regular demand
okay so let's talk about validation of
the vulnerability by the client
the following slides are more legal from
that perspective but I'm not a lawyer so
each one of the of you that want to step
into this market I highly recommend you
to find a lawyer so let's start we start
with this back
what is this back a researcher as a
researcher you don't want to give the
technical information about the
vulnerability one once you try one you
want to sell the vulnerability to a
client therefore as a researcher you
guarantee the end result of the
vulnerability on a predefined
configuration the client will Chile will
test your item based upon that spec and
if you are your item is not comply
comply to the spec you sent they candy
you can decline the offer itself again
there is a margin here about 5% that you
can make it like vulnerability said it's
95 percent and in reality it's 90
percent it's still okay but never
claimed that it's more than what it
should be
validation period usually 14 days either
the client has the ability to test your
item in this period the validation
period the client can decline the offer
if it doesn't comply with the spec you
send them but there are three different
things I want you to take from this
slide the first one is make sure that
you get access to the test environment
to the client test environment because
sometimes the client don't know as if
don't know how to operate your
vulnerability as you intend them to and
therefore it can actually
take a bed turn and close the deal and
when possible make sure you can supply a
full environment for the test
environment for the client itself in a
VM or whatever thought for you and the
third one it's just make sure when just
before you send the item itself make
sure the client is ready to receive the
item itself and the test environment is
already set up
because again you you send your item and
you don't know what will go with that
and you want to make sure everything
goes smoothly as possible
freeze and payments the first thing that
I wanted like to make sure everyone in
the audience understand that there is no
such a thing an advance payment there
are a lot of hustlers in the world that
will try to contact you and say I have
this amazing vulnerability with the
perfect spec and reasonable price but
they will tell you that I only need
$5,000 duty to buy a flight ticket from
one point to another just to make sure
that you're you show me that you're
serious you will pay for it so no those
are hustlers and we saw so many of them
and they actually been published in
Twitter's several of them but again I'm
not here to make show you the names but
it's true so that's why you would you
would not get paid before the client
actually tests the vulnerability
payments there is the split split the
risk approach that the majority of
clients work with meaning that you will
get X percentage after the validation
period and then the rest split in chunks
for three or six months usually three
months and if it's a relatively small
transaction meaning up to $100,000 it's
100% after validation of course as I
said before we're stepping out of the
shadows
meaning that VAT invoices is really
important and because
Evette cryptocurrency became more and
more difficult to handle because for a
company to purchase that amount of
Bitcoin for example cryptocurrency this
is making it basically impossible to do
so so if you're if you're working with
invoices you will get bank transfer and
that's what we're aiming for and of
course just to note it here the majority
of transactions are in u.s. dollars just
make sure you have a US dollar account
to actually receive the money okay next
property rights when we are talking
about property rights each deal has two
different its binary or you sell it
exclusively or non-exclusive when you're
talking about non-exclusive the
researcher sells and license to the
vulnerability and the license can be
used or resell to other clients as well
it can be solved multiple times and no
problem with that the problem is when we
go to exclusive because the buyer
acquire everything all the IP all title
all copyrights is owned by the clients
itself meaning that if you want to
actually use your own vulnerability to
find other vulnerabilities in iOS is a
really great example for that so you're
not allowed to so just make sure that
you as a researcher when you try to make
a contract you put that as one of the
things that you can actually allow to do
use the vulnerability for yourself in a
private matter in order in order to find
other items next support I told you that
I'm going to talk about that a little
bit and support can take many forms it
can be exploited justments two other new
newer versions and if the vulnerability
is patch you as the researcher have to
like provide a new vulnerability and
also can you can provide a workshop on
the vulnerability to the client itself
but what you need to understand that
that support worth a lot of money
you don't just give it away for free
meaning that if you are giving sort kind
of kind of sort of support make sure you
get paid for it
governing the law governing law it's
basically if everything turned horribly
wrong where you can sue because again
not a client
neither the researcher want to go there
but sometimes we need to understand what
are the law the laws that you are
applicable to for example if you are
French researcher and you sold it to
us-based company in which law are you
under the US law or the French law it's
really important to make to make sure
that you the researcher define exactly
where the law are governing exports the
ability and here you come the funny part
was another agreement I'm sure that the
your majority that sits here no that was
an agreement is for dual-use items for
example you can buy rather to find for
civilian uses and put it in an airport
or you can buy it and use it as a merit
military use so those things are for
dual use what's so special about that in
the past few years the under was on our
agreement vulnerabilities and exploits
are it has been added but what you need
to understand that each each government
or each country has a slightly different
laws regarding the vasana agreement
because what's on our agreement
it's an agreement it's not equal law so
each each government that signed the
contract actually obligated to form
rules based on the under on the
agreement itself in their own country so
each country has the freedom to do
slightly like to regulate different
rules so it's really important to
understand the rules in your country
this is like from the rotten agreement
is just
it said it's just a copy paste so it's
not that important but what if I'll try
to show it to you in a really easy way
there are there was an argument distinct
two vectors the first one is that you
are a researcher and you want to to
report it to the vendor and that point
you're good to go you don't need any
licenses and you don't break any law but
if you try to sell the vulnerability or
exploit to a third party that it's not
directly the vendor here you need to
have your licenses ready and usually the
one that the organization that hand
those licenses are the Minister of
Defense in the majority of countries so
you need the license for marketing and
you also need licenses for the sale
itself and it's really long process so
please start it as soon as possible
finding the customers sounds easier
right I have a vulnerability I know that
everyone wants it how do I contact the
different clients so there are three
different ways that I thought of you
have the official way you have the
personal connection and of course you
have the vulnerability brokers that I'm
one of them let's start with the
official point of contact some
governments and of offensive security
companies they have this official point
of contact it can be here in conferences
that you will be approached by one of
them it can be by business cards cold
email etc and again as a researcher if
you think a company is interested in
zero days you can just ask them and they
probably will reply you if we're talking
about government
it's like slightly different the
majority of governments would not like
to work with you directly they have a
person that they already work with it
can be a broker to be a company and
usually he do the entire process so some
of them are not that
we'll be openly work with you but some
of them are but what you need to
understand that the it's really
time-consuming and don't expect amazing
terms because there are big organization
and it takes a lot of time to actually
make a deal because they need to approve
the the contract they approve the budget
and this thing takes quite a lot of time
if we're talking about the pros and cons
here about official point of contact so
you know exactly what you're selling to
it's really easy to understand but
there's a lot of cons related to that it
depends where the company is based the
like the legal part is really important
because the last thing you want to do is
actually get involved in illegal
transaction if we're talking about a
personal connection it's basically the
same thing but you can say that you'll
get fully paid because you know the
person then they know you and you have a
trust relationship between you so it's
really important but again it's more of
the same if we are talking about
vulnerability brokers and again I'm one
of them there are different services map
that we offer it's not the full service
map but yeah this is me there but again
I will focus on selling and end products
because this is talk is all about so
from there's a lot of benefits to work
with brokers right because as a
researcher you can stay an enemy there
we understand the market landscape we
understand the pricing and how the
process works we have a closing an
intimate relationship with our clients
meaning that they will approach us and
ask us do you have item a B and C and
therefore we can Maksim the amount of
money then researcher get can can get
get paid legal aspect is also important
because from legal perspective broker's
has different entities in different
places around the world and it's their
responsibility to actually provide the
licensing
to export it so if you are a you for
example
EU based researcher and you want to sell
it outside of the EU you're not allowed
to you need licenses but once you work
with brokers with EU entity it's his
responsibility to provide those licenses
in order to export it so it's really big
benefit to work with brokers
how does brokers make the money right
because they don't work for free except
me and I will tell you all about that in
a second
broker fees it's one way to do business
the attack the take X percentage out of
each transaction
another option is reseller meaning that
I am the broker I bought the
vulnerability and I will sell it
multiple times it can be if I buy that
exclusive or non-exclusive it doesn't
matter it depend how many clients I have
and what they're willing to offer and
the third one is subscription a yearly
or monthly fee that they can if the
government or clients go with that route
they can we can make use of whatever
vulnerability is the the broker board
offer if I'll try to summarize up
everything here there is a don't waste
time on the surday industry if your
vulnerability is not mature enough
because it will waste the clients time
and your time it will never it will
never lead to a successful deer deal
ensure your vulnerability is ready to
use and your POC stable just because
then I already mentioned that if you
have an item and no one want to buy it
it doesn't really matter right and never
over sale a vulnerability it just will
not work do not this is really important
on the right side you see the bullet
meaning that again finding
vulnerabilities and exploit them are two
different set skills the majority of
researchers are focused or expert in one
of them so if you have this
beautiful vulnerability but the axe what
is the problem please tell it because it
can literally save the deal because
again most of the clients and
governments have an internal research
team and once they understand that they
will be willing to pay you the full
amount or reduce a little bit just
because the exploit isn't good enough
doesn't matter doesn't mean the
vulnerability isn't never treat or tell
about successful deals because again it
can it will breach the confidentially
contract and you don't want to do that
and if you sell non-exclusive try to
limit yourself to three or to four
trusted clients because if you will say
that sell it for multiple and multiple
times you will burn the vulnerability
and your credit will be harmed because
of it people would not like to work with
you another aspect of it
it's always listened to feedbacks
meaning that if you are Linux researcher
and your client tell you look you should
move to Android you should consider that
because the client is believing you and
understand that you can actually deliver
if you change the domain and basically
they do that because they think it will
be better for you because Android is
more popular than Linux and it's really
important to understand that 0 days
lately burn a lot more faster of course
when we are talking about browsers so
again in fact if someone is one client
to offer you I don't know 100 thousand
dollars less than the the market itself
sometimes it's the best it's the best
deal and you should take it
and of course transactions sometimes
when not go to the entire process but if
they do it's amazing and it's worth it I
already said that that supply and demand
is the most important parameter when you
are selling vulnerability
again it's more of the same here that
when this market is flooded you you will
have difficult to sell the vulnerability
and exclusive might seem easy to work
around meaning that you you sell one
client exclusively but in the end you'll
sell it multiple times it's really
important for you as a researcher to
understand that we all connected all the
clients are talking with each other all
the brokers are talking with each other
so if you do something like that
you will be people we would not want to
work with you in the end because they
would not trust you and this is the most
important part my take away the biggest
take away I want you to take it from
here is just if you want to start
working the easier the industry open a
company because you can work in a very
very legal way in a very traditional way
with invoices legal and everything and
it will make your life really easier to
do so I promise some tips and tricks
that I gather along the way so from
researchers that want to step into this
market and take part of it go play CTFs
CTF is a really good opportunity for
clients to approach you they see how
talented are you and you can again it's
really important for you to do that go
to conferences especially like that I
have so many clients here and it will
approach different researchers just
because they in familiar way they know
about read about publish it's really
important get help when in doubt because
again there is a amazing community of
researchers that will help you if you
find something that they will take it
from one level into the next and they're
willing to do that for free the majority
of them at least and know your shit
never fake it till you make it because
it won't work again the clients are
interested in the end product and they
judge you upon those not anything else
how can I help you on your journey
I closed my company a year ago but they
still offer my services for free
people call me nuts but I really loved
the industry and I worked with a lot of
researcher and helped them along the way
I have a slightly different approach
from other brokers but I can just ask me
anything you like I will be more than
happy to help you questions yeah go
ahead
yeah
I don't hear you
ah okay so he asked if during the
validation period if you already provide
the source code itself so the question
the answer for that is yes because the
first step is signing on took a contract
after you sign a contract the client has
to validate your item and they do that
by the source itself
okay so just say I buy one of these zero
days it gets
what contract
it depends okay the question is what
happened if I sold the vulnerability and
after six month we got benched so if you
use like in the agreement you said that
you will get paid fifty percent on
validation and the rest in three months
chunk nothing will happen you will get
the full amount
it doesn't okay the question is if
they're the client has a duplicate what
will happen from the client perspective
he will be obligated to tell the full
amount of the item itself because you
send them the spec and that's what you
guaranteed if the item do I don't care
in the client like I am as a broker and
you as a researcher don't care that the
client already has it so we will pay the
full amount I can't see but I have okay
so just a question general like what
would be the motivations for clients to
buy vulnerabilities like that if it's
not our product sorry what will be the
motivation for a kind to search for a
vulnerability if it's not their product
what what are they usually interested in
we're talking about like defensive
secret you world right right like we're
on the same page here okay so we're
talking about companies that offer the
food products as I mentioned earlier
meaning that they're our company their
governments or government's organization
they don't have the knowledge to create
those kinds of products or vectors so
they will buy it Peter by each owner
ability separately or the entire product
on the infrastructure so that's the
motivation yeah
in your experience how many of the
transactions that you started or started
down the road on failed burçak succeeded
I know it's a limited sample size sorry
it's a can you please repeat of how many
of the transactions that you started
down the road or research you start
working on how many times did it fail -
it never Preston see him again in my
experience in the past four years never
really when the spec was really good the
client know exactly what is getting I
had zero further right siren of
companies that currently have
vulnerability rewards programs or bug
bounties what do you think they can do
differently to attract these researchers
instead of that
to third parties and really far I can't
hear you
sorry is that better yeah of companies
that currently have vulnerability
rewards programs bug bounties what
should they do differently to attract
these researchers aside from you know
paying them a lot more money what were
things can they do so I have different
answers to their questions but the
majority of researchers just love the
fact that they're not reported to the
front door itself so it's really depends
because I saw so many bug bounty
programs that try to aim researchers to
find the specific vulnerability types
and they will be really exploitable and
I actually can mitigate them but in
reality the majority of researchers that
participate in this or the industry they
just want to get the money and the
thrill out of it so it's a little bit of
a problem
thanks you mentioned that there were 400
people involved and worldwide and
selling as a broker how do you find them
or do they find you it goes both way I
think because again this is part of my
day to day job so I connect with a lot
of researchers and they of course
connect me as well in my case or Farrell
is really part of it because if you help
researcher to sell the item he and he
had a really good experience with you he
will refer other to you as well
you mentioned in your talk that you said
that O'Day's burned a lot faster because
of zero and so can you expand on that
yep every time project zero usually
publish three or four vulnerabilities
they close the same vulnerabilities into
the industry again there is a lot of
talented researchers in the offensive
security industry they don't just
publish or report to the vendor and the
majority of bugs that project zero
already found that the researchers in
the offensive security industry found
them and exploit them and even use them
in the wild
as more countries are adding
vulnerabilities equities processed
programs how does that affect the
offensive sale are they adding in that
this has to go through the vet process
for example within the United States or
other countries with vet programs sorry
again I forgot it
it's really depends because if we're
talking about bugcrowd that hacker one
the only a platform in the end the the
vendor itself
is the client and he will get
vulnerability
I got it correctly or I mean to the US
process US government process is that if
they're in possession of a vulnerability
it needs to go through an interagency
review process I would think that would
affect does that matter to you or once
you sell it to them as part of the
contract what they have to do to see if
they're gonna disclose to the vendor for
the internal process with the US
government does that matter to use the
broker or to the researcher I'm much
more than this done of course I'm real
sorry okay is it okay thanks okay I'll
try to answer that later if it's okay
okay yeah amen okay
and I want to go up there zero days out
there available for that product but I
go to
I'll die
first idea
I think they advised
who will lie to you I'm if you want to
buy a product from another government
okay it's really okay
usually companies like product companies
do not sell to individual or other
companies they only sell it to
government because its dual use then you
have an end user and use certificate so
not in like companies cannot issue them
only governments and for this is the
second question the first one so if you
want to buy anything usually as a client
for like company or government the
easiest way is to go through brokers but
again you can open your own team that
buy and acquire them and actually
publish official point of contact for
example yeah I got a question is the
Reznor agreement so they impacted the
zero typewriter industry a lot the
Wassenaar green changed game rules like
from one one way to another because
today researcher do understand that if
they don't have the licenses there are
really big trouble
so I publish on Twitter like few weeks
ago that the Google offered three three
thirteen thirty thousand one hundred
dollars I think no early something
dollars for a sandbox escape from Chrome
and the value of the market it's like
around six hundred thousand so people
say that the market is not regulated but
it truly is because researcher
understand that clients the open
different subsidiaries in different
countries in order to to be able to
acquire vulnerabilities from different
entities so to answer your question yes
a lot so they just bypassing the
agreement sorry I just bypassed the
agreement by opening up companies in
other countries does the roster agree
they bypassed
wasn't our restrictions by opening I
will be more than happy to help you but
I running out of time so I'm right here
if anyone want to ask anything thank you
very much for your time
[Applause]