good morning everyone welcome to SSO
wars the token menace in South Pacific
with Alex and Emeril and Alvaro Munoz
before we begin we have a few brief
announcements please stop by the
business all located in the Mandalay Bay
Oceanside and shoreline ballrooms on
level 2 during the day and for the
Welcome Reception at 5:30 tonight the
black hat Arsenal is in the business
hall on level 2 please join us for the
Pony Awards in lagoon GHI at 6:30 today
lunch will be available in Bayside a be
from 1205 to 1:30 and don't forget the
merchandise store on level 2 and session
recordings from source knowledge they
have a desk on every level please ensure
that your phones have been placed on
vibrate to avoid interrupting the
presentation and now please welcome
Alexander and Navarro so thank you very
much so as he said my name is Xavier
Romanov he's Alexander meteors we are
both security researchers with
microfocus fortify team we have a packed
agenda for today because we actually
submitted this talk as a 15 minutes
brief embolic got acceptance of 25 1 so
we had to discard a lot of stuff but we
put that into a white paper that is
going to be published today and host in
the in the black hat survey so we will
start with a brief introduction to what
authentication tokens are and how are
they connected to the located in
syndication and then we will be
presenting two vulnerabilities that we
found in the net framework the first one
is an injection vulnerability leading to
a betrayal constructor invocation and we
will see what's the impact of an
arbitrary constructor and the second one
will be XML signature by path that we
found and how we apply that to bypass
the some signature bypass that's what we
call duty confusion and we will be
presenting what microsoft frameworks and
products are affected by this wound
repeating so the legate authentication
is nothing else that when the user
access our protected resource the
service provider who is serving this
resource is not a handling our
authentication itself
right so it's basically delegating the
authentication to someone else in this
case we call it identity provided so the
user will go to the identity provider
will present the credentials and upon a
body validation or verification of the
credentials the identity provider will
issue an authentication token for this
user so there are multiple formats of
authentication tokens right we have some
all we have JSON web token we have
simple web tokens we have many of them
but all of them share some attributes
and some properties and the most
important one in most important one is
the signature right because if we don't
sign the authentication token anyone can
change the token the user or any
attacker in in the middle can change any
of the properties or attributes of the
authentication token and then just
become anyone in the target system in
this case in the service provider so we
will be focusing our research in step
number six that is when the service
provider receives the authentication
token and the reason for that is because
we think that there are two very
interesting attack vectors here the
first one is when the service provider
needs to parse and process the
authentication tokens some of these
attributes needs to be parsed before the
signature is verified so if we can find
one attribute that can lead to an
injection vulnerability this will be
before the verification of the signature
the second vector will be what if we can
go one step further and actually try to
bypass the whole signature verification
altogether so if we can do that we can
basically craft any authentication
tokens for any arbitrary user present
that the service provider and get that
accepted as a valid token so we will
start with the token parts moon ability
that we found in the net this case can
be good illustration for token parsing
vulnerabilities for signature
purification server needs a couple
object that represents algorithms crypto
algorithms and usually crypto config
create for name method is used for the
creation but we notice that it
does not restrict type names so we are
able to call any no argument public
constructor but you can ask it can it be
dangerous if we cannot control any title
but actually we can control some data
for first of all type name itself is
under our control also we can control
some part of current Pacific context and
some constructor can use it other
question how we can reach this matters
for example a system in the data model
tokens GWT library
passes a energy field from GWT header to
it also algorithm attribute of signature
method element from sam'l token goes
without any restriction to it as well so
we took to Microsoft servers SharePoint
and Exchange server and try to explore
exploit this problem there and here is
the list of our results SharePoint
tournament asks a different results for
successful creation object and not using
this we were able to get information
about installed product and their
versions also they could rise on tablet
exception that can relate to on Daniel
of services for exchange server ascend
to duplicated user we were able to
invoke any arbiter public no argument
constructor from any dll or example from
arbitrary folder local folder
unfortunately we do not have time to
cover it today but you can find all the
testing out our white paper let's switch
to our colleague rail and let's look how
the entire signature if occassion can be
bypassed but security assertion markup
language or just sum of tokens has
xml-based format and uses XML signature
for integrity protection
we can see simplified some token on the
screen along with the identification
information itself
it contains signature element it should
protect it from tampering this element
contains three main parts signature
itself and signature value Senate m4 has
information how this signature should be
verified and the most interesting
element for our attack its key info and
it presents key this should be used for
signature verification
let's review pout net implement
signature verification for such tokens
first of all we need to obtain him using
key info element we can extract this key
from it or use key reference and fetch
key from some storage on the second step
we will use this key for signature
verification my please note
positive results after this step only
means that this specific token was
saddened by this specific key and was
not changed in additional to this we
need to be sure that it was done by
proper signing party so we are taking
key in for element again and try to
identify who has signed this token and
of course the last step we will check it
is expected sudden party or not she we
highlighted the key steps for our attack
so we are taking key info lament twice
on different steps
also we need different types of results
on this step security key and security
token so we will call two different
matters resolve security key and is all
security token on this diagram we can
see the general idea of attack we need
to craft keen for element in such way
that we will get different results from
resolve security key and entry so
security token one will be used for
signature verification and another for
certification of shannon party in this
case we will be able to use own key for
signature calculation but server still
in the define us as expected sign and
party and we can bypass the whole
signature verification and can create
some token is any
cremation this problem affects all
places where in.net
where XML signature issues including a
product that works with some tokens
let's review the key frame works of
dotnet that use some token now so we
will start with windows communication
foundation which is or D or w CF which
is a Microsoft framework to build web
services right they follow the
service-oriented architecture but what
is interesting for us is that WCF web
services will accept some old tokens for
authenticating the the client right so
the client can go and present valid
credentials in the form of maybe user
and password but also a valid say and
sam'l token issued by an identity
provider so the class that is
responsible for handling sam'l tokens in
the WC f is this sam'l assertion type
and this is this piece of code you can
see that there are two different method
invocation one is resource activity key
and the other one is resource activity
token but both of them take the same
parameter right the key identifier
parameter contains the whole team for
section that is all the different keys
in the King for section the first one
will return the abbreviation T that is
the key that will be used to verify the
signature and the second one will return
the signing token or the security token
that is used to represent somehow the
the signing party or the identity
provider so we'll focus in the first one
when resolving the key what we will be
doing is what we call depth first who
will be first iterating through all the
different keys in the key flow section
and for each of them we will be invoking
this drive resolve security key that
will basically try a number of resolvers
for those kids right so first we iterate
through all the keys then we iterate
through all the resolvers now for the
token resolution the approaches is
slightly different instead of iterating
first row the keys it will iterate first
through all the resolvers it will try
all the resolvers and then for it to
resolve very good it will try all the
keys so what we can do is actually abuse
that
even if this difference is very small we
will end up visiting all the
combinations of keys and resolvers but
in different order right so we cannot
use that and this is what will we we
will be doing for attacking for example
WCF web services like exchange so first
of all we can modify an existing samo
token or create one from scratch then we
will create a pair of RSA keys with
public/private keys and then we will use
the private one to sign the token then
we will send both the public key for
this RSA paper and also the certificate
or the identifiers from identity
provider so we will have something like
this in the key info section right first
the attacker RSA key and then the
expected key identifier so the resource
security key will iterate through all
the keys first then it will take the
attacker 1 and then it will try all the
resolvers the third one will succeed and
then it will return the public key from
this RSA per since really sign now we're
talking with the private one the
signature verification will be
successful and we will bypass this
authentication now when we solve in the
security token because we are going to
iterate first through the route solvers
we will start with the first one and
then try all the keys for this
particular resolver so the first
resolver doesn't know how to resolve an
RSA key so it will fail and will move to
the next one the next one is the
identity provider certificate so it will
succeed will return that and then the
first one will be used for signature
verification the second one will be used
to authenticate the signing party and
therefore we will be able to bypass them
the process so this is how it looks in
the XML sam'l assertion the first
element in jello is the injected key in
this case we are using an RSA key we can
also use elliptic curve keys or
symmetric keys and the second one in
green is the expected
identity provider certificate that the
server trusts and expects so let's see
that in action we will be actually
taking over any account in exchange by
abusing the exchange web services so
instead of using a real client such as
Outlook or link we decided to actually
create our own client
in order to make them demo more more
visual and more is simple to follow so
we will be intercepting so we have burp
here that is a an interception proxy
what we are going to do is we are going
to intercept the request from the client
so this is our simple client is
basically going to request the mail tips
or the mail item for example could be
another valid request for user 1 right
and it's going to authenticate as user 1
and ask for their mail items so we will
send that and we will intercept the
request now we will be sending the
request to repeater that is an easy way
to modify the request and if we switch
to the XML view we will see the sam'l
assertion and for example the subject is
the user 1 but we will be replacing all
instances of user 1 with administrator
now the attack is to become
administrator's and with administrator
mail tips now because we are not
changing the signature if anyone do
these kind of attacks is going to fail
because the signature is no longer much
in the content of the of the assertion
and the body of a of the request so if
we send that we get an error that is the
expected result we modify we tampered
with the request with assertion and
that's not valid now if we use one
better plugin that we developed but will
allow us to resign the token so as you
can see here in the King 4 section we
only have the original identity provider
certificate but now we click on resign
with RSA key we will be basically
resigning it with our own private RSA
key and then appending the public one to
the key infrastructure so we have the
original one identity provider 1 but
before that we have the RSA key that we
use to resign and this one will be used
for verifying the signature so with that
we send the request we get 200
successful response and we are able to
get the mail tips from the administrator
this is successful no error response and
the attack was successful
okay so bear in mind that this was a we
were attacking an on-premise service
on-premise exchange server but this was
valid for the cloud person right for
office 365 so we were able to actually
access any mail from anybody using
office 365 now we will be reviewing
Windows identity foundation for those of
you that are not familiar with wif is
basically a framework for for developers
to integrate with identity providers so
it will take care of all the process of
handling the authentication tokens
verifying that organs are extracting the
claims and then providing the claims to
the application to take a claim or
identity based decisions so wif uses a
different set of resolvers but what
interesting in wif is that for key
resolution it will only try to resolve
the first element in the key info
section but for token resolution it will
try to iterate through all the different
elements in the key info section so we
can abuse that by providing a key that
is supported by the key resolver but not
for the token resolver so wif uses this
token is your token resolver which is
secure because it handles both tokens
and keys in a similar way consistent way
and then we can't abuse this resolver
however if it fails to resolve the key
or token it will move to the next
resolver which is this 509 certificate
store a token resolver now this one is
interesting because when resolving
security keys
it supports encrypted symmetric keys but
when resolving security tokens it does
not support encrypted symmetric keys so
in order for the server or the
application to decrypt our encrypted
symmetric key it needs to use a private
key that is stored in a specific
certificate storage in the server
for the attacker needs to get access to
the public key from that certificate in
order to encrypt the symmetric key
that's a strong limitation but maybe in
some cases for example the certificates
are reused for the SSL traffic and then
attacker can get the public key from the
certificate for the SSL traffic so if
the attacker get access to this
certificate the attack flow is as
follows the attacker can change or
modify an existing claims then it will
use a symmetric key to resign the token
and then it will encrypt that symmetric
key using the certificate from the
server now it will include both the
encrypted key but also the original
identity provider and the process is
very similar it will lead to this
duplication of keys where the first one
that is attacker control will be used
for signature purification and the
second one that is the identity provider
trusted certificate will be used for
authentication of the signing portal so
that was the default configuration for
wif now if you are building an
application using WF you can customize
you can change for example the location
of that certificate the storage but you
can also for example customize the
resolvers and that's exactly what
serpent is doing so SharePoint uses wif
to handle the event occasion tokens but
it uses a custom resolver and the
serpent resolver when resolving security
keys support things like a symmetric key
RSA keys elliptic curve keys but when
resolving security token it does not and
obviously we cannot use that therefore
we can attack cell point which is using
waf without the limitations of value AF
and with that we were able to attack and
get access to any serpent again on
premise and also office 365 so
conclusions and takeaways first of all
we are not saying that sam'l or
WS Federation are insecure protocols
these are in this case a design flaw in
the implementation is pacifically in
the.net implementation of the XML
signature verifiers actually their root
problem here was that we
these two different methods which were
taking user control data and there were
inconsistent in the sense that we were
able to force them to return different
objects so that's very interesting from
a security standpoint if you are
reviewing code you want to look into
this kind of methods but for example if
you are writing your own application
that integrate with wif you want to make
sure that if you are customizing the
resolvers they are consistent and they
are not returning different elements
also we focus our research in dotnet one
of the reasons is that dotnet was secure
for all the previous attacks and for
sam'l tokens but we did not spend a lot
of time or actually we didn't really
look into other languages and frameworks
so we don't expect the same design flow
to exist in other languages because
somehow dotnet a specific but similar
thing similar pros can appear in other
languages and frameworks even in dotnet
remember this is a pack that is
affecting the verification of XML
signature not only exception as sam'l
assertions so even in dotnet XML
signature is used for many other
purposes and we found a couple of cases
where it was also insecure we reported
that to Microsoft and they patched that
but there may be others so the main
takeaway is patch but as soon as
possible
and follow Microsoft recommendations for
this CV because for example for sell
point you need to update the sir point
version but also need to update some of
the dotnet framework libraries in the
system so it's not straightforward
also we are releasing the burr plugin
that we developed for our internal
testing and so basically will allow you
to intercept as a sam'l tokens and
resign them using either and a symmetric
RSA key or the public key from a
certificate in the case of wif
applications if you can get access to
that certificate and with that if you
have any questions we still have four
minutes otherwise we can go to the
rubber room or you can just send out
your questions to our Twitter account
and we will be happy to do answer them
thank you
you
[Applause]