good afternoon welcome to the past last
child abusing kubernetes default in
Mandalay Bay Lagoon from jkl with Ian
Coldwater and Davi coolie before we
begin I have a few brief notes
stop stop by the business hole located
in Mandalay Bay Oceanside and shoreline
ballrooms on level 2 during the day in
for the Welcome Reception at 5:30 p.m.
the blackhat Arsenal is in a business
hall on level 2 and join us for the pony
Awards in Laguna Niguel at 6:30 p.m.
it's in this room thank you for putting
your phones on vibrate as well it makes
this easier for the rest of us to ignore
the ringing in while you wait for your
voicemail to pick it up in Rocky it's
all yours thank you thank you everybody
hear me okay awesome before we started I
wanted to just thank blackhat and all of
the organizers and all of therapy board
the people who put in the work for all
of us to be here today that's awesome
and thank all of you for being here and
taking time out of your day to be here
with us my name is Ian Coldwater and
this talk is called the path less
traveled of using kubernetes defaults if
you are here to hear about something
other than kubernetes you're in the
wrong room and that's all right we can
hang out anyway I'm a lead platform
security engineer at Heroku and I
specialized in hacking and hardening
kubernetes containers and cloud
infrastructure before that I was an
independent penetration testing
consultant I'm focusing on the same
my name is Duffy Cooley I'm a staff
cloud native architect at VMware and I
focus on helping enterprises find
success with VMware and this kind of
include new cloud native regime I'm a
part of a weekly video blog
that's called TGI K you can find it
online at TGA TDI K dot IO and if you're
interested in the kubernetes pace I
highly recommend that you review what's
there we're really excited to be here
talking with you today so the first
thing we want to say is check your
assumptions if you have assumed that
kubernetes is secure by default or that
applications deployed on kubernetes are
secure by default we recommend that you
don't because they aren't and
when kubernetes gets left on out of the
box you can do all kinds of wild things
with it which is what we're going to
show you today so but before that let's
talk about kubernetes defaults because
it's a little bit of a misnomer like the
cake is a lie here there is no singular
set of kubernetes defaults it varies
widely depending on public clouds
distributions just out of the box and
every single cluster is probably going
to be a little bit different according
to how it gets configured so that attack
surface doesn't always look the same but
generally speaking we can speak to
kubernetes as a system how it works and
how to attack that so that's what we're
going to do so I work on a project
called cube ATM which is actually trying
to rationalize some of those defaults
and provide reasonable defaults for
bringing you to the place where you have
infrastructure or machines and networks
already stood up and you're trying to
get to a fully configured kubernetes
cluster cube EDM does actually provide a
reasonable set of default security
options and we're probably gonna talk
through a little bit of that but all of
the demonstration environments that
we're gonna be showing off today in this
talk are actually brought up using a
project called kind which stands for
kubernetes and docker and it leverages
cube ATM to stand up the cluster so in
our resources lens you can find a lot
more information about what we're doing
here it's worth noting that we're
attacking this cluster that has been set
up with the same reasonable and
relatively secure set of defaults actual
defaults that are not defined by coab
Adium are usually worse so keep that in
mind so what is super days so kubernetes
is a container orchestration system it
described a class of system that helps
us manage the lifecycle and and in the
complex architectures of some of these
new cloud native applications as a cloud
as a container Orchestrator it's
actually pretty successful most people
who are actually looking at kubernetes
are looking for two things the first is
actually a better efficiency through
like API models so you can actually
deploy some of these complex
applications and and figure out how they
will connect and secure them and that
sort of stuff through a single API and
the second is actually bin packing or
better efficiency of those machines that
they deploy in some of the more
expensive clouds that we see out there
when we're talking about kubernetes as
an attack surface kerbin
really means two things it means it's an
application with its associated set of
binaries that can be end the application
can be configured and it's also an API
based platform defined by yellow so both
of those things can be attached in
different ways and we're going to cover
them both so how does kubernetes work
let's talk about what's in there and how
those parts move so this diagram you can
actually see all of the the actual parts
that make up the application that is
coop niggas right in the left hand side
box you see the you see Etsy D and se D
represents a key value store where all
of the state for the cluster is kept
this is where we would hold things like
config maps or configuration files that
will be associated with pods when
they're brought up in the middle just to
the left of the Etsy D pod or e at the
ED CD image we have the API server and
you can see by the plethora of error
arrows that everything talks to the API
server the people on the outside the
services on the inside everything talks
to that API server and that the API
server is the only thing that talks to
the - Etsy D the API server does kind of
what you would expect an API server to
do it's going to handle authentication
and authorization it's going to take
care of invalidating all of the
manifests or objects that get submitted
to the API and it's gonna handle that
sort of stuff if we look below the API
server we see the controller manager and
the scheduler the scheduler does kind of
like what you would expect it to do its
job is literally to associate a pod or a
pod manifest somewhere to get more into
like what that is and see some examples
with a specific node or cubelet and the
controller managers a bit more complex
the controller managers responsibility
is actually to run a number of different
control loops that are each responsible
for breaking down the higher level of
abstractions inside of kubernetes down
to the lower level ones so if you've
played with kubernetes at all you would
have made a deployment the controller
manager is partly responsible for
turning that into pods on the right we
see two cubelets
or two worker nodes and the worker node
is running that agent the cubelet and
that cubelet is responsible for keeping
track of all of the work associated with
that particular node and starting up and
managing the lifecycle of containers
directly
so the cubelet when it posed
Manifest it's actually going to interact
with docker to create those containers
that make up that workflow as an
attacker let's take another look at this
series of kubernetes components because
we're gonna be talking a lot about how
kubernetes works today because it's
really important to be able to
understand how it works on a deep system
level to be able to understand how
attack it well so at CD we have this key
value store that contains all of the
state and all of the information about
what's happening in the cluster as an
attacker at CD is a high value target
because it contains interesting
information that I might want to exit
rate or steal such as cloud metadata and
credentials things like that potentially
it also is worth noting that Etsy D
because Corinna DS is a loosely coupled
distributed system at CD is writable
it's not just read-only it works both
ways
and so because Etsy D is the final word
on like what is happening the state in
the cluster you can write to it and then
you can modify State which can give you
all kinds of options as an attacker the
API server is the highest value target
as an attacker because the API server as
you can see either touches everything
where everything touches it if you can
get control over the API server which is
you know what's going to dictate what is
allowed to be you know what kind of
traffic is allowed what's happening is
going to be like making the orders for
what's going on there then you can get
access to pretty much all of the
components and you're able to get a fair
amount of control like a lot of it over
the cluster so going over to the worker
nodes the cubelet is incredibly valuable
as an exploit target because the cubelet
is what executes all of the decisions
that are being made with your
configuration and and is able to control
the state of the cluster and what's in
it
the cubelet has its own separate API
that interacts with the API server if
you can get access to the cubelet you
can do things like create users you can
create service account roles and you can
change around authorization stuff so
that you can get that you could also
affect what's in the cluster and you
have a lot of administrative access if
you can get access to the queue but the
cubelet has
Doralee is the subject of a lot of the
more high-profile attacks that have
happened historically with kubernetes
like Tesla and ones that it happened
over time so now we're going to move on
to the kubernetes api part of it alright
before we do that I want to just touch
on the fact that like there is a lot of
configuration in between all those
pieces securing the communications with
TLS and all about stuff we don't have
time for that in this talk but suffice
to say that diagram is very high level
compared to what's actually out there
there's also a lot of misconfigurations
yes all of those components all of which
can be valuable for attackers so the
kubernetes api is generally accessed
through a number of different means it's
a restful api you can interact with it
directly with curl if you want there is
actually a cube cube kettle is a binary
that you can download as part of a
distribution of kubernetes and that cube
kettle binary track acts as a local
command-line tool that you can use to
interact with that kubernetes api
directly and it'll take care of your
authorization and authentication using
your config kettle is also known as to
control coop CTL and crew cuddle and
when I talk about coop CTL I'm talking
about the same thing and that's
important to note because otherwise it's
confusing think about it like given gyp
there are other so there are some other
superpowers that cube kettle has one of
the ones I like to tell people about as
few Kittel explain coop it will explain
enables you to actually explore the
entire API so if you want to know what
all of the fields that are defined
within a particular pod or deployment
manifest are or what that default so for
those things are you can use cube kettle
explained to interact with that API and
look at it finally the last command here
is basically just showing off queue
petal apply which is how most people
interact with it as an attacker if you
can socially engineer somebody to coop
CTL apply your lovely helpful yellow
file that will show them how to use
things or whatever it is that you can
convince them to do they run it they
don't look at it it's yours
and you can do whatever you want with it
so configuration this code can be a
pretty powerful thing on all ends so how
do those moving parts fit together like
what exactly is happening there end of a
hood so you talk about kubernetes being
a loosely coupled system and in this
diagram we're going to show kind of like
the life cycle of a pod being created
so in the beginning here we have a
person probably making use of cube
kettles applying a pod manifest to the
API server the API server is going to
introspect that and understand is this
person who is authenticating do they
have a reasonable credential are they do
they have authorization to create this
resource within the cluster according to
the namespace that it's being put in all
that other stuff it's also going to
validate that you have all the fields
necessary to define what a pod is once
it gets through that entire process it's
actually going to persist that object in
the key value store in SU D and then
it's gonna report back pod created
you're done the API server is now
finished with its work the next part
that happens is that the scheduler who
is also watching the API server gets
informed that there is now a new pod but
it is not associated with an underlying
node and so it does its scheduling thing
it just figures out which node it wants
to schedule that pod on based on some
hints and things inside of the pot spec
and it will actually schedule that on a
node and persist basically another field
into that pod spec called node name back
to that object and the key value stored
at sea in in the API server and then
back to a CD the next thing we have is
the cubelet this is the one that's
actually doing the heavy lifting
I call this out because it's interesting
we think about a pod as two different
things one is a manifest basically just
metadata describing what we want to
deploy and the other is a set of running
containers or processes sitting on a
node somewhere so in this case we're
talking about the cubelet pulling down
that manifest and setting about the work
of creating those containers it does
that by calling out to your container
runtime could be docker container d
there are a bunch of them out there
it also will connect a network and do a
lot of the other stuff necessary for the
lifecycle of that pod once it and it
will report back to the api server
status you know i'm downloading the
image i've started the container all
these things are happening and it will
continue to inform you where it as where
it is in that process so as an attacker
let's take another look at this moving
parts diagram and let's figure out
what's happening there that it could be
potentially interesting to us so the API
server as you can see does a lot of the
kind of moving back and forth here and
the API server is responsible for things
like authorization and authentication
and routing CVE 2018 one zero zero two
one zero five which came out last
December was a server-side request
forgery where no else oh my god okay
what that was was attackers could send a
specially crafted request and that said
connection upgrade and because they
weren't malla dating for error codes it
just opened a WebSocket
whether or not it was correct and if you
could communicate directly with the
people it and the backend while
bypassing the API servers authentication
and authorization entirely which was
pretty nasty and pretty easily mitigated
as it turned out because all you needed
to do is validate for error codes so
that's one like way historically if you
look at that how at eckers have been
able to attack the API server another
thing that we can do is you may have
noticed that in our components diagram
as an attacker I didn't actually mention
the controller manager or scheduler at
all mostly because for the most part
it's irrelevant to me except that you
can bypass it by directly scheduling a
pod and if you can by pets if you can
directly schedule a pod on a node you
might be able to do some interesting
things with it especially if for example
your cubelet is scheduled on the same
pod as the underlying node which is the
default for kubb ATM so we've had a lot
of kubernetes words here anybody want to
see how to attack some stuff yeah let's
do it
all right Felipe so in this
demonstration we're gonna we're gonna
deploy an sed client that's
pre-configured to access sed running on
a control plane note now as we said cube
ATM puts a cubelet on that control plane
node and so we can use this direct
scheduling trick to actually attach to
that so what we're gonna do here is
we're going to direct schedule our pod
on the underlying node we're going to
dump at CD get secrets from it and do
some fun stuff so this is a pod manifest
and it's pretty verbose it's got a lot
of information in it but basically we're
telling that we're gonna create a kind
pod and then all the rest of this
represents the body of that post we're
describing the image that we want to use
for the sit for this we're just going to
use the same entity image that is
actually being used to run a CD inside
the cluster because it actually also has
the Etsy dica CLI command line tool
we're providing some environment
variables that are actually going to pre
configure a CD for us
so we don't actually have to pass a
bunch of command command-line arguments
to Etsy DK CTL and then we're also going
to mount in the certificates that we
need to be able to authenticate to Etsy
D using host paths a very powerful
capability of kubernetes and then we
also have host network and the reason
we're doing host network is because we
need to basically access that local host
address and so we need to be a 16 the
host network to be able to achieve that
let's go ahead and deploy that now I've
used this tool pretty extensively to
actually interact with to interact with
sed in a troubleshooting fashion like
finally to remove a member or understand
performance or see what the status of
public of the sed cluster is directly
but there's other stuff we could do so
other things we might be able to do as I
said we could maybe try to see if
there's any kind of interesting secrets
or credentials in there that might do
anything for us so let's take a look
well okay we've got all of the secrets
in there those are broken down by
namespace you'll see you know ku public
tube system coupe system as it sounds
like is the namespace that has system
access note that there is one
particularly interesting one in here
called cluster roll aggregation
controller cluster roll aggregation
controller in kubernetes by default to
this day allows complete administrative
access to the cluster to default or by
default so if we can get access to the
token for example for cluster roll
aggregation controller we can
authenticate with that token and have
complete control over the cluster so
let's do that
let's grab that token there's your token
if we use a tool called this came out in
kubernetes 1.13 poop CTL can't I - -
list this was the best thing as a pen
tester because before that happened we
would have to manually list out like do
every single call to say if we had
permissions to do it which was as you
perhaps imagine really annoying it took
forever but kubernetes made it so much
easier for us by just automating our
enumeration process for
so now we can just do that and see all
of the permissions that we have on my
cluster just like that so let's try that
with this Nokia fuel we got oh we have a
wild card we have access to everything
so we grab that token we can identikit
with it it's ours game over you'll find
that a lot of kubernetes clusters or
maybe not using TLS between the
components or that you can actually get
a hold of if they run cubelet directly
on a control point note that you have
that access to be able to do this stuff
so some time on takeaways here users can
create pods that have wild permissions
by default tube ADM schedules the
couplet directly on the underlying node
which you ought not to be runs it on
that node which you shouldn't do and as
an attacker if you can grab that token
for that particular role you can take it
over really easily and the other two
pieces of takeaway here I think they're
important is that people frequently
think that when you start exploring
kubernetes that you know being able to
to isolate nodes with labels or that
sort of thing
can be thought of as a security boundary
and that's clearly not the case right in
this case what we're doing is directly
scheduling a pod and that means if the
scheduler never sees it and because of
that you can't assume that the
schedulers ever are going to be a
security boundary the last one is that
namespace isolation is not enough if I
have access to the underlying host and
have access to that underlying host
regardless of what pods associated with
what namespaces are in to mitigate them
so we mentioned host path and we're
gonna go into host path a little farther
because host path is wild house path is
so wild that we named this talk after it
the kubernetes documentation describes
host path as there is a screenshot that
is from that site a powerful escape
hatch they're not kidding it is an
incredibly powerful escape hatch you can
escape all kinds of things with it and
there are so many options for what you
can do if you pin volume mount the host
and be able to have that kind of control
in relation to the host so we're gonna
keep exploring that because there's a
lot happening here and we had more
exploits here than we had space for so
you know use your imagination okay so
host pass it
amounts of file or directory' from the
host notes file system into your pod
when I first heard about his path I was
like what on earth like to me this is an
obvious attack tool right like what
would you even want that for does it
have like legitimate use cases and as it
turns out it does there are a few use
cases I'm bootstrapping a cluster you
know it's path to be able to get to the
stuff necessary tip gonna bring the
cluster back up and in the case of a
power outage another is a docker and
docker is a common use case people who
want to build containers inside of
kubernetes frequently think the cut
docker and docker is a good solution for
this there are other solutions for that
out there today but that's another one
of the use cases you're basically
mounting in the docker socket underneath
saccharin docker is very commonly used
and also a very good attack target in
and of itself which we'll talk about in
a bit so doctor in docker doctor and
docker I think that people think
sometimes that certain kinds of docker
attacks can only happen if the contain
if the container is privileged and
that's not actually the case it is
actually possible to via attacks on
docker and docker escalate privileges to
root on the underlying host from an
entirely unprivileged pod with all of
the security things on it the docker
socket lives at Marv run docker sake
it's not unique to docker other
container runtimes also have them
they'll be differently named and that is
a very valid like great target for us
especially if we can mount it with
something like host path so let's take a
look at what we can do so we're gonna
bring up a pod and we're going to show
you the manifest necessary to bring up a
pot it has access to the underlying
docker socket again this is a pretty
common use case inside of kubernetes and
I find a lot of people doing it and I
shake my head a lot when it happens but
we're gonna walk through this manifest
this is a little more complex than the
previous one up here at the top we have
an annotation that describes this asset
calm profile that docker will use when
it's starting up that this particular
container down below in the security
context inside of the spec of the pod
we are also specifying a user a group
and @fs group and this is an interesting
detail this is dynamic I can change that
you
or group ID before actually deploying
the pod if I'd made this a deployment I
could just edit the deployment and
change the UID and GID and all of these
pods would be started up with that new
UID and GID it's not defined inside the
container it's defined at docker at
runtime and it's being is basically
making use of the user name space in
containerization we described the
container we want to use and then we
actually use this house host path
mechanism to mount in the VAR run docker
socket we're also making sure that for
this specific container we're not
allowing privilege escalation Sonos to
do capabilities we're also dropping all
of the Linux capabilities we're not
using any system calls to the Linux
kernel that are governed by those
capabilities now as a penetration tester
if I see context with that like has all
of that security stuff on it it drops
all capabilities privilege escalation
isn't allowed it's not running his room
which is relatively rare in docker
there's a lot happening there and that
probably is going to make my day pretty
sad and you know I'm gonna have kind of
a hard time except that with the use of
host path the powerful escape hatch
maybe not maybe I'll have a little bit
of easier time let's see what happened
so the first thing we didn't deploy at
manifesto then we're going to be able to
see that the UID and GID are exactly
what we set in our security context the
second thing we're going to do is attach
to that kind of container again and take
a look at the definition of the docker
socket so when you install docker on a
Linux host generally and every install
that I've ever seen a docker
it will create a duck or group and it
will associate permissions with that
docker group for the doctor socket so
everything about it as long as you have
a post path you can actually figure out
what group ID that is and just define
your pod with that group ID and you have
full access to docker
without running as without running its
route and to the underlying node so
people do this because they want to be
able to use docker tools there again
other options out there for that stuff
it's a very common matter so we're gonna
go ahead and exec eunuch in and do a
docker run command to create an end your
next instance and then we can see that
in the underlying hosts that are running
into the next instance and then if we
just wanted to drop that from the
underlying host we could actually just
do that from that perspective right
there so okay
I thought cool is an operator nginx
alright fine so what can we do with this
is an attacker well if you can get if
you can mount the docker socket on the
underlying node as it turns out a fair
amount when I see this as a pen gesture
it's the best thing it's like you see
you hit the button on the k-cup maker
you like walk out of the room you hit
enter your route you come back the
coffee's done your day is done if it's
dim it's great so hostname it's ours and
that's it game over so in this example
the hostname that I want I want to show
that I'm actually on the machine links
I'm connected to that house right there
and if I touch a file in se in the NC
directory yeah on that host I can see it
and now I'm gonna exec into the running
container again scheduled directly on
this host and from there I'm gonna just
go ahead and well that was actually
supposed to remove the flag right I
guess I type with my demo
you know Democrats what can you do but
yeah I mean you have full access to
underlying file system at that point
right because I've just mounted in bar
the SC directory from the underlying
node into the container as host that's D
and so I have that full access the thing
that's important to remember about
docker duck or your big takeaway on
docker docker is that when you run the
docker command contextually it's being
run on the underlying node which means
that if you express stocker and docker
up to a container
you're letting something you're letting
that container do anything to the
underlying node anything at all
kernels all the way up so takeaways
doctor and doctor very powerful for
everybody and perhaps not the most
secure option when used this way
backers an authenticated API with full
access to the kernel we all want full
access to the kernel right I think we do
and how can you mitigate that we can
restrict the use of host path with
admission control and we'll show that
here in a minute so you may notice that
that was all docker there besides host
path which we were using a Nakuru
Nettie's manifest that was a container
attack that could work entirely
separately from a kubernetes context
it's important to remember that
kubernetes
a container Orchestrator basically
containers are what's happening in there
and so container attacks will still work
and then further it's important to
remember that containers are made of
Linux primitives and if you understand
Linux primitives and how to attack Linux
you understand how to attack containers
containers aren't magic they're just
made of Linux and so if we understand
how Linux works well under the hood we
can have really interesting
possibilities about how to attack
container technology and by extension
kubernetes so let's talk a little bit
about container parts what is a
container container is a single process
on a shared host and and the thing
that's interesting the way that I think
about containers when I was really kind
of getting into like what they actually
do is that if you look at every Linux
process in any process analytics kernel
you can see that it actually has is
associated with a set of these
namespaces that's every process on the
system all of them right the difference
between every process and a
containerized process is that those
namespaces are mapped to a specific ones
specific specific to that set of
processes so containerization in a way
is it's just a way of actually providing
isolation to the Linux process itself
but also that means that issues
regarding Linux in the way that it Maps
things like processes C groups and
namespaces can also be applicable to
attaining to attack in containers in
that context if you can you know attack
for example the way that it deals with C
groups and namespaces you can
potentially be able to break that
isolation the way that Linux treats the
filesystem is that all processes
namespaces all of those things
everything is a file
so can me maybe do something interesting
with that filesystem we'll find out in a
sec basically these primitives like
there aren't new it's not it's not magic
they seem like they're simple and
magical and automated but on the back
end it's the same old attack surface and
we can still do things that apply to
that attack surface capabilities system
calls you know ways that you can
manipulate those totally still apply and
the fact that container shares resources
with the host other containers and
everything else on there
means that the attack surface is very
wide because it's shared so if you can
compromise the kernel in a container you
then can compromise the kernel on the
underlying node and it works like that
and it adds an attacker that's really
exciting to me because I have so many
options there's so many moving parts in
different places that I can go to and I
don't know I think it's fun so let's
figure out well first let's look at a
diagram about that and looks like
through that real quick and then one
attack it so these containers that we
talked about before effectively are just
collections of all these individual
pieces right so a container might span
all of the different see groups or
namespaces that are associated with a
container and that represents sort of
the packaging of that container at
runtime when we think about an image of
a container that's being shipped around
it's really just a tarball
it's just a tarball that represents the
actual file system underneath but
everything is but at runtime just looks
exactly like this I know that as an
attacker I really leveled up when I
started to understand better like the
ways that different kinds of attacks
against the Linux kernel and userland
can can apply in this context the ways
that those interact with each other in a
container context and outside of it and
the way that those interact
being able to have a deep understanding
of this system really does help in being
able to attack it as well as being able
to operate it so here's an interesting
thing we might be able to do he's a
tweet from Duffy a little while ago when
we were first working on this talk so
this is a tweet I put up after seeing
another example of this I thought it was
actually pretty smart what's actually
happening here is that we're using cue
kettle to run a container based on the
Alpine image and we're using NS enter
inside of that container to enter the
amount name space of the first process
on the underlying node and we're doing
that because you can see in the
specification it says host pid' true
that means that when I started this
container I gave it access to the entire
pig name space of the underlying host
but you also notice that I'm not giving
away a like host path or any of that
stuff just host pig and I'm gonna get a
privileged context which is also super
powerful let's play with it yeah let's
take a look
so first I'm going to show you the
manifest that's actually going to be
doing this I'm gonna deploy as it
manifested it's just described the same
way as actually in the tweet right I
have my NS enter command I'm what mount
filesystem to actually mount into and
then I'm running a command inside of
that mounted filesystem been sleep for
99 days I'm gonna use the standard bog
standard Alpine 3.7 image for this and I
have my hosts head set true and
privilege set to true as well let's go
ahead and apply this manifests and this
is to help for NS enter and I kinda want
to just point it out that the it's
really an interesting thing this is an
incredible tool and essentially lets us
enter into any of the parts of a
container right we're talking about a
container being a sum of all of its
parts the mountain namespace the pit
namespace the network namespace all of
those individual pieces of containers
just a collection of all those bits and
a sensor lets me in to enter into each
any any particular part of one so I've
used NS enter in my work to actually
kind of solve the mystery of how a thing
is actually configured in this example
I'm gonna grab a pit of our running
nginx process on a particular hose so
I'm gonna exact into my container where
it's been scheduled and take a look at
for nginx pits and I can see that I have
a few running I'm just gonna grab that
pit ID or the process ID and I'm going
to enter into the network names face of
that process ID now the neat thing about
Ana Center is that literally I just have
to tell if the target pit - t and then
the pit ID and then which namespace or
which part of the container I want me to
append you in this case it's a
networking one and I can see in my case
that this particular nginx instances is
is bound on port 80 and that's what I
was trying to figure out right I was
expecting to be bound on 443 which is
why it was not working for me you can
also do things like mounted to the
namespace the the mounting space and
take a look at configuration files and
that sort of stuff this all works
because every process has a proc /p
process ID NS directory and that
actually describes a map for that
their process and this is what we were
referring to before so if I look at the
process tree for this one I could see
that this running inside of a container
these are the maps for the C group IPC
mount names Network kid and user and UTS
namespaces these are mapped to these
specific names faces if I SSH in I would
see that they be mapped to a different
set of namespaces what you're actually
identified as a default set for that the
Linux kernel is going to use for that
user gland but if you're looking for a
way to visualize what a container is
this is it this is what makes up a
container this this LS directory right
here I want to emphasize how incredibly
powerful it is to be able to interact
with the different parts of the
container without necessarily having the
eggs back into a shell because let me
tell you that as a pen tester there is
no better way to make my day really
annoying than to create a container that
has no shell in it really annoying and
if you can't interact with that this is
that you still can and if you can
interact with all of the different
individual like you know namespaces and
all of these things there's so much
control that you can have over it it's
pretty sweet but what else could we do
could we do anything perhaps to the
underlying node could we escalate
privileges gain any kind of control I
don't know let's find out so we're not
even using host PAP here but we can
still take over the underlying note of
it so again because I have a data center
and I have access to that host pin
namespace I can just attach to all of
the namespaces that make up that
particular process and we run a bash
shell and so I'm picking pit one because
the init system it's always going to be
there and I'm running bash and so at
this point I have a root on the actual
underlying host and the center is
incredibly powerful sorry okay
so some takeaways we can take from this
edit Center is pretty amazing both for
operators and for attackers
host path is not the only kind of thing
that you need to watch out for
you should also restrict the use of host
pit if you're trying to harden your own
containers and you should restrict the
use of privileged containers because
just makes my life way too easy yeah one
other part of that is that privilege
containers actually have a very very
escalated privilege you can do anything
with any part of the container you can
create new containers you can do all of
that stuff with privileged access so
when you when you do docker run - -
privilege it's super scary there's
another one where you can actually limit
to Linux capabilities like sysadmin but
that one but that one is actually still
pretty risky although it still only
provides like read-only read-only access
to all of those things there are really
fun container escapes that involve the
Seidman capability though so that's the
thing to keep an out for so is there any
way that we can like MIDI mitigate
against attacks like this or anything
like that yes we can like admission
control is really like the only
defensible space within kubernetes and
what that does is it represents an
implementation at the API server just as
we discussed when we were talking about
all the components admission control
gives us the ability to validate or
mutate objects and and determine whether
or not we will allow them in this is
beyond authorization and authentication
this is about now that we've seen the
manifest we've gotten past all of those
things in is that manifest requesting
access to host pit or host path or any
of those things now there is a
first-class implementation of that
within kubernetes right now that's
called pod security policies and we can
show you that so as an attacker a couple
of things to note here
one this is actually fairly rare in the
wild
despite the fact that it's the most
powerful way that you can harden a
kubernetes cluster many people don't use
it maybe more commonly than not in a lot
of cases because the UX is really hard
people don't like it it's sort of
difficult and people have a hard time
with it that doesn't mean that they
shouldn't try because it makes by
default if you don't push it
put admission control on it all of these
attacks are just viable and great for me
bad for perhaps the people who are
trying to operate them or defend them
the other thing I wanted to do as an
attacker is mutating admission control
is really interesting if anyone is
familiar with LD preload and how that
can work in a linux context LD preload
is very useful for both sysadmin and
four attackers because it allows you to
turn things into other things and if you
have the ability to make any call into
any other call or for example just
dictate that this is going to be your
you ID or your G ID there's all kinds of
interesting possibilities there we don't
really have time to cover them all and I
wish we did and maybe that's a future
talk because it's really awesome but
worth looking into
so anyway hide security policies let's
take a look
we demonstate one of those one thing I
do want to say is that we're talking
about like mutating objects if we think
about it we've already shown an example
of that when we specified the UID and
GID of that particular part of the
security context or was being told we
were actually going to mutate that
object at runtime to make sure that
we're using that username and group ID
but admission control can do that to all
of the things so I could actually use
this tool to do something like inject
proxy variables if I'm in a highly
regulated environment and I can inject
those proxy variables to all of the pods
within a given namespace using things
like pod preset within cabrini this or
other kinds of environment variables
that might be interesting to me as an
attacker yeah pod security policies when
I'm like implemented well can make my
life as an attacker really hard like
I'll run all the same attacks that we
were running during this talk and
nothing will work and it will be really
frustrating let's maybe see that happen
so we're gonna run the same ones again
against one with a good pipe security
policy but we'll look at the mostly
first so this cluster I've actually
turned up a couple of different pod
security policies and we can look at
them there's one that's called
permissive and the one that's called
restrictive probably not super
imaginative but you get the idea
this permissive one really does actually
just give access to everything but the
neat thing about looking at the output
here is that we can see some of the
things that we can actually restrict or
constrain with odd security policies so
like first class citizen is like whether
to allow privileged at all or whether to
allow privilege escalation from within a
container all of what capabilities to
add what Linux capabilities to add or
which to drop by default are required to
be dropped before the container will be
allowed admittance into the cluster you
can also limit the number of the types
of volumes and that sort of stuff
let's go down here to the restrict
and we can see that you know some of
these fields actually filled out so in
our case we're gonna not allow
privileged containers again in the
restrictive model we're going to allow
any capability which we probably should
not do we're also going to only allow
specific volume types so config map
downward API these are all types of
volumes that you can use within
kubernetes and attach to your running
processes we're not going to allow host
network we're not going to allow host
pit host IPC this isn't the most
restrictive paas security policy but you
can see kind of the power of what we can
do here
so running the same attacks against this
policy what happens so let's go ahead
and rerun the attack I'll get the sed
client llamo that we saw we're gonna run
this as a different user that doesn't
have access to that administer to that
permissive policy now we get a pretty
useful error message back you know so if
you're a developer and operator using
kubernetes and you try to and you bounce
against a restrictive policy like this
it's gonna come back with good
information telling you that the pod
security policy does not allow host
network it does not allow host path and
so this it's not just gonna say no and
then walk away you're actually gonna get
some feedback from it as an attacker the
first time I ran across this error
message though I did not find it very
clear because it was like unable to
validate any plot security policy well
if it doesn't have a plot security
policy what's your problem and it
actually means that there is a flood
security policy and that it isn't
allowing you which is not to me very
clearly worded so this one also is
denied right there's a darker and darker
demonstration that we provided is also
denied but in this case is because of
host path and also because we didn't
specify a SATCOM profile now even though
we have a restrictive pod security
policy in place it doesn't mean that you
can't do anything sometimes it may feel
that way as a user and that's part of
the user experience kind of problem with
pod security policies today I'm making
this look really simple but it's
actually relatively complex and figuring
out how the user experience works but
you know get involved if you're curious
about it it makes illegitimate use cases
harder it makes would you it doesn't
necessarily be that too legit use cases
so in our case I was just going to
redeploy that nginx deployment again
using that that a that user that doesn't
have access
to the permissive and I can do things
like scale and create deployments and
all about stuff continues to work I can
see the sponsoring yeah so I'm not gonna
do an attack demo here because it
actually was just maybe exam so quit 5
security policies on your clusters it
can help keep people like me out
so takeaways there pipe security
policies give you a lot of control over
what you're allowed to do in a pod and
what you're not allowing others to do in
your pod it's hard to adopt as I said
it's difficult to adopt mainly because
of the way that you associate pod
security policies with users or
controllers there's a lot of regularly
great media including on the tgia i/o
website to talk about how that works
so does admission control like fix
everything
not quite there's actually static pod
mechanism and static pods are manifest
that sit on disk near the qubit agent
itself and the qubit is actually
interesting this the static pod
mechanism is interesting because it's
generally used for things like
bootstrapping the cluster itself but
that stack static pod manifest that sits
on disk will be entirely governed by the
cubelet so you would if the qubit never
talks to an API server it will bring up
the pods to find in those files and it
will run them and make sure that they
continue to stay a they continue to stay
running and then an opponent ever it's
not susceptible to admission control at
all it's not susceptible to admission
control at all because it's the highest
priority it it executes before admission
control even applies and because it's
designed to be you know continually
self-healing that also means that as an
attacker maybe I could do something like
persistence well that actually doesn't
actually get affected by admission
control I can put my evil pod up there
it'll work admission control will never
complain and it will keep coming up when
things get spun down and if you think
about it like direct scheduling that we
saw from the beginning can you direct
schedule a static pod and completely
bypass the scheduler in controller
manager you have host pass without
admission control you absolutely can so
that seems like a pretty powerful attack
tool if I can like put something there
that's going to be persistent going to
bypass thing
that are trying to prevent me from doing
that and are going to bypass Oh Mission
Control - yep and they're the highest
priority as you said so if you put a
manifest down on disk it will actually
make room for that manifest if there's
pods already on the node it'll kick them
out to make room for that pod manifest
fascinating is there any way to stop
that so again this is going back to the
term default so qubit by default doesn't
have that directory defined which means
that there's no way to actually exploit
this by default with the qubit however
in cube ATM for example the default that
cube ATM uses for all all nodes is
actually to associate a directory with
that so if you know what that directory
is you could place it there and so it
doesn't fix everything what helps so
coming full circle we're really not
trying to scare you here it isn't that
kubernetes is like large and complex and
impossible although it is certainly very
large and complex it's powerful it
allows you to do a lot and as well as
being able to allow you to do a lot at
scale it allows you to make a lot of
mistakes at scale it miss configurations
and not putting admission control on
assuming that kubernetes is secure by
default and developing as such just
means that it's easier for me as an
attacker to be able to exploit it so
it's big it's complex but it is actually
possible for the most part to be able to
secure it it's possible to secure your
clusters via admission control and it's
possible to work to make the kubernetes
project itself more secure that's right
so how can we do that you can get
involved career this is an open source
project and there are a lot of people
who are involved in just working in
different special interest groups or
groups but with focus on particular
areas I'll put a link in here in frere
okay so kubernetes is a really wonderful
friendly welcoming community that is
really good to its contributors and
tends to be very full of happy
developers who don't think like security
people I think some of its design
decisions could perhaps you know you
could think about it in that light so
and what that also means is that
kubernetes really needs to have
contributors who can think like
attackers it really helps a lot because
people are open to it
they don't necessarily know how to do
that so we want to encourage security
minded folks to come get involved in the
open source project if you do research
on kubernetes there is vulnerability
disclosure info leaked on the slide a
bug bounty program I think is coming
down the pike eventually and this week
like yesterday
anyway there was a third-party code
audit and there were a lot of
interesting findings coming out of there
that are most certainly worth reading
that are also linked on this slide I
just realized it's - on that slide
though if you do want to see the kids
audit which is that third party and the
result of that audit it's a cage - audit
okay it's - and yeah come get involved
and get in touch with us I'm on
kubernetes lacus cold water I'm miss
Amelia Lyon and yeah we'd love to help
so just send that here are the black hat
soundbites the takeaways that we want
you to have from this check your
assumptions kubernetes is not secured by
default green use is a complex system
with lots of moving parts and it's going
to take some configuration to action to
actually get that thing up and running
but go ahead
but understanding well how the system
works on a deep level can help you both
as an operator and as an attacker and it
is possible to make cooper days more
secure but you do have to put in that
work
so put admission control on your
clusters come get involved in the
project with us then we have our
resources up in the resources link so if
you want to see how I went about doing
the demos or explore any of that stuff
you can visit that URL for more
information we want to thank all of you
for coming this has been amazing and
yeah thank you very much