you're an Islander FG and welcome to
awoke hiring won't save us an actionable
approach to diversity hiring and
retention with Becca Lynch while you're
here today please stop by the business
hall in Mandalay Bay
Oceanside and shoreline ballrooms the
blackhat Arsenal is also located there
if you'll please take a moment to go
ahead and silence your phones for us
please and with that I'm going to give
you a Becca Lynch if you can give us a
round of applause to get started thanks
for being here bright and early today -
you made it we're here to talk about
diversity specifically gender diversity
within our field like you said my name
is Becca and I'm here from duo security
out of Ann Arbor we're part of Cisco I
also my bachelor's degree in computer
science from the University of Michigan
and I'm currently a master's student in
data science with the University of
Illinois so we're here to talk about
diversity specifically gender diversity
but I want to give a couple caveats and
what this talk is not going to be about
right this is not a talk about teaching
girls to code we're not gonna get into
how boys play with Legos and girls play
with Barbies this is a perfectly fine
conversation to have but it's beside the
point and we're gonna see why we're also
really not going to talk about why you
should hire more women and this might
seem counterintuitive but we're gonna
see that hiring alone is not the full
story right and also this is not going
to be 25 minutes of blame and shame I'm
hoping that by the end of this you'll
all have an understanding of the breadth
of the issue at hand as well as clear
actionable steps you can take to make
our industry a better place and one last
caveat this is a talk about gender
diversity right so that means we're not
even going to be touching on issues of
racial disparities LGBT representation
and even within gender diversity we
can't really even have a conversation
about non-binary and transgender people
because there isn't even data on that
and that in and of itself is a big
problem so we talked about diversity
when we talk about diversity hiring
we're usually talking about one moment
and that's the moment of making a higher
when companies say they have diversity
initiatives they're talking about hiring
more people right hitting some quota
bringing up some numbers this isn't the
full story and it's actually not solving
much of anything right for starters it's
really hard to build a diverse workforce
if we don't have the right building
blocks the rate of women graduating with
degrees in computer science has been
declining since the 80s on the flip side
we can't have a conversation about
hiring if we're not going to talk about
attrition right women in our fields exit
within 10 years at twice the rate of men
and there all kinds of theories about
why right we've seen the manifestos
we've heard conversations about
intrinsic ability and biology and I'm
here to tell you for lack of a better
word it's all complete bullshit we're
gonna see why but first let's talk about
your team right there was a study with
1,400 participants across 21 different
companies looking at how gender balance
impacted the productivity of teams and
we found that overall the closer that a
team was to 50/50 gender balance the
more likely they were gonna be to
experiment and innovate to share
knowledge among their team members and
most importantly complete tasks on time
right this matters we hear this cliche a
lot about diversity and how having a
diverse team gives you diversity of
thought what does this actually mean
specifically what does it mean for us in
security we talk a lot about risk here
right there was a meta-analysis of 115
studies all of which looking at how
gender affected how people perceive risk
found across the board women perceive
risks as higher than men in any given
situation they were more likely to
enumerate specific risks regardless of
the situation even more interestingly
white men on average perceived risk than
lower than any other demographic group
surveyed right the more homogenous our
teams are the more similar we're going
to think and this matters when we're
talking about really complex problems
talk about the money a study found last
year that companies within the top
quartile for gender diversity we're
gonna be 15% more likely to have returns
above the industry medians more over
turnover
is really expensive right study from the
Kapoor Center for social impact last
year found that unfairness was cited as
the number one reason for leaving tech
jobs 37% of people who left their tech
job said that they left because of
unfair treatment it was the main factor
in their decision of those who left due
to unfairness 35% were less likely to
recommend the company as a good place to
work
and 25% less likely to recommend the
product itself this is personal but what
does this have to do with diversity the
study broke up unfairness into several
key behaviors and these are five of them
here we see rudeness
and condescension poor management others
taking credit for your work your
co-workers being less educated and
assumptions being made about your skill
level and they found that every single
one of these instances women were
significantly more likely to have these
experiences working in tech right
regardless of our initiatives regardless
of our quotas these are the lived
experiences of people in our industry
every day and it's really expensive this
study from their most conservative
estimate said that the annual cost due
to turnover related to unfairness at
tech companies alone annually 16 billion
dollars because we don't know how to
treat each other right we're gonna din't
we're gonna get into what this looks
like in day to day interactions how we
can go about approaching it what this
really means but first I want to take it
back to building the workforce right how
do we build a diverse team and this is
kind of commonly referred to as the
pipeline problem right well there just
start women to hire there's no women
applying there's nothing I can do it
turns out there is a lot you can do and
it also turns out that it was not always
this way the percent of women graduating
with computer science degrees peaked in
1984 at 37% it's been decreasing ever
since for the last several years it's
been stagnant at just about 18%
nationally and we're one of the only
disciplines to see this decline right
degrees like mechanical biomedical
environmental civil engineering have all
seen increases in the rate of women
graduating with these degrees I want to
take a look at my alma mater in
particular there's a really popular
computer science course introduction to
programming it has about a thousand
students every single semester 40% of
them were women in 2016 the program
overall was only 21% women including
this massive course graduation rate was
even lower what's happening where are
they going so there was a longitudinal
study that looked at women from the
moment that they entered a computer
science program to the moment they
graduated whether or not they stayed
right it found that the attrition level
was the highest between the first and
second year and this makes sense right
this is when people figure out what they
like what they don't like but this
actually wasn't the case the majority of
women leaving programs in computer
science were leaving because they didn't
feel confident in themselves they cited
low confidence is the main reason and
they cited low confidence regardless of
their actual skill levels and abilities
whether they were actually performing at
the same level of their peers the same
study maybe unsurprisingly found that
men and women entering these programs
had very different levels of prior
experience but this didn't really matter
in fact they found that prior experience
was not a significant predictor of
success in a four-year program it didn't
matter so what do we do there was one
study a few years back that proposed a
solution and they said well men and
women maybe they just learned
differently maybe we should teach them
differently maybe we'll have one class
for the boys
and they're gonna learn programming and
all that boring stuff great and then the
girls are gonna have a class where they
learn how to program apps for shopping
this did not work it increased levels of
isolation it actually increased the rate
of attrition
within the program turns out people
don't like to feel different they don't
like to feel isolated so what do we do I
want to look at one institution in
particular that's doing a lot of things
right Carnegie Mellon has taken a very
intentional approach to retaining and
keeping really smart passionate young
women who are interested in the field
and their approach has three key points
building a community
within the University making sure that
anyone who's ready to work hard has
people in their corner has people that
they can go to and being intentional
about building this community
emphasizing that there is no experience
necessary but it is not a barrier to
success in this program and that's
proven and lasts providing visibility
into different pathways in the field
showing young women this is what success
looks like these are role models that
you can have this is who you can be and
this industry is for you so what does
this actually look like they have an
organization called women at SES school
in computer science
it looks like outreach that promotes the
different pathways into the field
including security looks like publishing
interviews with successful women within
the field connecting students with
alumni that are successful in their
careers opportunities in the community
like workshops panels outreach events
internal conferences where women in the
program can come together and talk about
their work corporate sponsorships and
interviews with faculty to show that
there's more than one way to be
successful in this industry and here are
the people who are making that possible
and the results speak for themselves in
eight years Carnegie Mellon saw the
percent of women enrolling in their
computer science program go from 25% to
50% 50% in just three years
the percent of women graduating with
computer science degrees rose by 7
percent this doesn't sound like a whole
lot right 7 percent in just three years
when you consider that the national
average only rose by 0.5% in those same
three years they're doing something
right the caveat here is that this only
works if all of us show up right when we
participate in our community when we
show up for one another we're sending a
message to everyone who's ready to work
hard regardless of their gender that
this industry is for everyone so we've
solved it right now we're gonna hire an
amazing workforce they're gonna be great
we're gonna encourage women and tech
it's gonna be amazing
turns out we cannot have a conversation
about diversity hiring if we're not
going to have a conversation about the
rate at which women are leaving our
industry so we see here from a study of
thirteen thousand men and women in both
stem and non-stem jobs this is the
survival rate for women depending on
their industry seen on stem in the blue
stem in the yellow and the survival rate
in the industry means what percent of
women remained in the industry over the
tenure of their career not at their job
not at their company the industry itself
right non-stem role saw a retention rate
of about 90 percent over 20 years for
stem it was just below 40 percent the
steepest cutoff was at ten years where
they saw an attrition rate of forty one
percent forty one percent of women who
pursued education who pursued training
who entered the field left after ten
years this is double the rate of their
male colleagues so what's happening why
are they leaving the same survey found
that 82 percent of them said that they
love their work women in stem they love
their work 100 percent found it
intellectually challenging stimulating
and interesting so why leave are they
going of the women in stem who left 77
percent said that they cited either
extreme pressure or a hostile macho
culture it's their reason for leaving
and I don't know about you my workplace
does not exactly look like the WWE right
there's no one lifting weights at their
desk you're pounding protein shakes so
what's so macho about tech what does
this mean what's happening and it turns
out it's really subtle it gets into how
we interact with one another on a day to
day basis it gets into how do we treat
each other how do we talk to one another
small things add up and turn out to make
a really big difference we're gonna talk
first about implicit bias what does this
look like what does it mean how can we
approach it effectively so implicit bias
is you can maybe gather from the name
it's not explicit it's implicit which
means it's not sexism or racism it's
unconscious products of learned behavior
things that are ingrained in who we are
we all have it right it's really
difficult to acknowledge it's not
intentional and this is key it's not
malicious it's ingrained and who we are
it's very difficult to over
and it's developed simply by virtue of
living in the world that we live in and
lastly it's not fixed by blame and shame
it's not fixed through lecturing and
calling out one another right it's fixed
through empathetic conversations and
thoughtful productive dialogues right
and I'm not a psychologist I cannot
teach you how to have empathy but we're
going to go over a few examples of what
this might look like so in action right
it's small things it's little things
like using male pronouns to describe a
male or a potential client or a
potential new hire right how many of you
have done this I have done this I do
this all the time
crediting an idea to someone else this
is super easy to do when we can't
acknowledge how our bias influences our
own decisions under estimating others
abilities and making assumptions about
their roles this is like when I new hire
came up to me at an event and asked if I
worked in marketing it's not intentional
he didn't mean to be mean about it right
but it matters think back to this graph
the behaviors that people experienced
that caused them to leave their industry
to leave their jobs in tech rudeness
condescension Mis crediting work
understanding under estimating someone's
abilities right all our lived
experiences of bias all proven to drive
talented people away from the field and
all experience significantly more by
women than by men so what does this look
like we're gonna imagine a scenario
you've gone out to lunch with one of
your co-workers and you start to discuss
a new colleague on your team your
co-worker says something like this she
seems kind of aggressive all right this
is a loaded statement we're not even
gonna get into what this really means
the gender dynamics of all this because
it's kind of irrelevant the key here is
to maintain assumptions of positive
intent right this does not mean
lecturing or calling out your colleague
putting them on the defensive and giving
them the ability to shut down the
conversation right no I'm not sexist why
would you say that you want to leave
room for a dialogue assume positive
intent this is a key part of our culture
a duo where I work what does this look
like it means asking questions right
getting them to nail down specific
actions right what makes you say that
this gives them room to point out
specific things that cause them to feel
the way that they feel and you might
find that in having this conversation
they'll reevaluate their own perspective
same scenario different colleague says
something like this she's very
articulate
both of these are things that I've heard
about women that I work with she's very
articulate and face value this seems
like it's kind of maybe supposed to be a
compliment right she's articulate what
does this mean means she can speak in
sentences it's kind of a given right how
do we have a conversation about this
that doesn't put our colleagues on the
defensive this is a point where private
feedback is going to be key we don't
want to give them room to end the
conversation similarly frame the
feedback within the context of your own
perception feel that by saying that you
might imply that you assumed otherwise
this is wordy you don't have to say it
like this the key is that you're framing
it within the context of your own
emotions about her experience about your
co-workers experience this isn't really
accusatory and what it does is it
doesn't give them room to make excuses
well that's not what I meant it's
irrelevant this is how someone perceived
it and that matters another threat to
retention of women in tech particularly
as a Singh called stereotype threat so
anytime that you are an underrepresented
group within some larger organization
some larger field right there are
typically negative stereotypes about
your performance your abilities and
these affect us right stereotype threat
is the fear that one will fall into
existing negative stereotypes about
yourself about your people
it increases anxiety and it's been
proven to decrease productivity and
performance right and this is really
hard to address how do we change how
people feel about themselves right it
can start with increasing the visibility
of men and women from different
backgrounds within all levels of your
organization if you can write
highlighting the talent that you have
showing people here is someone who is
successful here is someone who has made
it
here's proof that you can - and you can
do it here convey your high value of
diversity right we've seen the proven
benefits of having a diversity
show that this is something that you
believe in and that you're committed to
and be vocal about it convey high
standards and frame feedback within the
context of these high standards this
seems counterintuitive right we're
talking about people who underestimate
themselves right we don't want to make
that works
this means framing feedback within the
context of your own high standards it's
not I have high standards and you're not
going to live up to them it's I have
high standards and that's why I hired
you
that's why I want to work with you
that's why I know that you can do the
job and last one of the most proven
impactful methods of retaining smart
women in your organization is
sponsorship it's similar to mentorship
there are a few key differences a mentor
is someone who provides tips and advice
about your day to day a sponsor is
someone who provides public and private
advocacy for you within the organization
a mentor is going to be someone who
increases your confidence your
competence these are all great things
right a sponsor is someone who enables
your career advancement and visibility
within the organization they're gonna
make sure you're working on the right
work and that your work is seen by the
right people and last a mentorship is a
relationship that's generally formed by
the request of the mentee or through
some formal program like an internship
and onboarding process things like that
sponsorship is a relationship that's
formed by the efforts of the sponsor
right this is someone who goes out of
their way to take organic effective
actions to form a relationship to stand
up for their co-workers what does this
look like an action the mentor might be
someone who goes to their colleague and
says I know you should work on X and
I'll help you get set up I am this
project I'm gonna help you do it a
mentor is going to be someone with
connections they're gonna go to their
peers they're gonna go to people above
them and say I hear you have a project I
know someone who would be great and
here's why I hear you want to send
people to blackhat you should send this
person
here's why I here you want someone to
speak at the next team meeting I know
who should do it right there in your
corner and this is proven to work the
value speaks for itself when we see data
on sponsored versus unspun surd women
sponsored women were more likely to
report a satisfactory pace and
promotions they were more likely to ask
for high-visibility work and perhaps
most strikingly mothers who were
sponsored were over 25% more likely to
stay with their employer than mothers
who are unspun surd this makes sense
right you know you have someone that's
gonna go to bat for you it's gonna
promote your work it's gonna connect you
to the right people so we've covered a
lot of ground right this is a huge
complicated problem but hopefully now
you see that this is more than hiring
this is more than the pipeline right
this comes down to how we treat each
other and how the things we say impact
everyone all right but it's not hopeless
there's a lot that you can do starts
with getting involved at a local
university college programs that support
and encourage women and diversity at all
levels participating in local workshops
that promote diversity not only is this
great for visibility for young women
it's also kind of selfish you want to
hire some really great people within
your organization it means visibly
supporting diversity initiatives and
being a spokesperson being vocal about
the proven benefits of a diverse team
we've seen that it works recognizing and
addressing your own bias in your work
environment being willing to think
inward before you speak being willing to
have tough conversations with your
colleagues being willing to understand
how the things we say and do impact the
people that we work with and last
advocating and supporting one another
through efforts like sponsorship right
going to bat for our colleagues making
sure that everyone knows that they have
people in their corner and that women
who want to come to this industry have
space to stay and succeed and they have
that space with you this is a really
complicated problem but the solutions
are simple they come down to empathy to
understanding and just showing up for
one another
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]