well good afternoon
all right all right all right I know
it's five o'clock it's late most people
are like ready to get to food but you
all are like interested in hearing about
SCA or maybe you saw my tweet and you
want to hear about some other topics but
welcome aboard good to have you here one
way or the other so let's dive in what
what am I even talking about that tweet
if you didn't see it
the prime Museum followed me on Twitter
but for those of you who do you know
that I am working on my Pilot's
certificate
um this was a lifelong dream of mine
something I started on
the beginning of this year I guess
um
as part of that as things would work out
I ended up actually buying an airplane
now
y'all probably did not come here to hear
about airplanes
but trust me we'll get there in a minute
so let's talk about airplanes for a
second because
airplane safety and even just aircraft
operations there are there are things
that we can learn from that and things
that kind of draw parallels to what we
really should be looking at when we
start thinking about application
security is specifically open source
security so let me start to draw that
parallel for you for those of you that
have never flown a plane before
you may have been on a commercial flight
at one point where you heard maybe
you're being delayed for a few minutes
on the ground you heard them talking
maybe they made an announcement they
were talking about they had to get the
weight right
so that's the thing in aviation when you
fly a little plane like this it becomes
really really really important how much
weight is in the plane and how is that
weight distributed across the plane
some other things are really important
when you're flying an airplane is
knowing all of the equipment that is on
that plane
so one of the things that you get when
you buy an airplane is you get you know
essentially you know we call it a
pilot's operating handbook you also you
might think of it like an owner's manual
right one of the things in there is this
equipment list
this is every piece of equipment that is
installed in that airplane
and it comes in that POA is that pile is
operating a handbook now there's two
reasons they give this to you first is
for that weight and balance I was
talking about so you can you see here
kind of towards the end and actually all
along they're giving you different data
I know it's like tiny you can't really
read it but all the data you see in the
right hand Columns of each of those
pages talks about what does this thing
weigh and where is it in relation to the
center of gravity of the aircraft
all so we can get the balance right so
the plane flies correctly so we don't
crash into Terrain
the other thing this gives you is it
gives you an inventory of all of the
equipment that's installed because when
you're dealing with what the FAA calls a
certificated airplane this is an
airplane that has all components and
everything else has been approved by the
FAA not just individually but in their
combined State together inside that
aircraft
so we track all this
now that's what it looks like for a
little plane like mine
but then there's big planes like this
737 Max eight yes that's 737 Max 8 right
I get it we'll come back to that later
but that same list that you saw there
they produced the same list for these
planes that same balance and weight data
they have for these planes because it's
just as critical when we're talking
about a large commercial aircraft as it
is when we're talking about that small
aircraft now you saw the one from mines
about six pages long
the 737 Max 8 it's 155 pages long I know
because I looked it up last night
um but this is legitimate information
but it's all information that the FAA
requires in order to understand
everything that's installed in these
aircrafts so that when things go wrong
we can understand why
but also of course to try to make sure
that things don't go wrong in the first
place if a component has a known failure
that's caused crashes we'll talk about
that in a minute
we can look that up we know what planes
they're installed in
so now are you starting to see why maybe
this has something to do with our open
source software and why we would care
about this sort of thing with
application security
so that's where we're headed now uh for
those of you that don't know me really
quick intro first of all again my name
is Alyssa Miller
and first and foremost I'm a hacker and
a researcher been a hacker my whole life
I bought my first computer when I was 12
I broke into Prodigy so half of the room
hopefully at least understands what I'm
talking about there's some folks in here
who have no idea what Prodigy is but
that's okay so it was a dial-up service
that you could dial to before we had the
internet
um but that that's you know that's kind
of my personality from the very
beginning of my life um I've always been
that that type of person who is really
curious I like to break things like to
take my toys take them apart figure out
how they work
take my parents VCR take that apart do
you even know wait you guys know what a
VCR is at least right
um I've update your analogies all right
so
you know but I did that you know most of
my parents sugar in sometimes when some
of their Electronics were in pieces on
the living room floor but that's you
know that's just kind of my thing
uh if you looked at the website you saw
it lists me as a biso for s p Global
yeah that not anymore
um this is a kind of recent thing and I
think it's actually my fault I think I
didn't actually send over the update I
am now the CSO at a company called epic
Global so we are a global organization
as the name would imply we do legally
Discovery Services things like that
I'm an author and a blogger really
quickly just I don't really blog very
often
my website's kind of out of date but I
am an author I did recently release a
book uh we can talk about that
afterwards
um actually there's two copies of it I
think available in the auction too so
and then finally here's why I care about
all this I'm a former software developer
all right so I've been in the shoes of
software Dev
I've worked in application development
organizations most of my career in some
way shape or former another even in
consultancy I've always kind of been
focused on appsec because that's my
roots that's where I came from
so
that's why I'm up here talking about
application security because it's
something near and dear to my heart
so let's talk about how we develop
software
25 years ago when I started as a
software developer I just really dated
myself again
um
I should have a pool running y'all could
guess how old I am but uh when I was a
software developer if you had an
application that was 800 000 lines of
code that meant your developers in your
organization wrote 800 000 lines of code
it ain't that way anymore
because we have these cool open source
community in these package managers that
we can leverage to pull code from the
open source community so now I write an
application it might be 80 000 lines of
code that I've written but the entire
application turns out to be hundreds of
thousands of lines so for instance we
just we use things like these package
managers to say Hey you know go grab
this package that does this common task
go grab this package of this common task
and what's really cool about this is not
only then do I have this manifest like
you see here that says hey here's all
the dependencies from the open source
community that I want my package manager
Maven to go grab and include in my
software because I call different
components of it
but now each of those packages has its
own dependencies oh and then those
dependencies have more dependencies of
their own and in those dependencies have
more dependencies of Their Own
now try and go figure out how much open
source you have in your software that 80
000 lines I wrote turns into 800 000
lines right this is the story of modern
development
it is the best and worst case scenario
from a development perspective it's what
we've we preached way back when I was a
developer it was all about code reuse
and we we started trying to create you
know we had dlls that you know you could
use that and you could create classes
and you share those dlls amongst
different software you could leverage
all that well now we've got open source
so somebody creates something really
really cool like maybe something that
writes logs
foreshadowing that's what that is
and we can all use it
and we go because why should I have to
write my own logging mechanism somebody
already wrote all that and instead we
can all just contribute to it we can all
make it really good and make it really
cool and because everybody's looking at
it it makes it more secure right
the silence scares me because it should
be a hell no but we'll get there so
that's the story of modern day
development
so what could possibly go
I mean this is breathe everybody's
looking everybody's in there they can
make code that the maintainers you know
what if they if they get a pull request
they still have the opportunity to
review that and they can make sure that
it codes right so clearly everything
that we're going to use from the open
source Community is going to be awesome
it's going to be great because it's gone
through all this and now we've got
people like GitHub are putting in you
know different code scanners and all
that in into their you know into repos
and everything else this is awesome
we're going to secure that stuff
yeah I'm going back there okay I know it
was like five years ago Alyssa
God stop talking about Equifax we get it
but Equifax is still one of the one of
the perfect examples of
the challenges of Open Source
dependencies
because if you don't know what happened
at Equifax with their breach
epic epic reach okay I mean this was
this was one of the big ones
we have this vulnerability and struts
you know cve 2017
5638 I always forget
we knew about it we knew about it for
quite a while
what facts knew about it they went on
they fixed it in a whole lot of places
but they didn't know every place they
had it and this was a story with a lot
of people it wasn't just Equifax is just
the ones who ultimately fell victim to
that vulnerability because it was
sitting in software in a spot they
didn't know about now we can argue all
day and I know their CEO their ciso got
blasted for the response to this and
let's not get into those details
but
this happens every day
it's going to happen in any organization
in this case it affected 164 million
consumers data is exposed because well
we missed one
that struts library was sitting off over
here it was vulnerable we didn't know it
was in this system that system gave them
access they were able to Pivot blah blah
blah the usual story
but we've got a really cool more recent
examples don't we
yeah that logging platform I was talking
about oh yes long for Jay how many of us
dealt with log 4J and that
excitement we'll call it excitement
because we want to be positive this is
our happy little con we're doing
Saturday morning cartoons we're going to
be positive well yeah we understand that
turned into a vulnerability a pretty
massive one it turns out that log 4J
it got used all over the place and well
we found one CD then they found another
then they found another
and these were big time this was super
easy remote code execution vulnerability
is easy to exploit and they were all
over the place why because 91 of java
applications use that Library
what's more interesting is that 61 of
those
are indirect dependencies these are
those dependencies where it's buried not
in it's not that your software says hey
I'm including this in my manifest and I
want my package manager to bring that in
no no no no 61 of those were somewhere
in a package that was being pulled in
Long 4J was buried
maybe multiple levels nested deep
this is the complexity of Open Source
and of course it didn't stop there
because then you know spring had to get
in on the ACT too and it was only a few
months later and and of course we had to
we had to give this one a cool name too
on your spring for Shell they decided to
college because we're not really
original either when we find
vulnerabilities apparently
but again multiple cves
so we just come off of Vlog 4J and now
we're scrambling again trying to figure
out where do we have spring now it
turned out this one wasn't nearly as
nasty as the log 4J vulnerability
although it was still pretty bad
um but again
a lot of times this stuff exists in your
software and you don't know it
you might be pulling this in from
another open source Library you can be
pulling these dependencies in through
even third-party software that you've
purchased
because they happen to have it your
third party purchase software may have
these things so what do we do about it
well there's an initiative about
initiative out there that has been going
for some time a colleague of mine Josh
Corman if you've ever met him is out
there championing this to all ends of
the Earth and I happen to agree with
much of what he's saying that's the idea
of the software bill of materials what
if we could create a list just like we
use an aircraft that says hey here is
everything that goes into my software
these are all the components that
comprise my software this is what I have
approved to have in my software I know
this is what's there I can say
definitively that this is my code base
and this is what it includes well that's
going so well that in uh was it may of
it was an executive order
says hey
if you're doing business with a
government agency and you're selling a
software you now have to supply us with
an s-bomb
and there's lots of stuff out there on
what the format has to look like and
everything else of course they you know
the government being who they are they
work with Carnegie Mellon and they
created a whole bunch of stuff right now
I'm not suggesting that every
organization wants to create an s-bomb
of every piece of software you have
because when we start talking s-bombs
that gets pretty complex as I said
there's standard formats and things for
this that
generally when you work in that
Community they tend to be pretty heavy
weight and a little bit of owner a
little onerous but what if we could do
that same thing
so SDA is under the chat
software composition analysis
what is software composition analysis
well no one really knows because we
create all sorts of terms that we never
really know what they mean
but the general sense here is that
you've got a tool in most cases
doesn't have to be a tool but something
is going to go through your code look at
those dependencies walk that dependency
tree and identify all of those different
components that are now a part of your
software and create that inventory for
you
you can do it manually there are tools
and things like eclipse and others that
will give this to you and you might have
to do some more legwork
but there's also security focused tools
that are doing this one of them is right
outside the door here
okay
so there are tools that you can purchase
that will do this work for you
as I said there's different Utilities in
many of the IDS that will do this for
you but the point is starting to bring
to light that ability to understand
what's in your software
and so varying degrees and you'll see if
you talk to is like I actually just
spoke to the folks from shift left
earlier today because they're the ones
right out here
and I know sneak pretty well because
spoiler alert I used to work there
um and they all look at it a little
different but at the end of the day it's
all focused on that same strategy so
when we start looking at how do we do
this it's great to know there's tooling
but then you sit here and you say well
great another security tool so I've got
my SAS tool got my gas tool I'm Doing
Network vulnerability scan I'm doing
penetration tests and now I'm going to
throw to something else at my developers
the nice thing about these tools is that
they are really developer focused and
that we'll talk about in a second why
that's important because one of the
other things you have to do going back
to the aircraft industry
remember I said we've got this wonderful
cool you know list of all the equipment
well obviously over time you want to
replace that equipment
you don't want to keep I mean if I if
that plane that I bought had the radios
that were installed in it back in 1968
when it was brand new I don't think I'd
be really thrilled with it
so I replaced them but every time I
replace a piece of equipment what do I
need to do I need to update that
inventory and if I'm doing it on a
certificated airplane the FAA requires
me to fill out this form well actually
my mechanic or whoever installs it has
to fill out this form this is the FAA
form 30
337 geez I can spit that out
and all it is is it's a detailed account
of what was removed what was added and
how was that certified to be inside that
plane
those SCA tools give us the same thing
and they build us into an idea of what
I consider true devsecops
and that is where security is a
component in my
in My overall pipeline
but it's not a separate thing we love to
look at security when we talk devops we
love to look at security and bringing
security into that in terms of you know
you'll see talks on this well we need to
install these quality Gates
no we need to get away from quality
Gates
quality gates are the thing that break
our pipeline right quality games are the
thing that say Hey this pipeline is
supposed to flow from here to here in a
linear Direction just go one way and
then it repeats over and over again so
you can say it's linear you can say it's
a Infinity diagram I really don't care
but it's supposed to flow One Direction
the minute I stick a quality gate in
there between build and test
I have the potential to break that
pipeline because I may get to that
quality gate and say nope you got to go
back to code
well now my pipeline's going backward
so when we think about what SCA does
the way that these especially when we
look at these tools the way that they
work is they're going to look at yes
there's a scan there's a scan that
happens
it happens one time I've got my
inventory now maybe it happens each time
I build but a lot of these tools are
built into their pipeline tools so
they're sitting in your repositories
they're sitting in your build tools
they're sitting in your CI tools and yes
they are constantly active but the cool
thing is when you have that inventory
the other piece that they give you is
that monitoring so that when something
changes
maybe you didn't change your code at all
what's our solution for that with us
with SAS today
if I have a piece of code that hasn't
had any development done on it in 90
days
either my view of the vulnerabilities in
it are 90 days old because that was last
time I ran a scan or I got to have some
policy that says hey if you go so long
without scanning your code you have to
scan it again
well with SCA what you get is you've got
an inventory and now you can monitor
that inventory for new known
vulnerabilities you can get that
proactive alert to say all right I need
to go back and fix this so when
something changes it's documented you've
got that visibility
so now when the next log for Shell or
whatever Goofy name we come up with for
the next one comes out instead of
sitting there wondering
you know hmm I wonder if this is
vulnerable now
we know
we know because we have an inventory we
have a tool that's monitoring we have a
tool that's letting us know hey you know
what we saw this in your environment
you're going to need to know about it
well that sounds pretty cool so now
instant response sensors the chat right
because in the airplane
world when we have something like this
come up like I know you may not
understand the term but the angle of
attack indicator or well instruments and
on a 737 Max 8 are problematic
the FAA goes and they issue an emergency
or worthiness directive that says you
got to fix this or you got to ground
your airplane
and that happens with little planes like
mine in fact my specific airplane
there's one in particular about wings
falling off or you know little things
like that
little things they're not I mean you
know they're not that important you got
two of them
so
wheels are good too but the wheels are
attached to the Wing So if you lose the
wing you lost the wheel too
um but seriously that is that's a
legitimate airworthy instructive for my
aircraft is about an issue with wing
spars that causes fatigue cracks long
story
but imagine being able to do this now
when you've got something like log4j
where there's a log for shelf
vulnerability and it pops up think about
what it would be like as you're sitting
there how many of you
when logged four shells there are a
bunch of you that raised your hand you
got to deal with this how many of you
knew right away where all of your
instances of log Force log for J were
I one hand
yes because what if you had a tool that
gave you this
so this is one of my favorite stories
from when I dealt with it which was at
that former employer where we actually
leveraged one of the I won't tell you
which but one of those logos I put up
there before and we were using it in our
devops pipeline so when log4 shell came
up
within hours
I had a complete inventory of 953
locations in all of my software where we
had a log 4J dependency and I can tell
you A lot of them probably close to that
number from sneak that said 61 it was
somewhere in that ballpark of our
indirect depend of ours were indirect
dependencies
so think about the magic of that for
your instant response team when you can
go into something like that and you say
yeah we already know where all of it is
we can already start figuring out how we
Implement mitigations how are we going
to uh you know fix our own code how are
we going to reach out to a particular
vendor who's got to fix theirs how do we
prioritize these
that information was all there within
hours
within two weeks we had this completely
remediated I'm talking to cso peers of
mine who were still trying to figure out
where they had it
I think we're still trying to build
inventories of this
so that's where the value of SCA starts
to come in is okay yeah I can actually
understand this and I can gain that
visibility and now I've got that catalog
you mentioned that you've got s-bombs in
your organization
and this is what it does for you
so think about that that's awesome but
you know what incident response isn't
the only place
because guess who else wants in on this
conversation your compliance team but
then you know when compliance oh yeah
well you know compliance gets involved
goodbye
you know all right
but no seriously compliance wants to be
there
because what can we do with this from a
compliance perspective well there's a
couple really cool things
so when I think about again sticking
with my metaphor from the aviation
Community for one slide longer
for those of you that don't know the FAA
the NTSB and even NASA get together and
spend a lot of time and effort
finding Lessons Learned
measuring every statistic they can get
their hands on now I've for those in
here that are in the aviation Community
yes we can argue about how good they are
at that but
the intent is kind of there right
they're collecting tons of data and they
make this data available because the
focus is they want people to learn from
this so data on crashes you can go out
there you can read the reports from
these things are public
yeah you can argue again about the
qualities Sometimes some of the
information especially when it's a small
general aviation aircraft that crashes
versus a nice big airliner they tend to
care a little bit more when you know
hundreds of people die versus two
um but the data's there
so compliance wants that too compliance
wants to be able to look at it and say
all right how are we doing
are we getting better how are we
responding to these things where are we
seeing vulnerabilities
so just the metrics alone that you get
out of having a tool like this and being
able to understand all right here's
where we're seeing our issues here's
what we're seeing most of that common
activity around different
vulnerabilities that are showing up we
can start to understand maybe there are
components within our our software
packages that we're pulling from the
open source community that are ones that
we don't really want to keep as a part
of our software
because again you're dealing with open
source maintainers some of them have all
the time in the world and they're big
groups and they can spend a ton of time
on this a lot of packages out there are
maintained by one or two people who
maybe don't have the time to sit there
and review every poll request to make
sure that it's completely secure and so
you as an organization may want to make
a decision about do we keep including
that particular package or should we
look at something else or here's a novel
idea and this is the one that makes the
legal team and the financial team freak
out but maybe we start contributing back
to that project
maybe we
as form of payments since we're getting
all this free code
maybe our commitment should be to making
that code better some organizations some
of the bigger ones
are doing that
that's not the only thing compliance is
interested in think about this so if I
am pulling source code
from
the open source Community let's say it's
licensed with Creative Commons
what potential issue does that have
there's a few
one am I even licensed
am I even licensed to have these
components in my software am I using it
in a way that is consistent with their
license
so just that General licensing
discussion can be really important for
your compliance team
but let's think about in terms of IP for
a moment intellectual property
what is Creative Commons in most of the
iterations of their different licenses
require
think like share and share a like
so if I attribution as well yes in fact
that's actually an interesting challenge
too
um but think about the share and share
like for a minute so
Sharon chair like basically says that
well if I'm going to use your open
source software now anything that I
included in becomes open source too
your legal team may have an issue with
that
your product teams may have an issue
with that
those are things you want to know about
and so here again having that catalog
and being able to understand what is in
your software yeah this extends Way
Beyond security now because we're we're
talking about compliance things and
Licensing
that that's not really a cyber security
thing anymore
but hopefully what you're starting to
think and you're starting to see as I
start to tie into these other teams is
oh wait
maybe there's more people than just the
cyber security team that want to see
this tool in use
maybe even your customers care
you may not be doing business with the
federal government today
but what happens when you get that big
financial services customer
that Global Behemoth who comes to you
and says hey
we want you to supply us with an
inventory of all the open source in your
software
or at minimum they say we want to know
we want to have validation that you're
monitoring that
this is when you have things like
s-bombs now that are being mandated by
the federal government this is where
we're headed
so getting ahead of that and having the
capability whether you buy one of those
commercial tools or you find ways to do
it yourself software composition
analysis is important it carries
business value and that's the thing
that's going to be most important
because at the end of the day if you
want to introduce this to your
environment what do you need to do
you're going to need a solid business
case and you're going to need buy-in
from a lot of people because you've got
a lot of stakeholders who are going to
be involved in this who you are asking
to be a part of this program you're
talking about changing
that development pipeline you're talking
about getting your developers
involved in this in a way where they may
have to modify how they develop their
software they may need to be more aware
of what is in those packages so how do
you go about presenting this how do you
bring this to those people in a way
that's going to win
because
like it or not that is our job as cyber
Security Professionals we are not here
just to say this is bad fix it
we are here to educate and to influence
because when I go and I go to my CIO I
go to my CFO I go before the board and I
say you know what I want two million
dollars to do this thing it is my job to
be able to convince them why they want
to spend two million dollars on that
thing
so let's talk about how we do that
first of all
you have got to show the value to the
business
and if you are thinking in your head
right now and I know this blows people's
minds when I say this if you're thinking
in your head that idea of risk
management and that the language of
business is risk and wolf is laughing
because he's heard me say this a hundred
times before the language of business is
not risk
I cannot scream it loud enough the
language of business is show me the
money
businesses are in business to make money
in most cases
a few exceptions to that yes I
understand non-profit Community the
government mission's a little different
even well you can argue both ways in
education but let's not get into that
conversation
um but the reality is risk management is
not why businesses exist and in fact
consider this for a brief moment
if a business is in business today
there is inherent risk in being in
business
just owning a business any of you who
have started your own business you
understand like me that there is risk
and a risk conversation that goes on in
your head about should I do this or not
so at the point that you've decided to
be in business you've already accepted
that risk you've already said that being
in business
is worth whatever risk I'm taking in
order to try to make money and get my
thing into there or to take on whatever
Mission it is if I'm in a non-profit
where mission is my driving Factor
or the government where in theory
mission is the driving Factor
so if I come to you and I say
hey I'm cyber security and I am all
about reducing your risk how sexy is
that here bored or already accepted that
risk what do I care I mean yes they do
care don't get me wrong board is there
they have a fiduciary responsibility
they're there to make sure the business
stays successful that stock prices keep
going up and shareholders stay happy and
that's what they do I get that but
at the end of the day they're there to
make sure the business makes money
risk is a factor in that but it is not
the only Factor so come ready to talk
about how SCA has business value
as I said you want this to be part of
your pipeline it needs to be part of the
pipeline because what you don't want
this to be is that tool that creates new
friction because friction
in your development process quality
Gates that stop your pipeline
just like an oil pipeline if you stop
the pipeline that's bad okay that's bad
that's the antithesis of business value
that is a business blocker you as a
cyber security professional are not
enabling the business if you are
introducing quality Gates and things
like that that are going to stop
development
so how do you work with this differently
how do you bring these tools into the
pipeline so that they happen inherently
with the pipeline how do you get your
pipeline so mature that you know what
scary thought you can go to production
with known vulnerability in your
software because hey I know my pipeline
is mature enough that the next cycle is
going to pick it up and it's going to
have it fixed in three hours or maybe a
day or two and I can launch a mitigation
in the meantime maybe we've got great
wafts in place I don't know pick your
mitigation the choice or multiple
mitigations please
but at the end of the day
getting in there without friction so
when I've got a cool tool that plugs in
to my repos and GitHub or in Ado or
wherever I'm keeping my software
when I've got that ability to tie it
into my CI tools into my build tools
when all of those capabilities are
intertwined that's where the value of
devops automation comes into play
Because by the way devops is not just
about automation okay that's a talk for
a different time though well so getting
tied into the pipeline and keeping that
pipeline in motion and more importantly
if you really want to drive business
value and demonstrate this show them how
this is going to speed up the
development pipeline
what are the things that are happening
today talk to your developers and find
out how annoying it is for them when
they don't know all the dependencies
that sit behind a particular component
in their software and now they find out
that hey there's something in there
that's five or leases old that's buried
three levels deep in a dependency
somewhere that's causing all sorts of
backward compatibility issues hey I can
give you a tool that not only is going
to help us make your software more
secure but it's going to help you find
stuff like that a whole lot easier too
oh business value making the pipeline
faster
that speaks to people you mean I can get
product out the door faster I can get
new feature functionality to my
customers faster
that makes people listen
we also need to start changing the
conversation overall
you know it's funny I I started this new
position eight weeks ago
into a conversation with my CEO I think
my second week and
we were chit chatting and they had had a
major breach a couple years ago and he
says to me
just don't let us get breached again
okay
um let's talk about that for a minute
now we can all in this room sit here and
say well gee it's not if you get
breached but when
I know this in the back of my head but
why is my CEO saying that to me
because it was freaking painful when we
got breached
but I know that we're going to get
breached again I know that's going to
happen because the laws of averages say
so
I know for sure I'm not going to
guarantee him that I won't then I'll
stop all breaches
but what are we there to do we're there
to slow down we're there to be resilient
we're there to create that resiliency
we're seeing this as a trend in the
industry right now the focus on that
word resiliency
and that's the conversation we need to
be driving
so when I think about this in terms of
SCA is this going to stop all
vulnerabilities no is it going to stop
me from getting breached probably not
this is not the thing that's going to
prevent all breaches if that product
comes along I will be the first to let
you know
I'm sure there are some vendors who will
claim they have it but trust me they
don't
but the reality is when we have these
conversations if I'm going to go in
there and I'm talking about SCA what I'm
talking about is how do we get
incrementally better how do I start a
program of continuous Improvement where
I am going to make our software more and
more secure day over day year over year
because now I'm starting to shift the
expectations when the expectations are
I'm going to install this thing and
we're never going to get breached again
I'm lying
because how long did it take before log
4J became of cve versus when it was
actually first discovered
no one really has an answer for that
we saw lots of activity before it was
logged as a cve we know that
but we don't know how long that's been
known about we don't know where that's
been leveraged
so to sit there and say that this is the
end-all be-all answer no but to focus on
that story of how this is helping us
understand our ever-evolving technology
that's the key because I've also had
board members ask me hey when are we
done with having to you know invest in
cyber security like this
uh when technology stops changing right
so let's change that conversation and
make that focus when we're talking about
SCA or any other Initiative for that
matter it's all about our ability to be
resilient and what we're trying to do is
we're trying to strengthen our defenses
not look for perfection
because Perfection is the thing that is
unattainable that is the thing when
we've got people out there talking about
be breachless install our product
I don't even know what that means
be breachless that was a cute one I saw
we're trying to get stronger we're
trying to get more resilient we're
trying to make our defenses such that we
are a real pain in the ass to try to
breach
that's what I want
you know what I want to be a tough nut
to crack am I crackable probably I don't
think I will never stand up here and say
that I can never build an organization
that isn't going to be
but
focusing the conversation on making our
defenses stronger here's how it's going
to make us stronger not just in terms of
hey we're stronger from a cyber security
perspective but we are strengthening our
compliance we're strengthening our
ability to react
we're strengthening the entire
organization
through the use of something like this
and that's where we need to start to
again have a very different conversation
than what we've typically done you go in
front of a board and you say hey this is
the end-all BL Solution that's going to
make all our software secure
it doesn't fly
this is a tool that hey you know what I
talked to compliance you know what
they're on board because they say this
is going to strengthen our compliance
program as well they're going to we're
going to understand our licensing better
we're going to have better metrics we're
going to be able to understand you know
what third parties we're leveraging and
how good a job they're doing and all of
these things great okay we can start to
understand that better
this is going to make our pipelines
stronger and faster because hey it's
given us this ability to see in you know
the developers have told me this is all
the problems they're having and I've
I've got a solution that's going to help
them think about when you start to draw
that picture of how your initiative
affects all those other areas positively
especially when you get those other
areas to come in and say yeah you know
we support this and we want it too
getting your stakeholders on board to
say
we're looking for Extra Strength here
this is going to bring it to us
and then finally
I said it
risk is not the language of business if
you want to find the Holy Grail when you
are trying to sell an initiative to your
board
tell them how this is going to make them
more money well how do I make more money
with SCA
thoughts
let's start with that s-bomb idea
how many organizations are asking you
right now about
you know your software
how many of them are saying hey we want
to understand what you're doing to
secure it
when you can show them that you're on
the Leading Edge and hey you know what
this is something we do we're able to
understand everything that's in our
software we're able to provide you
immediate alerts when there's a new CD
that comes out as to in the open source
Community as to whether or not that's
part of our software we're able to
provide you that better visibility and
capability and we have the strength and
the processes in place to address those
immediately those conversations happen
easier
because what happens when you're talking
to say a gigantic
multinational
who wants to understand your cyber
security program and you can show them
that you're doing something that is
proactive ahead of the game ahead of
what most people are doing today
they don't ask as many questions
because now they start to see oh okay
they're doing like you know kind of
Leading Edge stuff we're on board with
this
so that's that's a
maybe less tangible but really specific
way to talk about how this really builds
your business development
how this starts to make money for the
organization now depending
on who you are and and the nature of
your business there might be other ways
that you can actually turn this into a
revenue generator
think about this for a minute how could
you take that software inventory that
you have that talks about everything
that's in your software depending on
what you're selling depending on what
you're providing
what if there's that opportunity to even
sell that alone as a capability to your
customers
that they now have that visibility that
they now have that capability or they
can leverage that in some way
when we start to think about our
security initiatives that way in general
whether it's SCA or anything else this
is where we really start to find
traction with the board with the
executives and so on
so be on the lookout for those talk with
your business teams talk with your
product teams understand what they're
doing and say Hey I want to bring this
new thing
where can we maybe look to leverage this
into a revenue opportunity how can we
sell an additional layer of service that
includes this sta visibility or
capability or some offshoot of what it
provides us look for those elements and
bring that to the table
don't come in there and say this is
going to remove all these
vulnerabilities from our developed code
that's part of the story but that's like
this tiny little bit and it's not a very
sexy tiny little bit it doesn't get
people listening think about the things
that are going to get people listening
filled a competitive Advantage because
that's what people want
maybe this is the thing you point to
it's part of a comprehensive cyber
security program that puts us ahead of
our competitors however you want to
Market this
make it something that becomes a
championing thing for your organization
in your Marketplace
leave you with a quote as I wrap up here
Perfection yeah it's the enemy of
progress if we're out there chasing
Perfection we're never going to get
there if we're out there selling
Perfection and we're telling our
organizations that we can deliver
Perfection we're not going to be making
progress because you're not going to
lack credibility you're not going to be
successful in that end and at the end of
the day that's going to hinder your
progress
so finally I do encourage you all to
continue the conversation I'm happy to
hear your ideas I'm happy to have you
tell me I'm completely full of crap
um you know I mean I'd appreciate if it
was a little Kinder than that but hey
you know what sometimes maybe but reach
out to me on social media Twitter by far
the easiest LinkedIn is okay but I will
tell you I don't get into LinkedIn a
whole lot uh my website's up there too
if you want to contact me through there
as well finally big thank you to my
organization to Circle city con for
having me here
um and of course thank you to all of you
for being a part of the day
enjoy your conference