good afternoon good afternoon everyone
my name is trevor hughes and i'm the
president and CEO of the IA p p the
international association of privacy
professionals we are the world's largest
privacy organization we represent all of
the people in the world who work in data
protection and privacy and I'm delighted
to be here at RSA this year joined by an
esteemed panel to talk about four little
letters four little letters that have
been causing us so much trouble so much
work and of course those are g.d.p are
the general data protection regulation
the regulation passed just some years
ago but went into effect on May 25th of
this year just over two months ago and
it has created an enormous amount of
work for organizations around the world
what we thought we would do for you
today is create a panel of experts
representing views from around the world
on the effect of GDP our what it means
to organizations today and what we might
expect in the future let me give you
just a little bit of background on how
we got to where we are now and then
we'll dive into things with our
panelists so first of all the GD P R is
a replacement it is a regulation that
replaces a directive in Europe in 1995
the European Union passed the Data
Protection Directive which was the law
of Europe with regards to data
protection for over 20 years however
given that that law was passed in 1995
and as a result did not reflect the
internet or smartphones the rise of
social media many of the technologies
that we take for granted today there was
a recognition that a new standard a new
set of policies needed to be created and
so the GD P R the general data
protection regulation it was drafted
early about seven eight years ago and
passed just four or five years ago with
an expectation of May 25th being that
compliance deadlines so now we are in
the gdpr era and it is a monumental
moment for data protection one of the
things that we are seeing around the
world is tremendous investment and
growth in privacy and data protection I
can give you a sense of that from the
IEP P itself we have 42,000 members
around the world in over 100 countries
but just 24 months ago we had 20,000
members around the world so the size of
the IEP P if that is any indicator of
how GD P R has affected our world
I think our growth is a great indicator
of that ok welcome to you all
I am going to play a little game as we
go through the panel today and the
little game is I'm going to read a quote
and you get to guess who it is
so our first quote is there are no grace
periods because the grace period was
already two years ago who said that I'm
gonna guess that was Helen Dixon wrong
any other guesses another good guess but
also wrong it's Andrea Yellin act under
a yellow neck is the Austrian Data
Protection Commissioner and aundrea was
talking of course about the GDP our she
is notably now the chair of the European
Data Protection Board and let's use that
quote as a way to talk about how
prepared we are so who would like to
start where are we in terms of our
preparations for GDP our and in many
ways are we too late if we're still
preparing for GDP are so Trevor I'll
start with that question one of the
things that we've seen in helping
companies around the world in their
preparation for GDP are is that a lot of
work has been put in but only 20% of
companies that we surveyed recently have
actually claimed to be GDP our
compliance many more are actually in the
process of implementation but have a
number of other
they're still trying to complete in fact
there are I think if I recall correctly
about 30% or so that have not even begun
to prepare and so there are many many
organizations that still have a lot of
work to do but we do know that many
organizations have put a tremendous
amount of effort in to place already to
begin to understand what's happening
with their data in a way that they had
not necessarily ever done before they're
doing inventories they're beginning to
do much more stringent assessments and
things of that nature
there is new year with a global
multinational describe how the global
focus on gdpr has affected a on is it a
is it a big project how many people
around the world how senior was the
engagement for four gdpr
so as a global organization I think the
focus on GDP are just really put a
spotlight on how important data was to
the company
we've always marketed ourselves as a
data-driven entity just being in risk
and reinsurance and so in terms of
involvement we had involvement all the
way up from the CEO level on the board
level and that really increased the
amount of I guess expenditure that we
had in order to be in compliance so that
that was a lucky thing that we had but
in terms of focus towards not just
Europe I think understanding that there
were data flows not just originating
from Europe but also coming from other
parts of the wall into Europe and those
are important areas has been really good
from a privacy professional perspective
because you do get to understand your
business better but also to understand
where your data is located where how
your data is being used and what kind of
people are we actually interacting with
when we are collecting this kind of data
so through Italy let me stay with you
just for one second because I think it's
important to note that the GD P R is a
European regulation but the effect of GD
P R is very much global and that's
because GD P R has what we call
extraterritorial application so if you
are an organization around the world
that that interacts with a data subject
with a
person in Europe you are theoretically
subject to gdpr is that right absolutely
and I think the gdpr makes a reference
that if you are transacting with an EU
resident that just makes you you have to
comply with the obligations of a GDP R
and I think there is a bit of a lack of
understanding with when there's a GDP r
apply outside of the EU I think a lot of
companies out here say that's a European
legislation you know we have other laws
here we don't need to comply with that
but ultimately you know when you have a
4% global turnover being the sanction
that's really when organizations really
need to kind of realize hey we need to
look at this European piece of
legislation that we've never really kind
of paid attention to much before so
we'll talk about enforcement in a second
but four percent of global turnover is
fines that creates I think some
attention from senior execs Alex tell us
a little bit from the perspective of
Accenture what do you see the readiness
as around the world
Accenture clearly is a very global
organization are there differences
between multinational corporations and
small and medium-sized businesses is are
there regions of the world that are more
focused on GDP are right now what is the
perspective that you see yeah so very
clearly and from an European perspective
specifically I think there is a great
advancement currently with many
companies on readiness so I see
especially in Europe everybody is
prepared on GDP are in a kind of way and
so it doesn't means that there are a
hundred percent done with it especially
for the semi companies so the medium and
small-sized companies but if I'm going
to the doctor even my Carnival Club all
all of those kind of associations small
companies if these bakeries if needed
they are kind of coming up with
notifications and consent and whatever
so it's truly like that are they ready
in other aspects of GDP our readiness
I'm not sure about this but you
definitely see a much greater sense of
understanding and awareness
it means to handle personal data for us
at Accenture obviously gdpr was a big
advantage also to push it as enhance for
our data privacy and also for our
information security system into the
company and push it through because we
are in more than 40 45 countries so we
really need to make sure that we have a
global baseline so we leverage GDP
alphas that are we ready yes we are we
have implemented what we had to
implement is this perfect I don't think
so
I think we are now in what we call a
phase to make further improvements to
what you have implemented in the
processes and also learn actually how it
really works because in the beginning it
was all on paper and it was all in
theory but now we are learning in the
daily doing what we can do better and
how to improve excellent so I I find it
really compelling that for a large
organization like Accenture you're using
gdpr as a global baseline yes that that
is sort of the expectation and then I
presume you do variation by jurisdiction
if there is law that changes beyond gdpr
yeah I think we are seeing an
interesting effect with gdpr and that is
that not only does it have a
extraterritorial application so you may
not be a European organization but you
may be subject to gdpr but also many
organizations like Accenture are using
gdpr as their baseline for managing data
protection managing privacy around the
world and one of the things that's
driving that is the need under gdpr for
you to having agreements in place with
all of the companies with which you
transact data data processor agreements
DPAs they're becoming a well-known thing
hilary maybe you could talk a little bit
about this so some organizations which
may not ever have a customer in europe
may actually receive one of these data
processor agreements because of a
customer or a partner
a vendor that they work with is that
right that's absolutely right so one of
the things that's required under gdpr is
if you are a controller of data
controllers the one who makes the
company that makes the decisions about
the data your obligation when you're
engaging any third party regardless of
where they are in the supply chain is to
make sure that they and those connected
with them in that supply chain are
entering into these new agreements that
Trevor is mentioning so a data processor
agreement or a data processing addendum
known by this new acronym DPA is
something that everyone who's engaging
third-party suppliers vendors is going
to need to make sure is put in place and
it's very different from the kinds of
agreements that we've seen before
they're very specific obligations with
respect to things like notifications of
security breaches managing individual
rights cooperating with a data
controller making sure that adequate
protections are being put in place and
then binding anybody else that's
actually working together with you
subprocessors hosting providers others
that help to provide the service
together has to enter into an agreement
as well
what we're seeing as a result is that
this is taking up a tremendous amount of
time for organizations to negotiate and
it does need to be coupled with some
really good due diligence about whether
the organizations that you're engaging
the vendors you're engaging are in fact
those that can meet these requirements
because of the as we were talking about
already three snoo is saying the 4% fine
that one can have if you're not meeting
these requirements effectively we're
gonna get to the four percent fines I
promise so it is interesting though that
whether you are directly subject to gdpr
because you're based in Europe or
through extraterritorial application
you're subject to gdpr because you're
based outside of Europe that you have
European customers there is a long
shadow to gdpr which is that many global
organizations are using it as their
baseline and many other organizations
are sending out these data processor
agreements which essentially bacon
GDP our protections through contract to
your organization I think the big
message that we're trying to convey with
the panel here is that whether you think
you are subject to GDP are or not you
are likely to struggle with some of the
effects of GDP our and you probably
should be ready all right
another quote ready here we go
you need to ensure that compliance is
not focused on the legal department but
throughout the company who said that I
know these are all gonna be tough
isabell South Dakota and Isabelle is the
commissioner of the canal the French
data protection regulator and I think
she's saying something very important
she's saying that gdpr is not a policy
driven regulation gdpr is actually a new
way of doing business that you have to
drive it across the company so
thoroughly why don't you help us out
tell us what has been the most vexing
implementation challenge for under GDP
our foray on sure I think I kind of
initially spoke a little bit about it
which is understanding where your data
is and really how much data do you
collect where is it being stored how is
it being used in an organization I think
one of the things that we immediately
see is that while you collect data at
this point what happens behind the
scenes is something that a lot of legal
professionals have never really taken
into account before I think this is when
you see the relationship between InfoSec
professionals you know coming true with
the legal department but also with board
level management because initially it
was well we don't really care where our
data is as long as we have it and we do
whatever we want to maximize profits but
now I think with the GDP our it says you
have to know where your data is and that
relates to the fact that one if anything
goes wrong ie a data breach that will be
a problem but two if an individual makes
a request either to delete their data or
access the data 200 to have data
portability I eat
for it from one organization to another
all of that comes down to knowing where
your data is and that for me is the
hardest part of compliance with the gdpr
but also the most important thing to get
right as well okay so that's a great one
one of the requirements or one of the
expectations of gdpr is that you know
what data you have and you know how
you're using it so data inventories data
flow Maps data audits those are
absolutely critical under gdpr and not
for one second should we think that
that's a small job because in most
complex organizations there are many
places in which data is coming in many
ways in which it's being used Alex what
was the most vexing most challenging
implementation problem that you had at
Accenture actually the most challenging
thing we have seen as definitely is that
it's a new law at the time we were
looking into the law which we started as
a project very early so two years ago
there was nothing out there to give us
any guidance on it so we really had to
interpret the law in the way it would
work for us actually that was initially
a huge challenge guidance came out
dropping in later right very late
some of the point and so we leveraged
that on the other side it also gives a
bit of a reflection on what is required
under gdpr
as part of the accountability you have
you are also required to interpret the
laws and rules how it would make sense
for you as a company and at one point we
really then we're taking the step
forward and saying like okay we need to
decide how we are interpreting it and
that's the way we are doing it we so
this is this is a really interesting
point gdpr is a new regulation they just
went to into effect on May 25th it was
passed introduced just two years ago and
the regulators in Europe and the courts
have not had a chance to interpret it
and I think it's fair to say that
there's many provisions within gdpr
that are less than
clear there are many questions that
remain unanswered how do you manage that
risk inside Accenture how do you make
those decisions what what is that what
are the tools that you use to try to
answer some of those questions yeah we
actually implemented and enhanced a
couple of tools for managing our data
privacy compliance and one of the major
actually not really changes but
improvements we did is that we
implemented a lot of data privacy
controls we actually had a lot of
security controls beforehand but now we
leveraged the systems for the security
controls to enhance them with new
privacy controls which actually required
us to work closely obviously with our
security people and to understand where
we have potentially overlaps but also
actually to implement those new tools on
the other side we implemented data
privacy impact assessment tools another
new tool and given the requirement of
the regulations that you need to
document what you are assessing we
really wanted to have it in a very
specific place and we wanted to use a
very specific tool for it and this
actually took a bit of Y to define what
are the requirements of the tools and
which would be the right provider of the
tool could we do it ourself or not and
then we moved on the third to will be
implemented and one of the biggest tool
and actually also reflecting a bit that
gdpr can be also an enhancer was our
supplier tool so we have certain
supplier tools and applications for our
procurement team the global computer
procurement and but with now or supplier
requirements we do have for applying due
diligence on the suppliers really
understand and know which supplier is
touching which data if you want to say
so
so that actually required us also also
taking into a
the size of the suppliers we have the
number that we implemented a new
supplier tool and also leverage said for
our supplier due diligence
excellent so so three really powerful
tools first you board from your
Information Security colleagues and use
their risk controls which is powerful
you implemented data protection impact
assessments a risk management tool where
you are assessing the data protection
consequences in new products new
features new ideas inside your
organization and third consistent with
what we were discussing with data
processor agreements you implemented a
supplier tool many are talking about GDP
are ushering in a new era of digital
supply chain management and it sounds
like that's very close to that Hillary
tell me about technological tools and
how important they are in a GDP our
response organizations clearly are
investing in these tools we certainly
see many more vendors emerging in the
marketplace your company trust arc is
one of the leading players in the space
tell us about that part of the solution
yeah so one of the things that we're
seeing and it I'm going to go back to
the data that we talked about right at
the beginning of our session today is
that people are not fully ready to
comply and even those who have claimed
that they are compliant needs to manage
their ongoing obligations with respect
to GDP our and as my colleagues have
shared already it's important to
understand what's happening to your data
where it's flowing and how that changes
over time so what we're seeing in terms
of technology is a need and a growing
need for many organizations to
understand what's happening with their
data so they're employing more data
discovery tools for privacy purposes and
really partnering with their information
security colleagues to make sure that
they're understanding what's happening
with the data more effectively
downstream from that we're seeing that
they are beginning to use data inventory
or data mapping tools and so by way of
contrast to
some of the tools that have been used
before to do an asset inventory the data
inventory tools for privacy purposes are
ones that are looking more into how
exactly are you using the data as my
colleagues have shared already it's
important in order to comply with gdpr
that you know what is the data being
used for it's a concept called
processing purposes and so we have these
data inventory tools that are helping to
understand what are the processing
purposes and help to better understand
as the data are flowing throughout the
actual data flow from a organization
from an individual from whom they're
collected to an organization to a
processor to another supplier to a
hosting provider to recipients exactly
what is happening with that data as it's
traveling around the world from there
we're also seeing that organizations as
Alex was saying are needing to assess
and they're needing to assess various
different things very similar to what
happens with data assessments from a
security perspective so assessing
suppliers but not just for security
controls but also for privacy related
controls as Alex was sharing lastly I'll
say in terms of the things we're seeing
the greatest uptake in our tools around
understanding risk and I say I share
that at the outset because security risk
I think there's been a lot of work done
to understand and define what security
risk management or information risk
management looks like to address
information security obligations within
organizations what we see under GDP are
that's particularly troubling given that
there's not a ton of guidance out there
yet is that there's an obligation for
organizations to understand and protect
something called the risks to the rights
and freedoms of individuals that's not
an objective thing that is a very
subjective determination and so what the
tools are beginning to do is to help
organizations define objectively what
does that risk actually look like what
kind of data may be sensitive that may
be causing some harm
two individuals what kind of processing
involves monitoring or surveillance for
an example as something that's perceived
by the regulator's to be higher risk and
I could list a number of other things
but those are the main tools that we're
beginning to see as part of the research
that we've done together with the ia pp
fantastic so we've kind of covered the
operational response to GD P R and as we
go through the list the inventory of new
tools new ideas new processes that have
emerged inside organizations to comply
with GD P R I'm struck by one thing
we've talked about data inventory we've
talked about data flow mapping we've
talked about strong vendor and supplier
and partner controls we've talked about
data data protection impact assessments
we didn't mention data subject access
requests which is another major tool or
another requirement under GD P R what
I'm struck by is how much these look
like presents to the information
security field you know these are good
data management tools and I think any
information security Pro should be
delighted to see investment and
resources coming in to these types of
tools in many ways all the people in
this audience should go back and buy a
drink or give a present to their chief
privacy officer or their data protection
officer back in their home office
because I think there really is some
synergy here all right let's move on and
talk about the global perspective and
originally I'm hoping that you can give
us a sense what has the response been in
the Asian marketplace you're responsible
for asia-pacific for a on what type of
engagement what type of receptiveness
have you seen market to market across
the asia-pacific region and and where do
you see that going sure so I think
there's a couple of like there are very
different countries and how they look at
privacy and data protection within the
region I guess the big one would be
Japan that very recently that you use it
will look at giving them an adequacy
status so an adequacy status means that
particular country has the same amount
of protection or the same level of
protection for individual data as it
would be in the EU but recent statistics
so ey conducted a survey that only a
quarter of Japanese companies surveyed
said they had made progress 20 percent
plan to do so I don't think planning to
do something would fly with a regulator
very much
26% updated their privacy statements
online again while that's a publicly
facing thing and you think you're
covering that risks are so much more to
be done but what I find really
interesting in this survey is that only
7% of organizations are prepared for the
72-hour breach notification requirement
and that is honestly a big key piece
when you talk about risk and exposure
when it comes to a data breach you need
to inform a regulator within 72 hours
and if you're not prepared for that
you're looking at very large numbers of
fines but which I understand ever will
go to later and in other markets in Asia
I think when you look at the companies
that are operating on global level the
level of awareness is there and in fact
it's almost taken precedent over the
local laws and regulations that exist
for data privacy such as the PDPA I've
seen that happen in some organizations
where with contracts they say EU law the
GDP are but not necessarily the law that
of the lands that's an interesting
development and in some countries as
well you see the fact that GDP are is
there it's bringing attention to local
legislation that there is an existence
almost side by side of local privacy
legislation and data protection laws and
the GDP are there's a lot of positivity
there but still a lack of I think
knowledge and also attention to the
details that are involved in the GDP are
because it's a large document I think we
might have all read it but not a lot of
people would go to that level and I
think that's really where the
regulator's need to come interesting
evidence it sounds like there's a lot of
work still to be done and Alex I
I'm going to ask you a rhetorical
question so it sounds like along with
French wine and German automobiles the
gdpr might be one of the greatest
exports ever from Europe is that fair
alright let's turn now to enforcement so
I'm going to read a couple of quotes for
you here the first is the aim of our
office is to prevent harm but we will
back that up with tough action where
necessary any guesses I see well done
our first correct answer well done well
done Alex that is Liz Denham the
Information Commissioner from the UK now
notably Liz Denham just brought an
enforcement action and issued a fine
proposed a fine against Facebook for the
Cambridge analytic issue and that was
500,000 pounds but that was a fine
brought under the prior regime which was
the Data Protection Directive and that
was the maximum fine under GDP our
maximum fines go up to 4% of global
turnover which is to say 4% of global
revenue for an organisation had the fine
been the maximum fine under GDP are in
this Facebook example it theoretically
could have been many billions of dollars
which is really quite striking let me
offer another quote there will be fines
and they will be significant any guesses
that was Helen Dixon the Irish Data
Protection Commissioner and notably
Helen Dixon oversees Ireland the
jurisdiction where many of the major
tech players have their European
headquarters so she will be the
regulator of record so let's talk about
fines is GDP are really all about the
fines is that the thing that we should
be responding to the most that this is a
risk management response that we're
trying to avoid fines and so the the big
stick of 4% of global turnover
that's what CEOs and boards of directors
are mostly
going to pay attention to and that's why
we should comply with GDP our Alex is
that the right answer I don't think so
however the 4% definitely helps in
getting the attention and awareness of
your CEO and to honestly also open the
kind of pockets for bigger budgets and
for more resources at least it
definitely had awareness within our
company and on the other side I have to
say just looking at the fines it will
not ever help you because GD P R is much
more about how you are able as a company
to handle personal data in an in a
responsible way and I think especially
in the area we are working in and this
is digital it is hugely important for us
to do it in a very responsible way and
also be trusted by our clients but as
well by our employees that we handles
the data in the way we not only should
do but it's also the right thing to do
and therefore GD P are obviously for the
privacy team was a big advantage because
now we had the money and the resources
to more invest actually we didn't get
all of what we would have asked for but
at least it happed a bit but yeah the
intention really needs to go much beyond
the 4% as as a stick here
so the 4% fines will capture one's
attention they will open the door to a
conversation and perhaps allow some
resources to be loosened up and created
within the organisation but they're not
the end of the story Hilary you spend a
lot of time in Europe what do you think
we should be expecting from the
regulator's with regards to enforcement
so Helen Dickson said well there will be
fines and they will be significant
Liz Denham said the aim of her office is
to prevent harm but they'll back that up
with tough action so the regulators are
putting
or word some language that suggests that
they're going to use fines so I think we
should expect enforcement what do you
think that's gonna look like well I
think first it's going to look like
regulator's responding to the complaints
that they are already receiving from
data subjects or individuals about whom
the data are processed we know from what
they've shared that they are getting
many more complaints than they have
received historically in fact many of
them have fast in the thousands of
complaints that they're dealing with
right now um what do I think it will
look like as a result I think that it
will force organizations to be able to
show how they have put in place measures
to comply with these various different
operational requirements that we've been
discussing on the panel today how you
can show that you actually have
maintained a record of what your data
processing look like how you've done
your assessments how you've managed you
know incident management processes
within your organization to actually
show that you're prepared to respond
timely and to report to them if you've
had a breach they'll be looking to see
whether or not you've managed any
breaches that have happened in
accordance with their expectations one
of which is as we were talking about
risk earlier to actually evaluate what
your risk is associated with that breach
consistent with the expectations under
gdpr so I think early on they're going
to be looking for demonstration of
preparedness that you haven't as three
sneh said ignored completely or done
nothing yet but that you've put these
requirements into place within your
organization that you're prepared to
respond I think ultimately though they
will be looking to see how well you've
managed the risk associated with that
data and if you've not taken that
seriously that you will not have any
mitigating measures when it comes to
these defines that they have the ability
now to to put in place I think that's
really well said and and let me just
capture that point for this audience one
of the things that we have heard
consistently from regulators with
regards to these fines is that good
faith will go a long way and that means
if you show the good faith in assessing
the risk in interpreting the GDP are to
the best of your abilities and you do
the hard work
that that will be a significant
mitigating factor in any enforcement
action that a regulator may bring or any
complaint that may come towards you but
doing that hard work I think is pretty
critical there is need tell me about
that hard work at a on tell me about how
how you have implemented resources
across a on and and where you see the
greatest work in the in the weeks and
months ahead sure one thing to mention
is with an a on the GD P our compliance
program is actually sponsored not by the
privacy team but by the global security
services so that so this event all the
way up to there are seaso and there are
the sponsors of the program
understanding that a huge part of GDP
are compliance rests within security and
our information security professionals
because they ultimately understand how
the business works and if you know what
we can advise on the legal perspectives
but from an operational practical
perspective it is the security
professionals to understand how to
actually operationalize that so the
cooperation between the privacy team and
the global security services at a on has
been honestly one of the most helpful
ways that this program has moved forward
and so in terms of the next few months
we're looking at also we've also called
it phase two there's a lot of the stuff
in phase one was just around
notifications consents contracts now is
actually how do we deal with a major
attack or a major incident that happens
within your our organization with data
flowing from various different countries
and continents how do we then address a
particular incident within 72 hours and
the hard work is not just with the core
team that's working on it so we we are
planning on having sort able top
exercises we've you know we've had sort
of fake phishing attacks that were
engineered by our guys you know and
seeing really it's not about whether
people fall for it but where the
percentages of people falling for that
did they actually report the fact that
they were fish to the correct entity
within a on for eggs
while these are the hard work we need to
do because if the numbers are not great
we need to get it to great every
employee needs to know their
responsibility to respond to an incident
really quickly because this 72 hours
passed by very very quickly and in
contracts itself if we are a vendor it's
not only 72 hours the data user will say
come back to me in 24 hours upon
discovery and as a vendor of a lot of
major organizations this is something
that is a responsibility for every
single employee and that's really the
hard work yeah Wow all right we're
heading towards the end of our time and
I want to talk about the future and
future risk and future complexity
because the data protection world does
not live in stasis it actually moves
quite quickly there's a number of things
emerging on the horizon that could add
even more complexity to what we already
experienced in our world so Alex why
don't we start with you I'd like to go
down the panel and just tell me what you
are thinking about now and preparing for
or worried about that might be coming up
in the next year or two years yeah I
think GDP is a good good baseline as we
put it but as we are a digital company
we are looking very much in new
technologies it's um it's providing
actually also some no answers I should
say to some of the challenges the new
technologies are bringing with them so
like IOT how how we are dealing with
that are we thinking about machine
learning blockchain these are answers we
are looking into obviously we now need
to look into it from a gdpr perspective
but we also want to find answers to it
from from our perspective how we are
interpreting it and how we are giving it
and yeah maybe not only one one legal
framework answer here but really an
ethical answer to how we manage personal
data with those new technologies so one
of your concerns would be sort of like
the 1995 directive could not contemplate
smartphones and the internet and social
media gdpr
may not be fully formed to contemplate
IOT and facial recognition and AI and
other things great there is new I think
working in an insurance company really
is to my benefit because so if you can
ensure risk they'll find it yeah yeah so
that's been pretty cool and so I think
one of the things you were talking about
new technologies and whether the privacy
laws really do help with that because
under GDP are one of the concerns is
monitoring behavior of individuals at
what point does this law start and stop
when it comes to innovation I think
that's really been a big I think that's
a big future challenge for any
organization you want to use data to
innovate can the privacy laws keep up
can we ensure that these privacy rules
are evergreen as well that these are the
principles that we can rely on to ensure
that innovation is there but also
individual rights because people tend to
forget about the people behind the
scenes so when a reasons I like privacy
laws it is focus on preserving
individual rights fantastic Hillary the
thing I'm most worried about actually is
when we haven't spend time talking about
and that is the restriction under GDP
are on cross-border data flow and the
limited mechanisms that exist right now
to actually make that happen
many of which actually are under threat
as potentially not being vehicles that
can be used in the future so currently
there are means by which people move
data lawfully using contracts the
standard contracts that have been
approved by the European Commission are
actually currently being challenged as
to their validity and so there may not
be a standard anymore in the absence of
a standard one individual company needs
to go to a regulator and get approval
for each form of agreement that they
need imagine how much that will slow
data flows so I worry about whether
there will be vehicles such as gdpr
certification or codes of con
or other forms of framework mechanisms
that will allow data to flow around the
globe the way it needs to in order to
drive the digital economy I think that's
a great one and I'll add to that mix
brexit so Hillary's absolutely right to
raise the issue of data transfers under
GDP are you cannot transfer data outside
of the European Union unless you have a
mechanism for transferring data outside
of the European Union those data
transfers are going to get much more
complex after brexit okay we are in the
speed round of our panel we have an
audience of incredibly engaged
information security professionals here
with us from your perspective as a data
protection expert what is the most
important thing that these information
security professionals should take back
to their office Alex yes actually data
privacy is going hand-in-hand with
information security we actually did
something very similar what happened at
Erin we partnered with our information
security team and built our enhanced
data privacy program in or within the
framework of information security
we now have implemented a team of
fifteen data privacy and information
security leads that's actually how they
are called and you see from the title or
name that they are not only doing data
privacy but also information security
because we are big believing that you
can't actually detangle that without a
good course so there is this idea that
whenever you have data personal data you
need to have security around sirs and
security is the dependency on how
privacy programs run so coming together
or getting together both angles and
actually hugely helpful and therefore I
think all security people should have
regular conversation with the privacy
people as a company Therese knee I would
just add on
that to say it's about speaking a common
language I think in the past you know
the legal department and security and
technology didn't speak a common
language and the GDP art allows for that
kind of conversation to happen a
security professional should know some
of the intricacies of gdpr and how it
affects their job and so with does a
legal department I think couple days ago
I spoke about the legal department
understanding terms in cyber security
and cyber attacks the different types of
cyber attacks that exist and so coming
together and speaking the same language
it's hopefully the take away from the
GDP are excellent Hillary and I will
just echo what they're saying through
the words integrated data governance and
risk management's excellent I will add
my point that I think this group should
take away and that is that the privacy
professionals the data protection
professionals in your organization are
your colleagues in arms they are your
partners in managing this incredibly
complex digital economy I'll tell you
one of the things that gives me great
hope for our future in data protection
in the digital economy is the strength
and wisdom of leaders like this so I
hope you'll join me in thanking our
panelists for a great conversation thank
you