thank you guys for coming my role
previously previous jobs of the last 15
years was to go into security operations
centers evaluate their maturity evaluate
their effectiveness see what they're
doing right what they're doing wrong and
what I've done is taken that history
into my current role at Palo Alto
Networks to kind of evaluate here's what
we need to be doing so that's what we're
doing it at Palo Alto is trying to
figure out what we should be doing next
and what I'm going to show with you
share with you today is my experience of
large companies small companies
companies that are new to sock companies
they've been doing it for 15 years
things that are working in things that
definitely aren't and not here to poopoo
on anybody's sock telling them that
they're doing it wrong
but what I want to do is tell you about
things that people are doing right so
that we can all kind of elevate our
effectiveness together so let me find my
clicker so like I said I've been in a
bunch of socks
the first sock I ever walked into my
life it was it had a man trap so don't
know if you know what those are but she
walk into the door and you step on the
scale and you shut the door behind you
and then it weighs you and make sure
that she weighed the right amount and
then you're allowed in or not and I
thought that was the coolest thing ever
I thought this place is made of magic i
sat down and they had you know all the
big screens on the side and I thought
this place is amazing and then you start
to get into and you're like okay this is
actually harder than it looks they don't
have it all figured out since then I've
been in socks where you know there's the
fancy snap glass and I'm here to tell
you that if they have that snap glass
where it's if you can't see through and
then they turn on a switch and you can
see through it from the EBC those
actually don't tell you that they're a
better or worse sock they just are
expensive some other things I've been in
socks where it's just an open cube area
I've had I've seen socks where it's the
network operation center people sitting
right next to the Security Operations
Center people do not do that please we
always want to separate the Watchers
from the doers and even though we're
moving towards where we want these
people to integrate and we want their
processes to work together we
want them to be hand-in-hand we do not
want them sitting next to each other and
influencing directly what each other are
doing so just to just the hint there
keep your knock in your sock separate
but talking a lot I've also seen where
you know there was a closed-in room
where people walked into the room and
sat down for 15 minutes in the morning
and checked their console and walked out
and that was their sock so there's a
bunch of different types of socks I'm
sure every different kind is represented
here from very large to very small but
that's kind of what we're working with
these days and we all need to be getting
better at it so how did we get here
I mean socks kind of came around
officially in about the 70s and at that
point I was really governments
governments were the only people that
needed a sock because who would attack
just a citizen so that's where you know
in the 70s by the way I got this off of
an HP paper but in the 70s it was kind
of governments and it was about kind of
like those nuisance attacks but then we
moved into kind of the second generation
of sock and it became really those
nuisances so nuisances for businesses I
started becoming a bigger problem but
still the only people that had socks
were those super fortune 100 type
companies if if even then then stage 3
that's when we started you know living
ecommerce everybody was on the Internet
and so you know cyber crime started
people start to figure out they can make
money from it and so what happens is the
sock has to evolve to be able to account
for that so that's when we're seeing
stage 3 is where we're seeing a ton of
financial groups really elevating their
security operation centers and then for
for is 2007 to 2012 and that's when
we're starting to see cyber warfare you
know Stuxnet existed before them but
that's when it was actually found so
that evolves how your how your sock is
actually working you no longer just
intrusion detection you're actually
doing intrusion prevention hopefully but
you know that the tools are increasingly
a number of tools that you have keep
going up
so that's stage four or the fourth
generation of socks then this little
thing happened the target breach so
there's everything before target and
there's everything after target and the
reason is is because target was the
first time an executive got fired so
completely change the game of the sake
now you say well I worked in a sock it
really didn't change that much it did
because it was the executive started to
see they're responsible for these
breaches they're getting more involved
so you might have seen more money come
into a sock you might have just seen
more pressure and more oversight come
into a sock but that's the difference
between four and five and I think today
we're still in this Stage five I think
some organizations are starting to get
to a next generation but right now Stage
five so you know we're trying to use
analytics we're using hunt we we're kind
of using hunt I'll talk about that in a
minute
you know we're started to really get
into the automation really build it into
our organizations kind of some people
doing better than others but we'll we'll
get into that so that's the layout of
how we got to where we are so I'm gonna
go through a couple things that I found
number one well number one was the snap
glass thing and I told you about but
this one number one naming makes no
difference so everybody's trying to come
up with different name security
operation centers of course the normal
cyber defence centre is kind of a close
second people are coming up with
Security Intelligence and operation
centers if you put the vet defence
center in there does it make it sound
more interesting if you put intelligence
in there does it make it make you sound
more smart you can call it whatever you
want fusion center I like fusion center
because it's kind of the holistic the
business is coming together and it makes
no effect no effect on the effectiveness
of your sock so does anybody not called
a sock here do you call it one of these
other names hands nobody's gonna admit
it okay fine I do get asked about sock
2.0 what if I call it sock I have a sock
2.0 okay
Sauk 2.0 is misused everywhere we use it
in marketing we use it everywhere
originally Sauk 2.0 was defined by
Forrester and it's basically a
virtualized Sauk so the idea is that you
can automate the first line analyst so
the only thing left for a sock to do is
that advanced analytics that advanced
investigation of the incidents and the
theory is that those are specialized
feature specialized tool sets that a
person has and they can do that remotely
so you don't actually have a physical
sock you have experts based around the
world that are pulled in to do what they
need to do that's Sauk 2.0 I've never
seen anybody do it so while it's great
Theory nobody is doing sock 2.0 so don't
buy into that so that's the naming call
it a sock that's fine number two the
mission matters so when the biggest
things I see for socks that fail is that
they're trying to take on too much or
they don't even know what they're
supposed to be doing so when I define a
sock I say your analysts do three things
identify investigate and mitigate
threats
that's all they should be doing and you
say no no we have to do all these other
things on the right your organization
has to do all of these other things on
the right your analysts do not and the
problem is if they start doing all of
these things in the no column their
mission is going to be diluted so that
means they're not gonna be effective at
it so you need to be able to define
here's what the sock does here's what
they don't do all of these other things
are necessary so somebody has to do them
but not your analyst so one thing that
I've actually seen work for a sock is
they came up with their mission they had
their limited scope and they actually
came up with a service catalog here's
the things that we are going to provide
to you and kind of just give a little
bit more of a definition of here's what
we do and here's what we don't do
another example of a terrible mission
statement I worked with a sock that
they got requests from the business to
say I need this port open on the
firewall and the sock would turn around
and create a ticket for the engineers to
do I said that's what you do
yes that's what that's what our security
operations center does no no so
hopefully nobody in this room is in that
position but it was not a small company
it was a very established company so to
find your mission well limit the scope
of what you're doing problem number
three or solution number three we all
have a people problem we hear about this
every day we've lived it for a decade
two decades I put a question mark on it
and I'll talk about why one we know we
don't have enough people we know that
we're trying to train them in University
we're trying to make sure that we have
the next generation to help us staff our
security operation centers is not
working I worked with a very large
energy company in the United States and
they tried to create their own internal
security university within their program
within their company they were an energy
company and they built a security
training program they did it for two
years they spent a lot of money they
trained a lot of people that went to
work for somebody else so it doesn't it
doesn't always work but but that's
that's the the problem right we get we
get in people we train them up and now
they've got the elevated skill set
they're like oh I'm gonna go find more
money work in a different place the
problem gets worse if you live in a
place where there's even less resources
so if you are in Australia there's only
so many people that do security in
Australia you're gonna have to ship them
in I mean it's not hard to convince
people like myself I love Australia to
move down there but you you have it not
only a limited resource pool but a
limited area that you can draw people
from so that makes it worse but I'd like
to argue that it's not just a people
problem like we created this problem
ourselves we created this problem
because well the attackers created the
problem because now they're now they're
automated so
they can launch attacks they just spin
up botnets they can rent um all of a
sudden we have too many events coming in
and what do we do we say we have to hire
more people
that's our go-to so we're creating that
people problem and that's not the right
solution the other thing is low fidelity
data is overwhelming our socks and so I
don't even know how long ago now when
did seem to come out over a decade ago
everybody said I want to sim because
what's gonna happen is I'm gonna take
all my security data I'm gonna put it in
one place single pane of glass it's all
gonna get correlated together it's gonna
be simple I've solved all my problems I
now have a sim most people pull all that
data in to their sim and don't do
anything with it so now all I've done is
congregated all of this data they don't
know what to do with so then that also
leads to more of the people problem so
that's what we need to solve say how the
heck do we do that well we'll get there
too
one other note - on Sims number of feeds
does not equal use cases so a lot of
times people will buy their sim and they
say oh I've got you know ten feeds
coming into it that doesn't mean
anything if you don't have the right use
cases built on it then you're not really
doing anything additional so number of
feeds does not equal actual
effectiveness in your sock keep that in
mind does anybody know what this is
nobody okay this is a Turing machine so
during World War two the Germans were
using an Enigma machine to to encrypt
all their messages we couldn't the
Americans the Brits couldn't figure out
how to decrypt them fast enough and the
problem reason was is because they kept
changing their cipher at a range that we
had rooms full of people and couldn't
figure out how to decipher them quick
enough so Alan Turing's like oh we need
a machine to fight a machine and this is
exactly what we need today we need
machines to fight machines not people to
fight machines because it's not working
we can't we can't train enough people to
handle it we don't have rooms big enough
for the amount of people that we need to
fight this thing so we need machines to
fight machines so this is a this is a
depiction of current this is my view on
how analysts spend their time so
Anderson Osaka spent almost all their
time identifying stuff most of the time
it's false positives most of the time
it's noise most of the time they don't
do anything with it besides ignore it
again feeds do not equal use cases so
they might have 20 feeds coming in but
if they're not doing anything with it
it's junk they're overwhelmed you know
it's low fidelity data they might only
see half of the picture because they're
not using SSL decryption it's just it's
just junk and they're wasting their time
on it so what do they do they be tune
the sensors say well we're getting too
much data in so I'm just going to detune
my sensors so I don't get as much data
in okay that's one way to do it that
happens all the time the other thing is
they can just ignore alerts so the first
sock that I walked into that I told you
where I got into the mantrap I sat down
next to an analyst and we looked at a
screen full of alerts and I said oh my
gosh that's you know there's there's 20
of them there there's only one of you
what are you gonna do about it
he does I select all delete you can't do
that well you just did he's like oh
those are probably all false positives
anyway and that's how he solved his
problem okay that's not what we can do
kid that's not what we do
the other thing is if they do find
problems then they're gonna create a
ticket for somebody else to solve
they're never gonna have a closed-loop
process they're gonna see the same
problem again so it's kind of the how
fast can we can we close out issues
without actually solving the problem
maybe we need to upgrade an application
maybe we need to upgrade a firewall
whatever we need to do let's do it
instead of just try to get people to do
closed tickets as fast as they can and
all of this just causes our people to
burnout which again leads to increase
our people problem so it's a
self-fulfilling process and prophecy
now do they really ignore events now
besides my personal experience of the
select all and delete this was research
done last year by ESG I don't know if
you guys can read it in the back does
your organization ever have to ignore
some security events alerts that you
believe should be investigated further
but can't because you can't keep up with
the overall volume more than 50 percent
said yes I think the other 43% are lying
to themselves but over 50 percent
acknowledged that yeah we ignore things
because we just don't have time to deal
with it as a business that's not what
you want to hear as practitioners that
we get this this is our life we need to
change it so one thing I've seen work
people are moving towards prevention
based architectures so instead of just
detect and respond detect and respond
detect and respond we've heard it for
you know every some vendor ever I used
to work for one we need to move back to
actual protection before it comes in I
believe that if we changed the inputs
and the outputs of a sock we can change
what actually happens in a sock and so
the prevention based architecture is
something that I've seen consistently
working for organizations so what does
that mean the first thing is consistent
protection so whether you're working
Network Cloud endpoints you need to make
sure that you have consistent
protections against all of them that
they're all updated at the same time
because if you lock the front door but
you leave the back door open you're not
helping yourself so figuring out how to
get that consistent protection we used
to think well that means you know I got
two by two firewalls I got two by two
that I got a you know if my first
firewall doesn't catch it my second
firewall will know you just need to make
sure that things are implemented
properly and make sure that you have the
consistent protections across your
environment so it's number one number
two is centralized management so
centralized management great I only have
to learn one tool that seems like it'll
make everything faster correct it will
also make things manageable so if you
have an update that you need to do you
can do it across your entire
environment instead of onesie twosie you
have to have the centralized management
and to make sure that everything is
update at the same time because you
don't want your Japan office to be
behind in your Sydney office to be you
know three levels up from Japan or else
they're gonna get into your network
you're gonna be in trouble anyway so
centralized management helps you with
that the third piece of prevention based
architecture is automated threat
prevention so I've been in numerous
socks and I say how do you guys handle
threat intelligence and they say well we
just subscribe to all these different
feeds it's overwhelming there's too much
so well okay what do you do when you get
this threat intelligence how do you
consume it they say well we get it an
email we read it and then within a week
or two we press out we push out some
updates we have our IOC as we update
those a week or two email people problem
you get where I'm going with that not
scalable and then takes a week or two to
update so there's automated threat
prevention available in lots of
different places you just have to let it
run so what this means is that a threat
comes in an IOC comes in and it
automatically updates your controls
whether it be your endpoints whether it
be your firewalls whether it be you know
your your cloud access you can get to
read permission to five minutes now I'm
not saying you're gonna get that for
every threat but if you can get it down
to five minutes from two weeks that's
going to make you better protect it so
that's the third piece and then the
fourth piece is moving all of our
prevention closer to the business so
closer to users applications data
services we want to make sure that we
are protecting those things not just the
network because who cares about the
network if we can't protect the users of
the apps and the data and the services
so that's kind of along the lines of
zero trust another topic that's going
around so all that together is in
prevention based architectures
this is where we want to be I've the
companies that I've seen do this so far
are not small they have a lot of money
they've put a lot of time into this but
I think that's how it always works is
that the bigger guys with the with the
budgets are going to be able to get
there first and then it can trickle down
to some of the more medium sized
organizations but what it's going to do
is you're gonna have that automation for
consistency so that again your Japan
office in your Sydney officer at the
same levels you're gonna have better
outcomes the reason you're gonna have
better outcomes is because you're not
spending all of your time tracing down
false positives and nuisance data you're
actually gonna have time to investigate
it's gonna go faster and the key is that
you want machines to do what machines
are good at you want people to do what
people are gonna so machines are good at
events machines are good at pattern
matching people are good at situations
people are good at finding patterns that
those machines can that's what we want
them to work on and that's where
investigate works ultimately they'll
have more job satisfaction so we're
taking away that the overwhelming
feeling of too much data
crappy data we're giving them more job
satisfaction so hopefully with all of
these things we're helping that people
problem I did want to note on the
mitigate section there's a bunch of
tools out there that will do automated
remediation edr XDR i know of one
company that has stood and done it that
has turned it on and this isn't probably
in the past two months that i've kind of
asked who's doing it and I mean fully so
that an action incident comes in and
they fully stand back and let it go turn
off the Machine pull it off the network
do whatever everyone else is scared for
good reason I mean you don't want to go
and turn off the CEOs laptop because
it's infected you really want to but you
know it could cause business impact so a
bunch of people use those tools to alert
them say this one should be taken off
the network here's the next action but
there
not many that are willing to do that yet
I think that's going to change hopefully
very very quickly so where else does
this get us this red part right here
this is hunting this is where we all
want to be so who here does hunting
nobody's raising their hands today for
me I got a couple hands okay
many many companies say that they do
hunting or they want to do hunting again
very few do or do it effectively so what
is hunting hunting is smart people
looking for things that couldn't be
found else by anything else so this is
smart people doing smart things not what
machines do machines do what they do
this is smart people doing smart things
the people that are good at it they take
time to do it and it's not just okay
it's Friday afternoon here's two hours
go figure something out it is here's two
weeks your mission is to be a hunter for
two weeks it's going to be documented
we're gonna have a process for it
we're gonna meet every morning and do it
like a sprint stand-up meeting to figure
out what they've done but it's gonna be
goal oriented process driven it's gonna
be driven by a piece of intelligence so
a lot of times it's so I've heard of
this new threat and I want to know if
I'm affected by it sometimes it's a
review of blocked events you go back
through your firewall to figure out what
you blocked figure out why figure out if
you're under attack
so always driven by a piece of
intelligence and then it ends with what
we've learned if you haven't learned
anything then your process is junk and
you need to go back and figure out a
different process for hunting this is
the way we want to be and these are the
companies that are successful with
hunting those that are unsuccessful are
those that say here's two hours on a
Friday go find something they buy they
invest in a data scientist who doesn't
know anything about security so it's a
good way to spend a lot of money I've
seen it done I've done it
but that's that's how it's not gonna
work you need those security people you
need to give them enough education that
they can go play in the data and find
what they want but they need to know
what they're looking for so that's how
you make hunt work so given that is
anybody doing hunt okay
my next big heart attack my issue
all right in your security operation
center who uses less than ten tools and
you have to raise your hand from one of
these so you're not getting out of it
who uses less than ten tools two three
okay who uses ten 250 tools should be
most most who uses over fifty it happens
it happens from what I've seen this is
nothing official I've never sent out a
survey but what I've seen is the average
is about forty forty tools I've talked
to CISOs that say see so the main big
banks and such that say all I'm doing is
vendor management it's all I do all day
I got the lunch it's night no it's doing
vendor management's taking calls it's
learning about new tools it's getting
the pitches they're not actually doing
security they're just doing vendor
management that needs to change what can
we do about it well everybody's got this
problem it's kind of like the people
problem we also have the too many tools
problem I think everybody has the new
shiny I want to buy one of those problem
I'm not sure how to get over the shiny
thing problem besides to say don't do it
but a bigger thing is very limited
feature use so what happens is we buy
all these technologies and then we don't
implement them fully we have a legacy
firewall and then we buy this brand-new
fancy firewall and we say okay I'm gonna
I'm gonna use all those features I'm
gonna buy all the subscriptions I'm
gonna do all the things and you take
your old firewall and you plop all your
rules into your new firewall and then
you don't do anything else and all
you've done is upgraded your metal here
you have the same security that you did
the past five to seven years except for
in a new shiny box so this happens over
and over and over again this is one of
the big pitfalls I've seen especially
with subscriptions I've seen people
spend forty thousand dollars on a
monthly subscription and never turn it
on if the people running the business
knew this they would have a heart attack
but as practitioners we understand well
we're busy we don't have time to learn
this new thing or turn it on well you
need to make time because this can make
you more more protected one of the seats
those I work with out of the Middle East
he has a rule if they want to add a new
tool into his sock they have to take out
too it's a pretty good rule it's working
for him so hard it so far it makes the
employees of the sock have to work think
a lot harder about what they want so it
takes the luster off of the shiny object
problem but it really works for him to
reduce the amount of tools so here's
another problem
extensive vendor management yeah you're
spending too much time talking to
vendors you have duplicate functionality
because you haven't actually turned on
all your features but the other thing
every time you buy a new tool what is
the what does the person want you to do
you just have to install this one agent
you just have to put this one more box
in your data center it's just one more
thing you have to add so what happens is
you have end-user degradation so your
user experience is slower it might be
eating you know the batteries of your
handhelds it's actually affecting your
users for every single one of these
tools that you you buy so what I predict
is gonna happen is there's gonna be a
consolidation of platforms I do not mean
a rollup I do not believe that when big
companies buy all the little startups
that that's a winning strategy because I
think we've all seen when really good
companies get bought up by bigger
companies and maybe it doesn't work out
quite right and that feature of that
technology that innovation kind of dies
on the vine so when I say consolidation
on the platform I do not mean a big
company buys up all these little
companies what I mean is that there's
going to be some big players that come
out with platforms and all of the
startup companies that we see all of the
fantastic innovation that we see those
are going to become features of the
platform it doesn't mean they have to be
bought by the big company it just means
they become a feature and so it changes
the way that we're consuming technology
it's changing the
that were were only having to install
one agent because all of our features
use the same data anyway so let's have
one agent it pulls in all the data and
then we have all these features that can
act on it so I think that that's the way
that it's going to move we've already
started to see some of the the players
do this and it's going to help us with
our our other problems of vendor
management etc so we want less tools we
want more features that's the goal but
but but what if I just build my own I
hear this especially the ones with money
I'm just I'm just gonna build my own
platform I'm gonna do this myself no
this doesn't work there was a large
customer down not when I say customer I
don't mean my customer I mean somebody
that I've spoken with down in Australia
who spent two years and about 20 million
dollars and it didn't work and they said
oh nevermind it was a fantastic idea
they had all the rights knowledge to do
it they just couldn't do it so high cost
low results don't try to do it yourself
there's one exception I've seen another
different energy company who is building
their own but what they've done is they
they are one that has bought every
product on the market and then when they
build their own they're building all the
integrations of all those different
products my guess is that most of you in
this room don't have the budgets or the
time to do that so when you say I'm just
going to build my own don't doesn't work
okay side note of cloud switching topics
to cloud this isn't a fully shock
message but everybody has questions
about clouds so here's some things that
I'm seeing in cloud everybody's very
very cautious the first year is usually
really really slow
these are the three big players
Microsoft Amazon and Google there's a
couple others but these are the three
that are really coming out a lot the big
guys that I know are on their second
third fourth iterations the first time
they always say I'm just gonna lift and
shift I'm just gonna take all of my
current applications I'm gonna throw my
cloud and then I'm gonna fix them later
it doesn't work and so if you're
planning your cloud journey and you say
I'm just gonna I'm just gonna pick them
up and put them in the new in the cloud
so unfortunately it doesn't work that
way
you're gonna have to take the time to
change the way applications work for the
cloud here's the other thing is that if
something was insecure and junky before
cloud it's gonna be unsecured and junky
in cloud so you have to do that
changeover you have to add in that
security before it's actually gonna work
so that's what I've seen there there's
also a lot of regulation challenges that
people are trying to figure out the
bigger ones are gonna have to figure
that out before the smaller guys cuz you
don't have time we don't have the money
to figure that out so it's ever-evolving
as far as protections the big the big
players Microsoft Amazon Google have
made it pretty clear about what they
protect and what they don't read the
fine print of your your contracts but
basically they protect their
infrastructure you protect all of your
data in it you protect all of the
traffic flows to and from it they
protect their data center you protect
everything else so data coming to and
from the cloud the data in the SAS
applications that you're using all the
user controls that's on you so when they
say oh I'm gonna buy the secure cloud no
you're gonna buy a cloud that is secure
on its own and once you put your stuff
into it
that's your problem
would just keep that in mind the other
thing is that prevention based
architecture the zero trust model if you
get that right in your network when you
move it over to cloud it's still gonna
work so a lot of times people say well I
don't want to do I don't want to do this
zero trust model until I move to the
cloud because I don't wanna have to redo
it you don't have to so do it now and
then you can move it to the cloud as
your business moves so number six there
was pre target there's after target
there's pre the business really caring
and now the business really cares so
working with the business is something
I've seen change a lot over the last
five years or so one of the big things
this sock NOC integration but not
physically do not put them in the same
room but it's it's more of the sock fine
something bad you have to work with the
network to go fix it block it prevent it
so that they don't see it again in the
sock
this works for bigger companies smaller
companies the sock is still an island
unfortunately and I don't mean small
companies I mean medium-sized companies
unfortunately the sock is still an
island so that's something that we have
to continually break down I have seen an
increase of socks CISOs reporting
directly to a CEO so that's interesting
you know 15 years ago it was the
security always reported to IT which is
a conflict of interest it's bad because
then the security people say well we
need to fix this and the IT person says
no no that'll take my network down and
so you have an issue so it's changed
over the years to the seaso reports to
risk and compliance or they report to
audit or they report to the CEO anyway
so that's how things have changed but
I've actually seen them report to the
CEO now so that'll be interesting how
that plays out business unit alignment
something that I've seen people do
is instead of buying an analyst you buy
you buy instead of hiring a new analyst
you hire a business liaison so this
person's gonna figure out what sort of
controls do we need on the business why
do we keep saying no and the business
keeps saying I hate you
let me do what I want and so they've
actually found a lot of benefit from
hiring that business liaison instead of
just another analyst other things there
Automation developers and operations and
engineers so not just the process not
just figuring out the processes and
engineering within the sock but finding
it between especially with cloud working
with those developers what do they need
what sort of templates do they need to
be able to spin up their virtual
environments quickly and securely so
investing in those as opposed to just
the pure analysts you know I forgot to
mention before to is with the people
problem a lot of times people say well
I'm just going to use an MSS they have
the same people problem we do so if
you're thinking about using an MSS just
keep that in mind a managed security
provider they may have the same people
problems that you do anyway so the
automations and operations engineers
kind of help if you are working with an
MSS figuring out those processes between
them and you and like I said small
businesses are still on an island I have
seen organizations where they run
reports and they say here's all the
applications that you're running go deal
with it they're never going to deal with
it you just gave me or the traffic cop
you just gave them a report and they're
never gonna do anything so that that
operations engineer can figure out those
processes to make sure that you lock
down those applications or you strictly
allow those applications so you're not
wasting your time on that anymore
so one more big topic metrics
I hate metrics and I love metrics all at
once
the right metrics drive change and
unfortunately our metrics suck they are
terrible they have been forever and so
I'm trying to push what I've learned
into what's what are terrible metrics
and what are good metrics and the
biggest thing is you have to ask
yourself can I do anything with the data
that I'm providing it's the so what you
give you given number hey today we're a
42 so what is that better or like what
are you gonna do with that information
so you always want to have metrics that
mean something so here are terrible
metrics and number one everybody has
because the business likes to see it
because security grew out of IT and IT
cares about how fast can you get the
network back up how fast can you do
things and so we've inherited mean time
to resolution mean time to response it's
terrible it drives the wrong behavior
because what you're doing is you're
telling your analyst how fast can you
get this how fast can you close it how
fast can you select all and delete how
fast can you close this ticket which is
not what we want them to do that does
not make the business more secure so
meantime the resolution is terrible
number of incident is handled is kind of
one of those so what I did I did 16 so
what if there were 200 then that's
terrible if there were 16 then that's
fantastic so number of incidents by
itself doesn't matter number of alerts
maybe you turned on any sensor and so
now you've doubled your alerts that by
itself just as a media thing and number
of feeds like I said I got 50 feeds
coming into my sock who cares if you're
not doing anything with it then it
doesn't matter and a note on red yellow
green I hate red yellow green here's why
if you show your board hey today we're
green you should never tell them you're
green you are never you should never be
comfortable that you're not
get attacked tomorrow this is a false
sense of security if you say oh we're
only at a yellow oh good I can go home
and sleep tonight no you have no idea
what's gonna happen tomorrow so red
yellow green is misleading and I don't
think that we should use those for
overall security of our companies so
what does work this is my rant I love
this there's two types of metrics I
think all metrics should fit into these
there's configuration confidence whit's
which is what is my confidence that my
technology my controls are up and
running that are configured to best
practice and are operating as I intend
them to operate so that's one set of
configuration I'm confident in my
configuration of controls the other is
I'm confident in my operations of those
controls do I have the people in place
so I have the processes in place can I
actually use the technology that I have
up and running because ultimately the
business doesn't care about number of
feeds or number of alerts they want to
care they care about what's the threat
am i affected how big is it and when's
it gonna be fixed that's what they care
they don't care about number of alerts
that came in today so what are some
examples configuration confidence are my
controls running so this is really hard
so you you go out and you install a
bunch of firewalls you install a bunch
of endpoint protection and then somebody
needs to make a machiya change in this
corner of your network and so they turn
off the firewall or they turn off some
rules on the firewall and then they
forget to turn it back on and it's
really hard to actually know that that
happened it's hard to track that so our
controls are running that's something
that we have to lock down just because
we installed it doesn't mean it's
running figure out what's been changed
especially in cloud
so there's configuration drift and so we
could need to figure out we started out
at this point and 48 hours later it got
someplace else we need to know about
those are we configured the best
practices if not why that's fine
feature use so if we're only using 5% of
our features which by the way I didn't
audit on a customer and they were using
5% of the technology that they had
bought we need to know that you know you
bought this technology go and use it and
be able to measure it and ask your
vendors to make to tell you okay I
bought your endpoint solution am i using
it right how much of it am I using ask
them to figure that out for you
and then percent of traffic visible
so if 70 80 percent of our network is
encrypted how much of it can we see are
we using SSL decryption can we not
because of certain regulations we need
to know these things to be able to run
the business and have a sense of am i
confident that I can handle an attack
which is where the operational
confidence comes in this is I'm going to
be attacked I'm going to I don't know if
it's tomorrow I don't know if it's next
week it's probably continuous
operational confidence is can you handle
it when it happens so a couple of
metrics around that events per analyst
hour this is like the or the holy grail
of all of the sock metrics because this
means if events per analyst hours to
high your analysts are overwhelmed
they're gonna miss things they're gonna
delete things if it's too low then you
can give them extra work to do it
whenever it's never too low but events
pray and all this tower is probably if
1313 is kind of what you're driving
towards and that's an extremely hard
number to get to but that's that's where
you can be confident that that analyst
can handle something that comes in
duplicate incidents if you see the same
incident coming in over and over and
over again that means there's a problem
in your controls there you're not your
closed loop process is broken because
it's not actually closing the loop
alerts for doing threats your control
should always be preventing known
threats you should never see those
coming into a sock and then deviation
from soft procedures if you have these
procedures in place and people keep
moving step five over here there's two
there's two problems that this could
indicate one is education people just
aren't using the processes correctly two
of your processes are terrible they need
to be rewritten so those are things that
are actually going to help you be
confident that you can protect the
business so there's a quick recap
so what's working if people do it right
well-defined mission in scope identify
investigate mitigate period we want to
do noise reduction in the sock how do we
do that well prevention based
architectures we've we've seen work
prevent it before it even gets to the
sock automate the mitigation if you have
the confidence to do so if you can do
all that then attempt hunting don't say
you're gonna do hunting just because it
sounds cool and you need an extra
challenge on a Friday afternoon if
you're gonna do hunting formalize it do
it right full utilization of existing
tools so make sure that what you paid
for your subscription is their target
turned on you're actually blocking
you're not just alerting make sure that
you're using your tools that you bought
try to get it more business focus
sometimes this is hard if you work in a
small organization sometimes you are on
that Island so you get you got to try to
work on that but the tighter you are at
the business the more you can not just
say no and actually work with them on
solutions one of the people I know
that's on their fourth iteration of
cloud what they've done is they've
worked to the business to say here's our
preferred cloud vendor here's all the
services you can get from this
particular cloud vendor and I know that
developers are going to want some
feature over here and they can do that
too but it's going to be hard okay at
least they work to the business to come
up with a solution so they don't have to
fully support - clouds - cloud vendors
they have one that they support and one
that they have is extras
so next week define the mission of your
sock
make sure it's defined in short and
scope and make sure that the business
actually buys into it because if you
just say this is what we do but they
expect you to do this that's not going
to matter so make sure they buy into it
second is question all your metrics see
if you can actually change people away
from MTTR
it's gonna be hard but you can do it
make sure that your metrics are actually
telling you if you can with stain an
attack or not because that's really what
we're here to do just figure out can you
find it can you limit it we're not going
to prevent an attack but you need to be
able to prevent it spreading in your
network and actually exfiltrating data
that you need so preventing successful
cyber attacks is our goal
evaluate your tool set use your features
in the next six months try to go towards
that zero trust model that prevention
based architecture if you can do that
then move towards hunting and if they
let you hire hire business liaison move
those controls closer to what actually
matters to the business because it's
usually not what we think it is so
hopefully this has given you some
nuggets of information you can take back
we only have a couple minutes left but
I'll be around if you guys have
questions and I thank you guys for your
time
you mean as far as the third-party
provider of hunting I haven't seen a
whole lot of it I've heard about it but
I haven't actually seen it myself so I
can't tell you if it's a good idea or
bad um
in theory I think it would be good
because then you don't have to hire the
the skills but yeah but I haven't
actually seen it myself so I can't
answer yeah
right yep yeah
yes yeah so I think if mostly so what
what I've seen in machine learning and
AI is so my theory is you don't have to
be perfect you have to be better than
the analyst you just have to be better
than the human so it's so that's why I'm
saying yes it can be successful because
you don't have to be perfect what I have
seen is some of the machine learning AI
that's trying to replace that first line
analyst some are actually very good and
you can actually run them in parallel
with you can actually run through 30
days of your old data and compare what
the Machine found against your analyst
and and figure out if your analysts are
better or if the machine is better and
so you can go with that
yes yes yes
it's possible and I've seen yeah we can
talk later about some tools that I've
seen that are effective yeah
and I've only seen so here's why I don't
want to say hey this is the best tool
ever because I've only seen a small
amount of socks in the world and I've
seen certain things work for certain
socks so we can talk about that later
yes
be data breach with the vendors that's
all in your contracts I mean there's no
automated way to handle all of that it's
all in your processes if I'm getting
your question right so the way to handle
the breach is to make sure that you have
the right processes with your vendors is
that what you're asking
do we have any what a technical way not
that I've seen so yes because you're
monitoring you can monitor you know what
data is flowing back and forth what data
is flowing to that vendor maybe you'll
work with an MS SP but then you're
basically doubling the amount of work so
you're not trusting them so I think the
only way to do it technically is to
double you know you're monitoring them
they're monitoring you and that's kind
of a waste maybe we can talk later and
see if I can get a better answer for you
anyway else all right thank you guys for
your time