hello and hope my role on today will
tell you some stories about my name is
Alexander itself basically for now we're
totally unemployed researchers and
penetration testers also we lack of
matter a bit so I think we'll get up
it today to find a way out tried to
cover some engineering parts of our
research how it went and then the second
part on Excel will tell you about kind
of business and talked about things with
this kind of stuff
small project
total needed to create our own urine
test network and as you all know there
is an open source project doesn't convey
beat but it's no matter how also visits
to Gianni and so it couldn't help I will
go and how slowly started to walk to
look towards
kinda cheap hotels as a platform to
build on and apparently followed by the
way you Apr 21 of its sold to a number
of Chinese science no matter that its
officials contend it works in some
promising feelings about what awaits us
turns out that the past our goal wasn't
as simple as we wanted to be an
excellent way so we tried to look into
it kind of dip and found out after
looking for the publicly available
interfaces were found on the web
interface with us and with it and found
out that both consisted of two both
while many bars and write about so one
thing a personal attention it was at 26
pin to cannot amend boat and we thought
we could get some interesting stuff of
the 10 26 pants could be a lot of fun
some debugging face especially when it
says kinda debug folder keep things
simple way to do it because it's
flipping through walls so we don't find
and started to prague all the pins
Senate title house in another trying to
find some correlations and electrical
problems
pendant 60 positions sold that one of
the teams and secondly when I responded
will eventually find out that this is
Josh p.m. sticks and rocks so we
discovered that
those rare talks there by connecting was
also know that the Xbox has attracted
quite a bit of attention in the security
community and so it was kind of
interesting things for us
found out the CPU the kind of action /
for them and the fact that it's going to
boot to flesh so how did it go
the body was waiting for a key press and
if it didn't look impressed on the yacht
interface it would it turn normal mode
to the main software which recorded
blooper remote where everything is as
usual it's kinda and it's not a web
interface he also previously opposite if
we interrupted the boot up process by
press any key to adopt him to the some
kind of weeks what shall we call it a
radical mode in which you can definitely
tell it the metrics as long as like
discovering all kind of things so again
about the loophole mode is just the
plain woman so just conflagration face
for the concealer kinda boring opposite
retro most
an instant rice we found out that it
exposed some debug capabilities even
interpreter football 5+5 system Texas
and basically broken support so sorry
one by one the debug subsystem it has
good help in half
so it has all the things you need to
debug your looking less code for the
truck's brakes on step like trains
disaster all kinds of things more than
that it can even manage some running
task what can be kinda memory dumps
memory at its greatest manipulation and
even-handed approach into it so no one
was there for us like one of the most
interesting thing was found that the
show itself the tractor show was in fact
kind of see interpreter so you could
write to see code and executive and
executed line by line by line
resting place so I tested we wrote some
code
personality and now try to show them how
it worked for us so I came to this
device get in the front seat conversion
and then just gotta based on our code
credence assault trust structure and
member of Xbox minded tribe interest in
the past hour and then we just issue 4
comments to connect and write something
like I do you think so it's kind of like
you had a nice personality for sure I'll
just hold a pencil and executed right
away
also ahead for flash file system access
right out of the box it has all the
usual comments
2004 system list editorial director is
recursive listing which you can see on
the right you can take your files by all
the way around you can see in the left
corner apartment of the main
configuration file you have seen which
Toyota sold critical condition said it
was time to sell as it wasn't already
enough these guys also left some
networking capabilities so we could
transfer files back in first gear and
remote shell so also
started looking for what's running
actually on this board we found please
three interesting tusks self explanatory
the tell it to be served and WGBH
proceeded to face as they lost task with
the red line you see it down it's a task
which actually boots up some may say a
prayer for the blue pill mold if we're
really only because it will just go
first and resume to the normal function
of it so that come out again here in
this society long-running map is all of
them but the problem when we should the
review process or device we can not see
this anymore so we wanted to do how to
work with this kind of forward first
time with first place we wanted to get
rid of all these past two hours and you
are still we made an assumption that
during the boot up the system actually
the service started before it jumped
over the global mode so trying to it is
that simple little cold trying to
connect to the toilet and issues some
comments to stop them but into
medication and on the right you can see
the logo this actually talking to us
conduct a mild one out and then you can
see that just stopped and talked to
people which
after which would connect our script and
can connect to the 23 portal thomas
Howell and throw away all these wires
and closed about what communis well tell
it so much we needed to get the code of
the main software global called a lot of
ways to do this the most obvious by time
is just to dump it all with the comments
after the firmware of the blue contacts
and then parse it but it's kind of slow
most remember that there was wbrc
which is kind of famous stuff such as a
sport model which made public is dumping
the whole memory by this
means so it was the things we tested and
they work out for awhile it gave us food
ready for the right side console itself
and does ready to go for analysis it
would be even more awesome if someone
could write
natural tobacco use in this capability
is with her report profile chillin
Metasploit remember in Redmond our song
but somewhere out there so this time we
came to the best of our out for us for
complete analysis
as I've already mentioned we had broken
power the bug symbols and we had a
simple table which we need to talk early
with a lot of code with it was simple
but a Python script and after which it
looks quite what you can see all the
simplest this kind of miffed example one
function which relates to how this
device handles its licensing licensing
actually is this long basics to
fostering on the down side
which is which turns out to be encrypted
by ace
and
small about task was to find out how to
decrypt it we did it wasn't a problem we
found out that there is a static part of
key which is limited and actually the
rest was just last six fights last six
characters of so-called that the
UniqueID of the device that it was quite
simple as a binding global which
tourists searching for a licensed mental
preparation of main features such as
data bandwidth and our capabilities from
Microsoft 10 2012 cells so analysis
actually wanted
to execute our corner booth homo here we
didn't want to stay or always in this
blog entry the bootloader and again it
was placed always do it first is long
and boring the law the former director
rich clawed back hopes all goes well as
alternate tricks arms caches and so
nothing as we thought was quick and
dirty and the plot to be quick but it's
just thought we wanted to try to take
over control dynamic loads and loads so
far this we needed some kind of some
piece of software which could be
injected upon written upon some
obviously security function in the blue
pill
actually which rose
the one that those entering the password
for web interface we're over it was
small but that
as you can see it opens a socket
received some compounds he called on the
circuit ok i'm for it and
balance practice balls in your task out
of them so when somebody wanted to look
into the first pictures from the socket
would empower called the executor to get
everything back nice and clean but it
was not quick
actually not trust us to be created
equal
during a so second batch of these
devices were found out that some of them
did not have anything of this interfaces
that described right now I wasn't telnet
no WBR proceed looking to go out it was
kind of sad for us because we wanted to
buildup on the cheap little but for him
to continue to research to give it back
to the community 20 kind of its result
this interface is that was not what it
so we tried to think hard whether it was
lost and there was no actually
we took a while I guess I'll just 26 pin
connector
time we found out that we did it from
kind of moments away with it also
depends on ground where did had to do it
which we're blessed with a target now
open source
sketch for the banana
connected all the prince told of these
nicotine so that I didn't do it started
but fawcett looking for JTAG pins and I
like the critical it's quite slow
process on the marina and
nonetheless have to somehow or so we've
got it and it was a total you actually
checked all bones and all these great
thanks
so this was a doctor we need to follow
to
achieve this availability of the
platform at the cheap fun and
interesting to build on so we connected
in a strange way to gain the right
adapter so we just very connected to the
attack beans on the board eventually was
refreshed version of open LCD that
suppose been banging you can use the TPS
had written up to
so there you go
we try to connect with you this process
will you can for some special
information and so on
was
actually the arm 926 EJ process and kill
can see that not what we expected so
what's wrong with it what's wrong with
optimism
turned up no there was another set of
people the boat on his jumper pins was
some label underneath it
talk which said JTAG mode 0 and one
turns out that switch and generous with
good access different interfaces for
different devices there are still this
and our process that we were looking for
that I want was when we set up the jump
of the day technology so terrific
here is the output open Oct was
conducted successful
and
full blown debugging interface with
remote to be attached to openness of the
interface you can register as modified
by a modified jumbo loan without us help
but wait we really drop
and will total the way we could make it
more convenient
grandis improved from the first look
it can connect to remote but shows kind
of bullshit members so drunk that we
tried to google google some of these
messages and actually internets for
things it was to the rescue and was sold
this problem was a small bush actually
people already doing the fold them all
the change to us of court some
modifications and try again
and their egos can expect more of the
convenient interface to analyze it on
the run time it has all these all you
need is just to dump all this memory
again using generic it's doable then you
just ripped apart a script quarterly no
symbol table to hold you in the banking
and do whatever we are kinda glad to see
it cuz it restored our faith that with
such capabilities we could modify the
control flow in any way would like to
for example just replace it with a
well-liked from while first time to sell
so the girls and the conclusions for my
pot the kind of the cloaks both
engineering hardware stuff we must
always some devices and not all away
during the last time and actually quite
a few times we see this
real-time also expects a lot of medical
devices USB modems smartphones you name
it especially was much about where they
like that sometimes when you think there
is no walks this season and poking
around underneath it it's two weeks
folks controlling over the radio Paz
stuff require real-time operational so
the last time to load close
friends and colleagues well what can do
this
similar research about the trucks and
telecom telecom devices this thinks we
think that due to increasing deployments
of deployments on target devices with
increased work site has some more
thorough and deep research from the
community from all you guys there are
things to be researched and
that I think to be found please go poke
with your finally spoke out there that
you can hack so this was a fun part of
the song was stupid pictures now it's
kinda hard core with audio from Alex say
about our actual telecom paintings so
please welcome our site
part it was about 12 thought you know
about weeks forms but actually watch
networks for example on the on the
screen you can see you in September so
that's connected internet security
gateway which is connected to the US to
the song so there are too many different
region people here
variations that will blow your mind but
actually want to hear it what does
security gateway
ordinarily p.m. it protects all the
connections on trust that if you're
looking to the white party London
channels these details and trusted
because everything inside the core
network is trusted you don't want to
mess with it works in the main road so
there is no between two to get the
household and guys from the concern some
thought that a key or europe seem good
way to protect this connection against
malware or evil purposes what is
actually obscene or if it's just
randomly to the SIM card and it returns
to 52 or sector reform its over there
here that the security securely inside
the SIM card you repeated three times to
get enought metro and with this you can
connect with them on the reverse side
there is a Sturgis with these they do
the same things every picard really
secure element it seems legit but
basinger summit indication you can take
the SIM card out of the cell and
everyday 2020 GSM networks are not reply
protect protection so their first prompt
control over the time to sell over the
New York we take SIM card out of the
terminal inserted into day two different
pairs of random number and he came from
this and with the piece of software
software and data actually can connect
from the cell to yourself and gain
control over sensitive information that
is possible through through this channel
there is a way to do horrible things to
connect elsewhere not connect him to
sell to you but we think that would be
there is well known as trucks 1
that has different levels of EP 10 this
variance is simple you create the state
troopers and substituted in construction
and actually there is consideration for
such a thing you can connect most of the
based on but actually it's small text
their presentation will be made public
later so you can just the world take
this configuration inside the tunnel
things interesting it's because its
interface that is kind of protected
areas with you open points 100 already
said there was on the details from
outside from the inside there was
different kind of bolts from samples
centerfire 10069 there is a CPA Review a
different kind of things but too many
shoulders increases you need Benjamin so
so it's Gold Coast here and there are
two different parts of it its initial
hamas this provides basic authentication
of the cell where the FBI and serving as
your mouse cursor from moving from one
place to another
delegating program provides
congressional pretty apart for example
provides information to vote
channels scrambling codes and so this
provides access to get away it's a it's
a key component to so many other so what
are you can we stations enabled them up
into pieces you can get information
about users connected to this one to
sell you can get in formation abode
difficulties for goodness sake and so on
and so forth but there is also not much
interest because we want to create our
own network so we provided IP address of
the way home gateway and undersell
connects to it with a clear political
especially in the sales we're in the
core network you should send your
details on this incident elsewhere
because it was really good and there's
nothing to be done and what happened to
sell connected to the way ready to help
us we have four different begins
that night the second sandbar shark
accepting requests and hopefully it will
be but can't accept the request just
like that there is a protocol which is
the base for the all the connections
from the photocell to the core network I
L scandal in Linux Linux thinks where I
want it has been things to access your
software it's widely used in telecoms
but long story short every 23 minutes
breaks no good reason maybe it's what
was available so maybe it was my hands
and after the recession but its protocol
that is used for get away and as pretty
simple issues Cerberus story itself or
network and you can just accept it and
when the user connection to you
accepted as well so that so
come to the moment without any
connection to regional telecom software
hardware or software was ready to accept
users to eat well and achievement but
not easy there is different domains
inside the telecom network its sales
domain
voice messages and PAS domain for
internet when to sell it to a different
to the office so location of it requests
and if you try and just accepted it will
fail I was about to die and didn't know
what to do i dont no specification bowed
5:30 discs just as PDFs with different
versions with different information
documents linking to the other documents
that these documents and other ways and
so there is a plane planes to read but
there are a number of things that really
useful for creating a network it's
2400 aid its basic core network
protocols describes pretty much
everything about how to connect how to
manage the connection and took indicate
and also provides information about
indication encouraging networks there
are different boss wants
news I C 03 genetics are protected from
the jet X Games to the base station so
it's really impossible but we found some
different things that enjoyable inside
not normal behavior for example we can
issue an interview request prior to was
information about inside and so this
commission actually is
that information that you used to pull
someone over the air and control the
subscriber I am I so we can create our
sure that want to be need to also but
can provide information about where the
person he is and what he's doing so and
the user can be ended by both the SIM
card and by phone so if you take out the
SIM card from but other one
telecom network can also follow you and
when the same they that they can't
storm cell phones don't trust them there
is jim information you provide inside
information about
the network connection for example you
can use his full name you can change the
time zone for example here trouble and
different local time
well there are interesting talk on the
book had last year about personal issues
yes protection we brought us it was
based on the internet connections so
what's running faster and justice is
blowed but there are different
restrictions for example the main one is
so all the data is claimed to shoot so
you can't just send information to plant
in Tennessee next just sense in beating
the past and we all take it without the
station and the most interesting part
about him here he's not really there are
different opportunities to bypass
integrity checks those checks that way
station
specification
it's impossible but with the bed copes
but if it is to use it you can do
different things
example conditions can send ever to rest
on your cell base station and for
example you can take her to chase them
with us
Redhill and our whole we issued comments
to bring it to life
difference
2004 and that is why Boston tickets
because we don't have any information
about he's distorting
SIM cards we just posted
of every person as you can but it's kind
of dog do now service subscribers that i
connect into a fender self said it was
can see multiple sources that doesn't
mean but the most interesting part is by
nurses can be used to give give a team
from the SIM card there were researched
by speakers and you can conduct all
those attacks that the transcript of
countries by the air over 3G so if
you're desirable to gene your phone
still not protect it and the update
fails I wouldn't it be later what are
indications integrity control in the GSM
introduced this year just to say thank
you for it as a condition just four
bytes of data that is sent back to base
station and that's it doesn't operate
the phone doesn't address space station
for example there are two keys that is
used to build and dignity for decorative
and ask for proof of things to keep both
for client base station they both should
know this kid and it should be saved by
and recipes redundant but there is a
standard that it's not well known their
opportunities to connect four different
cells example SIM card doesn't provide
just a key indication when it came out
indicating and as for it just it was
among them into attacks
others to talk more generally better
they are using
protection against replayed takes so you
can just take one confirmation from the
scene cuts for a longer time but there
is an opportunity for just me just for
you yes it's just a month indication we
sent only one randomly turned to the SIM
card it received 64 bit key and but we
should obtain integrity and savory
come up with an idea why we just needed
some way so we decreasing but forcing
resistance to 64 bits and actually there
is an opportunity to create rainbow
tables for UMTS the kitchen and to break
it in the matter of seconds so maybe in
a matter of minutes and there are some
actual quote from the standard where
they can continue until he's 40 Frankie
foreign keys for the simple whatever
possible doctor richter's if you want to
connect someone to 3G network you can
use Creek and topping kisi forgiving
rent this information to any subscriber
to the time to sell you can use such
information from the cancer cells
area and without the proximity to the
gym or just use smart card for those who
will understand this screen shows that
all data that sent
card is just one issue actually predict
connection what I getaways in couple of
days we are going to issue talk it for
themselves
create your own the box you can have
functional security gate with management
so you can have me get away and
secretion to connect some or all of your
SIM cards to the femtocell and receive
SMS from it it's a serious ocean-going
so this code will be updated there will
be different cures for example for now
we're going to carry over the 3G create
our own region that we have friendly
femtocell actually can be bought from
different changes
marketplaces and the knowledge about
this is not everything that good books
because there are different
opportunities to do things wrong and
different opportunities to do things
right and actually it's kinda think like
that you can use by itself to do this
opportunities for future plans are you
going to pride diplomat analysis
analysis of the digital signal process
there are different opportunities to
over 4,000 because I someone is friendly
interface because there are different
opinions $0.02 entertainment of the
protocol and have fun we are thankful
for friends and colleagues different
guys from the internet
helped us in our search form slump or
mister off or Michelle Marie for
different stuff thankyou any questions