good morning and welcome to the second
session and briefings that black had
2015 just a couple of announcements
first of all there will be a reception
tonight in the business hall at 5:30 the
Business College located in Shoreline a
also the party awards take place tonight
in Mandalay BCD at 6 p.m. we want to
thank you for coming and you are in
Laguna currently for the breaking HTTPS
with BGP hijacking IR Tim Jago one
reminder please no matter how cool your
ringtone is we really don't wanna hear
it so make sure those cell phones are on
silent and with that are two handed over
to thank you very much so
higher one
standard my name is ok for those of you
who don't know how to spell this story
right there in the title breaking a GPS
will be hijacking and first of all
what's the BJP hijacking well I guess
some of you almost have you are already
familiar with the terms however let me
do some introduction and might well
doing this will also agree on some
important definitions and the first of
those definitions is what the internet
so from that maintenance point of view
and not the social network point of view
yet but that prompted technical point
the Internet
consists of Internet service providers
and protein all the packets in the
internet is down between those internet
service providers we call them
autonomous systems through the use of
border gateway protocol BGP
well basically it works like this
autonomous system connects to another
autonomous systems grow as export
permissions and if the permissions are
granted it starts to announce to other
systems that it can provide and access
to set up a network of those systems
propagate the announcement and finally
there's a route established and present
in the internet so the internet knows
where to go if we need to send it back
it to these not work well
so the Internet is only when it sold
begin autonomous systems used to trust
each other and routing was based on
trust as a result of their arrows at the
concept of hijacking that autonomous
system that starts to announce of those
prefix without your permission
different reasons why this could happen
well from evil governments trying to
silence public media to spammers trying
to use and used other space in order to
send junk mail
whatever there's a problem and different
mechanisms arrived to prevent ordering
use the problem of hijacking
technologists include a test sets wrote
objects are PTI BJP sec
however some of those technologists and
mechanisms only allowed to sell the
issue partially and others are not
implemented globally you know the
Internet is a global network so if we
security practice should be applied
globally but was applied only in a
specific geographic regions so now
nevertheless there were very few cases
of BJP hijacking registered recently for
instance the most recent case
investigated by our company was spammers
stealing a large portion of allocated
assigned but at that time
unused and not announced
IP address space to overcome black least
to continue sending digital garbage
least me as a big surprise for you when
do you wanna start using your fresh you
AP before the space an expensive one
year and then you find out that most of
your fresh new older the seating that
inspire hopes yet this case was almost
half a year ago so speaking about
hijacking yeah quite rare situation
however the applause and ASP politician
allow another problem to a rope like an
example of a road click is multi home
cinema system so no transit traffic that
important salts from a local beer and
due to a mistake in a configuration send
them to upstream internet service
provider so and it starts to
to work with transit traffic which it
isn't ready to handle duet human error
the recent is is to accomplish and on
the scene though since I B networks and
network prefixes including those of
Facebook tutor one operator level 3
their consequences included internet
slow down nearly worldwide so and that
situation with countermeasures against
leaking is given much worse than the one
we are hijacking unlike a jking early
Qing isn't is it took even isn't even is
it to define if you find out
IETF draft with the definitions long
paper describes what they're owed
leaking is so it's hard to even to
define it let alone the event so nobly
slow down and actually denial of service
up the possible results of meat leaking
or hijacking getting traffic network
from all over the world allows
man-in-the-middle attacks identity
proofing and more 20 game may be
implemented through an unauthorised use
or vulnerable network equipment and
border altars and it's quite another
coincidence that those internet service
providers who are bad in implementing
prefix filtering and security black
sista back to open hit have the
equipment and gateways and parched for
quite a long time so as I said
previously hijacking is quite rare
nowadays
on the other hand thing happens here and
there there are approximately 5,000 or
out
leaking in the whole internet right now
now at the moment most of them go
unnoticed
some of them remained there for years
until finally somebody gets killed
it's got discovered though wrote leaks
and hijacking quite different concept
chile as defined in the said idea
proposals up their consequences for
network security are similar as in most
cases so we are here discussing them as
one question is a common caused by human
error but we don't doctors still prefix
is intentionally well generally it might
be because they don't see profit in
hijacking and most of them are afraid to
get caught
afraid of getting caught let's review
some methods proposed by community to
detect hijacking the post of them is
tracking code is in the autonomous
system paths for a network with Excel
there somewhere in the world using
whatever tools you choose either
manually or automatically the next one
is a tricky at that time to leave fields
of incoming IP packets networking
equipment is built in such way that
there's a receipt for that that it will
decrease their way out of the field on
each hole on the way so that detail
would not be the same in case when
hijacking starts next Mon cheap time as
you know you can't fight the speed of
light so if you need to forward packets
through a network infrastructure you'll
let us see
and if you need to if you need to
process the tickets on your own terms
and network equipment then you're going
to end the processing time so the
overall it and say it will increase so
there are ways to detect problems with
wrote however those wastes might as well
be insufficient for example here with
say biggest ASP defined business to find
out what's the abnormal autonomous is
you need to know well how the ordinary
01 looks like so when no problems so you
need to know the state but the
difference and you need to have some
monitoring solution and history of
announces just to find out what and
where exactly has gotten more notes that
you to field of and make it is just a
field in and in IB pick it goes through
the hands of a man in the middle so it
could be easily mental to mimic the
normal behavior and just some point so
entree salads and whatever so it's
possible to mangle so what's there as
its it said previously you can stand
stand the speed of light handling the
bigots you need to add processing time
and let them see so finally the
difference will be opus like they were
in the in the case of Telekom Malaysia
let's review a simple example of this
popular example so figure while there's
an autonomous system which announces its
proof exists or its upstream Internet
Service Provider see well it comes and
goes and walked four years and till one
day and autonomous system starts to
announce more specific break prefix
although websites to its own upstream
Internet Service Provider be
what's happening next as we know in most
of the cases about networking equipment
is built and sit up in such way that
there are more that the more specific
announcements will be preferred over
less specific one of the rockies aspin
it's not sure yet but however general
and almost everywhere in the world that
more specific prefix will we and the
traffic will start to flow into the
autonomous system so the players will go
up and web sites located in those the
stolen network segment engage their
services even still available yeah users
immediately noticed the latency has
increased that the web pages are loading
slowly that the emails being sent north
as fast as they used to be things of
that sort
next user it's called a technical
support for their services and finally
the issue it reaches of the network
operations center of autonomous system a
retirement system is a ghost autonomous
system probably it will escalate the
issue up to
autonomous system B and finally ate and
be resolved the problem it may take some
hours minutes days several at most a
homer of the issues going to be result
next other autonomous system is going to
undergo some investigation and probably
is likely to attract public attention I
so finally that permissions to set up
roads in autonomous system will be based
on a reduced so that kind of a deck is
probably going to be implemented on
there once for each autonomous system in
control that makes the check very
expensive one and then
result of Investigation their attacker
even risks to get so other states go
higher once again and the only result of
all this stuff is well did not have
service so probably probably the
disclosure of some plant a plain text so
just unencrypted an unimportant did not
that interesting
another service is a much easier and
cheaper done with some kind of dinosaur
NTP amplification and its cheaper at
home so that's the way to go
so looks like the speed of light works
cue however we could hide the increased
latency from most of the users what is
what if only a small portion of users
will be affected
is it possible let's review another
example well figure 1 is the same eight
announces its brief existence we get two
autonomous system starts to announce
well just the same prefix of the same
site to its upstream be what's going on
next as we see that preference of the
more or less specific routes isn't isn't
playing anymore so there should be a
preference on the based on the
principles so what those prints but in
sports our preference won't be random
really what their sake of simplicity
let's ignore their orbiting pluses for
moments and lets you know just for the
sake of simplicity again let's assume
that B&C interconnected so
situation falls into general one or two
cases and independence on the
relationships between B&C commercial
relationships if be traffic from see
that first be will propel that malicious
wrote because that's the traffic from
its client it will get paid for that and
if it propels the route from the
provider it should be for that so that's
economical and will be further out
coming from its clients or religious one
and see will be around coming from one
of its planes that I ate a good one
or be a poison so in case she prefers
the malicious owed by jacking will go
probably will go global if she prefers
huge out so that so-so and vice versa
now see mice traffic from be then first
he will be there ought to be a good one
from its cool and and we will have to
choose it will prefer either they're all
coming from C or they're all coming from
in the former case that hijacking
wouldn't even occur in the latter case
the hijacking will go global to be and
wouldn't be propagated to the rest of
the world remember this and enjoy this
figures for now this is the easiest
example but it illustrates the idea we
just said that B&C are interconnected
but what if they are not and there's
more autonomous systems involved in the
process that game becomes harder and the
result depends on the relationships
between
in C but on the relationships on all the
way between them so they provide us our
clients the beatings that kind of think
so but that simple case are your
strengths the idea of the prefix may be
hijacked locally so that only specific
geographic illogical regions would be
affected in fact that's how it should be
in a cast works for CDN sand in our
souls mitigation services and cloud
services and whatever we GNE goes the
same prefix is announced
safe from both United States and China
and United users from United States and
Canada are owed to do the data center in
the United States and on the other hand
all the asia goes to change so that
Asian region is actually is allocated
for that cloud service from the rest of
the network for that perfect in that
case the insulation made and would be
the point where policies and communities
of local beers that can make an
announcement even more local so ever
installed on the local users will notice
the difference and for most of the users
say put the customer Bates things will
go the same way
relations for all this arrived us we're
done with introduction sin el final
question is
why would we need that why'd you steal
prefix locally for well two or three
years in the whole world so sitting far
from your client's far from your
customer base so there's a procedure
this procedure how we obtain keyless
certificate for domain for a certificate
of authority the procedure is generally
as follows
firstly we need to register on our
website and then we should generate a
Certificate Signing Request well it's
highly discouraged but some certificate
authorities will even allow you to take
the private key from them so no senator
questioned this case but doesn't matter
so you create a sign in her quest you
uploaded and then you need to prove that
you're reading the owner you are really
in control of the domain that you are
going to certify that you want to verify
and for your convenience
there are plenty of options to do this
there are certificate authority will
call for you to send an email to some
kind of email address like postmaster at
the target domain it may point you to
custom that you need to boot in the his
records may give your
specific HTML page that you need to put
under a specific your eye on your site
is offering you a custom took in in that
you Putin Janice TXT record and so on
the thing is you need to choose only one
of this method so either its web page
done and it's ok what's happening on
next certificate of authority since
Robert so I bought two aside well takes
from five to ten minutes but goes to
your site
checks that there's a token that's a
page so the owner of the domain he just
what they asked him for so probably his
and controlled so then the ownership is
verified and finally you get your
scientists are typically it well you
need to pay money for that but sometimes
Obama actions and finally maybe even you
don't need to show your credit card data
so what what are we going to say next
first of all
you need to be in control of a border
out of control
autonomous system next you need to find
a certificate of authority that's close
to your autonomous system in a logical
sense so it's it's that there are no
more hopes
123 of that that kind of thing
hopes between you and the chosen
certificate authority then you need to
reject a prefix locally the pics that
are staying the IP address which aims
website so the following will should
apply the victims customer base should
be in the other parts of the world
should be in United States while you're
sitting in China white vice versa so far
from there so the victims autonomous
system will notice nothing and it was
announced is local so we need we need to
build it in such a way that the chosen
certificate authority traffic is routed
to us as I wanted to the hijacker so
next we are going to register with CAA
in question we're going to applaud
Certificate Signing Request get an HTML
page then sit up bench engineered so
whatever web site of your choice
applauded the HTML page make sure it's
reachable and then you pay and obtain
their science certificate for the domain
in question so that Taylor certificate
that's one way to do that there's
another one
well sometimes
authoritative DNS is sitting in another
network so it's easier to will might be
easier to hijack that one network so
hosting the authoritative DNS or locally
so that DNS provider should noticed
nothing nothing as well
well then you need to configure it in
that way that the certificate of
authority nearby looks at you and then
you register you applaud you set up a
nobody and not in a budget DNS server
you said it set up the genus txt recur
to pay and you obtain the science
certificate the next the way well
sometimes well the genus ovis are loaded
stuff websites
highly lauded however no one kills who
is server goes down well five minutes to
midnight so just the same you need to
jack the prefix hosting server near the
certificate of authority so set up
several of your choice and said that
they can get critical in this particular
case may be kind of prevented or
investigated later by a certificate of
authority using a popular decrease
server with complete cash however
that's the point that not almost always
there so summery the hijackers look we
need to design locally so we can get on
a bus system should not doubt noticed
nothing or almost nothing here
well there should be some problems far
from their customer base for some meant
so most of the time network operations
centers of Internet service providers
don't care about that kind of stuff so
the network issues happen so it's
probably be investigated the resulting
Killa certificate is a global due to how
it's implemented in operating systems
and browsers
certificate authority cash his plane so
get out Florida's with intermediate so
it's their certificate which is
generated by certificate of authority in
Singapore China or poland or whatever
will be steel billet in the United
States United States dammit so the
resulting Killa certificate can be used
for men the middle at X anywhere in the
world and vice versa
just as we can steal victims prefix near
their certificate authorities autonomous
system we can as well
steal their certificate authorities
prefix near the big gym so to Mundell
on the way back that's kind of complex
to implement so it's easier with UDP
well however you need to build some kind
of sorry sorry well deep packet
inspection or whatever so it will take
time but it's just as well possible that
might be of help when you're autonomous
system is near the victims one so you
can't find autonomous system for prom
week however you found out of 34 from
there the question how do we do local
hijacking
first of all you need to find a border
router and put it under your control so
vulnerable one whatever I don't care how
it's implemented because it's possible
so you need a broader alter next you
need to find out
bought the relationships near your peers
near Euro Tour so their customers
provide us beatings
this is mostly in most cases of this
information is secret but not a
top-secret there are services on the
Internet is one free.com.co.net
which figures out this information while
on our business using only public data
so this is a double-double and the thing
is
and communities will also might be of
great help
well doing this while trying to announce
locally well no mitigating the problem
that's not so now has received one thing
one thing and it an important one
this is the case with Jermaine validated
to certificates but not with extended
believe it once because the policy issue
extended the lead to certificates
required request to pass through more
additional checks and to provide
supporting documents it takes time weeks
for example so recent initiative Google
with certificate transparency which is
currently being implemented for extended
validity certificates may also be of
some help however
dating that German ownership is an
important case with extended the lead to
certificates as well just the rest of
the checks is the subject of further
analysis not covered here so next what
can we do that there's a problem because
public key infrastructure that's built
into pls just shouting it doesn't take
into consideration that there are flaws
in Internet charging that most of the
time the internet marketing can't be
believed however that you less public
infrastructure is something that's built
into operating systems and devices and
it's not easy to change that there's an
underlying problem that's a problem with
Internet routing so that the problem
we're implementing security practices
however just as we know this is a good
example there's ipv6 that's being
implemented for ten years so
probably the internet remote assist for
now and we are going to solve its as
well for now we have to go with four
prongs the first of them is monitoring
that's able to detect hijacking far from
there from your customer base if pointed
out three they are so well there are
even free ones so come on your next one
whatcha prefixes as a whole the BJP
monitoring one do all the work for you
you need to check what what problems are
there with perfect sense when it
notifies you you need to react next one
for the gipper Text Transfer Protocol
there's a proposal that significant
meaning what that does is when the
browser for the next to the site for
them to the website for the first time
the website also that here's my
certificate and eat will not change in
few months or years so that if there's a
Sports Illustrated ticket
the browser will show you apparently
next their browser plug-ins that help
you to be warned when certificate of the
site that you are using frequently I
changed certificate patrol for Firefox
and so on
next there are new concepts of public
infrastructure for example Dinas based
one day so fine lol
maybe it's time to think about how it's
going to be implemented one note told
about browser plug-ins that their view
from the Mozilla plugin website about
this certificate Patrol has found a
problem so while using certificate
cultural he found out that sites like
Google or Amazon I changing their
certificate buy certificates quite
rapidly so one two or three months so
there's one thing that is going to you
need to choose either you generate a
short leave too difficult which you can
recycle if it's stolen or whatever or
you use a long sleeved certificate which
is going to help you in case there was
one so the public interest is not
working
I'm running out of battery is it's not
now and so maybe I'll think out loud to
speak out loud I owe their hear me to
hear me now
ok so finally there's a problem with
public infrastructure problem with
internet charging so that now that
george et to discuss those problems
sound bites so as we know there are
flaws in public infrastructure chart
thing that not reliable so there are
corresponding risks those risks can be
mitigated with what grounds however the
better design of a public infrastructure
might might help to do it easily more
easily and finally be monitoring systems
are useful so if you're in charge of
network security in a large Internet
Service Provider even small in a small
one so if you are charged phone network
setup network operations will start
using them right away
built for you so silly questions