alright good morning till the morning so
basically the motivation for this stock
and a quick synopsis most access
controls are using Aurelio protocols
clear taxed and are very widespread
we're seeing us an 80% of the plants and
take a look at this market he does
physical pain testing he said hey that
would be really cool to build a device
that you know good let's play around
with this protocol maybe as wireless and
said i'm ok let's let's build something
so we bought the thing and we're going
to tell you about it we're gonna go
through a bit of a history of RFID and
tell you sort of how these readers work
what technologies are used that will
talk about the device rebuilt how you
can use it for penetration testing and
also how you could prevent against the
type of attacks that it can do quick
introduction my name is erika Van check
embedded systems architect at Verde
future for a new car company that's
building a electric vehicle from the
ground up I've never got to say this
before to talk but we're hiring so I get
to do that from 41 to work on cars come
find me and reach out and I Marcus AG 00
managing principal consulted a coupon
vision at whatever you want to call us
now work on the attack in Penn team we
do network security and also obviously
physical penetration testing we're also
hiring hit me up on Twitter or go to the
recruiting booth where we're giving away
two hundred of these this week so I
wanted to talk a little bit about the
motivation behind building this Eric
fill you in a little bit briefly but I'm
gonna go into more depth so as you see
on the left hand side here we have hid
prox reader and have a big bank and then
a refinery now these are the only these
are the only two places that you can
find this technology this is a spot with
Eric and the side there at Pearson
International Airport as we are flying
to DEFCON
this is also an HIV prox reader is also
vulnerable so banks office is
manufacturing facilities etcetera
worldwide in my experience I've done
work in North America done work in
Europe and in Asia that the utilization
across the continent is a bit different
but it's definitely everywhere so no
matter where it would go customers would
always be surprised when I cloned a
badge used our artistic RFID the 22 long
range reader badge and then clone it so
I started thinking I said why we really
need to build something that gets the
point right drives the point home and
hopefully kills weekend once and for all
nothing against the man it was a great
protocol but it's past its time so let's
illustrate how these systems work really
really basic here this is an RFID reader
it sends out a signal and right now it's
a little sad because it's got no card to
to read so we're gonna introduce a card
and the card once introduced is
energized by the reader and sends bits
back completely in the clear and the
readers like alright I got data and so
it has to do something with this data so
this is what we're interested in this is
called the upstream where it sends the
data from the card reader to upstream
device typically a door controller which
is what's pictured here and that data is
the bit stream that was on the cards
called we get so this is what we're
going to attack today weekend is clear
text as eric said it has been around for
decades and it's literally everywhere
but we'll get into that a bit more later
here's the whole system in one sliding
case went too fast for you there again
we care about weekends and read but
we're gonna ship yours for a moment and
Arizona fill you in a bit about the
history of of of readers now we're
picking on it seems like we're picking
on HIV today but that's just because of
their
prominence in the marketplace it's not
something brand specific they're just
everywhere and we see them all the time
other manufacturers are also vulnerable
to to this attack so start off with
twenty years ago and their history
lesson and this is hid prox it is a
completely unencrypted system all over
so the card to the reader
there's no encryption there the reader
to the door controller also no
encryption they're also all over the
place these are two of the more popular
layouts we have another one right here
which is without the PIN pad you'll see
these in smaller configurations bigger
ones ones that look like this guy you
know just just all sorts of different
knock-offs if you saw a picture from
Pearson Airport also you'll see
different company names but they look
very similar the truth is they just
stick up sticker over the HID logo and
sell it as a different Brad
popular thing to do some do have this
2000 eradication and I should say that
with two-factor authentication doesn't
quite work as you might expect when you
push buttons on that pen pad it sends
bits back over the cleartext weekend
protocol in the clear to the door
controller so the tax were showing the
doesn't help you move forward about 10
years to HID iCLASS big note here is
they introduced in encryption between
the card in the reader the only problem
is well they've got broken back in 2010
guy by the name of me Loesch Mary act
she discovered hey I can use some tricks
here and get the firmware out once I get
the firm are out I can get this desk is
that they're using to encrypt the cards
and other using the same to you in every
reader worldwide so that's that's a
slight problem in symmetric key as you
might assume the big thing that they
said they still say that this is like
these are words we took from their
website like last week they still say
it's enhance security it's mutual
authentication and it's not untrue but
it's kind of like saying tlass 1
play now is all these things but you
don't want to use it
these are super prominent and the real
key with our talk we're not talking too
much about the card encryption more
about the backend protocol these still
only support weekend and another format
called clock and data which is still
clear taxes just a different signaling
protocol it's pretty much the same thing
just different bits on the front lines
now will move into the future as a
couple years ago I class as he came out
and this does support a new protocol
called OST p
open supervised device protocol and that
does offer an option called SCP secure
channel protocol and that is encrypted
that being said it still does we get and
if you install it and don't specify that
you want OST piano wire at 40 SDP and by
dork nude or controllers that support of
STP or modules that convert between the
two in still going to do weekend so you
might think hey I'm buying a better
reader but it turns out not the same old
stuff you just different dads on it on
the card side they are supporting a new
type of card called high-class SU carbs
and the whole theme of this though is
that no one looked into them too much so
your mileage may vary on security of
this device but this particular reader
it says in very small letters that you
might not be able to read multi-class
and you'll see me as I class as well
multi-class what that means is it can do
multiple different versions of the cards
so this reader out of the box with the
right configuration will do
rocks I class I class II which means if
you use a proxy card on it it will
accept that as a valid credential which
sort of breaks the whole idea of using
encrypted credentials in the first place
the main point being yeah this could be
a more secure option but you still have
to set it up right and make sure it's
been configured with those options
enabled and with all the old stuff
disabled
so the real question here is as even use
one of these to get into their office
anyone I'm guessing a few people I see
some people are willing to put up hands
maybe some are but the truth is I walk
by you know ten or twenty of these
things every day on my way to work like
they're just everywhere and you'll find
one wherever you go now marc is gonna
talk a bit more about this protocol that
were exploding and where it came from
and how we can deal with it
years ago or so he discovered this
special type of wire that had magnetic
properties and this wire was then
embedded into cards and based on the
presence of the wire or absence of the
wire in the car when he was pulled
through reader it created a bit stream
of ones and zeros so the protocol used
to transmit that information back and
became known as the weekend protocol has
got a lot of stuff named after him he's
a physicist and I think that he's passed
on but his protocol certainly lives on
today the constraints that are in
current access control systems around
bit length as a result of the amount of
wires that you could fit into a card so
we have this cycle of backwards
compatibility with this protocol that
dates back to the Apollo 11 era and it's
it's the reason that eight bits of data
as for a card code and 16 bits of data
is for a facility code typically in most
of these carts and into I class as well
so going towards twenty twenty years
later with a vicious cycle of backwards
compatibility where you know people use
something so they implemented in RFID in
then it and they didn't buildings and
its demand more demand and thirty years
later here we are with the same protocol
now to show you the protocol we can use
his only two lines plus ground line one
would be on the top of the slide line
data data 101 the top data one on the
bottom vertically we have voltage so
goes from zero volts 250
the lines are normally just how high up
five goals
and the horizontal axis is time so this
is how we read the region protocol to
bits 0 in a one and one on the falling
edge what's called the falling edge when
we when we read it with a
microcontroller we count 0 and on the
falling edge as time goes on and we've
received a one now in this data stream
so with 26 bit card when we put all that
together this is a logic analyzer
screenshot from an entire card we have
data from the car so what do we do with
this data well turns out we can do quite
a bit so as you see here with the
bitstream and I've highlighted the first
eight bits that's the facility Cody your
card and the interesting thing is a lot
of places order cards in bulk so if
you're a company with 30 employees
chances are your entire office has the
same facility code so that significantly
reduces the difficulty to gas card
number and then the next 16 bits that
were going to highlight here the card
code
9644 so in this particular facility I'm
betting that twenty 9643 and also 45 are
valid cards say I'm an employee I'm
disgruntled and I'm let go I know that
probably the next card also works to
open the door and you can take the state
of this is all you need to create a
clone or two
replayed on the lines if you have a
device like a leaky attached to the
lines it's this is a funny one that we
had to point out were taking a little
sidetracked here but this is a bit of a
facepalm this is a dual technology card
so it has an antenna for eyeglasses
high-frequency has an antenna for profit
which is low frequency to separate chips
and on this card that authentication
data on the encrypted portion and the
completely clear portion is identical so
if in the situation we showed you before
we have a multi-class reader but are
using only you know saying cryptic
credentials but you have this
multi-class card you can read the
encrypted information I can take it back
because I
glasses broke and store it on to one of
those cards and get into the building
now the bigger facepalm is that you see
those yellow box the data to 70 that's
the card code 0599 for that's the
facility code you don't even need to
read it you just need to see it around
someone's neck and you can get in or
replace the data with our be led so hid
I don't think they willingly do this but
we we access the site today and this is
the latest I class SEC card that you can
buy from them that is the high-security
as an encrypted side or so I Class S II
and also again they've released this
dual dual technology card so it has an
unencrypted side and it says right on
their website it communicates no
traceable identifiers during cart
sessions to prevent card data from being
divulged or clone by unauthorized
parties which is totally misleading to
the customer because you sure you're
only using the encrypted side which is
not been tested by security researchers
then yes it may be protected but if I
can walk by you with a device like that
and lifted off your bell I can get into
your facility so the moral of the story
here is that physical access to these
readers physical access this information
is winning now we want to give some
people some props this protocol weakness
has been around for twenty years in the
design of of weekend they didn't
implement security because it was not
feasible at that time to put together a
device like this it was inaccessible it
was probably the realm of Engineers to
access this information and put together
something that would emulate a card or
transmitted on the weekend lines but now
with the Arduino and whatnot with a lot
more accessible so I think a guy named
Paige Mac you had some Arduino code just
posted right on the internet with Google
I found it wow this is really easy to
read this protocol another guy named
Carl Froch's colonias got a cycle
products gonna just experiments on my
class and he's really open about it and
he put all this information out there
rights white papers
icons like this but I sent an email to
give you all the information I needed to
turn in my class reader into a cloner
right on the wall pretty cool guy and
then of course we must give a nod to
Zach Franken who made a device that was
quite like ours called the get go back
in 2008 now obviously you're all sitting
here today we're talking about this
today we we think that the Gecko wasn't
released as far as we know and probably
don't have the impact that should have
because everyone still using this so
here we are again and we made a device
that we think a little bit easier to use
and now has wireless so we made a be a
leaky so let's talk with the hardware
that we're releasing today as open
source hardware and that's the whole
reason why you're here is this little
device you probably can't even see it in
my hand at the back it's pretty small
its eighteen by 30 millimeters or 0.71%
two inches and there it is next to a
Canadian quarter which is the same size
American quarter but were 30% less
we utilize this module here it's a
Bluetooth Low Energy model for coming to
rate Jack and it's great because they do
all the RAF black magic for us know
antenna matching no viene has now if
you're done our efforts
a lot of work so we just think that
module put it down it has a Nordic NRF
5182 to chip on it this is super popular
in connecting devices like that bit type
things it's a process that has not only
a cortex and 04 I'm course but also a
2.4 gigahertz radio and they provide a
software stack that turns out into a
Bluetooth Low Energy device so it's
everything you need in one ship and its
FCC certified so we don't have to do
that now it's it's pretty simple it's a
few passive components and some
transistors to drive the lines connect
there's there's a battery holder on the
back really the other innovative part of
the design is the connector we used an
insulation displacement connector lot of
you are probably familiar with one type
of this connector which would be an rj45
connector when you sat down you know how
those little teeth go up and they pierce
through the installation but they don't
actually cut the wire and all that's
what this does so you stick the wire in
you punch down the reader will still
work normally you just made an
electrical connection without cutting or
splicing makes it fast to install it
also doesn't break the existing system
and it runs on a ser 1632 coin cell
which is a tiny little coin cell battery
is taking the back so this is our
high-tech Development set up our lab you
know you need really sophisticated
equipment to build one of the is not
really you know this is Mark's desk and
we saw turn up the first ones literally
here with a hot air rework station and
patience and this is the entire
schematic there's nothing else
imprisonment slides you know it's simple
again this will be released as open
source hardware we're gonna
so if you want to take a deeper look
into it you can do that
worth noting mark had no experience with
the program we use which is chaotic at
my dad he had never used before he did
the first version of the schematic and
then I came in and did the next revision
but pretty simple stuff you know you
don't need to be some electronics wizard
build a device that will break 80
percent of access control years out
there we went through some design
iterations here we started out with AV 0
this is just a nice way to test
everything out make sure it works you
break out a lot of pain so you can try
different things and maybe add features
and now it's easier to solder together
and just makes it easy to work with but
then we wanted to make it really small
because we wanted to fit inside of
readers and behind readers depending on
the installation so we then went back to
the PCB program and trunk that bore down
at this point the space constraint is
actually just the battery holder it's
the size of the battery holder on the
back in order to get smaller it would
probably need to use a smaller battery
at this point you know sounds great now
we didn't screw something up really
badly and fun story in development of
really devices it's useful to give them
different means the reason being mark
and I are in the same room and we're
both playing around with these annoying
when you have like 10 different devices
called be a leaky and you're like which
one do i click to get to mine so you
know you give them just unique
identifier unique names so Mark he was
working on one and keep giving it a
unique name and he said the firm are
over we sent it off to our manufacturer
in China and then I got an email that my
12 year old self came out during this
yeah so it says we have updated the
former successful
sleepiness all two hundred and fifty of
them yeah we almost died like a bag of
Filipinos as but thankfully they were
very considering they may reflect all of
them really quick and ship them out and
we got the moment I'm so thanks you too
tiny to sign their Draper deming
manufacturing done and yeah so what do
you do when you have one of these
devices well you put in the reader so
this is the demise in this reader it
fits very nicely in aprox reader it
there's so much space and they're just
putting clothes whatever works great and
people were asking some calls with
reporters and stuff they were like well
how long does it take must take a long
time to put this and so we did a speed
round which will show you and here we
are so we put the cover open and that's
the top cover then there's four screws
to be undone I swear this is not sped up
it just happened to be exactly a minute
and the four screws come upgrade or
inside and there's the wires as for them
we need 30 marks now lining out that
first wire which is one of the weekend
80 wires and he's punching out and down
and get the next one in there have been
falling out of my tools and I could have
shaved two seconds or 30 right lamar
that's it all the wires are and now
we're gonna put everything back together
we'll just have to ask is because we're
not worried about forensic right now and
toss that top on and there you go one
minute and sure enough the door still
works normally and disapproving here
that we can connect to the device still
it's actually in there also just in case
our demos don't work as proof that the
thing works if everything goes badly
least we have this so you know gone
right characteristic and someday and
there's no card present but he has the
button and door opens just great and
will show you it for real
hopefully in this section called the
attacks so let's talk about what you can
do with this thing and why am I might
want to play with one and in this damn
I'll we're going to do some role playing
here i guess im going to be Alice we're
gonna use the cryptography actors so
many the innocent person mark is going
to be the evil Eve and he's also gonna
bring stuff up on the screen to show you
what's going on as we go through so you
can see how it works so well he gets
that ready let's talk a little bit about
this setup we have you know hid prox
reader active strike for the door so its
electronic strike plate that is open by
door controller and behind it as a sort
of risky but will turn around there's a
off the shelf hid her text or controller
like you see in any facilities in the
stuff fun fact still using the same card
data that had that it had on it when I
bought from ebay yeah that's never do so
it's as real of a set up as we can get
nobody wanted to let us break into their
building so we had to build their own
building so let mark as of right now is
a serial terminal this would not be used
in normal deployments we just have it
for illustration purposes and it's
really useful for debugging so this is a
wired connection right now and when you
scan a card on the winner of a line pop
up there saying nine cards credit cards
and we have the raw data and then the
padded
right so that's the serial terminal side
and this is the Bluetooth plant so
obviously you're gonna wanna do this
wirelessly you don't have to open up the
device and connect to it so Bluetooth
reaching connected to the specific MAC
address of this bleg and we have
whitelisting enabled on it so that you
know only certain MAC addresses can
connect but please don't please don't
mess with us so we're connected to it
now and the simplest attack is gonna be
reading the card so Alice walks out and
she she's never really which is not the
fastest wireless protocol but there's
the last 10 cards she comes again she
scans are card you know goes into the
office and we can do another red cards
and this doesn't look terribly exciting
until you realize that that number is
all you need to enter into a piece of
software like proxmire in order to write
a totally valid copy of the card so you
know once you have that information you
can be Alice and walk around the
facility just as if you were her that's
the first really simple attack
motivation for the device but once we
get back here like going to next and the
most obvious one that came up was
replaying data we have access to those
weekend lines and region not only read
them we can also drive them so they
don't want to have to copy a card you
know an approximate hardware tool you
don't want on the software whatever mark
in just over bluetooth is transmitted
command and he didn't send any of the
last cards and turn out the door just
opened with no card present
climbs doors open and hitting about and
so it turns out that you can also do
this from a cell phone please work from
a fire near yeah this is the rest of
testing Bluetooth devices in a venue
Holiday who will connect when we get an
appearance and we have too many devices
and parts and labor for the phone they
were using county MAC address filtering
so marc is currently strolling through a
giant list of all of your feedback it's
trying to find but you know that you
took three thousand steps today so
that's a no ok found it got a very good
I'm connecting but really connect
alright we're connected so I pick up the
attribute which is replay I tell it to
right and left which is equal the 255 as
the command I hit Send and the door is
open
have access to each and every realize
that it might be nice to be able to do a
denial of service attack you know maybe
you're running through someone's
building and unit a card and then the
door opens you run through and nobody
else can get into that door for the next
20 minutes or whatever that sounds like
a good pitcher so putting this all
together is quite useful because you can
assign a special control card and
regularly do whatever you want with it
so for example let's say you just have a
card with this case you have a tender
beef as a text value in the cereal that
it's going to read the control card
controller card it's going to replay the
last card that was sent and thats
alice's you know card right here and
then after that it's going to lock out
the reader or we're going to 20 seconds
that we haven't stuck up here waiting
for it but I can't program built a
knee-length you'd like
so evil market then that are now Alice
comes back and he's joining in the data
center she just can't get in the data
center though and like now
HSM a big unbolted and like they're in
the Arab and trying to steal staff or
whatever
you know
three demos for if you've installed in a
reader out of sight out of Selby but we
built the building of things I realized
I know this has another totally
different purpose what we installed in
our own reader that we bought off ebay
and then electrical tape back together
this is an HID long range reader you'll
see it on parking garages everywhere
this is the prox version of it there is
also a high-class version of it is just
more expensive and we don't have one
right now that works is you plug you
know in the back the BLET is inside of
this does anyone have a proxy card on
them
so if it is a proxy there yet so now we
have his card data and if you read his
name tag will figure out where it works
so this fits in a backpack its wireless
it's totally portable move in with her
big round cards so obviously you know if
you can get an elevator with somebody
you can probably steal their potential
also the speaker can be disabled by
pulling up jumpers I think it dips which
is having on proliferation purposes so
you can vary stealthily go through and
just grab credentials go back
take that card data like we showed make
fake cards that are totally valid for
that building and do whatever you want
so where does that leave us right here
so if you are in the overwhelming
majority that has one of these systems
what do you do
first off probably not the best to
blindly trust lenders not that they're
trying to mislead you but as we saw from
the 80 website information can be
misleading and the people actually
installing the systems often times just
don't know in my experience you know
when I write a report up send it over
the client to bring a bender in the
matter is every system is is just as
vulnerable there's no answer to that so
get a trusted third party in if you're
installing one of these systems or or if
you're looking at ought to be near your
system because they all they all they
all have those claims on their website
know five years after I classes broken
the copy is still on the site so the
first kind of real tactical thing that
you can do is make sure that tamper
detection on your readers is turned on
its very simple as just a switch and in
the new readers it's also the optical
sensors and some of them now this might
be challenging because from our
experience oftentimes not enough
physical copper wiring is run to the
switch to even hook it up because of
ignorance during the install process
that the RFP RFQ and so they're trying
to get by as cheap as possible so you
have to make sure it's hooked up to make
sure you have enough wires and then you
also have to make sure that you're
watching the console so I've been in you
know let's say chemical production
facility where he consoles actually in
the cafeteria publicly unlocked and it's
kind of stand-alone no one's watching it
so make sure that you're watching it and
that the logs coming out of the systems
are monitored by someone maybe if you
want to get fancy put it in your sim new
heuristics on it if Alice goes in every
morning at 8 a.m. and uses doors ab&c
but then one day she goes into door D
and I 4 a.m. this should probably raised
alarm bells
lastly you probably want to have video
surveillance trained on all of your
significant entrances and exits because
these systems now as we've seen are not
you're not able to actually accurately
know that Joel Morales is using the door
you need your camera to verify that
person's identity and I guess that
pretty much sums it up so I want to say
that you need decent security you
probably want to change your access
controls completely unfortunately for
consumers there is not a time of
information thereon which systems are
really secure we have to trust vendors
at this point I would like to encourage
them to embrace the security community
and allow us to take a look at these
systems more instead of erasing that
information from the Internet
just want to say thanks to a few parties
octave they produced 200 of these boards
I was pretty awesome and now two hundred
in the wild so you have a better reason
to go to your boss and say look this is
out there is a huge vulnerability and
get one
yeah and you can get one demonstrator
where do I get one mark at the
recruiting booth and you know I want to
thank my wife for putting up with that
messy desk and and and Todd and whatnot
for for all the support so Eric yeah so
it's been it's been a fun thing to put
together things where we look at some
old protocol and yeltsin their hardware
that just makes it really easy until it
and things of course the black after
having a house in all of you for coming
out and watching our demos that
thankfully worked
and thanks again by the way all the
coaching staff were gonna get happy
doesn't describe some math specific MAC
addresses from it
we're gonna push that always schematics
and everything will tweet out a link I
guess and if Black Cat puts out stuff
getting to follow us
yeah also thinks that Jamie Campbell who
was the one that got me interested in
RFID wherever you are out there thinks
it is there somewhere and at this point
we have a few minutes for questions
there's microphones in the aisles and
they've demanded that you go to the
microphones and talk so that the video
gets the lights and power connection to
get rid of the battery so we thought
about that one reason was just an
install time obviously you know little
faster than with three wires and other
one was we didn't want to do any melting
it's a 12 volt circuit that used to
power the readers and down the 3.3 volt
board you're gonna need either a
switching and murder or a really hot LBO
dropout linear regulator properly so the
problem there being a time of need it
really hot organ be introducing like 15
kilohertz which I know is into people's
RFID readers and we don't know what
that's going to do but it might be bad
so this way you know we're limiting how
much noise are creating other than being
on 2.4 gigahertz which is about the
proxy cards are using the middle here's
this limited to just the prox reader or
version three other smaller readers so
it'll work on on all of that I class
that we showed you anything that speaks
weaken in fact if it doesn't use the
same weekend protocol a bit bit length
it's quite easy to go in racing seko 22
deciphered whatever format it's using so
it it will work with anything that has a
five-fold we get my
or even clock and data for that matter
the middle apt
system also requires the pin number can
you defeat that as well so you're
talking if the reader requires a pin
number number and you get in right so
there's a few different ways of that
being done so the old icarly old
products ones when you hit a button it
actually just sense that number over
weekend so it's just an extra bit on the
card essentially it's on the card every
time you hit a button so you can record
that and then extract the pin number so
that you know it and climate card so we
show up at the card type it into the pin
number I class it has this thing called
bio class that's used for two-factor
it's an interesting concept they do
fingerprint readers and I iris scan as
well the problem is that it actually
verifies the biometric data against the
card but the eyeglass encryption is
broken so you can make a card with your
own biometric data on it but somebody
else's facility counting card number so
that you scan your fingerprint and it
thinks it's valid but actually you know
you you faked it so in most cases those
two battery implementations are are not
great
the pen is pretty easy to see if its
products like the one that we showed its
left how fast is the weekend protocol
can you brute force the card
yeah that's another potential attack
actually so that signal that we showed
you from the logic analyzer I believe
it's about 40 milliseconds each pulse
weekend as two milliseconds so we have
experimented with changing the timing
and it still works so that's another
attack is not in the firmware right now
but we could potentially expose you know
as a Newbie least service say okay we
know that silly quotes 200 so just brute
force hardcoded 1202 sixty-five thousand
five hundred and go and it will be much
faster than trying to do it you know
with a proxy mark 3 because this thing
waits for the card to be out of here
before you
cards would take way less time doing it
on the lines really will come down to
the card reader how they've implemented
that if they're going to probably
require some delay between cards being
read so you have to tune it depending on
your viewpoint or control that using not
reader just did it will be expecting you
know give me in bed and then wait like
$100 seconds or whatever to give me more
so the timing you can brute force at
whatever speed weed we had a code but
last night that where we weren't waiting
and actually it seemed like millisecond
we could probably get down to
milliseconds between cards yeah it was
like we weren't waiting at all
a few blocks like that process it was
probably about a millisecond to the left
to how long does the battery last
so without any power optimization right
now we worked mainly in features three
days one of the cards could be in
control card that turn Bluetooth off
quite easy it's just a simple call to a
function in C and that would probably
dramatically increase the battery life
and also improve your security because
then at that point not broadcast
includes all the time they would
probably ran up to him at least a month
easily the thing is the most power right
now is just advertising the blue chip
data which isn't necessary ninety
percent of the time when you're not
trying to get data out of it so I am i
turning that off a down but few days of
the batteries right now it is enough to
prove a point but not ideal like three
last chance they're making us make you
go to a microphone I'm sorry and sorry
that it will repeat it if you wanna just
just say that other people are we
selling them we're giving them out at
Optus boots so there's two hundred of
them there if they're all gone if people
weren't here and they want one of those
interests tweet at us and we're looking
at doing maybe another hundred run and
we can sell them for whatever cost is
we're not looking to make cash really
and you get off to see you make your own
as well if you just download the design
file and thank you everyone for you