ok so thank you for coming anything
before we get started
couple things please I'm gonna ask you
to give a warm round of applause to all
the volunteers like ngo dou letting the
staff and the black hat organization
ever used Windows I don't believe you
did get the question how many have you
ever used Windows ok that's everybody
how many of you have an adult signature
should test how many of you have done
their penetration tests on the Windows
network all of the previous ones you
should have seen what we gonna show you
because it's all trivial and also
interesting so what we saw my name is
Jonathan Ross Ave be presenting here are
a few times if you like the level
reverse engineering and things like this
we run a couple conference easy various
in a way you submit its
check on and reverse engineering but
once it's dried up for free just signed
up its invite only but I'm Hamas
security engineer at Salesforce as well
as my postdoc at black hat so it goes ok
to point out that we're breaking windows
and kind of sort of breaking into
standing Microsoft edge of at least five
days ago so good luck with that
yeah that's a lot of right agenda what
we're gonna go through today basically
we gonna do like an introduction to what
SMB is what kind of previous work is
done
are dealing SMB houses
as Amelia rebooted this is basically a
US attack you have a couple of
interesting to see Jonathan Sanchez
attack the syphilis which includes Matt
obviously how do we meet again against
ok so let's imagine for a second be back
in like nineteen eighty-four and we all
worked for IBM so we're working on this
awesome operating system called OS-two
with a small start-up
Microsoft has a bit of them so basically
we we train chew on these operating
system which he's not even so it's
really more than sixteen 16 bit that we
have one megabyte a river yet max we
don't have much of this key and will be
trained to Deweys sherrie dean for
sharing without multitasking is a
challenge in itself but essentially
that's where we are and the big question
mark is all about security 1984 a system
where should you consider that i-ninety
five when Microsoft shipped windows
ninety-five the shares which the
original behind it with that if you buy
a computer network and you want to be
able to share all of your colleagues
without entering passwords so we can go
back to 1984 like obviously there will
be even less security right and that's
where all the problems we going to
discuss today right
solar quick demo what exactly has been
done previously
forgive the video because it requires a
land to do this right so what we have
here is basically cool software from
core security which does a sampling
explain more about that later on we have
AV unsuspecting victim was going to some
internet website this is basically in
the land and this website has got an
image tag on it which basically is gonna
do like some magic and tobacco will
explain more later on and what is
happening over here is this browser send
NTLM crabs off the victim automatically
to a unknown sorts bridge is
mind-boggling itself I mean why would
you do that but fine it's all of the
internet so you would find well as an
airline is kind of sort of safe as you
can see it's basically have been sent
over here you have likely uploading some
kind of my love the payload so fantastic
so we're going to a show whatever right
so that is what has he done previously
so quick walkthrough what exactly is SMB
it's basically file sharing on your
Windows network it's so a message block
protocol whatever you can call it it
requires authentication back in the day
they used to be basic authentication to
basically sending your credit and plain
text then it improve my doing last night
before a few are potentials which could
be broken easily they didn't rule again
doing and LM p1 which was basically
before and each time I can be five
people and basically break the bottle
into two parts which you can make it
really easy thing is they came up with
and do what they gonna be attacking as
well today and was designed for local
networks and telling me to like I
mentioned it's a server client challenge
response protocol basically it I can be
five and before the apostle is used to
sign all the mess
the good thing about this is that cannot
be deeply about actually be really which
I actually showed the demo today
basically it's a really really old
experts found really like what fourteen
years ago in 2001 by statistical CDC the
two that I showed you right now is
basically from core security
accessibility links you can download
from online audio so kids can use this
what it does is basically it replays a
half from one machine to another machine
that's about it
it authenticates using that the original
audio is very limited it's basically on
the on the internet
those of you have done penetration
testing for Windows networks will
definitely have done this before
basically set up a website Angeles
toppling houses all across the stress
this a lot not possible over the
Internet
this is the mitigating factor apparently
for this exploit behind it with that the
Additional Protocol was never meant to
be exposed to anything from the very
start to read like operate networks and
the first explodes being so you can do
whatever you want with it so interesting
thing the slide came up because I was
telling Johnson like when you're doing
this research like it basically
repeating what everyone else is doing
only remotely over the Internet and just
as a slick looking at me and said you
doing it over the internet about anyways
so SMU lady Boonton
what's going on
machine we sitting up a relay
shark just you see what's going on in
the background and we gonna load page
using and we can see that there is
actually something going on and this is
happening over the internet so there's
just not supposed to happen it'll you
can also see over here but we have a
receive challenge and I received
indication that we really over just to
prove that you actually doing that
anyways right
all Windows versions are affected back
from my guest 95 maybe altimeter Windows
standing edge this is all default out of
the box what I'm trying to stay out here
is that Yard Machine ascending NTLM
crabs over the internet without doing
any user interaction ever so basically
you visit a website that's it not your
own it's fantastic right this is another
fantastic slide basically Microsoft has
a great mitigation log on FM being
feeling this was published be back in
late 2009 or something but they are
saying over here that the issues lots of
your mainly because it's limited only to
the local internet I don't think so they
have a better fight that ok so if we
look at it was actually sitting like
we're supposed to return to gate using
it so you can you anonymous logon the
default is to log on on the Internet
zone so what I just described this
report basically it's leveraging single
sign-on so when you are using Active
Directory and you can exchange their
shares of somebody else inside you
company you don't have to enter your
credentials again so this is the default
and there is also automatically go on
with your password and username and
password
what is interesting is that none of this
actually works if we look at the trigger
so the trigger is we need to refuel it's
basically like you redirect through an
image tag or something like that if you
are taking bio HTML you read this you
mention to remote chair on the internet
and that's it he the trio so we saw we
saw that a semi truck is actually going
on which is not supposed to happen
rights because it defaults were
connecting only over the internet and up
like sending you credentials over to the
Internet to anybody yet ok and if we
look at the back it's like we can see
the user name in plain texts we can see
the DNS will bunch of stuff and there is
actually a better but which is like it
derived from original best we can get
that from the internet
let's look a little bit like why is this
happening so we've been looking at ok
this is just sitting box off windows if
you look like you know inside a burger
like which is actually running like we
find that one and then looking a bit
like poking around we actually find the
vulnerable lol so you can see on the
right hand side the corresponding to the
previous one
what is interesting out there that these
DLLs actually not exploit you know it's
a deal in which is in the system
directory by many more applications and
not just tight so then we
we took a snapshot of the registry we
change the setting to another one for
instance like you know prompts for
username and passwords every time we
took another snapshots of the registry
and this is a diff so basically he's
actually stored in the registry and this
is working but if we look at a trace of
you know running and connecting to a
remote exploits we can see in the next
slide so we can see that it's actually
carrying all those registry keys so when
you correct from the Internet to a
remote share over this overseas up a
probe and none of them works so we
learned a few things out of this we look
like which reaches ricky is actually we
learned that the the applications which
match your else I mean unless you're
writing your own TCP IP stack basically
you leveraging the one of windows and
you should only rage the URL mechanism
of Windows you are able to get another
tomorrow so this time we gonna leave
range from the internet so it's just a
couple things that you operation you
attacking the machine is enjoying and
that there is an SMB server exposed to
the Internet to relate to that company
that's a pretty big assumption for the
time being
so you can see you like the green asking
the WebBrowser control with age and
that's essentially yet calm and in
control we got you shall be no major
producer so we gonna be able to like
another process idea memory then we just
gonna push matter where do the same
machine migrated successfully inside
another process for the memorial the
target victim
and now we can actually have a show like
we can you know these directories roles
directories Internet
right so why exactly because this was
made up about one hour ago when we
decide they ok vs sending my love their
over the Internet
basically be set up just a any website
people know how difficult it is to set
up a website now has apparently you can
set it up on our / that say you use
isn't saying check out these brand new
exploits Davis I guess if you get sick
you don't use IE but you can get your
creds the document control of you upload
all of this was running mate tools
apparently this is not supposed to
happen still I'd like to keep
emphasizing the point but just upload is
not enough apparently what about using
it to be authentication first I'd like
to see some limitations to this first
SMB signing has to be disabled this was
one of the medications for the proposed
by microsoft which doesn't allow you to
upload any files to anything using a
somebody without SMB signing it is
disabled by default unless going to
demand controller people recommend to
disable it because it's a huge
performance impact is like a pretty
percent performance tuning percent
performance impact and you need somebody
out on all of your machines from the 50
this is interesting slide re-signing
must be disabled for southern corporate
firewalls to be to work properly
like to see ya but yes so fantastic but
one mitigation that's there is disabled
by default
not a big problem ok another bomb that
is basically so people say they save
like why okay so it's not a big deal you
have to have a zombie ports open it
doesn't matter I have complete firewall
security at all impressed by security is
all set up properly but not many people
know that he can do RDP apparently it's
a new feature in Windows Server so
here's a little quick demo of how it
actually works so you don't have the
credit and everything so this is a
Windows RDP gateway basically you can
set up absecon set up RDP connections
you can see the show must go on Skype
and in this case we choose to like just
executives yep so just one interesting
County review authentication that you
saw here on this web page and BLM also
wish to be so great so this sort of
problem of going back to the network
once used when you want to really you
know it's a harsh on the internet I want
to connect you you know I still have to
pierce your firewall so instead of just
over SMB you know I'd like to not going
to happen because people don't allow
incoming traffic using US and UN the
reason I bought the problem because we
can just relates to FTP over HTTP like
he should savor this enables like that
so we worked
so for this to work we need your first
sniff harsh then we need to crack / to
get like you proper financial decision
means that we sent in plain text of the
crash
needs to be correct that we need to we
need for GPUs we have one machine like
five GPUs it's using a very extended to
all guests and we cracking a two to four
billion second so that's what records
like and so this key space were used for
mowing was like a key space of 60
characters makes a fabricated lowercase
alphanumeric characters as you mean you
have a best 18 or less we can break that
in less than three days and of course
like you should have a median hashes
breaking this medium has the median of
hashes is not gonna take longer to all
of its so if we look at you know I was
like you was actually using this
delegation office in be over HTTP
probably nobody so I gave it to a show
then search of people the first one
being Sony in Asia let you draw your own
conclusions
so the impact of this so what exactly do
over here right now we can retrieve user
credentials great we need to do that
that's no problem you have remote code
execution if you have SMB signing to say
about it that's all they have done
because of performance are forever
details anyway the ban users ie a
corporate environments banks are Bank
all these uses ie so great for us I
guess he's gone however this is not the
only trigger that we found the triggers
against that create a zombie connections
like you only mentioned one dll it's not
just used by its use by literally
everything in videos are doing and not
so it's ups lol right so your trigger so
let's try to instead of just using a
year ago we're going to try to you you
know use different clients so for
instance we can leverage to redirect its
just cuz its funny I actually took a
malware was doing it and I just happened
to change the URL this is supported
feature of Windows automatically when
you play the video and if you do that
like it you can redirect page and you
said so the rest of the day we got him
in temperature shell
migrating to bid process adding memory
and this is it more so when the user did
was basically opening video
instead of breaking the harsh like with
the LDP we actually gonna relay over the
Internet to a server which is this the
same kind of connectors accepting a
simpleton station over HTTP so instead
of using RDP we actually attack and
Exchange Server I mean many many people
you know
Exchange servers using Microsoft
Alliance
like a reasonable said he's gonna start
in the background response service which
we listen for incoming Mb
and the trigger is actually just look so
just the fact of you in this you may you
didn't click on any picture anything
sexually sending your credentials may
soon be server listening and disassembly
server is relating it to exchange to the
point that will do little to you and
tell you made box is not one you made
this was going to be made box
we don't look like the entire mailbox in
XML and from a user perspective like
this interaction music you receive the
email opened email and that's it by
default like when you open so direction
can be like absolutely zero I think we
just like to point out over here you can
see the name of the sender you can see
the email ids you can see basically the
subject of lighting so this is your
entire mailbox over here that's it so
you emails and books how many people use
exchange service will be here so this is
very cool right
once once you do more like XML file from
the user to cooperate user access to
most of the password to access to all
your contacts and things like this we
could do that to you know and we made
ok so we have like these dolls we've
been doing it over as you're a WS we
show either clients or servers on any of
those you are busy available featuring
so like we saw with the showdown carrie
is actually thousands of servers SMB
connection over HTTP and the defaults
are unsafe like extending protection is
not enabled by default which is the only
thing which would actually prevent
discusses attack even if you like it
signing enable since we really over HTTP
you extended protection would but it's
not your fault it would prevent you from
sniffing packets to about really so to
protect yourself he said the first
mitigation is at some point you need
exists you need to have an SMB back yet
which is existing judo internet is
absolutely true dropped SMB valuable
corporate environment is actually the
preferred remediation offered by
Microsoft and also it sucks why because
if your Domain Join on her laptop and
you bring your laptop home
well then you're doing remain vulnerable
so instead of you know doing their work
like in the nineties like hot outside
consultants I'd much prefer a solution
which is based out inning so instead of
relying on your cooperate firewall I
would strongly recommend you actually
use your windows personal firewall to do
the same thing which is essentially
dropping SMB traffic to public aP's you
can like you want to keep the
functionality within you know where this
will be fine but I don't see any
legitimate reason to send SNMP packets
over the Internet are you doing
something insane like exposing SMB
servers anyway so you might want to
enable I get signing
which prevents doesn't it won't prevent
the packets from the king and you how
she has to be linked to the internet but
if a hacker gets your house she is it
will prevent them from coming back to
your network and pushed me away like we
did if using reading an SMB server these
will ever forget signing is not going to
prevent leak of your credentials
basically does kill the connection but
once the greatest 11 cents in Jim's
office you know preventing
engaged in the work and of course enable
extended protection
right so what's the takeaway over here
over the internet that's one super
simple to do you have a ready-made tools
to do it for you literally beaten do
like crazy amount of coding for this
oppose all of its lot of ready made
stuff out there it is not supposed to
work according to Microsoft reported
about nine months ago they don't want to
fix it because its defense in depth you
need you like you said you need to ask
voters on your file we managed to do
differential through a variety of ways
through a website through an email
spamming users download a mailbox 20
video my mom and dad were definitely
open up a video easily convince them to
do that
rentals that way you could upload
malware you up you relayed from SMB to
exchange this is just a small tip of the
iceberg kind of thing that uses and the
MSSP I mean literally every video
service uses and BLM in the background
too often to get everything people use
Kerberos nowadays but gerber is limited
because you have to be in the domain to
do that so NTLM is still being used
widely we show that we did it on the
stand great news for that post and it
was completely patch nothing is going to
block it and it was all done remotely
fantastic enjoy soft triggers so we
interesting this when we were actually
working with seven ensure we're
presenting tomorrow on another classic
attack which is like a division of pics
sexy like this year many attacks on
Dixie and then you trusting one drama I
mean both from silence was absolutely
related to what we doing they were
working on a sexy and they realized that
when you can
man in the middle of dates locally many
many software actually can be can be
forced to do an SMB connection instead
of just i mean sixties or from an XML
file is available software include like
huge value to your software which are
linked against my crew discovered you
like things like iTunes major antivirus
clients for you know to be cool web
protocols so yeah three we've shown like
they belong to Microsoft but it auto
body so affected by this weekend but an
URL anywhere and the survey results to
SMB you are not be like to say thank you
to the source E
I don't like to point out fourteen years
justice has been found and nobody has
done packets nothing on the lmo to where
it should be pretty sure somebody's
using it out there just alright
questions so I started by asking like
was done like you know network
assessments against windows networks did
you miss any questions we gotta make
exploit that you were remotely getting
the username and password for the user
name and domain over HCP in this niche
that you show up they're coming through
the clear that's a pretty big free
agents operate with his where the user's
credentials not there
ask her but I mean you've got something
to Crestwood Lane text you get has she
is the credentials that you need too hot
to break all really so that's a pretty
big like we identify that user or petrol
and just something about the internal
structure of the name of the company
there from the coming off like an
anonymizer something I'm using Chrome
that affect chrome does actually
litigated because it asks you before
sending any credentials he play your we
haven't checked like you know plugins
media players and stuff like that within
Chrome which could very well be the very
same API as away brother tell you right
chrome is not gonna believe the way i
coming to your question in regards to
you what's happening inside the network
when you try to play inside a user I
don't think we care so much about me
permission just closer we got shells
like you know the exact works to get a
shot inside the network will like making
the network like you don't there is
nothing gets basically you are inside
the network
in that case but you know maybe I don't
out exposed her breasts and beer are you
still leaking my name but I don't want
to change it
that's alright that's awesome just to be
clear if using a file on your computer
on your router you're not possible right
by default you of a level using a file
absolutely to block certain ports like
you install the Windows machine like
you're not safe basically you need to go
to your firewall to block traffic to
public aP's always gonna break like
sharing which may be you know what you
want just because we have like you know
each other better and that you will use
a bid to YouTube lucky you are
vulnerable when asked if you guys had
explored you mention one of the major
mitigating factors on SMB and you
explored WebDAV or the new features with
Windows to have work specifications on
the outbound connections we tried with
another operation I won't mention true
come back to work by creating holes and
I tried my best but we didn't try to
wind up in a letter I would say you know
every technique we know the rules apply
if this is really the way you want to go
back to say the network you could do
that to make a deal
attacked words that you use to log on as
the Ministry of her all just any account
the needs treat her group as far as I
know
any relief to all you mean when you read
what are you talking about like licking
her shes to the internet or where can we
execute and really still program so
unique stuff on the internet yet and you
can't has been able like you login with
your machine if we if you basically you
can browse the web you are vulnerable
area when he comes to reading back so he
can it depends the exchange stuff we've
seen him a box and Exchange you all know
the reason I see what you goin USD meet
every user about able to operate two
other key and no its not the case but
agreed what more can you put that
mitigation slime echo request and then
what was then DLL again you were
speaking I don't think it's on that side
ok its new white paper anyway which you
you should have access to that the Glu
school I need see you'll see the dealer
and it's under see Windows directory
automatically sends an SMS connection
that's a yes
any other questions yet so is it your
understanding from communications
Microsoft that if he almost was
implemented correctly it would be paying
attention to the registry flights and
offering us and be off or is that
something that microsoft says its
intended function now I don't work for
Microsoft I don't know you you might
need you would you have them like they
want to watch this is a deal they
acknowledged that is flawed in that deal
well the alleged there is a problem and
she's cheating and therefore my question
so you're talking about the very first
demo where we actually pushing matter
where you need to be able to coming back
to us and be the problem we we we
discussed right so either he takes balls
straight away on the internet and does a
public IP and no firewall and other ways
like you you cannot be that way and i
cant sign you cannot but anyway we have
this announcement which is basically
relaying over should you be and then
there is also would like to point out
that SMB allows you to upload files and
execute them as services so have you
shared anything on the Windows phones
tablets we actually SMB is not a
protocol support Windows balance as far
as I know the question my question he
said today one more I don't really I
haven't tested but I mean in terms of
doing the issue to be connection should
know like the corruption that means by
other proxy than what happens within the
proxy stranger to resolve the SMB share
that he's ready they're up there are
questions I don't know I don't I would
assume that it should you P process it
seems apply to other particles but it's
worth checking out model that basically
a process going to replace most proxies
do that kind of how I don't set
contention that he feels the same
credentials over because NTLM works on
the basically it also has the DCP stream
it as an authorized like that one
particular question so it had it cannot
get it so until the end of the proxy
proxy creates another and Jhelum
authentication to whatever it's going to
get
questions
SMB signing so we just got to be saying
tremendously right I am nothing it's
okay I asked if it works with SMB
signing because I didn't see it before
yeah it does be sending but you can
still download Exchange mailboxes ok I
guess we could put your day thank you
very much