you're here for a presentation I panel
about how the Wassenaar arrangement
export to Asian software affects the
security industry the panel will be
moderated by Kim Zetter without further
incident without further ado good
morning everyone
you probably already know what that
arrangement is that I'll give you just a
brief introduction and then I'll
introduce our panelists and I just want
to say up front we want this to be
participatory so we don't want to leave
questions for the end if you have
questions that come up for you at any
time comes microphones and we'll take a
break and take your questions so the
bison are mangement is export control
got a treaty but it's an agreement
between 41 nations including most of
Western Europe and the USA and it's not
a binding agreement I'm tired now
legally binding agreement what happens
at the forty one member nations that are
expected to pass export regulations or
rules or codify in their own nations
that would either lock the exportation
certain products and services or require
a license for them and in 2000 and 13
December 2013 by starvation was amended
surveillance software exactly was called
intrusions offer to the roles and now
member countries are in the process of
implementing their own rules to comply
with that he was already implemented
some that went into effect earlier this
year and the Aus Department of Commerce
is a division of it is currently
proposing its rules and if any of you
been following it costs a lot of
controversy because of the broad
definition of what they're using for
intrusion software and all the other
products that would be affected around
it so they've had their first round of
comments
and they've announced last week that
given the number of comments that they
received so far they will be going to a
second round of commenting and and
presumably that will result in a second
proposed rules were only gonna talk
about the proposed rules we have because
that's all we can address at this point
so I want to introduce our panel about
an excellent panel here can be a more
perfect I'll discuss this because the
people here have broad experience and
expertise in a lot of areas around
Boston are in that touch on it and are
affected by it I'm gonna start with my
left here this is Nate Cardozo he's a
staff attorney with the Electronic
Frontier Foundation focusing on
technology privacy and first and then
another free expression issues he works
on efforts coders Rights Project
counseling academics researchers
security professionals and hackers and
he also manages ESS eff has your back
project which analyzes how Internet
service providers not just in terms of
service providers subscribers or
handling your data next to him is Dino
Dai zovi is currently mobile security
lead Foursquare but he's been working in
information security for over a decade
of experience both in defense and
offense and his has extensive experience
in red teaming penetration testing
software security he started his career
with the illustrious group at state and
has worked on returning to them and both
commercial companies and government
customers these co-authored several
books including the IRS hacker's
handbook for the Mac hacker's handbook
and is renowned for winning the first
possession contest against a question to
them to understand is a Washington
dc-based researcher focused on
measurement and control on the Internet
including network ownership and access
restrictions with an emphasis and
countries that restrict the flow of
information he monitors the
International Sale of censorship
equipment which include exploring
alternative me
means of communications to bypass normal
channels of control and works on Open
Data projects to shed light on the
increasingly sophisticated restrictions
implemented by repressive regimes dating
service with you instrumental in getting
Microsoft finally launched the program
during the timeshare company is
currently chief Policy Officer hackers
on which helps coordinate and manage but
many programs for other companies in
addition to her work with her when she's
visiting scholar with MIT Sloan School
research and the vulnerability economy
and export markets Katie started her
career however computers but in
biological sciences working at the
bioinformatics bioinformatics lab at MIT
on the human genome project and at the
end
eight-year-old doesn't tell is CEO of
natural card which provides threat
assessment and assessment and advanced
penetration testing services that regard
also develops and brokers exploits 30
days and otherwise for its own using for
sale or at least it did until recently
announced last month that he was halting
the sale of exploits after hacking team
was hacked
there were confirmation but we'd all
suspected or known that the company was
selling its intrusion software to
repressive regimes and using it to spy
on activists human rights activist and
political activist it's particularly
apropos for what we're talking about
today one of the main reasons for
amending the bus and our management or
cited reasons is happy teen and its life
and so i think is going to have
particularly interesting important all
of this and so feel free to ask everyone
questions when they come up to my
pleasure said and will break but i wanna
start which is an overview of the big
lot of confusion about what fasten art
says and what it actually would do and
how to interpret it and so I want nato
to start with a smile can ask Colin to
step in after here to tell us exactly
what what does it say what are the most
problematic parts of it and how those
parts could be interpreted so I make her
design and staff attorney Electronic
Frontier Foundation is Kim said and I i
do some work in this area may need to be
counseling security researchers I also
submitted comments today to commerce
department in July on as well as in
concert with Colin timetable and a
number of other people so the Boston our
arrangement and I think colony became
can give a history of it
and what it actually controls but the
reason that that we're here the reason
that were in this place is because of
companies like hacking team JAMA the
preacher sure these are companies that
human rights community has had a problem
with prolonged sells software to two
governments who do you really nasty
things with the western democracies you
push the companies that are selling this
kind of software do you want happy
that's all you want to make sure so so
the history of this controls go back
about a decade maybe I can hear you ok
so this controls date back to about half
a decade in which it had increasing
visibility into the into the
facilitation of human rights abuses by
Western surveillance technologies
increasingly this became evident during
the Arab Spring in which both by
research methods but also by just those
use of information we started to see
specific needs those specific names such
as insist in Libya such as as tobruk or
in Bahrain such as
I can't even fucking became evidence of
what people knew which was that there
was a new and emerging market for the
the surveil the sale of sophisticated
technologies in order to allow
governments that were necessarily
tech-savvy to conduct their own
campaigns of intrusion into violence
against their citizens not only their
own citizens but actually often
diasporas abroad because of that
especially because the Diaspora
component there is increasing pressure
on governments to to start to to
restrict the sale of these to certain
states so actually a step back and and
note that in fact the Jew controls that
we're talking about are not the first
controls that were conducted for the
sake of privacy implications actually in
the 2012 funnier if there was a
restrictions on AMC coaches and actually
incidentally catcher catchers that came
into effect
quiet in the United States he said under
what's called the service here to just
listening control that's actually really
strict control when we start to use some
of these terms will use terms like
presumption of denial which means
effectively don't even bother to try to
get a license from us because we're
probably not going to prove it actually
this had already been in effect in the
United States House of 2013 so you know
that that sort of benchmarks that the
beginning of the of the use of what had
been predominantly sort of an anti
nuclear proliferation treaty and TE
conventional weapons treaty as as a
mechanism in which to control for the
the proliferation of
surveillance technologies and
technologies that human human rights and
foreign intelligence purposes so what we
have as we have currently two proposals
that have been implemented in the EU and
are being considered in the United
States when is the intrusions offer
control and it's really important that
we talk about these things we do so in
detail because this was actually highly
complex and a lot of the discussion at
least initially there's been a maturity
and increasing maturity but at least
initially was predicated on I think
misunderstanding of what these these
controls are so we have to we have to be
very careful when we discuss it actually
intrusions offer was a controlled a sort
of periphery of technologies around a
true from soccer well for the sake of
time to tell me this was the first
control actually that was presented by
the British government the British
government had been increasingly
pressure domestically and
internationally because of the presence
of companies such as gamma they had in
2012 actually gone to great lengths of
using encryption controls to be able to
to regulate the flow of them outside of
the UK and led to another market
concurrently we had during the plenary
withstood the discussion of the IP
network surveillance control and this
came out of france due to the
involvement of emphasis in in in Libya
the very highly publicized involvement
of incessant Libya providing substantial
network equipment substantial
surveillance equipment to the Kentucky
government again when we talk about
these sorts of things were using
specific terms that these two terms are
defined sometimes the definition of
problems talk about that but when I say
IP network surveillance I'm not talking
about
just dpi there's a there's actually a
seven if this and this and this and this
and this and this
the Defiant what IP network surveillance
is for the purposes of these controls in
and we should we can talk about that and
people can look but I want to make that
very clear so they started to come out
and implemented in the EU and where were
out is they were not implemented in the
united states in fact the united states
is generally the first the first date
implemented the way that the USM forces
at the way that the US interpreter
interprets it generally actually defines
what it means for the rest of the world
but what you saw was a very sort of
public publicly evident inability to
understand how to conduct this really
really come out of the progress of the
united states and so impact in one case
the Department of Commerce who is
responsible for the implementation in
consultation with a broader range of
agencies you put out something when they
implemented some of the roles that came
out that year and they said the cyber
security rules will come september
september passes and nothing and nothing
and nothing and nothing until very
quietly it drops in May May 2008 I think
that's a very very beleaguered this is
where we're out where we sort of have
this Department of Commerce trying to
figure out what these rules are that
came from Europe
not on me when you are confusing to say
the least
the Commerce Department of Commerce
Department is is usually guided by my
industry to call technical chinese Vice
Bureau of Industry and security on these
regulations regulations that we've got
our music industry hey I can talk about
why that's probably a little bit later
and we got a 68
everybody industry and their mother is
the name that he needs to be calling
putting tito submitted comments and it
was a resounding what the heck did you
guys just do and that's where we are
commerce has since the close the
commentary and done what a lot of people
urge which is say we know we screwed up
on this one we're going to revise the
rules and we'll have another comment to
that are already there were at the
crippled stage talking commerce stream
how to make these rules
implementable without computer screens
so let's have a quick question for
Atlantis what the problem areas are does
anyone know if when Boston are was being
amended was there the kind of kick back
in Europe around the member states when
they're deciding this ended a consult
seriously with any technology as part of
the reason why this is exposed as a
conversation is in part 41 the countries
of the USS legal regime are little bit
more difficult
practices such as deemed exports that
complexity but also to a certain extent
is actually brought this upon himself
and not necessarily a bad way which is
the US government more publicly debated
these rules in the EU member states and
so for example the Department of
Commerce did not have to be believed
open up the sixty-day comment
they did it very clearly engaged in a
process in order to solicit opinions and
to state what their implementation is
and so the fact that this is a argument
in the United States is a product of a
more open deliberative process that
seems to have existed in Europe it is
possible as I for starters I know the
japanese government had gone through
consultations there is a language
barrier that that is is difficult there
but this is in part just born out of
Commerce going through public I just
wanna remind all the panelists answer
any question
jump in and also an interview questions
so I think we should move on to so what
exactly are the problematic areas and
the repercussions are possible
repercussions from them I know that it
can get really detailed so let's give it
a little higher on the details so that
we can not get too bogged down between
might want to exploit are not exploit
and all that you want to jump in first
also have to say I speak for myself
current players I'm a scooter researcher
my concern of this is how to curtail my
ability to do research as a hobby or
more public areas are what caused the
diamond exports so for instance in the
BAS language there are talks about the
technology required
development tools and proprietary
research and indeed exports and see what
they could become problematic is yes I'm
also not a voyeur so I write for any
corrections on me
also ask mister I don't want to have to
consult a lawyer before I go to work to
know I'm going to the gym but deemed
export as I understand it in the ER
definition includes oral tension so for
instance and also applied to every
situation that is not public or not
immediately due for publication and
technology required for the development
of engine tools includes I own abilities
and techniques for bypassing type of
controls might be hiding from an
antivirus engine wear this runs into
very sticky details is if if I find him
guilty in Joesph whatever because none
of these regulations just like anything
about what classes where the size of the
user base and I use that to say you know
what
here's a picture called it we need to be
aware of the need to defend against and
maybe start work life time to go to the
disclosure process and open myself up to
cancel risks that way but I know where
she's like this I can't get into that
for non-us person and I work with a
coworker Nov 05 hehe
I am running afoul of these regulations
as they understand them and as I said
one of those one of the more problematic
areas here is that techniques were
controlled so if you want an elegy even
if I control even if the code is not
controlled the comments are probably
control because you're describing how to
techniques and technology before you get
to that there's a there's a there's a
there's no point in prison if I'm wrong
the proposals and make a distinction
between exploit and 0 day exploit so
anything that you described about mir
incorrect so they don't differentiate so
I think we're kind of going into which
is firstly which is one of the one of
the things that we're talking about is
as a part of the rules
intrusion software regulate doesn't
regulate intrusion top of the control
doesn't regulate itself it regulates the
basically the seat to infrastructure and
as as a part of that it regulates what's
called technology for development of
intrusions so this is what was given to
the Department promise this is something
in which all the summer people are
trying to figure out what is the what is
the
what isn't true sometimes there is an
exploit what is the ad technology for
the development of intrusion soccer this
is exactly what we're doing is referring
to is intrusion software vulnerability
is technology for discussion include
vulnerability and exploit so when this
came out the Department of Commerce very
again to their credit and gave him an
epic you process and they took questions
on a weekly basis posted to an FAQ often
it made people more confused but
sometimes it was clear maybe the more
confusing point is they said look
actually if not all of them
exploits they have to be this extended
criteria but if they do remember
intrusion software is not is not
actually what's control so what they do
say 20 days doesn't factor into but
what's interesting because as a
component as they say so the way the bus
networks is member states have to
language specifically but they have
flexibility in the way in which they
implemented what the like sort of if
there is a presumption of denial how
hard it is to get a license who can't
get their flexibility in that respect so
it is ahead as we are going to propose
that as a part of it we have a licensing
process that has a disclosure require
disclosure requirement actually kinda
including potentially the disclosure of
sorts but when the defense of it says is
we're going to have a denial in the case
of intrusions offer systems that include
0 days a rootkit capabilities so it's
not that they're regulating 0 diz
themselves they're saying if a product
has the possibility of supporting root
root root 0 there then you're going to
be a presumption which is a death
sentence for an expert that's very vague
because friends and Metasploit you can
just drop in a zero-day exploit written
as a display module now and that's
Tribune so boy has capabilities for your
tax place by that definition every
single penetration testing framework on
the planet by that definition by it
being a framework has 30 day
capabilities and didn't say whether
included it so I wanted to stay on that
part I care under UN and it really is
well above talked about how this might
affect research and communication with
workers also I wanted to address one
other issue in terms of implementing
your own security software on your
system presumably that's going to have
some kind of effect as well but did you
want to talk about the bug bounty
program said how this is going to affect
disclosure processes in general
and bug bounty programs in particular
our incentive or ability to structure it
is a subset of vulnerability disclosure
overall and the way that threatens the
primitives vulnerability disclosure
alright something with the other
panelists have been discussing if I
could simplify what would it is what we
need by me give you an example
rear have heard as it's been past few
months earlier in 2013 you mentioned
that I was pushed forward to Microsoft
but none perhaps one of those programs
were specifically designed to word
security researchers for coming up with
new exploitation techniques the language
in the litigation bypass County $100,000
bounty that Microsoft has paid out five
times since then I have to learn about
the language is nearly identical to the
language that you know everything about
exactly what is control so if you think
about it this is something that defense
needs to learn about as far as early as
possible as opposed to which can use
existing tax return
example I'm pretty sure to become last
night on this example of an existing
medications bypass took me two years to
bypass all the protective
countermeasures on you know on a given
platform that existing techniques often
doesn't necessarily need to invest in
learning about how everybody reads learn
about these techniques so an example
that would have been actually not even
possible to launch had been past few
months earlier I mean I didn't confirm
this with the TWC lawyer who helped me a
couple of weeks ago that I don't think
it would have been possible so
distinctly this is getting a new where
Jimmy Bullard the disclosure that alone
research as I want to add actually
something about let's say microsoft word
designing medications and as part of
that they were they had a team that was
investigating new techniques and and
that team included a non-us person so
unless Microsoft publishes those
techniques those application techniques
which I don't think microsoft is the
type of company to be publishing
techniques as I understand it they would
be violating the BIS proposed rules by
having their researchers in-house
communicate to their defensive
researchers are working on improving
medications if any of those two teams
included a non-us person that gets us to
the export as well because it deemed
export it to you
you CenturyTel for national nationalism
so that's one of the ways in which to
export provision of this is damaging to
even inside the same company
communication about these these
techniques that you would need to
actually implement defense I'm wondering
if you know where to look we're all
talking about worst-case scenarios and
I'm wondering why I understand the need
to have precise language and the house
narrowly defined terms and all of this
but are we making a big deal about this
and also
the question is you know it's only an
export license what's the big deal so we
have a doctor in the united states that
the short in his voice for Vegas there's
a criminal statute that a person can't
tell whether their conduct would lead to
criminal penalties for not that statute
is unconstitutional so average person
ordinary Italians and this is a betrayal
of ordinary soldiers can't tell if
whatever they're about to do is a
violation of that statute is
unconstitutional on its face so we are
making a big deal how big this is
because it has serious legal and
constitutional law perspective so we
don't just have to get the definitions
precise we have to get the definitions
understandable or they are for sale and
what are the repercussions insisted on
another note katydid something but I
wanted to ask if you don't understand
and you do violate oh no I mean what are
the potential
its criminal and civil penalties so
there you can go to jail and five years
since a willful violation commission and
omission noted as one of the big
questions and I think you're trying to
get at it in terms of consultation with
the right technology etc when drafting
original version is I think they did
attempt to essentially threat model this
when they put it together what we're
actually pointing out is that there's a
few key elements they didn't understand
vulnerability disclosure because they
thought vulnerability disclosure would
be protected because they assumed that
every piece of technology involved in a
disclosure would eventually become
public they did not understand the
distinction between between a technique
which may not become and a vulnerability
or an expert or all the rest of the base
so that is essentially gas and their
threat modeling this regulation that
essentially why we're in this place
where we're struggling to push back on
these definitions really crispy defined
but also point out areas where they
misunderstood the mechanics of what they
were trying to control its so I wanted
to inject point going back to the
drawing board of Law Center like as a
researcher I understand the desire to
control surveillance tools and I would
wish that the language is crafted more
focusing on the aspects of the tools to
make them surveillance tools and they
cause less collateral damage to
penetration testing tools and other
things that may provide external
instructions to system processes may
export trade some data but once you
start getting towards the aspects of
tools that heightened team and democrat
produced it makes them especially
offensive like I don't know capturing
Skype audio streams and bypass
encryption that way there's no mention
of anything like that and these are the
things that make these products
especially useful for these reasons and
it would in my mind
more clear if they focused on that but
don't you think though that especially
when delivering real penetration testing
services figure things out there about
the tools that we're going to use that
might also be easily classified as
surveillance tools there definitely are
and having done it myself like I did
remember like to add some flair
screenshot or a picture of the camera
however I feel like most engaging since
capturing audio streams from the target
computer setup a time capturing video
streams capturing your personal
dedication that is not encrypted once
you're entering into bad category like
you know delivered as a report that did
that your customer you pretty upset for
invading the privacy of their employees
in the basement you can yesterday
experts and data just to show you access
so these are things that are unique to
be surveillance tools that I don't see
being
running in common with it testing
testing engaging abort their tools
after you so we have customers that will
ask us to reproduce the type something
like she coming from the enemy state
right and we have customers that want
this is just how much we can reach and
and I want to see how hard we can dig in
the privacy of their employees like just
like you mentioned the facility building
the to leak on radar threats and radon
does a lot of stuff along with
Countrywide actually does all the money
it's completely undetectable by
president of our style is different
things what the customer ends up getting
it in his report that shows not only
where vulnerabilities are but the pastor
compromise access to critical data and
it shows a different possible to use to
covertly short trade data and we're able
to hit hard and didn't even use that
level threatened Coast Customs
infrastructure we can provide the
customer with Metro threat I i
understand the value and I agree with
you on the value of the attack path as
well and showing the choice of attacker
makes to get to that data but I
personally feel that like in Avengers
disengagement like a single picture of a
webcam is enough to demonstrate you know
maybe not a live video feed
you know or just saying look we have
full access to the system we've actually
traded two gigabytes of stuff data that
is mean you need to steal your xxx will
trade yo
exel traded to the actual P I have to do
that but by two-time detected that may
match the regular expression for credit
card number for instance
enough to show the access and capability
and there's a well-defined line there
that could differentiate surveillance
tools that are used for surveillance
from the tools of the penetration of the
skin she uses everyday
question so my question is to phone you
know one question is export restrictions
on software just the idea of it in and
of itself just seems illogical you know
your restricting say source codes is
someone's thoughts how do you enforce a
global Internet and is this just
financial software you pay for so free
and open source software things like
that and you know how do you how do you
enforce an expert restrictions so it's
actually a two-fold actually partly as a
result of the work of the ear open
source software is considered speech and
is not controlled by the ear
secondly there exists within Boston or
something called the general software
that is a saudi control node says this
doesn't apply to and what it says is is
that if this is available commercially
off the shelf it is not controlled by
Voss not part of the reason we have this
point of controversy is that what the
Department of Commerce said is there's
only one thing that is not in
put it in the general software nothing
corruption and and what the Department
of Congress said was I said actually so
we regulating corruption we see these
things we have a presumption that
everything that would be controlled
under intrusion software already employs
encryption so we're going to remove the
generous offer no cold place and
exemption tsu in the United States and
so in part what they start to do and do
in doing so they start to winnow it down
to a select piece of software which is
things that are not this is the
attention they usually are not
commercially that are not commercially
available that they had they are sold to
a restricted user base and exercise some
level of exclusivity and who can
consumer and so we're that starts to get
away from this being sort of open source
cloud projects ideally into something
that is being sold to some somebody
privately restricted highly and sold at
a very expensive rate this is the this
is the intention of the controls general
two points one another to control the
size or call mention sale and likening
the suffered a speech i agree that
increase after is great but if only free
softwares beach and only commercial
software speechless like in that two
publications books or speech blog post
and tweet their speech private
correspondence not speech
shows that there is a wide for a wide
variety of protected speech and these
categories are not sufficient
you mentioned encryption I was wondering
the mechanism to implement these would
comparable to the nineties when we had
the export restrictions on strong
encryption
sounded like we have similar the
apartment communities and forcing it is
it the same mechanism in place just not
covering encryption but software in
similar so in the nineties encryption is
regulated by the rules that we're
talking about our department of commerce
during get thats case on behalf of dan
Bernstein against the regulation of
encryption aight are awaiting the
government reacting to something very
similar means the controls ever looking
at today I got restrictions from back in
my case study
leg holes today we should learn from
from those original could do worse is
how much control ended up doing the
opposite of what was intended which is
weakening the security of Internet we
are looking at essentially the same
possibility with unfortunately well
intentioned regulations and where I see
this we're sorry this is where we have
regulators and lawmakers who are
struggling and age where conventional
weapons could be regulated in such a way
but cyber weapons are an entirely
different different object for very many
reasons and I'm much more difficult to
control using expert export controls for
technology if I went to send out we are
in danger that during the Prohibition
era for exploitation and often research
and much like the provision about the
whole that that occurred in the United
States for what
12 miserable years we do not need we do
not need to suffer the consequences of
such a state I think at this point we're
we're at a point where we can we can
stop up and also add to your provision
of metaphors I love by the way
regulating something that you can make
in your home in the bathtub is
problematic but I mean a stronger more
793 the net interpret censorship is
damaging wrapped around it
that's applicable to the liver alcohol
reference there's a difference between
the moonshine what the professional
distillery is true but not in the scope
of these regulations basically there is
no distinction of ability and Joesph
keeper and if I W or affordability and
windows or Android two billion people
use and that's fundamentally the
importance of this conversation over
whether the general software note
whether what sort of license exceptions
are brought to bear because this is one
of the things civil society action
engaged in this issue starting from the
issue and this was one of the important
point was there is a fundamental
difference between what you know I as a
computer science was doing to do with my
friends back in back in high school back
in college and what happened to him is
putting up in the level of
professionalism support and what the bus
in our control framework allows for is a
differentiation however with the
Department of Commerce has issued a
proposed rule out of town over old does
not differentiate these two things that
I had my reading of the last couple
nights ago but the text I need some help
sleeping and didn't make a distinction
either general softening attempts
intends to make that distinction with
the
I wanted to talk about so we're talking
about a third of the difficulties of
regulating this and also does the
difficulty of nine who you are and the
user is so after it was exposed in the
heading to me know that you're told an
exploit to hacking team you announced
that you were going to and sell it
exploits and you feel that though there
is a need for some kind of export
control
and that can help you know we're in end
user is in part so talk about that I
think I think there has to be meeting
2004 salable and everybody is going to
perform research and we're gonna they're
gonna be breaking assistance watchers
resigned today getting what I think is
control should be really prevent
legitimate issue because I care about
last year's I think that I think that
there needs to be some kind of framework
towards the end users Council guest
vocals sorry but I provide one example
that I love
children example is what I didn't 2013
posted a message on board with your
Firefox you know that was in my opinion
I don't think that's the reason we're
actually ended up being something really
good but they need people like i cant in
which they go beyond a result of 10
people like hiking today are are just as
they don't even under contract but
candidly and and
they don't care they provide their
technology to that kind of technology
run characters and dangers in the right
place so it's necessary I I am not sure
about the idea actually control control
guns and handguns object was your day is
also objects but we control the users
and so i think that the better framework
maybe something that focuses on the
user's you know framework like what I
was doing really can also get a group or
whatever else is out there people you
have to be licensed to have some kind of
a process used by the train working ugh
I think the trying to regulate here it
is you know is it's really interesting
do it is going to have a really big
impact on securities or negative impact
and it's not just researches the effect
that either its online service is in
response to mean we have got it
you know we deliver penetration tests
and all our team members we have enough
to stop Luxembourg if we were if we're
going out and infrastructure and we
identify a newborn ability we can surely
provide the information first overseas
the people in my portfolio project and
also let alone here what about instant
response what happens if your business
overseas offices in your piece of
technology this local but for some
reason you can't actually the technology
because it violates something like shit
you not to respond to this incident
before it becomes critical for a license
Company time you apply for the license
the damage of time that is specifically
or not it is but I don't think that I
don't think it's focuses so i'm waiting
for time so I just a lot of people
standing I want to get two questions
will go with you first
actually come back on something you said
at the start of the whole basis of the
Wassenaar changes was down to us we're
being spotted the Arab Spring and the
journalists reporting on this camera
Busters three years now for the Arab
Spring and nothing but nothing was done
about it so why why now so it's because
the process is slow it's because there
wasn't sufficient amount of legal
mechanisms in some cases such as the use
of encryption controls to regulate them
that led to them leaving the country
that's also an important point as to why
unilateral controls and unilateral over
enforcement of controls is ineffective
compared to a harmonized multilateral
regime which the vast arrangement is
supposed to do obviously people can
moved to you know like China export but
this is the this is the this is the
interest of providing a sufficient
amount of tools to create a regulatory
structure in order to exercise at least
some sort of government oversight and
some sort of transparency and
accountability towards those those
coming so we have time for just one more
question just any word on threat
intelligence services they claim to go
out and mine data or cross the web and
the dark with and goes up to their
clients this
ok we have time for another question
apparently turned away from people and
come back out
insights by the panel think you guys my
question really is I'm glad to establish
a conversation I'm glad we still have
the opportunity to talk about it what
are some things that we can do as a
security professional community to kinda
ramp this make sure that our voices are
heard that we protect the ability to do
threat collagens you guys give us a way
forward
just want to step in both KTM and Colin
have gone through the comment
extensively that have come in and if you
can address in that responding that also
what people have been doing that doesn't
help the kind of comment that the good
can easily get dismissed because they're
not helpful or no one really empower the
feedback that we're getting good so
actually I've been a proponent of these
rules and I i sat in consideration
going for it and thinking how am I going
to get lynched coming to black and and I
reached out to some friends and I
thought well is there still constructive
and the answer is yes the proposed to
comment period is closed but bis Randy
wheeler is going to be at one tomorrow
that's engagement and so even if the
comment period is closed the likelihood
of any sort of outrage getting sort of
attention is very high in the meantime
in addition to that we now know that
there will be a second a second proposal
and so that will have its own comment
period in which you can put in what is
helpful is not necessarily people put up
I think the jailbreaking community
misunderstood or I guess they understood
and put up some very farcical comments
some known people in this or aside this
community put up some hateful comments
but the vast majority were people saying
I am afraid of this this is not helpful
that's good
it provides public pressure but what is
even better is to say this is the
specific things that are prevents me to
do this is what you want to enable this
is how I think that you can fix it and
so the more that people can speak to
material concerns and how they affect
their security operations the more the
BIS will listen to you and what ends up
happening at the end of the day all
those suggestions get put into a table
and the more the people are saying the
same thing the higher the back gets
attention and and and you should ask if
you're going to be a tough run tomorrow
I don't know if it's a faux pas to cross
reference if if you're going to be asked
Brenda ruler directly what can I do to
help you to make sure that you have
constructive and doesn't put more work
on you as well
of Commerce business is required to to
come up with a rule that complies with
the original I think that they are
obviously they're engaged they're trying
to get comments back however about that
they would need to apply in order to not
fundamentally in P
the defense of the internet itself in
all of the various ways the panelists
here and there is a few in the audience
would would have as an example of how
the rule would affect them and what
effect you know defensive uses of office
technology I think once all of the
carve-out are presented it will be clear
that we actually need to revisit
Wassenaar itself I do not think it will
be sufficient to simply men and a man
and provide part about we will do so you
know as a community and I think that's
important but I think that should ended
up raising awareness when you provide
all of the exemptions required to to
make sure that this does not impede
defense that we are going to have to go
back to us and our and talk about
different proposals to get at get it
something that is more substantive and
narrow to you the to the cause at hand
which is protect human rights
ok so we're out of time unfortunately
but if you want to continue the
conversation I believe people will be
happy to answer questions outside the US
off the stage at allies but thank you
for our panelists