you're currently inside Mandalay Bay EF
and you are here for defending past the
hash with seven more and Murray said I
thank you and please put your phone's on
vibrate nobody's ringtone is cool thanks
guys
good morning we're here to talk about
mitigation surpassed the hash which are
in Windows 10 so passed the house is
really a term which congress applied to
multiple attacks all of which encompass
credential fashion which is at the heart
of many high profile attacks had a
couple of years ago we had us'
newspapers such as The Wall Street
Journal New York Times were breached
just last year I believe Sony Pictures
right around the release of the
interview the movie they had a big time
reach lots of lots of data dumped out
they didn't want external and then kind
of my personal favorite just because
it's kind of a movie heist is the carbon
at group indian guys made off with a
billion dollars by deeply infiltrating
bank networking computers and
essentially setting up time dropped at
ATM machines and they would just walk
out
make a small withdrawal and actually
walk off with hundreds of dollars
instead of $20 so all of these attacks
use a feature that nobody really wants
to live without their OS that is single
sign-on so single sign-on is effectively
delegating to the operating system the
capability to act as you on the network
to access resources no one wants to log
onto the computer and then type your
password every time the access a file
share internet site something like that
they just want those things to happen
and that means the computer connectors
you and that means attackers like this
or to Pilates heists steal those things
still credentials off the device to act
is here so what does
past the hash or credentials have to
look like in Windows so poor start
talking about it we need to talk a
little bit about what this architecture
looks like in on Windows in this example
we show Alice and her laptop there's
something called else asked which is the
Local Security Authority subsystem else
asked and it hosts all the
authentication protocols and does a lot
of security stuff in Windows in here you
can see it's hosting in TLM and Kerberos
the two most commonly used protocols on
demands so inside the logic inside the
memory else asked for these protocols we
contain things which are still double by
the attacker so an admin level attacker
can read into memory on the device that
he wants to which means he can read your
in TLM hash or we call it here in teow s
kind of a mouthful he'll still that and
be able to authenticate his you using
NTLM the attacker can steal your ticket
draining ticket key out of Kerberos
which means he can act as you using the
Kerberos protocol and if your user like
Alice in this example is using a
password
the attacker concealer that password
still it out of memory or just social
engineer or fish house so once the
attacker has one or multiple of these
credentials they take he's in replay
them forming a sort of chain reaction to
the chain reaction starts with one
system a foothold system and it could
just be something like a front desk PC
that an administrator uses and the
administrator get social engineered or
something on Facebook downloads and
malware and and their pop their own it
happens that often back user is admin on
their PC which means the attacker the
malware can now harvest the credentials
out of Alsace once the attacker does
this
they can move to another system once
they're on that system they attempt to
gain more credentials if there's
administrator access and then they go to
more systems and where systems gathering
more and more credentials and till
you're doomed right they they've they've
deeply infiltrating your network is kind
of a big deal so multiple technologies
exist today to make prudential theft
more difficult so one of these
multi-factor off which means you you
can't just steal when prudential in
order to completely take over someone's
identity you have to have to steal
multiple things such as their cell
phones and a password
there's something we call strong
credentials which really needs key based
credentials for a key a private key is
in hardware such as with a smart card or
a Fito hearing these the attacker cannot
steal the private key software attack
and another solution to the problem
which kinda takes a different tack is
called token binding which is the
concept of credentials are tokens which
are downloaded to the device as a part
of authentication are then bound to that
device cryptographically so that even if
the attacker steals them they can't
replace them they can only be used on
the original device so we have some cool
technology and its well-known but we
can't always deploy it because
businesses like to make money it's it's
what they do and the corollary to that
is they don't want to spend more money
than they have to so businesses have
lots of legacy components like a printer
or a file server that only talks in TLM
and the businesses don't see a big
return on replacing those so
these devices use legacy protocols and
these legacy protocols are vulnerable to
attacks such as past the hash so our
challenge here is defending against
these attacks on legacy protocols
without requiring a lot of training in
these devices which requires keeping
secrets which already talked about in
Christchurch
morning Caroline my name is going to say
that I am one of the leads in situations
team and we know spanned by some group
decision is about keeping secrets and
remaining product is keeping secret is
not very difficult actually let me share
a story too long long time ago perhaps
they could exceed far far away and
improved told me to get ready for a big
motor company share information
disclosure though he doesn't share the
exact time I am so tired country stood
catch them off guard
one of the general security she knew the
details she could prepare his army much
finished goods repaired a tactic
spirited queue size of two teams
everything's so he insisted on knowing
the details he kept asking the Emperor
kept asking asking asking you one day
and told him to his presence he said
come close tell me do you know how to
keep a secret jail got excited said yes
I do know how to keep a secret
members found it so the white
implying just be me lol so keeping
secret is easy in fact all you have to
do is just keep your mouth shut by did
nothing productive either of course the
Emperor was issued a sick received his
generals so they can prepare better
generalize right and you'll of course
want to be able to share your secrets
said maybe to return email with your
accountant doctor just keeping secrets
to yourself is not the solution so you
need to be productive long gone are the
days of emperors individuals who can
make all kinds of decisions
oversight or No Deal accountability
other governments today Dave balance
powers to ensure accountability and
parental
the way they achieved by separating
powers first legislative day make laws
they may decide the highway from this
city that city which lanes and just kind
of quality executive branch carries out
the tasks they hired contractors to
build a high-wage they make sure that
the quality is there and just judicial
system make sure everyone is playing by
the rules even though the justice system
even the executive branch for instance
they've made dramatic wish to build a
highway is to pass off the highways
going true tribal dance or two national
parks or they made
punished executive branch is down not
awarding the contracts charity it is
reasonable to think all the modern
operating system as a modern government
in this case administrators for power
stage and decide who / AP Egyptians
authorization kernel system services
drivers Rd executive power they allocate
memory they create processes threats
they allocate see if you called us and
they just perform those tasks arguably
the biggest difference of modern
operating systems he trusted computing
base which combines the operating system
from being a jungle make sure that
everyone is playing by the rules
Edmonds and turn opens with it if you go
to assume the kernel which includes a
TCB you would be taking a huge risk for
118 staters humans and humans make
mistakes you made it really curious
about an email to watc and you hate to
see those cast by these two double click
on that and you shouldn't i mission is
compromised we don't want that also who
say administrators can be trusted at all
times they cannot be humans can play tf2
gaming channels you know cheating point
of view all
software licensing or think of month in
scenarios hussein's these administrator
is the only administrator on the system
did he not be the case that may be
operating the street to street certain
secured expectations and who says this
system is the only system on this hot
day maybe virtual machines which
certainly security expectations so it
was being equal to TCB his logo journal
on our hands one may argue is just so
fair and just like humans they don't
make mistakes maybe but is a Tax Service
and the typical operating system
hundreds if not thousands of system
calls and I'll tourists there's a huge
attack surface and most operating
systems journal is shared between August
and told party drivers and you start by
two drivers may come from companies had
questionable security policies this is
not a new problem
Microsoft Windows tried to solve this is
the best one of them is attached to
court or in principle we are putting in
a petition often attends cheated
identity on the line I just Microsoft
Microsoft scientists piece of court and
I trust is key dates
well in theory but in practice
strongly situation off publishes buying
certificate authorities is questionable
at best and if one of them makes a
mistake to certificate is slow and hard
process so this can be the ultimate
solution for ticket process sleepy or
product process like people to do the
same we noticed a big no salen in
principle protect certain user more
processes says the processes from the
rest of the user mode including the
engineer if it means stated choice to
access for instance a CSS process by
injecting tracks it has blocked the
kernel or if she tries to read memory
right memory just block the problem is
it all boils down to colonel and he just
so join those cannot be the source of
truth because of its attack surface of
its complexity that God was designed to
protect Colonel Charles it limits what
Kermode can do in kernel however it is
risk-based and your brain too choppy to
hackers
dates not feel safe for them or doesn't
protect drivers from other drivers which
I am proud of the state agencies are
designed and developed by PeopleSmart
today these are good technology spot
they all head of fundamental flaw they
rely on software we should do our
security on something harder something
for her let's take a quick locates hard
and long distance on x86 and x64 systems
they headed a single spaced Journal ran
a min 00 had access to end I additional
200 space so if you get code execution
colonel it means stands you have D
D with a hypervisor
another section made it just similar
story inspired is nothing time winding
stairs and nothing to do with the Rings
it's it's brought it down for its also
known as minus one its promises on
hardware and all the difference from
earnings that it is very small very very
very small therefore it is much easier
to protect and it is so much easier to
secure Darfur hypervisor and show me
that small simple space can be our true
trusted computing base now we heard
place to store our secrets but says I'm
ancient the only goal is not starting to
secrets also being able to process them
to do something with those so we need
extra cords to make something
encouraging secrets
the province keep in mind that coating
hypervisor we are back to square one
hypervisor gets more complex it is more
difficult to secure and it is coming a
jungle so we don't want that carry yours
hypervisor technology want not pollute
hypervisor let me introduce virtual
trust levels using virtualization
technology and six others translation
sections of memory can be protected in a
just getting fishin just virtual to
physical which can lead to a system
physical that way I love of memory it is
access protected from the Rizal to
system with the ground case of
hypervisor and from their busiest the
architecture behave today bring three
user mode on the top
which is less access 2003 space which
has more pillage I need to buy them is
the IP wiser and Amir Johnson computing
base that's called his detailed 0
instead of growing vertically norwegen
Grove rising forty we have all the
information security video 1 isolates
itself sleep to leave from the rest of
the system by default the rest of the
system including 20 cannot access media
15 you 2012 he may decide to share
called on to shared data patients all
details hero and a beautiful status in
the future
extended but the school to use to you
just love exactly let's take a deeper
look this is our normal girls today we
have transplanting process is making
calls into kernel for executive branch
support and hypervisor keeping everyone
in line between gel 19 V Pro Bowls tanks
we have received your username and
secure tunnel secured and unsecured user
behave trench just like a normal user
those threats running processes call to
+ lets those trust let's still depend on
secured kernel for certain things
creating trash other teaching memory for
instance secure channel in turn alliance
at the moment colonel I will explain the
interaction in the next lane but really
hard trying to use a lot of calls to
make the situation as accurate as much a
small as possible and user roles normal
growth can talk to secure user using RPC
secure all is invisible it is not a new
education and you will see there's no UI
no user interaction
it has minimal impact on performance we
are expecting in fact less than 2% of
heat in most cases it has much tighter
control there's not going to be any
third party called into secret journal
it's going to be all operating system
trustees are isolated from each other so
even if one of the trustees scared all
it's not going to be able to inject the
trust will be limited in number they
will be purpose-built and they will be
much smaller than for it is easier to
protect it's easier to secure a dismal
into saying security is smaller the
catchphrase serious could use if there's
no security perhaps because your heart
doesn't support it translates can run as
normal process
Security Alliance and lightens normals
roles and tools for meetings scheduled
range also former management and
synchronization could use however there
are certain things state secret journal
thats make sure the institutional stays
secure for instance contributing / are
including the pages before dad being
paid out by
and toes is among those tasks detailed 0
is not trust it's important to
understand
30 doesn't mean security anymore in this
new world retail 0 is not trusted secure
colonel while he is depending on 07 does
its job
hardening against the system called
senator Mounties
secure is important and it is not in
concrete hypervisor depends on where and
I'll 464 is still part of the trusted
computing base just small
1800 of course any signs of Sophia can
have box inject into he's presenting
later this afternoon about the
implications of firmware political tease
I really encouraged to attend a
presentation at home so bottom line is
secure vault is secure all the integrity
of Holt ECB is maintained so I have to
of course one of them is called our
partners we are in this game together
like so and he tell his partner
providing valuable tools green shoes or
stools
engage with us and police catch the
security vulnerabilities in bios and
other people other apostles to favored
time in a timely fashion and cold to our
customers
it is very important to keep the
firmware and BIOS updates in Windows
stand windows updates can make sure your
system is secure our Emperor as a way to
start of cigarettes and also too
intelligent to process them as my dear
friend said we'll explain thanks so when
I'm gonna talk about here is how we can
use this new architecture using the
hypervisor is a new essentially lowering
to secure a legacy protocols before we
can really dive into the architecture of
what we've built here need to talk about
a couple of Primaris the first one is
down critical string not all credentials
are created equal so it some potential
such as passwords or naive cookies are
extremely weak because they can be very
easily stolen cookies are stolen out of
browser cache users are fished for the
passwords are key lobbed very easily to
me credentials are a problem
strong credentials are credentials that
we consider theft resistant such as a
smart card smart card requires physical
staffed tried to steal the card
two-factor authentication is also not
necessarily as strong but strong and
this leads to a loss is accepted into
which is users with me credentials they
get out they they get finished their
passwords leaked yet still in bad things
happen so we need to start with strong
credentials that said
I also feel it's important to talk a
little bit about how we do smart card
off in Windows Windows users Kerberos
standard protocol for porting smart card
authentication Kerberos of course the
three headed dogs it's a three legged
authentication protocol you have your
user and this case Alice with her smart
card at KDC distribution center that's
what you authenticate to authenticating
property and then some service you want
access network which is the files over
to the first thing that happens is
alexander's ARP in the smart card is
used to do some proof of possession of a
key that proof is presented as an
authenticator to the KTC who hands back
a ticket printing ticket for TGT and the
key associated with that TTT so that he
needs to be used with the TGT
when Alice wants to access the file the
TGT is presented to the ATC in the KTC
replies with a service ticket and a key
internet service ticket is used to go
get the files so already we can see one
thing that is going to be interesting to
attackers to steal and that is the TGT
he says if an attacker has a key there
you for a time-bound about a time but I
believe it's seven days by default in
Windows it's it's days of time which is
plenty but there's more interesting
stuff to steal whenever you get a
service ticket in Windows you're into
UWS NTLM authentication hash is returned
as well and that was done years ago I
believe in 2002 support backwards
compatibility with Intel and shares
because nobody even then could give up
there in tellin so now we've we've
talked about two things in this diagram
better vulnerable to theft so how do we
protect those things well this is sort
of a zoomed in version of the
architecture bias was talking about
earlier but we have the attacker
you can see that he is unable to access
memory and I UMCOR secure world and
normal world he's got free rein we're
assuming he's an administrator and it's
also important to note that all devices
are in normal world there's no device
i/o in the secure World
everything there sits on top of the
hypervisor so when the New World things
look similar to the old world alsace
continues to run it continues to be
vulnerable it runs inside of normal
world and the vast majority of political
logic is inside of Alsace so I buffer
manipulation things like that
what is new is prudential guard or
credit card for short it's a new process
that runs inside of the secure
environment it's very very small and it
contains protocol support logic so
anything the protocol needs to do with a
secret such as you're into your WF for a
curb risky that always happens inside a
credential guard that secret is never in
Alsace in the NL SAS uses the protocol
support logic but hardly see all the
secrets are only ever in the clear in
credit card they may exist in an
encrypted format in normal world so
we're assuming the attacker can still be
encrypted Wednesday its strong
encryption 256 bit AES those secrets may
be passed back into credential garden
used where there in a decrypted form the
attacker here cannot access them so it's
just a little bit more and look at the
specific artists artifacts to protect so
in the old world prix windows 10 all
these artifacts just satin memory
waiting for someone to run many cats or
something and come out in the New World
the only ever exist in the clear in
credit card and they're protected from
sniffing so that's a pretty good first
start but it's not quite enough to
really mitigate attacks as noted earlier
in the prior slide devices are
accessible in normal world
this includes your USB bus which means
if you're using for example a smart card
an attacker can sniff your smart card
and key target then use that smart card
to start the entire authentication
process go get a TGT service ticket they
can play the whole game so you're still
here still owned this point so we need
something to prevent this avenue of
attack in the way we do it is by
building a promise that the secrets are
isolated since the attacker historical
access to your cred they can still pass
the hash so we need to guarantee the
isolation is actually happening but it's
not an attacker using your smart card
and so the solution here is actually an
existing IETF standard RFC 6113 its
astoundingly good bedtime reading if you
can't get to sleep in existing standards
we implemented I believe in 2012 are too
it's it's out there in the field and it
provides something called compound
authentication so with compound
authentication you combine the user's
credential with the machine credential
in order to build proof of where the
user is authenticated trunk and so with
this proof we can build the promise that
the artifacts that are returned to the
client from the KTC remain hidden so the
first thing we need to do to leverage
compound authentication is start with
strong machine credentials so machines
in Active Directory domain have
credentials just like a user they sign
on to the domain prior to 2012 are to
the only credential machine can use was
a password is a high entropy strong
passwords not to generate a couple but
it was still stored on the device it
could be east slope ran it could be
gathered off the hard disk not very
strong so we need to do is use a private
key which is owned inside of credential
guard in that way represent attacked her
access to the key
so by combining this stronger machine
authentication with a strong potential
with compounding which is provided by
Kerberos fast and 2012 are to that level
of functionality we can apply what we
call an authentication policy which
dictates which systems a user is
actually allowed to authenticate from
let's talk a little bit more about
exactly how this compound authentication
works so first we start with the machine
ninety key the machines logs onto the
demand just like user gets a TGT and PGT
key with that
credential from the machine TGT key we
now derive what we call in our murky
it's really sort of proof of origin key
that says yes I'm coming trauma system
which has access to this machine TGT so
our user credentials combined with the
proof of origin in order to authenticate
and using this we get beat EDT for the
year so only by starting with a strong
team credential combining losers off
with that stronger machine off can we
get the TGT the policy is checked at the
domain controller side since the
attacker has no access to the machine I
D not even normal access to the ski
there's no way for the attacker
even start this chain to get a DDT so
the path we have here to get to a strong
user involved users using only strong
credentials the systems need to be
secured and the systems need to be
provisioned with the machine key not a
password passwords are just too easily
stolen and then authentication policies
need to be set up on the domain
controller because that is where we
really do the gatekeeping and prevent
these steal artifacts these possible
hashes and keys from being returned to
the device for the first question was
everybody asks is why I'm just gonna
turn it off its on the client right
thing so it
what makes it a little more than just
client trickery so let's quickly so an
attacker has taken over alice's laptop
now has an N and has found a way to
disable
protections and that's bad news right
but if you notice the machine identity
he also goes away when credential bart
goes away because the only thing that
can use that key is credentials so now
when alice is credentials are used to
request a TGT from the domain controller
the domain controllers going to check
the policy see that there is no proof of
origin there's no armor on that request
in say no no way I'm not gonna give you
what you want so that said we have a
demo so what we have here is a couple of
clients are running care and so alice is
a user on this domain with a smart card
and we need to set alice's password
password idea someone yell loud
password 123
that's an awesome password every go so
well said her password if I can't type
correctly right now we're going to go on
to the clients and he's many cats and
tried to steal the hash for the password
so first let's go to the system the
system has no this one does not have
credentials are disabled so i'm gona
login here with the virtual smart card
and while that's all that was cool and
I've got a second system here with
Prudential buried on cuz I like T rex is
better and I'm gonna log on there too as
Alice so it takes a little while to log
on when I searched rehydrate the PM's
but now you can see alice is a desktop
we have performed a complete dance with
the domain controller I now have a TGT
and the into WS is on this device and as
you can tell by the dreadful looking
wallpaper it's easily stolen so I'm
gonna go be a bad guy and still the
password I can take
so the first thing we need to do is see
what alice's hash looks like so I just
got a little talk here that will dump
the Indy for the password the entire WS
so here we go
89 F d remember the first word that's
good enough
around rusty old many cats and see if we
can find out
so let's see it should be at the top
wow
so here we go a 950 that sounds correct
as it so Alice you got popped you're
you're done so that's no good she should
know better because the skull and
crossbones so forget this system which
is not running critical guard currently
is not actually supported in the RTM
build in the initial build of Windows on
GM's we have some private that's here to
make things work so let's let's login
over here let's be Alice again except
this time when the secure system and so
let's go maybe cats and we'll see what
comes out of jealousy memory
that's logging on so you may have
noticed that alice is still not in a
good position 'cause alice is able to
log onto the skull and crossbones system
right she still very very open to attack
so how do we prevent that from happening
what we need to do is use authentication
policies so the authentication
authentication policy set up with
Prudential guard enabled so what you do
with that policy is applied to specific
user in this case Alice to Alice's has
this policy applied to her and this
policy says down below that alice is
only allowed to log on trial i
unenrolled machine so she can only login
from machines which have credit card
those are the ones we trust so once I
enable this policy now can no longer
live on the global system
so what's happening let's go back over
here this is the awesome system is that
it has potential guard running so we can
tell credential guard is running because
it actually shows up right here in task
manager
right here we go running a little bit
memory waiting for you to authenticate
producer guards running slips that
stands out now
security and once again but now you can
see where one engage just to build off
of the head of many catches get out from
a few days ago you can see that many
cats now recognizes that gosh this is an
encrypted hash opal you could see it as
a happy ending many cats so I'm gonna
ignore that tastes like I ignore most of
them and say hey look there's no house
share but many cats recognizes that
there something encrypted here that is
very resistant to attack so now I've
applied that policy now so we can go
back to the first system so she is not
actually authorized to log on from let's
see what happens
oh no I i can assume this hopefully you
can see it it says your account is
configured to prevent you from using
this computer that's what we want this
computer is vulnerable to attack
we want to block Alice from using his
computer and so what has happened is the
domain controller has actually not send
any possible hash to this device and it
hasn't sent any Kerberos keys that can
be stolen device at most what the
attacker house is my pin which is 1234
the best plan ever
and access to using that smart card on
this device but it's not really usable
to log on from this device so that all
said I did show you the group where
we're doing a little bit of a call it
cooking show magic broken open the other
hand pulled something out there is cake
the machines are in groups which is kind
of weak so the way we want people to
actually use this is by enrolling
machines with a certificate and
certificate and he's to contain a
specific weighed so as a Windows 10
sir trek toward the built-in tool now
has the capability to enroll the machine
with a certificate and key so what
happens is an RSA 2048 bit key is
generated and then a Certificate Signing
Request is made and the device gets a
certificate that it uses to authenticate
in this certificate contains an oil did
and then we mapped out a way to the
group so the proof really comes not from
the machine itself that you just trust
this machine and you know it's
configured right the proof comes from
only credential guard on that machine as
the certificate enrolled and it is the
only thing that is able to actually get
back toward it's it's it's the only
thing that can get that is the only
thing that needs the authentication
policy and allows Alice to log on
that wraps up the demo so I want to
reiterate
we have designated steps to mitigating
many known attacks such as writing me
capture or maybe made a splitter
something on a system and as we go over
really quickly what these steps are the
first thing you gotta do is get rid of
terrible protocols like Emma strategy to
an Intel Mb one those are really the
same protocol but they're the terrible
they basically just blast year intel and
hash on the network with really poor
encryption at 8:57 it does or something
equivalent does it's very weak users
need to use strong credentials smart
cards are good for chill smart cards are
good as well
devices need to support I am and of
course there are hardware requirements
which we have documented Windows 10
support needs to be enabled the
credential Guard searched everything
needs to be enrolled all the
documentation for the setup I demoed
here is online definitely I was hoping
to be online for black and it's not
there yet but you'll be able to find it
at microsoft.com / heheh and from there
you can download the documents and set
this up yourself and it's ready to be
tested in RTM now when does 10 download
it right up my little time for questions
before we get to that I went to give
thanks to some folks when is the
Microsoft TSN team lot of smart girl
dies lot of smart hypervisor guys every
manager dudes worked really hard to make
this platform and credentialed are just
something that we developed on top of it
and I'd like to think he'll be offered
many cats he was super helpful and even
updated many cats when Windows 10 moods
and things around in memory so that it
it actually recognizes as you can tell
the demo that we've got isolation on her
critics and on so thanks to those guys
questions we have a microscope to shout
yes if you have a TPM
the guidance is you really need a TPM
and if you've got it
the route encryption key for secrets for
trust let's is bound inside a repeat the
question
oh I'm sorry to hear that he was asking
how do we prevent someone from just
stealing the secret such as the machine
he offered advice and if you have a TV
and we will we will use TPM to bind to
the device
he says he understands that the keys
themselves 40 p.m. are actually stored
on the disk and identity p.m. mighty
p.m. food is not super strong that I
think you're right but what's on the
disc itself is actually encrypted so you
have to import the keys off the disc
into the TPN and you get a handle that
key in and that's what you use so even
if you steal that the long-term storage
of the keys to the Jeep keys off the
discs they are encrypted that it is is
it as credit card and every building
windows it's on enterprise builds in
education builds I know and I believe
all server builds the documentation
trusted when it's always like more than
me I don't throw rocks at me as I can
the question is if there's going to be
any sport or service scenarios yes
there's going to be it is planned
that's obvious I'm currently for
credentialed art it's it's primarily a
client-focused mitigation so that's
awesome question you may need to be
updated we do rely on features in 2012
are too so yes you do need to be new and
that's newer than what many customers
are unfortunately it doesn't have to be
when does it end though
you're doing here it's going to be a
survey of these questions
Microsoft's that's a good question I
don't know we we rely on certificate
templates which is a Microsoft isn't as
far as I understand but I am Not sure if
you if you want to catch me later I can
follow up and find out for you
yes the question is since all this
depends on hard ground turmeric and
since her various physical assault there
how much issues we can get from his
entire system that's a good question
responses to that rough time he might
resign from there is much smaller and
easier to protect users to secure the
attack surface is incomparably smaller
than anything else but the true a cities
at the end of the day it will have on
the movies and the system must do its
job to make sure that they are doing
proper testing proper security assurance
before releasing and often do they
should keep maintaining farmers in our
customers must install the updates as
soon as possible
agenda good businesses in 10 staff
windows update will keep you secure
automatically I think we have time for
maybe one or two more questions
the question is will it work on VMware
to require hyper-v I don't think so I
don't know I'm sure buyers are
hypervisor Microsoft typewriter
else thanks thanks for coming in today
and listen to us take care of thanks
very much