our time together today about talking
about the inspiration for this talk
be back so last year
LinkedIn Jeff Weiner halogen article and
title thirty people that I most enjoy
working with you can see the core
message distilled down and to avoid and
we want to work with people who are
dreamers and get people to its people
industry we have dreamed big thing we
are eternally securing their unsecured
and he would have been made thereunder
whore
feel they're getting colder around
security people on Twitter wrote general
things we do I'm pretty sure we know how
to how am i right
not going to a party for drinks in Syria
you can change your mind however were
not as effective as we could be I think
we need to work more on this get stuff
done bubble it's not about working
harder or even put in more hours than we
already do instead we need to evaluate
what we're doing with a more critical
eye and make sure we're as effective as
we could be so let's get to it I'm
Coruscant orkut LinkedIn director of
security responsible for our application
security programs incident response and
this is David sense Senior Technical
Program Manager he is our bloggers and
are one of our instant response folks on
the applications so while the talks were
giving today described some of the work
that we've done it linked and it's also
filled with our own opinions and biases
so it's going to end up being a mix of
details and case studies and sharing a
result that definitely belong to
LinkedIn but our opinions and
interpretations of the work are
definitely our own alright I think we've
jumped off the platform into the high
water portion of iraq we're not talking
about the plight of this current
security organization allied strategy
won't save you but tactical success
might just work will talk about how we
build our assessment for rounds and some
of those results
a bit of a sneak preview and the last
year LinkedIn's assessment team
performed 440 assessment and over 900
books and we'll get into all we did that
later
will look into a rapidly evolving
specially we like to call tactical
application and send response and it's
it's own unique hybrid of traditional
application security and traditional
information and value for us to do so
here's the thing about strategy is this
is a good entire ground from a security
check Cecil playbook where you to focus
on building some things in the
foundational side but at the end of the
day you want to be that executive
strategic see so and this approach does
not work for application security at my
work for things like us and so the
problem that we find here is that
traditional security programs focus on
strategic vision and stuff tactical
success application security it's one of
the most dynamic disciplines in the
field and ask her to approach takes time
and is less forgiving for rapid
iteration and it's not even a line with
your car parts and application
development and engineering undergo
frequent forays into outsourcing cloud
application and options and seemed to
introduce a new framework to secure
every year long-term strategies suffer
from a lack of agility and that is for
application security so
initiatives consumed budget and time for
the eventual promise of reward down the
line tack gorgeous return value
immediately and connect out so why would
we fought the strategy and the first
place because management strategy and
management psychology focuses on
planning and measurement to achieve
strategic goals the middle manager in
most organizations can survive for
longer executing against an outdated
irrelevant strategy as long as you keep
hearing those artificial milestones
won't survive long however if you commit
to execute in short-term tactical
in the process of killing her and some
minutes complexes application security
is causing people to steer diving and
here's another thing is that your
non-security pure love it when you talk
about strategy because it means two
things to them first strategy that
sounds like it's not my budget and so
the second security conversation wrapped
around the budget we're going to go
nowhere fast and he's not to the next
budget planning session and second but
the other thing that i think is I don't
have to do anything right now ensconced
on my and generally agree and that
brings me to the side of the point of
immediacy we need to do a better job
pushing the pace into our security and
our organization's strategy does not
include real time improvements and
assessment and response you can't figure
out how to add out today or tomorrow the
attackers as Wayne Gretzky's dad Walter
used to say skate to where the puck is
going not a word which means you have to
take the ice so enough pursuing a
strategic approach may not be the best
idea let's talk about what the technical
applications are dirty program is about
one thing that I thought that was
interesting and as as you build a strong
side of your program actually be
perceived as strategic light successful
execution rather than my road map so the
first thing to note about a nap tactical
program is this lightweight a narrative
and let me give you an example so let's
say that you need to do an APO I review
and you're getting on fire was a request
for this is overwhelming your existing
staff so what's on the ability to
experiment so the first generation of
your view may simply be just a catalog
that request three questions the three
most important questions and then do
some can't advise the next generation
you could actually add some conditional
around and reducing the designer of you
in the third generation you could add
automated scanning the idea is to build
a great
rather than try to make the perfect
solution right away and so what will
happen there is is that you want to have
a uniform interface into the process you
want people to know that they always can
go to you for this type of review but
what might happen in the back in my
actually change depending on what your
capability that given quarter so the
second is akin to monster really reduce
risk for each action taken so one
question I asked myself frequently
sometimes every day and also I asked my
staff enough times to the right up to
the point of annoyance is my work today
prevent it from happening in the future
let us know about something bad happened
that we didn't know about already are
produced on a clear line power the
stopping in the existing bad thing from
happening anymore and so you see here is
is when we take a look at those she set
of questions we look at every spring
plan that we have and if we don't feel
good about the Sprint plan answering
those questions we we do it because at
the end of the day that's what being
tactical is about you do the same for
your team every quarter we look and
document the results and answer those
questions and bubble those things up to
our management so they understand
exactly how are executing the next is
that we focus on operational excellence
and less on authorities have got to see
the inner workings a lot of security
programs over the years and I've done
the best want a consultancy and best
thing about these when they're working
well as a day drive operational
excellence and so what we do at LinkedIn
as we measure our assessment team on the
set of core Metrix so we look at the
types of assessments that we've
completed in the bugs and we filed and
how many times we were able to complete
an assessment for product
and then on the ecosystems we look at
and are bugs and how those bugs were
discovered and how the current status
and and how they impacted our members
and the dark or things that we look at
and measure because our operational
excellence to do a quick digression
about authority and by so terrible
security teams operate best when they
are a consultancy you and a girl and
they have a government commission that
the key kind of well concealed your back
if you drag that thing out too many
times you're going to people are going
to tune you out because the idea is that
if you're insulting you're actually
helping someone stole a particular need
now on the matter of this doesn't
necessarily mean that you need everyone
to agree with you all the time or only
perceived when you have a hundred
percent by an across the organization
the traditional advice about your
primary job as an empathic men Jersey
get buy-in from everyone else to a
consensus as opposed to a parent what's
going to happen is when you start to
execute tactically you're gonna find
people that will fit into one of three
camps is your supporters appreciate what
you do they are important to the
security mission and frankly they're the
people that you go to work every day for
you want to make them succeed and make
them build secure products and you have
a group of people who follow you and
those are the ones that rely on reliable
sustainable and predictable execution
whether be giving them an assessment
done or doing an answer or sports though
isn't if you do these things well people
will call you if you don't feel you can
execute them they're gonna go off the
rails the third is a group that will be
resistant to you no matter what you do
and the idea here is that you give them
no excuse it's no excuse to resist by
the fact that you continue to execute
and provide value by the analysis that
you're doing so remember how I talked
about those had not in my budget earlier
we need to get them to move and so one
of the first things I did when I joined
LinkedIn as I saw that we were about
significant gaps and component component
of our internal network security and so
what we did was we called a code yellow
and gave a small amount of work to each
team like system administration
administration I T help desk all these
different groups and a small little
chunks and rather than coming up with
big strategic plan then we would have to
wait to get by and for six months to one
year plan and so that's the example of
how you can do that by making people
move rather than wait so let's talk
about program so that you can see here
is a pie chart of breakdown of the work
that we did and so as you can see the
majority of them are penetration test
but we also spend quality time with a
product designs and third-party
applications hosted in the cloud for
both internal and product use all those
cloud assessments and I'd like to share
with you how he did that from a
technical perspective so first off it's
important to conceptualize assessment
activity as a fellow it starts with
intake moves execution and then ends
with a deliver all it can be as formal
as a certified audit process for an
informal and a two minute phone call
during intake you could be giving ad hoc
requests from colleagues are seeking
your guidance could be driven by process
driven checkpoints we call this external
demand the alternative of course is
self-generated intake where you're out
there and finding things to look at
we call that internal demand and it's
important to have those in your program
so the ideal intake process is one where
people willingly come to you for
assistance of their own volition I mean
something way is happening so strong
consultancy house a set of operating
principles and here's ours first is that
we should be easy to find and engage
should really feel like you're speaking
with an advisor who is always available
to give you guidance and we use our
office hours process as a as a way to do
that the second I would look into it
with the second we should not be too
demanding on their time and flexible on
documentation and preparation as long as
we have the information to determine
next steps we strive to be and all I
can't tell you how many times we've
actually help the teams build their own
data flow diagrams illogical dire around
to help build some of their
documentation must be clear
understandable and have a reasonable
likelihood of being executed if you give
people here in schemes in order to
secure their products are going to the
fourth is you must assist your customers
and giving solutions and then include
getting guidance from other parts
blasting you want
organization last thing you want to do
is have them play pinball where they
don't you then I gotta go and talk to
legal then they gotta go into a customer
support and they gotta go and talk to
someone in engineering that's going to
frustrate them through the entire
process and if you were the first person
they talk to the person they're going to
blame
so the idea is to bring all these people
together I can't say tell you how many
times we played matchmaker a pretty
different people together
talk about the security impacts the
organization is that we must be
passionate and working with us to not be
like drugs or punishment sometimes you
feel like you really want to come to lay
the hammer down it really is and current
counter to the tactical approach so one
of the secret weapons that we use to
consulting friendly approach and to
handle demand generation is the use of
office hours so that is available to our
entire product line engineering group
twice a week but can be scheduled on the
man and we have a signup sheet which is
the document of record that's where we
start in the office hours you meet with
our house security team as well as our
trust and safety team and product legal
all in one place and so it starts with a
brief presentation that you give us a
product and then will document
requirements as we go
will give them product requirements as
well as for security anti abuse and
legal
all right there and then we'll also do
the scope of an assessment just like if
I was a consulting sales person and I
would go into identified the threat
model and what type of assessment I want
to perform do I want to do a designer of
you do I wanna do a code review do I
want to a penthouse and so when they
leave those office hours they have a set
of requirements and a set up next steps
of what they need to get from our
program so this is an entry level 20 so
we did and we do on every each month we
do 230 product consultations 25 general
office hours I'm or speed around and
that doesn't even count and 400
assessment number that we have in fact
there's no way we deal execute that
number of assessment and less we have
this type of office hour consultation
the other thing is that they want to
consider building a service catalog you
can see here what we currently have on
LinkedIn
each service should have a dog
documented and to find methodology worth
of things to look for in your testing
team
generally follow it and publishes the
team knows what theyre Venus us but we
also want to do some scope and we want
to figure out what the game overs are
poor that give an assessment and
documentos as part of a test plan and
then finally the idea is is is to
determine what your methodology you can
keep and which party controls way in
order to get that number assessments
done so one of the things that happens
when you get some support it is that
they all say things like our products
need to be reviewed before launch when I
first heard this my marching orders are
clear and I was happy to have such
strong executive support while I'm still
in tremendous gratitude for the support
that I have every day I quickly realized
that this stuff in the policy discussion
here actually left me with more
questions than answers
what does it mean to be reviewed and was
like incremental improvements that
happen every day ends and another one
begins and how do you know when you're
done so what we did was as we started to
break these questions down and so we
used office hours at the entry point and
then we had to have the latitude to
determine what types of review were
necessary so we think a lot about member
privacy and expectations first and so
and then from there we would have seen
how the application can be abused then
we go on to think about how the product
can be internally secure and then
finally we rely on our expertise to do
that custom school and then the answer
the question below even mean or what is
it more important when we can do a lot
of a/b testing slow ramps economy and
thence to small percentages
customers review too early the chances
of you having good powered by the time
the product makes it to a larger
population as slim without significant
repeated over and we review too late you
may have a vulnerability in production
impacts only some members is important
to do a couple things here to make
doubly sure no Tripoli sure that when
you have a B testing of them in a
trampoline capability that it can be
overridden and controlled by an attacker
second is defined features the most
meaningful from a security perspective
in our case anything that touches
confidential financial member data so we
talk about them and talk about internal
demand for a little bit so you want to
be part of the product launch 2008
LinkedIn we have a product review
process and we sit there and monitor
what's going on in those and then
determine where it's best to insert
ourselves into this weekend starts with
the office hours but all also end up
being things like how we're doing
ramps for products and looking at the
road maps there to determine how best to
do the reviews but the other thing you
want to try to do you want to look for
opportunities to contribute security
guidance outside of testing and code
review to do white papers on how the
product to secure and reducing
third-party assessments or doing abuse
detection and monitoring these
definitions
the other thing we do is we look for
changes and staging and production we
actually monitor how people are using
the site show up we take a look and and
figure out how best to those
applications and cialis through our
price and then the other major thing you
want to do is befriend the gatekeepers
these are the people who are registering
your domains the people who are
maintained DNS and those that are
responsible for fun in traffic because
when a new endpoint shows up
you don't want to be surprised so there
are some people that could trap your
tactical maneuvers as you increasing
number of mandated or get more
interesting things to reviews these are
projects or products you need to go
through you quickly realize that will
result in little value to me very quick
to identify these early in the final
usually through office hours and quickly
and ruthlessly out of us otherwise
you're gonna get caught in your own
here's your assessment team will be
unmotivated there are questions will be
annoyed and you simply won't be
delivering as much value as you think
you could the other question we get is
about standards so clear standards about
how to deal with common security issues
and what to avoid will definitely help
along with sharing your application
specific test plans but don't allow cell
certification is a good idea instead to
keep an open book on how people will be
assessed tree in the assessment like
some type of magical black box create
unnecessary uncertainty and anxiety the
project team testing methodology and/or
pre-release checklist for webinar iOS
and Android applications all document
engineering we point the team to these
pages as part of the engagement process
there was a bit of a car via air about
the tackle susman approach and that is
in strong consistency your goals
exclusive you make your client which is
the product you are working with
internal security TV you have to balance
other things the satisfaction of courses
of the team they're working with but
there's also the overarching company's
governance and security and the
president same behavior that you execute
and of course and most importantly as
customer remember safety so if we take a
look at the case on LinkedIn and roll
where we had some challenges with that
product we actually did everything right
from a technical application security
perspective
we worked very hard to secure this
product tactical tell us so we performed
a client with a product team was happy
well as happy as a heavy security
presence like project we as a scary team
failed to identify the impact of the
design and the broader perspective of
the product and how the products
approach could be perceived as less than
untrustworthy right show that response
so there are spots so the effectiveness
and reputation with security
organization is most frequently judged
by how they respond to incidents and
security bugs if you do things well
people will rarely see your assessment
program and how it works
however the spotlight critical bug being
exposed into production
gather as many interested parties
LinkedIn we handled 77 critical
vulnerabilities in the last year twenty
one of them were extremely discovered or
reported to us thirteen of those were
from our private look around and fifty
six of them were discovered internally
either by our own team or by other
engineers know how I talk about that
generating your internal demand your
tactical approach to actually encourage
exploration just staying in a given 1900
pretty aggressive what constitutes a
critical bugs and in almost every case
these books were handled and close
before any member data impacted in any
way I will start with a case study
David
loud so before we get into the fun stuff
and disclose a few critical that we have
seen recently reports coming from the
outside world like many companies we
receive reports from external security
researchers are fairly regular basis
multiple reports coming to us through
our security alias security at
linkedin.com however they also come to
us through social media customer service
tickets and of course executive
escalations now for some reason people
in the community sometimes like to write
to our executives thinking they'll get
some sort of special attention however
doesn't always work out the way they had
hoped for and usually end up talking
with me to handle the incoming reports
we have implemented an on-call system
for our assessment team that are penned
testers and is a one-week rotation the
main mission for this individual on call
is to quickly triage any incoming buck
during the normal business day within
four hours if it is a time such as
nights or weekends we do a lot of
investors to sleep so we just es la
accordingly out to eight hours
note that after hours only following up
on critical this will help reduce the
on-call burnout while some may question
having an experienced pen tester triage
incoming bugs we viewed here is a
necessity having someone who has the
experience with the products
architectures and existing issues can
quickly triage any incoming bug that
comes in
regardless in addition it's also very
important that we respond to the
researchers in a very short period of
time even if just a simple
acknowledgment that we have received the
report and are starting to investigate
again we want to do this as a human this
is not an automated response
the on call is responsible for triaging
the incoming bug establish a working
proof of concept only appropriate
tickets and of course responding back to
the researcher again we want to respond
to the researcher that very short period
of time and like I said it's again just
an acknowledgement that we're working on
it and are investigating if it is
determined to be a critical and we'll go
through what determines or what makes a
critical need then responsibility ship
store ecosystem team which are then take
over responsibility for coordinating
response and we'll talk more about the
responsibilities here shortly so now the
fun stuff but she will realize critical
now this report came to us from the
external world and what this show runs
you could change any profile picture for
any member across all pretty scary and
so let's treat this one last note is the
original reporter to us was not actually
the original finder of this and we found
the original as a YouTube video already
online in spreading wild place so much
demonstrate the vulnerability here so
first one to pick a profile of a
colleague of mine Tony tremor he's in
the back here the rain was I could go
ahead and faces profile of you just talk
show after a difficult to do not want to
face that send message we that we come
up with some blocker report we didn't go
click over to the next one which is
Marcus inappropriately is ready for the
fun technical stuff now
great we click the Done button that was
it his
is now me now argue this is a much
improved proper him it's much more
handsome I bet his profile views just
went skyrocketing have a bit more fun
with this and play with him I can do the
same steps to change my profile picture
and I change into Tony the Tiger's
across all just like that
pretty scary right now know my lawyer
lawyers and PR one me to emphasize this
this is now fixed so please don't go
clicking through this like thinking your
friends are gonna change profile picture
to something which I can imagine it
would do so this report came to us after
hours and as discussed earlier we tried
triage bugs as soon as they come it was
able triage this blog and respond to the
researcher in about an hour again this
is not an automated response this is our
on-call pen tester confirming that there
is a bug and that we are working towards
an immediate checks now the next
question I usually get from people is
David what makes this a critical why do
I have to work right now now in this
case it's pretty straightforward if I'm
able to change anybody's profile picture
across all of the platform pretty
straightforward and doesn't require much
arguments what we found those works
really well for all the other times that
we have to have this discussion is a
clearly defined bug classification table
and this bug classification table has a
list of blogs the related severity
critical high medium low and established
SLA for resolution this gives clear
guidance to our testers who are triaging
the incoming bugs and makes it easy for
them to diagnose them but also gives
clear guidance to the teams that we are
working with and have to fix these
things after triaging which we handle
the focus immediately ships to alerting
the specific team and get them working
towards effects now we're more than
happy to help them identify with the
root cause is and review their fix
however we put the responsibility on to
them to design the fixed and pushed to
production now the great thing about
being on my company like us as we have
the ability to push code to production
very quickly usually within a few hours
of identifying an issue
however this isn't fast enough sometimes
when you find a YouTube video already
online and people changing profile
pictures you have to implement a stopgap
solution so in this case we did we had
to implement an upstream filter which
broke member functionality but remove
the vulnerability from our site
this was definitely not the best member
experience however it was a necessity to
protect the site in the members and
we'll talk more about how these upstream
filters and other stop-gap solutions can
be use so within next hour to go after
working with the right teams and the
on-call pen tester we are able to push
optics to production and closed at the
bug and restore member functionality now
as many of you know the incident isn't
over yet this is my profile but that's
definitely not me
released I can hope you can tell that's
not me up there my picture that evening
as we work to this incident problem
change at least a dozen times as my oh
so funny colleagues change it to animals
and other objects throughout the evening
as they tested out this new feature is
pretty funny I got my profile views one
of my mom called me to issues like I
noticed your profile picture change you
look different
alright so does seem like the next
logical step your right but obviously we
have to determine the scope first how
many members have been affected how long
has this been in production and has
anyone been abusing the flaw other than
my own so funny colleagues wait until
the fix is in production you're gonna
inevitably delay closing out the
incident until much later in the night
without fail
most of what you wanna answer is buried
deep in some log files and need someone
specific to analyze it
the application response team needs
access to this member data log data
state changes and other valuable
application information these systems
will be a combination if you're lucky I
do HDFS elasticsearch and other
structured query identities as a result
your tactical response team needs to be
able to parse through large amounts of
data very quickly now when an engine
kicks off one of my first calls the
store security data science team
we're lucky enough to have a dedicated
data science team who can help me answer
these questions however this is not
necessary and you don't have to
establish this in your org can be done
with members of your own team with
access to this information
ideally though this data is being
shipped it through in parallel to the
fix being built
you don't want to wait until the end
this one hour and speed things up but I
guarantee management lawyers
NPR's are gonna start asking you
questions and you're not going to have
the answers
better start looking right away now like
the spare tire on your car though if the
first time you check it is when you're
on the side of the road on a dark and
stormy night I guarantee you you will
find it flattering missing don't wait
until you're in the midst of an incident
to find out that you don't have proper
logs or that the IP address being
captured is that of your own CD and it
happened
alright checkin out check him ahead of
time it's worth it so let's take a look
at another case study here this report
came to us via our private bug bounty
program which will discuss in a moment
interest in going up this person had
committed after only being the program
for a short period of time what this
person discovered was that they could
upload sorry this was to delete my bad
they could delete any slight chair or
any YouTube video from any SlideShare
presentation for any member across the
entire platform pretty scary so
following standard procedures of
triaging above on-call pen tester
started looking at this upon further
investigation and following the path
that the researcher the external
researcher had laid out we also found
that videos could be added now this is
another great reason have a season pen
tester here if we'd only focused on the
initial report of the deletion we might
have missed this bug completely this is
a pretty straightforward critical
imagine all of our SlideShare
presentations in bed with an NSFW video
I imagine our users would be to policed
so during the last case study we focused
on remediation cleanup in communication
with the researcher and
that's pretty much it so now pieces we
didn't cover were communication
processes internally why we chose to
implement that both classification table
and some stop-gap solutions so any
reason will engineer designer paint
tester understands the impact of
uploading or deleting YouTube videos
from anybody SlideShare pretty easy to
see how this is a critical and doesn't
require much discussion however we
ensure security professionals often find
ourselves trying to convince someone
else an organization why something is
important needs to be fixed now and now
usually leads to them labeling us things
like argumentative or my favorite just a
jerk and it's true that label all of
those now is it because I can share a
moment ago we're trying to convince
someone else within our own organization
why something has to be fixed now and
that discussion typically devolves into
the other person arguing things like
impact more mobility accessibility and
my absolute favorite it existed like
this for years why do I have to fix it
now
ok why can't I get to next next month
next year next quarter right when you
have to fix it now and constantly having
these discussions and debates in the
midst of an incident especially if it's
two o'clock in the morning will turn you
into a curmudgeon it will turn you into
that juror I guarantee it
we found that helps really well the curb
these conversations is a well-defined
bug classification table which I
mentioned just a minute ago this is
implementing the clear and concise
easy-to-understand bug severity table
negates these conversations a store
cross-site scripting introduction to
your members is a critical and requires
an all hands on deck approach to fix it
right now and I said not now and get it
right there might not so the industry
would argue though that we should be
using a CVSS approach here however as
mentioned we found that this release to
our own engineers and developers arguing
and trying to game the system to lower
their score so they can go back to bed
and in all honesty I can't blame them I
wanna go back to bed to so many teams
can do the technical work and many of us
are graded solving technical
vulnerability and it's great we can
smash vulnerabilities however what
separates a great incident ones that are
run smoothly versus those are run poorly
in the eyes of the outsider to you or
security or is communication
one of the key roles that are ecosystem
team place is coordination and
communication during any incident
there's gonna be many individuals if not
teams involved and everyone needs to be
aware of what's going on in a
centralized person to gather this
information and spread that knowledge
becomes imperative ecosystem team as air
traffic controllers asking for updates
and disturbing that information the
communication doesn't stop at just the
teams working on the issue this has to
flow up to your management and to your
lawyers and PR alright and none of those
teams should learn about the incident
through back channels or word of mouth I
guarantee you it will make them question
what you as a security professional are
doing and how you're running the
incident all you need to do is give them
a brief summary of where the years she
currently stance what your plan
remediation is next step and next time
you're going to be given an update we
believe so much in this methodology that
for every one of those 77 more critical
that began last year one of these
communications went out so here's a
quick example as you can see an example
here we have a deadline given a quick
executive summary fall by more in-depth
explanation and a link to the ticket and
disclosure and pulled know what that
this disclosure and bold it's over here
on the other side is on the bottom of
every single email that I sent out the
two critical really all I started
sending out these communications at the
request of Management I was escalated on
and also read out by colleagues saying
that I was writing them out or title
team lean on them
ok idea here is not to rattle your
colleagues from making a mistake the
idea is to inform all involved parties
adding this communication to the bottom
of the email as well as making sure I
pre briefed the teams and what the
process was
escalations and complaints about me well
most of the complaints about me away so
the other point here is not the tone of
his email again it's a very positive
email I even have a think you like here
the ideas a lot of your college price
probably are not super motivated to be
working late nights weekends or drop all
the other projects to work on your
critical incident adding this positive
spin will help keep keep the team morale
high no one last more one last thing
before we move on with the YouTube issue
we were able to fix it within a couple
hours only one of these went out pretty
straight forward now
other incidents that many of you might
encounter the incident could last hours
for could last days
management PR or lawyer should never be
reaching out to you for aspirin update
you waited too long at that point the
idea here is you want to beat them to
the punch you need to make sure they go
out on a regular basis if you don't have
someone like an ecosystem team or
someone like me to do it that's ok to
you just need to set the expectation my
personal model here when I run these
incidents is beat them to the punch down
both cases we follow a standard playbook
which gave us a framework it is not a
100 page document that no one ever read
your updates the idea here is that the
PlayBook that's practical predictable
and consistent team to have been
assigned a critical call from us and
know what to expect that this comes with
time and exposure but also comes with
transparency we believe so much in this
methodology that we're releasing public
version do this after our talk will
provide a link you want to go back and
took one second collaboration
unfortunate immediate all hands on deck
approach to critical so there is a
reality that certain things aren't going
to change immediately
products cannot always be redesigned a
framework redone or new functionality
built overnight while you can't allow
the long-term fix discussions to happen
and I guarantee you'd that's where the
team wanna go all 11 of this framework
in three months that's gonna fix this
and didn't know we need to focus on
fixing the vulnerability now we have
found that many times we can implement a
block an additional control or break
functionality in
order to reduce the severity of the
threat know that I'm not saying we're
closing out the threat completely we are
reducing the threat surface by
implementing an additional control
remember though uses security
professional or the consultant and need
to come ready to talk to these teams
offer up some of these countermeasures
that they might not be aware of all
right now the fun stuff and now there's
a lot of people probably interested in
this bug bounty programs so I think we
can all agree why bug bounty programs
have been implemented across the
industry we want to receive quality
reports establish good relationship with
the security community stay out of the
media of course and you could use of
resources of money and contrary these
programs have fostered an influx of bad
reports from researchers simply
attempting to gain abounding we've seen
the signal-to-noise ratio of the public
but bounty programs continue to degrade
requiring companies to hire dedicated
resources engage consultancies and used
to sift through all the junk and ordered
find actionable reports before it
launched into the specifics about how we
built our program I want to share
another case study here which I believe
will help set the tone going back the
other year to the intro product which
Corey discussed it was getting a fair
amount of negative attention a blog post
surfaced showing how our internal
product could potentially be used to
social engineer picked up the researcher
had not reached out to us or had not
attempted to contact us in any way but
had just written a blog post now many
companies at this point I'm which starts
licking their large legal or PR arms and
tried to smash the vulnerability smash
the author or the block we decided to
take a different approach year we
decided to reach out to the author and
bite him to check unsurprisingly he was
more than willing to work with us and
share what he had found using the same
methodology as we discussed earlier in
the talk we were able to close out that
vulnerability that same day as a result
his follow post the next day what about
how greatly didn't was and how great it
was to work with our security team I'm
sure this case study with you guys for a
few reasons the first is collaboration
this is not and should not be an
adversarial relationship the researcher
was willing to work with us and
collaborate the change in attitude on
both sides of that fence changes he
outcome amenable party's win the second
reason I shared this does availability
due to the fact that we were not dealing
with hundreds or thousands of reports
they were coming in we had the
availability to reach out and personally
talked with this member and learn what
they had found this personal touch
communication and understanding with the
researcher truly born changes the
outcome we believe that every researcher
should be treated right regardless if
there's a bug bounty program in place or
not this is the spirit of how bug bounty
program should be run and how we run our
program so how did we get to our program
well before we launched we received a
number of emails to our security alias
most of which were on actionable and not
meaningful however a small group of
people emerged who always provided
excellent write-ups there were
meaningful and well thought out and a
pleasure to work with so we thought geez
we like working with these people
they're providing excellent bugs that
were willing to work with us in a
collaborative fashion why not get them
into a program that rewards them for
doing their research moving for and this
is the spirit of how be regional bug
bounty program started and I believe
this is how we bring it back to its
original intent the advantage of making
a private invitation only allows us to
having more meaningful relationship with
the researchers by eliminating the
distractions a poorly researched or
relevant reports providing response
analysis to the researchers on their
reports and actually fixing the bugs
takes considerable resources if you want
to do this right so we did in October
2014 we formalize the partnership with
the creation of LinkedIn's private bug
bounty program the participants in our
program have submitted over 65 bugs of
which we've closed each one of those in
too many to fix the participants have
given us great feedback about the
program and in return for all their hard
work we paid over $65,000 and counties
we've had a significant reduction
in the authorization related issues in a
recruit product thanks to the
researchers we've also been using the
researchers to identify bugs in order
code that didn't go through the same
level security diligence that Corey
discussed earlier we've been able to get
out bonuses in certain types of awards
that show creativity or persistence due
to the availability to reduce noise
another advantage here is we're not need
to deal with the gamesmanship present in
many public bug bounty programs where
you end up paying out for about me for
something that's not meaningful yet
still somehow within your rules might
miss that one so the thing is our
researchers tend not to go down this
path they're usually interested in much
more meaningful or impactful budget
actually mean something to the
organization into our members the
researchers have the ability to invest
time into their research the problem
with the bounty programs in the public's
sense is your recent against the clock
most likely there's another researcher
out there working on the same bugs you
why do you want to spend time
investigating doing a thorough analysis
if someone else is gonna beat you to the
punch and claimed the balcony it doesn't
work what you need to do is simply take
a screenshot make a submission with a
really cool sounding are scary title k
public bug bounty programs don't
incentivizes in-depth are thoughtful
analysis the incentive ice quickly
poorly written submissions in contrast
our program has seen an influx of great
thoroughly done investigations are right
after my researchers they know the
competition is limited and most likely
if they invested time into research and
finding the bug there will be a reward
so we've spoken about our bug bounty
program is different from the others in
its advantages so let's talk about the
impact here for a second I can spot a
free shows here and tell you that we
have an awesome signal-to-noise ratio of
723 and that the industry averages
training towards one in 2000 in less
you're probably involved in a program or
you're running one or you're looking at
running one I probably just alikum
spouting off numbers here and playing a
bit too much of inside baseball
so very simply put if you have a 120
ratio this means for everyone good bug
you get you get twenty back reports
pretty simple but companies don't
realize though is the impact this will
have on their organization every one of
those reports regardless if it's good or
bad
has to be triaged because what if it is
a critical bug and you simply put in the
pileup 0 will follow up on it later I
guarantee you the researcher is more
than happy to take it to the media and
the headline will read company nor
security researchers zeroed a imposing
sad for all it will happen so ever
report and we can agree has to be
triaged and communication sent back to
the researcher this can easily take an
average of one hour per report without
doing any math it's easy to see how your
workload significantly increases if you
don't have the proper processes for
handling reports pre-made templates for
responses ticketing systems agreements
with your engineering endeavor teens on
a salacious for fixing these things this
can grow out of control very quickly
the industry is experiencing a costly
degrading signal noise ratio as we
continue to operate these programs
check out the latest research from both
hacker 1 I'm proud they support this the
days of launching a public bug bounty
program just because everyone else is
doing it is over
think about what your mother said if
your friends jump off the bridge would
you this is a complex endeavor you must
prepare for our suggestion here is to
start small with a group of researchers
or people you trust at the end of the
day what really matters is protecting
our members employees and products we
know how we can assemble an amazing team
that will help mitigate the threat and
reduce it will always need help from the
outside our strategy is not to throw a
bug bounty programs completely is to
better connect with the researchers who
will help us achieve that goal of
securing our data thank you
and if you're interested in the slides
updated slides are at the URL below it
so the LinkedIn get stuff done shortener
reports and that ratio increased sounds
wonderful but if you've got a community
and that's the only place you're
listening for reports for what's to stop
someone who's poking around on LinkedIn
who has no idea about how your body
program works from approaching you with
a real dog and you be able to react as
you increase the chances of ignoring
people on the outside now so we still
responding to reports their treat them
just as we would if they were in the
program
exactly so we've actually people are
processed into the program for its
almost like a two tier system
high school reform the first part of the
talk I was really interested in the
service catalog and the frameworks
methodologies are developing I can see
great applications of sharing these kind
of events on way to join organizations
open source elaborate on this i think
there's a set of methodology is or
should be sure the industry's so that we
can understand what the different types
of attacks could be like him afterwards
streetcars and talk about that
opportunity
think he just say you can't she played
he said you know that over to the slides
and then later on it's accurate on
linkedin.com will be publishing the
PlayBook this week but what is the size
and composition of your security team so
we have approximately 20 people in this
in this part of our security team
focuses on the program so we talked
about today and can you talk a little
bit about the skillset areas obviously
you have been testers what other sorts
of skill sets do you try to employ
observed penetration testers are acts
controls we also have a program enters
off like David execute some of the
technical aspects of over and we also
how to respond more tourism information
security engineers deal with things like
how we secure our production networks
and operations and we also have incident
responders and people with experience
and and forensics and incident response
and security monitor and developers do
you support I'm not sure sure we have
that number gets roughly not sure I have
it
career yes here do you get a lot of
acquisitions and how do you feel as the
new acquisitions into the pool so one of
the things that we try to do right off
the bat is essentially officer offer or
service catalog to that position so we
only 10 some regard we treat them like a
new client those poor organization so
immediately though they get all the
incident response to offer free trade
they get all you know it is a security
we take over the security out we handle
all that from that side so right away we
get to know them up close and personal
in a position to LinkedIn there's a lot
more attention I get paid to them and
then on the assessment side what we do
is that service catalog start looking at
points of generation and and more from
there ok we are going to be with me
right outside if you have questions