hello thank you everybody for coming to
our session on Monday bodies and this is
my college then you know bianco and
we're going to talk about our Open
Source project called the USB armory so
we have a company which is going to be
presented a few times a blackout first
our first thought was just to give you a
little background about what do we do
about injecting traffic navigation
messages into cars then we done in 2009
and talk about anything keystrokes off
from power outlets in 2011 presented a
talk about credit cards and two years
ago we didn't talk about package impact
fees just to show you that were heavily
involved not only software security but
also hardware security we like to tackle
you know kind of peculiar topics
concerning and every two years we tried
to do a talk in a research and easier we
decided to build something from a change
you know taking things apart and this is
and then the idea for the USB Memory
Project came out so what does the USB
armory so the USB armory is an open
source are compact device which
basically implements a secure computer
that you can carry around it was
designed for personal security
applications and the first idea . we we
had the reason why we had the idea of
building such as device is that we
wanted something that we can carry her
only does in our pockets that could be
as much trusted as we could possibly
make it and he would allows us to have
included storage you know there are a
lot of USB flash drives the day
claim they provide military grade
encryption or whatever certified
encryption and you have no idea about
what's going on in the hardware of the
device or in the firmware
and encryption which is actually
implemented in this class of devices has
been known to to have very poor quality
and and you know implementations that
are not secure at all so our our first
idea was to have first of all and has
mass storage so something where if I
would just copy a file on on a device he
would be you know option on the scan may
be for you know my world or whatever but
encrypted with something that we know
whether it's you know GBG or or the
means and then put on on on storage in a
way to control it so we fought of advice
I would just emulate a mass storage
which is the protocol that is normally
use for your USB drives but that would
allow us to be in control of the
encryption process that's going on and
we want to do encryption process to
happen on the device itself that was one
of our goals and then we fought you know
but if we have something which she's not
single purpose but as a little more
horsepower and that can do that I
execute more custom code then we can
also have something that rather than
exposing a mass storage device we could
just expose out whatever web application
that we want and have a convenient
interface with just uploading files and
then downloading them again and then
maybe sharing them in a secure way that
was that was the old west something that
we can easily use for file encryption
and secure file sharing and you know
quickly D requirements for such a device
went from having some dedicated single
purpose hardware to try and have
something which is a little more generic
an which became 22 to get the shape of
you know of a stunned are open source
computer in in such a time for doctor
and then we fought you know if we have
these custom functionality it and we all
kind of cool features such as you know
we can have a failsafe actions where if
I do a specific action then we have data
self-destruction for instance so if a
type of specific cost or if I copy a
certain files so if I did not do a
certain action and I'm supposed to do
then everything gets wired door locked
so things done right now we will propose
USB devices meant for security secure
storage of files are are some key
features that are not dare not possible
to do and then we fought but we have a
standard computer on such a comfort
factor than we do other things we could
use a proxy I go to computer which I
don't trust particularly I can logging
into my device we'd throw a password and
then I can ssh out with my keys which
are stored on the device and then to my
servers or or whatever that's one
application we can have a password
manager if we have a device which I can
easily connect and can expose a web
applications that I can control then you
can have all kind of a pastor manager or
authentication token of you know
whatever kind you want to and also one
of the other interesting things dots was
a photo of while developing bees we can
also have the USB device we have
something which is actually a full
active computer and no longer a passive
device we could have the USB device
authentication to host so you can have
it so that when you plug your device on
a computer device itself will try to
probe your host and understand if it's
true or not and then take whatever
action depending on how you configure
device and so and also other
applications you know you can have a
tour router on its network computer
connected in such a small form factor
you can have a Bitcoin wallet and GPS
and so on so all of these ideas start
you know no we knew once we fought to
have a generic computer in such a
compact USB device and so right from the
beginning we set a few design goals so
it must be a USB power of course so not
requiring external power supply because
that will be cranky and inconvenient
must be very small amass
must be a legal be a future-proof so
have a CPU and a generous amount of rum
we were clogged with embedded systems on
a daily basis out of breaking them or
analyzing them and most environments or
are are very for you know cost-saving
are very constrained resources that they
give to you and this of course if you
are developing one single purpose task
for these devices is fine it's it's good
engineering but it was something which
is ordinary that we want to propose a
blast from other people that we wanted
to be you know fast and and and you know
good specifications we must have secure
boot of course we must be able to boot
code that he signed with your keys not
our keys as manufacturer of course so
I'm not the kind of secure boot that you
have on your laptop where you can also
reset it if you want but something that
can permanently to use signing keys and
then only your coat off of a specific
device must provide under convene
including DVD over USB and very
important the developing an execution
environment by Smith familiar we didn't
want to how really customize and and and
and compact Linux distributions or
development environment he must be easy
to develop this device ended as I must
be open a security device with the goal
of handling very sensitive data on the
hardware and of course the software must
be as open as you can get so when
developing heart were the first and most
important phase is selecting the right
components for developing hardware and
the complaining that we selected that
for the first version of this device is
the Freescale I am X 53 it's an ARM
Cortex a eight which can be closed
between 800 and on 14 majors in one
point so really fast for a USB device if
you think of it all of this size I mean
we're talking about something which is
very very tiny almost all data sheets
Emanuel Republic and does not require
force features such as secure boot
sourcing that we really care about for
security reasons
the data sheets are okay or not you know
when you when you look at that she's
four components there is always some
quirks and and some issues in
comprehending them but I would say okay
far better than other vendors that was
eased the development process and we
also have a good implementation of armed
trust me on this device and secured with
secure storage and secure room for
cryptographic purposes is a detail power
consumption guide available which was
very important for us to ensure that the
device can be power from a USB port and
is actually need support for Android
previously for DISA professor so that
met our goal of providing a familiar
development environment and is good
soccer production support guarantee you
don't want to commit to a design and
then Freescale's how's your sorry apart
is not available anymore because that's
sucks that's also an important part of
the development process the system W was
as a lot of features that we are not
using because we are making a USB device
were not connecting into display GPS to
say that these can so on so it's a very
complex process during week power only
the things that we need so concerning
trust soon so you might have heard and
what Trustin proviso trust is
instruction set support for certain
armed force extras which allows you to
have execution domain separation between
what is called to be the non-secure
world and the secure ward in one of the
eight long-term ideas for DS platform to
leverage on these kind of over feature
for providing more separation between do
you ask the runs on the device and the
more sensitive coat that maybe handle
cryptographic keys and and so on and the
idea is that you have your own user mode
applications and application so your
Linux environment running in non-secure
roared and then whatever you want to do
some operations which somehow must be
executed on a more privileged context
you can ask to switch to monitor mode
and then the code which is in the secure
domain gets executed in these codes as
its own use or modification its own
privilege
and more importantly it can also have
its own device driver for a specific
hardware subcomponents off the demise
Indies hardware subcomponents can meet
only assigned to secure domain so for
instance you can decide to assign the
micros the controller only to the secure
domain and the non-secure domain would
never know of the existence of the
microSD controller so by hard work it is
physically the x-axis it's physically
blocked an insult by defining an API
between the non secure and unsecure word
you can you can have a separation which
allows to expose the median serve face
to the non-secure warning and control
exactly what you're doing a lot of the
applications is for instance that you
might want to handle encryption and
decryption often microSD card completely
secure domain and a secure domain holds
your passphrase which you do time for
instance and that's holding this jury
convicts so a non-secure domain if its
compromise for whatever reason cannot
physically goal in memory and see the
past phrase that helped me to this
occurred to me because the context the
execution context and memory are
completely separated and at the same
time to non secure the main cannot
access the micro sdcard directly so this
is just one example it is also one one
of the reasons of why we have chosen
this specific system-on-a-chip because
we know good support for tyson and the
harbor to can be a sign depending on the
specific system-on-a-chip you might be
able to have a different kind of
granularity in what you can assigned to
either to domains and we do specific
system-on-a-chip it's very flexible you
can find the USB controller board with
the LED for instance GPA also on the
board we have one led that we can decide
to assign to secure domain so easy led
Eastern on you know by hard work that in
dot moment to secure code is being
executed because the non-secure code has
no hardware means to access and turn on
dots
led and if the non-secure domain tries
to access device that is not supposed to
you can have an exception which then can
be dropped so the idea is to have the
reach all access into the non-secure
domains such as Linux and then more
compact more tiny maybe a microkernel or
directly arm assembly code is running
into the secure or handling a very
specific corporation that you might want
to confine to a different execution
context so their hardware failure is our
official mascot because we think it's
cool and matches the color of the board
very well so the hardware is completely
open source on the stock is completely
open source and this is the final
version of the device also after to talk
if you wanna come in seed we we have two
samples here that you can come and take
a look so that you have an idea of the
dimensions off the device define a
specification so we put the IMAX 53 on
it on its USB horsepower
power budget he's absolutely fine it's
very tiny we have a five min break up
header and where we can break our GPAs
and serial console for debugging
capabilities or for other purposes like
there are people adding buttons on the
pin header which is here so they can and
will aid kind of you be key style
press the button and menu trigger
specific action we have the LED which we
can trigger on assigned to trust them
secure domain if we want to offer a
secure moment it detection so that you
make sure that the normal worry is not
fishing for your password and we have
excellent native support so now we have
two GB on Archlinux we have Colleen
works we had the arch assault charges
for Argentina's which provide also
penetration testing tools which can be
easily installed on it just like you do
on a Raspberry Pi or are devices also
good for penetration testing we could do
USB device simulation so we emulate CDC
your friend and a thief also just shows
up as a server which you can connect to
weaken and storage keyboard and so on so
we also use it for low-level penetration
testing of the USB devices because with
the Linux USB gadget framework we can
control and emulate everything which is
exposed on the USB site so it's also
good for for those kind of offensive
capabilities it it's probably it you can
consider it he says as the perfect me
know implementing bags will be here if
you want because this device can be
whatever you want any active you can run
your firmware and as soon as it's
plugged in you can execute you know
whatever you like and is completely open
hardware and now interesting thing that
we realized after developing the
hardware is that not only we can run in
the vice moment which is our default
mode of operation but we can also run in
DOS mode so you see here on the USB arm
reattached to so this was one of the
first iterations now we have an adapter
for that but we can plug it directly to
a keyboard and mouse and USB display but
just by just 13 the roll off the USB
device from device becomes host and you
see it here so here we use my mo
DisplayLink USB monitor browsing a
completely run the page on the internet
for your benefit so and you you have a
USB power here on the right so the hob
provides power to the armory itself and
then the army itself sees the hob and
all that you any USB device which is
basically supported by Linux can be
attached to it so now we made
adapter for this purpose which basically
what did I Z bridges from female to
female and then you can ceding power
from a micro USB plug so in this case we
provide power we provide wifi usb wifi
dongle and here you have an access point
where you can rent or or or whatever you
want and of course you've got such as
USB powered hub you can feed the power
back in and then you can attach more
than one device so it becomes you know I
completely standalone our computer if
you want to end this is because the USB
controller allows as a great freedom in
considering it so even if we drive the
USB I D pinned to the ground because we
didn't think we could all we could use
the device we can override that by
writing to certain registers and we can
just ask that the plot to be in host
mode so we just need to change the
gender of the connection and then you
just have a standard USB Host like so
what were the challenges in in
developing these kind of hardware so
first of all it is not some Harvard you
can easily prototype on your own and
soldiering on your own because there are
two components which have up BGA form
factor which is called the ball grid
array so this is this the
system-on-a-chip been down below the
ddr2 RAM modules you have 529 beautiful
tiny balls that are soldered to the
board and this is very difficult to do
by hand so this is one of the challenges
and we tried to be smart into developing
this kind of bored and we said let's
make a breakout board where we had a
very expensive
Dr we can clamp the system-on-a-chip we
don't actually need so we don't risk
losing the board and the
system-on-a-chip every time and then we
break out every single connection for
debugging purposes so this board works
fine it's great for accessing all the
balls without risking kerosene
soldiering and so on so you just screw
everything with a precision Torx
screwdriver and he works however the
issue why's that
enabling the power components the
tolerances were so high that hadn't sold
during the power regulator is we you
know it wasn't it was insufficient for
having a stable power supply to the
device which meant that we had to create
a PCB for to power components but if we
create a PCB power components that we
might as well at the sock and the song
then we might as well go ahead
with the first prototype so one of the
lessons learned and he's so the Darth
Vader there it sits myself and and the
idea which is that is our colleague
Andre rosanna which tried to do 72
rationed he's bored and at some point we
went you fail me for the last time and
we just decided to to go with the first
production because we weren't getting
nowhere and so this was an important
lessons learned so this board which is
very nice turn out to be like a
superstar disorder or something very
expensive you know big which is
completely useless in falls apart onto
the ground but it's a cool thing to have
in our office now so a lesson learned
just go for the first prototype you know
when you making hardware there's a lot
of paranoia een you know there are
things I am i kno worried about you know
it it's not as bad as always go for for
the first version and you know you'll
get lucky at this this is what was our
what happened we don't see the second
challenge was that since we want to do
designed to be open source we also
wanted to tool that we use for the
designed to be accessible because even
if we released the design if the tool to
open and modify design cost 40,000 euros
that's not gonna help a lot the open
source community so we decided to
implement these using gchat dork i cud
which is an open-source design tool
which is fine for most purposes but when
you tried to make high specification
PCBs wheat manual routing off of the ROM
then things gets really ugly really
quick so the issue here is that when you
connect around module two assists all of
those traces that you cedar they need to
be exactly the same length and if you
only have one direction to make the
connection that you cannot do dinner
outing on on the size of the
system-on-a-chip you don't have much
room for daddy gets really complicated
and also at the time he could was not
offering any length trace matching
capabilities all of the word for
connecting those traces was a manual
labor in in in making sure that they
were you know exactly the same lamb
produce you know more probably do I have
been working prototypes and this was the
most critical and most difficult part in
the board with open source software but
other than that it was fine and I think
it's really amazing dots in Fremont of
time you can be completely open source
tool implement something like this we've
come a long way five years ago kinda
thinkable on the other hand Afridi a
graphing capabilities of key code which
are useless are are very very good so
you can see your boarding freidy if you
want before having to manufacture which
is which is kinda off a prototype that
we received I was a little bigger
because we had JTAG exposed to the week
debug if the bar for some reason would
have booed up we could at least
understand is the issue was whether I am
or if she was with democracy controller
or some other components of course if
the issue was weird powering up the War
II then it gets more difficult to debug
but we had tests pointed out so that the
first version is it was a knock custom
off a prototype with a little more test
points that are required production
version and you can attack a detailed
connector on into and step into the cold
and so on but he wasn't actually
required because again we got kind of
lucky so the first off a prototype
worked right away to our surprise so
this is kind of inspiration to make open
hardware it works and he's very
interesting to see that the power of
these tiny device is comparable to paint
him to but we have everything
stand-alone impacting such a compact
form factor so from the outside we did
some better envisions where we fought
there were gonna be the final design by
what we tried to do we tried to be less
conservative in the design and eliminate
a few components that you know even if
you don't follow recommendations they
can be treated as an option on Andy's to
lower the cost of the board as much as
we can we also reduce the number of
layers from 8262 see if you work or not
and so on and then eventually we did the
LED for secure remote detection and then
eventually we ended up with a marked one
design so what lessons learned form
action the first iteration had some tiny
doctors after two weeks would just fall
off the boards
Friday also make sure that you test for
done before making 2000 boards because
it was just gonna sock if the component
gonna fall off after four weeks so it
was that was one lesson learn and the
second lesson learned was really
interesting in debate are versions when
we were plugging the board and we would
see a five-second delay in to YouTube
sequence so now when you have five
second delay that's a very precise time
what you do you go and searching all
data sheets of all components for the
words five seconds because you need to
understand why that's happening and you
turn out that the power regulator
enforces a five-second delay if under
voltage is being protected so the
question was why do we get an
undervoltage detection and the reason
was that for doing the gold plating on
the USB connector the manufacturer added
East races that were not on our design
that we're going outwards towards the
blog for depositing the cult but the
problem is that by cutting then the
board they would have they would create
for Lidl tiny conductive thought that
would make a prima true connection with
the USB connectors and then the
connection we lost for the space for the
transition between this little tiny
contact here and the actual pad and then
you would have a connection back again
with the power so this would create the
undervoltage connection is was kinda
very interesting problem because it took
us a few days to figure out what was the
issue and he was introducing our designs
one case where it's something that the
manufacturers body was completely safe
to do but at the end it was in sao in
the final version we had the gold
deposit connection done here in in a
safe manner so this this was an
interesting issue that we had and this
is the final design so we have the stock
here and the center we have the ROM we
have the pin header and on the bottom
where the microSD card slot which
provides the class there's no water
resistant stories on the device except
for a few fuses in the system achieved
for the signing keys so there's no BIOS
there's nothing that can be flashed
everything gets up from the microSD card
which we think it's a it's a good
feature it's a good a property security
and everything else is power related and
we have the smaller JTAG pins here for
anybody that wants to access she took on
the board for it trust and support so we
now have upstream support on Gina Gina
interesting last framework that allows
you to have many more real-time
operating system in the secure war and
then you can put them in the non-secure
word so we gino asked what we can do we
can compile I immediately patch version
of Linux with just some fuel loading
addresses redefine and we can put in a
word and Gina genotypes provides a
platform where you can develop your own
module and your own board concerning
support everything and now the leaders
saying that we require will push OPP
same so the bootloader the Linux kernel
everything is doctor no specific patches
or customizations require to run the
news on this port which was important
for us and it is one example of how you
can use trust them directly without any
support so this is one example of secure
remote monitor so this is the code which
runs a boot so we have a modified
version of you boot which executes
escora start and this is an example
would be led so what we do we assign the
GPIO which is dedicated attached to the
led to the secure domain and by doing
that the non-secure domain cannot acces
dots
because there's a hardware firewall so
to speak that prevents doctors from
taking place
we also said internal drama to secure so
that we can execute our secure domain
code into the secure on which is on the
system-on-a-chip otherwise we would have
to split the areas in the external
memory module areas which are secure in
areas which are known secured and that
we have a security code that which you
it's a very trivial example so what he
does he checks is in the arse
or register would put the ex traffic by
you and if we do that then we jump to
our security code hendler otherwise we
go back to not secure word and this kind
of switching can happen on the man so
the non-security can raise an exception
and ask the secure work please do
something for me and DAPI is done in
terms of what you put into the register
soon will be expectations are offered up
and the handler what it does is
basically it's sets the GPIO 22 outputs
and it has this is true that just goes
the led operation and mean war zone
leanings we can have a kernel module we
just execute the SMC 0 operations so
when we do SMC 0 instruction we jump to
secure Ward immediate so if we put the
cafe value into the RD registered then
we would trigger the operation into non
dled cities is a trivial example how you
can have the non-secure were
communicating with a secure and asking
for you know in this case led to be
turned on and off but of course you can
have more elaborate functionality such
as asking for encryption decryption
instance on Android phones for instance
the curing is implemented the norm award
asked for the secure work to do
operations now so I mention a lot for
the file manager functionality and and
so on and we propose this hardware as a
partner of course which is as open as
you can get it running under Linux so
you can just use it as you know as a
normal device I V he replied to my
laptop so as you can see I can just ssh
to its so right passenger so here and
just you know connected to my USB device
this is on Archlinux set up we can see
we have half a gig of RAM available you
know and we can even so we can run
without obligation 12 we can even have a
complete desktop session running on it
so I just executed the ANC server and
here
and have my session which is running on
my eyes so this is what is one example
of the power of such a device but what
we've done within an application which
is interlocked and we just made the
first non beta release today of this
application is available now and this is
an open source file encryption fronted
which is developed for the use of course
is not limited in 22 execution to the
USB armory you can you can running on a
raspberry by or you know whatever server
that one any any Linux based device and
the eight-year who provide a web
accessible File Manager which is
directly tied to the Linux unified key
system encrypted partition and that can
also perform additional symmetric and
asymmetric encryption on the store files
so the idea is to have something which
provides easy access to encryption so
i'm gona democrat if the demagogues have
been kind to us now ongoing a demo this
application here so the first thing that
we see when I connect to it is that it
violates my client's certificate so this
application if you want to you can set
it up so that you will read them and
volleyed sorties against form your own
CA to actually connect with so you don't
have the browser then he's never going
to present you with anything and he's
never going to unlock the predictions
this is one feature that we have this is
a TES unprotected connection so the
authentication credentials of these
applications are directly tied to the
encrypted partition so the user name so
to speak is the volume name of the
encrypted partition and the password is
one of D many passwords that you cannot
afford that storage and the reason why
you can have more than one password is
that these passwords can be disposable
so if you connect the device to a
computer which you don't trust
particularly and you
worry about keyloggers there you can
make sure that the pastor as soon as its
use
it's it's it's gone so it can never be
used again all for unlocking the
specific
petition if this is the last battle
available in your system than your
encrypted partition you will not be able
to unlock it ever again I'm not gonna go
not logging as soon as a blog Indian
crickter petition so everything that you
see here this is kind of a Google Drive
kind of interface where you have a file
manager and all of these files here our
store on the petition and uploading
files is as easy as just taking off
taking a file and drag and drop the file
here so now the file you can also drag
and drop directories so now the file has
been uploaded here and once it's
uploaded so we have a final managing
features such copy move on the trip to
storage delete my name is encrypted and
we can I encrypt symmetrically so we'd
see Metairie password so here we have
you heard that file or we can also
increase in with your peeps he's so here
at two beauties and I can just decide to
encrypt a file with PGP
I can generate encryption keys on the
device or I can import existing keys on
the device and of course you can also
the crypt sign and verify you can also
make seed finals if you want and you can
of course the files and you can take
advantage of the fact that we have a
file manager that also allows multiple
selection such as thought so I can
delete the file so the idea is that if
you wanna share a file you can unlock
your encrypted partition you can have an
encrypted under USB arm itself with your
private keys which are on the USB armory
and then you can encrypt and filing
sherrit in this API does not allow to
retrieve private key materials so once
you upload a private key when she
generates a private key you can never
get it out
you would have to use other means such
as SSH without a password and and and so
on
here you can add and remove all the
passwords that you want for the Linux
unified key system is also a patch
called nuke looks where you can have a
password which triggers destruction of
the competition
surrounding and having your last boss
whereas the one that if pos- everything
is is a usable you can have one specific
failsafe password that when you use the
encrypted partition will be destroyed
and also one of the features that we
implemented and we're announcing today
we also enable secure and signal
functionality inside the store so right
now so we see here we had the audit logs
of everything that's going on with their
also saved here on a fire which we can
also view by the way from Sarai now
incidence of interlocked is connected to
a register a phone number which is
register with this application using a
tech secure signal protocol so we have a
direct route all the contacts here and
if I ask daniella to send me a chat
message from its own USB armory also
running internal also registered to a
phone number so if network on DVD works
see so here we see the notification that
I received a message from his mobile
phone number so his mobile phone number
is actually registered to the internal
keys which is running on on his laptop
and here I see that I received a message
from unknown because i dont have it in
my address book I can also rename this
conduct and then I can Daniela
and I can open a chat to anybody out
there
hello work and I can send messages and
these works not only in terms of course
but with any tech securing signal user
so you can upload your contacts here and
you can send messages to any mobile
number that is register on on Dec secure
and signals so you can receive messages
and send messages and you can also send
and receive attachments so now he's
gonna send a file to me
zoe has interlock instance here and he
just trigger action so here we see in
the log . an attachment was saved from
the newly and if we see in the chat we
see that I got a message
ok I received this attachment so if I go
into the attachments section is a fire
here so I know that is going to be any
mention so the tech secure protocol
doesn't doesn't give you ran out this
library doesn't give you the content I
but we're going to fix that soon so I
need to know what it is and then i can
download a file oh and by the way these
are files that are handled by defining
manager so of course all of the actions
that a show you you can also do on
contacts and attachment you can encrypt
and decrypt you can compress them you
can download new consignment you can do
all the fine manager 492 you can also do
indeed have been so i can download these
attachment and then I can open it
any such a lovely cat first time like it
so we just shared a file to each other
so interlock not only allows you to do
encryption capabilities but by plugging
into the tech Securency infrastructure
we can also easily share files we did
you know or chat sweet we got our users
can you send me one more attachment so
now I got another one and this is a text
file so I can also viewed a text by here
and all of these has been executed on
the use the armory there is no this is
just you know that the browser is just
acting as a as a climbed to all of these
all the data remains on the USB armory
all the communication is done by the
army all the tech security
he's our store on the USB armory on the
encrypted partition and as soon as i log
out so I can also power off the device
but as soon as i log out to the
encrypted partition gets locked and all
the data is safely store there and of
course you can add me from volumes if
you want you can also have a decoy
volume if somebody ask you to a lockheed
you can present you know picture of
kittens and then is safe to another
interpretation so you can do something
like that so this application is
completely open source it's because that
provides as nice as static binary that
we can easily deploy on such a device is
clear separation between the
presentation layer and the service so
all of the JavaScript HTML overruns
client's site and the server is a JSON
server with a clearly defined API for
patients and you can take a look at the
API and co2 protocol is implemented that
we would try to be as many Mullen as
efficient as possible and we also have a
minimum amount of external dependencies
so all of the features that you've seen
except executor integration hard on an
ATV by application without using any
external library just undergone library
and a texaco integration uses a scene we
support OpenPGP so we don't pipe to GPG
binary this is old natively done in go
we a symmetric a yes
ciphers we also have security tokens I
haven't shown these but we also we also
you can also add your TOTP your your
one-time talkin here the we're talking
about the Google authentication tokens
for instance so this is my get have
token I can refresh and I can have my my
talking here so instead of having the
Google route you can have a back up here
so you can also have one time tokens or
being there and you can also use them
and we have now texted you are and
signal support and yes you look at the
APR is very easy we have Jason request
from the client from logging in an
organized and all these requests are
tied to looks commands for opening my
own team or unlocking the creature
petition and downloading the files it's
all been sourced
been released today with security and
integration and we hope to be able to
build up more functionality into these
devices that we can have easy sharing of
files using on infrastructure which we
believe to be secure such as tech secure
seen on framework and 12 direct
communication between these two devices
or other clients that use these products
such as and so on so I think we have a
few times for questions I thank you very
much for your attention and for your
interest
any questions
yes
heat
not so far so the temperature is is
under control we compile colonels all
the time on it and we have any issues or
so far so we tested of course before a
manufacturing and yes we have no issues
and is also there are things that we can
do we set the CPU frequency on the man
so the frequencies office office only
set to maximum 20 is actually required a
device locked down
the power is off when the shutdown
procedure is complete the LED turns on
so I need on a boot it turns off when
the boot is completed and then he turns
on again so that I can add visual
feedback that the shutdown procedures
but it takes two seconds so you would is
plain text but he can be signed with
encryption keys that you can't fuse on
the system so you can choose up to 4
signature keys and then you can sign you
boots and and that's single device will
only boot
sign if you lose your privacy is and
you're not able to sign anything then
this is a break that you can just throw
away so it's also interesting feature
for the petition if you want you can
also use a run them citing keys and then
make also the hardware device and usable
if you want to but we should be with our
keys we plan in the future to have an
option and when you order you give us
your public key hash and we use it for
you so that you know that he trying to
see did the boys can only be hoped so
that's one thing but we gotta be careful
we not because you know there's some
customer support issues there are some
people might not have generated the key
properly or they might lose the key so
it is something that is only for
advanced user but of course it's quite
possible yeah
for the interlock application that's
your web application for interfacing
with this USB device are you doing
anything about the browser cache to make
sure that you're not leaving all your
encrypted information that you're
pulling out of the device so there's a
reset it certainly must be improving
will be improves but I think we're
requiring the browser not to catch
anything from it
ok I think we said yes and we quest for
perfection as well I i so recently a
very nice article about additional goal
modules that allow more protection I
kinda don't want to use external
dependencies that caused more
protections and if you have some always
welcome any other questions yes sir
you're doing a lot of crypto work there
what is sure random bits source so we do
not recommend crypto so we use days
undergo library which I would say it had
issues in the very early stages but now
it's getting more and more audit and
also going as far as implementing site's
content protection and so on and as we
we paid directly to the library which
provides an adequate support for that
and which also uses
we also have and this is a true random
number generator and as a driver for
that which works we haven't tested it
yet
specifically but you can also use that
there are also several co-processor on
the system-on-a-chip
however some people they preferred to
have encryption done in software that I
can control writing so so far we don't
never
but using them is just a matter of
enabling the right options in the car so
all of the drivers are our most of the
drivers are there so that's a layer
which is a ball our number one of the
question is the specs are the
specifications for the Terrapins he
opened them a little from the doctor
tells you the registers and all the
eighty-eight you need to use for the
random number generator in the driver is
open source improvised you know we works
date i dont Freescale dozen you the
exact insight on how internal I don't
think you will find any manufactured but
does that but at least you have the
option of either feeding from other
sources
overusing conversion on Linux kernel
random number generation think you and
your question no
okay thank you I got any you want to see
that