you are in Mandalay Bay gah for the
session Android security state of the
union with Adrian Ludwig couple quick
announcements there'll be a reception
tonight and the business call at 5:30
p.m. which is located in Shoreline a
youth room the podium words will take
place tonight and Mandalay at BCD at
about 6 p.m. and if you could please
make sure to set your phone to vibrate
because there are no awesome ringtones
thank you very much
all right thank you all for coming to my
first time on this side of the black hat
stage so excited to be able to share
some of what we're up to and my screen
locked so you could see my password
really see that it's got lots of letters
and numbers that have been pretty bad at
typing in all right
that's my live demo of exploiting a
system
adjusts eroded my own man oh well
responsible for Android security at
Google here to talk a little bit about
how we view the Android ecosystem in the
state of security in the Android
ecosystem at this moment in time
one of the things that's really
interesting about Android is it is in
fact an ecosystem there is not a single
point of control and there are times of
different viewpoints and so I want to
start off by emphasizing that what I'm
gonna shares my view certainly there are
others and I think it's important that
we keep that in mind we're thinking
through what it is that's going on that
said that's absolutely the case that
there are times when it's important to
reflect for a moment on what it is
that's going on you know we've heard a
lot in the last week or so about the
stage fright I'll talk about that in
just a minute we hear a lot about
Android security almost on a daily basis
there's a thing in the United States for
those who aren't from the United States
called the State of the Union where we
asked the us- president actually written
in the law to stand in front of
everybody and give a speech about how
things are going it's a sufficiently
impossible task that pretty much the
only thing any of us remember within the
USS is the following the state of the
union is strong looking at Android
security and having been a security
practitioner for going on twenty years
at this point on almost every side of
the coin from off against to consulting
to defense I'm confident saying that
that's true for Android as well it's
certainly the case that we have seen
threats and we've responded to those
threats it's also the case that we've
taken extensive proactive measures to
make sure that the union would stay
strong and I'm gonna spend quite a bit
of time talking about what it is that
we're doing and then talked quite a bit
about the threats and how we're seeing
those threats as well
the union is a complicated one
there over a billion users of Android
devices
thousands of OEM thousands of devices
and incredible diversity of experience
and incredibly diversity what it really
is to be in the Android ecosystem from a
software ecosystem standpoint it's
perhaps unprecedented nearly every other
platform is a closed platform in a way
that Android has strived not to be open
diverse and available everywhere what
that means is that diversity is one of
the core attributes and open this is one
of the core attributes of security for
the platform as well
their millions of lines of source code
all available to anybody to review I've
had many interesting conversations about
this group or that group and whether
they would be allowed to post into open
source and the answer was always the
same absolutely as long as it's good for
the platform and as long as you know
your name is gonna be on it that kind of
transparency about what goes into the
platform allows for extensive security
research and also allows for trust at an
unprecedented level for operating system
for mobile devices you can get it from
whoever you want and you can see what it
is that the devices can do it helps that
they're not coming from a single place
they you as an individual can see the
opportunity to purchase from a supplier
that you like on a network that you like
its matches the security preferences
that you might have
in addition to the contributions being
made at the operating system level and
in the diversity of devices one of the
things that's unique about Android is
that the OEM themselves all of us as we
have the ability to make contributions
to improve the security devices as well
as allowing for extensive customization
at the software level by application
developers enterprise security solutions
and variety of other places in the stack
so when I look at the Android I sort of
asked you know where is the innovation
coming from its coming from everywhere
which i think in the long run is what
makes Android resistant and will make
Android resistant two types of attacks
that we really haven't seen and that's
one of the things that I get excited
about this i think is like the visual
representation of what people think of
when they think of security a big safe
have the iron completely immutable and
if you look at the Android thinking
about safes those kinds of features have
been incorporated right application
isolation is at the core of how does
we've been designing and read from the
very beginning
device integrity is an area that we've
made rapid advances ensuring that both
data integrity and application integrity
can be ensured exploit mitigation is
something we've been investing from the
very beginning
recognizing that it's critically
important that even if devices aren't
able to be patched right the second they
have some line of defense all talk about
that a little bit in the context of live
stage fright and the vulnerability what
we've seen discussed over the last week
or two what's interesting to me when I
put these slides together a couple of
weeks ago as at first I thought I'm
going to highlight the things that are
new people care about the things that
are new but over the last week it was
actually the decisions that we made a
few years ago
introducing a hassle are introducing an
axe fortify source and some of these
medications that have proven to be an
important line of defense while the rest
of the industry works to deliver updates
to devices and so
I think it's important that we
constantly maintain a focus on the new
features but also recognizes those
features are going to be providing lines
of defense for years to come
and that's how we're thinking about
Android not about building a safe it's
about building something that can react
in a dynamic and changing environment I
spend a lot of my time trying to think
about
analogies so it's not a physical analogy
maybe it's a biological analogy is this
security a big toothy animal that if it
slows down guys know I think this is how
a lot of people think about security in
a biologic sense right aggressive
predators but when you look at the
Android ecosystem this is really the
more appropriate analogy diversity at
the core enabling solutions that are
security solutions on a device by device
basis a service by service basis that
together make for a safe environment and
that's really what we're trying to do is
foster an environment where that kind of
innovation can take place at any point
in the stack and allow devices to be
safe
layered on top of that we recognized
that there was a need to have uniform
rapid response the focus and rapid
response to this point has primarily
been in services and making sure those
services are available in all places so
Google has provided a comprehensive set
of security solutions Google Play it's
just out for at least a tie people
thought about it a couple years ago but
then we realized that it was a little
bit more than that in fact it was what
gave us the ability to have deep
understanding of a developer who is
posting an application that might be
used by User
there's a commercial transaction that
takes place between Google and that
developer there's also a long history of
interactions with those developers that
allows us to prep to evaluate the risk
associate with specific applications on
top of that it is a mechanism for us to
identify and prevent proliferation of
applications will spend quite a bit of
time talking about the consequences that
that's had on the Android ecosystem that
are favorable from a security standpoint
but what was interesting was it wasn't
visible
high-profile security feature and was
only hears after we'd make Google Play
available that we even start talking
about that the protections of been there
all along but the safety preceded the
communication and that's a theme for me
over the last couple of weeks is the
safety of in the entry ecosystem often
precedes the communication so we're
gonna try to do some communication
specifically about some of those issues
but it's not just google play that's
providing security service we've taken
that same approach of having a security
service available
deep into the rest of the device as well
offering safe browsing for chrome verify
apps verify apps essentially is the
world's largest antivirus solution over
a billion devices connecting to Google
and checking whether the applications
that they are installing are safe
based on the analysis that we've
conducted in the past based on in part
the analysis of the entire ecosystem of
application developers as learned by
interactions they've had a Google Play
right we've found the software
development ecosystem to the security
ecosystem in a way that's unprecedented
previously there was security and there
was development which for me is a
consulting company in business because
the security people built security tools
that nobody wanted to use to scan their
code and then the developers just built
things and ship them so that's one of
the things that really interesting is
that convergence as a platform between
development and security it's new and
it's happening I'll talk a little bit
about how that makes a difference as
well and then we have a few little
things like safety net which is an
intrusion detection system deployed on
over a billion devices as well as an
intrusion reaction it looks for specific
high-risk devices based on
characteristics and then react to them
so perfect
none of these reactive technologies are
but in terms of providing protection at
an ecosystem level it's absolutely vital
for making sure that a low minimum
common denominators available for all
devices will talk about that too so at a
macro level for a while now I've been
talking about these three pillars if you
will the strength of Android security
robust platform with lots of features
that are sort of classic out of Orange
Book security features comprehensive
services that make sure that there's
nobody gets left behind just because
they didn't pay their antivirus solution
and last month an open ecosystem that
allows for innovation that can take
place anywhere in the platform I think
there are four pillars I know I'm not
unique in saying this I think updates as
one that the Android ecosystem needs to
be talking more about and so we're gonna
do that for a few minutes
currently
we're updating all Nexus devices to
patch issues that have been discussed as
lives change for Nexus 456789 10 and
this is my favorite Nexus player the
thing that used to play videos on your
phone because that's part of the Android
ecosystem we've extended not just the
phone for this isn't about this is about
a much broader ecosystem now are
receiving over-the-air updates and
they've been receiving them some of them
starting this morning some of them
starting a couple of days ago
our response is not unique I think in
many ways outside the Android ecosystem
it's difficult to know how companies are
responding and so we spent the last
couple days asking and here's what they
had to say all of the devices are
receiving intense attention at this
exact moment these are devices that are
either in the process of receiving OTAs
right now or will be receiving them in
the next three weeks
this is the industry response from my
perspective it looks like every device
I've ever heard of is getting an OTA at
the same time i guess i phones not on
there have also heard of that they
probably should be getting an OJ for
something as well but it goes way deeper
than that on Sunday evening I was
speaking with Henry league's MVP of
security at Samsung after stepping out
of a restaurant called me cuz soul time
in San Francisco time a little bit
different
they had over a hundred and fifty bills
that were coming through Google to Bota
aid in the coming days on Sunday and
that's not unprecedented but that
clarity of what was happening is
unprecedented
there were lots of people who were
looking and asking what's going on this
is what's going on my guess
anybody could track of this my guess is
that this is the single largest unified
software update the world has ever seen
hundreds of millions of devices will be
updated over the next couple days
incredible but it's not gonna stop there
we wanted to make sure there's clarity
and the communication issues that lead
to strong response that lead to hype
don't get in the way and so this morning
we started talking about the fact that
we're gonna be doing monthly security
updates for those within the Android
ecosystem involved in partnerships with
Google they know this isn't a new thing
for a practical standpoint we've been
providing security bulletins departments
for over three years on a monthly basis
they've been incorporating those patches
and they've been making them available
we just haven't been talking about it
and so now we're going to be making them
available on a monthly basis and we're
gonna be talking about it for security
bulletins I'll be coming out immediately
after the Nexus OTA comes to the public
at all of the issues that are fixed in
the next update and we promise to do
that on an ongoing basis for three years
or longer if necessary
from the data device first becomes
available in market simple transparency
about how it is we're providing these
things onto the public was very exciting
for me this morning to also see the
Nexus is not alone
Samsung has made a similar commitment LG
is made a similar commitment as an
industry we've looked at the events over
the last few days and weeks and we've
realized we need to move faster and most
importantly we need to tell people what
we are doing because I think that in
many ways was the source of much of the
confusion so I hope this clears up what
it is that we're doing immediately and
on an ongoing basis for all of the major
devices that we support directly from
Google and that the other partners in
the Android ecosystem support as well
there are now four major pillars that
we'll be talking about on a regular
basis for describing the State of the
Union for Android and I'll be honest
this is black hat we want to talk about
bad things so let's do that let's talk
about threats and talk about malware
exploitation vulnerability all of the
work that we're doing to try to
understand what's going on so we can
have an assessment of the risk that
exists in them in the ecosystem and to
provide all of you the tools that you
need regardless of what your job is to
be effective for some of you thats data
for some of you thats bug bounties we
want to make sure that all of that is
available to you so first let's talk
about other one of the interesting
things about malware is a previous
ecosystems have run into problems with
now we're really had very few checks in
those platforms to identify the flow of
code through those devices with Android
and especially for those devices that
have Google Play we've got checks and
lots of different places that makes each
one of those checks itself useful but it
also allows us to use one check to
measure the effectiveness of the others
which is an interesting theoretical
problem how do you know how well you're
doing and so
within Google playing we look at the
applications themselves there are some
applications that come from outside of
Google Play and in those cases that
users at a minimum we're going to
receive a warning that they're
installing something from outside of
Google Play they're gonna have a
confirmation that they're about to
install an application this sort of
blows people's minds sometimes on
Android you just can't get code running
without a vulnerability and without user
confirmation just different from other
platforms that are more familiar with
the desktop world the mobile world is
fundamentally different in that way and
we're taking advantage of that to make
sure that security stays robust there
are additional checks if applications
came from outside of Google Play verify
apps looking at the content of that
application to make a determination of
whether it's something that we should
warn about and then there's the core
platform capabilities trained as an
operating systems are oriented person I
think about runtime security checks I
think about seeing boxes and permissions
I think about vulnerabilities there but
I think it's critical that we don't lose
sight of the fact that they're all of
these layers previous to that that can
be an effective mechanism for preventing
exploitation of vulnerabilities and in
fact in the Android ecosystem
vulnerability exploitation of will talk
about it in just a couple minutes
extraordinarily low almost all of them
aware that we see almost all of the
potentially harmful applications are
internal way of describing the word
malware authors precision around that
language are of the form the user tried
to install it they chose to install it
and it does exactly what the application
said I was going to do through its
permissions and so we're actually
providing defenses against social
engineering or not the types of things
that can be implemented in San boxing
and runtime security checks so I talked
about application analysis what are the
sets of things that we look at where do
the traditional
analysis of an application signatures
static code analysis behavior these are
the things that I think the antivirus
industry in particular has been very
effective at generating and producing
good defenses for protecting sort of the
masses much of our emphasis at this
point is on the next generation of the
fences these are not signature-based
static or dynamic these are around
trying to root out the behavior
associated with the development process
and the deployment process right looking
for similarity in the application
development itself a simple example they
sign up with the same well this one was
bad and that was bad and this one looks
fine but sign of the same he was about
both of them and so we're going to be
taking it happened taking four years now
a more aggressive stance about code that
we can tell is related to bad behavior
we at the very least can force a
conversation literally a conversation
with the developer to figure out what's
going on and understand whether it's
good or bad it's a completely different
dynamic from the one that existed when a
navy company was completed entirely
adversarial role and disjoint from the
development process right and so
similarity mystics in many ways are tied
more to the development process and less
to the behavior of the application
itself or something else that we're
doing some very excited about which is
combining that with data that's been
collected on devices and this allows for
boss to instrument functionality in the
Android operating system and on devices
call in open source you can see what it
is that we're doing and you have the
same capability and other applications
as well but you can gain deep
understanding of the behavior some of
the applications on these devices
through that transparency and we feel
that inter analysis as well and of
course we work with third parties with
your own manual review and look at all
that information as well
ultimately in the world of Google Play
you either get too loud or two blocks in
the world outside of Google Play
verify after my second option which is
we warn the user hey this is a ruling
out do you really want to install it and
they can make a decision about whether
they want to or not I reference safety
net earlier so this is raw data for
those of you who look at system uptime
reports we actually were changing the
logging and it's a couple days and so
there was a drop in our lobbying for a
couple days people were still protected
and we don't fudge the data but there
was a brief period
back in June last year where would start
have lost that set a time Google's that
happens anybody who's run a system at
skilled at that so we built a system and
deployed verify absent early 2014 with
extensive data we extended it was safety
net in early 2014
this is sort of to give you a sense of
the scale of the system right this is a
number of devices that are checking in
with Google they were performing scans
on on any given day the cyclic nature
there's a lot of elements in the Android
ecosystem that are sick people use
devices differently during the week etc
this cyclic nature is actually something
that we put into the system because the
devices basically check in once a week
and took a while for that to normalize
after the roll-up took place and then we
did some force normalization to get a
little bit more smooth so early is our
fault the later is actually the decline
around the end of last year or early
this year was a conscious decision on
our part to modify the way we were
interacting with the service to reduce
the load on user devices we were at that
point in looking at the data for long
enough to realize checking in every six
days not necessary let's move to 74 some
devices let's move to different brothers
you see an increase in the last month of
data that I have here that's available
that's actually an increase because we
decided to turn things up in russia
specifically based on data that we were
seeing their and the need to provide
more aggressive response in that
particular region of the world and
interestingly enough we haven't talked
about it a lot publicly but we've
started to see other security companies
described in russia a decrease in
in what they considered a malware will
be considered potentially harmful
applications they don't know why but
we're reasonably confident it's because
at scale we were able to deploy
protections to nearly all devices in
Russia in the same way that we're doing
that for the rest of the world we put
out on a date about two or three months
ago we're gonna be putting out more and
more of the state of my goal as a
individual is to get to a point where we
can have that kind of dashboard
country-by-country languages by language
etc
available it's not going to be in near
real-time it'll probably be on a 60 90
day delay but this information should
all be available
these are things are critical for you as
an enterprise if that's a business that
you're in to be able to understand the
risk that you have for your devices and
so we want to make that available right
now it's in document format but we like
dashboards better and so we're gonna get
to a point where available
one of the things that's defined in that
document is the definition of a PHA
potentially harmful application I'm
gonna talk about those for a couple more
minutes so this is the percentages of
the percentage of devices worldwide that
do not have PHA installed as for all
devices and you can see over the period
of time that's here about six months
again I mention that we do a tape delay
of about 90 days to make sure that the
dead data is clean sometimes things go
back so this is tape delayed by about
ninety days this gives you a sense for
the overall we consider to be device
hygiene for the ecosystem so
in general over the last six months and
we've seen this going back further than
that as well
around a half a percent of Android
devices have some potentially harmful
application installed on them we work
very quickly to clean them which is what
makes the graph go up and then there's
new things that they discovered and that
makes the graph go down this is a
complex interaction and we have no
expectation in an ecosystem the size of
Android that the numbers ever gonna be 0
there will always be some new person who
decided they want to write some bad
application and they've published
somewhere in the world there will be
users who is install it we will be
looking for it and incredible scale and
we find it will take it down but there
will be some amount of churn and so our
goal is to get that churn as low as
possible while doing as little damage to
the user experience on these devices so
that's what we're tracking these are
internal metrics for making sure that
we're doing that this is the same data
upside down and broken down by language
just to keep things simple as possible
it gives you a sense for why
targeting specific regions of the world
and choosing our response to the
specific regions of the world makes
sense
Russia in particular has been
persistently high water mark for
potentially harmful applications if you
look towards the end here sort of
mid-march that number starts to drop and
the reason it drops is because we
increase the frequency that we were
responding and start taking more
aggressive measures particularly
targeted at russia were planning on
hopefully we'll talk more about that
publicly in the future but this gives
you a hint at what it is that we're
doing there are a couple of other areas
of the world where we've seen
periodically increases in activity
Persian language in particular as one
we've seen increases in activity on a
fairly regular basis it's not as
substantial as we see in Russia but it
is something that we see Chinese devices
have also had some instances increased
exposure China is particularly
interesting if you look at the report
that I referenced earlier
because the behavior there is actually
just in many ways distinct from the rest
of the world there are large
corporations that sponsor teams to find
reading vulnerabilities in order to
incorporate reading abilities into the
functionality of their applications and
it's the equivalent in many cases of
Google rooting your device
we're working to make sure that those
companies understand the consequence of
that one of the consequences of course
those applications can be in Google Play
another is verify apps warns the user
about that and so over time I think
we're seeing normalization of behavior
on a worldwide basis but that's gonna
take some time this is a global view
again just to give you a sense for the
difference between devices that have the
ability to install applications from
unknown sources and devices that are
only installing basically from Google
Play the risk profile for them is
substantially different the risk profile
for a device that installing only from
unknown sources are installing from only
Google Play have unknown sources
disabled as well under about 0.15%
unstable that at that level for devices
that are installing from outside of
Google Play borders around 1% which is
where you get the blended average of
about a half a percent across all of the
devices in the system so these are the
things that were using to analyze and
understand the state of the union
sort of talked about this a little bit
already but I do want to emphasize that
0 is really not the goal it's both
unrealistic and not the most effective
way to manage ecosystem there is
functionality that is desirable but that
is risky
we know that
people want to be able to do lots of
things that when they do it it's good
application did it and unexpected manner
and there was adequate disclosure is
that so that's some of the tension that
exists in one of the reasons that we're
never gonna have 20 a perfect example of
that is really good or bad but i wanna
take a poll but I don't want to take a
poll same time yes is the answer in both
ways both good and bad freedom of the
individual is very important to come
down on this one but I think it's a
perfect example of the tension that
exists right and why it is that there's
going to be lots of investment and
exploit development lots of investment
in research and one of the reasons why
we make Nexus devices unlockable is to
make sure that for those users who want
to have that kind of flexibility they
happen and there's an outlet and we are
an open ecosystem there many other
members of the Android ecosystem to do
the same thing delivering devices that
are unlockable we think that flexibility
is critical and we think it's really
fascinating to watch what happens when
it's not available what does happen
explains happen let's talk a little bit
about exploits so I mentioned safety net
the phrase that I used was an intrusion
detection and prevention system I'm old
school from a marketing standpoint
meaning I don't even know what the
current description of injuries instead
I'm sure I'm like dating myself I 15
years basically we looked for data on
the device
anything that we think could be
potentially relevant and that's
available as remember the Android
security model makes a lot of data not
available for security and privacy
reasons we analyze that
and we try to find what's going on so
what are some examples of that one of
the examples is looking for abuse of the
classic abusive SMS if you're to go back
a few years was to have an application
to try to send a premium SMS feature
that was introduced a few years ago and
read was a warning to the user about
whether a particular SMS was premium or
not if a user says yes they want to send
that SMS from that application that's
probably an indication maybe not perfect
one but a reasonably good signal that
that's intentional behavior on behalf of
that application and there's not
cognitive dissonance between the
application and the user on the other
hand if a lot of people are saying no
grade they've been protected by the
platform but be we can do more than that
in that we can understand that that's an
application that should not exist at all
it should get blocked higher in the
stack that's a really simple example of
how we're looking at did on these
devices and then being able to move
higher in the stack to provide
protection settings like safe browsing
provide them to verify apps or do better
scanning applications and Google Play
based on that type of data collection
but it doesn't just stop with going up
the chain we've also been very active in
putting capabilities to make changes on
the device in real time again
referencing SMS the list of numbers that
are commercial varies by region by
country by time sometimes carriers will
make a decision that the service I used
to be premium is no longer form and so
there is the ability in the platform to
update those lists it sounds really
simple but thinking about how you
introduced checks that a couple of years
later will turn out to be useful as one
of the amazing exercises that we go
through when we're looking at the
Android platform one of the examples
that we haven't talked very much about
is called the interactive firewall is
really called the intent firewall wanna
go search for it it looks and intense
you can blacklist why did that get
introduced because many years ago there
was a specific application on a specific
device that it received an intent from
the browser which was perfectly
reasonable expectations it could cause
harm to the device and we don't have a
solution they had to update the device
we thought about it he said you know we
can do better than that we can make sure
that in the future there is a mechanism
that firewalls from one application to
another in order to protect the user so
we introduced into a firewall and we
didn't use it we didn't talk about it
existed in the API documents wasn't a
secret and then we were looking in
russia specifically and we realized that
it was a key way for us to be able to
disable some of the potential
applications that have become persistent
there we used it enables that's one of
the reasons you see that dramatic
decline in just a couple months ago so
that's one of the things that we do a
safety net is try to deploy those types
of protections
the other thing that we try to do is
maintain perspective on what's actually
going on
has been fined for life just this year
for me on the internet security team but
for the last three years these are the
two previous blackouts and
vulnerabilities were both found by a
blue box
great work on behalf of those guys they
work with us in a coordinated manner and
in exactly the same way that Joshua did
just to make sure I'm not shooting
anybody to make sure that those patches
were available that we were able to
respond etcetera
one of the things I was really
interesting about master key in Fig
heidi is that they were perfectly
instrumental meaning not only did we
have checks in verify apps on Google
Play that gave us perfect visibility but
because they were in the signing
mechanism and because we had logs going
back four years we know for the billion
devices that check in with us how
frequently there was exploitation and so
we have the ability to analyze that
relative to the headlines is pretty
interesting and it's one of the things
that we're constantly trying to do is
understand can we put the exploit
ability of a specific issue into context
and make sure that the conversation
about that issue whether its historical
in this instance or forward-looking is
grounded in reality and so hype in many
cases drives the very early conversation
and then more information is introduced
that helps to stabilize that
conversation so let's talk a little bit
about live stage fright as I promised
that I would talk specifically about
that and I don't think there's anything
that's on this slide that hasn't already
been talked about by the folks at the
Imperium that hasn't been talked about a
blog post hasn't talked everywhere but I
want to make sure that we have a shared
understanding of what the facts are it
is the case that nearly all Android
devices as of six months ago had a
vulnerability it allowed for taking
control program towner instruction
control I actually wrote exploits back
in the day I don't sound as ignorant or
I'm not as ignorant as I sound at this
exact moment
but what was interesting was it a lot of
devices had thought about that and how
defenses in place they're not perfect
offenses their statistical we refer to
them as medications very reasonably
because what they do in my view is by
time right that's the point of his
medications if you haven't found it yet
they make life more difficult for the
attacker and if you have found it
they give you time to recover right and
one of the interesting thing about the
Android ecosystem is a diversity of
devices is itself a natural medication
every single exploit at this point
that's a remote exploit has to have some
level of customization on a device level
of perhaps level etc no prob let happen
because everything's the same we don't
know what happens in a software
ecosystem when everything is different
we haven't had this before but it seems
to be a powerful and underutilized store
but we do know though was that SLR was
implemented in ice-cream Sandwich
Android 4.0 and we do know that over 95%
of devices at this point have a hassle
or so we know that a fire and forget
attempt at an exploit delivered over
something like MMS is really difficult
on those devices difficult in the st.
seen it done yet
kind of way and I would like I would
love to see it done because that is a
medication that we can then get into
Android now so that for years from now
when there's a new exploit that we don't
know about people already have more time
so that's one of the things that I want
to emphasize yes there was some
protection yes it brought us some time
and yes people didn't talk about to
start with a communication issue that
we're working on I applaud the folks at
Joshua in particular but the folks at
same period on helping to get the word
out that there was a little bit of
confusion early on and we're trying to
do the same there are other things that
you can do you can change the
applications
Google messenger applications being
updated by the end of this week so that
it will no longer play video delivered
over MPs automatically didn't actually
play it automatically what it did was
extract the assets in order to give you
a thumbnail I'm sorry for some period of
time in the near future
your hangouts and messenger behavior is
going to be a boring from now as opposed
to a topically relevant thumbnail
generate from the piece of content but
that's a defense in depth measure to
make sure that the risk to users has
been reduced I've mentioned already the
Nexus devices are being updated over the
air right now and we're in the midst of
what I think maybe the largest software
update cycle the world to scene until
next month and will do it all again so
with that backdrop safety net is giving
us visibility into some of these
exploits one of the things that we're
also interested in is instrumental
behaviors to see whether their exploits
that we don't know about this is not a
useful slide shows you that we're trying
to understand whether there are issues
related to SLP 3 downgrades and
unfortunately so far we haven't found
them there's some like weird anomalies
like European nations have downgraded to
b3 more frequently than Asian nations we
don't know why we suspect it's related
to the structure of operator networks
telcos carriers and each of those
networks etc we don't know but it's the
kind of thing that we're looking for
their some needle in the haystack kind
of investigation which is graphically
interesting but not at this point
informative as one of the types of
things are looking for other slides
and other data that were collecting are
immediately actionable and immediately
interesting this is I think the only
slide that I have that on the left hand
side has an absolute number I mentioned
earlier which scan about a hundred and
fifty to two hundred million devices a
day out of those we're seeing two to six
hundred that have a compromised
google.com certificate or responding in
a manner that indicates that they have a
compromise google.com sort of advice
we've analysed dogs what we consistently
see on those devices is that they are
have installed after having had the
device routed a certificate that from a
marketing standpoint has like the name
of a company that does man in the middle
for an enterprise or four schools are
for somebody else we can tell what's
going on there at least it has all the
hallmarks of somebody intentionally
installing a solution that's designed
for this purpose whether the user knows
that that's what's going on in the
device I don't know but certainly the
case that somebody had physical control
the day's knows what's going on they
probably paid for the service we are by
the way
advance from that making changes in
disclosure to make sure that the user of
the device does know what's going on
there so that when we see potential
tampering or more visibility into those
kinds of things and where their
certificates that have been added the
user has visibility into them as well
another thing that we're looking at is
St Lenox SELinux at this point is the
canonical representation of the Android
security model I say that again
SELinux is the Android security mall
really that straightforward
and Nick I'm sure I think he is not here
actually and Stephen Smalley a bunch of
other folks will be excited that that's
the point where at its a mechanism for
defining interactions at application
level it's a mechanism for understanding
the attack surface is a comprehensive
set of never allow rules that constrain
that constrain that attack surface and
provide defense in depth in the event of
a local compromise to minimize the
likelihood of privilege escalation and
on and on it defines Android security
model on a device so it's pretty
important if you wanna understand what's
going on out there in the world so this
is a simple at a device turned on if
your answer is No
something's not right or if your answer
is yes but I'm permissive something's
not right
as well so that's something that we're
tracking and at this point we're seeing
about a quarter of devices in the world
at this point you're signaling this does
that mean five minutes left as I mean
I'm done okay so there are some rapid
acceleration in time at that point we
may want to check something so phones
I will be
cognizant of my next speaker and I will
say we're platform we have security
boundaries the security boundaries are
important that's the definition security
model we've talked about that a little
bit already a thing that for this
community is absolutely important is the
announcement of Internet Security awards
a few months ago one of the really
interesting things that we've done with
the Android security wards is think very
hard about how to structure these
rewards in a manner that works to the
strength of the internet ecosystem
around diversity of devices and multiple
sources of innovation so how does that
work
we pay for bugs and tests in CTS tests
and those value amounts are comparable
to say the chrome bug bounty terms of
what it is that we pay out but in
addition to that baked into the program
we have a strong emphasis on exploit
change so out of the gate we pay a lot
more for people who provide exploit
chains and Wheatear how much we pay
based on how useful your contribution is
to the entire ecosystem so a bug is very
useful about gonna test for that bug
that can be deployed to all of the
industry so they can understand whether
devices are vulnerable is that much more
useful than clarifying the state of
particular devices tests that have been
incorporated into CTS are available on
the basis that much more valuable etc I
said the numbers look similar they do
and then they go up from there
individuals who are able to generate
exploits and demonstrate that the
medications that are in place are
insufficient for the state of the art
that's what our expectations of these
bugs are coming under gonna be the state
of the art there were gonna pay a lot
for them I can't make promises given the
response we've seen so far I think these
numbers are gonna have to go up in order
to get a compelling response from the
research community
we'll see how that shakes out it's a new
program you add it all up
$38,000 per issue anybody that finds and
reports and explain that form there's
more details
the other thing that we've done is to
focus a lot on application of a
vulnerability we've added new features
to help users protect themselves one of
these that I want to draw special
attention to actually two of them are
not platform level features their
capabilities providing Google Play one
of them is the ability to use a version
of OpenSSL a security provider provided
by Google Play this is important if
you're running on a device that has not
been updated but you want the most
recent version of OpenSSL you can get it
it's available you can use it go
use it the last thing I want to talk
about the developer security warnings we
have the ability to interact with
developers this is new in the security
space this is new
let's use it withstand all the
applications that come into Google Play
we look for potentially harmful behavior
we look for malware we also look for
people making mistakes
introduction of all abilities that are
unintentional over the last year we've
begun to roll out developer security
warnings raising for all application
developers the minimum bar for
development of applications and response
to security issues we've learned lots of
apps as you know what developers make
mistakes and they respond by fixing
those abs and their 0 is the goal I'm
now being shepherded off
even more aggressively I thank you all
for your time I'll be around as always
and if you have any questions you can
send them to me a lot with the
google.com or you can inundate folks on
my team at security and radar com they
always love to hear from fams thank you
very much