welcome blackout 2015 I got a couple of
quick announcements here there's gonna
be a reception tonight in the business
call at 5:30 p.m. that's located in
Shoreline a there's maps right around if
you need to find out where that's at the
Tony Awards also will take place tonight
mandell abcd room at 6 p.m. if you have
already turned your phone off please do
that now nobody else wants to hear your
ringtone no matter how cool you think it
is and you're in Jasmine ballroom so
that's not really intended to be that's
where you are
this is the session server-side template
injection RCE for the modern web app
with James cattle and make you welcome
can you hear me tell me ok great so I
welcome
good morning this is this is my attempt
by injection and you may be familiar
with being so focused on exploiting a
particular vulnerability you missed
something that was staring you in the
face with feeling tired of seeing pool
off to a pool of the report with nothing
better than cross-site scripting and it
or simply really wanting to get a show
on a box in the session I'll introduce
to you availability that can easily be
mistaken for cross-site scripting but
isn't and share with you a six-step
process for hijacking simply engines and
getting show was on boxes
my first encounter with him play
injection was around eighteen months ago
decline in get an acclaimed arrangement
and stressful environment we will crowd
into this tiny room and there was a
whiteboard up with Italian the number of
shows that each person had got within
the last few weeks so you can imagine
how that felt the application I was
testing hadn't quite strange behavior
will let you customize emails that will
be sent out to uses and these emails
contained some dynamic content so where
the template that I could edit said use
it at first name
the email abuses would contain that
tonight and I thought well that's
interesting I wonder how I could have
used this I know what to do I'll change
it from using first names to use that
password I don't tell me everybody's
past let's put it so I tried that and it
failed completely but what it did do was
tell me that this input was being
processed by the server as a free market
template so I looked up the free market
template documentation and in the
Frequently Asked Questions section is
that something like is it safe is it
safe to allow users to submit template
if the untrusted and also games not and
it went on to list all the terrible
things that as someone can do to your
server with a malicious template and
this led me on a trail of breadcrumbs
through the documentation and exploit
the full show on the server and access
to healthy amount of sensitive financial
information which is great
it was really just a one-off event that
it was quite lucky that the survey made
it really obvious that this input was
being processed as a template but it was
also lucky that the flea market
documentation was so forthcoming to
Hawkins about how dangerous it was nine
months ago we received a report the book
sweet was failing to find a blatant
cross-site scripting vulnerability which
isn't something which happens every day
so I investigated manually and around
once again the server was behaving quite
an odd way that's why we'd miss the site
scripting and thanks to my poor
encounter with template injection I saw
the issue for what it really was which
was simply injection so the client
thought they had maybe medium severity
cross-site scripting issue on this site
but they had something was potentially
more serious this left me with a couple
of questions
exactly how common is template injection
how many times someone sound cross-site
scripting I'm not realize that it's
actually a symptom of a much more
serious issue and secondly how serious
is simply injection is it only free
market that can be used to get show on a
server quite easily or other template
engines also quite exploitable so I
decided to investigate and go some way
Justin results social with you know
just introduced him play injection talk
about what is how it happens and then a
walk through this process for
identifying and building i working
exploit for whatever template engine jet
engine you found in whatever environment
it is and then go show this process
being applied to fight the most popular
template engines to see how they hold up
and these engines have been selected
because they show the different things
that happened when you when you apply
the exploit development process to them
then demonstrate remote code execution 0
days in a couple of real applications
that you may have heard of but hopefully
don't have installed on your networks
and then take five minutes of questions
and wrap up Wednesday by injection is
simply when using employees on the
safely embed it into a template like
this example here if you look at the
first argument to this they went to
function so you don't use in Burbank
encapsulated into this template and that
means that if the user input contains a
template expression that will be
evaluated by the server that's the core
of this vulnerability just to be
absolutely clear this second example
here is not vulnerable to simply
injection you still have used in both
within the first name variable being
passed into a template but it isn't
being put into the template itself is
just being passed in as an argument if I
use water embedded template expression
inside that variable it would just be
ignored and as with all vulnerabilities
this can happen by accident however I've
also seen it happen
food developers intentionally letting
users edit template in quite a few
different circumstances because they
want to offer this functionality to
users and they may be don't realize how
dangerous it is
to this issue is serious first you need
to find that there's some kind of
temporary injection happening then you
need to figure out you need to identify
what the template engine and use is
exactly then simply build an expert for
it which is where things get really
involved so how do you recognize
template injection given that there were
scores of different engines out there
and they will slightly different way to
do it is to embed a template expression
and if you something really simple like
seven times seven then you got a piece
of syntax there will be supported by
almost all engines so if you send that
payload highlighted in green and look at
the output you can tell whether it's
been evaluated by the civil and you
could just repeat this for the for the
various different common types of
Sendak's the template engines which are
listed on the bottom of this light is
actually a second way in which simply
injection can happen using palm oil
being in import directly into the
template Amobi being placed inside a
template expression and this this is
even harder to spot it often won't
result in cross-site scripting because
the user input is just like a very
boring and if you make any change to
this or any change line not realizing
what's going on on the server then you
get an error message back or you just
get the empty string so in order to
recognize this we need to we need to
safely close the temporal expression and
then in bed something often if you get
input
if you don't get input selection
straight off but you do when you try to
close a template then that suggests that
some kind of temporary injection and
then you can follow up by trying by
trying to embed simple mathematical
expressions and the like
so this template injection happening how
you build an exploit fully you can start
off with a really simple payload like
this just confirms that there is some
kind of valuation happening and then you
can build a decision tree based on the
behavior of different template engines
so if that seven times seven syntax
works we know that the server must be
using one of those specific set of
template engines which support that
syntax one of which is Marty so if we
send smarty comment syntax and that
payload works as well we've confirmed
that the service running smarty and if
that fails and we can try some different
syntax which is a tuned to a different
engine and so on so using this strategy
without relying on something like
pausing and the messages them I have any
kind of format we can easily automate
how to figure out exactly which template
engine is in use this is a subtree of
the strategy used by sweet identify
service identify injection so if you are
about to use it then at the end of this
presentation you'll find an update
waiting for you that will automate these
two steps it will detect them by
injection and will try to identify which
template engine is in use
things get a bit more interesting you
need so what you found so far is not
necessarily a security issue or not
necessarily more serious than cross-site
scripting what you need to prove is that
you can do something uniquely evil on
the server with the template and the
first key step to that is simply to win
the documentation that myself really
quite late but often if you mean the
documentation you will find everything
you need to build a fully working
exploit and get show on the server as we
surely the key areas of interest within
the documentation before 10:30 author
section will tell you what the basic
syntax of the template is so how to do
things like which is gonna be really
useful when you're allowed to the
password that you stolen from the server
or whatever if you're lucky the template
engine also have a security
considerations section on this list of
the most dangerous functions which are
clearly the ones that you need to pay
attention to
if there isn't such a list well there's
pretty much guaranteed to be a list of
built-in functions built-in variables in
extensions and plugins that might be
enabled by default so those make up the
core attacks us next step is to find out
exactly what you have access to within
the template execution environment
most template engines have some kind of
object and this will contain everything
that's in Scott see if you can find out
what the name of this is and find a way
to loop around that attributes and
methods the subject then you can
it would simply identify everything you
got access to some template engines
don't have a self objective or they
don't have a document itself objects but
they may still have one for internal use
for this use case bill would list by
calling get help of the most popular of
a variable names so you can run the one
that would have any more names to
brute-force potential variables I live
in this wordlist in the insured and it's
also being added to be shirley is now
once you know exactly what you have
access to is just a case of trying to
exploit it which is your standard web
application attack like you might be
able to explain one of any number of
common vulnerabilities it's just the way
you calling in to them is slightly
different it's a possibility it's a bit
like building an exploit for PHD's on
serialize function so you may be able to
call some you may have access to some
methods but not be able to call them
unless you use other methods get the
object references and so on
this presentation is focused on getting
code execution however I should mention
that information the template engines
are brilliant vectors for information
disclosure because they're being
executed right in the heart of the
application they often have access to
things like environment variables which
may contain really sensitive stuff like
a good case for example and to get
access to those you don't have to do
anything fancy just use a loop and print
out the value of the variable it's
really really easy okay so that's the
theory of this exploit for us now let's
see how to play engines actually hold up
in real life
firstly free market so this is the one
that I already mentioned and the
documentation says it lists the most
dangerous functions are one of these
functions is the new function and the
documentation for it contains some
useful stuff but the key point is that
this new function can be used to create
arbitrary objects provided that they
implement the template template model
interface so let's have a look at them
and see what classes now that's only
maybe a third of the classes there were
quite a few and you might find no one of
these classes jumps out at you slightly
sounds quite promising any ideas
yes exactly execute execute does excuse
to show command on the server and gives
us the perfect exactly what we need so
here the joke Mondes highlighted in blue
and it's really really simple to just
execute a shell command with free market
on the server and get the app now the
brilliant thing about it is it's clearly
intended functionality is never
to get patched it's just city is just
sitting there as a kind of a trap for
developers you don't read the
documentation and find out how dangerous
free market it's dangerous I'm not
saying this is their fault in this light
ok next up the nasty which is another
popular Java template engine and I from
the documentation here to be a lot less
forthcoming it didn't list any any
exploitable sounding methods and I
couldn't even find a self objected so I
ran a brute-force with variable names
with my word list and I found something
quite interesting if you say that the
class variable
then the album from the server looks
like a generic Java object so i thought
well that's cool lets Google this in
stride I was going on
it turns out there is an extension for
velocity which i think is not part
Corbella steven is enabled by default
and bundle with it so that's why I
didn't find it immediately and the
purpose of this extension is for the use
of job the flexion in template now so
using a couple of methods of the
subjects we can easily get an arbitrary
job object and it's just a matter of
taking standard run of the mill Java
code to execute arbitrary commands and
wrapping it with these with this class
methods to get references to the objects
so we can call them so this command here
will simply make the server sleep for
five seconds using that show and we can
verify that it's executed by seeing how
long it takes a server to a spot but
what we need is the output of the show
quite unfortunate because this is Java
it takes 10 to get there
this isn't exactly job this is nasty
you have to use the syntax of whatever
the tempeh engineering find out why
would the velocity of looping around
something it's but anyway once again
there's no exploits and that the one on
the last flight is just a way of getting
out but in a nice easy way and once
again we have an exploit that he's
pretty much using intended functionality
it is not really an ability within the
nasty although it could perhaps be
better document this one's a bit
different
third one marty is a popular PHP
template engine and by default it so
tribute to execute arbitrary code within
the hour long talk about it but it
offers a secure and the purpose of this
moment is to let on trusted users edit
template I thought intentionally making
you application vulnerable to template
in her injection and then it uses it's
kind of a sandbox you think to try and
stop the template from doing anything
bad to serve this is implemented using a
whitelist of PHP functions so I can't
for example just cool PHD's exactly or
system function to execute arbitrary
show however Marty has a sofa objective
and subjective as a method called get
stream variable which i think is for
internal use but we can easily use it to
read in Ann Arbor to file some stuff
which is a nice start so I command just
reads in your idea to find out the idea
of the commonplace even better lets us
in the secure mode invoke all between
methods on static losses so provided
they've been imported and Marty by
default imports this class
schooled smarty internal wifi oil with a
method called right file it does is
right what are between contents to all
between locations you can also be used
to over life I was the only catch here
is that the third argument to this
method has to be of type smarty
fortunately we can get a handle on an
object of type smarty using the method
of the self object so by chaining these
two together we can do this this script
name variable is available by default
and contains the location on the file
system of the current php file so what
this does is it the current php file
with about 200 leading us execute
arbitrary commands on the server so this
one is pretty clearly a vulnerability
with smart and I i have I have aborted
it and it has been fixed but you might
be thinking well that was a very
difficult to do and I would agree I get
the impression that with a lot of these
kind of sandbox mode see secure boats
they haven't been audited by anybody
ever this is something like clothes and
books right so if you are going to use
the secure mode of a template language
is worth doing is going to make his life
harder but don't rely on it
is another popular PHP template engine
and it's used by the simply by Mark I
think and it's actually by default more
secure than smarty secure mode so in
addition to there being a whitelisted
PHP functions we can invoke any static
methods and we also can be object
references out of functions because they
just get however as ever
object I think this one is not
documented anywhere but you can find it
with a variable named resourcing and
this doesn't have any directly
exploitable methods but it does have an
attribute cold and which is an instance
of twig environment and to avoid it
hasn't quite comments such as one of
them which contains a colder PHD's
which is built in PHP function where if
you control the arguments to it you can
invoke arbitrary functions with
arbitrary arguments and hear the name
variable which is the argument to the
function is being passed as a parameter
to that function so we we we have
control of it up the callback variable
comes from the show to go back Sat
review of this object which we can set
using the register undefined callback
method so once again by combining two
methods chain them onto each other we
can call a method to set that attribute
and they call this method can then call
the other method to invoke the coal use
a funk with with exec and I D an extra
all British okinawans on the server and
once again this isn't this one is not
really intended functionality or it
doesn't look like it but I wouldn't say
this is a vulnerability into it is too
much for the sole purpose of letting
users
beyond just the template and this is
where things get really quite tricky so
in addition to all the previous
restrictions we also got we also call
which read attributes so I can I can no
longer get hold of cellco end and is
whitelisted medical so even if I
developer partners in an object with a
vulnerable method we can invoke the
method on that object unless it's been
waitlisted that might sound like you
can't get anywhere that's why I thought
first however whenever the code that
implements the whitelist I found a bit
of a floor right this target so I
actually we can call on any object that
implements one of these two interfaces
and guess what implement one of these
doing traces the subject so we can go
all but she met is on the sofa on the
subject which is quite nice and as I
said the self object doesn't have any
directly exploit wet but it does have
this one method for internal use only
which contains a line which which
contains this cool whatever the block
variable method is on whatever the
template object is safely control these
variables which we do because they all
come from the argument we can use this
method as a proxy or gadget of sorts to
invoke are between methods on any object
that we can get a reference to so
here the user has passed in the
developer has passed an object object
with a method called reliable method and
we can't call it directly but using this
method is a proxy we can invoke that
argue about that met which is now you
might notice that I haven't got a show
him actually that's because by default
tweak doesn't offer any references to
exploit objects however developers can
Policy Objects and will cost in objects
to the template and they may have
methods which are vulnerable to all your
standard attacks something worth noting
here is the different instances of
template injection within a single
application may have different objects
passed in so it's worth auditing all of
them until you get code execution this
is a publicly accessible website which
by design lets users in a variety of
different languages
now those in the Jade language because
why not and you can see the input of the
top and in the output from the survey in
white on the bottom and you can easily
see you might skip saying but they've
actually litigated that using a sandbox
domains are you can't do anything bad
with that you can also confirm you can
execute commands on mathematical
expressions on server pretty easily so
now it's just a matter of following the
export process but in this case it's
completely black box day so Jade's a
node.js template engine and I didn't
really know I don't no no no jesse is
just this is how you do it with have no
idea what's going on so first off you
find the self objective in this case is
going to root and then you find a way to
move around the subject and find out all
of the attributes and methods and you
just kind of go hunting for interesting
sounding things and eventually I wanted
to this which is quite promising really
so code pin is recognized I'm trying to
do something then why do bad things to
their service to ok but however if you
look carefully at the phrasing of this
warning you might have a suspicion that
this defense is implemented with the
regular expression and actually is so we
have to do is take that top line which
is what which is why this method and
split into two statements
so this excuse exactly the same command
on the server
wonderful so now I've got access to
require so I can import external module
things which can be used to excuse
oakmont on the server so I couldn't get
the album of the show cause notice
asynchronous not understand I think
those things but so what this does is it
executes
idea and it points out of that to myself
so you can see on the bottom
ok I think I've answered the question
how serious is template injection but it
can often be used to get on the server
not always but within pretty much any
template engine depending on what
developer objects are passed in you
might find that they've introduced code
execution vulnerability so now that
leaves the question of exactly how
common template injection it's why I
don't know for certain but what I do
know is I've run into quite a few and
it's quite easy to miss and I had no
trouble finding a couple of applications
to demonstrate for you
which is a content management system and
great thing about this content
management system is that implement some
of the pages using free market templates
which you can see here however as I know
producer here you might as well start
from as low as possible I'm going out to
edit the template so this template makes
this page but I can't edit it however
administrators Canada and in alfresco
there is I found a series called stored
Russell scripting vulnerability in the
comment system that's the bottom is
skipping payload
views there isn't but so good choice to
allow say face tomorrow and they allow
the image tag and they think that this
is an attribute with a name of the empty
string like but what about the Seas is
an image to add some random crap closing
time and then an SVG thing with an event
handler and excludes it and this is the
free market back door I want the
administrator to inject for me so please
try some javascript that request forgery
to over like that file with the with the
back door so he looks kinda message all
it does is grab the user's request for
you talkin and use it to make the same
origin request to inject the doc what
and when encoded it looks like that so
let's look at what happens when an
administrator
views page with a comment on it with
this payload in so this just does one
and this has now we shouldn't see
anything out of the ordinary
blank document there's like around
imprinted on them what's wrong with that
but nothing but now if only do so I look
at what the contents of this file ah I
see all look so I gotta do is put like a
nice showing 1 2012 it's worth
mentioning
thank you
documentation when I was trying to get
the server working actually is says the
Linux installer may decide to disable
SELinux systemwide permanently when you
want it so that's not a bonus I guess I
should also mention alfresco is an
application like WordPress where any old
reason can easily XQ object code why
they couldn't find any other ways to
execute arbitrary code from being an
illustrator and alfresco is available as
a cloud service which suggests I think
countermeasure
this is actually it's one of the most
popular media is one of the most popular
weekly applications often MediaWiki I
think and it's quite heavy great thing
about expert he is anyone who encounters
like by default anyone can just run up
and register their own account on it all
you need is access to it and you can
register an account obviously it was
very many many many privileges so I'm
doing everything here with the self
registered and if we add any page we
could you see that in my support will
not stay I we've got a payload for the
last day so let's see what happens
okay so it's failed and that's because
the class variable has been quite wisely
removed by the extra key benefits so
there's no job reflection of a little
unfortunate so I was left to do but to
win the documentation well key things
about lost a it doesn't require special
privileges anyone can run it but it's
one-sided sandbox with only access to
safe objects to sound promising and also
there was some other scripting languages
but you need programming whites to
execute them but they're not sandboxed
so let me show you why me so this is a
nice place and I don't and I can try to
inject this but because i dont have
privileges if I might cause I'm
programming so let's have a look at
these safe API so we've got existed
first thing you notice is that really
enormous
tons and tons of stuff and the first
thing I found his days this
document class which refers to the
current document so using a method of
this document you can make a wiki page
making it to himself and in safe and
there's something quite interesting here
I noted it yourself there's a method
called safe and there's another method
to save as author bear in mind that the
author of a wiki page is the last person
to get edited it in other words me so
the presence of a sailor's automatic
makes me wonder who the same method
might say that perhaps it's the user who
is currently reviewing the document in
fact perhaps he gets the privileges of
the user is covering the document so
I've done here is taken mine and wraps
it in some velocity which says does the
user viewing this page have programming
white if they don't ok now get them to
inject the back door and say let's just
try and see what happens
ok so nothing's happening there because
I'm Union I don't have to but if a user
if an admin happens to view this page
which because I've added the homepage is
gonna happen pretty probably I think
they both do anything out of the
ordinary either but now my back door has
been injected by then unknowingly
happened to put a show come on here and
wait for a bit
ya gotta show on the seven
kind of a little bit focused on the
defense side let's have a look at what
to do if your application has to let
users edit template say it's a business
requirement by core defense is
simplicity is using a really simple
template engine something like like
moustache or Python's built-in template
something they basically just as
variable substitution is literally tax
office you'll be really hard to happen
ok if you have to offer something a bit
more advanced than that
well you can minimize that you can
minimize the attack surface boy using a
sandbox mode if one is available only
reading the documentation to find out if
there's any like secret third-party
plugins the execution really easy and
only part in the minimum number of
attributes the minimum objects like just
passing the exact they do you need the
template to have one method I've seen
used effectively as far as I can tell is
that by MediaWiki and Wikipedia
Wikipedia actually lets you embed in
wiki pages which is online no idea of
celebration from now but actually this
lure is executed in so I don't really
heavily sandbox environment so like on
the APR 11 V all the methods and modules
that can be used to do anything
dangerous have just been removed so it's
actually really hard to do something bad
with media with these sandbox lou even
though you can do I say they're not just
because I felt happy about because as
far as I know no one else has got show
on Wikipedia recently
allow quite a few different Empire
engines and normally be feasible to
manually sandbox each individual one so
you can fall back to which is what
they've done is using is your inbox and
operating system environment using
something like doctor and then heavily
locking it down so using things like
colonel capabilities to prevent the
template from doing things like any file
handles or accessing the network or and
like turning off set your idea making
the file system we'd we'd only and so on
so combining loads of measures like that
you can make a sandbox it's maybe not
impossible to break out but it's only a
huge amount of work please don't think
so i'm saying you should just put
something in doctor and then forget
about it without too many configurations
I won't get you very far
ok now I've got four minutes for
questions
which is available that would it is very
much is it is it is very much available
question ok I'm going to lap up in
several minutes after these questions
questions
great
so the key things to a member of our
team play engines are so besides and
boxes if you view them as that you
realize how challenging it is to make a
template engine that she holds up to
injection is there if you look for it
and we explore finally on the backs more
questions or you can send me an email
don't forget to follow want to thank you
for listening