Thank You Black Hat for having me it is
excellent to be here among all you
wonderful people again I apologize my
voice is a little rough today but it's a
good thing that I have a voice at all I
did training here black after four days
and it turns out I get really excited
when I talk to people about math and so
it anyway I talk to people big room full
of people that matter four days straight
and I'm completely lost my voice but
it's it's coming back to his way back
it's a little intimidating having myself
like $50 there but at least that means
that you guys can all see myself and
it's a place that t-shirt
the USA plays started
about a year and a half ago and in our
heads and before I get going too much I
want to give you a little a little
caution but a lot less of a caution live
at in so my previous talks about the
project this presentation includes no
content from leaked classified documents
so those of you who were hanging out in
the back of the room what are your
biggest day maybe you can sometimes some
of the jobs that we've given myself and
others in the end it's a place that
project some of these talks have had to
have included lead classified content
because this project was inspired in
great part by leaked classified content
but today I want to talk about what
we've created in the project and not so
much about what inspired us or anything
that might be troublesome for some
people here and it's kind of interesting
actually I think especially if folks in
foreign countries I find are quite
intrigued by this whole phenomenon that
we get information leaked from the
Government classified information that
is and other folks within the government
who have a security clearance are most
of the time
asked to avoid it to not read it to not
have copies of that leaked content on
their computers it creates a
bureaucratic hassles for them and is a
violation of rules to
to actually have classified content of
their not explicitly authorized for and
so sometimes we have we've seen leaks of
information that is useful to us in the
security community that informs us about
threats that maybe we didn't consider
before and we as the security community
as a whole have the benefit to learn
something from these leaks and not
talking about learning what our
government is up to I'm talking about
technical learning learning about how
threats that maybe we should be aware of
it maybe we should take into
consideration when we're developing
defenses for our own systems and of
course there are many many fine people
working for the government doing good
work
who are who have their own systems to
defend and tiny tiny fraction of them
are able to learn about those threats in
the same way that the rest of us are
it's it's a strange thing that in many
cases folks who have a security
clearance and being in the dark
more than some other folks so sometimes
I set out to tell people about these
leaks or the content of things I've
learned from the leaks rather and
sometimes I tried to avoid talking about
those leaks so that I can give
information in general or about the
types of threats that I've learned about
from the leaks may be in part but in a
form that can be consumed by folks who
are otherwise able to consume the leak
information directly so this
presentation includes no leak no content
from leaked classified documents I don't
talk about any details or show any
screenshots from the classified
documents but I will mention
the leak I'll just talk about it in
general terms a little bit but I'm not
gonna give you any content from that
league so in other words it's only
metadata right at the end of 2013 we saw
the league and catalog and this is not a
page from the hand catalog this is a
page I did for fun
inspired by the end catalog made to look
like a page me and catalog so there's
nothing here that actual content from
the and catalog but it looks and a fair
bit like something from the catalog and
it was a leak that contain a bunch of
these pages of information the AMT
catalog from the NSA and so this was
about a year and a half ago and folks in
the security community had a lot of fun
with going through the the tools in that
catalog which included all kinds of
hardware and software tools that are of
interest to the information security
community and and there was it was
interesting I think to see people's
reactions to it sometimes folks who were
I think a lot of folks were unsurprised
by a lot of the tools in the catalog
there were a lot of things in there that
work capabilities that that the
information security the public
information security community
research community the hacker community
we already had a lot of these tools are
things that were somewhat similar to
those tools and we didn't see for the
most part a whole lot of her shattering
things in there but it was still pretty
neat to see the stuff that the spooks
use the month my first impression as I
was reading it my very first impression
was that we can do all this stuff
everything in here where we already know
how to do or isn't much of a stretch
isn't much of a leap and then my second
impression was kind of like for the few
things that were in there that that were
new to me I thought why haven't I seen
these things before this is kind of a
gap may be in the research that there's
there and in the the public information
that we have a hacker community in some
cases some of the stuff that was in the
air catalog was kind of like well you
look at it and say you have you have any
kind of technical background you look at
it and say yeah that's kind of obvious
that should be possible to do but you
know what has anyone actually done it
has anyone showed this stuff at Icahn
has anyone written a research paper on
this is particularly techniques and and
in some of the some cases the answer was
no there were things in there that while
being unsurprising in some ways or also
knew and then talk about publicly and
that was one of the things that inspired
me to start thinking about the NSA
playset project and in particular I
wanted to give a talk about how we can
build these tools the same tools like
the nation states use and we can build
them ourselves in the open research
community in the hacker community and we
can build them out of open source
hardware we can build them out of open
source software we can build them out of
off the shelf hardware and software
and have easily accessible tools that
people can use at least to serve as a
demonstration of threats that folks
might not have considered before and I
thought of this and and I did it I ended
up doing a talk last may may have 2014
was the first talk on the NSA place and
I K I gave this talk I and it was about
here are my ideas I went through the
whole catalog entire catalog and focus
on the hardware tools and I said here's
what we hear what they have and here are
some ideas for how we can build these
things and it was sort of a reprieve
project talk it was it was just sharing
my ideas for how these things can be
built but originally I didn't conceive
of the idea that we would actually go
and build them necessarily I just wanted
people to be aware that they could be
built so when I was preparing for that
talk with the first thing I did was a
female dean peers as the picture I found
on Twitter of him it's the reason I
chose this picture is because he's
wearing a park or gtfo t-shirt PRC or
gtfo and and many of you I hope are
familiar with the International Journal
of POC or gtfo
and that this picture was taken years
before the International Journal of beer
seizure or gtfo by which I mean to point
out that team is a man ahead of his time
and he he had actually coined the term
yet it's a place that also years before
and so when I had this idea for this
talk last year I wrote to Dean
immediately and I said hey D can I used
the name is a place for this stock and
he said sure
and let's start a wiki and let's get
other people involved in this actually
build these things and let's just make a
whole lot of fun stuff so it's in great
part thanks to deal that many of us have
had joined the project and contributed
in various ways and we've gone way
beyond just thinking about how we can
build tools like the spooks use but
actually building them and so what I'm
here today to do about a year later
after the first and it's a place that
talk is to tell you about the things
that we have in fact built this is one
of my favorite ones and this was
presented at DEFCON last year actually I
have it in this box up here but it's a
tool called slot screamer that Joe and
Miles talked about and it is a PCI PCI
Express attack tool and there are a
number of ways it could be used one idea
is that it can be implanted into into a
computer and this device allows you to
implement a PCI Express and device that
then has the ability to to for example
access the memory bus on the computer
and one of the great things about this
particular implementation is actually
the the device that you see on screen
here is a PCI Express to USB 3.0 bridge
and it's fascinating it's built on this
interesting chip and you can buy the
board online very easily and it's based
on their chip that serves as a USB
device and also as a PCI Express device
which is a little bit funny because it
means you can let me be taken attacked
laptop and connect through your
attackers USB port to this guy and
control or emulate a PCI Express device
actually in software on your laptop if
you want you don't think I also work the
other way around if you plug this into
the attackers PCI Express slot you can
use it as a USB device to attack the USB
host but in the particular
implementation Joanne miles showed they
also they did things like put this
device into a chassis a thunderbolt PCI
Express chassis and then they were able
to from their attack laptop connected
via USB to slot screamer they were then
able to implement an attack against
wonderful on a on a system and so they
can just plug into the Thunderbolt port
on a laptop and like reading right its
memory which is an extremely powerful
attack and in many cases there are well
it in a growing number of cases there
are actually countermeasures to this
sort of attack on thunderbolt and PCI
Express but there are definitely cases
where their devices that are entirely
vulnerable to that kind of thing to all
were using at least 44 part of their
attacks inception which has been around
for a long time I think originally just
for firewire but and you could do direct
memory attacks over a firewire port and
now inception has support for this
device Joe just got his chassis and off
the shelf the other day and I downloaded
the latest version of Inception and plug
all and it worked perfectly for his demo
chuck wagon is a
isn't another kind of hardware implant
and the idea here and again this was
presented at DEFCON last year by Josh
and Teddy the idea here is to take
advantage of a bus on your computer that
a lot of people don't even realize is
there it's called i squared senior i2c
and folks who do electronic design he's
I do see all the time I've used it on a
corrupt designed for example if you have
a couple of different integrated circuit
design aboard and they need to talk to
each other as gracie is one of the
common ways to do that so of course
there are i squared C buses on PC
motherboards of all sorts and it's a bus
that is generally exposed to the
operating system so like in the Linux
kernel you can you can look at rockwell
system or so I'll system or your deb
file system and you you can find their
faces through the through your kernel to
talk to ice cream see devices that are
connected one way or another to your
computer now one thing that a lot of
people don't realize is that some nice
greasy buses are exposed on the outside
of your computer including in the form
of a couple of games on your VGA cable
if you have a VGA port and there's also
a nicegreat Seabus that's part of the
HDMI standard so if you have an HDMI
port on your computer you have external
access physical access to this bus and
the idea with chuck wagon was that
that's a convenient interface for if you
wanted to build an implant that you
would install and somebody's computer
surreptitiously and you could then
create an interface like a computer
communications interface for malware
that's running on that computer so it's
a piece of hardware a little game plan
that the Mallorcan talked to over i
squared C and chuck wagon is just got a
prototype thing and they decided to
build it using that VGA ports they could
just the tax it externally to any
computer that has a VGA port the end
what they added to have the capability
that they were giving to the system was
at communication so they have a for
example they they showed how they could
put a GSM GSM modem and their data
connection cellular data connection and
a lot of malware to have this back
channel covert channel over a cellular
network and as long as you have one time
the ability to install something like
this and somebody's computer attached to
somebody's computer man you have a
covert network into that computer or out
of that computer school was one that I
didn't think it was going to be possible
at first when dominic and I first
started talking about it it's a USB
cable that we installed a
I convert our interface into some kind
of the same concept as chuck wagon kind
of the same concept that there might be
malware on the computer but how do we
how do we control that matter where or
how do we export trade data from where
what channel do we have especially if
there's an air gap and this is kind of
cool idea that we could we can take a
low-cost did you call radio transceiver
chip like the one that's in popular I am
me and actually implanted inside USB
cable cited inside a USB cable so that
we create over the USB port a covert
channel kolbert radio channel now this
also has the possibility of being used
to implement USB attacks if there isn't
mylar running on the host computer you
could actually radio control this device
that is plugged into a USB port and
implementing UN attacks against the USB
host and that might be a way like some
of these other tools could be a way to
gain malware persistence on a host its a
very powerful thing when you have the
hardware in plant into a PC and it has
the capability to tack to attack the
operating system in some way cause that
means you can have now we're running on
the system and even if it's detected
even if it's cleaned up and totally
removed from the operating system you
can always the attacker can just read
implant that malware from the heart
transplant so as one of the potential
purpose purposes or use cases for
training school now turn up school ended
up totally working and we it's based on
the yardstick one design yardstick one
is an open source hardware project that
I'm talking about later today at Arsenal
and what we did was we we took the chip
from yardstick one which is in the same
family apart from the Miami my favorite
pink toy and we put it on a tiny little
circuit board that fits inside the mail
a conectar a plug USB a plug so there's
that one little chip that's that's a
combination microcontroller a USB device
and radio and then there's a second chip
on the other side of the board that is a
USB hub and the USB hub allows this
cable to appear at first glance to work
like a regular USB cable because you
plug
you plug it in and through the hub the
device plugged into the other end of the
cable working normally now you if you
look closely you might notice that there
are a couple of USB devices that you
weren't expecting but how many people
actually list out all their USB devices
every time I plug in the cable so this
picture was taken just before I in case
the thing in with an over mobutu that
was made out of my hand for mobile and
formal black silicon and Dominic when he
finally convinced me that we could do
this project he's he said yeah you know
i i think we can do it I think we can
fit all that stuff into a USB plug and
he said no I might I might even take a
crack at that he doesn't do a lot of
electronics design but he give a shot my
said you would dominate tribute to the
schematic I'll do the PCB layout and I
really got the wrong end of that deal
because this was tough but Tony Alamo
was something that Mike Ryan talked
about last year the the debt card
wireless village and this is really more
of a software attack he used to achieve
as part of the as part of the project
and he also used an off the shelf
bluetooth dongle he was able to do some
reconnaissance with over two and and
implement an attack using just a regular
old Bluetooth interface Bluetooth dongle
or maybe even one built into a laptop
and what he was targeting was keyboards
and mice and it turns out that there are
some Bluetooth keyboards and mice course
you've probably seen those before they
they're a lot more popular since the
advent of tablets and there are also
fairly recently some Bluetooth Low
Energy keyboards and mice starting to
show up there a little rare compared to
classic Bluetooth input devices but
they're starting to show up especially
especially nice and what he discovered
and I highly recommend checking out any
of his talks on those whose low energy
security which is given several and what
he discovered in the case of this
particular device is that the mouse he
was looking at really had no security
features whatsoever and so he can just
move the mouse and inject inject input
events into a computer and here's an
interesting point about this type of
attack when you're able to spoof for
wireless mouse in most cases you can
actually inject keystrokes because the
driver on the host doesn't really care
what kind of device you are you can
inject any kind of device any kind of
input using the HIV USB HID protocol
human input device protocol and so in
this case he was able to take a device
that was just a mouse and you know if
you're using a mouse or if you
manufacture and a mouse you might think
well miles isn't too terribly security
sensitive you know there's some exposure
there but like you can sniff keystrokes
from a mouse for example very easily so
you might you might kinda punt on the
security measures and Mike showed that
using the tiny Alamo project he showed
that you can actually take that
vulnerable mouse and do something much
more powerful with it you can speak and
and start injecting keystrokes not just
my also bans
sweeper
internet favorite and Sammy did this
wonderful device that looks just like a
USB charger plug into the wall and in
fact is USB charger but he put some
other stuff inside of it he took an
attack that was originally implemented
some years ago by Travis Goodspeed an
attack that allowed the monitoring the
snipping keystrokes from wireless
keyboards again we're looking at
keyboards this with this tool you can
snap wireless key strokes from a number
of microsoft wireless keyboards quite
easily and again this is a case where
there are input devices that don't have
really did security so Sammy took this
attack and shrunken down and stuck it
into a tiny little package in this
package is a sniper the wireless network
that sniffs the keystrokes and there's
also a GSM module that allows him to
send those key strokes over a cellular
network to wherever you want and it also
still functions and the USB charger
this into a little while a somewhat
bulky off the shelf USB charger and
which means of course it's easy to plug
in somewhere which is where it gets its
power and people are unlikely to notice
that anything is amiss this is an
example of one
project within the NSE place at that
wasn't even originally conceived to be a
part of the NSA place at Sammy kind of
did this on his own and publish any
information about it and some folks from
USA plays a project contacted him and
said hey Sammy this is great for the
assay place it can we do that so sammy
is giving a talk on some really cool
stuff that he's going to a more recently
coming up this weekend also I should
give some other talks and I go back a
little bit here joe is giving the talk
this weekend that I'll talk about a
little bit later and let's see who else
would give your talking like where I am
and which 0 are doing a wonderful talk
on skateboards coming out more and more
Bluetooth madness from from him and
sammy is doing a talk this weekend on
some some interesting automotive related
research that he's been doing
is a handheld spectrum analyzer and
here's an example of something that
existed before we can seem to be in a
safe place at and we just thought it fit
so nicely into our project we're going
to give it a silly name and put it into
our project but this is an older mobile
phone using the calypso chips and the
various hackers who have learned to
write code for that chipset over the
years released some interesting little
tools and there's a lot of folks aren't
aware of I don't think that some of that
there's a tool to measure the RSSI the
received signal strength indicator from
the baseband and you can tune your radio
to a frequency measure they are since I
move on to the next frequency measuring
our society and so forth and do a live
spectrum analyzer application with
limited radioman with embedded in a
mobile phone and I think it's really
cool that you can take off the shelf
mobile phone and do such a thing this
requires no hardware modifications
whatsoever it's only software using
off-the-shelf hardware also mobile
spectrum analyzer handheld spectrum
analyzer applications which are super
handy for implementing all sorts of
radio shenanigans I wrote this one for
the IME my favorite pink toy as I
mentioned before I wrote this spectrum
analyzer applications some years ago
shortly after Travis Goodspeed
introduced me to the device and at the
time I was able to find one on ebay for
$16 but since a couple months ago Sammy
published his brute force garage door
opener attack on the IME know they're
going for like 300
so so I have a few on my shelf and I'm
thinking by next year and may be able to
retire with them at the rate this is
going to play this was a children's toy
that you could buy on eBay at least
until recently for pretty affordable
prices
most of mine for like 20 to $30 and
similar to the leviticus it's a handheld
spectrum analyzer and also similar to
limited guess there's no hardware
modification required this is an off the
shelf children's toy with a highly
capable radio in it that can tune into
quite a range of frequencies in the sub
1 gigahertz bands including all the
popular bands like the 900 megahertz I
say I'm 433 megahertz and the bands that
are used by remote keyless entry systems
including garage door openers and
cellular bands all kinds of fun stuff
can be done with this little radio chip
that is inside the AME and it's it's the
same family of chip that we use in yards
they go on hand in turn up school so
this this is this chip from chip kahn is
the gift that keeps on giving for sub
gigahertz radio hikers and so i i throw
this in here because I was like I was
thinking oh I put leviticus in there
really should put the miamis began in
the case of a place that catalog do but
I just through this in my slides like 45
minutes ago and we don't have a silly
name for it yet so we need a silly name
for this one has any suggestions I'd
love to hear from you and will get a
silly name and put it into me and it's a
place a quickie its online and it's a
place a dork Twilight vegetable
that's why my favorite names to Twilight
vegetable is a tool
Dean and Loki talked about last year and
it is really basic in terms of hardware
it's off the shelf it's just an off the
shelf USB stick that comes with a
special purpose Linux distribution that
has all the software you need to do
GSM snipping and you can use Twilight
vegetable with $20 Realtek TV tuner
dongle all you need is just the USB
stick with the code and the USB stick
for your TV tuner TV tuner and you plug
them into laptop booed off the USB stick
of Twilight vegetable and it gives you
all the software you need to start
sniffing mobile phone traffic and what
do you do with that mobile phone traffic
while you use your drizzle chair which
is i think thats a play on rainbow table
chair again is just off the shelf
hardware it's a it's a large hard drive
that includes GSM rainbow tables for
decrypting GSM communication and I'm not
sure that people realize how easy it is
to capture and encrypt traffic all you
need is to highlight measurable and
drizzle chair the
and so in this case they weren't talking
about any attack that hadn't been
published before they were doing what
they were trying to accomplish as part
of the NSA place at project was making
the tools more accessible and showing
people how easy it is to accomplish some
of these things yes people have been
sniffing GSM four years yes people been
cracking just four years but did you
know that you could you could do this on
your your laptop that you carry around
with you just by having the right
software and the right one terabyte hard
drive and a $20 TV tuner dongle it's
pretty pretty cool and it's pretty cool
that they're able to help people see
that that this type of thing is is
possible in a very accessible attack and
that's a big big reason a big motivator
that we wanted to do that and it's a
place that project was because we wanted
to show people the stuff that the nation
state actors the tools that they use the
gadgets they have their nifty but we can
do that too
we can do all of those things where you
buy a masquerade I never actually soft
liner on DEFCON last year but I think it
was was at one point but dared appear
posted this hunt on our mailing list one
day like right before Dec on it said in
part by masquerade and it's just
basically just a flying high 5 pie apple
it would you know it's just obvious what
kind of silly thing but you know what we
have some wonderful tools to wifi in the
security community we have kids for
example open source software is a
fantastic tool for monitoring wifi
communications we have readily
accessible tools
like the wifi pineapple and all kinds of
of special purpose tools for wifi
hacking but also general purpose
hardware like and software
wifi cards and chips that we have in our
everyday devices in many cases are
perfectly capable of implementing all
sorts of shenanigans and where we're
kind of lucky in some sense that wifi
works out that way a lot of other radio
protocols and this is what I spend a lot
of time talking about doing research and
teaching people about a lot of other
radio systems are a little less
accessible little harder to some cases a
lot harder to have tools for develop
tools for but in the case of WiFi we
have amazing tools and just off the
shelf hardware and this is an example of
using off-the-shelf hardware which is a
little bit customized and being able to
fly around and you could do something
like this thing
automatically follow a person who has a
particular market dress or you know use
your imagination congo block was the
first RFI retro reflectors that I built
and this is an area of research that i
think is very important for the security
community going forward at least in my
opinion and I talked about this last
year I started talking about it and i'd
give it a couple of talks here and there
are two reflectors the interesting thing
here is that this is a device that is
what is that about a half a centimeter
wide and that's really much bigger than
it needs to be the only reason it's a
big is because it was the minimum size
PCB I could get me and I wanted it on a
printed circuit board for convenience
and experimenting with it but really
this device consists of only one
component
one transistor transistor and two pieces
of wire to serve as an antenna and what
you do with Congo fog is implanted in
some hardware you for example a cable
you implanted into a cable or you
implanted into a monitor or you
implanted into a keyboard or into a PC
any kind of electronic device that has
any sort of signaled that goes over
aware if there's a wire or trace on a
circuit board that you want to tap the
monitor is connected to conquer flock
and what it does is it creates an
opportunity for an attacker to eavesdrop
on the signal on that wire using radar
so this device requires no power supply
it makes no radio transmission on its
own but it modulates the activity its
radio reflectivity according to the
signal on the on the wire that connects
to end so what you do as an attacker is
you have one of these implanted
somewhere like imagine that this is
implanted in a keyboard cable ok so you
just have to swap somebody's keyboard
cable and then it just sits quietly and
does nothing until the attacker from
somewhere nearby maybe within a hundred
metres ish directs a radio signal at the
device and then measures the reflected
radio signal using very traditional
radar equipment with this technique the
attacker can observe the signal on the
wire and do things like sniffing
keystrokes video screens if you put this
on a video cable etc
this is the first retro reflector I
built and and I think it
I intentionally set out to make it the
simplest possible device from which we
can experiment a starting point from
which we can grow and try other types of
red reflectors there's been a fair
amount of research published research on
the subject of unintentional emissions
from from electronic systems electronic
devices digital electronics primarily
and and video screens and if you're
interested in this sort of thing I I
recommend starting with papers by Markus
Kuhn on the subject but while we had had
research on the subject of
unintentionally missions we haven't had
published research on the subject of a
mission security based on reflected
radio signals and this is just a
stepping stone i think because here we
have an intentional implant something
that is put into a device or put into a
cable that is an intentional our efforts
are reflector that reveals information
about the system that is attached to buy
by means of radar but it's entirely
probable that there are caissons there
are situations where our everyday
electronic devices have unintentional
Aref rector reflectors in them without
even knowing the designer of a product
of an electronic device might have
created a system that can be
eavesdropped on through radar without
having to modify the hardware in any way
I haven't found any of those yet but I
speculate that they exist and if people
start poking around that we will
actually find them and so a good place
to start experimenting is with these
custom made our efforts reflectors that
are designed specifically to
intentionally service record reflectors
so-called uplog I've used to sniff ps2
keyboards for example
and USB a little bit then I started
building some slightly larger worms and
the only region reason they're larger is
because I wanted to have connectors on
them which makes it easy to experiment
with plug them into different types of
cables and this is one tangle flock is
used to monitor USB connections as only
works at low speed and full speed USB
not hire SuperSpeed USB but this
includes for example all USB keyboards
and mice flamingo clock I've had a lot
of success with and I demoed publicly a
few times and its ps2 same exact circuit
one transistor just on a comedian form
factor to plug into ps2 cables and and
demonstrate sniffing ps2 keyboard
keystrokes this way also block is a
little bit more complicated I wanted to
sniff VGA signals and I wanted to show
that it's possible to use an RAF retro
reflector to allow an attacker to
recover the image on a screen with radar
gonna give you a little demo here this
is a live demo I set up my radar and
everything but I want to show you the
data that I get out of this attack by
fire radar at salsa flock which is
implanted in a target VGA system and
then I measure the return signal I'm
using software defined radio I'm using a
car a platform to implement this but it
can be used you get it could be
implemented with virtually any radio and
radar type of system that has the
ability to digitize enough radio
bandwidth so they show you what I get
out of it I get this nonsense and I have
a very simple digital signal processing
implementation where I take the received
data from my car and I simply measure
its amplitude I do amplitude
demodulation
and then I jump lady modulated output
into a file and then I reopen the file
was something like giving and jim has
this is open source software that lets
me that lets me simply open the file and
then give a different parameters for
like what how wide and high I expect the
image to be and lets me do some things
like oops I just say while is there an
image there well I'll just try to rest
her eyes it with a bunch of different
widths see what happens
and so I go through and I try a bunch of
different ways and you can see there's
definitely some structure there is an
actual image that I got in my lab from
doing it pretty close range reflects a
reflector test with salsa flock so as I
get closer to the proper resolution
pops out at me you can see I was I was
targeting a Gentoo Linux screening and
you can see I was running backs are in
our to change my screen resolution
before I ran those tests and as I scroll
through here you can see actually there
are thousands of images of the screen or
then like something broke I moved
something an antenna or something and
then he came back there are thousands of
copies of the same screening here so
even though it isn't particularly easy
to read you can see that there's so much
redundant information because my screen
refresh rate is something like in the
target is something like sixty refresh
as best I can
well if you're trying to read texts
often somebody's screen you know how
often does that text change it's not
changing sixty times per second so you
get a lot as an attacker
a lot of redundant information over and
over and over again I get these kind of
porn images even though
in many cases their readable I get these
kind of marginal images a target system
screen and I could combine those
multiple frames of information together
after the fact if I wanted to do in the
future
not entirely sure what's going to happen
with the NSA place at project but I hope
that that people learn from it and maybe
we'll have more place at tools
certainly we're having more this week in
particular just the other day at bsides
presented lingering cough which is a
covert channel implemented through
optical data transmission built into a
BGA cable and so he built this custom
the circuit board it's a little funny
but has that long photodiode there are
phototransistor taken out but that can
be made smaller and he actually talked
about how you can create networks of
these things like a mesh network covert
channel among leave da cables that have
all been replaced and installation so
this is just one example of something
like that happening just this week that
I didn't get into my talk until this
morning but it's it's a part of the NSA
place a project that is part of ongoing
work to help people see the kinds of
tools that could be used another another
one is coming up this weekend Joe Pitts
is giving a talk on his JTAG implant
that goes in PCs cold solder peak and I
have some solder be PCBs with me up here
that I will try to give remember to give
back to him before his talk so we have
some things going on still in the NSA
place a project but I thought that the
one year mark was kind of a good time to
take a step back and look at all the
things we've built it's a it's a group
of people that is loosely organized
anybody can join us
anybody can go to and it's a place at da
toward contributor on project join our
mailing list I would like to see going
forward
more retro reflect your research done by
myself or done by other folks I think
it's an important area that I hope liane
it's a place that can inspire people to
to get into as a research area and one
last thought is that one thing we should
consider is that the things we're
creating the things we've created
already mine actually be used by nation
state actors instead of using tools that
they develop their own on their own
lives interesting to consider that they
might end up using the very ones that we
use which could give them the benefit of
plausible deniability in some cases
that's an interesting implication of
this project that I don't know people
have thought about necessarily before
but I find intriguing so thank you to
deem peers for coming up with the name
and it's a place and make for drawing
some really cool pictures that i've
using some of my presentations and root
killer for making these awesome t-shirts
and everyone in the end it's a place
that crew in particular everyone that I
mentioned that was listed on slides
today who've contributed something to be
part of the NSA place at it is a group
effort and it's a lot of people having
fun and also trying to trying to find a
fun way to educate the community so
check out sa place it or hear some of
Nick's drawings and I hope that I hope
you'll enjoy some of the tools that
we've done already and I hope that some
of you are inspired to contribute in the
future thank you