for the session trust kit code injection
on Iowa State for the greater good with
our speakers are banda que era castro
and Angela jail here on thanks for
coming this early on a presentation
about something we're very excited to
release called trust get together we
looking at this company called
authorities when we build a tool to
automatically find security and privacy
issues in mobile applications and Angela
here is part of the security team at
Yahoo today we are using a new library
for I was in western it's called risky
so we're gonna have described this is
where you may want to use in your abs
and then we won't go into the details of
how it actually works its way the
implementation is interesting and all
the things that grow in all this happens
behind the scenes as you're using it but
possible trust kids are going to surely
which is really simple is degrading
yourself meaning every file as soon as
we started working on that we really
really wanted to make sure that that was
going to be usable in real ants with
lots of user requirements like that
without an overall make sure that this
is something I've ever be able to use
and now some idea of how to get there we
had the opportunity to work with the
Yahoo Mobile Security games and angela
is gonna talk about health challenges
when trying to do by nine thousand
a self-cleaning it's been talked about
for years
pretty much everyone in the security
community agrees that it's a good thing
to do and I mean who wants to trust
hundreds of CA's where some of them are
compromised others government-owned and
yet others do BS the mobile app while
it's the perfect place to do
pending because he owned both declined
Sizewell service side of the
communication so i thought well this is
a great project to do and when I first
started to do self and then for Yahoo
Mobile apps I thought it'll be easy
street for a project maybe just had a
few lines of code to check for the right
sort of a kid then that's it all right
so I thought until I hit into some
technical challenges and operational
challenges as we shall see the first of
all what should we put in a ticket or
the public key certificate as we all
know certificate often reissued with
different extensions or expiration date
so that there but rather to print and
public is better because not going to be
changed much but even just the public he
bids are not enough as we also need to
know the algorithm that the public is
associated with
together as well as the public he bids
SPK I on the subject public info and
that's what we should really be pinning
to however unfortunately yes there's no
API to in the extract at PKI certificate
so I started looking all over the web
examples libraries and just to see how
other people are doing
mobile pinning and i couldnt find one
that used to speak at all but most of
them are just comparing the host
certificate so and then another
challenge I am I gonna do implement this
I'm not like I don't want to go into
line and modify every single instance
and its yard connection and a nasty
recession in all of the mobile apps that
we have and so I thought I'd be smart
and use methods whistling while I need
to do it once I'm about to get a
transplanting that is until I hit upon
not a problem which is in you I feel
it's not using your connection or and
this year's session and so therefore
methods whistling would not work and so
we need to intercept the color even
lower level and finally the operational
challenge thighs how they get buy-in
from the product team looking at factors
that could cause we do want to protect
the user's data but when you say you
have this great idea that you can block
user connections they are understandably
a little nervous and say which users how
many users are we talking about and I
don't know what if we blood to run
connections and so at that solution
which is to have a report only mode that
we can gather today the first to see
what we would have been blocking before
we actually enforce the blocking and so
business can decide with the data
whether this is not so there's no
existing library that as these three
requirements that they need and I
thought I probably have to MyLibrary
from scratch
until I met up with data theorem and
they start telling them my challenges
and how we need to start this project
and he got interested and so why not
start the collaboration project and so
we are still like to thank you so we
started collaborating and only know
basically sold all these challenges
wanting having all your network
connection and all the guys and we had
that because the way we did it up on the
back there's a lot of different if you
can use data network connections ideas
like gets too high level in association
with you can do is to be what's
interesting about that is for anything
SSL HTTPS they're all you secure
transport to get involved she's the one
on the bottom right
is apples and apples addition to all
these appear in all the areas you can
use day or you support as possible it's
a cell so what we've done is we've
extended to comply with all every
quarter and so we decided that I
something for charity to secure
transport and once you do that basically
all you hear is can take advantage of
all the conditions are predicted to
basically it works on all kind of
trouble you don't have to do anything to
find all the instances of an asshole
connection then the other thing is it's
very easy to deploy you just said you're
planning policy in the Absa manifest
just the main you want to be in your SBJ
shoes some other settings and it's all
based on the issue to be bookkeeping
which is a specification fall so if
you've done the same thing but unless
you have all these sayings and once you
put that in the manifest you're done
that's been invented we have its
beginning in July said there's no way to
get so we just have to ask what the
killers that means there's no way around
that unless you wanna write your own
so that was the best social and actually
we have a report so just like also the
fact if you're up somewhere on the
device
season unexpected safety chain will send
you reports that with which will tell
you what's going on the subject to
change it was seen and so it'll give you
a global verge of saying are you saying
that a change in the world so we've sold
all these things the right way to really
see that is so we have a team of that
it's basically on the left have a real
phone with pre-installed quality trust
in honor of you have a broad set of 2
proxy or different connections to your
kind of minimal setup and I have an
Xcode and I was very simple over
so-called cold out there I'm just gonna
be in store and when it does it's just a
way of you when you can connect to it
until I know when you connect to it you
can see all the traffic because the
whole setup rocking in the rough CA
strutted India
expected and now I'm gonna do and you'll
see it pretty quick
surfacing I'm gonna do is drag and drop
the Xcode project and then I have to
tell it's cool that I want actually been
just getting to you so you have to add a
framework and end is just setting up
your planning policy in the UPS managers
are already set it up so I'm just gonna
paste it into
my first has to go and their calculation
and inside a key you can configure
pinning and in that case something for
dinner and I'm pinning all the
subdomains and a third of all the ashes
to ashes and also the report your eyes
report sent to the server if something
so I'm gonna rebuild the historian and
I'm going to try to get a look at it
again and I try that you get them and
you can see anything involving then in
the logs you can see that trust these
tickets picking up tickets trying to
find the spins and didn't find them so
the only thing you can see the actual
report was sent as it was an issue of
your own story bolts into myself to let
me know that something and that's pretty
much it so that and I have it's
something you're up for all of your eyes
and you can use it now we opened this
morning and it's also works in western
US will talk about more than just get at
the end but for now
will give more details about how it
actually works behind the scenes and
what's interesting about it is that we
used techniques that are used on
jailbroken devices as well the exact
same function who came into cattle bones
and other things interesting is it could
be applied to other problems in this
whole this whole idea started was when I
was released won't change we noticed was
that Apple started slowing down any
celebrities to be and there again I have
a lot of experience working on two
schools serious after eight weeks which
also adding employees to modify on the
job device so it's used to customize
your phone and also using security
security tools that are based on to the
substrate to have rocked on services
like a circus which tools to make it
easy to reverse engineer and Jennifer
try to understand bob's work so we gotta
make that connection with ok no worries
I so would be able to use the same
techniques on a non jailbroken device in
a normal and now eric is gonna talk
about what it really means to have
dinner with everyone
so before I S eight de only way that
applications interacted with dynamic
libraries with the windows that we're
installing the system like the Apple
frameworks like you were a kid or a
confrontation some few units libraries
like see collide or so you want to
create our own libraries the only thing
that we can do would be steadily and
this was enforced by the App Store
review process because of that time
Apple leading really have a reason to
allow dynamic libraries because
application of word consists only one
single executable and because of the
sandbox there would be no way that
applications could interact with other
applications through shared goat through
a dynamic library so now that has
changed because Apple introduced app
extensions which allow developers to
create functionality that it's outside
of the application context so you can
create these things like widgets for
notification center or custom key wards
extensions or photo 59 of these are part
of the main executable these are
separate extinct animals so made total
sense that Apple would start allowing
dynamic libraries because especially now
that there is so much about the
application site on this and you can see
that as well with a las nine with
features like obtaining a slicing so
dynamic libraries help reduce the
application site when you have signal
and what we saw that is not really
necessary to implement an extension if
we want to use a dynamic library in our
inner project so that's what we did with
trust get so you could see if you just
drag-and-drop our framework for project
and what's happening behind the scenes
is so I don't have already been and
she's been created in the magical binary
that we're building that's a wrap and
it's raining a lot command structure so
if you've done some reverse engineering
or security research in iOS four hours
then you're probably from you
we make 054 met with just the one for
iOS and stand out and so the executives
are going to interact with the dynamic
linker which is called ald which is
gonna be responsible for loading our
labor at runtime and then because we're
in a sandbox environment Xcode gonna
package are dynamic libraries within the
apps bundle and Wade dialed is gonna
find them is gonna use couple prefixes
in the local structure one defense for
example the signal path with points to
the full path in the in the tabs in
within the device inside the sandbox and
then there see our path prefix that
allows for multiple applications for
libraries but then again because we're
in a sandbox in iOS this is limited to
only one single location which is
frameworks folder that it's created by
Xcode when will we be lower app and so
if we if we check our our application in
in a tool like macro view which allows
us to inspect the microstructure of
binary we can see that in there we have
our load command are low delivery man
referencing our trust in library and so
we see the path so it's located in the
typical that framework folder and then
if we see if we replace the value of our
path prefix with the contents of the
loan command we can see that indeed
there is a framework for learned that
it's inside the executable path again
that's the databse folder that its and
advise the full path to so-called we now
know how libraries are loaded in ISA
which is no different from OS 10 but
this is kind of knew it and then we
needed something to initialize are our
library so we can make use of something
that it's called the constructors series
can have constructors which is basically
a C function that it's called when the
lady
gets loaded by dialed in memory so and
and because this function can still get
executed before the app starts is the
perfect place to initialize or hook's or
or patches or replacement and if we had
any settings we can use this to to to
initialize are settings so she see if
you look at the you four point that's
what it looks like it's again it's just
a static function with the constructor
attribute that to make a quick recap we
when we added this dependency on a
project we were creating this load
command that will basically allows the
daily begin to get automatically loaded
when the app starts and then there's
gonna be constructed its gonna get cold
right after that and so basically this
whole think it tastes garrity injection
process of our library which is
different from what we were used to in
an environment but for now we can solve
it with with the just a dependency
mechanism and then the only thing that
was left as ok so we need to look into
functions in to see functions which
again is different from methods
whistling because we're trusting we're
trying to make modifications insecure
attachment which is a CPA ca va so now
always going to tell you about a couple
of challenges that we are using the
problems we have and how we solve it I
said yes so nice again see the first
attempt was to just try to make a jazz
great week into an ad pages using
existing to use which you can have to
make some modifications and trade could
sign of forcing does some said that then
you can get an A that's learning that
week but once you try to study a crash
secure code signing and if you look at
the stack trace for the crash it's a
very big tries to get to that it was
actually in a sec series you have
basically the first thing is the daily
construct all the trees constructing and
then it's going ms function and it
crashes when you call this function is
used to read before any action is used
to replace you want to replace it with
your own nation
ok with this but when you go in on a
knowledgeable converted crushes and the
reason for that and we are going to be
detailed is basically the way substrate
function is actually modifying the very
beginning of the function in memory
replaces instructions so that when the
fishing at school they actually jumps to
your own implementation
basically itself anything which is not
something you can you not because you
can write code and executed and as a
safety mechanism that you do that
knowledge do that unless you're just so
you know if you ever need to run a great
week
best you can but you need to be running
a debugger but for a normal lifestyle
it's not going to go up people don't
think I'm gonna go running it in a
debugger so there's just no way and I
trusted him failed
there's no way to make it into a normal
life story something else we tried it's
kind of a well-known technique deleon
celebrities such an environment variable
just when you look at your library to do
it and say ok I want to replace this
again with my own function said symbol
remaining it only works with text
palette options so you cannot modify a
private that since idea but any of the
dependencies
where their sex symbols you can replace
them with a technique and an environment
environment variables is that you cannot
set an environment variable universal
next good when your listing on the App
Store there's no way you can set an
environment able to get in the way to
use that and in the last attempt is that
it turns out there have been some new
memories that also do simple remaining
just telling celebrities but it's done
anything goes on from Chemical city to
city does many different things it can
function just like substrate may
actually touching also has one specific
function to do that in deposition which
gonna work on an auto mechanic and the
other one is from face book and it's the
same thing and if you actually try to
use these works are you able to repay
symbols and make changes to going back
to just now it's going to recover how it
really works when you address key to
your ex to your school library into the
UPS package and then a log in to your
appt so that when you add starts just
get it also loading it is loaded and
construct or define and so that concert
targets and when he does it gets to
being policy from the money first and
then set up some hoops and specifically
it's extending
SSL handshake which obviously they
scaled it extended to you for watching
when using Facebook and its way as you
saw in the gym or on the only thing I
had to do was just drag and drop it
actually change the absolute this was
just all they can you tell us how it
works so you should try it out it's open
source today very diverse in the western
and it's already on the App Store it's
not an idea it's live on the store right
now in one of the Yahoo have another and
we're working with all the companies
interested in using as well the more
people use it to but also you should
check it out and let us know what you
think and hope will be useful to you as
well thanks everyone
that's I have 15 seconds there's one
less thing if you need to do security
research on an advertising also released
a tool to divulge asleep on the job
converse Surgical Associates which too
so don't spend days range against our
job base so it's not a threat model of
stopping in that maybe this was all
right this wrong