we're going to talk about third-party
code party libraries the risks if you a
little bit what's going on and they
would also also offer up some potential
solutions for you so many JP the sea so
crisp a security been doing
vulnerability intelligence for a long
time
runaways BTV and data loss did you know
that I'm joined by can't believe I am
Kimberly price director of red team for
crowd before this I work in security
incident response at blackberry and data
analytics and threat intelligence that
Microsoft had crazy cat picture poster
on there but she didn't like that so
every Friday on Twitter it's Kat writing
so you're the cash alright so what are
we here to talk about and really for
most organizations and most people it's
no big question mark still most people
don't understand sort of what this
third-party library stuff really means
and in many cases people really
understand how it's impacting them at
their organization right to try to get
your head wrap around the issues as part
of the biggest problem this whole
third-party risk so what happens when
you don't think you understand what's
going on
well you turned to sort of metrics are
some sort of what's going on out there
in the world right and so security space
we love our metrics right well we seen
better reports coming out things coming
out
unjust up all probability statistics
blackout in 2013 Steve Christie and
Brian Martin were here and it's all over
police tax and pretty much why they suck
so if you're interested in understanding
that sort of going out you can go check
this out right so regardless of them
complain about statistics what are we
gonna do so get ready so this is a chart
data from PDB about vulnerabilities
overtime
so what you want to look at your we're
trying to describe basically is what is
going on in terms of the number of all
abilities not trying to say that's the
right metric or anything like that but
you can see from this is we are not
seeing a slowdown and vulnerabilities
reported discovered so we may be
investing in securities we may be
talking about it all the time and the
government and this and that we're still
seeing a whole bunch of crap code coming
out right and in fact in 2013 from these
CDs that you're seeing over 13,000
vulnerabilities disclosed right if you
look at sort of the breakdown of all
received a ton of process group in the
tunnel sequel injection vulnerabilities
that should have been eradicated ten
years ago or still most prevalent out
they're both pretty frightening right
now there's a whole lines here that this
is even talking about software
ok so there's a lot of all abilities
still coming out ok all right now we're
playing war games and he's later
actually brutal so it's really hard to
say there but let's play a game how many
vulnerabilities in terms of cash did you
think there were an OpenSSL for the
issue known as hard police so the
artfully fallibility how many would you
count that one let's not overthink this
right
11 vulnerability to agree yes I can
barely see most of you saw me hear you
you reach $1 billion answer is yes
$1 ability and our our world right so
company that does vulnerability
intelligence they put out for its pretty
nice report they counted that there were
over $15,000 abilities so again when you
look at some news reports you need to
understand the methodology behind it so
most people would agree are pleased was
$1 bility when you look at the
methodology of this report and what you
start to see a candidate two hundred and
ten times we still believe it
14 durability but yes two hundred and
ten times it was counted in this report
we have to look at these reports and
understand how things are being counted
what's going on before you sort of run
often as sort of make decisions on
what's going on
ok so I wouldn't say that are believed
was 210 times where these scream about
it but it was a big deal right
harpley was a big deal he got a lot of
attention and people started to
understand what was going on
fancy logo can go a long way we all know
that but it really was the point where
it started to get people understand that
one vulnerability can go across multiple
things and when you're seeing
reports on news media at all this sort
of stuff it's something they get
people's attention so it started to
raise the awareness of this thing called
third-party live people get mad at the
slide but in estimates it was around
hundred plus vendors + impacted by our
beliefs as well as over 600,000 servers
on the internet that were impacted by
the Heartland village you get mad at us
all you want the point is lots of all
abilities lots of impact all over the
place here one vulnerability and packing
lots of vendors and left a code that was
unexpected so here's just a small sample
of some products that we're listing up
here sixty eight or so before we got
tired of typing and most people say wait
a second you know the only people using
opposite OpenSSL and things like that
already startups or small companies can
afford is an enterprise stuff right but
then when you start to see is a very
large companies are in fact using
OpenSSL and other libraries in their
code if I can't tell you the number of
times I've had conversations with people
will say we don't use any third party
libraries our company and then a list of
all the vendors are using the right so
people are still trying to get their
heads wrapped around it hardly we had
the wrong number this is what I got more
attention it was maybe super-three but
the same point we're starting to see
more and more these homes we then have a
scary poodle right so scary poodles
gonna come attack network and a log jam
right so get your continuing to see sort
of the naming of vulnerabilities logos
all those things are likely another game
how many vulnerabilities you think
there's been an open a cell center
police and please for the love of god
don't use the security counting how many
vulnerabilities do you think we hear you
50010 ok well so here's the ugly I
Charleville abilities and OpenSSL heart
believe once the little animation comes
in there all the way to the bottom
you'll see that's always back there
April 2014 when Hartley was there and so
52% fifty you're pretty damn funny for a
beverage later but they do have all
abilities if you're a person that like
CBS s right there was something there
that had the CBS 410 on average 6.78 and
if you think about it probably itself
was rated as a five right so one could
argue that lots of all abilities since
then and a lot that we're so far more
critical now if you hate CBS s version 2
and maybe even version 3 that's coming
let's look at a different measure here
right so let's look at it we go we look
at nine of these 52 and exploit publicly
available or some type of POC so now
we're talking about a little bit of a
different way to look at it and if you
look further fourteen of those actually
had a private exploit its just a
different way to look at it so many
people can look at this and say well we
didn't see all these on the news and
they didn't all have fancy logos and
whatnot
they could be more impactful than even
the ones we saw it so here's a scary
ghosts and for all the researchers in
the room remember your name and your
logo carefully or one like that might
get assigned to you but the point of
this is just a show that we're beat up
on OpenSSL for good reason but the same
time this is much more than this right
this is the new library coast so it's
not just opened a cell that this sucks
out there and in fact I'm not sure
what's going on with these days we need
to go to but if you even go back to 2005
it was a naive on out there we called
ghost so let's try not to recycle the
same name but getting more creative
right so what this is showing to us is
this whole concept of systemic risk
things are interconnected right and if
you think about it in terms of the
insurance were
this is really well this is one
hurricane event that comes up and calls
massive problems right one of them
calling lots of problems and you start
to see this in third-party code library
usage right one of all ability affecting
all that and that's why it's such a big
concern in many cases so I'm not here to
talk
complete trash about third-party library
usage whether it's open or closed source
nothing of that nature there are great
things are developers and companies are
under pressure to deliver better faster
cheaper all three and libraries are
great they do a lot of great things but
at the same time you need to understand
that this deficiency in the goodness
that comes with it comes to potentially
at this call at so many cases is not
just the one involving a crossed low
into products organizations and the
researcher we're doing we're seeing that
one application can have hundreds and
hundreds of third-party libraries and in
many cases organizations are not
treating that that their party Co
Cordingley this coming up black duck out
there that categorizes open source
components and looks at it we reached
out to them to say you know how much of
the stuff is out here right we've made a
couple of all abilities kimberly's gonna
go over some vulnerabilities in and
libraries but like typically said
they're tracking over a million open
source projects we believe that means it
with with versions different versions of
it across six thousand sites in our
world we think the numbers probably
around 1,500 to 2,500 libraries that are
routinely used but this is still areas
being discovered their party libraries
probable over the place but so get part
of it is really understanding what
you're using another metric that they
shared with was interesting is that 30%
of the Forbes Global 2000 Enterprise
code is actually open source it's
something that's out there is something
that truly alright folks library
I would love to start a library date it
to talk so I want to be clear first off
we're not advising is judge said to not
use third-party libraries we're hoping
to talk to you about the information you
should have on the libraries that are
being used to ensure that you're
planning your resources whether their
technical or personnel resources or time
scheduling for secure development and
and not just the post-release incident
response piece of it but even during
design and development so all of the
data we're presenting today is from
public sources are going to be able to
go back to your office and if you needed
to do it proof of concept to demonstrate
your leadership team why you need
funding to implement some tools or
threat intelligence feed you can do that
it's not super steel wool long term but
you could at least get a start and and
show them why this is useful so I pulled
the data from public sources but as you
can see on this line as and pig in CT
details as a hundred and ninety-one
vulnerability short if you look at
involved ed which is a paid for
intelligence feed there's over a
thousand math is hard but it's a cord
and so why are wiser difference will
flat out tell you they silently patch
vulnerabilities they don't sign CD East
here so if you're looking at a public
CDE database you're only getting the CD
East when you're considering a threat
intelligence library make sure
that the vendor you're considering the
money to you is doing a thorough
security assessment of that library and
documenting the silent fixes for you
this is all public beta I'm not gonna be
able to tell you that there goes to
taxes let's start with OpenOffice out
and i wanna talk a little bit talk about
the spread of this but i wanna start
with them because it sets the stage for
their libraries we're gonna talk about
who use it
gmail.com LastPass VMware down Dropbox
black right
all these companies I got tired of
playing logos so we've also got Val Red
Hat McAfee f5 siskel 14 at every time
there is an OpenSSL vulnerability all of
these lenders have to patch and
sometimes I have to catch in multiple
products and I've actually seen products
use multiple iterations of the same
library where you've got to feature
teams that both you deliver that they
didn't talk to each other so they're not
dynamically linking it and they're both
running there
own versions and sometimes running
different versions so this is a whole
lot of catching for OpenSSL and we also
that pain during Hartley it is Jake
mention if you hurt lead and you didn't
pack again until free or some other
major named event you probably missed
items in the modalities so next up this
free time rendering library and super
useful I don't really recommend that you
decide to start graduate of murdering
library he's never done it before a
really nice to be able you something
that someone else has been working on
for years and years and is used in
Android iOS wrong FreeBSD ghost script
is in printers all over the world so
basically got some things invested in
there it is also in OSX WebKit what's
interesting is it is another third-party
libraries you have libraries now sit in
libraries so anything that uses WebKit
may be vulnerable when three ty possible
ability
we've got plenty to Oracle blackberry
zadora Playstation or shine again
indicating devices operate four-week
multiple video games and I'm not gonna
live was kind of fun like investigative
Lee tracking down these libraries are
resistant the American Girl doll game I
didn't see that coming
you know those laws are a little creepy
maybe maybe they're not accurate but the
bigger issue is very tight
libraries and a lot of places so CDE
2011 0226 didn't have a catchy name but
RCDs 933 and this vulnerability was used
in jailbreak for the iPhone in 2011 and
Israel locally exploitable
vulnerabilities the Joburg will
primarily be Terms of Use violation if
you look violation but it was remotely
exploitable so there is a missing
parameter check that allowed a malicious
program to move the stack pointer and
now started if you're using frito to
render your email and your browser just
reading email condone your device so
this is why libraries really matter
because now you have to wait you can't
have free time you have to wait for the
vendor departure for you with PNG which
artist over a hundred and thirty
applications including Google Apple
Adobe Microsoft VMware blackberry next
it everywhere and the reason is
everywhere its compatibility you want to
be able to view PNG is on everything so
we've eaten in things like PowerPoint
Visio and then again it's in WebKit
again you've got to know some libraries
going on
their Solaris VMware Server countless
application now we didn't talk about we
haven't talked about tom cat awful lot
when we get in this presentation in the
past tom cat is used in ASAP VMware
Nokia and seek you're starting to see a
very different type of application fees
are much more enterprise applications
you're seeing controls that there that s
AP accounting and payroll that matters a
whole so we've got that all over the
place and you're also starting to see
the scene fender logos over and over and
over and that's going to be important in
a minute to the next last prayer /
players in Microsoft and Oracle and IE
and Chrome and Firefox and Blackberry
and WordPress and even Apple you you you
can point to the fact that Apple isn't
shipping Flash Player but if you thought
using your enterprise with Max had they
install flash there how are you getting
that fixed so at least still issuing
patches for flash player on so that
still has to get up to it as well and
then a few other things it it was
actually used in some Samsung smart
televisions as well don't know Samsung's
patching
but and then Java Java wins hands down
on the vulnerability spread competition
we shifted to mars it is on the Mars
rover it in almost every eniac
joking we thought it would be easier to
list of places it wasn't used its not
used in towels for example it is in
nearly everything and so let's look at
the actual breakdown of numbers from
January 1st 2007 until june thirtieth
2015 and win a library wasn't around
that long over due to the data to
OpenSSL across the state and a half
years has had ninety vulnerabilities
they're averaging 10 to 11 here that's
what they're releasing three times a
year so far patch management perspective
you're only gonna have to look at the
library on average three times a year
their average EDSS scores 5.49 here to
see the US but as jack mentioned earlier
Hartley was only a 50 sometimes really
bad stuff comes in small packages
freetype at fifty longer to Rudy's
releases a year and you can see their
CBS score is higher at 7.43
Eng dropping down even further only 28
vulnerabilities are eight and a half
years 6 165 and CBS two to three days a
year
jumping back up 205 days a year on
average four point seven to go and
here's where you get into weird things
with your data
tom cat will see de
really low CBS formerly known as you see
de on a two point four and a lot of
vendors will only CBS in the five and
above range so again data isn't perfect
but this is what probably available
you'll see $100 abilities but overall
the impact is much lower lash players
2009 to present
they have five hundred and twenty-two
vulnerabilities in that time but they
have a very consistent release schedule
about once a month and their average
CVSS score is 8.9 6 job will be to flash
player with five hundred and thirty-nine
daily update quarterly know so when you
get a job
day think about you know just rolled out
you do some a compact testing you make
sure you're not going to break anything
software vendors have to do the same
thing so if they get a Java update that
has 52 vulnerabilities in it that's a
lot of testing before they can integrate
it but that's a half years worth of data
how bad is it today
whatsoever in 80015 just forum for
OpenSSL has 29 out of those ninety just
in the first six months of this year
down to Flash Player of the Year hundred
and thirty-five in the first six months
of this year that's 25% of their total
eight and a half year total load of
vulnerabilities Giada 58 so far this
year this
is not to say that retail is more secure
than Flash Player Adobe has a robust
mature security team that does pen
testing they bring in consultants they
run by the county they're actively
looking for vulnerabilities I don't know
what I don't know about three types so
again when you're looking at data this
is not telling you what's more secure
tell you how to plan your resources if
you're using any of these libraries so
that's the hasty generalization don't
assume something is less secure because
it has a lot of vulnerabilities in it so
we'll wait until you just told me how
many vulnerabilities they have I thought
it was just like jesus saith insecure
should you be using accountable should
be live you be looking at a frequency of
updates
variable annuities maybe the most
important thing is is there a crx way
yes there is no one measure to its all
data used to make conscious risk
decisions and and what we're going to
talk to you a little bit more about this
is all laying the groundwork for what
they say about to talk to you that
around window of opportunity so how long
has the vulnerability been known for and
is that a factor for you to think about
as well alright so we tried this sort of
lay of the land for you what this
third-party libraries stuff is give you
a little feel for where it is which
seemed to be everywhere but what's going
on but in terms of what you can do it
your organization right now sort of
feels like
little helpless it seemed right so wanna
talk to you about this thing called
pitot and it's a number of years of
research finally coming together this is
the first time we're talking about it
publicly and so it stands for
vulnerability timeline and exposure
metrics and so basically what it is it
took train more that's trying to define
that provide guidance for vulnerability
timeline tracking so if you think about
it or ability there's a lifecycle
associated with it right from the time
of all these introduced into a codebase
was discover to gets
and all this other stuff is all these
dates and time right to this spring
we're trying to define what those dates
are and then some calculations and maybe
can give you some metrics write those
metrics can allow you in and doing
better vendor evaluation better product
evaluation and then ultimately at the
end understand the exposure that your
organization is really facing to these
these issues so we went through this
little bit but you probably sit there
and say I really care about this stuff
right so we're hoping that you should
care for a few reasons and again the
metric should help you evaluate and
select vendors to work with it actually
care about security so we keep you know
tracking data left and right nothing
looks like it's getting better than 10
years now we give the same Tacopina say
the same crap you know bones keep coming
reaches keep happening nothing seems to
be sort of moving in the right direction
well we actually start to have something
that can better evaluate our vendors may
be that enforce vendors that actually
start cursing secure products so instead
of working on that next feature they
will start working on actually securing
their products as we know there's going
to be some evaluation against them if
you choose to work with vendors and use
your wallet or your pocketbook and put
it with vendors I care about security
and start to force things down that path
right market forces prevail maybe
instead of sort of the software
liability
arguments they keep coming up and
secondly it's actually a truly help you
understand your organization's exposure
and what vendors and what products are
really sort of the biggest offenders in
your organization what are you doing so
what we want to accomplish with with me
time so we wanted to find the time on an
exposure terminology and try to make it
consistent consistent usage right so for
organizations for researchers are
discovering vulnerabilities as well as
software vendors and even more so to
find that patient's for certs the
software vendors and researchers on a
date in the data that we're looking for
in their vulnerability research in their
disclosure or coordination processes
again it's a framework to assist your
organization with understanding your own
time of exposure identifying those
vendors and products that are
contributing to this exposure allow you
to create a scorecard where you can you
can monitor performance of these vendors
and products and assist you more than
anything goes maybe that upfront select
the right vendors and products to work
with understand that total cost of
ownership of making these decisions so
days so over there are nine days right
now that are part of the v10 framework
but there's already another Wang being
argued that needs to be added into it
just fine this is meant to be a living
framework but think about it so quickly
right
vulnerabilities introduced at some point
I'm availability is discovered at some
point I'm a vendor is informed at some
point in time about it and then at some
point later they respond right now
things get great in the role of Billy
lifecycle you actually spend the time to
do with these dates are all over the
place they're not sort of linear street
you know things come out before other
things happen as it gets a little murky
at time but again
defining the dates that we want to
understand this is what we're doing
first so better informed about it then
directs some point acknowledges this and
we're gonna get a vendor solution to the
situation
another point in time and then the
disclosure of it now if a vendor doesn't
do it we expect in terms of a solution
maybe there's a third-party solution or
fix that can help if there's a date for
that exploit publish date again that
could come out well before any of those
other ones but there's a date with the
export becomes public and then the final
one that helps you with your position is
Ben do you actually solve this one is it
the solution implemented at your
organization so these are the court
dates of the framework right now so
great just thought about that what does
that actually mean what is it what does
it matter she'll show you the money
right
ok so over the next couple slides I just
pick one going to Billy to sort of give
you a flavour of how this can work so
this is an old school met screen
vulnerability that I personally have
understand you know and know that all
the dates for these calculations existed
there are tons of vendors that could
have been picked and bad examples and
all that sort of stuff of things we can
go into that later but this is a net
screen phone from back in 2002 long time
ago and so the first metric that beat em
provides when we called into response
time and again the purpose is to
demonstrate the response time from a
vendor being informed until they
actually respond to a researcher we're
not talking about our automated response
and if you think about the whole full
disclosure Apple this and that
coordinated disclosure stuff a lot of it
about is about the new response I'm
actually responding so we can do that
right that those dates that we talked
about we have that so when was the
vendor informed and how long did it take
to acknowledge so we'll get this ball
here you can see they were informed on
October 8th and they acknowledged a
little bit later we have a date right
37 days to get a response and my
sympathies to you not in good or bad
that comes later on we start doing more
work but we can see what their response
time was on this particular
vulnerability time to bash what we mean
by this one this one means to
demonstrate the response time of the
vendor from when they were informed that
when they provide and publisher working
patch with customers again you can see
here there are formed in October Asian
2002 and then the solution comes out
late November right so simple metrics
here that makes a 48 days is what it's
all the time that they were made aware
of it
21 they provided a patch now here's
we're gonna get a wordsmith in a commit
rights we see time to patch there's all
these variations to it so the next one
is total time to bash and what we're
trying to say here here trying to see
what is the total amount of time when
the vulnerability was discovered that
patch then becomes available so you can
see here in this particular case it's
not too much difference because when I
was discovered it was only a couple days
later that it went over to the to the
vendor right now there are gaps in this
you can understand it researchers are
sitting on vulnerabilities if there's
something else that there are two
different sort of metrics that you can
start to look at the making action for
your organization
all right now we're going to talk about
a few that are more specific to what
your organization could be in this is
the time of exposure metrics that we've
been talking about so let's assume that
all of you work for a company called
evil we agree we're all working for you
and in this particular case were trying
to determine when evil corporate able to
solve this this this possibility so this
metric time of exposure is to
demonstrate the exposure the
organization is vulnerable from 16 is
published today implement the solution
right now so you can see here we go
through the whole deal basically saying
that evil core it only solve this
the next quarterly maintenance window
which happened
Valentin today the following year and so
what's their total exposure for exposure
here
eighty-one days now we're gonna do again
another slight variation and we're gonna
say total time of exposure and this is
the demonstrate the time exposure an
organization from when the issue was
discovered until fully right so we can
see here that metrics quite a bit
different now right now 231 days so
you're starting to see the differences
on this ok that can help you to make
those decisions about what's going on
with this particular vulnerability now
looking at it as just one of our ability
to get to see all the metrics and it's
it's great it may be something that you
say what does that mean to me when you
start looking on the whole for lots of
all abilities to a pic of your product
in this particular products to vendors
starts to paint a picture of how is that
product being handle house then the
response time being there so it starts
to help you understand a larger picture
right and then over time we believe
we're gonna start people see what
averages look alright so here's another
one just to show you a little bit of a
different situation than some of the
stuff can be a little bit challenging so
this is the Seagate SAS code execution
from late last year and so this one was
tricky with of interest the Ravenna
response time just things got a little
crazy but I think this is a perot polio
or for worse than to respond to a vendor
response is this one right and so when
you say the lamest what are the sort of
qualifications for that we can start
using to be temporary work to put in
there some response data and metrics
maybe that also helps right so the
vendor actually responded quickly if you
will but it was ridiculously effective
right they created this two and a half
sort of month the leg and you're not be
able to read this but this is OJ on
Twitter who kept sort of going to
their their support on Twitter and they
kept saying so they didn't support
technical support it kept saying over
and I'll try to see the whole ability
I'm trying to do it securely and it was
just bad right so then eventually over
LinkedIn he gets the right security
power attack and they were able to
acknowledge it but you begin we're
seeing sort of a problem with that right
so you can see sort of the metrics down
below
again it was October 2014 when it was
discovered a few days later as when he
started trying to make the contact and
then there's a new vendor contact and
then all the knowledge you know that in
the next year in July 23 January so that
point I'm talking about eighty three
days to actually get some sort of
response a response from the vendor and
again just for the sake of it we saw a
Chinese some of the calculations again
assuming you will call you know patching
ninety days later you can see sort of
the amount of time and what you can
start to see is that when communication
through vulnerability disclosure and
contacting vendors and those sorts of
things happen to start putting your
organization more at risk for you want
to work with vendors that have to step
down that actually when you contact them
and they have an issue you don't get
stuck around for two and a half months
it's putting more exposure for the right
so
report came out here recently from
Symantec and it's a did you know it
takes forty nine days on average decree
published patches 40 days does anyone
know that that means if you actually
look at the report a little more what
you find is they say the average time
taken between publication and cash and
so many would say well is that we're
talking about 10 that right now I don't
know who agrees and again I can't see
you all but I feel like zero day term
has been so bastardized that if you sort
of all the time right so if you think
about the old school code area 0 day in
many cases it was used to define some
sort of issue that the vendor didn't
know about it wasn't publicly disclosed
I was typically 10 days but now you're
here and all sorts of things where maybe
something goes out public right but it
doesn't have a fixed with it now will
call in those days so it's getting sort
of confusing know what the heck's going
on but you can see you again these are
just some random things pulled from
Wikipedia the likely to see you again
0 day vulnerability refers to the whole
software vendor unknown to the event so
the whole point here is can we finally
with the v10 framework to find what the
hell of a day is right we do have some
dates now that we can talk about and
maybe what we're trying to describe with
zero day or a day there's a couple of
flavors till the pain over getting so
again couple dates that are important
you're right the vendor informed eight
disclosure day again if you're one of
those folks that argues it's actually
about pollution day that it's there as
well right but again if we want to say
hey 80 days when a vendor doesn't know
about it or it hasn't been publicly
described on this chart here you can see
from those two dates at work all day and
then anything after that not only zero
day right so look we can argue the stuff
to death but it would be really nice to
finally sort of with some dates
described we're talking about so we
communicate consistently alright more to
come with the framework right so exploit
availability this is a big one is again
the life cycle changes differently and
when you talk about privatization of all
abilities have been some great calls it
can really and some others have done as
well
exploit availability in many cases
community helluva lot more than a sort
of CDSs or things of that nature right
time of exploit exposure what are you
doing with their and then there's all
these other variations potential to look
at right so even saying total time to
patch but is that really what it was
should be something different should be
when they were introduced to even talk
about some additional metrics enable
call them you know TrueType were true
total time we're talking about when it
was first introduced in the codebase
right we've seen some bugs that have
come out that have been sitting it in
plain sight for twenty years it was
introduced here hasn't been discovered
here so that you can give you some more
clarity on who's looking at these things
what's going on
third-party solutions are they getting
involved and then a whole bunch about
the role of calculations how can we take
one on the whole doesn't give you a
whole lot of information give you a
little bit but when you start to roll up
and understand about that product and it
gives you a lot of course we're gonna
argue their names in the calculations on
this stuff get something out there in a
framework that we can start using
alright so what to talk a little bit
about more about sort of that exposure
analysis and then in order to do it and
I talked about some scattered so stop
electric it's again this particular
honor this is something that near and
dear we know all the dates and so that's
why I was selected a little bit of odd
confusing one but want to share this
with you see how this happens so this
was actually found by Carson I am he's
the chief research officer at my company
so we know all the gory details on this
one but he found a row code issue
and a serial driver which you could say
is a librarian or component for them
right because this one vulnerability was
across 11 of their products so this was
an early 2013 and January reported to us
certain they were the long as it then
start to liaison with the company's time
and again that's one of the dates will
probably gonna add in here is because
there could be a delay time from when
intermedia when you as a researcher
reported to sort of important issues
vendor a bug bounty vendor there may be
a delay we want to make sure we
understand why that is maybe another day
coming here soon so a little bit later
too long twenty days or so
cider confirms the vulnerability and
then a little bit after that a month or
so after that day then publishes
security notification with no patches
they descend something out to their
customers just saying is there's nothing
you can do about it right I see a
certain person going back and forth but
didn't really do anything else nothing
else was published from ICS sir at that
point in April was found earlier this
year
details were then published in the bundy
be in some other things as well they're
already on a daily basis we're picking
it up
alright so great we can calculate all
sorts of metrics in there the beach and
stuff they're all the dates are there
that we need to do that but we want to
focus on a couple things so it wasn't
until April 1st 2014 that's what I see
as provided a warning until that time
from the time it was discovered it was
no c2c sign anyone relying on NBD was in
the dark right and even when that
information then came out last yes sir
it was wrong they were saying was a
local issue which it wasn't right
issue and therefore this CBS scores were
wrong etcetera and what was also really
weird was BC no cash until that time
right and what was really strange about
it there was one developed cider
actually develop the past they just
chose not to release it to customers
they basically said patches there but
we're not include that we do
irrelevant to another version that we're
gonna release so again you start to
think about this there may be a fix for
the issue but your vendors not even let
you get to it so again reminder as well
as Billy was discovered January 5th 2013
ICS April Fools Day imagine that a 2014
release is it that so when we start to
look at some of our calculations you're
saying here the total time the patches
451 days ok now why does this matter is
beat him you know gives these these
metrics of time to passion total time to
patch so they're not saying hey the
products greater it's bad but there
again talking about the vendor
capabilities the response capabilities
to these issues unfortunately right now
not that many information is being
provided we're not sure why right why
does an ICS or provide the stuff we
should be asking that we should be
wanting things as with everything we see
that not all abilities are equal and so
it takes a different amount of time but
in general we're seeing that people
believe hundred eighty Days is probably
reasonably many people believed to be 90
or less we did a quick calculation using
about two year period for some scattered
vulnerabilities 25 vulnerabilities were
analyzed in 14 different vendors on
average that old-time the patch 155 days
with the worst being the one that that
Carson discover 451 why is this
important because when you talk to sort
of any energy or scatter people they
always come up and say things like well
loved her sister Kourtney requirement
that we have to do our thirty days so
yeah we're really good at catching stuff
30 days that's all our exposures but the
reality is when you look at these things
your time of exposure or total time of
exposure is based heavily on your
vendors and they were in their response
is there any so this gives you a
different way to look at things what
you're dealing with a few minutes I'm
gonna go fast believe started having
this talk we had a 25 minute talks a lot
last year at black hat and we had a
bunch of vendors in the audience really
interested parties were slides and so
like I said earlier we were trying to
help people use this data and their
business and put it to use without a
data scientist to the vulnerability data
is out there it's public it's free if
you have a paid annuity feed source
awesome
spreadsheet software you really confuse
with Excel probably around it would be
helpful I that is really all you need to
do all of the vulnerability analysis and
trend analysis that we talked about
earlier so we and where the TOC and
they've got a pretty mature Security
Response and really security assessment
team across the board and they want a
copy of the slides they invited us to
come to their internal security
conference they were talking a lot with
her leadership team about security risk
and they discovered just like I had
discovered when I didn't like her legal
team is your friend
crazy I know your legal team is your
friend because they care a lot about
third-party compliance they want to make
sure they're clean and true with all the
legal agreements so if a developer just
implemented a liar and forgot to
document
your legal team may be able to help you
get funding for things that you need to
monitor that better because you can't
fix something quickly if you don't know
all the places you use it going on I
Easter egg hunt looking for where you've
implemented OpenSSL winners are hardly
it happening you need to know exactly
where it is and so they like i said im
injuries and response team what they did
was they added proactive evaluation and
rating and approval of third-party
libraries to now wants to the library
they have a essentially a dictionary or
a playbook
hear the things that are approved for
use in these situations here things are
approved for use in other situations
that are not approved for use because
we're not gonna take on the security
risk and as I mentioned legal team gave
them funding to implement a source code
scanning tool that would tell them what
library news what they're doing loads
came with it they could really quickly
when that new advisory team now go
figure out exactly where they had to
patch so you don't get a lot of really
great stuff to move the ball downfield
and managing their third party library
risk in terms of partnering with dead
teens active testing you know you can't
just has to your native code if you're
taking on a third-party library it's
yours to have and to hold now so you
need to start contributing back
and actually testing laboratories well
up streaming vulnerabilities to that
library vendor make sure that that that
state securities you're using it quick
action in response we started giving the
stock last year focused on security
response helping Security Response Teams
talk to their development teams about
catching libraries but the reality is
where he's created nine and
implementation of your security
development lifecycle where are they
identified verification and usually in
your response be there for you release
the product and your external security
research community does your solid help
you find out all those long ago he
didn't know you had a third-party
libraries because Boehner abilities are
being identified all the time and so you
could designer application using library
version one point for point six and
designed by the time you get to release
their up to one point four point nine
and he kept up with it
have you been updating your library
during development and changing your
design assumption to go with the new
library because you've got an earful
their duties taxes so that's the first
call to action don't think of library
management as a response issue it's all
trust ya second thing prioritization
matters if you have a hundred and fifty
vulnerabilities over the CDI 7.5 and
above summer intern we found some are
externally reported from finders or
security researchers is there more
commonly referred to some third-party
libraries your abilities but say they're
15 Dec tasks week you even know how many
security
tax you fix week what do you think's 1st
highest median score first in first
class in class but externally know if
you need a clear prioritization model
because intelligent prioritization
reduces your risk in those libraries and
so all of the data with you today the
work we're doing the trikes you create
heat am not just on availability by
vulnerability basis and and he gave his
duties specific examples today but
that's when restarting we need more data
we need more dialogue about how to build
this so that we can take it up to the
vendor level is a on the whole looking
at the body of the liabilities that this
vendor was responsible for years with
their time of exposure is here with
their responsiveness is this is a mature
help your organization or they're kind
of languishing I just like animals and
if they get actively managed service
understand what third party libraries
you're using and where treat those
libraries with as much diligence is your
native code used data go talk to your
leadership team about that larry we just
adopted they had this many
vulnerabilities last year thats X
percent more vulnerabilities and we had
last year with our current dev team how
are we going to do that how we gonna fix
that do we need more resources to we
need to plan our schedules differently
had that conversation to make sure
you're spending resources on the most
important thing
thing and then work with vendors who
care about security I guess that it's
not just about all alone about
responsiveness it's about they clearly
make security a priority
testing through their security
advisories you know what a secure
organization culture of looks like look
for that in your vendors and try to
collect more data on the date metrics
and the more data we can get the better
we can measure these things and please
please please get in touch with us if
you would like to work with us on the
town or if you have feedback about this
talk more about B town we would love to
hear it I just got 20 signs I think
we're gonna have any questions timer be
done done done done