so my name is Tim and Garon
she's in there and this is joint work
Peters ferrets and Martin so as you all
all right so as you all probably know
neural networks are not robust against
the input perturbations so here we have
three very nice images of roads and as
you can see it's probably good idea to
go left here but we have three neural
networks the end of a green and the well
the red one and one of those okay I
didn't press ok and one of those
actually disagrees and tells us to go to
the right and to be fair somebody was a
bit evil here and actually modified
those images so you can see some black
patches and those are responsible for
those misclassifications but of course
we don't want this because as humans we
can see you should go left and there are
many other ways to there are many other
kinds of adversarial attacks on deep
learning models for example you can
actually impersonate someone else in
like by just varying some sort of funky
caucus and also a text that there are
also text that actually are not
perceptible by a human so here we can
have we have an image of a panda bear
and then we add some noise to it and now
the neural net is actually very
confident that this is a given and
there's been a lot of work on attacking
neural networks also some heuristic
defenses that empirically improve
robustness a little bit but there's been
less work on proving that neural
networks actually do what they're
supposed to do in the sense of they
don't behave differently on specific
images if you just change the image a
little bit and in this work we're trying
to address this
okay and we want to prove that there are
no robustness violations around the
specific image and what we want is we
want a system that is automated and
actually scales to real neural nets so
this is the problem statement so we have
a neural network it well it Maps inputs
to outputs some of the outputs are
possible and some of the inputs are
possible those are the inputs that the
attacker can cause by perturbing a
particular image for example and they
have a save set of outputs so this could
be all the outputs that classify to the
same thing and the challenge here is
that xxxx may contain a lot of inputs so
there are many possible attacks and we
need to defend against all of them and
existing solutions based on SMT actually
do not scale to a large network they
work well for small networks but if you
have large neural nets they stop working
and the key inside of this work is that
we can use a I to analyze neural nets
and by a I mean of course abstract
interpretation and who knows about
effort interpretation okay not not a lot
of people imputation is actually about
40 years old which means that maybe it
will become the next big thing soon but
it also means that it had a lot of time
to develop and whatever the invitation
actually isn't it will be the most
technical slide of this talk
okay it's it's a theory for
approximating program behaviors so you
have a program and now we want to say
well what what can this program do and
you're satisfied if somebody tells us
well it can do it mostest
this means the deputy interpretation it
is sound so if it proves something it
holds but it's incomplete it usually
won't prove everything you can and the
ingredients very freaked interpretation
are you have some abstract domain and
each element of the expert domain
represents some set you can think some
geometric shape and you have this gamma
function that tells you which shape it
represents and in FFA transformers that
preserve this approximation property so
if you have something that approximates
a and we take the image through F then
there to transform of F will give us
something whose concretization is an
over approximation to the actual outputs
and after domains have some standard set
of built-in operations about we need or
this meet operator which just intersects
given a certain element with some linear
constraints with a join operator that
combines two effort elements and gives
you back a combination and we have an F
fine transformer which is just an
external form for an affine
transformation so there will be some
more images for example this one so what
this shows is that there are actually
different types of domains one of them
is just the Box domain is illustrated in
blue and this is what standard interval
arithmetic will give you so it will tell
you that the output is somewhere in this
box then in green we have the so no top
abstract domain and so no dope is just
an image of an M dimensional hyper cube
under some affine transformation so it's
some sort of a symmetric polytope and
yes okay can we go backwards Thanks so
we have the polyhedra domain which is
just some convex set and we have four
points here the blue points they are
approximated then we apply some function
and we will get
some other shape and all the four points
will still be in this new shape and this
is fortitude interpretation does so now
what are neural nets and all the
networks are just some compositions of
layers and for us each layer is either a
fully connected layer a convolutional
layer or a max pooling layer and our
goal will be to define a few
transformers for each layer type because
everything imputation is compositional
so if you can do it for two functions
you can do it further composition it may
not be the best way to do it but you can
so this is a high-level illustration of
how everything rotation of neural
networks we have an image of an eight
and this well every pixel it is white
probably you can make it brighter and
you will still get an eight and this
will give you a number of different
images here represented by blue points
which you can over approximate by this
green abstract element and then
everything can you go back thanks
everything beyond that is a neural net
so we have a convolutional layer
followed by max pooling layer four fully
connected layer and they will all
operate on the shape and give you some
auto shape that over approximates the
result so yeah also some red points
those are points that cannot occur in
practice but are included as possible
behaviors by a strict interpretation and
define the property you will check on a4
okay so you will nest usually use this
sort of Rayleigh activation or the model
nonlinear activation function what
really does is just it picks all the
neurons layer and caps them to zero so
if they're negative the activations will
become zero perfect thanks and the
electric transformer therefore just
intersect so it's it's a composition of
n transformers one for each of the
neurons and it just intersects the
effort element with these conditions
that it's smaller than zero or larger
equal to zero if it's more than zero it
will set it to zero using the effect
transformer and this is an illustration
if you have an abstract element and we
split it into two you can see that each
of those two is no approximation to what
it would get if you intersect it
actually with this constraint then we
apply the relevant transformations to
both of them and join them together in
the end to get something that
approximates both branches and for auto
layer types I mean for fully connected
layers is easy so fully connected layers
just an F and transformation followed by
a radioactive ation so we can just use
the FI n transformer which is provided
by the extra domain and follow it with
the railroad transformer then there also
convolutional layers and convolutions
neural networks sometimes convolve a
given layer with some multiple filters
and these filters are actually just
linear functions so we can obtain some
sparse matrix such that this convolution
layers actually equivalent to fully
connect layered and we use the same
approach and we also have next pooling
layers but in the interest of time you
can see in the paper if interested we've
implemented this approach it was
initially based on the apron library now
it's based on alena which is in-house
and about to be observed is that is so
not all abstract domain strikes a good
balance between precision and
scalability so we evaluated our approach
of course so here you can see results on
a convolutional neural network it's a
lot of neurons we showed that the PAC's
domain is fast it's not top domain and
we've also tried polyhedra domain but it
was too slow so it didn't terminate at
all this took place in one hour
but it also results are out-of-date and
now we can do actually a little bit
better than that does in terms of
precision then we've also compared to
existing methods to certify things that
are SMT based methods that actually just
solve a set of constraints and are
complete in theory but of course will
timeout to be a set a timeout of one
hour here and as you can see we loop Lex
shows the sort of very exponential
scaling
whereas with abstract interpretation you
don't see it at early so we have here so
no top domain restaurant of 64 which is
the same as soon at all but you keep up
to 64 different snow tops to get some
more precision and as you can see our
approach actually verifies more than we
do Plex within this time limit of one
hour in the future or actually right now
we're using effort interpretation to
train the neural network we're adding
support for more activation functions so
not just rare lupa does the sigmoid and
10h and we are improving the after
transformers but specializing them to
the abstract domain so everything I've
seen today's are generic they can
actually do better by doing a direct
transformers directly for this on the
tops and you're also deriving data
parallel life certain formers
so to summarize neural networks are not
robust we can use abstract
interpretation to show that for specific
images you cannot get the necessary
perturbations we have defined after
transformers for common layers and our
approach is quite precise and scales so
I will be happy to answer questions also
offline if you like thank you very much
[Applause]
okay we have some time - for some
questions and I'd like to start with
with one question so you said that this
type of analysis is obviously not not
complete so based on your experience
what are some examples where this
approach fails to find the proof well
that they are all in the paper actually
so we have improved approach now and for
some of the benchmarks we can actually
now prove 100 percent of them so so
basically the takeaway is that you can
get more or less precision based on what
your reference for matter I think we
have a question about the evaluation it
shows that it seems only a one year come
loose in your network have you tried
larger networks
this was just an illustrative example
this is not what we evaluated on a lot
of layers we had feed-forward neural
nets with nine layers for example
actually and the convolution lept i
don't remember how many layers you type
but i think like six or something okay
so for the experiment I didn't hear it
clearly so what is that sorry what is
the data set at the data set
very good point so it's eminency for ten
oh thank you
all right then if there are no more
questions then let's thank the speaker
[Applause]