I'm content from some attack today I
will talk about a bazooka angola is this
is a joint work with housing from UC
Davis but in Christ different was to
trigger packs as T fasted quarter
fighting is needed by coverage every
attempt to make father more effective at
at the passive exploration it is
instruments the program's data to track
the branch coverage in the fighting loop
in mutational imposed by heuristics the
mutations is for a new past now father
gives the imported otherwise it's
cut the input so far in baton random
mutation runs fast but I have difficulty
in producing quality in force in
contrast shamanic execution can create
quality imposed by so being passed
constraints in one snow and they can
also many types of constraints efficient
Angola combines the advantages of
fudging ang molix exclusion it's not
only ones fast but I can create a query
quality in boost if efficiently here is
our motivating example the can the
conditional statement in word has two
branch we want to tackle actual branch
of the conditional statement we should
stop the path constraints
most of us constraints depend on of only
only a few paths in the input for
example the conditional statement in red
it influenced pilot input bias from 1024
to 1031 it's
Oh be an unproductive to new tech entire
input and going out and got a determines
which improvise flow into this
conditional statement and new head this
eyes only after determines which include
path to meet head
we need to decide how to new ten men
fighting based on random mutation it
cannot solve this path constraint
efficiently instead Angola me use this
past constraints as a constraint on play
on a black box function and use quality
intestine to solve them during great
query and distant we evaluate the prep
box function over is arguments well some
arguments consist of multiple parts for
example love input bias one 1024 to ten
twenty seven
for example a bite from 1024 1024 to
1027 it's interpreted as an integer type
in this program we ought to consider
these paths as a single arguments it it
it it is not enough to only mutated the
input past some constraints are solved
if only after a longer in the employee
is dongle and a stress harder for
example the function main we not call
function foo no input is too short and
gonna instruments the program is called
that the test along when a longer
improved Mac is pro a new path and that
determines the minimal length they are
first test in angola first Angola used
Angola uses can i they were contracting
to locate which improve ice flow into
low pass constraint then it second it in
follow in lab chef and the type of the
input then it muted mutated today even
for the truth of the path conjoined blow
in fluid is too short and Dorothy Thomas
it minimal length due to time limitation
we only introduce such how we mute
header info by gradient is a nice
presentation we will how to mute error
input who saw past constrain constraint
as such problem fighting based on random
mutation search input without any
guidance
instead we solar constraints using
optimization equations in our in in our
employ implementation we use gradient
descent in our approach when you review
each path constraints as constraints on
a bypass function f of X where X is a
white hole of improved values in the in
footer and this way Lee was flawed in
tulip path constraints f of X is
computation of the past
ronger Peking Opera from the start of
the program to this predicate since the
function is practice we need not
analytical expression also we need to
convert the constraint of log function
through P less or equal in jail because
no God no God grant distance to mean
minimize the function when design is the
iterative method each iteration styles
and improve x8 computer the gradient of
the function
up and after that our input with the
negative direction of low function no
the Equator
imagine ending the goal is to fire
global minima
however in pardon we just need only a
cool enough solution for example in a
figure F of XT is not a global minimum
but but it can't suburb constraint of
that X T less than 0 I will we face we
however we invite him we first election
in Janette
we cannot computer gradient directly
because I will access Apple of X has no
crossed expression there is no
continuous to solve this problem we
applying a numerical approximation as a
equation T Phi we need to run a program
twice as with the original imposed then
we improve with a small inquiry and run
the program again absolute warrants we
can we can computer and the duration of
the relative and the catalog Radian
finally in our implementation for we
instrument the program with a royal win
pass we also extend that applause and
sanitizer which by there were 10
tracking we improved implemented our
fading loop by rust nested we valued we
evaluated Angola in our dataset I was
returning that now I was at having for
producing Guangzhou's coverage that
injured him edit where these tick box in
the program sauce
figures shows the figures just that the
the parks found by the fathers they're
arranging pass the Dinos the misty parks
in our indelible past shows the part
from the park from by Angola Angola fund
most of the parks in our performing all
the other fathers in a large imagine
also Angola file found 103 and these t
parks in our the the allow also injected
the honesty box paddle were unable to
trigger and also we found all the parks
in the first reproach program in only
ten minutes as we evaluate her Angola in
a in a open source program we came past
and go out with with April this Pringle
shows that the night coverage from from
by Gnawa and from by Angola and the FL
the blue path shoulder knife correlative
vampire Angola and the white one shows
the like college found by a burro Angola
Alphonse ever all on each program this
figure shows the community night ecology
on average by Angola and
by Angola in the air we're all in in the
first in first at the first Angola is
worse than ever because and goal at us
10/10 striking after 10 minutes and
gonna found more nice than a drill
because Angola can create equality boost
also Angola want more unique crashes
than ever all because angle I can cover
more pass of local going next we
evaluate our Kittanning gradient descent
we compare gradient descent with random
mutation is figure shows that a gradient
descent pattern can solve more path
constraint has constraints and a below
on all of programs in conclusion we
decide and implemented Angola it has
four key tenants vision pilot Wharton
tracking such algorithm based on
gradient descent in the shape and type
employees and the importance of
exploration since to list Prince
principal Tammy's and goal up brings in
fresh thomas think
[Applause]
sucks
this is BOGO from Penn State so I've got
two questions first quite rates that
since this way parts about children say
so how do
did you try something like model the
ones the observation a dog want and so
it maybe gives you better efficiency
simple innocent so second culture inside
what if your ifx is non different about
say the operations are not numerical
friction so they don't consider this
kind of situations we only implemented
quite the same aquitine in in our in our
implementation also if you are
interested you can implement a color of
my attention is a cuisine with we have
happened compelling now last question is
not squadrons but what did you consider
the situation that affects your life the
functional defines not different of all
so if say the operations are not
numerical operation so maybe in this
situation you cannot use grade innocent
punishing is not is no cameras or
monotone Tomica normative Tomica if we
define a function is hard to use
gradient to solve in multi we have
multiple iterates
iterations we used random mutation okay
let me give an explanation to that a
question
so your program or operations are you
miracle so a strictly speaking none of
them
the f of X is never differentiable
because we're talking about discrete
numbers integers so but we use a
numerical approximation to approximate a
partial derivative and use that to guide
our a mutation that is in which
direction we should mutate the input now
in some cases let's say if you are
trying to match a string then that's not
a value but if you look at the program
when the program compares two strings
the program compares them byte by byte
so now once you have bytes you have a
value now you have a f of X so
eventually all the computations are
based on numerical values so that's why
we can do this approximation so you see
for discrete values approximation to
computer like numerical computing
proximation to computer grading instead
of just used using the itself just
computing with some we always use
numerical approximation because no
analytical form of f of X f of X is a
value computed by the program whose form
we have we don't have okay so so back to
the first question so can we please take
this question offline because we're a
few other people waiting thank you hi
great talk by the way
I'm Johan from Seoul National University
and I just quick to two quick questions
at first you mentioned when you're
finding a certain part of the input
influence the reaches the predicates you
mentioned train taint tracking kg it was
a kind of a movement in how implements a
train tracking we we we were youth that
have loss and sense and that has in
arrow a.m. to ten tracking more detail
the people quite level attained tracking
so for every input byte we're assigning
it a special label and then we keep
track of all of these labels you might
think that oh this is hard
because another space so actually that
we have a tree-like algorithm a data
structure I so do that efficiently so
that's described in detail in our paper
Thanks I'm just a quick question when
you did an evaluation the lava em
dataset you managed to find all the
bones in all the other programs except
for who I think could you give us any
insight in the probative reasons why
that would be the case there are some
conditions there yeah we are in in
difficult we had some difficulty for
example two conditional statements are
nasty or happened there now input I
scroll in Toulon honesty we and if we
you had the improve improvement in will
improve base flow into life predicates
we we can we should at least predicate
because the other condition can
conditional stem and will be will be
first that so so so so this for families
K these cases we can solve them
efficient now so you're saying that if
the two constraints in that state it
yeah yeah all right thanks very much
okay Brendan quick okay gathered from
NYU I was curious if you had tested your
constraint solving directly head-to-head
against an off-the-shelf constraint
solver like XIII and I guess if this is
doing better would you maybe suggest
that like the XIII developers include
this sort of numerical gradient descent
approach in their constraint solving as
well
we haven't tried it so because we have
new analytical forms of our functions so
we can't compare this way however we can
convert in another way so given an
analytical form then we can try both to
see which works better but that's not a
fair comparison because it depends on
the distribution of the types of
constraints
so what you we don't have statistics of
what kinds of constraints appear very
often in the program so we can't do that
easily and also in programs we often
have nested conditional statements so in
what form do they appear in what
distributions do they appear we really
have no statistics of this but that's a
very good suggestion I think that's in
itself is a good research topic thank
you okay now I would like to conclude
the session thanks a lot for being here