okay thanks for attending my talk this
collaboration started with when I
discussed with CEO Li and Danny again
keen and you by how we can mitigate draw
hammer attacks but all in all we just
found another flip in the wall of Roja
Mary defenses so what is wrong about we
already heard that in the in like three
talks ago
it's about DRM and today if we look at
DRM it's organized in channels in banks
and ranks and if you look at one of
those banks in detail you'll find that
this has several rows many rows and
these are the actual capacitors in the
in the rows like 64,000 capacitors we
store the actual bits in your memory and
when you read from memory the marry
controller actually has to load the load
the actual bits into the row buffer that
happens in the DRAM and then it's sent
to the memory controller to the CPU
there's an effect that leads to the so
called row hammer effect which is that
cells leak fast upon proximate excesses
and we're going to exploit that so if
you activate those rolls after a while
you will see if it flips there are
different directions that we can now go
the first is how do we do eviction and
there are a lot of papers going in
different directions here we've just
seen one in earlier talk but there's
also another direction how do we
actually hammer and previously there
have been two techniques known the first
is we have a one row next to a victim
row and other random rows or we have a
two neighboring rows and it looks like
this so if we do single sided hammering
we just hammer a bunch of rows and
expect bit flips next to one of them in
case of double sided hammering we are
hammering two rows and we're expecting
the bit flips for instance between those
two or directly next to one of them the
question then is how to mitigate row
hammer and there have been a bunch of
proposals how we mitigate roarhammer
attacks for instance detecting row
hammer attacks by up
Mormons counters because they have way
more cache misses and cache hits than
other attacks or other benign workloads
also so we can probably single them out
the other idea was another idea was to
detect them before they actually happen
for instance using static analyzers on
the binary and finding that there is
such attack codes there is an of course
an open problem the false positives but
we will see another problem in in a
minute
they have been software based defenses
like envel I'm just picking a few here
and there uses performance counters to
detect to detect which rows are hammered
and then refreshes the neighboring rows
this also is available in hardware in
assembly a variant and it's called
target row refresh there was at using
last year
big head and jig head and there the idea
is to either disable the vulnerable
physical memory locations or to isolate
them so to place some very a physical
barrier between the different security
domains in that paper it was just kernel
and user space but in general you could
do that with more security domains of
course so if we put there all of that
together in a table we see that we have
a lot of defenses that use performance
counters we have a lot of Hardware
modifications I didn't discussed them
and we will also not focus on them
because most of them are not applied yet
on current systems and a few other
aesthetic analyzers physical proximity
memory footprint so also the memory
access pattern plays a role here and the
question one of the core questions when
we started was do you actually have to
hammer multiple memory locations and
that brought us to one location
hammering actually there are at least
three different hammering techniques
because we proposed a third one and
there you only hammer one row and expect
bit flips right next to it works like
this you hammer it you activate it it's
deactivated you activate it again it's
deactivated you activate it and after a
while you see bit flips next to it why
does this work because we heard enough
in the previous talk that there was a
system which used open page policy
probably the idea there is that you keep
the roll open and buffered and then you
have a low latency for subsequent
accesses to the same row but a high
latency for excesses to any other row
but there are thousands of different
rows so this is good if you are pretty
sure that you're going to access the
same row again more efficient if you are
expecting that the next access goes to a
different row is the closed page
policies there you immediately close a
row and are ready to open a new row so
you have a medium latency for accesses
to any row including your the row that
you have just opened before so it's just
a trade-off in this case it has been
found that these perform better on
multi-core systems because there you
have the memory accesses from different
cores and usually they are not so much
related to each other if we look at the
bit flip distribution on a four kilobyte
page you can see that most of the bit
offsets are covered so we ran this test
only for eight hours but basically you
can reach any for bit any bit offset on
a 4 kilobyte page with double sided or
single sided hammering with one location
hammering the number of bit flips is
just lower that's why we only have 32 6
it's a 36 percent of the bit offset
covered after 8 hours the distribution
of 0 to 1 flips and 1 to 0 flips is
approximately the same for all methods
so next question is how do we exploit
random bit flips and we already heard
that in a previous talk they are not
actually random they are highly
reproducible once you have a bit flip
from some memory hammering pattern you
can reproduce it so the strategy is
always the same you choose a data
structure that you can place at an
arbitrary memory location then you scan
for good bit flips and then you place
the data structure there then you
trigger the bit flip again and then you
have your bit flip in the right location
previous defenses suggested that you
could just make the kernel out of reach
right
like the G ket confirmation for that we
came up with some technique called
opcode flipping and with opcode flipping
we found that many applications on your
system run is route for instance pseudo
runs as route because they have to do
some operation that unprivileged users
cannot but unprivileged users can use
those applications for instance pinging
and mount also we target pseudo because
it's easy to exploit it's
straightforward if there's something
wrong in pseudo then we might be route
and to illustrate what happened happens
or might happen in the pseudo binary we
will look at a jump equal instruction
and if we flip a bit in a jump equal
instruction it will change the semantics
of the program and if the right bit
flips it changes the semantics in a way
that you can directly bypass the
password check this is quite unfortunate
let's see whether we can actually have a
bit flip in exactly that location first
we don't need to target exactly that
location we can have a bit flip
somewhere else in a binary as well for
instance comparisons addresses of memory
loads and stores address calculations
there are loads of different
opportunities what you can flip in a
manual analyzes we found 29 possible bit
flip offsets but we think that we should
automate this search for possibly bit
flip offsets but we haven't done that
yet all of these bit flips somehow skip
the password check so somehow we can
become route without knowing the
passport the question now is pseudo well
it's a binary right how do we get the
target virtual page from this binary to
the target physical location where we
can induce the right bit flip and for
that we introduce the technique called
memory waylaying the idea is quite
straightforward basically we want to
maneuver a target binary page to a
vulnerable
Paige and it's not as easy as with page
tables or other pages that we can spray
over the entire memory because binaries
are only once in memory they are kept in
the page cache once they are in the page
cache they will stay there even after
the program terminates the page will
still be there so when is it evicted
only if the page cache is full only if
the entire memory is full and the page
cache has to remove one page to load one
more page into the memory the page cache
usually occupies all the unused memory
so we would have to occupied occupy all
memory to throw out our page however
instead we can also just move the victim
page to a target page by occupying the
memory with other page cache pages so we
are evicting the page cache by filling
it with other page cache pages with that
we can evict the victim binary and we
can use mink or that's a quite
convenient system called for that to
check whether the victim page was
evicted so we just fit load more binary
pages into the system into the DM until
our victim page was evicted and then we
reload the victim and see that it has a
new physical page we continue that with
this until it's on the target page and
then we can induce our bit flip there so
just to illustrate this a bit we start
with maybe a memory layout like this the
blue parts are occupied the white parts
are free and the gray parts are occupied
by the page cache our binary page is
marked as green with a B and our target
page is the X and then we evict the page
cache so our binary page is gone we
reload it we repeat this again and again
until it's located at the right offset
how well does this work well it's first
of all system dependent it depends on
where the operating system which pages
the operating system assigns to your new
page on a default you're going to set up
we got this so most of the physical
memory was
right with that so we were able to
maneuver our page to virtually any
physical memory location the great
advantage over just evicting the memory
with a large array with occupying just
Mary with our own data is that we have a
very negligible memory footprint as you
can see the memory footprint stays very
very low because the page cache pages
are not considered our pages they are
just system pages right and now the
third step that we introduced is we
combine row hammer with SGX and we get
two things out of that the first is
cheap denial of service SGX
is an instruction set in extension and
it provides integrity and
confidentiality for code and data and
untrusted environments you can run it as
a regular user program but you cannot
perform certain things so that you're
not it not able to implement malware in
it right the enclaves use a dedicated
memory area in the physical memory at
the epc region and this is integrity
checked and encrypted what so the
question then is what happens if a bit
flips in this integrity checked region
right and of course the integrity check
will fail what will happen next
we lock up the entire memory controller
which is not a good idea right because
no further memory goes through the
memory controller the system hearts
immediately I don't know think of
backing up some stuff before halting the
entire system yes sounds unsafe it is
unsafe you will lose data if that
happens and we we were able to trigger
that actually the first attacks we
attack implementations we had triggered
that by accident we were not intending
to trigger this in the beginning quite
annoying if your system has all the time
so the next thing is what if we have
what if this happens in the cloud right
if a malicious end clave does that in
the cloud for instance Microsoft now has
an
has an has a cloud that allows you to
use SGX if we trigger that in the cloud
the entire machine house including the
co-located tenants so this is cheap
denial of service attacks in the cloud
and you can do that again and again
every time the system is booted up again
the other option that we can do is we
can combine SGX with mana location
hammering and opcode flipping and build
an undetectable row hammer exploit
because STX protects software from
malicious environments it also protects
it from some attacks like performance
counter based attacks most performance
counters do not work on SJ X in case
they are just not included in in in the
performance counters and this defeats
quite a lot of counter measures that
rely on performance counters putting it
all together we can see that static
analyzes performance counters are both
defeated by using Intel SGX one location
hammering destroys previous assumptions
about the memory access patterns of code
flippin works around the physical
proximity issue and memory waylaying
solves the problem that you have to
acquire a lot of memory and by that
bring your system close to out of memory
situations and by that we have defeated
all the different defense classes with
that I will get to the conclusion and
the conclusion is it's easy to break
previous assumptions and that this is
possible shows that we have an
incomplete understanding of the attacks
we first need to get a complete more
complete understanding of the attack
before we are able to design complete
countermeasures the current counter
measures were only patches against
specific exploit they were not really
solutions to the underlying problems and
as we heard in the previous talk already
it's quite difficult to solve the
problem because in the end it's an
optimization problem on the one side you
want to optimize for performance on the
other side you want to not have roham a
bit flips the pro
that the attacker becomes more and more
powerful so attacks that were once not
possible because the boundary was chosen
wisely might become possible in the near
future and also new features might
introduce new attack vectors especially
the combination of SGX and ro hammer
here allows to change the nature of the
attack quite a bit thanks for your
attention and I'm looking forward to
discussion all right amazing work Daniel
again questions please approach one of
the mics and state your name and
affiliation don't all run at once though
because we don't want to flip any bits
okay and then by design Intel SGX
prohibited like you're reading up the
direct value but there is a side channel
attack on like we can get some of the
performance counter unit value for from
the uncor performance monitor and then
by subtracting some of the values then
we can indirectly know about that what
SGX has performed and did you cuz did
you have any concern on there like it
that kind of the things could rebuild
let the defenders can exploit that
features mmhmm yeah thanks for the
question I actually we looked at quite a
lot of performance counters something
like forty to fifty different
performance counters and including also
the uncor for instance the CBO cache
events and I'm sure there are
performance counters which would work
and which could be used to detect this
attack but we haven't found any but
probably there are there is an abundance
of performance counters I'm not sure
whether this is the right way to solve
this problem because you can induce bit
flips
quite quite quickly in a small amount of
time and also our assumptions that ro
hammer is so the attacks that we've seen
today are still sort of local attacks
right because they have local code
execution but there is an upcoming view
SEC paper that shows that you can do row
inmate X over network thank you yes Matt
Matthew Hicks Virginia Tech so yeah you
mentioned the upcoming you know packet
based network based row hammer tech we
saw earlier you can have sorry system on
chip kind of GPU based other you know
row hammer tax you see in this work a
very systematic destruction of existing
defenses so where are you and you said I
want to start out doing defenses where
is your current mindset your groups of
mindset on defenses now does it have to
be hardware is there any hope for
software where you add on that it's
quite difficult because I think we need
a solution that is also backed by
hardware mechanisms the pure software
solution probably would not work against
the raw hammer problem then this
challenge of deployability comes into
play what about all the systems that
exist how can we provide protection do
you see a way forward and for existing
deployed systems luckily many systems
seem unaffected where many is something
between 30 and 70 percent because we
don't have any good prevalence studies
on row hammer but most systems are
probably unaffected especially by the
more exotic variants like row hammer and
JavaScript I'm not sure about the the
GPU variant because I haven't looked at
the details probably this one is a bit
more realistic but for raw mrj as your
system has to be really really assisted
susceptible for row hammer bit flips
from JavaScript on a
from using the CPU cache a vacation
probably with the GPU it works a bit
better for in general like the the throw
hammer attack that also requires RDMA
most systems today don't have our DMA so
I would expect that most systems today
are not immediate attack targets and not
that much high on a target list of an
attacker also because we have more easy
vectors to get into a system right okay
we got two final questions are nice work
no sjx didn't have in its threat model
either side channels deny your service
attacks but of course if the side
channel does threaten loss of
confidentiality or integrity which is
what SGX is trying to protect the games
then that would be serious but I guess
all you showed was a denial service
attack which is interesting but you
didn't get any loss of confidentiality
or integrity right so for the first
attack we had any niall of service
attack but the second one where we
combine it with opcode flipping and
memory whaling and for this variant we
we actually compromised the system the
integrity the integrity so basically we
we compromised the system we can take
full control of the system not over the
SGX part this will still be protected
yeah the key point that we try to make
here is that if you build SGX in a very
clever way so that you cannot spy on
benign applications you also won't be
able to spy on our row hammering clave
so SGX then also protects our malware
I thought your last comment that we
really must understand the attacks
better before we can hit the
countermeasures I was wondering can you
articulate the fundamental problem in
hardware that causes these broham and
light attacks I think that the the
problem that exists in hardware is known
to the DRM vendors for quite a while now
not the rim I mean broader than dieren
what is the fundament big class of
problems that causes these Hardware
side-channel it takes yeah in general we
always have a trade-off between
optimization in optimization between
performance and security and the problem
in IT security is that we that we don't
optimize towards a physical boundary to
have towards a physical law that exists
that prevents us from optimizing further
but we're optimizing with security I
hope so
with security in mind and the problem
now is that the adversary doesn't stick
to its boundary that we intended for to
exist or that we thought to believe to
exist the adversary pushes the boundary
more towards us and changes what it what
it is allowed to do so our previous
assumptions about what the adversary can
do might be wrong over time and I think
that's a problem we need security
mechanisms that that we can at a later
point adapt so that we can cope with a
stronger adversary later on and so as we
go to the last question I'll just also
answer that there's actually a workshop
that will be happening this summer with
position papers due on June 1 just one
page position papers if you search for
the CCC embedded security workshop not
the Chaos Computer Club but a different
CCC the embedded security works up a lot
of these fundamental questions will be
discussed our final question
yes so Alex can't run from welcome so I
couldn't resist since you set it up so
well Daniel but your point about needing
to you know develop proper long term
mitigations based on real understanding
your attacks so do you feel that the
current disclosure practices adequately
incentivize proper development of
countermeasures over immediate
short-term fixes it's difficult to tell
I think currently there's a lot of
things changing but in general I think
in we we've seen it in other areas bug
bounty programs solve a lot of problems
but or solver they reduce the number of
bugs in products but I'm not sure that
they necessarily improve the software
quality on a long run so the question is
whether we are going the right direction
here in hardware security it's difficult
to predict the future right all right
thank you now we have one oh thanks
first
[Applause]