okay good afternoon everyone I'll be
presenting my work on analyzing the
threat to speech privacy from smartphone
motion sensors so as we all know our
smartphones these days how multiple
sensors and these motion sensors are
used in many applications such as
driving applications gaming image
stabilization in photography and various
health applications so because they're
so widespread there have been multiple
exploits which have been researched that
you utilize the zero permission nature
of these motion sensors to perform
attacks zero permission means that any
application or any web browser web
content can access the output of these
motion sensors without asking for any
explicit user permission and using so
using this vulnerability it has been
found that it's possible to infer the
keystrokes from the virtual keyboard of
the device and using that we can find
what password or PIN has been input
during user entry it's also possible to
find and map user location and driving
route using a combination of gyroscope
accelerometer and magnetometer so
speaking in the context of speech
privacy speech privacy we can say that
it's the leakage of certain speech
characteristics to an an unintended
party such as the leakage of the gender
or the speaker or maybe even the
language and of course the speech
contents themselves might be
confidential as in case of credit card
information social security number the
year of data birth so these are also
confidential information that can be
leased recently research has shown us
that
it's possible that by exploiting
gyroscopes we can recover some of these
speech characteristics and talking about
it in a more benign setting
accelerometer can be used to pick up to
perform to pick up key words from the
speech but it's much more benign
scenario so in the light of the the
recent research in context of speech
privacy threat from motion sensors we
see multiple media articles that
perceive this threat as very very
serious in the sense that these motion
sensors can essentially be turned into
microphones which are constantly
eavesdropping on you like and like a
microphone voice and the reactions to
such news articles have been pretty
reactionary in the sense that people are
thinking that they should not even use
their smartphones however this is not
true the reason why it's not true is
that these motion sensors are pretty
much limited in their capability of
picking up the speech characteristics
because of the limited sampling rate
microphone on the other hand they can
pick up speech signals at very high
sampling rate which is like if you're
talking like CD quality the sampling
rate is around four to four point one
kilohertz but these motion sensors they
are limited by the operating platform to
around especially in the case of Android
it's around 200 Hertz so and that
limitation is put in to minimize the
power consumption so it's not possible
for these motion sensors to act in the
same capacity as the microphones and
that's what we are trying to explore in
this work so we are trying to examine
the threat posed by the this exploit of
motion sensors in the context of speech
privacy and in particular we ask
ourselves these questions that what are
the possible scenarios where these
census can essentially be used against a
person to compromise their speech
privacy in addition we also look towards
what factors that contribute to the
behavior of these motion sensors and
what leads to these motion sensors
capturing this much amount of speech
information and finally the question
that is well most dangerous is are these
motion sensors able to capture a phone
conversation that you are doing so we
build our threat model inspired from
previous works which has an external
loudspeaker as an audio source for the
speech and gyroscope as the motion
sensor and we also but in our work we
add an exit we also consider
accelerometer motion sensor and then we
have the also test multiples scenarios
where we have vehicle speakers because
loudspeakers well they can be pretty
rich and they can output sound at about
90 decibels but we can we also test
laptop speakers phone speakers and human
speakers and as you can see I have
categorized the threat model into audio
source the propagation medium and motion
sensor so moving is so building on that
with the psyche the speech privacy
threat and we explore its reach in
multiple scenarios we perform this
dissection on the basis of these factors
such as audio source propagation medium
and we also consider the loudness level
of the speech so the idea behind that is
that the louder the speech the more
information might be captured by the
motion sensors and we analyze as I said
we analyze the live human speech impact
against motion sensors one point to note
is that we are not trying to create a
new attack technique and we are not
trying to improve the existing attacks
so we divide our speech source into two
categories machine rendered and live
human speech machine rendered audio
sources can be considered like the large
speaker set up the phone speakers they
are different from the live human speech
in the sense that we can fine-tune their
loudness and their richness the
propagation medium is then the
smartphone which contains the motion
sensors and audio source are put on the
same surface and then the other scenario
where they are put on different surface
and of course and then there is air gap
scenario where the speech signal has
only one propagation medium that is true
air the loudness level is normal
conversational which we can consider
below 60 decibels and the loud speech
would be somewhere above that so in
order to assess the threat from these
motion sensors we look for the speech
footprints in both frequency and time
domain to look for a speech footprint in
time domain we look at the maximum range
achieved by these motion sensors in
present speech so the idea behind this
is that if these motion sensors are
capable of picking up speech vibrations
then their sensor readings would be
higher than what they pick up in absence
of any speech or any external vibrations
and in frequency so and then in
frequency domain we transform these
signals from time domain to frequency
domain using fast Fourier
transformations and we plot the power
spectrum and we look for speech
footprints there and we compare these
the behaviors in presence of speech and
an absence of speech to get an idea of
the behavior of these motion sensors so
these are the experimental details we
use a subset of dehydrated corpus which
contains single word pronunciation and
as I said earlier Android platform
limits the sampling rate of the
motion sensors are smartphones to 200
Hertz so as you can see even though
gyroscope and accelerometer have
capability of outputting much higher
sampling rate they are limited by the
operating system we tested these
scenarios which are categorized as
machine rendered speech and then sub
categorized as placed on the same
surface or placed on a different surface
for human speaker we have human speakers
speaking in a normal voice and human
speaker speaking in a loud voice into
their smartphone microphone so for the
results of machine gender speech we the
first scenario is the loud speaker same
surface scenario with the loud speaker
in the smartphone motion sensors are
placed on the same surface and it's a
recreation of an earlier work and if you
could take a look at the freak and the
power spectrum for the gyroscope and the
accelerometer you can see that there is
no noticeable impact on the gyroscope
but there is a noticeable impact on the
accelerometer along the x-axis so we can
say that probably motion sensors will be
affected in this case moving on to the
time domain analysis we have for each of
the speakers speaking each of the word
pronunciation in the TI digital data set
we plot the maximum range achieved by
the motion sensors for that sample along
y-axis and if you see for gyroscope
there are much higher Peaks as compared
to the motion sensor readings taken at
other locations which are in absence of
speech the motion sensor readings which
are taken in presence of speech they are
denoted in blue color while the rest of
the colored lines are for motion sensor
behavior in absence of speech so as I
said for from a gyroscope along y-axis
if you see the there are much more piece
and a more higher than other colors each
times for accelerometer maximum range
the effect is much more prominent if you
see the z-axis figure
the accelerometer readings range in
presence of speeches which is denoted in
blue color is higher while the rest of
the colored lines are pretty much flat
in case when we have the smartphone
speaker placed on a different surface
than the loudspeaker its we see that the
only way it is possible for the speech
signal to reach the smartphone motion
sensors is through the air gap between
the two surfaces so there is no
possibility of any vibrations traveling
across the surface
apart from the ground and we believe
that there might be too much dissipation
across the ground and again if you see
the gyroscope and accelerometer
frequency spectrums we don't see any
effect of pronouncing the one void and
for the motion sensors the time domain
analysis of gyroscope confirms our
findings which we found under frequency
spectrum we can see you some peaks for
the blue lines but we also see Peaks for
the green lines so that behavior is
consistent across the locations which
are in absence of speech and in presence
of speech and if you see the time domain
analysis of extra meter readings they
are pretty much flat line and we don't
see any peaks that indicate any presence
of speech now in the case of laptop
speakers versus motion sensors or I put
on the same surface we tested two models
of laptops and I go here and ThinkPad
and we saw that the MacBook Air was able
to perform able to generate much louder
speed signal as compared to ThinkPad so
we used MacBook Air as our inner test
and our initial observation with a
multi-tone signal was that we found very
minimal effect on the accelerometer and
we found no noticeable effect on
gyroscopes and I do mean to figure there
is like within those circles there is
some impact on them for the multi-tone
signal but it's very faint and that's
normal because laptop speakers are very
much like
low in loudness when compared to
external loudspeakers there were other
scenarios that we created which were
like laptop speakers and motion sensor
placed on different surface but again
since we saw that it on the same surface
it's much diminished response on
different surface it would be even more
that will diminish it would be even more
diminished so we don't think it would be
impacting the motion sensors to a
considerable degree and if you use phone
speakers in our testing scenario they
are even less loud than the laptop
speakers moving on to the human speakers
we recruited 10 participants and they
asked them to speak into the microphone
of a smartphone placed on the table and
but we asked them not to touch the
smartphone so as to confirm that the
only impact on their smartphone motion
sensors should be from the speech from
their mouth to the microphone of the
smartphone
and possibly to the motion sensors and
the frequency domain analysis shows us
that we don't see any presence of speech
in both gyroscope and accelerometer
sensors along all the three axis the
time domain analysis of for the normal
voice which is as I said less than 60
decibels we don't see any difference in
behavior of gyroscopes in presence and
in absence of speech again I want to
remind you that in presence of speech
it's the blue line and do all the other
colored lines are in absence of speech
same behavior was observed for the
accelerometer readings we went to the
loud wife scenario where the speech
signal is more than 60 decibels our
results remain the same for both the
frequency domain and time domain
analysis of gyroscope and accelerometer
there is one lone peak out there along
the axis but that's probably an
aberration due to the inconsistent
behavior of the user probably touching
the smartphone or
you know it's so summarizing our results
when we tested the loudspeakers same
surface we saw that there was some
effect on gyroscope and accelerometer
was definitely impacted for loudspeaker
different surface scenario we didn't see
any noticeable effect on both the motion
sensors for the laptop same surface
scenario there was minimal effect on
accelerometer so it may be possible for
the accelerometer to get affected but
for the rest of the scenarios we did not
see any effect on the motion sensors
from the speech source so the insights
from over are that it seems that human
speech may be incapable of triggering
the motion sensors especially when you
are just talking into the microphone of
the smartphone does the name speechless
and the motion sensors may be able to
pick up those speech characteristics and
certain restricted settings but that may
be mostly due to the vibrations which
are traveling from the loudspeaker
across the surface to this smartphone so
it's not that the speech signal is
traveling through air and impacting the
motion sensors rather it is speech the
audio source is generating vibrations on
the shared surface and the motion sensor
sensors are picking up those vibrations
and we categorized it into three factors
the audio source propagation medium and
loudness and we believe that all three
sources all three factors have impacted
this are responsible for the motion
sensor behavior that we observed and one
other observation was that the
accelerometer seems to be more sensitive
more sensitive towards picking up this
speech vibrations than gyroscopes in
future work we can look towards
measuring these surface vibrations and
so that we can collaborate we can
correlate those surface vibrations with
the sensor response that we see and we
can use devices such as laser Doppler
vibrometer which measure the surface
vibrations
since a vision may achieve a better
response and what we have seen and of
course increased sampling rate which can
be obtained in a relaxed model where the
attacker has the capability of
overriding the limit imposed by the
operating system and when such teamwork
has already been done we're in using
embedded motion sensors having higher
sampling rate and using sensor fusion
they were able to reconstruct speeds so
it's definitely possible and these are
not the only scenarios that we can
create there are other scenarios that we
have not explored
we could also extend so so far we have
only discussed smartphone motion sensors
but with all the small devices and smart
variables we can of course look into a
speech privacy threat from that angle
thank you for listening and I'm open to
any questions we have time for like two
quick questions remember when you ask a
question please state your name and
affiliation along with it thank you hi
I'm cholesky formerly Stanford now a
start-up so I'm actually doing one of
the authors of one I have actually a
couple of questions so one of them is
why didn't you run the actual machine
learning algorithms on the recordings to
see if it results so as I said earlier
we were not looking to actually see to
what extent it is possible to extract
the speech information so so because
when you say running those machine
learning experiments they would be
actually looking at - what accuracy are
you able to perform speaker
classification and stuff like that but
we were just looking at the so we were
looking at a more basic question as in
are we picking up speed signals which
are traveling through here or are we
picking up surface vibrations see
because in our factor actually we didn't
make any claim whether it's through
progression on anything else I can't
share that in some of the recordings we
made I was just holding the phone next
to the speakers of the words and a
mutual surface and
comment about the papers basically
regarding the recording with the
subwoofer so actually the data said that
we published on our website the
recordings were not done with with a
subwoofer
those were pretty strong speakers
obviously a pretty pretty high DBS but
without a subwoofer so I would speculate
against the claim that the really low
frequencies are responsible for picking
up some speech and I would put the size
it's rather the alias of aliases of the
higher frequencies yeah it's but that's
true that of course because of the
sampling rate limit right it's up since
this limit is in like 200 Hertz you can
only pick up frequency characteristics
which are below hundred Hertz but if
it's a very loud so before as you said
right no no the unfortunately we're out
of time so let's all think abhishek for
a great presentation