thanks Austin hello everyone my name is
Eric and in this talk I'm going to tell
you about a new phenomenon that is
called a citizen developer I will tell
you how the citizen developer creates
apps by use of so called online app
generators let me tell you how it is
generated apps affect security and
privacy and the mobile ecosystem but
first things first what is the citizen
developer so citizen developers are
persons of developers with little or no
software engineering background now you
could ask why should such a person
develop software in the first place well
this term was coined during the
evolution of the web development now
basically in the early days only experts
could write websites now today with an
increasing demand for websites literally
everybody can create a fancy website
they can do this by use of so-called web
builders like WordPress or Weebly
this method is abstract from technical
aspects and require you only to provide
content you have to choose layout or
design and press the publish button
that's it and now we are facing a
similar trend and mobile domain so
there's an increasing need for apps so
for instance more companies that cannot
afford in-house development you have
club sports event organizers and also
individual persons that have no IT
background at all so in contrast to the
web those mobile app builders have to
account for different mobile ecosystems
like Android iOS Windows Mobile and
equivalent to those web builders for
citizen developers our online app
generators so they provide the mossad
like point-and-click map interface which
you can use to compose apps by use of
so-called predefined software modules
and the key aspect here is that you must
not write a single line of code to show
you how this looks like this is the web
interface for the generator app machine
so you have a preview of the app on the
right side you have your design space in
the middle on the left you have two
selected modules that are shown here as
legal plots so you can add
plox this that come with predefined
functionality so you can integrate video
you can increase social media RSS feeds
web views and so on and these up
generators literally allow you to create
apps within minutes so the first
question that came into our mind was
okay is this really a new phenomenon and
mobile domain or was it already an
established phenomenon so it's already
kind of a market penetration so we
wanted to find that out and to that end
people the classifier that takes an
Android app extract some high-level
characteristics like package name code
name space included files and also
extracts information from the signing
certificate and you see this classifier
the basically could map apps back to
their generating service so we applied
our classifier to Google Play app
repository that had about 2.3 million
apps and what we found was that already
250,000 apps are generated by these
online actions in other words more than
11% of the entire App Store of the
Google Play app store is generated by
developers that have never written a
single line of code so there are few
more popular app generators so the top
five that we found account for about
three-quarters of all generated apps and
what you could sing okay if you use
these online app chants basically the
outcome will be a very simplistic app
then you are absolutely right you cannot
recreate Facebook after such a service
but you can do create very popular apps
so we found different apps of different
options that already had one more than 1
million downloads so for instance
Virtual DJ apps a nightlife app so it
could already see that there's a real
large market penetration but what we
don't know is how do these app chance
generate their code so if you don't have
to generate the code they have to so we
wanted to find out what is the app
generation model and if we find that out
are there specific securities
related to this generation model so to
date and refer together the data set so
we subscribe to the top 13 on an app
generators according to our market
analysis seven of them were free six for
which we had to pay a monthly
subscription fees and we generated the
exact same three apps for each option to
get kind of a crown troost so the first
one was a classical had a word app so
the smallest app that we could possibly
generate the second app basically was
app one with an additional web request
to our server nap three was with me
again at one with motif or user login or
form to submit user data so sensitive
operation we additionally then took ten
random apps per option and then we could
basically start off our analysis what I
haven't told you so far is that we
stumbled across the topic a bit
differently than what I've told you at
the very beginning so we regularly
conduct different security analysis on
our app repository and what we found was
that there are large clusters of apps
that show the exact same results
typically sign for spam apps but as we
got to know these were generated by the
online services so the first idea was
okay there's probably some kind of code
we use involved so let's measure the
similarity of Pyatt code of different
apps generated by the same service and
to the end we adopted a technique that
we use to detect the party libraries in
apps that as we generated hash tree
so-called Merkle trees over the class
hierarchy that we could extract from the
bytecode and then the result is
basically American 3d but you can see on
the right
it's an hierarchical tree let's give you
three layers of package class and a
method layer and that is because Android
apps are written in Java on Kotlin and
this code is organized in hierarchical
namespaces and these namespaces are
preserved in the binary so we can
exploit that fact pass and extract those
namespaces then great sartre marquetry
we then compare the code hash to root
hash of different files we can check
whether the bytecode is exactly the same
and if it differs we can compute a
package based similarity to measure the
extent of the code reuse the surprising
result is that there are only two online
app generators that use module dependent
code boilerplate code that means they
reuse the exact same code for the same
module but they only generate code for
the modules that have been selected by
the citizen developer and this is in
contrast to all the other 11 online app
chants that use monolithic boilerplate
code this is say your option provides
100 modules and then they will basically
generate the code for all 100 materials
no matter which modules have been
selected by the app developer and these
apps only differ in one config file and
one almighty config file so that caught
our interest so we take the bit deeper
to check how this config file is
included so the Scala files to begin XML
or chase it fire there are two ways to
include them one is a static config
which basically means yeah you included
in the application binary and for the
dynamic config it is dynamically
retrieved from remote server now as you
can imagine if you include it's directly
in play without encryption integrity
checks that's not a good idea but even
worse if you dynamically retrieve it
from remote server in HTTP and without
encryption whatsoever this really opens
the door for some severe attacks and I
will show you one of them but that we
called an app reconfiguration attack so
say you have an app X installed that was
generated by some service now upon
launch it will basically retrieve the
contract from the remote server via HTTP
then initialize the modules and then
it's ready to go but so far you can
basically predict but what can possibly
go wrong here so first of all if you
under network you can read the config
file the data the content of the config
file and it does not only include the
module configuration let us include all
kinds of sensitive data like API crypto
key
credentials even information personal
information apparent the citizen
developer that created the app but even
worse you can also temper this the
config file can change any kind of data
strings API keys you can change the API
key for advertisement libraries conduct
code at revenue shaft you can also
change resources and you can change URLs
so imagine you create an event app say
for some security conference and you
include the back view pointing to I
probably security talk now we can on the
fly change it to something like ìwe
secure security dot-org so easy fishing
there you go without having to touch the
app at all but that's the name suggests
you can even tamper with the code logic
so you can reconfigure the app on the
fly you can change the set of enabled
modules their connection pretty much
everything without having to modify the
application code the root cause why this
works is this monolithic boilerplate
code generation this conflict that is
retrieved from some remote button plane
so we also wanted to find out what is
the code quality in general regarding
security privacy to the end we
implemented common attack vectors from
the literature and what we found was a
long list of security issues I wouldn't
say that these results are burst and for
apps from an average developer but what
makes it problematic is the
amplification effect
so all those identified issues will be
an every generated app of the same
object now if you have a look at the two
module dependent code generators we see
that they perform much better so they
have less problems was known at hack
vector so that is because they follow
the principle of least privilege they
only generate code for those modules
that have been selected and we assume
that they also are more willing to
adhere to security and privacy best
practices now I will give you one more
case why just wanna lay the boilerplate
code
problematic and add us if you generate
code for all modules that you can
possibly include then by definition you
have over privileged apps so you have to
declare all the permissions necessary to
run any clue any code that was included
in the application and then our analysis
does range between seven and twenty one
permissions now if you include
additional advertisement or tracking
libraries this becomes a privacy
nightmare because past incidents have
shown that especially those kinds of
libraries are stealthily Pro for
permissions of the host app and if the
permission is available the extra
sensitive data and exfiltrated to some
remote services we had one particularly
worrisome record of one on an app
generator that included different
tracking libraries that combined issued
more than 250 web requests within the
first five minutes of execution finally
we also checked interest for
infrastructure attacks because a lot of
options may be we bind our customers to
their back-end servers for instance if
you have modules for user log ends or
forms to submit user data so we check
the backend servers against available
online as analyzers and we found that
only three of these services had a valid
and trusted server certificate and all
of them run outdated versions of as a
libraries that are prone to one or more
recent attacks like poodle beast free
clock jam and so on one of them was even
prone to any of these attacks so by now
you should have the impression that code
generation is a bad idea but this is
only partially true I think the main
problem is this monolithic boilerplate
code generation if you've managed to get
rid of it and move to module dependent
code generation this will improve our
security of privacy of the ecosystem
significantly and one way to do so is
Epidaurus ation and there are basically
two concepts available that allow you to
do this now the first one is Android app
bundle so
idea is to split functionality of your
app and core functionality an optional
functionality that can be installed on
demand the second one is instant apps so
basically allows users to preview your
app or parts of your app without having
to install it and the nice thing is
there there's no strong IDE support
development SDK is available to support
developers in achieving this task so
takeaways from this talk we have seen
different pitfalls of this
one-size-fits-all app generation that
typically is this monolithic boilerplate
code generation
I think AB modernization is key to
remove large clusters of attack vectors
so for instance when we move to module
dependent code generation we can follow
the principle of least privilege which
significantly reduces the attack surface
and I was strong too and I did support
us there are really no more excuses why
such an option can't do this I let me
conclude with a question where app
generators are here to stay
I would say definitely yes because there
will be an increase in demand for apps
especially from one IT people but
recently Apple had removed these
template apps from the iOS App Store
they intentionally marked them as spam
apps while I could partially follow the
argumentation saying ok these apps are
amplification of security and privacy
issue I would still say that this is the
right this is not the right approach I
think we should turn that argument
around and say ok if we manage to have
those few companies to make their
product more secure and this would be a
positive amplification factor for
security and privacy and still there are
tools for non IT people for citizen
developers to create apps was that
thanks you for your attention
[Applause]
so yeah please state your name and
affiliation - my name is Maksim with the
University of Arizona I'm wondering if
you saw examples where app developers
whether intentionally or otherwise we're
pushing out updates via these config
files which to me kind of sound like
firmware and if so whether or not that
would be a violation of the Terms of
Service for developers on the Play Store
and the iOS App Store since you are
supposed to push updates
programmatically through those doors
yeah but they don't change the code I
mean they only change which code is
enabled so it's only like your update
and config file so actually the app the
code and the Play Store is always the
same so there won't be an update and it
also differs from option to app chance
some options also publish for you while
others say okay we just generate and you
have to push the update so if you change
something this your app then basically
you have also to push the update and it
depends whether you have monolithic
boilerplate code then the app code is
always exactly the same no matter which
configurations you chose if you have
this module dependent configuration then
all it really changes so your published
app lets me changes you have to upload
it again but it would say it's Greyson
especially for those monolithic
boilerplate code generators okay I mean
that would still be a contradiction I
know of the iOS App Store terms because
even if you update like just an image
asset you have to do it through an
update to the app you know it's a static
asset but I guess it was not the main
reason by the band ourselves maybe a
contributing reason but the main reason
was basically okay those low quality
apps security and privacy issues hi
Eric Penn State do you think that
androids new stance of requesting
permissions at the time they were used
instead of installation is some of
mitigating the effect of the over
privilege of the monolithic app I don't
think so because I mean it's basically
dead code so it's doing it's just
included but you as an attacker can
enable it but you can also attack
certain things for instance it can be a
content provider that leaks internal
data and it's not protected by a
permission and I think I can just attack
this component without the user noticing
it of course if it's somehow protected
with permissions and it has runtime
permission not all of them already
adopted runtime permissions then at
least the user has shown some warning or
request
thanks Robert from Idaho National
Laboratory did you do any analysis of
the percentage of applications that were
malicious or were spam or anything like
that from the generators I don't think
that you can generate Malafaia bestowed
services because basically there's no
predefined what you're called now we're
in terms of functionality that like not
spyware but just something that a try
can speak something that a user might
not want so just using the generators as
a vehicle for sending spam or something
to that effect it depends on the
implementation of those modules so we
didn't see any difference between free
and paid apps that we would say ok the
paid apps are free of advertisement and
tracking but they are not and I don't
think they intentionally generate
malware it's basically they use some
libraries to build some functionality
tracking advertisement and of
these components leak then basically
it'll be an amplification factor and
maybe each app will read the data
Thanks okay thank you Eric