okay good morning thanks Nikita
I am excited to be here today to talk
about some recent work we've been doing
in tracking certificate magicians in the
wild this work is done in a large
collaboration with the University of
Illinois the University of Michigan and
Stanford University so HTTP relies on a
supporting public key infrastructure
that is composed of hundreds of
certificate authorities and these
certificate authorities by and large
have one main task to verify the
identities of websites and to issue for
those websites a digital certificate the
way HTTPS is built any trusted
certificate authority has the power to
sign a certificate for any domain on the
Internet and in the last ten years we've
seen a number of instances where these
certificate authorities have failed to
do this job correctly you might remember
the Turk trust example from late 2012
where Turk trust was caught Miss issuing
a certificate for star google.com that
was undetected for fifteen months but
what you might not know is that there's
a broader class of Miss assurance that
goes beyond simply you shouldn't have
signed this for Google in fact there are
a number of strict technical rules that
are associated with constructing
certificates these are called the sea a
browser forum baseline requirements as
its name suggests the sea a browser
forum is a large consortium of CAS and
browsers major browser vendors and they
come together to ratify the BRS which
are the set of rules that a CA must
follow to maintain browser trust in the
ecosystem and in the last few years
browsers and the web PKI community at
large have focused on how well CAS are
adhering to the rules unfortunately
there's a lot of anecdotal evidence that
suggests that CA is just aren't keeping
with it if you look on Mozilla dev
security policy mdsp
a public google group where a lot of
this discussion happens you'll find
posts that look like this or like this
or like any of these and it's easy now
to take a step back and to look at some
of these instances and this issuance and
think oh nobody cares some certificate
authority swapped a URL for a domain
name and some certificate fields and
assistant security related you know why
should we care
well the web PKI community actually
cares a lot they view adherence to these
rules not only as core to the
trustworthiness of a CA
but also that it served as a proxy for
how well a CA does their job more
broadly and kind of inspired by this
insight as well as the anecdotal
evidence we observed online we set out
to systematically analyze the
certificate miss issuance ecosystem in
this study and to that end we build
Zealand an x.509 certificate winter so
the core idea of Zealand is very simple
there are two code books you've got to
follow if you're a CA and you're
constructing certificate certificates
this is RFC 50 to 80 and the BRS what
Xiwen does is it takes all of the
technical clauses in these documents so
clauses that look like certificates must
be of type X 5 or 9 v 3 or the subject
key identifier extension should be
included in all and entity certificates
and puts them into a program that takes
as input a certificate and outputs
anything that's wrong with your
certificate Zeeland is written in go
contains 220 links that span both the
BRS and 50 to 80 we have 95% coverage of
these certificate related causes in the
BRS and 90% coverage of the certificate
related clauses in RFC 5280 the only
reason we don't have 100% is because
there are some clauses given just a
certificate that we can't test in
isolation for example online domain
ownership checks in this particular
study we're focused primarily on
certificate construction for each of
these Lintz zealand will encode a
severity level that corresponds to
different kinds of clauses so if you are
in violation of a must clause zealand
will return an error if your certificate
is not of type x.509 v3 zealand returns
an error for this particular lint
conversely violations of should clauses
are warnings so if your end entity
certificate does not contain the subject
key identify our extension zealand will
return a warning in the context of this
talk an error a violation of a must
clause or an error is considered an
example of miss issuance so we have a
system now we can go and answer our
first question now how prevalent is
certificate miss issuance to do that
we're an zealand over all the
certificates in census through july 2017
census has been aggregating certificates
through internet wide scans over the
last few years and recently incorporated
all certificates in known certificate
transparency
and in particular we were interested in
the certificates that were browser
trusted and what we mean by that is that
they changed to a trusted root in the
NSS root store which is used by Mozilla
Firefox in total we ran Zeeland over 61
million non expired certificates and 171
million total certificates that were
browser trusted at some point in time
okay so what did we find
well it turns out certificate
authorities have not always been great
at adhering to the rules in 2009 and
2010 upwards of 20% of all the
certificates in the ecosystem were in
violation of some rule in RFC 5280 and
by the time that the baseline
requirements came out we'd seen some
progress on this front we moved from 20%
miss issuance to about 10% miss issuance
but you know still a long way to go in
mid-2013
certificate transparency was released
which as the name suggests is an effort
to enable the transparency in the
certificate ecosystem and in light of
this mdsp discussions on this topic
started to increase in 2014 you have
this great public data set now
certificates that are actually issued by
certificate authorities we can actually
go and check whether or not people are
adhering to the rules and this kind of
takes us all the way to where we are
today which in 2017 at the time of our
study only 0.02 percent of certificates
that were browser trusted were missing
or violated some rule and I want to
pause and say that this is a good result
for the web PKI community I mean I can't
prove causality of any one event or one
effort but it definitely appears that
certificate authorities are starting to
take adherence to these rules seriously
but in late 2016 and early 2017 we see
something quite interesting which is
that low sign and semantics too large
certificate authorities that issue more
than a hundred thousand certificates are
slated to be distrusted by browsers now
both of these cases are complex and
there's a lot of moving parts that go
into this but one of the reasons
browsers cite as a reason to distrust
these two certificate authorities is
long term certificate Mis assurance and
indeed if you take a look at their
missions rates compared to the rest of
the ecosystem at the time that they are
slated to be distrusted low sign and
semantics are miss issuing at a rate two
to eight times worse than the rest of
the trusted ecosystem and it's not just
their rates that are a problem
if you take a look at the largest miss
issuers so these are the CAS that pump
the most raw number of bad certificates
into the ecosystem four out of the top
five are some way related to well sign
and semantics the only exception here is
GoDaddy which actually is kind of an
interesting case 99% of these
certificates issued an error in our data
set here were issued in late 2012 and
early 2013 and after fixing whatever
problem GoDaddy had in their in their
pipeline they never made another
instance of Mis issuance in the same way
so if you exclude these GoDaddy has a
near 0% miss issuance rate but what
we're observing here is that browsers
are taking down the largest offenders
and as just like a engineering decision
this totally makes sense right we have a
problem the problem is certificate miss
issuance let's find the people that are
making the biggest stink and get rid of
them so it is easy to take a look at
this graph and kind of sit back and pat
ourselves on the back and say good job
we're done certificate miss assurance is
decreasing to near zero percent in 2017
and browsers are not afraid to be taking
down large certificate authorities so
what's next well as it turns out looking
at aggregate miss issuance can be
somewhat misleading and if we dig a
little bit deeper you can actually start
to see why miss issuance has been
decreasing over time so to show that we
can take a look at the mrs. Xuan spy the
largest issuers in our data set
so what I'm showing you here our
certificate authorities that have issued
more than a million certificates the
first thing I want to call out is that
the top seven certificate authority is
account for 93% of all browser trusted
certificates in the ecosystem this is
not new but if you take a look at their
mrs. Xuan rates they are all pretty good
in one particularly stellar example
let's encrypt who issued 37 million
certificates in our data set issued only
13 with errors for a mrs. Xuan srate of
zero percent and so what we're observing
here is that large CAS are miss issuing
only a small fraction of their
certificates and so overall this is good
you know the folks that are pumping out
a lot of certificates are pumping out
good certificates but this also masks
some of the underlying problems in the
ecosystem so let me show you what I mean
so
what I'm showing you here is a tree map
of all of the certificate authorities in
our data set each box corresponds to one
certificate authority and the size of
each box corresponds to the number of
certificates that each certificate
authority issued on log scale as you
move from dark green to dark red you are
missing a larger fraction of your
certificates and what we see in our data
is somewhat alarming large certificate
authorities are doing a pretty good job
they're pretty green but a number of
small certificate authorities a large
number of small certificate authorities
are missing a large fraction of their
certificates and so what we're
uncovering here again is that there is a
problem with small CAS browsers are
taking action against big obvious
players but small problematic CAS are
kind of hiding in obscurity I want to
mention that there is movement on this
front Pro cert being a notable counter
example so in our dataset Pro cert
issued 39 certificates total with a 100%
miss issuance rate and at the end of
2017 Mozilla Firefox actually said okay
we've had enough Pro cert in future
versions of Firefox we're not going to
keep you trusted in the root Store and
we argue that if Pro cert is getting the
boot then there's at least 17 others
that should go and a whole number of
other people that need to be
investigated there are at least 17
others in our data set that have Mis
issued all of their certificates so I
want to change gears here a little bit
and and go back to the quote I put up at
the beginning of the talk and in
particular I want to call out this
particular clause which is that
technical rules are but a proxy for
procedure rules this kind of got us
thinking about another question
regarding certificate miss issuance
which is now in certificate miss
issuance correlated with other kinds of
mismanagement that a certificate
authority can do so what I mean by this
is you know in the BRS there are a
number of things that aren't related
just related related to certificates but
a number of these things I can't test
for example I can't tell you if a
certificate authority is has the proper
protections in place to keep their
keying materials safe and secure but
there is something I can test and this
is how LS CA handles revocation so there
are two systems that a CA are
responsible for
in terms of revocation these are OCSP
responders that support online
certificate status protocol this is
mandatory by the be ours and CR ELLs are
certificate revocation lists
distribution points these are optional
by the BRS but if you run any one of
these systems there are strict rules
associated with their revocation service
response times that is if I issue a
valid request to one of these services
you must respond within 10 seconds or
you're in violation of the BRS and this
is something that I can measure so what
we did is we made a valid OCSP and CRO
request to all responders every hour
from September 1st through September
20th 2017 and what we observe is that
most responders are pretty good they
follow the 10-second rule but of course
there's a long tail in the worst case 53
OCSP responders took longer than 10
seconds to respond and to only to crl
distribution points in the worst case
took longer than 10 seconds to respond
so the question that's on our mind are
these events correlated well what we
find is kind of very weakly correlated
with statistical significance and so
what we're observing here is that you
know this does lend some credence to the
idea that misses Xuan's can serve as a
proxy for at least how well as CA
manages revocation but it's a weak
correlation and it's a little bit a too
weak to be making such a strong claim
okay so z lint is open source the code
is available here in the certificates
are available through census we're
really excited that sealant is deployed
so it's deployed in both certain SH and
census these are two tools that the
certificate or the web PKI community
uses to investigate certificates and
what we're especially excited about is
that sealant will be deployed so we've
gotten word from a number of certificate
authorities that they're planning
including Google that they're planning
to deploy sealant in their issuance
pipeline to ensure that before they put
a certificate out in the wild that
they'll run Zeeland to make sure that
it's not miss issued ok so moving
forward what's gonna happen the PKI
community has already started to use
sealant to focus removal investigations
you can go on mdsp today and do a quick
search for zealand you'll find people
using sealant and saying hey the
certificates miss issued this
certificate authority needs to be
investigated but we really need to start
considering if small regularly offending
certificate authorities are worth our
trust I mean to this point we've had a
lot of fear uncertainty and doubt and
anecdotal evidence that's a small
certificate authorities kind of have a
lot of disproportionate power in the
ecosystem but now we have data that
suggests that a lot of these certificate
authorities don't have the proper
protections in place haven't written the
right code to follow the rules and so we
really need to consider if they are they
should remain in the ecosystem Zeeland
enables the monitoring of the
certificate miss issuance ecosystem but
there are a number of other things that
certificate authorities are responsible
for in this study we focused on
revocation but you know you might
imagine a new BR that came out last
September called CAA records which are a
particular type of DNS record a
certificate authority needs to check and
we still need tools to measure other
forms of this management to make sure
that CAS are adhering to not just
certificate related rules but all of the
rules that they are said that are set
out for them and finally you know this
is kind of like a call to arms this
needs to go beyond a research paper
beyond one system as new rules are
ratified we need to be watching we need
to make sure that certificate
authorities are keeping up with the
responsibility to us and to the web on
maintaining trust in the ecosystem so
with that I am done and thank you for
your attention I'm happy to take any
questions now
I haven't talked from Cisco thanks for
the very interesting talk
and I was wondering so you said that so
this this er they say that well mrs.
Hughes already happens if there's some
formatting errors like domains versus
URLs and can you give me an intuition of
how security critical these things might
be or like a concrete example we could
not be kind of obviously security
critical actually yeah so you might
think so yeah like you mentioned the BRS
span anything from you know you didn't
include this field to your using sha-1
as your algorithm and we've sunset shot
one a long time ago one example that I
think is interesting is the most common
example of missions is actually when the
subject common name is not included in
the subject alternate name extension and
clients have to rely on well when
they're doing hosting validation have to
rely on either the subject alternate
name extension or the common name and if
there's a mismatch there then you can
actually have some problems in in
hosting validation and they could also
lead to interoperability problems in
getting clients that you know are kind
of following the protocol so that's kind
of one example of where this could be
security related to the rhodamine turist
University of Maryland I have a related
question so did you look at whether some
of these fields are correlated with
historical incidents where CAS or CAS
issued certificates for the wrong entity
yeah we didn't look at that we looked at
primarily the in the last year we saw
three big instances of you know revoking
trust in particular certificate
authorities that's what we focused on
but we have the data so if it's
interesting we could probably line
everything up and having to talk offline
yeah a WCPO delft and i was wondering
whether you could make any qualitative
statement on whether or not formal
assurance but actually issuing from
happened sorry could you so if I
understood your contribution correctly
you're looking at formal violations yeah
can you also make a statement on like
semantic violations like issuing a
certificate for a domain they should not
have been a certificate issued for oh no
in Britain no particularly we're looking
at certificate construction in this
study yeah okay thank you all right
there's no more questions