about them when I be possible feedback
zillion times but he says a concise
feedback for site feedback comments
feedback and they give you a specific
sessions feedback on schedule click on
the sessions feedback feedback survey
link on the beginning session again we
have won the raffle coming up $100
Amazon gift card courtesy of Gemalto to
make sure you can infer that there's
also some t-shirts I think there's some
seizure / so friendly to go grab one if
you can find one in your size
otherwise this is getting ever ongoing
speak on ABC reports and speculation
about how you doing today so you're
enjoying these aren't the droids ok so
originally this was supposed to be an
hour ago CCC and then it was pushed down
thirty minutes at Kaspersky sauce and
now has 25 minutes something to keep the
introductions ungodly and usually do
this within Baras gets a lot of credit
for me and we just started so the clock
now the talk is obvious the apt reports
of evolution or as we like to call it
these are you looking for and the reason
for that is we think that most if not
very many of the more sedate simply so I
can use this num which I'm not saying
that but that environment right now many
of them are good many of them and we
would like to essentially simplify the
process
would like to show the evolution of the
actors while they learn what they do
with that
and suggest ways to close that
evolutionary specifically buy mp3
reports on how they can help us in the
position that offers some gonna run
through this as quickly as they can
while still making sense I do want a
couple months ago and people didn't know
what a PT's I'm gonna explain why doctor
or whatever to finish in you choose to
use their ego so let's start with a
story just to get an idea of what I want
to do was about time where we're forever
it's not a news story we've been there
we've done that that is fine but then an
apt report came out the rainforest 1 I'm
really aware of their benefits before
naturally but the one that truly to the
news and a security practitioner to be
honest I didn't really care said yeah we
know I mean sure the building in China
where they work which has been a call
reports matter to me any way whatsoever
but it did that reported in table when
you go talk to the board trying to get
funding or anything else this report
made a whole lot of difference for me
personally and for many others the
monthly reports and more importantly the
operations of APT 12 infrastructure was
significantly disrupted but they were
not alone we've seen many many other
campaigns for example stuck into stocks
and was very tight 500 K Muller very
very target specific very specific in
what he wanted to do on the other end
with flame within mustard was twenty
megabytes big every I'm imagining that
every single module they could have
everyone I am probably wrong but that's
what I imagine they put in there once
was a big hit for their intelligence
organization was behind the press says
either or whatever length without them
trying too much in the impact of an apt
1 reports that skill and boggle the mind
operationally there in trying to think
they have enough sex talk they try to
figure out what to do when twenty
megabytes of all there to get lost
so there's a logical so let's talk just
a couple goes they are skilled a
permission overtook J
as far as we know but also been used on
whoever specific targets in a way
encrypted so it only opens on specific
machine how do skill that you still that
how much effort you put into it to
create such a specific attack it was my
research along with some others such as
Microsoft in the Soviets and within the
stock a year ago it's easy they just
used in office
impact if they lose that do they care to
do not care for them to get this
capability supposedly run around like to
think they had these optic meetings
select the off seconds we see each
relevant here in 60 seconds why do you
need first of all you want to assure the
success of your permission
very simple you want to prevent the
detection of the operation was a success
and you want to prevent attribution
firstly I understand let solution is
important to understand what people
concentrate contribution I see the west
of a little efforts lol calling but
that's fine and there are all these
processes whether its regular software
development risk management we want to
see how much do we need to invest how
much need to stop are still what we
ought to reach more than that when these
compliments to markets rushing it is
never good
humility you try to scale the operation
you taking risks
and deployments how easy do you need to
sleep nighty guy teaching about the
security investigator USB key could be a
pain so generally every
I don't use that word lightly ever
report out there and there is based
somehow an epic failure comes down to
what can we do to learn from this and
use it against them better are still in
a way so we actually had a really good
example according to see if we could
actually reading there in how they
reacted to being exposed between 11 and
then a quote their primary concern seems
to be not getting caught again but we
don't you sort of visibility so we need
to guess now reports many of them are
good but with many of them I feel like
it's mainly made for PR purposes and
they're really huge essentially what we
get from them
commentators just working on other
people's work on trying to figure it out
so as a result there is a symmetry and
asymmetry in cyber cyber nowadays is
really a problem we're facing every day
when I'm going to that and for me
reports are good for that talkers
essentially being there other everybody
is learning every actor out there is
looking at these reports on how the
other hand just helps them so let's look
at the couple lessons learned just to
get started with you one very basic
command control servers IP addresses
compromised infrastructure is done we
have truck which was released by cast
and they were hijacking something like
traffic pollution goes in several years
in between
there is learning approaches the Stuxnet
and flame flame tattoo actually still
had similar code in its ultimate
solution and then you never know when
Tiger I'm sorry if you don't know all
these campaigns that's fine was clearly
going to that later over beer correct
though the mosque everything was so
perfect
distribution of the attack who else
would care about these
in Spain Spain right everything will be
sold for even saying good this false
flag how can we really make sure enough
they started learning there are multiple
cost less for many many amputees right
to throw the researches out of whatever
they're trying to do
reports that's pretty cool what do you
actually get a lot of it all season the
kind of compromise some easy to setup
command control service medical doctors
not really effective nearly never
anything at all so this feels like it's
really confusing again what we actually
do it this to move forward so for me we
tried to reverse engineer attacks but
look at forensic data apt reports what
if we tried to use all the technical
investigation went in through this talk
and when other anybody who are all their
investigation went into this just to be
able to do one thing reengineer that
doctors methodology their operations and
technical information for this quickly
first thing they do and this is
simplified not really changes between
that doctors and country's intelligence
requirements is like going shopping what
would you like to know
examples are doesn't stain where are the
W does he intend to use these who is
working on WMDs
how can we get back we ever got the joke
thank you very much appreciated in
germany not so much now the second part
is you know what you want the target
list where can I find answers or
withhold information I need example
calls we get that the report sometimes
targets not so much again exceptions
were pretty hot right now they're just a
party needs to get far as I know they
take whatever they can we're not talking
about any exception
intelligence-gathering third step in our
simplified model first of all the target
reports you're trying to figure out how
to the target but it looks like we're
going to face all that stuff
nice Asian one in my plan of attack in
what toll a weapon would elect to use in
order to execute the person next let's
think about the specific tools such a
claim and gas and then using something
on the ground for example this Dell
SecureWorks report showed you can tell
Tara system i hope i pronounce it tries
in order to use that to me is that
organization to do what they want to do
one thing if it goes on this same
process can be on the outside of work
then instead of trying to people to do
not remove and it goes on and on and it
feeds on itself its intelligence cycle
so how many of us watched it on facebook
when it came out that much the whole
thing through right I'm gonna save you
the trouble so at this stage with the
back and think about intelligence
gathering and all that involves and
figure out OPSEC is important again how
do you plan attacks of course first
thing I would do even 10 years ago is
not the target do the other night late
care care unit stopped me to take the
risk then suddenly started thinking
about security vendors back and
communities when they put in silence you
can they try to figure out what they
doing retrospective installing right now
but they can find me later
complex though trying to figure it out
when you're back next
we have came out supposedly and as a
group and it was an apt magnets he was
found in a machine read the report and
one other apt thats all there what's
going on so again the formation so my
old apt is out there who looks for their
existence
they're going to get caught before
installing software that's on the
operation on information so you need to
really try to hide her identity now
that's what we get out of it and then of
course we have this example in the names
changed he says the crowd state name
they had an actual case to get upset
when they didn't care that much they
would do and then that doctor will
change they doing that on the network
for quite a while many doctors don't
really care when you starting incident
response to mind but they did run away
eventually according to reports looks
interesting to see no hearing your
report about Symantec report about the
US stocks and you can see for the
compilation time the infection time
things for example if you see a
compilation times at memoranda Shabbos
maybe there is really have no choice but
to give you information for example how
to compile time section time time to
inspect our own operation you can learn
a lot and everything was crumbles so
they do learn so let's take a quick call
these agents i coevolution
example though they like many other
creditors revert to OS tools for example
W my PowerShell and that's pretty much
what we're seeing is four strokes goes
into a two
in our example when you can never
happens
they were basically inspecting only
actually doing the work was really cool
to look at so there is another parts but
need to take into consideration which
haven't seen people will talk about and
that's what we call the fall retreat
part of the operation they have been
discovered now up so I want to speak
about three examples remain greatly over
the Chiefs months after publication
partially and fully two weeks whatever
and then the Masquerade we spoke about
this the was invented local Austin wrote
about it on the blog and four hours just
to name the match for hours later things
down and then look into PA to this is
gross my own interpretation don't wait
for the publication break into the
vendor they're going to do what they
want to release so there are certain
pollution here is a look at it that way
their counter examples of again
operating that's why I saw the defender
said this is really important to me it's
not perfect but that's what we gotta do
to start progressing in making money to
us so we're gonna talk about problem
takeaways in solution based on the
simplified model just waitin for all
employees rights much more complex
composed intelligence requirements
the problem is not enough information
what are the objectives we don't always
know about our as they look at how can
get more like having a stalker when they
like you they really like you really
like you they're not gonna stop yourself
this is an example from RSA October
death one shows an example when they
were attacking they started to use in
response to what the rest of the weekend
and came back again with slightly
improved lateral movement all they're
not gonna give it up most of them
I'm an interesting to me number to
stealing days just one option and
everybody wants everybody not surely but
a lot of people were surprised that saw
me think about it for a second we know
what a Trojan horse can do it is
organization do they know something else
but you haven't seen here and go to keep
on top of that stuff so still there is
just one of the options we just go out
what else they can do once they're
inside and we know they're inside so
site to Sami the main action and all the
way back to boring security risk
assessments risk assessments are boring
documents we have absolutely no used
mostly for compliance this big if not
bigger and withdraw the way them and
they're done a risk assessments tickets
reasonable tactical operational
you can also use it for something else
that could be useful for us and that's
my taken second compile target least
there in no time since the information
out there
reports they mostly meaning no pattern
is really hard to do better recognition
now though is if you have similar data
or platform on any organization
organization you can know you're on the
list and more than that you can perform
a threat the system for some intense
capability to see what's going on and
did because of their final cell systems
make sure their voices are securing
what's going on there
37 given cycle talk about a little bit
engagement stage publicly available
system is not really their security
awareness it's pretty much an issue that
could you get along with your network
that's fine
the public information which is blowing
my mind right now
but there's nothing better than this
dick engagement stage not many sheriff's
reports please turn down that they go
and engagement there are many you're not
alone in this game and lost his many
obstacles can overload security
reception area he tells in Falkland
retreat that doctor can destroy the
forensic evidence even going to say when
I'm gonna back it up right now I'm just
saying it's possible I'll look at this
log mother lots and adjust for
monitoring today we based our security
incident response and that is the case
that came out in a really important
snapshots of the day love skip them and
backup your blog or instant response
that can destroy their evidence it's
pretty simple actually made a name for
this my partner in crime get burp
response month this is important make
sure you have the data you can try this
at home
essentially you have two things we
talked about we have the type of data
that you actually have an apt reports
CNN report comes out 24 how much you
actually have to rely on to go through
this engagement process figure out what
you can do for defensive IOC's if you do
the more you'll get more and that is my
personal take away from this now there
is something else like to talk about and
I something we like to call the decline
of shame it seems to me almost like a
beauty reports have come to a point
where they've been doctor is no longer
care about what you know the first time
I thought he saw they lost
infrastructure with Eric sign away
quietly nowadays people get caught they
don't even care to keep moving up there
for a minute and just having fun with
this but there is a solution and the
mindset in consideration
we would like to see better more action
reports many of them are very good many
of them are the information to mount
them number to earlier reports hate you
can give us a heads up and we know your
vertical is targeted that's where the
importance and we know the type of clots
forming at that that's really important
a lot of these shares closed circles
most of this is not think about it
third actionable public information
sharing I was very worried about
actually saying this for many many years
anybody from the airport initiatives in
the security space but I believe in this
if you got to share more information
will be amazing and that's that
and loss I understand a little people
wanted to do something with the lizard
brain and can help with policy but
enough already
contribution it's not the most important
thing is we have shown please okay so
we'll talk later please for me
ok no public reports follow warrants
reports can be a huge help they really
can think about it he said there in QA
for the tuckers but it's more than that
when you release the report they are
hurt you imagine fashion police report
that helps us create the defense we need
they'll be really great which means we
want them the Tigers tix keep releasing
the information
relevance does help make it better
essentially let's increase their costs
everything I do for my startup to any
project on hold with other people
talking about the asymmetry in their
past you can change this cost of the top
players in the tax that's all I really
care about personally and this is
something I think abt reports can really
help with thank you very much and if you
have any questions that would be most of
us are but I will say he's been very
quick there is an entire research behind
it if you're interested
sure thank you very much
two minutes from now on we got we got
time for questions just raise your hand
I'll come find you gotta question yes No
thank you thank you so much and again on
behalf of b-sides and sponsors Fitbit
Fitbit thanks thank you