hello everyone my name is Gary pepper -
and then security researcher and
positive technologist company and today
I'm going to show you and make some
presentation about don't age I think and
playing with some I which it stops well
as I said I'm working in positive
technologies company and we make some
solutions and research in different
fields and areas of security it's also
apply applies to wireless and telecom
security so and nowadays we starting to
play with some of your stuff
so I'm involved in this and today I'm
going to tell you about drone hijacking
what is devices I widely use nowadays
they are surrounded us well you can see
them there in in veil you can see them
any day in all day life wireless
keyboard wireless remote control
different stuff to always keep as I said
keyboards so my presentation is about
SDR partically I think that some of you
are familiar with se ours but some of
them I think not so I had to explain and
tell you few words about what is this is
there there it is software-defined radio
as it's written it's very useful and
unique devices it allows you to make a
lot of interesting and very cool stuff I
more information you can easily find on
any wiki but just imagine yourself you
want to sniff and hijack some devices
some remote control some planes make you
face proofing and all in in all these
cases you use only one device one HDR
not a scope of some transmitters and
responders just one as they are in and
of course software so let's talk about
some easier market where nowadays is a
really huge market of is yours there are
many many of them
well known for example hacker one I'm
sure that people who knows about is the
earth knows about soccer of one too but
not so many people know about soccer of
blue it's some kind of Cologne it was on
Kickstarter projects nowadays you can
find Cologne of a carafe on some Chinese
side and it will cost and it it cost
will low it's about two hundred dollars
by the rest
nice devices you can run some solutions
from Yeti with the s and some UT
projects on it
nice device excuse me yes it is easier
peanut laser not accurate it is user P a
user piece National Instruments
solutions it's a really huge amount of
devices very very interesting devices
they appears nowadays new one real it's
a very cool stuff man here one of them
it's user PB 200 well cool stuff but not
so cheap one in Tariq's it solution from
some some Russian guys not bad device
it's this device it's some situated in
some middle between blood wrap and user
P it have got same tuner as in the blue
dress and have got nice EPG and
amplifier which allows you to run BTS we
very big coverage from the web box so in
some simple you in some simple is yours
you had to make your own amplifiers and
some filters and in this device all in
one nice device well I'll tell is there
is a huge family of devices to they
bring new life of them some guys from
the osmocon make and understand that
it's not just a simple derivative
receiver but this receiver can allows
you to smooth
huge huge range of frequencies you
if GSM VSC and even some satellite
signals were just simple she divides
which cost about $10 nice device if you
want to start to play with as yours and
you have no national and we have no
money just try to play with them one is
here
well this device appears I think about
half a year ago it was a crowdfunding
company a really nice device there are
many solutions nowadays which allows you
to make to play with different stuff
with different software nice device very
small very convenient very useful highly
recommended list and there is another
one device by the way line is there
produced new chipset and the line micro
and this is chipset is set in new line
as yours the same chipset you can find
on exericse it from fairways pretty
small very nice device just imagine
yourself you can make your sniffer and
hide it in any device even in an Aleph
top this device has got form factor of
the Wi-Fi module you can easily use it
anywhere and by the way mini PCIe
interface allows you to sneak very huge
range of frequencies at bar and get a
really big bandwidth bandwidth well I
took it might tell you few words about
devices and let's talk about software
for as yours
I usually split these devices with
software on a free moon areas it is
easier sharp GQ rigs this is solutions
for how to say for simple analyzing you
can see just what happens in radio air
ready by online you can see waterfall
make some simple demodulation
just listen radio fm I am and it's
pretty simple new radio and LabVIEW is
another one kind of different software
solutions these solutions allows you to
make anything absolutely it's anything
in radio is very flexible constructors
we very huge functionality highly
recommended to play with them honestly I
usually play with my radio because it's
open sources it's very good constructor
and I have no enough knowledge is in
signal in digital signal processing but
this software the new radio allows me to
play with the earth and make some
research and analyze it and boot line
this software is very simple but very
powerful in right-hand this oh excuse me
both line is well good line allows you
to make any kind of analyzes but you had
to have you have to help know much more
about digital processing analyzing you
must be familiar with mathematics the
huge amount of magnetic inside of this
but it's allows you to do a lot well
let's see let's talk about what is there
allows you to do there is a simple list
of some something that you can play with
an array you can easier you can play we
radio just with single with this simple
block box jamming diagram you can make
your own radio FM station you can make
some replay attacks for example in this
case in this diagram presented cracking
of the ring bell just simple replay
attacks nothing
nothing more some some flow graphs much
more difficult and complicated so
example for example it is adjacent
which allows you to make a multiplexer
and make an analyzing of many channel in
a one köppen in one photograph but you
had to help a really good computer to
compute this online well in mind
research and make this him it's pretty
simple
it allows me to analyze some devices
Ouija FSK modulation I will talk about
the play about it a bit later I will
explain what is this in what is
listening RFID and if in CC imagine this
module you can play and with Azure you
can play with such kind of devices
logical in CC you can make a plank blink
tracking it's pretty simple pretty as I
said previously you can make GPS
spoofing lots of projects with UHD and
some of them for hakura
well you can make some user targeting
you can analyze who around around you
who who is what which devices is used
you can make indicators if you similar
we with telecom you I think no that is
mean what does it mean you can make a
Bluetooth low-energy sniffer you can see
some iOS IOT devices and etc where are
some projects and of course I think the
most interesting for some people it is
because base stations can be easily
round on the easier SDR there are many
projects such as asthma home videos open
videos yet CBDs open LP you can run your
own ok you can run your own LP base
station with using over there and
software and with the software it will
be cost adjust to the price of the
computer and Azure and just imagine you
feel good and lt base station well let's
talk about let's look about close about
our target our target is an RF 24
chipset and RF 24 is not X in the
conductor chipset is proprietary
are very cheap widely used it can be
found in a lot of devices such as remote
control Mouse's keyboard drones and etc
it's very what we use is give you a very
good high speed for 2 megabits examples
and it works on the frequency to end
point for either here you hear is open
its open frequency so this is device is
very good I'm working with this device
through this library it is you can see
this lightning you can buy the link
below by the link on the bottom of the
slide you can use this API well I use
some kind of chipset that works through
the API interface and you can directly
work with spi and write 2 registers of
the device but it's more comfortable to
use API and I use this API by the way
there are a lot of analogy of the this
device of an array chipset for example
in some zones in some photo cultures I
find BK 24:23 analog some if this
chipsets have got some additional
functionality but usually it's pretty
same well let's look closer let's look
closer to packet of the NRS 24 where are
usually two kinds of packets one packet
is in common practice is considered
preamble at the rest payload and 30 your
seeds not Astro field it's additional
field sometimes is it not it not used
address can be from 3 to 5 bytes well
where I am and where is another packet
formatted code shock dose but take let's
talk about first one common packet I
find this using of these packets in
different kind of devices well an RF
chipset allows you not only to transmit
that data but receive data - it is very
interesting that to Smith data you had
to put address of to the target chipset
to sniff area with this address and if
you want to make a sniffer on a device
we had to brute-force three bytes of
address it's about 16 millions
combinations eat too much but there is
some trick if you can if you read data
sheet very some illegal instruction you
can see this and it is marked with
illegal instruction allows you to use
two bytes of the address space two byte
address space for sniffing all two bytes
we have to good for 65,000 combination
it's already not so much and we can make
a passing make a sniffer for a few
minutes and we can sniff all devices but
there is one very interesting trick the
very preamble in this beginning of the
packet and it is interesting that she
says not look doesn't look at the
preamble at all she said only looking
for a dress if she said is tuned to
receiving a data from the air and it's
fine
correct address in the air in the air
packet it decided to receive this packet
and it decided this packet while to
these chips standard to this chipset so
now we make a trick and first we make
ability to work with in this illegal
instruction you should make winner
changes in API or this library to write
to write and register with data to make
the chipset works with
to byte address and after that we put in
the address just data from the preamble
so we start to sniff all packets with G
FSK modulation which can be found with
the preamble so there is a sniffer I
would like to show you on a practice how
this looks like few seconds here is a
just raspberry pi with a config set
inside its the NRF 24 chipset as I said
is work to SPI interface
well pretty simple I connected from
laptop to this device and there is some
script inside legend let's here we are
it is my Raspberry Pi with chipset and
let's start our scanner
well it's run and let's look a bit
closer let's find this remote control
honestly there you can read from
datasheet that there are a lot of
channels which can be tuned for this
Android model but I already tuned for
correct frequency for the correct
channel channel 9 uses encima remote
controls as a channel for
synchronization so I turn on it and you
see data start goes eh-eh f AE this is
data from the remote control the this
one of this is with this data so you can
see how to knit my
chipset post-meeting you see that as
receiving a dress I put data zero zero a
a zero zero a a it is free ambolyn
preamble so a bit later a lot that
explain why i use zero zero a a well
this is pretty simple scanner main idea
of the scanner is who goes through the
channels and find some data so we can
play with some devices and very they can
be somehow system in remote control
circuit boards and after some we just
goes through the channels and after that
we can see that out in our scanners find
devices on a channel 9
we with a dress on the channel 3 a on a
visa drop you will be sad rest and after
that we can shoot our chipset exactly to
the device so we can analyze exactly
this device that we are going to steal
so that is pretty simple and what I'm
not the first one who guessed about this
trick we use to buy the dress and
preamble share this good fit is very
cool research and make this research
much much earlier well unfortunately I
find his research I think about half of
the year only when I bought a face
dancer I find this source code you can
see God sees dot an arrest this trellis
make his own solution makes his own API
to work with these chipsets through the
SPI interface he even make his own work
for hiking all these devices he make a
very good work for this
so let's talk about what about the
awesome frequency shift keying
mutilation this is modulation you can
read about more about it in a wiki
it's used in a lot of devices and a lot
of chipsets well we can see how it goes
on in the radio air here on this picture
we can see data on a channel 24 seconds
I can show you it on the real line I
think for this we will just all we need
it start gqx something terrible in the
air honestly where a lot of data goes so
I think that we couldn't see remote
control but maybe we have a lot i
[Music]
already know the channels in which
frequencies works with solutions so we
can i think we can find it as i said
previously on the channel 9 you can see
on the middle yes ii i think that this
is this is no no no no no blockage
definitely now II couldn't see oops
here we can see you can see the spike
sometimes appears here for example with
this this is our transmitter you can see
that sometimes it's higher goes higher
eat our transmitting data but were a lot
of some devices in the air it's not
white wine it's some kind of another
transceiver so I hope that that will
come that we've all seen this kind of
picture but unfortunately where a lot of
us here well what about GFS came
relation to make a bit more
understanding you should make this no
radial theme and make analyzing all the
data what we received after we after the
analyzing through the board line we will
receive such picture I'm not sure to the
early scene you can see the pike on the
picture below it is starting on the
transmitting you see this part it is
starting off transmitting is our chipset
start to works
after that it's tuned to the frequency
this is in this surface it is then our
transceiver tooth the frequency after
that you can see jigsaw this part is
zero and hose it is preamble of the
packet after that we can see address
payload and as we empty our tea well and
another pipe it is the end of the
transmission this data our transmitter
turns off it is
of middle-earth connectional just just
turned off for a while so in the in the
bottom picture you can see these
explanations of this data it is
consistent zero and one
you this part it is a lot of City a lot
of one it is this part of the packet and
the end of this is a Searcy or the
packet you can make analyzing all
received data dated by your own by your
hands not automatically so with this
knowledge we can make simple team
finalizing on Agnew radio we make a
doodle ation of the received data and
put this data to a FIFO channel just in
a simple peaceful file and our him put 0
& 1 to this channel and real the simple
program we read 0 & 1
and combine it in a full pipe in a
complete packet that you can see you
know in the bottom of the but so I can
show you how it works and there is this
hint well we are starting that him it
right the data to a FIFO file and here
we start our GFS key finder use seconds
and here we see some data which can be
found on the air let's let's turn on our
remote control now this this boxing
configured to Smith data from the mouse
you see this is Mouse this is data from
Microsoft Mouse Phil first five byte a9
and etc until the 44 it is addressed
after that goes payload
payload 263 after that gold CRC CRC all
the NRF chipset and 63 it is the CRC
inside the payload it is additional part
which is made by Microsoft with
invaluable not so him is pretty simple
you can easily configure this to dismiss
dismiss a remote control I know that you
know control work on another one word
rate so and works on another Channel we
know that it is channel 9
so let's tune to channel 9 here you see
that there are a lot of data in this
channel but we can find our remote
control
this is synchronization data of our
remote control after synchronization
after we receive instrumentation this
remote control start to regional send
data on other channels with shouting I
will show you edit later let
well we'll this is what not so cheap
scanner why not so shit because it using
SDR as here it's not $1 device cost
about from 200 but it depends of course
on the device on a page day six we may
contest we've tasked to hijack and had
to eject a draw and we got a winner one
guy can solve this solution so so this
test and talk and he can tell our drone
for this by the link on the bottom of
the slide you can find description of
this contest for this contest to make
two kinds of devices one of them works
on the Arduino and another one remote
control works on the Raspberry Pi you
can easily make your own universal
remote control with these solutions well
and this our diagram while a block
scheme once more you can see here
explanation of the data on the top you
can see the picture from a broad line
with the explanation of the received
data zero once its preamble before
preamble we can see that is that L
device start to transmit its duty
frequency after that from a two it is
already address of the device and after
that it goes payload so you can read
about the solutions by the link well a
few months ago I decided to refresh some
knowledge about the solutions and find
interesting open source project it's
called deviation seeks this project
allows you to make in new vs. universal
remote control from just and another
chipset and any other remote control you
have just make such a film very for this
it is pretty simple you can use this
Lucian's to make your own remote control
on a zr2 it is not so difficult so let's
show you some drunk hijacking as I said
previously we can find we know procedure
of the such I think and in configuring
of the remote control well as to step
before a remote control start to work
with the drone 13 it sends a data on it
channel 9 with information in which
channel and in which we which address
this drone should just work so and after
that there is a synchronization so
that's all it is since natural knife and
it is start to listen my device but we
know algorithm of the synchronization
and there are some like stove in a
protocol some ethnic mystics and this
mixes allows allows us to understand in
which channels and which addresses work
out this device so let's again start our
scanners
you second please so we start our
scanner and we are starting to go
through the channel and on the channel
10 we can see data from remote control
to fit wrong to this folder culture so
this part is address of the device and
some guy is already a reverse or removed
for Seema and we can make our own remote
control we're putting just address of a
device we in which was it synchronize it
show us in which channels it works and
you can see that this remote control few
works but as I said we have our own
remote control oh I don't stop and so
original remote control wouldn't work
[Applause]
original remote control still work and
John still receive data from this remote
control but we other rural Channel and
to send much more data that is why our
remote control is have a big prayer
priority mapper have got a big aperture
we are tied so this is not working and
this is working so now let's turn it off
and don't forget that this we have
previous project that I should show
before deviation seeks you can make a
lot of remote control a lot of
description for example after I make
solution for a schema my colleague give
me another one John is called Skywalker
I think and it takes I think about 10
minutes to make solution for wisdom too
because it works on the thing she said
but there was inverse if I am not
mistaken there was inverse throttle
sticks but everything other was
absolutely the same
so you second by the way we can look for
data over share of a remote control well
this is data she is second let's turn
our scanner to look for this address
this address of device
yes this is a data of the second here
this is a packet sometimes it I'm not a
good programmer so my program sometimes
failed to open one one more time okay
and here we can analyze data this is
moving all the six you can see just pot
here and this sort of water and etc well
so I saw the contest here that you can
win the prize with Wilma so if somebody
wants to win this prize please call me I
can teach you how you can win click yes
definitely so let's talk about Mouse
Jack attacks
researchers from but you network or a
year ago in make a white pipe paper
about my mouse Jack attack this attack
consists of three different cases first
two are pretty similar and not so
interesting and the third one it is very
very interesting just imagine yourself
if you don't remember I can repeat that
if you send the mouse take it from the
keyboard this novice dongle allows you
to receive packets from the keyboard and
make a press of the keyboard so you can
send unencrypted psychic as it was
crafted for amount of as it was crafted
for a keyboard but send it to the
address of the mouse
and don't go receive this packet and put
it to the USB part and there will be a
pricing called key there was no more
people ask for poke they saw that they
saw just white paper without any proof
of concept so I decided to make this
proof of concept for myself and it takes
not so much time as a target as I said I
use the most mouse keyboard and mouse
mount and let's look what what we have
as a as I said in previous previously
mouse accepted keyboard packets and
these packets are not scripted so two
seconds let's run our GFS key analyzer
once more
oh I forgot I change configuration here
second we should change betrayed to the
mountainside let's start let's start
here there is data from the mouse so as
I said previously this is address of the
mouth and from 44 stars fellows with CR
C so you can see that we make very
simple script this scripts and they are
send data to this address to address of
the mouth just for bite it is untreated
because well to prove that it's not
created I will show you something
you see that we can see the speed of the
mouse and direction of it it moves it
works not all the time because mouse
have got many channels in which she will
it works well here we see this I moved
and we can see the speed with direction
of our moves it is very simple packet
you can see this 7 F and F every
direction and speed of the mouse
movement so we make the same script is
we the same packet and try to files make
some simple sizing over data inside this
we Lord
so it was not this great well it is
creating cost F 1 and F 1 K it is make
some sizing try to get the number of the
packet and always send say an impressing
call the F F 1 K so yes we got we
opening at the terminal we sent from the
Raspberry Pi like it to a mouse dongle
to most address and we see that one like
it so that was thank you
well while we make if I think we can
find that we send one G packet but then
we make a HB hits information of the
scan codes of video of the key presses
one D it is not fi d f1 but if one is
free a it is because data in the tail
and in the packet is shifted on one bit
so that it is our PI think of f1 you
and this you can imagine yourself that
we can send any data to the target if
our readings have got some kind of this
dongle some USB microsoft we can not
only see new data and sometimes decrypt
it but we can put data we can send a
some script we can get for example with
some some malicious some years - visited
some verses site and etc and what about
other devices we'll go out and frequency
shift keying modulation this very lot of
devices with Jacob came relational
assess it is beautiful energy in the
wave big BTC 24 0 2500 all these devices
use
gsst modulation a finalizing of these
devices for missing all these devices
all you need is just a new radio and
this one block from no radio it's called
for the two demodulator all magic do was
doubled by this block you can make
simple analyzing of wireless what goes
around you you can analyze radio air
interface so just one simple with just
one simple block more information and
more some interesting stuff we place
with the weight and DB you can find on
by link on the bottom of the slide there
are many interesting things which you do
with device and why we're talking about
JFK JFK and the way it be ourselves are
widely used the using some smart kids
smart home kids IOT keys so you can not
hide
you can not hide your devices just
imagine how many devices nowadays in
involved in all this process maybe you
heard about that half
about half of a year ago some research
find make a security issue in a
lightbulb from Felix well and very a lot
of such about lightbulb and not only not
only feeling there are a lot of lot of
devices from IOT smart keys that can be
hacked by these devices by radio you you
cannot not only you know rule in your
house but some other guys will do so
what is the main point of all this
presentation we should understand that
you must be ahead one step before the
criminal you make you should help you
should make analyze make audit of the
devices so smart kids before you
implement before you start to start to
fail them so let's not make mistake
let's make our diesels they make this
world a bit more secure well together as
you so thank you for your time I will
find some ways of good question I will
be glad to answer you if I can know so I
will teach you so if you have got any
questions you can ask me a bit later
maybe some show and Microsoft keyboard
decrypting I can show you it is pretty
simple so thank you thank you so time
[Applause]