I'm good morning everybody I I don't
know if anyone can hear me in the back
of the room but it should be okay
perfect so in case Adam was just talking
now about the CTF in case you have any
questions about the tdf reach out to him
reach out to me or reach out to anyone
and in the front row we can help you
with any questions you have about that
having said that I'm going to talk a
little bit about how to be successful in
the azure bug bounty program what adjure
is exactly what are the highest payout
which we have had in the past and so on
and some of the most juicy bug sweeper
we've seen along the way my name is
Michael Hendricks the funny spelling of
my last name LG I'm not they're not
native from Goa I'm from Belgium I'm a
security engineer from Microsoft in fact
i'm a senior security engineer for
microsoft that just explains how old am
my twitter handle is underneath reach
out to to follow me whatever you want so
the agenda today we're going to talk
about a few things we're going to talk
about attack surface of a sure what a
jury's exactly we're going to talk about
the background of the bug bounty program
that we have we're going to talk about
fast payouts which you had four bucks to
scope which of which type of ducks are
within the scope of which or not and
then we'll explain you a little bit how
to get started and how to get cracking
on this bug bounty program so the azure
attack surface with the show of hands
who doesn't know what a jury's good one
person our marketing team is not that
bad in the end adger is the Microsoft
cloud right and it's not a copy of
anyone else of course it's it's a little
bit more than that it's not just the
website to spin up VMs and if you see
from an attack surface it's relatively
complicated when I joined Microsoft and
I'm still struggling with all the
aggravation there's a lot of
interactions with it so in the center
you have this Microsoft Azure on the
left you can see different ways you can
interact with it there's a PowerShell
window over there there's visual studio
there's two different portals to talk to
ezer and under on the right you can see
talks to data centers and all these
things as well but there's a lot more to
it for example we have
I read somewhere along the way as well
office 365 uses file storage blobstore
stable storage which is all hosted on on
agile after that we have things like
federated identity fear of your your
Active Directory on-premises in your own
data center you can sync it with the
realtor and don't worry I'm not going to
explain what it does appreciate it it is
a marketing talk if things such as
virtual networks you can extend your own
network to the cloud you have things
like multiple tenants in there obviously
we don't just have one customer luckily
your things where you can deploy
applications any applications you can
deploy your web applications mobile
applications but also worker roles which
are sort of a little bit like like cron
jobs in UNIX and the list keeps on going
we can obviously spin up VMs in the in
Azure we have something called the vm
marketplace so it's not just linux boxes
and windows boxes you can actually
download web application firewall images
and run them in the clouds as a
virtualized image so the list goes on
and on we have on frame applications
that you can publish in the clouds you
have SQL databases obviously one of our
flagship product we have no SQL
databases we are catching such as ready
sketches and so on you have user
management and the list goes on and on I
don't know which on kinnser ok now you
have extra gateways to to connect your
data center to the cloud and so on you
have load balancing in the area of
network security groups which are sort
of lexus like virtual firewalls there
are you sell services in case somebody
forgets their password or their account
is locked out then then they won't be
calling you at 3m if you're on if your
asses that mean on top of that you have
noticed factor authentication obviously
we have scales it's whereby with normal
scripts very rich in PowerShell or in
Python or anything you can manage up to
tens or thousands of VMs all at once
load balancing is there extra there's
backup obviously if you want to send
data to the cloud we have a CD and you
have media services and so on and before
I fill up this slice with all different
verse
that are there the feeling what you
probably get and the feeling i still
have after working in Microsoft
networking adjure it's pretty much what
is the what is this thing all about it
talks the storage we took the database
it talks to a lot of things and it's not
just because a sure is complex from an
attack this point of view from an
offensive security point of view it
means there's a relatively big attack
surface as well you have either as a
very abstract thing you have a few
portals talk into it a few scripts it
talks to hundreds of other things it's
very complex which makes it interesting
to to attack so what we noticed when you
have such a complete complex beast in
fact it would be a handy thing to make
that subject to a to a bug bounty so in
April 2015 we started this bug bounty
program to be included with the other
ones that we have to give our customers
as well as the research community a way
to find vulnerabilities in a way to
reach out to us we've expanded the
bounty ever since if you have a little
over 50 domains included in this and
here you see a few headlines that a
researcher made some money twenty four
thousand dollars in signing books but
we'll talk about bug specifically in
terms of a timeline what you can see is
that Microsoft has a mitigation by size
bounty stars in june 2013 half a year
later we opened it up to office 365 as
well and half a year later after that we
also open it up to azure as if either is
a very complex thing it only made sense
to be in there a glm mentioned yesterday
as well that we have a double reward for
EXO which is Exchange Online and office
365 portal which which started to
yesterday or day before yesterday on the
first of March and identity first of
first of May our other bounties the
maximum payout in Azure is 15,000 US
dollars on office 365 as well and a
little bit more about these double
bounty in exchange online and the office
365 portal the domains receiving the
double of ours or portal at office.com
out of that office 365 com and so on you
can find it on our website and the
payout range is everything between a
thousand dollars for low
bugs to thirty thousand dollars for for
high-impact sucks obviously duration as
I said it started on the first of March
and it will continue until the first of
May this year so if we talk about this
pathway out these are the lucky seven
these are the top seven bucks which we
had in a sure to date now I know what
you're thinking you think like Michael a
second ago you said the maximum payout
is fifteen thousand dollars and a tub
duck we actually paid twenty four
thousand dollars for it this was found
during a double bounty program the
researcher found a bug we awarded twelve
thousand dollars times dude its basic
maps every we gave the person twenty
four thousand dollars on top of that
that person joined Microsoft is also a
signing bonus plus the above the bug
bounty with a pretty good months for him
I think if you look at this if you look
at the general trend of this as well
it's very much you can see a lot of
things coming back right or dub bug it's
an authentication by that the other one
is an authentication bypass as well and
then there's impersonation again about
identity wrld em wrl decoding is against
the steel authentication token so if you
have to if you have to get anything from
this slide is that we pay quite a bit
for for authentication bugs identity and
authentication is very important over us
we're going to talk a little bit more in
depth about them three on these slides
the azure virtual network gateway bypass
and two of the web box and a little bit
more of Lauer of lower payout so you can
see what sort of amount of money we pay
for for what type of books so number one
the azure virtual network gateway bypass
in a sure we call it to Zenith what is
Enid actually this virtual network is
your network logically in the clouds you
can set up any private IP addressing
with your own DNS servers if you want in
the cloud and the great thing and this
is not a marketing spiel the great thing
is you can have several networks with
the same subnet so you can test your
applications in a test environment
production environment without changing
any any IP addresses now how that how
you can connect to it I mean this runs
in the cloud how you can come
how you can extend this to your own
tiran on-premises data center is one of
the possibilities is a V netgate raise
virtual network gateway it's using
something called a secure socket
tunneling protocol or at the CP now how
ssdp works initially you set up a TLS
tunnel or 443 which is HTTPS so it'll
break out it will break through most
firewalls once that tunnel is set up you
actually do some SSCP state control
packets and with that you can you get
access to the network so somewhere
something went wrong and by by sending a
special crafted sequence of packets you
could skip the authentication step which
in plain English will actually means it
would give access to a virtual network
without any any credentials at all which
was pretty bad that's why we paid 3,000
of 13,000 and a bit dollars for finding
it so this is a very specific reverse
engineering network packet back and
forward you run a lot of Wireshark and
other things just to see what's
happening another box of where you can
leak tokens is is basically in all up
when you try to log into a certain
website there's something called a
redirect URL which is basically as soon
as you're authorized a certain
application it'll send you back to an to
certain to certain URL that you specify
this URL obviously cannot be anything it
needs to be limited and so on and
decides in our case Microsoft make sure
that this URL is what what we expect it
to be somewhere something went wrong and
we weren't doing double encoding which
meant that somebody could could give a
URL which was doubly encoded now in URLs
you can put a percentage sign in the hex
value so percentage to F which you can
give you later which you can see over
there just becomes a forward slash and
percentage 25 actually become too
becomes the percentage sign itself the
checking did more than one decoding the
value we give back didn't so the problem
is you could actually have this as a
valid domain giving back to us now those
who ever try basic authentication on
websites if you would know that
everything if you type in your browser
HD
eps something at something else calm
that something would actually just be
seen as a username incidental to the
second to the second domain so in this
case when you say Center token back to
this URL it doesn't mean it's going to
account at windows azure com which is
address the domain from our standpoint
it actually went to evil domain dog net
which is something that that a hacker
would own for example and add darker
custard as thirteen thousand dollars
because we did you could steal access
tokens and login as someone else to stay
a little bit more in the land of all up
everyone has seen these I'm sure
everyone has run through some sort of
all up authentication authorization
already so basically what you have is
you have a yes any website or mobile
application you'll see a log in with a
certain providers can be faithful Google
Microsoft Twitter github what have you
it would redirect you to a certain page
they do allow this application to give
access to your account to your email or
driver your timeline any of these any of
these permissions reappraise yes there's
your magic happening in the back and it
will go back to the website to your
application saying welcome with your
name and has access to it or what would
you said it would have access to
somewhere where something went wrong is
that in application itself the my app in
this case you could put JavaScript and
those who work in application security
you know that the second you can render
JavaScript if you cross site scripting
vulnerability stored cross-site
scripting vulnerability and in this case
instead of showing an alert button
obviously or instead of stealing cookies
you would just fake a click so you could
have somebody authorize your application
on your behalf basically to make this
into an evil thing you could say good
and go to my website it redirects you
automatically to a screen what you would
expect you to click years on you don't
click on it at all JavaScript to do it
for you and basically the attacker would
have access to ER to a lot of things
that you authorize the problem is you
didn't authorize it JavaScript
authorized it damaged twelve thousand
dollars for this for this bug for
cross-site scripting now if you stick to
cross that
thing don't take this as an vfa twelve
thousand dollars for cross-site
scripting a few months ago there was a
blind stored cross-site scripting result
I would pay a little bit less for this
it's a bit of get rich if you if you
translate it down it basically it's a
ping back to a certain domain those who
use who use burp suite which is your
intercepting proxy it has a feature to
to basically put a certain and image an
image tag in a page in it and it reaches
back to you okay
and we're back sorry the thing Microsoft
Adam axis the microphone wanted me to us
to make sure stop working I'm sure we
can edit a video right ok so anyway with
this yet across site scripting
vulnerability store the assorted
scripting vulnerability as well in one
of the azure domains basically an
attacker could give a certain input
which is sort of over here and it could
only be read by back-end engineers the
problem is it's very difficult to find
out if a backend engineer actually click
on this unless with some sort of call
back to a custom to a custom domain this
thing works two thousand dollars and in
the end this is very difficult to
exploit the backend URLs are only
accessible from from the Microsoft
Network brilliant it's a valid valid
bounty then the more of the lower
payouts microsoft obviously has a lot of
websites a lot of website and we try to
make sure we have this internal drive to
make every site we have HTTPS and every
link on our website should be encrypted
as well should be HTTP ssl some of her
if if one of our pages has an HTTP
hyperlink hard-coded in there then we
basically the problem is someone who
does a man-in-the-middle could redirect
traffic so now this doesn't cover every
domain that if you have a sensitive
domains such as account of microsoft com
which as the name tells you is something
about your account at the microsoft
domain this is eligible for a bounty as
well as that it's more of the lower
payout so this is a five-hundred-dollar
five-hundred-dollar bucks again this is
very subject to which domain it is so
don't start scanning all our domains and
look for HTTP in there because that's
not gonna as I'm going to fly so well
so basically what things do we look for
right this is more or less you're always
stop then on the left here if you cross
site scripting in there you're CSRF in
there certain authentication
vulnerabilities and so on and so on and
so on but the highest bounties are
basically earned on authentication I
said it earlier and I'll say it again we
have a multi-tenant environment if you
have if your customer one you can access
customer to that's a bad thing obviously
so anything authentication I really
related is it's pretty bad any something
will say will pay quite well for
privilege escalation and welage is sort
of from a vertical escalation point of
view we'll talk about it in a second
curse that scripting and cross-site
request forgery Artem are most of the
bugs which we get and which have the
high fails as well in scope domains
obviously don't learn this by heart it's
on our website so you can see this we
have multiple little over 50 domains of
multiple domains which are in scope some
of them even have have sub domains as
though you're talking about a lot of
domains which are all included within
the bug bounty program their second
slice on this result obviously
everything excluding user-generated
content is covered by it if somewhat
agree if somebody creates of a burnable
asp application and put in an azure
that's not part of the bug bounty
program that's just bad coding and it
won't won't be covered by us if there's
something from the infrastructure itself
we will will cover it now we spoke about
what everything that's in scope what are
the things that are out of scope
obviously the domains that are out of
that are not in scope or by definition
out of scope but I put a little asterisk
a result in a way of if you find a high
a high vulnerability bug in the domain
is not covered by us reported to us
anyway not from and thank you and we'll
stop emailing you but more as in if this
is really this is really valid duck will
obviously love Italy reward you for it
user-generated content is out of scope
as well any testing that you do outside
of your own tenant is something we don't
really like because we don't have the
staging environment you're testing the
real deal you're on there with all our
customers
if you do have a duck and you think it
will affect other tenants talk to us
we'll set up an extra tenant for you for
testing you can now you can do that so
you don't target or real a real
customers any volume-based denial of
service is out of scope which makes
sense you shouldn't really be big
dusting a sure and then saying there
that you that you found something and if
you move beyond a proof of concept for
example if you can read local files just
make sure you read local pfizer files
and that's the thing that you that you
report don't try to look for passwords
and then connected to other things
because that will invalidate the
bounties of any fishing and social
engineering engineering attacks against
customers or Microsoft employees are not
allowed as well which make them how do
we reward these things we use the CBS s
version three scoring to determine how
much we actually pay out we look at how
how strong the bug is but we also look
at how much is impacted does it affect
users in the same tenant or across all
tenants or even worse from our
standpoint that it affects all users in
in Microsoft the bounty cells exist off
of a few things there is a cash payout
we usually give em at the end credits
itself so you can download microsoft
software and we keep as your credits as
well because we want to encourage you to
use the platform a lot more
I'm quickly well what I talked about
earlier so for example we have a
multi-talented system there are two ways
if you talk really about authentication
where you can go wrong you can have
horizontal abuse and vertical abuse
horizontal abuse and the name sort of
implies it is when you use your a and
you can become user user be for example
in the same application or from one
application jumping into another or one
step higher if you can go from one
tenant and access to that in the other
tenant vertical abuse as the name
implies is sort of the way up here and
it's a really poor choice of colors no
now I can see when it's presented you
have anonymous users at the bottom if
you can do some dogs become a user in an
application that's that and this is
privilege escalation of course the
higher you go fabric admin which there
are our so that means you can't reach
that level that that's really bad so the
higher you can go the more impact your
bug has and the more the payout will be
so how do we start all this how do we
get cracking right with to access a sure
there's a few ways that you can do one
if you have an msdn or a visual studio
subscription you actually have a droid
credits already we give you one hundred
fifty dollars of credits per month that
you can use to run VMs and whatnot if
you sign up for a sure and then
expansion slides will show you how to do
that you can use it for free for one
month gives you two hundred dollars
which is roughly the equivalent of
running 13 or 14 vm or having 40 sequel
databases or having a terabyte storage
or something in the clouds and then
you'll run out of the two hundred
dollars other things you can do it
instead of radius caches do machine
learning IOC Azure Active Directory and
all those buzzwords once you run out of
money once the ones that month is over
they shouldn't stop testing in fact as
long as you want you can keep on using
Azure Active direction you can create as
many users that you want you can still
deploy I think up to 15 web and mobile
applications you can still do machine
learning you can look you can do log
analytics up to I think 500 megabytes
per day you can still set up your
virtual networks and all the things all
for free for as long as you for as long
as you want
so how do we spin it up relatively
simple initially I was thinking of doing
it live for them with internet you're
not always sure basically if you go to a
short microsoft com you end up on on our
page or if you google or use being
obviously for to go to azure you'll end
up on our on our page there's a big call
to action in the middle there you click
on start free and it'll get you to the
next screen little bit of marketing
thing basically say the same thing as
said before there's two hundred dollars
of free credit you can try any service
if you want which isn't like the old
shareware from the from the 90s and that
shows you how old I am but in the 90s
you would have this function limited
shareware and so on this isn't that you
can use anything you want for the credit
and once that credit is over you pay
nothing at the end you can you can still
do a few things for free you can decide
not to use it anymore or better yet you
can start paying i use it i use it for
real so what do you do you can you click
the start free button gets you to the
next screen you obviously need to sign
in with this you can sign in with a
normal outlook.com account or hotmail
account or a live account or if you have
any work or school organization which is
on a ad when you're using office 365 you
can use that account as well so you
basically look in plus outlook accounts
obviously or free yourself so too young
you need to pay for anything like this
as well you keep your basic information
your name there you are your phone
potentially which company you work for
you have to give your your phone number
and if you change countries for example
i live in canada if you see 200 canadian
dollars is not the same as a 200 US
dollars so if you say you live in canada
it obviously it automatically changes to
250 a canadian dollar so it's always the
equivalent of two hundred US dollars it
gives you a phone number it sends you an
SMS to make sure this phone number
really belongs to you sort of lacking
like an OTP thing you give the code next
thing and this is where a lot of people
are taking a step back a little bit you
have to give credit card information now
we're not going to charge you anything
when we say it's free it's really free
it's just it so it's the reduced froth
is to make sure
that you're really a person that that
you that you have a credit card you fill
in the number obviously I blacked it out
here you put your expiry date a normal
thing if you buy something online and
then after that yeah as I said is it a
few times already your cart won't be
won't be charged and in fact it's not
that when the monthly is over we
suddenly start charging you without
telling you you actually have to
manually enable saying okay from now on
I want to start to start paying so
that's so that's the manual step you
need to do so after that you're ready
you we obviously all read subscription
agreement so you're going to read that
you're going to agree to it and then
you're going to sign up and that's and
that's all that all it takes to get
started to eat with Azure basically how
it looks it'll take a few minutes to set
up your subscription after that is done
there's a big green button in the middle
you click on that and this is the portal
that you end up this is the same total
that all our customers use when they use
a sure as I said there's no test bet
there's no demo environment this is the
real deal from here you can start using
virtual machines you can create
databases deploy applications and what
have you if you want to figure out how
much money you have left of these three
two hundred dollars or how much days you
have left in the month I'm basically
click on the menu on the right at the
bottom it says view my bills it's a few
clicks away then at the bottom you would
click account Center one more click in a
way that if you have more than one
subscription this is the free trial that
you just set up you click on that and
then finally you can see that you have
27 days left and a 250 credits remaining
now why is this 27 days I made this
slice the week ago because I wanted to
make sure at the latest portal and so on
and the Dean wanted to show all screens
februari only has 28 days so now it's
marks you're happy it's 31 days make the
most out of it
so once this is there just to see how
much you have left and an epic weekend
closes again in fact the portal we were
on earlier there are two different
portals the one you saw earlier is the
new one we also have something called
the old portal which looks like this is
a little bit less appealing to the eye
my opinion the good thing about it is
well you can you can still get to these
to manage that Windows Azure calm that
sort of like the previous domain we
don't use it that much anymore the great
thing about it is that it is also
covered in a bug bounty so you're sort
of talking about a codebase that's a few
years old that's not i'm not going to
actively developed anymore because
that's wrong but but we're obviously
pushing a lot of things to the new
portal but this is still part of the of
the bug bounty we're not going to say
well no one uses these anymore so it's
not valid this is there so you can
access assured from a web point of view
to do through two different ways let's
move back to the new portal we can add
users to our tenants you virtually
create an active directory in the cloud
you can add users to it and they can
sign up you can enable notice extra
authentication so they could at the
message when they log on and so on and
so on aside from users you can also add
enterprise applications to it web
applications mobile applications
wherever you want but it's not just only
to the portal in fact if you use visual
studio and you write any asp.net
application you can easily push this to
the to the clouds as well you right
click on your project you click publish
web app it ask you a few questions where
do you want to do it in your data center
or in Azure next thing it will actually
pick up the same subscription that you
have it knows who you are when you're
logged in automatically from here you
can set up some extra things what sort
of machine size you want what's the name
of your resource group would be very
hazardous Pacific things here you can
also see that once you run out of money
you can always still set up a free
website without without an issue it's a
free website hosted in a cloud running
asp now why do I show visual studio in
here because that slides with a Jackie
Chan picture in the beginning you have
multiple applications talking to a shirt
they're all using the either
same or different ap is the visual
studio talks to Azure as well powershell
talks to azure python scripts dr. Azure
this is the huge attack phase attack
surface electric attack surface that
people can can can abuse so don't just
only focus on browsers and so on there's
a lot more you can do it it so that's
basically how are you how you spin up a
sure now now that we are running what
are the rules of the game we sort of
have this thing called DVD to
coordinated vulnerability disclosure we
ask you to keep our customer secure
obviously otherwise I wouldn't have a
job anymore but maintain confidentiality
of bugs only to emma's are see if you
find a bug and you know someone who
works in Microsoft don't send it around
too much just interact with with MSR see
it they have a process that creates the
case out of it and that goes that goes
on there if you want to talk about this
bug please wait until after after its
fact and after it's fixed and if there's
an unfriend on-premises component that
attaches have been released we actually
recommend or we actually asked that you
wait for 30 days so customers actually
have this time to install these things
never publish any exploit code plc code
is fine if you send it to us never say
like this is how you how you hack every
hotmail account in the world and we are
happy to provide any data any technical
data to talk white papers or blogs or
anything that you want so to take to
take actions go to a km/h / bug bounty
for current list of all the active bug
bounties assure is one of them office
365 is one of the Michelle this page
pretty much links you to all the rest
all the domains that are in scope how we
pay out our bugs what is in scope what
is out of scope the denial of service
and all these things identify the bounty
of your honor you want to go after so
you sign up to after you sign up to
office 365 and so on report your
findings to secure at microsoft com and
said they have a process that tracks
everything and and manage it properly
the better you describe a bug any of you
if you probably provide a POC or some
people when they went
to describe it well they send the video
with it as well give some information
about it the more information you give
us a higher quality report is the larger
boundary you get the more impact it has
on Microsoft and Microsoft customers the
higher of a bounty you get obviously
give a name and an email address where
we can reach you back up in the end we
need to know who we who is paying
encrypted with your public key if you
have a nigga exploit code or a plc and
for any eligible bounty cases obviously
get state so as a quick recap we spoke
about about how to sign up to 2a sure
the highway out bounties we have in the
in the back as well at a list of targets
they can go to and how to file bugs if
you want to reach out to me you can
email me at me Henry at by microsoft com
or i'll be here for the next two days as
well just come and i'll just come and
grab me and are there any questions i
know i start speaking fast towards the
end up typically me but are there any
questions whatever catalytically hosted
to Microsoft Azure so what you have
talks about the related to individual
shiancoe Valley how to activate that
type of data in a corporate to give a
corporate login for finding the bug and
getting the not getting earning money
but to follow something that's something
that we're planning to do is and it's
actually a very active is called the
azure penetration testing program for
customers if you are a customer with
Microsoft if you have I assume you have
a tam or an Accounts Manager that you're
working with talk to them about it they
should have details so there's an online
forum already on the agile side where
you can go enroll your company inform
your time that you want to conduct a
penetration testing effort and these are
your domains this is a user-generated
content this is how you would like to go
it & M SRC we anyway get lubed into
working with them but we are more on the
engineering side and we don't work with
end customers and we work with our time
to give us this information but that
program has already been set up to
enable customers to do conducts
penetration testing on as your if you
want additional information I can't ask
you my business card and we can
definitely talk offline on that yes so
there is a the terms have documentation
on how they need to what documentation
they need to provide external customers
in order to work with us it's
essentially an online forum on azure
where you need to fill it out give in
for Microsoft that you are conducting
the penetration testing on your as your
instances so that we don't shut you down
if we think there's some sort of abuse
going on and give us a domain there's an
the tab should be able to guide you
through the entire process and if not
they should have the training
documentation so they should be able to
find the resources to do that and I'm
here for the next Michael and I hear
Swami's also here we also Microsoft for
the next three days hit us up we're more
than happy to discuss this further can
you repeat the question as well as
recording how long does it take
Microsoft attach a bug it depends it
genuinely depends some bugs it depends
on the priority depends on the severity
of the bug it depends on the quality of
report that the researcher has submitted
us and that's why we always ask
researchers to submit high-quality bugs
we try to I can't answer that it just
completely depends on the type of
vulnerability each engineering group is
different each product is different we
try to patch the buggy as fast as
possible to ensure customers are secure
and it's a holistic thing because when
we receive bugs it's not just go do one
particular fix and that's that we do
variant analysis for all the
vulnerabilities and Swami in his talk
tomorrow in the wind
of mitigation we'll talk about how we
use all this information variant
analysis work with different engineering
teams to do a very holistic patch
because we want to ensure that no one
can just bend if what patch you've taken
and then it basically becomes moot all
the work that we've done but in short it
depends I'm sorry from the business
perspective from the technical service
catalog perspective we should have the
service definitions well defined in line
with the turnaround time for specific
vulnerability or bug so we definitely
are in line with industry standards gbv
and a few other folks externally have
set what the industry standards will
look like and we are in line for all of
those we make sure that as soon as we
get information for vulnerabilities it's
not like we sit on them we immediately
take action and make sure the patches
are released for any customers in a
holistic way as soon as possible oh
that's as earliest as early as possible
I understand but do we have the define
SN iphone that I think your technical
account manager should be able to give
you additional information on that but I
won't be able to speak to that here all
right just one question in verse slide
you have said that we should not
disclosed p or seen in public but
recently as p.m. tonight at google has
disclosed windows hn indian next or even
if it is exploit so any thought on that
early what Microsoft has been fun any
stops on that my diplomatic start is it
intersects a sure sighs enough
yeah i think that's that's that's the
right answer yeah i'm here to talk about
Asher one more hopefully an easier
question so my question is related to
SEO and I want to know that what are the
different service that edge is providing
for handling the incident response in
case somethin happens on our as your
infrastructure so how as a company we
should go for it to Miz look for what
are different instances or different
services we should look into it I don't
understand exactly what like ink in AWS
we had cloud trail and cloud watch on
different blogs where we can look into
the words our different authenticated
means different actions has been taken
by the attacker but what means is
irrespective of track what are the
different shall we see that SEO is
providing for looking into
unauthenticated access I'm different
action or different services that
anything i don't know exactly if you and
I know this is a very bad answer to give
but if you go on the azure website to
see all the security offers we do we do
detection for for scanning for passwords
password abused and all the things as
well so we have those things built in
the balance reckon i can give you i'm on
the offensive side so i don't know
exactly what as a result keeping to
automatically presented aquila looks
angry at me and I'm sure she's gonna
know I think what I would recommend is
microsoft india team is here and a lot
of them are the folks working with the
customers and they work and there's also
a bunch of folks on the marketing sites
they inherently know a lot of the
information that customers will use for
detection so I would recommend speak to
microsoft india the microsoft booth they
have a bunch of tsps there to help
answer that question is it a product or
i'm just talking about a basic services
that a company should look into a lot of
that is baked into the service and then
I think they're different tiers of azure
as you go as your company decides to
adopt a few tears they have different
detections
that get big into office 365 and Asia
but depending on what you ended up
purchasing there we go did we definitely
have a huge booth here and the lots of
folks are microsoft india so if you have
specific questions about how your
technical account managers can help you
or specifically on products please
please feel free to reach out to them
unfortunately via time out of time small
portions okay yes I'm cool um thank you
very much as Adam was saying rifles
before it right here this is the pass
phrase that you need for the CTF to get
your extra 25 credits