Ueno-san paid off 10 years in the 1st session of the last session.
It
's a bit early, but
that route start
clos 40 is a bit too early for soccer
, isn't it
?
Web's
10 years of eating oysters
There was a serialization, but
I've been talking mainly about the
story of this series.
In the latter half of this
, I thought I'd try to deal with
recent data for both of
them.
I've seen quite a lot of them, and there's a
trending Articles of Incorporation judge behind
them.
I've already done about 44
tests, and
there are so
many.  Around the same time as Bouba, that
guy called Anonymous got dirty.
It's the main
feeling, but hacking is also included
. IP Cyber ​​Investigation
Team This is TV
Asahi, isn't it
?  But that's
why other Pokka companies supervised
things like this, too
.  or Mr. Luck
Well, it's already been worked out, isn't it?
It's hard for a hacker to be the main character, isn't it?
There's that
kind of slave
I'd like to see a
bit of it, but umm, well, the hacker's expression in that video It's a story in the first half, but it's a bit difficult, isn't it
?  I haven't seen hackers at all,
but what
about the direction? The hacking scene
is, after all, something like that new interface that's a
little
cg-like, and there's always something like that of a
laptop computer.  I'm going to do something about people who are just showing off
.  Well, at that time, hey,
well, that scene where the Falcon flies,
here, I've made a lot of
silly hacks with
that guy.
The editor of the web company wrote
an article about hardships behind the scenes in the scans he was doing, did
n't he?
I feel like I want to cherish each and every process, but I said that I would
show it in the express video that is
sold in the video.
It's fine, but I've been told that
it's a custom, but it's
very rare, but it's important.
No, it's just good again, isn't it? There's a
project on it,
so many names come up.
When you try to depict it in detail, in
terms of visual expression, that sense
of speed disappears even if you pass it through
.
Also,
why recently
?  It's
just a lecture about things
like Fear's length and so on.  But
that's the secret behind breaking this password
.
Isn't it great when a music scene appears in a drama?
Only the scene at hand is according
to Proger.  I want it, but I want it to
sound
like it's being played properly
.
But, yeah, yeah,
yeah, I think it was before
.
to
high  If the king scene is
okay, it's the one that Rear Rack was
doing, right? Yes, that
cyber defense head supervised
it.
It's not that
kind of acting instruction that shows how the stand is
doing now, but there's an
article
saying that they did
something like that.  It feels like technical guidance,
but it seems that this area is about to be included. Yes, it's a relatively difficult place.
Security camps and
earning cones are often mentioned, but a
Conversely, I
wonder if we're the one who's doing it.
It's the flat
security that plays that role, but what is it?
I thought
it was a bit nice to have a bar that looked like something
you know.
Hmmm nup
If it wasn't for manga or movies,
we'd have to go beyond reality
.
Well, that
's good, Anz. It was just a panel
discussion
.
I'm doing art production, and I'm going to edit
it.
After all, the inclusion is like this video
It's a work, isn't it?
I think it's gradually permeating TV and other things
.
It
's already over,
isn't it
?  It's a very realistic
depiction, and well, it's the same for
children,
isn't it?
For example, there are actually a lot of people
like that, so it's green radish.
It's been about 10 years now, and I
've been running quite a bit, even though I
need physical strength.
I don't think it's because of the
influence
of Nimasu, but Ozawa does
n't care. Japanese dramas have a slightly lower production cost
.
ーExpression and processing
PatternsーIt's earthy, isn't it? Well, it
's
like South Korea
.
South Korea Manga and movies are amazing now, are
n't
they? The same goes for music, is
n't it?
A little j on Netflix
Ariel's bell ringing key is good
.
When I say run, I
've loved independence day since then.
I want
Connor Arthur, who picked up + or once with a pen on 4 Independence Day,
is
n't he?  I love that
, hmm Roland Emmerich Park
likes really big things The
1996 movie
I'm talking about Oh, there's a huge spaceship out there It
's kind of weird, isn't it?
For a moment without disappearing,
that's right, that's right, the president is a child who pretends to be a beautiful game of fighter planes, and it's the most amazing
thing.
It
's stressful to
say that I'm using a mac powerbook
5300. I think it's amazing binary compatibility
.  I don't know what kind of bribery I'm going to
do, but I don't know if it's working in such a place
.
You have to get close to each other and you have to communicate.It
's probably a relatively short-distance
communication or 6
short-distance communication protocols,
but I don't know
how the bluetooth is so
powerful.  I mean, even if we get close,
the contents of those communications and the
promises will be the same,
right?
Since the repair work of the
spacecraft was attached, it seems that the protocol is probably a school
milk.
Ah, I see. That's not vulnerable. It's
amazing, it's just infected with a
virus.
Please say it's not the real person.
It
was a good month for my sister, but I liked it and said it with momentum
.
There's a manga What? It's
unexpected, but it's a
change,
isn't it?
Well, I thought
you
didn't want to say "back" when you read it on purpose,
but if it's not your head, then you can't
do this.
In a strange case
, there might be a movie company list gold industry
.
You
can see it as a fever, you
know, it's like I'm indigestion, and I'm worried about it
again, and I
'm raped.
I thought I'd take a look at it
next time.
Cyber ​​Revenger is a
former 007, isn't he
? ap love Labor Union 7
Oh, I wonder if he'll play an active role in Aizu 007
.
Kana Sono is actually stalking
Internet stalking is quite
a subject that has been taken up
in various content such as movies from Fluke.  So, the internet
or something like that is used, isn't it?
I bought a related movie that will be posted on SNS later in a
qualitative sense, right?
The screen ends on the SNS of this guy, the
child who can't hit this look already I saw it on International Assistance
Day or if I was listening to it
I wanted it quite a lot I can only see it at that level Mr.
Adama, the secretary  And then there's the mystery solving
, and I think I'm a girl, and I'm a
good girl.  Well, outside of Hollywood, yeah, it
's up on Tuesday,
and the actor who plays the picture of the main
character
is Saatchi.  It's Ise,
and it feels like it's really representing the times
.
Properly zooming in, demonstrating
Toko-chan
Movie oh yeah It's true Zoom movie I ca
n't see it
I wrote
that you shouldn't use zoom for something like
that, even
Yurashi-chan.
Let's go
year,
that kind of thing
like the Internet is already appearing in every movie and every drama
, isn't it
?  There are
quite a lot of people
who say that they are good at raw computers
or something like that.  I don't think there are people who
normally look up their SNSs normally among the people who normally stand up and operate in various ways, even as people who collect information
,
like the current police investigation.
Well, this is a long-running drama
called Criminal Minds in America, is
n't it empty of profiling?
It's a premise
that the person can
draw out as much information as possible from
various sources,
but there's
a Higashi-Ue field called My Stand, isn't it?
Even if you look at the shopper, you can see the antenna, but I think it's a little bit, but if you
call him a super hacker and say that he
can extract various information, you can
advance the story quickly
.  Amazing dere
Gesture kids Well then fur
Actually, what kind of intrusion does that kind of information come out
?  I
don't know who's information Is it an SNS style? No,
this village isn't armed with data
.
It's
hard to get confidence, but
it's hard to find information after that.
That kind of
information is nothing but a
hit, but recently
there are a lot of companies using that cloud type,
so when they break in through a pen test, they search for
something like google drive
.  It's easier to find it now
, but it's well done.
Isn't there one
?  It
's
summer, so I think it's convenient, so I can't
underestimate searching.
Once you're done with it, you'll be able to use the tool, which
means
that it's convenient, and it's equally useful for
everyone.
It's a
serge, and it
's one and another It
's an old drama, but I'd
like to
see
it  You know it's
a character from the office file Groove leg file x9 x
file meeting It's a spinoff
I don't think it's popular, so
it's like a home 4 f
I shouldn't have done that spin-off Oh,
no, it's a
door.
Heh, that's all
sorts of things that were useful in pulling out all sorts of information, so I
'm Investigator Mulder from my own point of view, I'm tired.
If you start to feel like Nishichae, it's
okay Sakura
That's a pinch, so the
simultaneous terrorist attacks
You say you're painting your eyes, right?
That's what you say,
it seems that there are some hacking elements in it
, right
?  Yeah,
when I'm researching various things about it, sometimes that tech geek
comes out and
shares it, but after all, it's like a convenient person who comes out and researches even if it's a franc, is
n't it
?
But I'd also like to take a
look at it
.
I
've read something called "connect with big data" data
correct, isn't it
? Actually, I
like Nisho Hayakawa Bunko
.  I think for a moment
that we're going to go with the ax case
.
I think it's interesting, but I'd like to see the
idea of ​​peace, yeah, I want to see the fans and the hugging style ignite
.
I'm the Kyoto Prefectural Police, so I'll answer OK, and I love the first Bon
season, right
?  It's quite interesting tomorrow, so I
'll wait and read it.
It's a little bit of a story, but
novels
can be covered
quite well with descriptions
.  One,
so as long as it's
logical, if it doesn't break down logically, there
's no danger that we'll be forced into the details.
What's good about manga,
you and us
Let's talk about access, let's talk about
it.It would be nice
if it sold as
well.How many
years is
it?  It was fun,
right,
Mr. B and his wife
.
I do it and openly sell
it, but
that's a comic
book, or I get an account
.
When it comes to having people read it,
recently,
the children of today are more interested in manga and other things than in the past,
but
I think it's quite
nice to pass it on to their grandchildren.  It's easy to bake, after
all, that's what I mean, even in
the cleaner's camp lecture, I was selling a little bit
about how to get a pass
, but manga is, well, isn't it
?
When I tweet on twitter, the picture is a
thumbnail, and
I'm really eye-catching
.  I'm glad it's so
real.
I feel like I'm really in
demand,
and I think there will be more and
more scenes where j is needed more and more in the future.  When I think about
it,
I don't think it's strange if that way of working is a little less
.
Trying hard to notice various things  I
'm going to do my best and try to make an effort
Wow,
not even one bullet
Kane Spa
That's right
, I declared my retirement once, but
if I take it from there, it's better to line up, so
please call pets for about 3
months.
I think the taste is one
minute.
Hey, I want to say it while drinking a little bit,
right?  Hi, it's
by-sama, so
what's
going on now?