hello how are we this is going to be
completely different to what you feel
lessons to do today no idea
I do give talks outside the industry
surprisingly it does exist a world
outside and a lot of the time I'm asked
to talk about some of the skills I use
in the job and I thought I'd have a look
today is that what I needed to do first
of all as an experiment so I'm going to
talk a bit about deception and deception
detection I am I'm gonna give you some
stats later about how the general public
and a couple of different professions
are we're detecting lies but I wanted to
see how a security audience would do so
I've got three people are gonna help me
out I am and I'm just gonna need to do
something for a minute so in my hands
I've got three pieces of paper identical
and what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna get
three of my volunteers want you to do
for the three people you are piece of
paper on to the pieces of paper a blank
and one of them's got the word lie on it
in a minute I'm gonna ask you to tell me
more and just give the audience two
sentences okay if you've got nothing on
the piece of paper just tell the truth
and if you've got the word lie just like
to make something off all I want you to
do is very briefly tell the audience
about a memorable meal okay
so nothing that anyone was with you at I
am just very briefly you know what it
was why it was memorable could have been
good could have been bad anything like
that okay and what I want you guys to do
is see if you can spot the liar all
right so do that in a minute
so obviously as a social engineer a lot
of the time I'm actually introduced as a
professional liar
we're so a bit of an insult I'm and I
suppose it's kind of true you know if
you define deception as the act of
hiding the truth illegal methods used to
get to something or to make people
believe that something is true and it
isn't social engineers are professional
liars and obviously we use that and
various ways throughout the job so
whether it's physical infiltration
whether it's writing spear phishing
emails I am any kind of contact involves
deception but also there's another part
of the job where Lane and outs of spot
deception is quite useful on the
investigative side on the defense side
so I learned a I did some extensive
studying on credibility interception a
few years ago and I've used it in the
job for various things now if I'd
mentioned today inside a threat a few
times I said deception worth is involved
with that we put emails and awesome
investigations for clients so for all
clients criminal clients and also a lot
of high net worth individuals they were
looking at their teams and looking to
see if we can spot if you like the
insider threat and it's also applied in
what we call we now have to call
intensive interview we used to call
interrogation we're not allowed to call
it interrogation anymore I'm really not
supposed to call intensive you're
supposed to call invest it's it but the
reason this matters is because the
insider threat is on the increase I am
or at least the report of it is and when
you think you've identified insider
threat and you want to go through what
they've written and perhaps do
face-to-face interviews if some of the
stuff I'm gonna tell you stay might help
you spot as some deception now before I
give any further on that I just wanna
let you know this is a massive area I am
it takes years to get even close to
perfecting it
and I've seen half an hour I'm gonna
give you a few pointers but I still
think in this community
useful aim and that's why I put out
there so if I could have my three
memorable meals don't be insulted by the
potatoes I did say to you if we could
have Tom and Eve and say oh come on just
tell us about your meal now please don't
be insulted by the potatoes I set a
memorable meal they said Island you've
got to put spuds oh and I thought you
wouldn't like that but then they say so
yeah just so why don't you just observe
make it making mind or put don't say
anything to anyone raise your hands or
anything and we'll do it again at the
end Tom let me watch you though
my memorable my oatmeal was in New York
City
Peter Lugar's it was with two friends
who are 40 are no longer with us
and I heard about this restaurant
because I watched a TV show about it
where they hung the meat downstairs and
when I asked if I could go and see the
place downstairs the waiter kind of
threateningly said to me we can't let
you down there because you might slip
and hurt yourself which felt more like a
threat than a warning my most memorable
meal was when I was also in New York
City at lathe Hall as a steak house
there and it was a fantastic meal and
Colin Farrell ball people was at the
next table and that was it was a pretty
interesting
[Laughter]
my memorable meal was at the witchery in
Edinburgh with my mum who's no longer
with us and it was amazing we were
watching the fireworks on and New Year's
Eve out of the window so that was mine
[Music]
in your hair anyone else see if you can
pick out which one you think was the one
that was telling a lie and then what
we'll do is we'll ask you to play it one
more time before the end after I've
given you some tips and then we'll have
a show of hands of who we think but just
to put my money where my mouth is
I'm gonna write down on here who I think
it is and we'll see if I go straight as
well okay okay so find out whether
someone's tell the truth to tell a lie
has been the holy grail for humanity for
ever okay we've got lots of different
lie detection methods back in ancient
China
you see he's of a spoon I'm put it in
someone's mouth and if it stuck to your
tongue you were lying because they were
awakened on the see that your mouth goes
dry when you lie which is sometimes Joss
and I'll show you why in a minute
we've got the bucket della verita in
Rome which was someone who's accused of
a lie let's just put the hand in the
mouth and now if they were telling the
truth the hand came out intact if they
were lying they'd lose some fingers it
probably doesn't take a genius to work
out that there was someone standing
behind the Baka Televisa with a big
sword you see light attached as a
political thing a lot of the time a lot
of the basis collection methods are
political the data sacks tend to be
biased
so for example a lot of the technology
only focuses on at white males even
though it's used to help convince people
of color and other things you might be
familiar with docking stores hopefully
you're not and then you know the tack
goes on we've got things like tooth
serums you know McMansion polygraphs
polygraphs do not measure credibility or
deception what they measure is
psychophysiological responses so
everything from pupil dilation to
endocrine activity so how much you sweat
a blood pressure that type of thing they
work well because people think that they
work but actually what the measureless
stress responses it's the question in
technique and the convicts or gets
people to aim to look guilty and admit
guilt and then we've got things like a
because I thought I put tack in for you
you see there's even one slide just
wrote technical cloud which is a high
definition thermal camera images
basically the face everyone but what's
so lovely is everyone is exactly the
same under this skin right human face
has 44 muscles and they move in certain
ways when we experience one of the seven
major emotions and regardless of your
age gender ethnicity anything else these
are the seven you might need must make
her facial expressions people to keep
trying to describe as a micro facial
expressions but I am the research just
over again shoes that we all do the same
thing I've no more time to talk to you
about that today unfortunately we've
also got brain scan technology because
apparently part of the brain when it
remembers lights off as opposed to part
of the brain and that's never seen
something before lights up just got
implications if people are accused of
say for example of murder and you show
them a picture the scene if they've seen
it before one side of the brain lights
up if they've never seen it the other
side does so in theory it's gonna help
with
innocent people are Hughes de crimes and
then finally we've got hey I
particularly looking to go into a of
course and the problem with all the
technology is that just tends to be a
lot of false positives and of course
some guilty people get through as well
so we're still not there with the
technology now we are crap as a species
a detect interception okay and this is
why I'm so interested in this little
experiment that I'm doing the general
public had no basis and chance and
needless law enforcement depending on
what study you look at anything between
49 53 percent intelligence community our
own slightly better but it shouldn't
surprise you to see that maximum
security prisoners are the best people
in the world reason emotion and detect
and weather basically someone is
bluffing and that's because it's
obviously a marshal life-and-death
whether they know that deception
detectors as in people who've done all
the training claimed seventy percent
right now anecdotally it's hard to prove
sometimes because sometimes we never
know the outcome and so what we never do
is say whether someone's telling a lie
or tell the truth we give a balance of
credibility so the probability of
credibility is acts so why are we so bad
firstly because you do not want to
believe that people are liars now this
is the security community but we are
paranoid and we don't mind this or a
general public want to believe that
people they want to come from a good
place they want to believe that people
are honest more than people are
deceptive and there's also some people
will incredibly go today so if you go to
the sociopathic psychopathic tendencies
and the lies we hast very well so
whether we can spot someone lyin depends
on the person who's doing the lie the
lie itself and the consequence is the
enormity of it and the life spotter
right so some people are bastards
detecting it for other reasons but we
also like to think that good-looking
people are people who look the part and
sound the past a good we are we make our
mind off as a species very quickly on
whether someone's credible or not and
that can cause us problems because we
all now
that what people think we are and what
we actually are sometimes not the same
we've also got things like biases
kicking in if you've decided something
is right and particular if you've
declared it in public it's very hard
psychologically to go back on that
there's also an awful lot of frankly
rubbish and pseudoscience about lie
detection particularly the eye movement
thing and which is from the discredited
pseudoscience my opinion only of NLP and
the eye movements is not credible as
being disproved by a professor Wiseman
and others over the years so well
rubbish at it and we shouldn't be
because when we lie we give off lots of
signals what we have to do so tell a lie
the first thing you have to do is
conceal the truth right you have to
remember the thing that you're trying
not to talk about make sure that you can
seal it and the other thing you have to
do is fabricate a new tooth preferably
one that is credible and and you need to
forget the old one and wait with the new
one you also have to try and look
innocent and not arouse suspicion this
genius broke into a house stole a phone
took a photograph of himself with the
phone in the house and then sent it to
the lady's wife means in car services
and you also have to cover your
deceptive actions with something else
and try and give a story the covers of
what happened
and also you have to remember the
details of a new story
I'm preferably not one that anyone else
can deny and so what happens is your
brain student a lot of heavy liftin it
kind of overloads we call cognitive
overload and I was just but we say to
you for a technical analogy but what
it's like is this so you live around of
course my kids ever technical flight
why I used to describe it to
non-technical people we perhaps wouldn't
judge me so bad if I get this wrong is
it's just like having every program open
on that on your computers like
everything's going on your brains doing
the heavy lifting and what happens is
that you leak
you start to leak information now we
don't have time today for me to give you
too many details but I went across the
said entrapped system so basically when
I'm interviewing and someone who is a
person of interest another inquiry we
look at different things we look at
these seven things and today I'm just
gonna focus on a couple of them for you
okay the man that I do not want to split
up any marriages cause any problems in
work just me telling you this does not
mean you can conclude they're just some
tips okay very minutes the first thing
you need to understand is that a myths
about body language okay and we wouldn't
even refer to as body language in the
trades you defense don't variables and
there's so much about that I really even
can't even begin to address us today but
basically Jess just can't be judged
because they're nuanced in the same way
that we have language within our
community that is body language within
communities even within families so you
can't really judge that's what I'm going
to show you it's what human beings do
under certain conditions so you can see
what stress looks like but from a body
language point of view the first thing
that we would look at is just these
three things
you basically assess them when you're
looking at a subject is this person are
they confident or do they lack
confidence right just generally without
any other trained and remember that
we've got only used words for about
ninety thousand years as a species but
we've been communicating for millions of
years as long as you don't believe in in
that we just landed a 2,000 years ago or
whatever and and so we've always
communicated without words right so
you've got a lot going for you up front
so they confidence are not are they
comfortable or not I'm particularly and
pacifically in there not so much a cyber
security well but insecurities are they
calm or agitated okay now all that is as
data we don't conclude it's just is it
this or is
is it they stories of this once we know
that and once we establish I am
someone's kind of base state and I'm
going to talk more about that later and
the next thing to know is what stress
looks like in a human being to tell a
lie to the other dishonest or deceptive
is a stress factor in human beings and
because it's a stress factor it kicks
off certain things in our physiology and
particularly in the brain so what we're
dealing here with here and I'm very
careful to say this is he's sitting
right next to me is the autonomic
nervous system or ans right is it just
me not got no so what that does the
autonomic nervous system and it controls
the automatic functions of the body okay
and what it does is it sends signals out
to the heart the lungs internal organs
new glands particularly in the reason
glands are important is because they
start to make the chemicals that assist
in fight or flight which I'll show you
in a minute
and but the the autonomic nervous system
is associated with the threat okay
and so what it does is it's constantly
scouring the environment looking for
threats to your well-being or for
anything significant to your well-being
and it's due and it automatically
without you realizing it if it was more
conscious it'd be slower and it wouldn't
save you so you can imagine if you drive
no long and a car pulls out in front of
you a whole heap of things happen you
know you might go through the brake you
might turn the wheel but before you've
even turned to do that your pupils are
dilated to taking the threat and then
constrict it to focus upon it and a lot
of other things are happening you've got
a chemical cocktail going through your
system everything getting ready to
protect you but it's not subconscious we
call it opaque to consciousness so it's
kind of happen and even beyond
subconscious okay and it's there to
protect you and we use in social
engineering because what we know is that
if we can get someone into an emotional
state we can override the part of the
brain the neocortex which is actually
your thinking brain okay so what happens
is the thalamus here
sorry biology lesson um the thalamus
here processes visual in order to audio
signals common in from that automatic
system and it passes passes it through
to the rest of the brain it goes pretty
much straight to the amygdala which
controls emotion
the amygdala works very very quickly and
overrides everything else and so we act
in that emotional fog and that's where
social engineering comes in because if
you can raise that in a pace and their
decision-making capacity just plummets
okay finally when the threat goes and
when the state starts to kind of climb
down for that emotional state that
informations pass to the neocortex which
is the human the rational part of the
brain and we have more time to think
about it which is why all the floor
programs and everything's help people to
take - and to step back and just come
away from the immediate situation and
the thing is when you lie it's a state
of fear as much as anything else a case
of stress and fear are very similar in
this particular area and fear is a
prescription right so we're all scared
of some universal things just as humans
but every human scared edition thinks oh
I'm scared of spiders there'll be people
our neighbors probably pets by just
given the crowd so um so it's on a
spectrum of stress okay so let's imagine
that you're an insider threat of some
other am bad actor and someone's
investigating you and talking to you
what do you what happens to you from
that autonomic nervous system that you
can't do anything about and we go into
the freeze fight and flight mechanism so
in freeze mode now not everyone does
this in the exact same order by the way
and that the strength of it's different
for different people because people
individual can control things
differently but typically what we see
first is that people go into sort of
rabbit in the headlights syndrome right
to the becomes slower and what they do
they have little flash freezes when we
interview them and I film a lot of it
and then analyze it later
I am the nervous system starts to raise
the blood pressure the breasts become a
bit shallow and but the main thing that
we see in interview is that you find
motor skills
knocked out by this state so what
happens is people will if they're
sipping water or wherever they'll put
the cup down and if they draw in or do
and I think else they stop everything
become a lot more still if that doesn't
work in other words because keep and
still is your best defense against a
predator right if you've got you've seen
Jurassic Park most of the movement right
I am but what the thing is in this
situation in investigators interview
they can't get away so they go into
flight mode from what happens in flight
mode the blood gets directed to the legs
by the autonomic nervous system because
that your biggest muscles are in your
legs
so that's your best chance of escape so
now you've got blood come through your
legs
you've got chemicals coursing through
your system and everything's telling you
to get away but you can't get away right
the threat is still there so what
happens as we have near this energy and
people start to fidget and that's where
certainly law enforcement over the years
have told me the fidgeting and stuff is
a sure sign for them that something's
wrong okay
and what is if you're trying to get rid
of that energy but you can't run and but
the edge two runs there and it becomes
irresistible finally if that doesn't
work we go to fight mode and our
proximity to other people becomes closer
if you want to have a factor that is
just put your hand
don't touch the person next year but
just what the fingers close to their
face as you possibly can without
touching them I see so many people
didn't even do it you don't like it
because you become a space invader right
but in fight mode you get closer to
people the eyes focus on the object of
the attack your brain sharp and some
starts to recall things and natural
anesthetics kick in so if you're
introduced about the ability to run away
that's why you feel pain sometimes after
the fact but what tends to happen in
that situation is that we don't
physically fight anymore we argue and
because we've evolved so what happens is
you've got assert that you've got a
subject you think as guilty you've got
them under pressure you see in these
stress signs and now you've got a choice
and the choice day is do we keep them
under pressure or to be like them off
and that's up to the investigator so I
just want to finish with a few things
just before
time's up I just want to show you three
things about linguistic flags and
indicators right now so say please just
take this as a starter pattern do not go
home and judge people for the first
thing that we would do is ask the
subject to talk about whatever the event
or events are that were asking them
about to see if they're guilty and what
we're looking at for here is narrative
balance so story should have a beginning
a middle and an end
typically and remember I'm only saying
typically because it's so nuanced but
typically an innocent person will tell
the story or focus a lot on the heart of
the matter what most people who ask
questions and interviews don't do is
focus on the real topic in hand right so
criminals and Liars can talk for any
amount of time about their journey and
what they have for lunch and everything
else it's when you get on to the actual
subject that they accused of or all the
difficulty and that they have trouble so
we get them to focus on that so it's a
story and what make sure they focus on
the middle bit safer believe or tell no
lie we focus more on what's not the
topic all the indicators refusal to
answer the question right so if you're
asked a question like it most innocent
people if I said - did you kill someone
on Tuesday you'll know unless you did
and again who knows this crowd did you
kill someone to sing now but
unfortunately all typically liars
wouldn't do that they'd start talking
about other things they change the
subject
you have a comfort break or the answer
another question well let me tell you
about Tuesday the other thing that they
do and innocent people don't do this but
often guilty people do this as they
start making what we call hailing
statements is so they say things like
I'm on my honor as God is my witness why
you ask to me you know I've always been
a great employee right where's innocent
people time to go no I didn't do it how
could you possibly accuse me of that
it's not company policy that's like the
thing the reason is is the two full
witnesses the more confident the facts
will prove what they're saying so they
don't need to say I'm a good person
right
there's also flat refusal to deny if you
remember this scene from Game of Thrones
where she said she should be felt little
fingers crimes and after everyone she
says do you deny it and he never denies
it and it unfortunately were not
unfortunately but typically that's the
case they just fail yet to deny the
other thing is is not answering the
question with javis answer in a general
question right so did your more back
Hill all those people well she would
never fly yeah but we're not talking
about a fly we're talking about people
she's accused imagine do you say I'm
really the last one distance and
language you know I am typically when
someone's lying in my still to us they
won't use hair or the name so in
strategy or not uses that woman and then
says her name after pause we caught
response latency so typically and this
would be an indicator when this came on
everyone in the community the latest
action community and the phone yeah if
I'm was kind of pinging each other and
everything else because it was very
clear indicator truthful people their
story is logical by which I mean often
when someone's telling you either just
the fuck still nods off so we had an
incident once where someone said well
you know I was in they were saying that
they were important say at nine o'clock
in the morning but the thief managed to
get to Aberdeen for example by lunchtime
the fuck is just a lot of snot logical
it's not consistent we also have issues
of aim you might think about what
details right when people tell them the
truth what happens saves your memory
memories of rubbish I have manipulate
your memory lighting give all the time
in where we can manipulate memory become
pictures and images numbers and people's
heads all the time but when you'd be man
during something because the truths on
your side things pop into your head all
the time so you come up with IEDs silly
details that aren't really relevant to
the story the story pops all around so
you never heared at one point and then
you can go backwards and forwards you
can move along the truthful story really
easily because you'll be member in but a
liar typically will be here's a story
from start to finish so if you ask them
to go in and out of that Marisa
it's quite a difficult thing to do and
what they probably haven't flossed to do
is put some irrelevant detail in you
know so when I say relevant details it
might be like over since a few Mon lady
and she said oh yes I mean though it was
a really it was a big fraud and way and
there was a lot of money at stake and
she'd been socially engineered so she's
why I was looking on it and you know I
remember that day sharing I look good
because I cut my hands and actually
there was blood all over the post-it
knows was horrible actually people
wondered well that's not one to do with
this is it
well no it's nah right but you wouldn't
remember it we'll put that in unless you
would be mad you know it's like it's
unlikely Ally would put those kinds of
details and um so memory remembers
relevancy as much as two elephants okay
and then we use emotions I got no time
today stored you anymore about emotions
but you know the study of and the
manipulation that's at the heart of
social engineering but the way it
affects people's at the heart a lie
detection as well so I just wanna am
before we go into our se how we did on
our lie detection I'm just gonna give
you this sexy model it's really
important that I tell you this because
some of the stuff I just tell you is
fairly powerful I am and I don't want
you to just go in and use it so this is
the way it works the first thing you do
when you learn a subject is you look at
the baseline for the subject
okay so what's that person like when
they've no reason to I see you and
they're not under pressure once you have
that baseline established you'll home
for a change in state so a very both
space and stop store in a relaxed pace
and becomes more agitated that type of
thing when you see that the context is
everything so nine times out of ten you
know if people are rubbing their eyes or
squinting or touching the face that can
be a deceptive sign but often it's just
because they're tired or they're looking
into the Sun we look for clusters not
single signals and we offer congruence
so is what they say a matching off with
the way they behave not and all these
interfaces if you think you see
something it is not an opportunity to
draw conclusions to project to suggest
it's just a circle action and at that
point it's your cue to use question and
technique
in order to get that pair some more
under pressure that under sistine off
their time the truth or a lie but I've
no time to tell you about questioning
techniques you just have to ask me back
to Dublin actually if you want to know
about that so wanna say so if we can
have our three volunteers up again I'm
going you just tell the same story again
and then if no one can do anything from
it and don't tell us if you're like if
you got the light AB and if ya and I'm
just gonna ask for show hands we'll see
how we did my favorite meal was in a
restaurant called Peter Lugar's in New
York City with two friends who are
fortunate with us and I particularly
remember it because I seen the
restaurant on a TV show and I'd heard
that they hung to meet themselves
downstairs where I asked a view it's the
waiter said to me I can't let you do
that because you might slip and have an
accident which sounded more like a
threat than a warning my memorable meal
was with my mum at the which we
restaurant in Edinburgh and it was
really memorable because it was newsy we
were watching the fireworks out as a
window and my what my memorable meal was
that Liz Hall in New York City and would
just happen to be that Colin Farrell
sitting at the next seat and I'll leave
in the back is pretty much accepted
all right so if you just done my chairs
I don't you remain standing so from a
show of hands can have a show of hands
who thinks that Tom what you've Tom for
me hands up if you think Tom was the one
Tom the lie okay hands down never show
of hands if you thought that it was date
you tell my hands down if you thought it
was Sarah okay hands down if I could ask
the two people tell the truth to sit
down and the patient on the lie to
remain standing and thanks for listening
[Applause]