more than everyone and thanks for coming
and so I'm going to present our humans
of one of those well before I start I
want to say a thanks to Brian forgive me
the opportunity to speak ours come today
so we're gonna start off with Who am I
so my name is Emma I'm Ashlyn I'm a
third year student in technology lien
first student and instead in
cybersecurity and digital forensics true
this I play CTF so my work is in
part-time security analyst or odd stuff
so yeah sorry
and so I also play CTF son true like
school I've always wants to be a maths
eternal wasn't Center where I wanted to
go to one three months each until you
two accountancy and things didn't go my
way and I don't aside straight to come
back in June 2016 and I kind of led me
to around I just like suicide security
and true that I'm at a few my lectures
they they have strong CTF which is zero
days then so my computer and sure that I
got onto the national team for armed has
sort of compete there and depressed
sterner Anya this year and
secure that that's my passion of
cybersecurity months at Mathematica
logical problem solving and so I'm gonna
go on to do we feel that humans are from
bility to companies and well simple
answer is yes I've hunted a
vulnerability to any region already so I
think that we do and so she was further
I'm gonna go on to my own fish or
spearfishing experience true in the
summer I started with the internship
four nights gun and I tweeted about
straighten and it's gone how excited I
was
I drew this I had a lot of people
congratulating the same welder on that
was great
then I tweeted this that I found a ball
gun or what looked like a ball done to
her which wasn't a local about me so I
posted this and had loads people like
you know get in contact say here's what
you could do here some suggestions but I
had one guy on he was a bit like oh DME
he tweeted a couple times under my post
smells like okay yeah ground so I opened
my DM that message me and he was like oh
hey like you can do they're seeking
duple panties sitting so I had a look
and then I kind of gave up the whole
book because it wasn't a book and then
kind of few days later he kept texting
me and saying oh you know what's this
terrain for so he asked me about a
domain I had been scanning the company's
Network obviously homes kinda didn't
reply didn't wanna you know reveal too
much information laughter it could have
been a security breach
could've been a serious security breach
if I had just given any information to
this guy and crying alarm bells to me
cuz you know I don't he started a
nightstand a couple weeks and I'm just
this guy you know getting a contact so
you know I think what's this yo for so
it was kind of like as if he saw me as
the weakling for the company and also
for mobility to company so then when
they got me thinkin he sent me a message
I'm a good hacker and I don't talk you
don't worry and I'm right
okay so I kind of I was picking about us
so it's like I'll check out his profile
look this profile not sees a
Piketon hacker so whatever app lights
and hackers I'm not sure and if anyone
knows you can let me know and so after
this he kind of we had reached the line
he kept asking random questions like oh
just study here and you do this and you
work this and you know he knew my
birthday he knew what our information
from my LinkedIn account which I put all
the information on late dinner Twitter
that I want people to know and so he had
enough information if you had asked me
what my dog's name was he for me got
into my email or whatever and so I
blocked him good-bye tumble through the
whole process of learning from this I'd
record of Bryan's made sure that the
company was aware that this guy had
asked me what this you're Alice for and
not thought I gave them any information
about the company well if he had a tried
anything like any attacks against D or
another and so and so I'd love to what
triggers I kind of learned less than
that I should have opened my dancer
destoy and I should always be wary who
he adds you know how much he gives these
people like they're experts in the
fields we don't actually know what
they're doing they could look friendly
but not friendlier you know voice first
this boy could lock he might not have
been malicious but then he could have a
malicious we kinda had to be very very
so kind of got me tink and then like I'm
not the only one disaster carpenter so I
kind of started research and I find this
treaty today and so someone was a
vulnerability for accompanying or such
lots of people use like Instagram and
Twitter and you know sometimes we don't
think when we're posting are we post of
them obviously this person would pull a
picture of so basically the two guys
they're famous and this person took the
picture of them if you can't really see
it on the board either and but you can
see the gmail password on the email
account was also in the picture a
stranger had no assistant said oh look
there's actually a father
so basically accidentally leaked and
emails and dmoz a lack of attention I am
putting the planes
the credentials and this was pop wife
doesn't know my work had come here as
such and then another one was I'm not
sure if anyone knows their Equifax admin
admin and so that was another human
error like no one changed the default of
the password and you have your admin
admin you know why don't we use key pass
or you know password managers is such
we'll just remember one long strong
password is supposed to have one long
strong password put on every platform
that we use and some live long then we
have our choice of password management
which kind of ties them the same the
last one I shall drop off say an
employee of the company we reused their
LinkedIn profile in ten password on
their Dropbox which gave access to
anyone that had originally like got the
breach and then move along let me have
the sis's men for get lap had struck the
database of all the people that's also
kind of why hey Donna and well it was
like as if he was testing the framework
of search and you can see that in other
words that they've tried everything that
they caught with their backups who not
work at least you know they were
transparent about toughness that they
tried and you know so then we have
Amazon really one of these really every
week at one so kind of research it's
putting the Prudential ze like
information into the booklets and so
from you know owners getting access the
privileges were incorrect
so allowed people to look in well I have
a video next I will just go back for so
so the next video is you're going to
look at see that your mana social
engineering himself to get in or if you
want to find out where you can see the
guy
[Music]
okay I'll play the video anyway and you
might not hear about Alex linguist and I
don't fancy paying let's go make some
baseball saying that it's gonna get us
jacket you know they get an earpiece now
making some clips peer to peer talkin
[Music]
two days welcome true Mike wouldn't show
many ticker any signs of
[Music]
if you're not was server actually going
to check the tickets as you're going in
what you say the sturdier just suits an
authority lost
[Music]
so basically he's social engineer
himself in black people think you know I
belong here as opposed to humans and
that allowed him more posture actually
the vulnerability because you know how
many other people could have got into
the World Cup and you know got free
chicken my heart okay so looking at
these examples just like a quick summary
of water about like in my own experience
I've learned like trust nobody until
they're proven otherwise
and can't always trust who you find on
the internet search and kind of have to
be worried about their what they're
looking for them the lack of emails it
was a lack of observation you know like
not thinking before the posts you know
making sure everything on it is right I
mean it's time-consuming to change a
password apparently so keeping your
admin admin is let them suffer you know
a big big loss and then we have the get
lab guy well you know drop in the
database it's not exactly something that
we all want to do and then the security
just a lack security in mind
Cuauhtemoc letting the right access for
anybody to access these and the last
hole at the video of that's genius other
well we can all try it sometime and so
with that being said I just have a
question for the audience can we afford
to our investor and our employees or
humans or such like you know is it worth
not investing in them and I definitely
[Laughter]
definitely think that we do need to
train our humans to give respect and you
know communication is key between
employees and employers or between two
people you need to be wary of those what
they're saying as well and but training
their employees to have like standards
that everyone needs as opposed to like
putting that image of them that's you
remember you're a risk in the whole
picture like not just a picture or if
you list our laptop and it's stuck onto
the laptop like how many people you know
that got stole and you have an access to
it so that's like an another flaw and
there's like this many ways like we we
all invest in technology as opposed to
as
the Train and like we don't go and get a
job what I've done asserted her you know
Adam to her skills are supposed to or by
the latest laptop and then you know I'll
get the job because I've whatever I said
I'm going off this kind of it's like we
compact herself her but we kind of
partitions and obsessed controversial we
can train our human some we can teach
them the right ways of getting there but
you know that's that's my end point of
the whole presentation like you know we
can patch itself we're going how much to
human so but that says I'd like to take
everyone's listen and if you've any
questions here yeah
if there's a few questions or something
like you know like team like team
building and surface but can't depend so
on the train lever do our training for
security reasons you should show how
it's doing us you know provide like a
few alternative home
I'm not exactly like I haven't talked
too much on the training side of the
book you know that could be I think we
kinda need to all work as a collective
group and kind of that's why I'm through
with already house yeah
[Applause]
[Laughter]
and I don't quite understand what the
word means but yeah and that's yeah like
I hadn't blocked them straight after
he'd sent me I won't hurt you I left him
like you know lat because he was liking
all my tweets and retweeting and you
know he's getting me fused so I know
that was good for me and then I kind of
got to the point where he's nice to me
like oh happy birthday or I put it a
suite up about an interesting YouTube
video that I'd watched and I shared or
what everyone and he's I go really like
can you explain more and then he was
tell him that he had books for me with
just a ton of links and he told me to go
look for them and that's kind of like
yeah I'm not gonna click here or else
I'm not gonna like you know so I kinda
got to the stage after he was like happy
birthday he had enough information I was
like yeah that's kind of like you know
the end or yeah interesting yeah a good
idea where the line is in terms of
information to be visible in a job yeah
yeah well I definitely think like being
visible online is got chills because
you're interact I love network miles
getting to know new people so that's my
big thing and you know I didn't want to
decline this guy just cuz you know he
might have been strange whatever I wants
to see what he has to say and then I
kind of got strange so he was like going
or 1/2 K you know and you kind of you
don't I don't draw the line straight
away I kinda you know he never judge a
book by its cover so it kinda gets to
know the person in there you know you
know where you stand been kinda yeah I
found Susu question so I'm going to
truth yeah
I feel like an monster officer you know
yeah that's for any more questions yeah
I got into it so we have picot CTF and
so beginner CTF there's also a URL I'm
Explorer security calm and then do like
forward slash hacker sock or that's just
like a mini see Jeff is like a
challenges on there
I am so people just trying to get
started and we have zero days coming up
next year and that's another CTF to try
and get involved as well they kind of a
my students as such yeah that's good and
the years
so George St soon as they once exist was
and wonderful companies to have to
encourage waited at justice cares about
forget people who aren't tradition i key
on Social Security to take part in and
then genocide to help them and I'm duty
toughness door to the yangzi appendices
okay that's what Emma's going next
yeah yeah any more questions
[Music]
[Applause]