one lacrosse the stage thanks very much
for coming and seeing me today there's
as Gordon said it's my third iris
carotid last year and back in 2012 and I
saw a mate for the first time he really
Mabel to see him again and yeah real
delight when Brian asked me if I wanted
to come along today to present on the
state aside security report version two
according to the extended play though
actually this is the unexpended play
originally we did a report which we
launched InfoSec Europe
back in June and then I did that
slightly longer version which became the
extended play but that was 45 minutes
now about to go back to 30 minutes yeah
you just keep up with me there's a lot
of Statistics coming up in the next 25
minutes or so so do boost it with me
also for anyone in the front row I
wasn't just ahead because I've been
sitting there this morning and something
maybe just I hate a bubble lectern so
it's great view isn't it so just a
little bit on me likes no video in mind
you'll be glad to know I've been info
security now for just almost four years
in about two or three weeks and I've
been covering side security since 2008
and a lot of people seem to manage my
time at SC magazine which is nice and I
was also called previously with the
4-5-1 so the same time security report
the idea of is we get lots and lots as
the threat of course has gone and said
anyone here whose works in the media or
works in any kind of environment we see
vendor threat reports you know how heavy
they are they come in oh yeah I'd like
seven in one day a couple of days ago
and there cuz they're people they employ
to promote them some wonder why you
don't write Martens like because I'm
like constantly so you know when I email
people I Brian so you gotta views on
these reports and he says is it trying
to sell a product and I'm like maybe is
it is it by that company that ends with
that you know Darkfire web I say
whatever when they made this rule never
trust any company with those words in
their name and so yeah we start looking
at these these thoughts all not freaky
do one ourselves that was actually going
to be maybe not as such a broad spectrum
of
responses but you know you can sauce
training and weaknesses ourselves we
talk to people that we know and that
sort of things so we did the first one
last year and this could be we couldn't
stay inside security report because it
was you know the first thing we thought
of as quite hostile up with a new name
first one 2018 we talked to 32 people
not a large sample I'll be the first to
admit and these are the numbers we got
back so 46 percent of the respondents
were about gdpr as being the top finding
tops trend in their perspective we did a
lot of the interviews I'd say around the
march/april time in the run-up to talk
to the InfoSec in June so hence you know
GPR was a lot of people's radar at the
time and then you can see the other ones
I won't know run through so some other
things coming up so we thought this it
seemed pretty popular actually so let's
do a second one which we started in in
2019 and we just got version to me and
I've seen two too complicated when
you're trying to write a report like
this you go to industry and so I'm
trying to do this the lot of people can
be quite hesitant there like one morning
this is going to be four am I gonna have
to go on the record or a sub to about
this trying to be quoted not know I like
this once you've done one on to me
really easy you just go you know that we
had last year yeah we did again
yeah and so it's about 60 people about
six weeks or so between 30 April and now
we determined 31 distinct trends if I
pick one of you out Tom Wayne could and
said maybe 31 things are happening in
cybersecurity right now you wouldn't go
you probably about six in it 31 trends
that's how broad we are as an industry
now the included five top trends so they
were the most prevalent and nosy trends
find lower trends lights at six to ten
if you think about the top ten and then
a single response trends the reason I
put that in this piece interesting the
something which is a trend but only one
person thought about so we're gonna run
through them just a couple of previews I
did get asked what's or people actually
do did get and serving I'm not keen on
putting up a huge list of names because
don't want that to be about you know who
was interviewed to be more about the
trends but yeah the job title so here's
kind of the log company people I was
also
on previous presentation who were
surveyed from what the from the balance
was that it is a little imbalance a lot
of private sets people which you know
there we go maybe we do this again we'll
do a bit more private and I've been more
public and a bit more third sector but
VC legal association there Emilie's
cetera so this is top five I'm gonna go
through this slightly faster because
there's a second piece of research I
wanna focus on a little bit more top 5
top finding only 35% brain when you and
that's the spread those 31 friends was
product problems and these kind of with
the the breakdown of reasons why so
you've got more technology than problems
one quote we've actually got in the
report is like there's about 26
solutions that air for 16 problems or
something like that yeah that's the
fluting are outweighing the actual
issues detection issues vulnerability
management just you know heard about
patching just now too much legacy
technology there's not much you can do
about that
number two is human factor great to
aware me this morning I know Jenny's
coming up after me as it were off the
break human factor takes into
consideration things like usability
empathy of the UPS fueling is quite an
interesting while you know how do we get
people we get people in but do we then
push them up through the ranks to
actually get them to the level but they
can then get into a senior position
social engineering weak first strongest
thing that could be another entire day
talking about that one as I said number
one last year was compliance and when I
was actually doing the initial research
it's with barely coming up a lot was
like thinking it back mad god no one no
one talked about compliance no one
talked about compliance look at the top
quite many trees like coming in so
compliance was the third most prevalent
trending twenty five percent of
responses and reasons for that is for
example as a GPR is around BSD to PCI
DSS also some of the stuff I did a lot
of the research as I said so February or
April and we wrote it in April ma April
May proofed it and then got it and push
that in early June these were before the
intentions of fines for BA and Marion so
hence why
that thing there about disappointment
over lack of finds however there's
definite compliance is also push vector
is the response practices and also like
an international impact which the CCPA
is the California privacy and you might
source in bear talk about that it's
pretty cool actually it's taking a lot
of the influence I would say from GDP
are right number four is company and
board engagement and it's an area where
the security team needs to be part of
the business really and also they need
support the business and what the
business does and so you don't like
businesspeople in a mature market now
cybersecurity mature market in their
view the discussion between the CEO and
the board has changed Brian said this
morning you know we've got the attention
now a government of law of boards of
regulators and actually you know how and
we actually what we do with that now
we've got their attention because as
Brian Graham was saying crowd of people
are followed it all hit the front pages
even with an arrest of someone hit the
front page also measuring culture that
some of you you know full of what we do
know that culture is a tricky one you
could sort of say where's the value in
that well I will say look at know before
buying Cairo as company you didn't
actually find the number I was about an
hour ago trying to still find out and
that make bought for them but you know
we were able to put a dollar amount
whether that dollar amount probably a
million-plus on actually having culture
as part of your as part of your business
strategy really and brought awareness
obviously we talked about right and the
fire fifth and final one is automation
the as doing this b5 Belfast about three
weeks ago and someone said automation
what do you mean by that isn't on AI and
machine learning this thing differently
competent in the same thing that I'm
like god that's the other so AI machine
money I did sorry if you don't like that
but I you know they first uncle said
they do sit in the same kind of silo and
the same kind of container as it were
but maybe we'll see having to go if we
do this again in 2020 you know how a I
and machine learning are though to so
distinctly different things
than when things are moving that people
will actually see as two different
things
I'll see a DevOps dfi our automation
even though actually you see from the
right hand side there's so much part on
AI and machine learning and immature
market even though it's negative thing
he still was being cited as a trend even
though it's not kind of a hugely popular
area that people want to talk about so
they were the top five so these came out
in June and so I've been talking around
this for a while and well you know I
will people sometimes say you know can
you compare 18 and 19 while the answer
is probably no because there were 32
people versus 60 people interview there
were different sets of people from the
people I talked to last year I didn't
talk to this year just for various
reasons availability etc so yeah I
decided sit-ins was to try and you know
do something original so if you want to
kind of go a like-for-like is probably
not there but you know ultimately
compliance is seen as less or less
severe kind of a trend the last year and
the five lower trends then so these were
as following yes hygiene cloud apt apt
was interesting one because I thought
this has been kind of dismissed by the
security community as being very you
know hype driven kind of thing but it
really came up actually I guess if you
consider the state of the world you know
the ransomware being developed by
nation-states the attacks the
interference kind of thing then yeah
maybe it's being seen seriously now
where I did one doormat ransomware into
that and agile transformation that
actually was when I started doing this
research idea of transformation was
actually a really really popular one but
it seemed Windell away into like 10th
place and the finger response trends her
I like putting these in because these
are just interesting to sort of see you
know what one person thought you might
look through those and go I can't
believe more people didn't say bug
bounties
the upset people among you might stare
can't believe no one else is puzzling
that's always fun in front of a Seto
audience and they go and my services
well another one that's kind of you know
it's pretty popular just one more thing
on this
I actually got this
normally go through who was talk to a
lot of people we do know but I did get
this from a chat group on Ben Tom hey've
then Hawkins of you know it's fulfilled
and saw a big Gardner he fed me this DM
and after you came out and saw said
rather surprised they weren't response
about containers so I thought well you
know let's have a little look into the
wrists of responses and see what people
actually said about containers and how
many talked about it yelled sir was to
him and someone else the other one was
these were some of the comments we got a
little more bang for your buck sorry no
more bang for your buck without the
security overheads
but option if contain technologies as
kubernetes rapidly matures like tweet
disposable virtual systems you had to
manage and batch best to hold containers
while they support all positive no one
else don't I said negative back
containers out to people obviously and
holding Italians Barrett and migrating
workloads between cloud providers and
also lets me do that as well so it's
yeah it could take us was an interesting
ones put in and like I said again I
think he's laugh at that okay you know
we got a few people since a me and did
anyone mentioned brexit result buzzing
we'll talk about yeah there you go okay
now for me you know and I just thought
let's put that one out because you know
he's Pacific Lee asked just as it came
out people often say a few questions
which I have address than some of the
added slides so that's kind the main
part of the research but what I wanted
to do was try and see how this yeah this
is all very nice to sort you know we
wrote about this and we push that the
report now and I've did some talks in
for a second a few other places but what
I want to try and do is see how these
trends actually being adopted by
businesses or not as the case of mobile
and actually helping the next generation
of people to come into the industry we
do a lot of sort of coverage info
security around how helping new people
come into the industry it's all very
well sitting going all there's a skills
crisis and you know no one's hiring well
maybe if you find the people who are out
there trying to find a job then and they
know what they were expecting we kind of
help bridge that gap so we're quite
interested in helping new people coming
to the industry and
yeah and try and do that kind of thing
so this is part of research I didn't I
thought let's try and find some people
we can talk to so I saw the second leg
of the research I went off to find
people who were in the first few years
of their careers still at university or
on work placements and so I guess 25 and
under I suppose there's something a bit
older if that's just you start your
period bit like it's about 50 plus so
almost actually in the end almost as
many as I did with the original research
and often seven questions based on the
findings and asked them how these are
affecting their skills their training
and opportunities in work and just big
shout out to Creston side secure
challenge because they actually helped
me do some they didn't mail outs for me
and got some people responding to it so
seven questions and the first one then
was quite simply are you ready to deal
with malware this is because of the
technology problems especially around
detection and those kind of issues so I
thought if the next generation of people
are seeing these stories about
ransomware like right Rogers talking
about and they confident in actually
that they go into a business though
right let's start reverse engineering
for example
so they've the answers of the 53 who
answered it obviously slightly more
majority were positive and I just
through some of the comments so it's
becoming more days today a lot of the
responses were very much like I've
absorbed taking an interest in this
person me and you know from the
negatives without experience if you are
training people this is could be a real
way to soar help people learn a little
bit more always do solve it reverse
engineering and seeing McAfee guys at
the front here you know where your
situation but if you know you were able
to do this straight out that at the
university or college or even just doing
your own some people might just be
interested in this stuff
covering all the bases probably an
impossible task there was a bit of a
trend of it being very much team effort
and if you're able to actually run
things on your own time as well then
that's gonna be harder and catching so
far as give me the knowledge to deal
with these types of threats efficiently
these these level
inque's I didn't make these up these are
actually quotes with the people we
actually talk to and I'll give you a bit
more information at the end just where
your hints or read a bit more thoroughly
so that was positive inflection to the
first trend of technology problems and
detection etc the second one oh there we
go okay I think I might write the second
one then it's that I see cry out wasn't
a top-five trend this year but was last
year but with so much around that is
your AWS and infrastructure-as-a-service
in 2019 the actually this is now a real
quite significant trend I think for the
whole industry so I thought you know
let's ask the question have you learned
enough 20 work with these as a service
options rather than your pretty standard
network security yeah pretty pretty sort
of harsh no actually this might just
because it is literally perfect it just
feels to me like an emerging trend on if
you're in university of course that was
maybe designed in 2017 for example how
up to date is that going to be as you
come to graduate maybe next year on the
year after to actually give you that
train to work with with them IAS as it
were
so yeah the training is available sort
of thing they've got around training is
it's out there if you want to start
looking around the internet look at
maybe even watch YouTube there might be
some YouTube videos on this kind of
stuff
things are out there and available you
need to have the work list users part
with job role it was tough and no doubt
that personal research again much luck
with the now loved one if you peds but
the sort of the legwork in as a new
person or you know you're looking for
people to hire and you know they've seen
they've done that personal research
element hopefully that's enough of the
boosts to make you feel actually this
person's blonde kind of the extra mile
and oh that's a third one is very third
question was to get compliance and as I
said top top
finding last year top 1/3 out fired this
year as a result then we see a lot of
talk now GRC governance risk in
compliance are we seeing more demand for
this in job as a people do people need
to know about compliance
to actually be able to get a job now so
for this one clearly 5050 almost
slightly or veering on the 27 slightly
higher so yes that's positive obviously
and a positive means that yes I have yes
I've seen is it cetera so just a few
points sketching which is coming out
more often some of the comments wish you
saw the more negative ones where people
just don't seem to be looking for them
so maybe about half a dozen what kind of
we'll see I'm not really looking for a
compliance job well okay The Apprentice
- probably still needs to know about
compliance framework so you know
consider that if you are actually sort
thinking I only want to work with
malware for example it's probably
working about PCI and I've actually even
packed of ransomware upon that the
current job seeker definitely increase
seventeen eighty ten that my job at
alerts are in this area so compliance is
the big one and that's why we asked this
one more clients is always mentioned for
audit or written six roles let's go to
the next one then so people were seeing
these but as I mentioned you know gdpr
is pretty prevalent we all quit you
familiar with that but do we know the
ins and outs of it this OPC IDC isso PSD
to did so et cetera so are you worried
the demands of what actually is required
of them and from that I say 54 answer's
yes we see like pretty clued up kind of
next generation of people who seem to
know what's going on but their guidance
material media has been pretty good at
picking up compliance because people
want to talk about compliance they want
to read about it but there's a lack of
education around this again this much
good timing issue it might be down to
the fact that universities aren't we
keeping up with the change in things
like data protection laws because you
know these all pretty new those of you
remember the intake GTR was now 18
months in I'm not saying we haven't we
are care anymore but we do carry still a
lot more but our training capabilities
there are they keeping up you know I'm
seeing more and more conferences now
roll up you know purely about data
protection and
I don't eat demographic ligo's these
things are and I've not had PSD to if
you haven't heard of guess teaching
there is some magazines dishing had
hanging around so a couple on that row
over there good that's like blue cover
it's my own PSD to no plug so yeah I
can't worried about that I pay them
services ping services standard thank
you thanks bro PSD - yeah this was a
very difficult one that's going to hold
up to some some issues around different
things but yeah worth looking into that
one
all right next one now obviously two
things there have been compliance and
clouds so if you don't have these things
and you haven't been prepared know you
haven't put the extra work in are you
gonna go into a job on day one and
they're gonna sort of say right work
what have you got and you're like I
didn't have time to do it well actually
is it up to the job to actually train
you and the aren't we obviously gonna be
yeah pretty heavily yes still 13 out of
the 5000 I'll actually did say no but
they'd only do it if there's a business
requirement to actually just train this
I think kind of a few of the mist kind
of sums that up a lot of the responses
really practices companies won't paper
training if they don't have to and any
jobs provide training to help employees
grow in areas that will benefit them and
one bit about but there that still
obviously affects a lot of the career
tracks in cybersecurity is the job ads
that are posted
we've all had conversations about HR and
how they demand certain levels of
expectation because you know they have
to tick the boxes of what people need to
have to get the job
so are they requiring unachievable
levels of experience and qualifications
obviously you know fits in with the the
research receiver actually with the IC
squares came out police say there's our
four million who's now the skills gap
globally so from that yeah 5130 one out
of the 54 isn't it said with a positive
response they often require degrees you
know degrees
yes universities are doing a great job
but if that's the only you only pull
this to look for people actually I've
got that level of education there the
limit which is a it is a shame preachers
don't really know what they want or need
and especially yeah this is current
summarize it really wanted to be cyber
ninjas that have uni and paid military
level wages I don't actually I mean I
did all these interviews to this
particular section all anonymously I
said the one salgo shaming anybody who
was who was responding I don't remember
a few up top my head by gently want to
make these anonymous so people could say
things like that and not to worry about
you know ruining their entire career
before beating started it so yeah that's
a great comment this is the last
question then so the board engagement
was in our top five and also board
awareness has been in the top five last
year so of communication and
presentation skills been taught or
encouraged to a level that you're
comfortable with I think yeah 20 X 25 so
48:53 yeah if you get very much split
down the middle they're actually about
people out there I think that that's a
personal thing I think people some
people are very naturally quite capable
of speaking on stage you know hopefully
things like hacking societies and local
b-sides event and I respond now you know
and other things are given the
opportunities for new people to come in
but if you're not getting the
opportunity to do it you can interrupt
your CEO and explain why you're not
vulnerable to heartbleed as an example
or do blue cube is probably better
example
so just a few comments hasn't been
taught a lot of emphasis on these
abilities and be able to comfortable as
present and communicate and also
hopefully that's the kind of thing
conducting a professional manner may
communicate to ease bias or the any
organization so these were the yeah
that's the last of the seven then so and
what I'm actually doing is I'm write an
article on each one of these questions
every week the third one is going up
somewhere Tom never exactly which one it
is
where I use a lot more of these comments
that we're free to read maybe these
questions are three degrees so that they
got up tomorrow and you know hopefully
gives you a bit more insight of what
sort of the answers I Robin just these
each your comments so just kind of few
takeaways of the overall research then
yeah so detection is remains a large
issue and but people feel comfortable
dealing with malware it's not something
that's a major problem
or it seems for the next generation
compliance people are aware of it even
though it wasn't top five clouds never
present and yeah just believe the hype
on automation because it's not going
away so if you want download that the
original report which says in its on the
is on the website
white paper you have to go back to about
sixth of June I think he's been glad you
came out if you want to follow me as my
email that's our Twitter's if you want
links to any of their articles or
anything then just tap me on on Twitter
I'm sitting here the rest the opening
about three minutes enemies but any
questions happy to be shouted out
otherwise because you know I'm gonna be
sticking your hat but I just I say just
got a recording said actually I came to
I respond in 2012 for the first time I
watch people like Ric Flair this and the
near Jones and Brian and Phoenix speak
and hey I got to do today so thanks very
much and I'm gonna go
[Music]