good morning and thank you Gordon an
apologies up front I I have a really bad
voice and so I thought I'd actually have
to stand up here with hand signals but
thankfully presentation decks are really
good for this so look as I'm delighted
to be here and I'm here because I sit on
the steering group of technology Ireland
ICT skill net and in particular I chair
the advisory board for the CSI
initiative which is really what I'm
going to talk to you about this morning
and in addition I sit on the board of
cyber Ireland so were they part radula P
oh dear what a type of - sorry
stay away from that sack for thinking
[Music]
you can see where I taught you when your
career as IBM gets yours oh yeah okay
that's the bottom Isles okay thank you
perfect so look I'm gonna take you on a
little bit of a journey first of all to
explain well what is technology Ireland
ICT skill net who are they
it's a network of over 400 private
sector organisations and they
collaborate to determine what skills are
need to progress their industry and
particularly if this is the ICT sector
so this is where the CSI piece comes
into play it was established in 2005
under the aegis of Technology Ireland
which is a member of I bet and it's also
part funded by still net Ireland okay so
to give you that bigger picture skill
net Arland as an organization has 68
skill Nets and they are broken down by
industry sector and by region and they
have the same model their industry or
their enterprise lead and Technology
Ireland ICT skill net is just one
network within skill net within the skin
that Ireland brand so to just give you a
sort of a picture of what that looks
like so what we do is we provide high
quality and focused education and
training
it's really to keep the organization's
our member organizations at the
forefront of whatever skills it is they
need so we're constantly looking to the
future and one of the things excuse me
one of the things that we have done this
year is we actually amalgamated with a
technology Ireland innovation forum so
this is a new chapter for ICT skill net
and very much one that will allow us to
start to look more as innovation because
obviously innovation is huge within the
ICT sector so bringing that innovation
and research to our members so the
challenge that we faced and this is
going back about three years was this
cyber security skills gap and you know I
can stand up here and tell you we still
have themselves that problem as all of
you probably are very aware but what we
were seeing was the digital
transformation the obliquity of the net
of their web cloud applications and
organizations finding it really
difficult just to find IT people and
that just became more compounded when
you were looking for cyber security
skills yes we were trying to do that in
the face of organizations really
beginning to become very aware that they
needed to protect their data so very
much echoing what Brian has said this
morning it is one of the key things
every organization faces or should be
facing or should be looking at and
skills really forms and having the right
skills actually forms a core component
of that so we're also seeing increasing
are decreasing unemployment the double
negative so as our unemployment levels
go down we're also now focused that
we've got actually less people available
in the workplace and also every
organization of fighting for cyber
skills it's not just an IT or a
technology companies problem it's
everybody's got a problem whether you're
a small solicitor's office right through
to a multinational the whole cyber
security business is evolving
excuse me I'm really sorry about this um
and you know what we've seen is a 40%
increase in cyber roles over the past
two to three years so what did we do as
a direct response to that and without an
a direct response to that the massive
skills issue an organisation's feeling
that they weren't really adequately able
to protect themselves we launched in
2010 18 the CSI framework which is a
comprehensive plan to train individuals
in cybersecurity skills and it was
really to help organizations to address
those skills shortages so the first
thing we did was we put an advisory
board in place I'm not going to name all
of them but I will call out the fact
that Brian is an active member of the
advisory port and this is a group of
enterprises government organizations and
academia which helped us to shape the
needs of the industry using all of the
you know constituent parts of government
academia and enterprise so we came up
with a five key or five core strategies
and this is what we see as our road to
excellence so on the bottom left-hand
corner you've got the cyber skills and
pathway and this is about building
skills building knowledge bringing lots
of different types of programs to play
not just a one-size-fits-all
the second was organic growth and this
is something that we discovered by
talking to a lot of our clients was that
how do we take people who exist in the
organization today and upscale them or
rescale them or retrain them a lot of
people make decisions around careers at
the point where they leave school but
you may have people in your organization
who are not in an IT role yet actually
have competencies that would make them
really good cyber experts so we actually
started to look at how do you take those
people how do you identify them I'm
using cyber aptitude tests so that you
actually can grow people that exist in
your organization today
you're going back to what Brian said
earlier again this is a business issue
not just an IT issue it's not okay to
say oh I've got a business partner they
look after my IT or that's you know we
have a 90 department and they look after
our security it's everybody's
responsibility but particularly within a
business if that needs to come from the
top down
and I think CEOs and the senior
leadership team needs to be asking the
questions so part of our goal was to
raise the awareness in that area we were
also focused on new entrants so trying
to encourage people to go into cyber
security when they come out of college
or before they even go into college and
particularly to look at and females
coming into the cyber security space and
then the final strategy was continuous
development this is really important
we're hearing this in every sector now
that you know lifelong learning is
something that's really important to
regardless of what role you're and what
industry rate I think there's no more
important area than in the cyber
security space because your knowledge
your skill it has a really short shelf
life so I think it's really important
though if people continue to grow their
professional development that is the
fifth of the key strategies so then
there were five aims that were going to
bring this strategy to life the first is
raising awareness so I lived him back
again to what Brian said I'm really
Lapierre I'm following Brian this
morning has he had a lot of but of his
comments a lot of his key ideas actually
flow nicely into this is really to raise
that awareness across the board so that
organizations know that they have a
potential issue and they have something
that they need to work on preparing
organizations to be ready for cyber
attacks resilience to grow those skills
so that organizations become resilient
and are able to defend themselves
standards to look at standards for
cybersecurity roles and for
cybersecurity training
and then the final piece is automation
where possible to use automation and to
use AI to actually help to grow and
develop skills in the cyber space so I'm
delighted to say that for 2019 their
cybersecurity skills initiative that
framework has had over a thousand
individuals participate in the programs
that we've developed and over 400
companies have engaged in the framework
as well so in just a 12-month period
it's a really great set of statistics
for us and that has included a number of
things so the framework itself is a
whole series of different programs so it
is literally everything from basic
awareness training right through to a
master's in cybersecurity which is
actually run by a technological
university Tomblin at the branch it's on
campus so of those 1,000 individuals and
400 companies that participated this
year they engaged in everything from CSI
awareness training which we held
nationally and I can tell you when I saw
the list of the places that this was
rolling out over the year I'm from New
Ross from County Wexford and I saw that
honors and I excellent
crash this is a national program we've
got small little town in the southeast
of Ireland is actually on that the
program for awareness training and
cybersecurity and we ran a number of CSI
webinars and the commercial cyber
aptitude test or C cache is a set of
aptitude tests that is produced for the
commercial organizations are supposed to
defense there is a defense one and
that's the technology that we use to
assess people's capability in in cyber
in aspects of cybersecurity and we also
ran a number of information security
passes risk assessments IRAs and capture
the flags we had a number of those that
we ran for organizations and some open
ones around the country as well and
there is one running here today as well
and then there's the MSC in
cybersecurity which has been running at
a technological university Blanchard
sound for the last
number of years so there are plenty of
details on the all of the programs that
make up the cybersecurity skills
initiative on technology and ICT skill
let's website and my colleagues from
there are actually here today so I
certainly would encourage you to to go
along to meet them
not a sales pitch but I think that if
you're wondering about awareness
training if you're wondering about any
form of growing skills skills assessment
training please do stop by and have a
chat with them and I'll take any
questions if there are any Kashyap
finished ahead sorry I flew through that
any questions from anybody all right
what super come on if they're you know
playing familiar
[Applause]