[Music]
welcome everyone and thank you for
joining us this afternoon i'm andrea and
i will be your host for today's webinar
i'm glad to welcome today david and
sandro david is a phd student at the
university of mino with a strong
background in embedded systems and
systems programming where sandro is an
associate research professor at the
university of minnow in today's
presentation
they will present disarming trust zone
with t
privilege reduction in this talk they
will present and discuss rezone a new
security architecture that can
effectively counter ongoing privilege
escalation tax by reducing the
privileges of a potentially compromised
trusted os
before we start a little housekeeping
the presentation will last 30 minutes
followed by a 10 minute q a session and
if you have any questions please share
them across the chat and we'll answer
them once the presentation is over
without further ado i would like to
invite you to start your presentation
so
first of all i would like to thank the
hardware io team and in particular
andrea for for the invitation i would
like also to thank the audience for for
taking the time and the interest in
attending our talk
so my name is sandra pinto
and with me today
we have david which is currently doing
his pg under my supervision uh also
we have jose which is also another phd
student under my supervision as a
collaborator of this work and also
professor nunu santos which is called
advising david with me
and so what uh i'm going to do is i will
try to explain our work entitled disarm
interest on with the previous reduction
in just three slides as a kind of
trailer or preview about the talk
and then we will discuss the talk into
more detail so
with it taking much of your time so
untrust some technology was introduced
almost two decades ago in 2004 in the
arm cortex a portfolio cortex
application process as a security
oriented technology and this technology
has been leveraged to build uh tes or
trust execution environments in billions
of mobile device worldwide in different
applications ranging for example of
biometric authentication drm service
such as one used by netflix or either
online online banking payments but
the sad reality is that over over the
years trusts on a ccte were attacked
and was not only one two times it was
hundreds of times and uh if you want to
understand a little bit more about the
state of affairs of the security
vulnerabilities affect interest on tvs
you can refer to this paper that we have
published two years ago at the ieee smp
hawkland which is s okay understanding
prevailing security vulnerabilities
interests on assisted
so
a particular observation resulting from
this study that we have done was that
the majority of the reported
vulnerabilities resulted from
architectural flaws which are highly
linked with this excess of trust and
privilege of the tea
and there was a particular gentleman
whose name may sound familiar among the
security experts in the audience that
was gal beniamini that
was in fact the worst nightmare for
qualcomm between 2015 and 2017 and he
basically demonstrated that it was
possible on the qualcomm te for a normal
world application within without any
kind of privilege to hijack for example
a trusted application or even worse to
hijack the the trusted operating system
and
yeah once you have full control of this
trust operating system in secure world
you can basically access and tamper with
the main operating system such as
android or you can
tamper with another trusted applications
or even worse you can basically fully
compromise this humanity which is the
firmware running at the highest level of
privilege and this is bad really bad you
can basically have full control of the
system
so uh with our work we tried to
basically address this problem and we
tried to to fix this access level of
privilege of the tea in the over
ultrasound archetype
and for that we proposed razon and rizzo
basically leveraged traditional agnostic
hardware primitives available in
commercial off-the-shelf platforms to
partitioning a monolithic trust
reduction environment in multiple zones
and by doing that rezone is able to
restrict the e from access in the normal
world
accessing other t's or other zones that
you may want to have on your system and
even
restricting the access to the secure
monitor
so
i pause here for a second at this point
you should have already like the big
picture about the motivation and what we
have done and so after this slide we are
going more into detail
of our work so i will spend more time in
the motivation and the goals and the
trend model then the vid which in fact
was one doing the ev lifting part of
this work will explain the design
implementation and evaluation of our
solution and i will get back at the end
of the presentation just to share some
final thoughts
so i will start from the over ultrasound
tea software architecture trust sony
center around the concept of protection
domains you have the normal world and
you have also the secure world
and the the normal world typically you
run your rich execution environment or
your main operating system such as
android and your normal
applications on the secure world in fact
you run this
trust of operating system that is
somehow minimalistic comparing to to the
main operating system that is
responsible for managing these different
trusted applications uh one particular
feature of the trust on architecture is
that the normal world is it cannot
access to the secure world but the
secure world is able uh to access to the
normal world and you have a kind of
secure monitor that is responsible for
managing this this world switch
well from a hardware perspective what we
have here is a kind of simplified view
of an architecture of a dual core system
car wall zero core one
private level one cache shared level to
cache
uh and also the the buzz interconnect
that connects different
memories and peripherals and other boss
masters in the systems and the the trust
zone technology is not only
available on the core itself but in fact
it propagates uh through the system to
the bus uh with this non-secure beat
that flows from the car to the bus and
in in this system or in this
interconnector but there are additional
controls or additional trust and
controllers uh that you can leverage to
basically configure memory and
peripherals as secure and unsecured in
particular you have the truss on address
space controller the task that you can
use to partitioning external external
memory and the same at the same time you
can also use the thrust zone protection
controller that you can also use to
configure peripheral secure and non-cq
well uh the the key motivation for for
for our work as i explained before is
this excess of privilege of of the tea
and in fact uh if he
look as this orthogonal view of the
trust on architecture we can conclude as
it was demonstrated before that trusted
os can for example access the normal
world and other components in the system
so the best way to represent the
architecture that in my opinion somehow
misleading uh from an orthogonal to a
vertical approach is something like this
okay so in in this architecture i think
is more intuitive that the secure world
is more privileged than the normal wall
so all these components trusted ours and
secure one can access the the layers
that sit at top and
since there are no real isolation
between the el3 and the security l1 what
we can have in fact is something like
this so in practice what we have as the
tcp of our system is not only the secure
monitor but also this trust operating
system and in our study what we conclude
was that
this tcv
is very large because the trusted os in
practice as as a considerable size
so what we tried to come with was one
with a novel solution to to fix this
problem but it was not really really
straightforward there were some attempts
on the on the literature in the state of
the arts to try to address this problem
uh mainly by moving the trusted
application from the cq world to the
normal world and leveraging some
capabilities of the trust and address
space controller i'm referring in
particular to sanctuary that was
published at the ndss conference and it
parts from the observation that the the
trust on address space controller 400
implements one feature that is the
identity based filtering
which is able to to to assign memory
regions to specific buzzmasters for
non-secure access but the problem with
this solution that was demonstrated only
in emulators not in real hardware
platforms is that this assumption that
the core id in a cluster typically you
have like quad core dual core uh
the core id is different for each car
but in practice in real platforms this
doesn't it doesn't happen so what we
conclude was that
in real systems reducing the privilege
of the security l1 was not possible only
with standard threads on mechanism
because the cpu from a cluster
has the same master id the trusted os in
practice can always tamper with the
trust on address space controller and
change the configuration
and the the security l1 and the l3 in
practice has the same privilege
so we came with an hypothesis and the
hypothesis was in fact that
we try to restrict the t
privilege not by leveraging the trusts
on controllers but by using additional
system level hardware controllers
available in commercial of the shelf
platforms
so parting from these hypotheses
and part parting from these standard
trusts on hardware architecture we tried
to draft what we believed would be an
ideal platform model to restricting the
trust otherwise
and the first thing that we thought was
instead of relying in these nes speeds
what if we add a second layer of
firewalling that
we call the platform partitioning
controller or ppc
that
implies some policies that are not based
on the states of the nes bit but based
on this
id of the different masters that we call
mid
and well this is a start but what we can
conclude is that
in this cluster of different course the
course has the same id so we cannot use
these main course of of the system to to
reconfigure this ppc because they shared
the same mid so in fact what we need is
an what we call
acu or auxiliary controller unit that
can be a simple microcontroller
available in these in these modern
platforms that can take the role of of
coordinating the configuration of the
access permissions of this ppc and
guaranteeing uh that these main
processors cannot change at runtime the
the policies that we
apply
so another block that is needed but is
not depicted in this picture in
particular because is widespread
available in the platforms is the secure
boot and the secure boots basically
validates the integrity and the
authenticity of the firmware basically
to ensure that the acu has been securely
bootstrapped and is the owner of this
ppc that is the most important component
to enforce the policy
so then we try to understand the
availability of these of these hardware
primitives in different socs and from
different vendors and we surveyed
19 or
17 popular socs from nine different
vendors and
what we did we tried to study public
available reference manuals we inspected
the linux kernel we we tried to find on
bootloaders and we inspect the also the
the security monitor the trusted
firmware
and in some cases we also looked in
existing available cds to try to
identify specific components and uh this
the the information of this study is
reflected in this table and what we can
see is that
for the ppc we saw that modern socs have
have this component either as a custom
or proprietary system level controllers
such as nxp or xilinx and xpsd rdc or
resource domain controller
i think i can use
this
point
yeah
and
also another
some of white speed widespread component
that can be used as a ppc is this system
memory management unit that is quite
available due to the widespread use of
fertilization on modern platforms
for the acu this is a trend acknowledged
by arm that they are integrating uh even
more and more small microcontrollers on
on these big socs uh either for platform
management
reasons are either for security reasons
so in fact what we conclude was that
uh from 17 uh
socs that we served 13 are able to to to
implement a reason and in fact for the
samsung uh
socs uh because the public available
information uh
regarding the peripheral mmus were not
able to conclude if the features are
enough or not so we we classified at
this note of it
so
uh
with regard to the design goals we tried
to come up with a novel security
architecture that leveraged this uh
hardware novel artwork primitives to
create the the secure world sandblocks
and we try to establish first the
security properties we need to reduce
the privilege of trusted os
so what we want to do if we take this
vertical image as an example we try to
come up again for the orthogonal view
but then imply
policies that restricts in fact uh the
the
all different components assessed to
each other so we try to reduce the
privilege of the trusted os to not be
able to access the normal world the
secure monitor and the other teas
also we try to establish as design goals
to depend on a small tcp in fact relying
just on the firmware running at the
august level of privilege neil tree
and to maintain these software
portability and compatibility with
legacy systems because it's really
important as well and most importantly
we try to offer a good trade-off between
security and performance we know that at
some point sometimes security it comes
at the cost of the trade-off so we want
to have the best of of both worlds
so for the trend model uh an attacker
may want to subvert the security
properties that we have as design goals
uh so the rich os as we know is too
large to be trust but also the trusted
os it's our intention to reduce the
privilege and so we we take it as grant
that can be compromised uh so a
compromise trusted os can try to access
for example the acu to subvert the acu
and try to change the the configuration
of the permissions of the ppc that
basically is responsible for enforcing
these these policies we trust uh the
secure monitor and the code running on
the acu and we consider out of scope
like physical physical attacks such as
photo injection uh micro architectural
side channels uh and also the nail of
service attacks such as for example one
malicious trusted os do not release the
control of the cpu to the normal world
so i pause here for a sec a second and
now i hand it over to to david that will
explain the design the implementation
and the evaluation i will get back at
the end of the presentation so hello
everyone my name is david and i'll be
taking the presentation
from here so let's start by looking at
the design
design this is this picture
the results design so the first thing
the first things that we must
take into consideration is that result
requires the
possibility to establish at least two
security domains so one for the
acu
and one for the processor card
and this allows us to establish the
different tax control
properties
depending
for the processor car and the acu
so
then we must include custom
functionality into the secure monitor we
call the size reference functionality
the result trampoline and the main
the main responsibility is to securely
exit
the
control to the zone to the te
then we have the gatekeeper that runs on
the acu and trampoline and gatekeeper
actual coordinate in order to securely
configure the ppc
lastly we have the ppc uh we already
mentioned and you send it between the
car and the memory and it enforces the
actual access control policy
okay the next picture
uh
depicts how reason works
from when i have a high level view on
the left we have
execution flow of a call from the normal
world to a zone to a tee on the middle
we have the access control policy that
is established
established and on the right we have the
memory layout of the system so let's
actually start on the right by looking
at the memory layout
and looking at the memory regions we
must take into consideration the first
memory region is the memory region of
the normal world which hosts the rich
environment os for example android
and also on the normal world we have the
shared memory so this shared memory is
used to communicate with the zone with
the t
on the secure world then we have the
monitor which is the same as the typical
uh trust zone deployment but now we also
need a special zone
for the trampoline
and again the trampoline main function
is to safely perform entries and exits
to and from as well and lastly we need a
memory region to host a zone which will
host trusted os and its trusted
applications
now let's look at the memory access
control policy
so the control policy is established
depending on the privilege level that is
executing
so starting by
the
res or the normal world the el 0
and el 1
the re can access its memory well it's
executing so this is similar to or it's
exactly the same as just some typical
software it can access its memory and
the shared memory then at the el3 we
have the monitor and it can access all
the memory it needs it's the since it's
the most trusted component of the system
and we have for the secure el 0 and dl1
we have the permissions that we can only
access
it's the memory uh it's the memory and
the shared memory however note that the
trampoline is actually marked as we
don't and this is important as
doing so allows performing actually
policy reconfiguration and also so okay
let's look at how we actually do the
memory partitioning securely so the
first thing the thing that's key here is
that the gatekeeper so the code running
on the acu authenticates the trampoline
by using a secret token
this token is generated randomly and is
generated at the time for example and is
shared between the monitor and the
gatekeeper so only they know this token
the in our implementation with a 64 bit
wide token it could be larger but we
find this to be sufficient
and
one of the most important aspects here
is that while a zone is executing
the token is stored on registers that
are only accessible to el3
and what this allows is for
the
to guarantee that the security l1 cannot
modify the exit interface and it cannot
do so because it doesn't know the
secrets
it's not stored in memory so it cannot
access it
okay so even from a design point of view
using ppc like mechanisms which only
works at the system bus level
some
issues
are highlighted
so
the first thing is that the bbc only
acts on the bus level right so this
means that accesses are not
to control accesses to the cache
okay so let's see an illustration here
to better understand the problem
so this is what we would expect so we're
running trampoline in for one we do some
configuration and we want to mark this
memory as not accessible
okay so right now we have the core one
executing and it tries to access the
memory the memory region that we don't
want the core to access and the ppc
locks it
however this is not how things work
because
the data regarding that memory vision
can actually be in cache and if it's in
cache when the core tries to access it
it will do a cache hit and it will
freely
be free to access it as it will
so how can we solve this problem
well what we do is
flush the
caches to memory
and this will result in the data in the
cache being written to memory and the
data
the cache content is being erased and
now when a car tries to access tries to
access memory that is marked as
non-accessible
the ppc will actually trigger and block
the axis so this is one of
the first issue
the second issue
um will actually
force us to hold
cores on the same cluster
and this is because we can differentiate
between both axises of collocated
cluster cores
and this means that the access control
policy applies to all cores the same so
let's look at an illustration here
again so we are now we have two cars one
running the rich environment one
executing the trampoline and tripling
will actually will actually enter a zone
so we configure the ppc and because we
are entering a zone uh we want the
normal world memory to not be accessible
and the te starts executing so
however we are still
executing calls in the car zero
regarding the normal world and
when we the course heroes tries to
access its memory it will not be able to
do
okay so this is the problem
so what we must do is actually the
trampoline must actually suspend all
other cars in the cluster
and only after the cars are suspended
can we safely reconfigure the ppc
and then proceed the execution
okay so finally let's look at the
execution flow of a call to the to a
zone
so the flow starts on the normal normal
world a normal world will issue a secure
monitor call
it will
be handled eventually by the trampoline
and trampoline and gatekeeper will
coordinate
to lock or to unlock the ppc reconfigure
it and lock it again and then
the execution control will be handed
over to the zone after the zone does
what it's supposed to
this one will return to the secure
monitor
the trampoline on the gatekeeper will
coordinate again in order to unlock the
pc reconfigure it and lock it again and
then
resume the execution on the normal world
okay so these were the main design
the main design aspects let's look now
at some implementation
instrumentation aspects
our test pad is the nxp's imx
8 mq
we use its rdc as
ppc this is the resource domain
controller and we use its cortex m4
built into the asusc as an ecu for
software we leverage transformer as
monitor
and we use opti as a dee
and for normal worlds we use a mixture
of embedded linux and android to perform
our tests
there are a
few implementation challenges that we
have to overcome
i'm not going to go over in detail but
let's overview them
so the first one is cross-court
synchronization as you might have
guessed from
one of the previous examples so we must
use synchronization primitives and then
interrupt to make sure that all cores
are halted before
running a
and the second challenge is required
potential microarchitectural maintenance
where we do
cash maintenance and tlb maintenance and
we
have evaluated this issue
deeply and we
make sure that we have as little impact
as possible
facing our limitations then we use um
the way we implement the dynamic is the
reconfiguration
is actually
optimized in order to to diminish the
time spent in reconfiguration
and the last issue which is the most
interesting one is how we handle
exceptions at serial one exits
most of the other three challenges of
being somewhat handled or addressed by
similar studies but the way we handle
exceptions as material one is quite
unique and we think you will enjoy
knowing these details so
we have two issues
we must prevent crashes so let's start
by looking at that
so the first issue is that the tlb so
the translation with a size buffer which
contains
how the
memory virtual memory translates to
physical memory may not have the
required el3
tlb entries and so when the zone exits
the tlb will try to exit your trampoline
it will not be able to map memory and
we'll try to fetch page tables
however remember that we marked the
monitor memory which holds the page
labels as not accessible
and this results in a crash and the
program will simply not
will not continue since it can't
translate
the memory to run the code so this is
the first issue
the second issue is that
we must
keep some things in mind trampoline is
read-only right
and the ppc doesn't control cache
accesses
and so what this allows
a malicious structure os to do
is actually is to make a rift access
which will fetch the memory to the cache
and once in the cache the malicious os
can modify it
maliciously and
in
this case he can modify the code the l3
code it will handle the exit
and this will give him the attacker
execution privileges at the l3 and which
will allow them allow him to undo the
access control policy
okay so we have two issues like a crash
because of clv and the
accordion injection on the cache the way
we solve them is by disabling the el3
mmu
so this stops the tlb
misses because now we don't have
translation
enabled while we are executing a zone so
there's no crash and
on arm once once you disable the mmu the
cache is bypassed so we are no longer no
longer at risk of having of running
injected codes
however we must do an additional step
with this we must invalidate the cache
thus removing the malicious potentially
malicious code on the cache before
enabling the mmu okay so this were
implementation
aspects i hope you find them
interesting now let's look at some
evaluation
starting by the performance we do some
micro benchmarks and we leverage up the
x test test suite this suite provides
some benchmark tests
storage sha and aes algorithms and it's
also although it's not meant to be used
as a benchmark the test suite actually
exercises
uh varying
workloads
or call types on the secure world and we
find them
we found them quite useful to understand
how resonance impacts
the city world workloads
and one of the most interesting things
for example if you look at the internal
api
a group of tests you see that's one of
the most impacted so
four times slower execution times and
but if if we look at the embed ls tests
we see that they are not
affected as much
what you can conclude what we conclude
from from this test is that shorter
execution times translate into higher
overheads and
to
make sure that this was the case we
actually
delve deeper into this and we modified
some tests
and we arrive at the conclusion that
for workloads having many small calls
rules
exhibit much higher overheads than
workloads which have fewer but larger
calls
so this is one of the main interesting
things we found
we also wanted to look at your real
world applications and we have here
bitcoin wallet
and this helps us evaluate some non high
frequency workforce
dca is actually quite realistic because
it uses various key apis the way this
has to set up we measured the program
execution
for each
operation
the main finding here uh the main system
finding here is the corroboration of
what we observed previously in that
shorter
operations
will result in higher overheads for
example if you look at the check which
master key exists operation we see that
overhead is supposed to
over two times slow down but if you look
at the sign transaction it's actually
much smaller than that
the second application is the rm
and this helps us evaluate the impact on
high frequency workloads
the vrm application
decrypts the video content on the te and
then
that is then made available to the
normal world to present it to the user
and we have measures for this both of
these operations so we measure the t
data decryption times which is on the
left here
and we observe uh one and a half times
slow down
and we also measure
how the application is impacted where is
zone by measuring the interval between
data processing events
because the data processing events
the interval is much larger than the
time it takes to decrypt the data
we find that the user experience on
their own drm workflows is not
significantly affected finally
we also wanted to evaluate things
security-wise and what we did
was first start by assuming that we have
multiple zones with one trusted
application for zone
and we then looked at cves
that are rated critical regarding to
these and these reviews we got from our
previous work we found that result
mitigates against the most trusted os
and application vulnerabilities
and this is because it prevents
attackers from gaining from escalating
privileges and from compromising other
parts of the system however result
doesn't mitigate against poorly
implemented ea for example visceral
secrets hardware attacks cryptographic
flaws or bootloader flaws
sorry just uh i just wanted to say
something before um and overall uh
result uh
mitigates 87 percent of the critical
owner built it's a quite significant
number
so now i want to give words to professor
pinto in order to conclude with some
final thoughts
thank you thank you a little bit so just
sharing some final thoughts to wrap up
this presentation uh so
in the paper uh well the presentation
and the focus of the paper is for
platforms prior to armv8.4
and the armv8.4 basically introduced
this secure hypervisor mode and you may
argue basically that this new hypervisor
mode on the secure world can basically
create isolation between the trusts uh
the different trusted device and this is
true but the fact that is not true is
that this fundamental problem that we
are fixing here is still here because
the iper the secure hypervisor can also
access the secure monitor and and vice
versa and secure world components can
still access the normal world so uh we
believe and in the paper we discussed
our rezone can still be
used in these platforms from a different
perspective in the arm v9 architecture
that was introduced a few months ago
arm already recognized these
architectural flaws of existing in the
previous architectures and
in this new architecture this el3 uh is
now a root world and is completely
isolated from the other from the other
walls from the secure world and this new
realm world but
uh still in this architecture realm
world and secure world can access the
normal world so in the paper we discuss
how we envision reason helping in these
new
new archetype and still because rp9
platforms are not available in
particular because these specific
architecture will be just available in
rd9.2
so in summary uh
we have explained why trazantes have
architectural flaws we have proposed
rizon as a novel security architecture
that address and fix and reduce the
privilege of a te
how we do that by leveraging interest on
agnostic hardware primitives that we
showed that are widespread available in
in commercial off-the-shelf platforms
uh
in fact we implement an evaluatory zone
in a real-world platform not only on
emulators and in on the paper such as
former work and
we we
conduct an extensive evaluation that
that basically concludes that
despite these games in terms of security
the performance of real world
applications is not significantly
affected and we explained how resound
could help mitigate these high severity
vulnerabilities so
i finish here the presentation and now
david and i will be happy to address all
all your questions thank you very much
for your presentation uh we already have
a question in the chatbot in the chat
box uh how does your approach compare to
multi-zone and c5s world guard
approaches for risk 5.
david do you want to take that or do you
want me to take that i think you you're
more qualified to answer that
okay so
the solutions that
they they are trying to to compare is is
not on r he's on risk five in particular
i'm quite familiar with multi-zone and
uh and basically the the what we tried
here was to grab some ideas from the
five wall because in the risk five world
in fact the agros privilege mode is
completely isolated uh from
from from the the privilege levels that
sits at top and in fact in risk five
what we you have is a kind of component
uh that is the pmp that
we try to basically uh
emulate with this trust on agnostic
platform so to go to the point of your
question so we were inspired with with
work that we did on risk five and we
came with these ideas and we apart from
this observation of the existence of
these system level hardware controllers
in arm platforms and yeah we bring this
solution so
the comparison is they try to address
the same problem and at the end of the
day they don't suffer from those
problems um i would like to thank you
again for uh coming and
for doing this great presentation i
think people
really liked it and i see that they are
also thanking you
um it would be nice if you would give a
shout out
to david and sandra on social media for
the talk and hope to see you next week
with another webinar thank you very much
again
thank you thank you again for the
invitation and thank you all for
attending our
talk um
[Music]