[Music]
welcome everyone and thank you for
joining us this afternoon i'm andrea and
i will be your host for today's session
on moonbows
um just before we jump into the webinar
let me share what we have been up to
so recently we have opened our call for
papers for the hardware io usa edition
for which we are looking for advanced
technical research covering diverse
topics including but not limited to
hardware contesting embedded systems
cryptography automotive and medical
device security smartphone firmware or
telecom networks nevertheless if you
have any kind of hardware security
research feel free to share it and we
will get back to you the deadline for
this is the first of march so you still
have one month to go at the same time we
have also opened our registration for
our hands-on trainings
on a variety of topics for instance
hardware hacking basics
car hacking
side channel analysis revert and
engineering firmware with kidra or
reverse engineering uh baseband firmware
um our early bird is still available so
if you're interested in any of these
topics please feel free to head to our
training section
today uh
i am happy to welcome mark
mark is a senior security researcher at
kaspersky and in today's presentation he
will explain how in the spring of 2021
his team was made aware of novel threat
against using uefi in the wild
where it was evident that attackers had
modified and embedded an implant with a
benign uefi firmware image
mark and his team dubbed this discovered
implant moonbounds and in this talk we
will learn more uh delicate details
about how
mumbai's research went from its
inception up until uh today
mark i would like to invite you to start
your presentation thank you all right
thank you andrea i hope uh everybody can
see my screen
right yes we do good
uh okay so uh hello everyone and uh
thank you for joining this webinar
hosted by hardware i o uh as andrea
mentioned my name is mark leftick and
today i'm going to walk you through a
recent research released by kaspersky on
a uefi firmware implant
that we dubbed moonbounds
before we dive in uh a quick uh
introduction to the people who were
involved in this research um and those
are um vasily bernikov and ilya
barrissov from our anti-malware research
team uh as well as denis
and myself
who are part of great which is the
global research and analysis team of
kaspersky
now uh if you join me here today you
probably uh have a general idea of what
we are going to talk about or at least
you should uh from the title uh but uh
still so what is it that we are going to
discuss
so uh the story that uh underlies uh
this webinar revolves around the
discovery um that my colleagues and
myself had at the end of last year uh
wherein uh kaspersky's firmware scanning
technology uh has made us aware that a
formerly unknown ufi
female implant was actually lurking in
the wild
and interestingly from our analysis
we could learn that
this particular threat was in a sense
more advanced than uh other ufi firmware
implants that we have seen so far
which um to be honest are quite a rare
occurrence um in and of themselves and
as a matter of fact we are considerably
confident that the actor who deployed
this particular implant is an infamous
threat group
that goes by the name of apt41 and in
this webinar i'd like to share with you
how we reached that conclusion but more
notably i would like to go into the
technical specifics
of this
curious piece of malware that we found
of course everything that we are going
to talk about here was already
documented in kaspersky's blog on
securelist.com
you can access it through the qr code
that you see on the screen and get up to
date with all the research details that
concern this
case so uh to contextualize this
implants behavior on the system i will
first quickly review how exactly ufi
works
and
you probably know uh by now that ufi is
the standard that constitutes how the
boot process on most of the modern pcs
and laptops work
works and it can be broken down
essentially into several stages uh the
first two stages um that you see on the
screen right now that are referred to as
the security and the pre-efi
initialization environment um are
executed from a designated hardware on
the motherboard called the spi flash
chip
and those are essentially in charge of
initializing the most uh imperative
components of the machine like the cpu
and chipset but most notably they
initialize the memory controller which
is
fundamental obviously for creating a
permanent address space um in the
computer's ram in which any subsequent
um
boot code can operate
from those two phases um control is then
passed to an uh important component of
the blue chain which is called the dixie
dispatcher
and that component also happens to be at
the center of the infection chain that
underlies the moon balance implant and
we will discuss this um in a little bit
now what the dixie dispatcher is in
charge of is setting up what's called
the driver execution environment
which
is this sort of a restricted environment
that facilitates some basic control of
the machine prior to the loading of the
operating system so for example uh to
allow boot code to access the disk and
load files from it or allow later
components in the boot sequence to
print a console or a ui on the screen
this environment uses a set of drivers
that are called dxi drivers that allow
this sort of rudimentary
interaction with the machine's hardware
resources
the access to some of these resources is
given through two sets of basic apis
referred to as boot services and runtime
services with the boot services uh being
essentially uh functions callable by
other components uh throughout the boot
sequence um being of the primary inter
interest to us in the context of the
moon balance infection and again i'll
tackle that um in a short while
the next uh part of the boot sequence is
quite straightforward that is what we
refer to as the boot dispatcher which is
uh generally speaking a mechanism that
allows the user to choose which
operating system
to boot to in case the user has more
than one operating system installed on
the machine
and that would in turn invoke
the particular
and relevant operating system loader
and then the operating system loader
will of course load the corresponding
operating system kernel
which is where roughly speaking the boot
sequence ends and the operating system
takes control
so now with this very high level
understanding and general framework of
how uefi works
we should probably ask ourselves how
is moon balance's infection manifested
in it
and to answer it we can break down moon
bounces infection to
or moon balance infection chain to four
essential phases
with the core of the infection being
based in the component that i described
a few moments ago called the dixie
dispatcher so in essence what the
attackers did
was to infect or modify the image of
this uh particular component within the
ua5 firmware on the spi flash and that
allowed uh further malicious code to
propagate from the from this component
to other boot sequence
components uh once the computer is
started
more specifically uh the implants code
first reaches the uh windows operating
system loader
um
then it reaches the windows kernel and
finally it deploys a malicious
components uh a malicious component in a
windows user mode process
so having that in mind
we can now articulate the particular
steps that are taken from the moment uh
that the malicious dixie dispatcher
kicks in during the machine startup and
until the malware propagates to user
land process once the operating system
is up and running
so let's do it
so as i mentioned uh a moment ago um
the uh core of the infection lies um in
some changes made by the attackers to uh
the uh dixie uh dispatcher
uh in the firmware and those changes are
mainly the addition of um inline hooks
first of all of of particular payload
and then inline hooks within um
some efi boot services functions that
divert the execution
of the original execution of this
component to the particular payload that
is embedded within it
generally speaking uh these hooks um are
plain patches to the first bytes um
of the hooked functions
such that the first calls
to these functions are diverted to a
designated hook handlers
after the first execution of each
such handler the patched bytes
are restored to the original ones and
control is passed back to the original
functions so as to
not interfere with the regular boot
sequence because essentially that one is
still required to work as well in order
for the infection to properly go through
so
let's try to tackle what each hook
function
achieves in this stage
when the dixie dispatcher runs
upon the computer startup it first calls
at a particular point
the allocate pull
boot service function the hook logic
logic for this function will in turn
allocate a designated buffer in physical
memory
and we'll copy shell code into it
and we'll discuss this shell quite a
little bit later um
before we do that let's talk let's
tackle another uh function which is the
create event x function um
in which case uh the hook function will
be invoked um
will
eventually register a particular
callback function
for an event of a legacy boot so as some
of you know um ufi uh has what's called
csm
which stands for uh
compatibility let me recall the acronym
that should be a
compatibility support module and the
compatibility the compatibility support
module uh allows uh essentially to load
um to to to conduct a boot sequence that
uh initiates from the mbr uh while uh
having alongside the ufi um um the the
the ufi loaded uh through firmware as
well so um that uh kind of support for
legacy boot uh is facilitated by the csm
and in the event of a legacy boot uh
we'll have a callback that will allow uh
to map the uh formerly um allocated
buffer to which we wrote shellcode to
map it to the address space of the
windows kernel and invoke the shell code
from within it so we're kind of
in this case being able to tackle both
cases the legacy boot and the boot uh
through uefi firmware
and then uh after we have those two uh
hooks running and um
we actually let the uh boot sequence
carry on until um
we reach the point of execution where
the windows loader runs
um so at this particular point um
when the operating systems loader kicks
in
it is under essential to understand that
uh the cleanup and termination of the
boot services um is done by the os
loader um and that is done through
invocation of a function that is called
exit boot services which is in itself a
part of the e5 boot service table
um so the hooking of this function is
really what allows the malicious code to
propagate essentially from the dixie
dispatcher to the operating systems
loader which is uh where it is in charge
of installing um another hook to a
function that is called osl arc transfer
to kernel
uh this function is originally used to
pass control from the loader uh from the
os loader to the windows kernel so
invoking malicious code in that um
transition transitional phase uh when
the os kernel image is loaded in memory
uh but has still not been executed uh is
what essentially allows introducing
further
malicious modifications to the kernel
itself
um an interesting uh note here is that
this particular technique was actually
um been seen
in the vault 7 leak that consists of
information on some of the sensitive
offensive toolset that is used by the
cia
and
this
could be used just you know as a very
broad speculation um
that
the threat actor could
could have used this particular resource
in order to mimic this particular
technique but again this is just a
speculation
so for the next step the osl arc
transfer to kernel hook
installs yet another hook um to a
fundamental kernel api function called x
allocate pool
now recall that during the dixie
dispatcher's execution
the malicious code set up a buffer with
the shell code in memory
however that memory was not part of the
windows kernel virtual outer space
as the kernel was not running at that
point which is why
the x allocate pull hook first maps this
particular buffer to the kernel's memory
following that
it gets it passes control to the
particular shell code that is within
this buffer and in turn the shell code
is in charge of reflectively loading um
an image that is embedded within um
uh within um the original um
dixie dispatcher um sorry within the
original uh driver um and the uh sorry
within the dispatcher and this driver um
is in turn um in charge of notifying uh
what's called an image notify routine
which is a callback that gets invoked
upon a load of an image
in the operating system
um and
so now the question is what is the
purpose of that uh callback that was set
by the driver
well this particular callback uh is
intended to check uh the path of the
primary image um in each uh process of
the operating system and verify if the
the the image is loaded in the context
of an svc host that exe process with um
an argument um that is named met svcs
or in other words basically
it tries to see if
there is a loaded service in the
operating system that has access to the
network now the first instance of such a
service
will actually
be used to inject a further uh malicious
code through the apc injection technique
um
which would in turn um allow to which
would in turn reach out to a command and
control server and we'll try to fetch a
second stage payload from it
unfortunately
we were not able to grab that particular
payload
but
nevertheless we could still determine
that the attackers
who most likely deployed moonbounds on
the infected
machine
were
were very likely affiliated to the
apt-41 group
now
what is the apt-41 group so apt-41 is an
infamous chinese-speaking threat group
that is known to be engaged in multiple
high-profile um
espionage as well as criminal operations
including some
quite
famous supply chain attacks
for example the the one on c cleaner
that happened in 2017
and
really why do we make the connection to
this group
so
the primary reason is the fact that uh
throughout our investigation on other
nodes uh in the same network range we
were able to determine that the
attackers used a very specific user land
implant called scramble cross
that is actually known to be quite
unique to apt-41
the particular variant
of this malware
that was used in this attack
as well as the loaders that started up
which are named stealth vector and
stealth mutant
were all actually covered by both trend
micro and eset last year
and both reached the conclusion that the
tool sets as well as the underlying
activity
could be traced back to abd-41
now in our case it wasn't only the mere
presence of the implant um that kind of
suggested uh that apt-41 was involved
but it was actually the fact that um the
scramble cross implant that we found
reached out to command and control
infrastructure that was shared with
moonbounds
so if you recall i described that moon
bounce eventually sets up the stage for
the execution of a malicious
user mode component
that reaches out to a server in order to
fetch subsequent payloads
so as it turns out
some of the scrambled cross command
control servers shared the very same
domain
with moon bounces server which is
this
glbai tag.com
that you can see on the screen
not only that
but all the domains um both the one
corresponding to moonbounds and those
that reached out
uh
reached out to by scramble cross
resolved uh to the same ips in different
points in time
so um in addition
uh we could also observe that uh quite a
few of the servers on those ips
responded with a unique certificate that
was only used
by infrastructure leveraged by apd-41 in
fact uh some of these servers uh that uh
used that certificate were were
specified in a security uh bulletin um
that was issued by the fbi in 2020 that
outlines some outline some of the
indicators that
could be identified with the activity of
apt-41
other than apt-41 though it appears that
there was presence of
several other implants on the same
network that could also be
affiliated to chinese speaking threat
actors
most notably we found a backdoor named
microsyn which is known to be used by a
threat group named slm uh or six little
monkeys um
um that
actually if we look more carefully at
the timestamps of deployment for uh both
microsyn and scramblecross
which we
already established as very likely
connected to moonbounds
it appears as though um both pieces of
malware were actually used or deployed
in tandem
and this could allude to the fact that
microsyn was in fact
a tool that uh was used as part of the
very same operation in which
moon bounce was leveraged and actually
it could also suggest that
apd 41 and the slm thread group
may share some resources
be it um shared uh toolsets uh or actual
developers that um could be um
coordinated by uh those uh two groups
um apart from that
we could also take note of the
compilation timestamps on some of the
images in those
attacks and
and if we try to understand what those
mean uh then first if we look at when
the infected dixie dispatcher was
compiled
we see that it happened back in 2014
and that actually seems to correspond to
the date in which the particular
firmware version was released by the
vendor
in contrast to that uh the p images that
correspond to the driver and user mode
malware stager of moonbounds
seem to have been compiled in proximity
to one another uh during the end of
2018.
now what could that mean so for one if
we are to believe those times the
timestamps then um well obviously you
can understand that those could be fake
but
if we are to assume that they are
correct
then we can assess that mood bounce was
actually compiled apart from the
original firmware
and that's actually a pretty plausible
assumption in fact
the idea that the attackers had to
access the specific uh core uh the
specific dixie dispatcher image uh parse
it and then uh introduce uh those subtle
changes that um i described earlier
suggest that the attackers had um and
likely ongoing access to the infected
machine
now considering the timeline and other
backdoors found in the same network we
can assess that actually those other
backdoors that we found could have
facilitated facilitated a remote and
long-standing access to the machine in
question which would finally allow the
deployment of moon balance
apart from that um considering the 2018
timestamp
we are kind of faced with an important
question um if we are to believe
this
compilation timestamp uh and we know by
fact that the ufi furore infection
actually happened during mid 2020 um
we found it in 2021 but the infection
itself
occurred sometime
mid-2020 um then we're faced with the
question uh of whether moonbounds um
could have been circulating somewhere
between 2018 and 2020 in other places in
the wild before we found it and that
actually is a question that remains to
be answered
so
now that we know how moon bounce works
and we have a general concept of who
deployed it it's worth trying to think
how we can better protect against uh it
or similar attacks uh that target uefi
firmware
and
here as much as i would like to devise a
single solution i think that the best
approach is actually considering a set
of hybrid methods to mitigate such an
attack
and the first one is being
a very simple proactive measure of
updating uh the uefi firmware with
vendor authenticated images casually of
course
this could prove to be insufficient as
some firmware images
are not well protected
and
this is why it's actually advisable to
use additional protection layers
two notable examples for that uh would
be uh technologies like uh the intel
boot guard and trusted trust platform
modules or tpm
uh in the case of tpm um which uh as
some of you may know is uh
sort of a designated crypto uh processor
uh on on the machine
this is a feature actually that is ought
to be enabled by default in windows 11.
so
if you're not using windows 11 and you
do have the support for dpm
i do uh suggest um verifying that it is
turned on because
that would be
a useful measure against such attacks
unfortunately though
not all machines support um
guard or tpms and there are still a lot
of legacy u5 firmware uh circulating in
the wild and for this reason it's also
beneficial uh beneficial to consider um
an additional security solution that
can scan ufi firmware um and notify the
user
if there is some anomaly found within it
except
this will only be efficient as long as
the
network or organization that deploys
such a solution um has actual people
that are trained
to identify such alerts and act upon
them so in that sense it is also
important
in light of attacks like
moon bounds to train the blue teamers or
analysts that deal
with threats in the organization
in the organization to be aware of
alerts that concern um firmware
compromise
so
on this note um i'd like to address um
maybe on a more uh general um
term the problem of ufi firmware attacks
um which um um is the fact that albeit
uh the defense mechanisms that i just
mentioned a lot of ufi firmware is still
vulnerable and
quite exposed
to abuse by threat actors
on top of that
the security industry as a whole
it seems still lacks visibility
into this type of threats
which
were actually publicly tackled in the
past few years but they are certainly
not a new threat we have all seen
the ufi
boot kit that
was in use by
a hacking team back in 2015 and 16
and we can estimate that the threat of
ufi funeral compromises
probably exists
for
a little less than a decade um so
by no means the fact that moonbounds and
similar threats were discovered right
now
means that this threat is new
or that this threat is
is about to go away so
we should realize that such threats are
actually here to stay with us and
that's why it's important at least in my
opinion that security vendors um
will share or give more attention um
to the information to such threats and
will share the information that concerns
them
as we did in this case
because that
is what will essentially be able to
educate and alarm blue teamers and
defenders
as to how
such threats behave
and how to address them in order to
employ better mitigations
so with that
i think our time is up and i'd like to
thank you for your time and attention
if you have any questions at this point
i'd be more than happy to take those and
thank you
thank you mark for the presentation uh
i
think we actually have two questions
already in the chat box is it all right
if i ask them uh read them out cloud
okay
um
does it have hooks tools to threaten
linux os
sorry could you could you repeat that
question one more time
yuri is asking does it have hooks tools
to threaten linux os
let me open the chat and and see it but
if i understand the question correctly
uh
the question is whether that particular
thread is also applicable on the linux
operating system is that is that the
question
well i believe so
if if it is then actually no moon bounce
in particular is um
designated for the windows kernel there
are a lot of assumptions throughout its
execution
that kind of
[Music]
assume that the
loaded operating system is actually
windows and
it will not work on linux
that said though
we cannot exclude that there is a
variant that would essentially target
linux
but
um it's not the variant that we discuss
or that we found
thank you
another question is do you think
measured booth will be able to catch
such attacks
well uh i think
yes well
measure boot will certainly uh be able
to notify of an anomaly in terms of
modifications that happened in the
firmware image um
however it's up to uh the people who uh
who read the logs uh and kind of uh
interpret what happened during boot time
to be able to understand that uh there
was um a compromise going on and that
this compromise has to be mitigated so
yeah by by all means measured boot uh
will be at least if effective in the
sense that it will indicate that there
is a compromise
thank you mark
um we actually have a few more questions
um you've mentioned dpm as a counter
measure will it raise the bars
significantly in your opinion
um
well
for this threat yes um because right now
um
the situation is that um
this particular threat and actually
other ones uh mosaic regressor that we
uncovered back in 2020
and also uh lojacks
they all kind of relied on the fact that
um the underlying firmware did not have
proper protections against writing
and uh considering that um
all of
those
uh this kind of um change um
in the firmware and and to to kind of uh
raise um a red flag in case of that that
um
that the signature of the firmware
doesn't check out
um
having said that um
there could be other measures to to to
bypass tpm uh which will not go into in
this talk so i wouldn't say that tpm is
a bulletproof solution it's it's
it's not um you know
unfortunately we cannot say that
anything
in our world or in the domain of
security is a bulletproof solution
however at least for the attacks that we
have seen so far for the three public
known cases that we know um that
[Music]
employ
compromise of ufi firmware um in those
cases tpm would have definitely raised
the bar yes
all right
um how do you avoid a scan from being
fooled by the implant as it can
potentially manipulate any tool running
in user kernel mode running from a
separate physical host
sorry i i
i didn't follow the question
no problem i will repeat it
how do you avoid a scan from being
fooled by the implant as it can
potentially manipulate any tool running
in user or kernel mode running from a
separate physical host
well um
for one
we have um already discussed well there
was this question erased about measured
boot
um so red measured boot has its own
mechanisms i'm not an expert in tpm but
but i do know that measured boot has its
own mechanism of
sending uh encrypted logs
to to
possibly an external server uh where uh
it could be
let's say compromising the u5 firmware
does not mean that uh compromise
happened uh to the tpm uh in fact i
don't believe it's that simple to do so
um
in that case in the case of tpm the logs
of measured boot can still be um
used to to alert the user of a possible
compromise
as far as um
having a ufi firmware implant uh fooling
a a kernel mode uh solution
um like a driver uh or anything actually
that happens uh after the boot well i
definitely agree that there's a problem
here
because if you cannot trust your ui
firmware then well you cannot trust
everything that is loaded afterwards
which is exactly why i think that there
should be usage of
additional
components that
that kind of allow
verifying um what goes on in the u5
firmware itself
and that are external to the ue5
firmware and not being loaded by it
that that's that's as best as i i would
i would you know tackle this situation
all right um
how do you verify if your machine is
affected manish is asking this question
um
well in the case of moon bounds
well it's hard to you know hard to
answer this question generally
uh
obviously you cannot always know that
your machine is infected
um however for moon balance
because um
it it it had some anomalous behavior um
happening um
even after
the execution of the uefi firmware
implant for example uh the injection of
um
of payload from the kernel mode driver
uh to user mode process um and then
having that um injected code reaching
out to a server um this is a behavior
that is being caught or that was caught
in our case by our product and and i
assume will be caught by a lot of
security products so
um
in any case that um you may encounter um
an infection
and you know
a simple measure as
um
let's say
formatting your hard drive and
reinstalling the operating system
doesn't seem to remove the thread so the
thread keeps coming back
then you have you know good a good
reason to to to speculate whether you
might have some more lower level uh
infection of course that won't be the
first thing that i would consider but it
will definitely be one of the things
that um at least nowadays uh should be
uh thought of as um
as a marker uh that a um kind of low
level boot kit
firmware compromise
could have happened
thank you mark we have one last question
from danny
how do you think the main factor of
infection was
well um as i mentioned um
[Music]
we assess that the infection um has
taken place um remotely
and
um
it it was done um
through well i cannot say exactly what
what was the utility that was used to
override the firmware but i can
definitely attest to the fact that uh
the underlying
firmware itself did not have any proper
protection mechanisms
and against writing uh for this reason
um it is not that much of a problem or
was not that much of a problem to
override the firmware um
that that that resided on that
particular machine so
so having said that um well considering
this i mean it is plausible to assume
that um the overwrite happened through
uh software not not through access to
the hardware itself
um and
the other thing is that um well now the
question is asked whether that override
happened locally so somebody approached
the computer and you know
leveraged
his local access to override the
firmware or has it been done
remotely and we think it was done
remotely because um
the the uh particular changes that um
were taken in that particular film were
so uh those uh subtle hooks that were
installed
in the original core dixie or dixie
dispatcher image
those required um the attackers to have
some kind of long uh standing access to
that particular machine they would have
uh had to um
read that image
introduce some changes to it and then
override it and
and um
that is assessed to have been done um
along
across some uh period of time across um
you know an extended period of time
and um given the fact that we have seen
other um
uh backdoors in that network
um
for quite long time span
um we can assess that some of these
vectors were used to facilitate this uh
long uh term access that would
eventually allow the attackers to uh
prepare uh the tempered firmware image
and have it overwritten
in the targeted machine
thank you mark for answering all these
questions
i think that
we can conclude the webinar now thank
you very much once again mark for your
presentation and thanks for everyone who
attended today's session