well hello and welcome to the second day
of nam khan if you're not familiar with
the second day all we're doing today is
workshops all the workshops are going to
be free the first workshop we have going
on will be with Jeff Foley the author of
a mass he's going to show us how he uses
a mass and how to be efficient while
using it so before we get started do me
a favor go ahead and check into discord
make sure you're looking at all the
announcements we're still doing the IOT
village workshops all day that's going
to be offline within this chord all you
have to do is go to the website and
enroll and if you're lacking the content
and you want to give back and you want
to donate consider donating to Isis by
going through Isis
org slash donate you can also use the
donate command on this cord and go to
the link the way the workshops are going
to work is the first workshop is going
to be live but we have a very packed
schedule so if you have any questions
just hold on to it until the end of the
workshop if we have time we'll make sure
to get to it and if we run out of time
and don't have time to come to the
questions we'll make sure to answer all
of your questions either on discord or
on Twitter also if you have any
questions and make sure you hold on to
them until the end so let's jump right
into it please give it up for Jeff he's
going to give us a very cool workshop on
amass Jeff thank you so much for doing
this and the floor is yours all right
thank you then yeah I'd like to start by
just saying you know thank you to nam
khan for inviting me to do this it's a
pleasure to be supporting women in
cybersecurity and I want to thank Kwan
Tyrion for making it possible for me to
make time to prepare all this and just
uh if you have any additional questions
or interests in attack surface
management feel free to reach out to
kuan Tyrion so I've broken this workshop
up into an intro to this project the
OWASP amassed project in case some
people aren't familiar with it and then
some basic usage which could include
things that people are not used to doing
with it and then some more advanced
usage which I where I address some ways
to get better performance from a mass
and then I'm going to use the end of
this workshop to cover the new mass
scripting engine where you can script
your own data sources for for mass
alright so with that start with so where
do you go get this if you're not already
familiar with us hopefully everyone can
see this yeah we can see it oh yeah you
should just be able to type in OWASP a
mess it should bring you right to the
repo a few things about what to do once
you get here so you can go to releases
these are updated on a pretty regular
basis I would definitely recommend
always getting the latest release since
we put out bug fixes pretty frequently
for instance this one went out last
night we get a lot of great feedback
from all the users so we try to respond
as quickly as possible to the issues
that they present to us also you can
come down
here and find our documentation so I
definitely recommend if you haven't
already take a look at this since there
are a lot of things you can do with this
tool and we've tried to capture at least
some of it in these documents but I
don't know I'm not sure how much to
assume people know about this already
but in case you're not familiar you know
just like this says this tools focus or
scope is all has always been to provide
in-depth attack surface mapping and
asset discovery so it's to try to give
you the greatest number of findings
possible and as I'm sure some of you are
aware that hasn't always meant as fast
as possible since it takes longer to
find more and not all the techniques
that amass uses are passive so we'll get
into that a little bit so those are the
basics I just want to cover about
project if if you have any further
questions about the project of course
please feel free to come to our discord
which you can find right here it's
that's the preferred location to bring
questions troubleshooting you asking us
for help for things like that if you
have problems like you know for sure
there's something wrong with the tool or
a release has broken something or you
just have feature requests then please
feel free to go to the issues all right
so enough
I think so one thing I wanted to cover
before we jump into using this is how
what is the mass doing when you execute
it because it's as I mentioned a moment
ago it's not simply reaching out the
data sources pulling data and getting
unique results and printing them out
it's a mass has a cyclic process where
the results from each data source are
feeding that engine that that cyclic
process and they are feeding off of each
other right the results from one are
then being fed back into other ones and
they're using that to find more and more
and more results which is why it can
take a long time for it to finish
because it only takes one more finding
to potentially fire off a lot of
additional activity and mass attempts
keep that going until it can actually
say there's nothing more I can do so if
if you know for sure that you just can't
wait for the exhaustive process to
complete then I would recommend using
the timeout flag and people have asked
questions like what do I do to address
this if I have it in a you know a
workflow or something like that where
I'd like to know I can complete it in
two hours if that's a requirement then I
would say just use the timeout feature
because then then you know it will stop
at that point and the rest of your
workflow will continue all right so
before we go again into me putting hands
on the tool another thing I'd like to
show is the configuration file so this
configuration file is the same one that
you can get from the repo under examples
and there's a lot of things that you can
provide on the command line with a mass
that can also be provided in your config
file so a lot of people
myself used this as a way to save their
fingers from having to type these things
over and over again what I'm going to do
today on this call so that we can I can
aim this at a couple interesting targets
is I'm going to include the target
domain in this config file and then I'm
going to turn on the demo feature which
will turn will make it so you only see
some of the output so that we can feel
like we're doing the right thing you're
not exposing organizations
infrastructure yet we can get some
interesting results to see during the
workshop so I'll be using like these
here so if you what you're gonna see me
doing is just providing the config file
normally if a lot of people I think
would be instead putting those arguments
on the command line all right
another important thing is and I get
questions about this law so I want to
make sure to cover this so the amass
tool has an output directory which you
can see here in the configuration file
but it's common
because this this is the default value
and actually interesting this right here
is not the statement is a little off so
let me let me explain what is actually
happening here
if you
with no direct output directory
specified it picks a location that's
based on the OS that you're using so for
this operating system which is Linux
this is Kali Linux it is it should be
located under dot config I'm asked which
is where it stores as you can see the
log file the JSON output the text output
you would receive if you said - oh and
the dot bolt file is the local graph
database but there's other things that
we're going to get into later in this
workshop where if you include them under
your output directory you can get
special a mass we'll go looking for it
there so it's important to know about it
for instance if you build yourself a
config file and you put it under the
output directory a mass will
automatically consume it or use it
there's other files like that like later
I'm going to talk about the scripting
engine there's a special location under
this directory where it will look for
custom scripts so this is an important
place to know about but if you don't
want to have to remember where these
directories are for each OS like for
instance under Mac OS it's your home
directory library application support
amass kind of kind of a long path to be
worrying about it's just easier in my
opinion to use the - der flag and just
give it
a directory that you want to use since
it needs the directory anyway and some
people just you know and would prefer
use the default and I have to think
about it it uses those special locations
or default locations so I thought I'd
mention that since many people have
asked about you know how exactly does
the output directory work and you know
what they use for why is it being
created things like that yeah I get a
lot of questions too about the graph
database so the graph database is not
necessary it is used by default there's
a flag pretty sure it's no local
no local DB that sort of so if you use
this flag you can cause the local
database not to be created the effect
that has on your experience using this
tool is that you will not be able to use
the tracking features you will not be
able to use the visualization generation
and you will not be able to ask the tool
to produce previous you know previous
discoveries or findings since it's not
going to save it anywhere but it would
cause your workflow if you're simply
going to use the data from say an output
text file and send it to something else
and you have no intention of using the
data later then it could speed up the
process since it's one less thing that a
mass has to handle before it's finished
mm-hmm so it's worth noting or being
aware of the graph database is generated
at runtime in memory but it does not
have to save it for you if you don't
want it and the reason it uses the graph
database is because graphs are the
structure that infrastructure pipe is
actually laid out in it's more natural
than say relational database are a list
of some type so it just it works better
it allows makes it easier to work with
the data alright so moving along another
thing I was going to quickly go
is the subcommands so we will not have
time to go in depth on each of these
today but I do want to mention what what
are these though or what are the
differences between them so the one that
most people I imagine are familiar with
is this one right because this is the
vertical domain domain name correlation
or DNS enumeration of the main
numeration which many people are fond of
but the other one that is probably of
interest as well is Intel so in the
future I'm thinking of changing these
names to be a little bit more clear I
might call them horizontal and vertical
just to make it perfectly clear what
what the differences but the goal of
Intel was really to allow you to provide
what you know about the target and find
more of its attack surface or more of
its infrastructure more of its namespace
so that you could expand your scope so
if you're not trying to expand your
scope then it's probably not of interest
but if you're looking to know as much
about the target say organization or
network as possible then Intel would be
of interest to you and and I'll mention
a few things today about how the two of
these can feed each other which Jason
Haddix has covered in the past and some
of his previous presentations is
quite simple it really just takes data
that you feel already collected and then
makes it possible to generate files that
can then be used to visualize your
discoveries I personally find this very
helpful I'm a very visual person and I
also like being able to present the
findings this way to other people since
I have personally found that people who
aren't doing this like we are tend to
understand it better when you can point
at something and say that this is what
that is this is why it shouldn't be here
things like that the tracking feature is
so that if you're doing these
enumerations multiple times against the
same target and your goal when it's all
over is you just want to know what
showed up or what changed from the last
time I did it don't bother me with the
things I already know then you would
like this feature because it allows you
to just get the highlights or just get
the changes what's been removed what's
been added what has moved to a new
location the DB sub command is becoming
more and more important it's it's the
command that allows you to take control
of your data after it's been collected
we have a lot of work to do on this as
we keep moving along with this project
because there's a lot of things that
currently I'd like to see users be able
to do with this that you you can't right
now
right now you kind of get what you get
and the DB command can tell you what's
in there but for instance it doesn't
really let you make changes to the data
or maybe add things in that you know
should be in there and to be honest
last one is a little bit of an
experimental feature right now it's just
in here at the moment
for testing kind of eventually I'd like
to think it could be exactly what it
says it could be if you have a list of
names and you just want to resolve all
the names and be able to get them into
your amassed data then this would be the
sub command to do it as opposed to doing
a full enumeration all right so moving
along so let's let's see what this up
what does this all mean what does this
look like it's all I'll start out with
what I would guess everyone is or
everyone that's uses before is already
familiar with which is you have a domain
name and you'd like to get sub domain
enumeration performed against that
domain so I tend to use these to make
sure I can see all the results for all
the data available and then we'll just
put in a wasp or gray now so what
happens right now is it it's firing up
the engine where the various data
sources that the services get fired off
and the engine that sends out the
requests are starting to send them out
and then soon you'll see it say that uh
it's engaging actually I'm surprised I'm
not seeing it there we go
but it's engaging the various data
sources in asking about OAuth org I'm
gonna have to make this a little bigger
I think
so as you can see it tells you what
which source found it first what the
name was
and then what the IP address or
addresses was that for that name now one
thing that many people perhaps would
know is that let's say that this is the
data source that gets reported for
finding this it does not mean that if
the only data source that found it it's
just the first one or the or the one
that was chosen to be printed since
there's only really room here to be
printing one but the chances are
actually pretty good that there could be
several data sources that found the same
name and in the future we're thinking of
creating a DB sub command like flag or
requests where you could say for this
name show me all the sources that found
it I think there's some value in knowing
that because it would allow you to know
how likely is it that people can find it
how known is that is the target for that
or the asset because if you found it and
says well only one data source knew
about it then in your mind you could say
this the chances are pretty low that
other people know about this maybe it
hasn't been checked yet for security
vulnerabilities perhaps it's worth my
time to take a look at it
relative to some of the other ones so
anyway this
small domain rate got very small number
of names it only found the results from
you know a few places and they all are
under Cloud Fleur so it printed it gives
you the summary information at the end
you know it indicates that it's finished
and then it moves on to if you didn't
turn off the local DB storage then it
migrates the data into the local DB that
that's in my mind at least typical usage
of this tool many people I've seen on
Twitter use this in passive mode I would
argue if you use it that way you are
guaranteeing probably that it's going to
be faster to complete but you're also
only using a mass for the most basic of
of capabilities that it has you're only
engaging the data sources pulling the
results and printing them out
it doesn't even allow a mask to validate
that the names are still being used or
still in the DNS records of the target
organization so it's extremely limited
it's just faster because there's less
work to do but if you take off the
passive flag it's pulling the same data
but now it's checking that those names
are still legitimate or they're still it
valid and it allows you to get the
additional information of not just that
the you know what are the names but what
are the IP addresses and it allows you
to find more of the infrastructure for
the target organization and it's going
to find more names name is that that the
passive data sources didn't know for
instance by using things like reverse
DNS queries and things like that
Oh me
check how we're doing on time here then
real quick do we have
questions at the moment about output or
what I've covered so far or is everyone
holding their questions as asked I'll
assume that's no one will continue
moving forward so that's basic usage or
what I would call basic usage once you
have the
information though as I mentioned
earlier earlier there's other things you
can do with it so right now if I bring
this to the top of the screen I type a
mass and I say DB and I'll just say show
me the summary information for Alice org
so it will print the same
we saw a moment ago when it completed
the enumeration mmm
thing that's interesting about doing it
this way though is if if you've done
that enumeration ten times say over the
course of a couple weeks this summer
information will will include only the
information you've collected so each
enumeration isn't guaranteed to give you
the same results all right it depends on
how each data source behaved it depends
on how the resolvers behaved that you
know you queried for the names there's
all sorts of reasons why you could get
different answers each time you fire
this off also though if you have data in
the database a mass pulls the data as
input for future enumerations against
the same target so if I if I do another
org enumeration all those names that
showed up the first time which we can
look at despite typing this so all those
will end up in the next enumeration mmm
you'll just get added in immediately in
order to encourage consistency from one
enumeration to the next so that we're
not missing anything we already knew
about assuming it's still there which
hopeful
the effect of that is that every time
you run this you should only be getting
more and more results as long as you're
not wiping out the database in between
executions so that's a nice feature it
also helps the tracking so that again it
creates consistency so that hopefully if
you're using tracking and it says you
know a name was still you know removed
hopefully that actually means it was
removed not just that you didn't get
lucky this time and discover it all
right so another thing you can do once
the data is in the database is visualize
it so what you're seeing here is this up
lots of to hear but d3 is the format
that I'm going to ask it to export the
data in which allows us to open it up in
a browser because it's got HTML around
it and allows us to just look at the
results in the web browser so it's nice
when you have a small number of findings
because I would say III can probably
handle at least with the way I'm using
it up to maybe a thousand discoveries if
you start getting higher than that it
starts getting overwhelmed I think and
probably want to consider other formats
other programs to visualize it so if we
D 3
hell it wast org should end up with our
d3 information in the output directory
say about that
Clara t'v go look at it
that's interesting
I imagine though what we're hoping to
see is right here so yeah this isn't the
most
and graph to look at but that's your
domain
the subdomains these are the addresses
which the fact that they're so huge
probably means a lot of these are
pointing to the same addresses maybe
maybe all of them are pointing to the
same ones which I think what we saw
earlier and we have the different net
blocks the IP addresses belong to the a
s information and I've got some pointer
records that are pointing back to some
of these names and that's about it now
larger targets give you more interesting
things to look at but um anyway that
that's how you would output that and
open it up quick to take a look at it if
you had a more interesting graph you'd
probably have structure more interesting
to look at which could give you ideas
for where you want to spend your time
investigating the the assets maybe where
you would if you start to see say a lot
of names that are indicating maybe
there's development activity going on
there you know things that would cause
people to make bad decisions and could
be again worth looking into more perhaps
you don't hone in on those parts of
their network I also notice you can just
quickly see relationships between
organizations you know such as people
using certain services and you know it's
interesting to be able to quickly pull
that out of the realization whereas you
know trying to glean that from you know
a list of names and IP addresses at
least for me is not quite as easy all
right so
think this would be a good time to move
along to not just basic usage but I mean
if you haven't noticed already I'm I'm
skimming and trying to hit points that I
feel I get a lot of questions on our
discord server about if I were going to
try to cover everything about this tool
we'd have to have a probably a full-day
training session or something like that
I've done training sessions in the past
where there at least twice as long as
this workshop and still like at the end
feel like there's more to talk about so
I'm trying to use this as a opportunity
to share with people answers to
questions I feel like I get frequently
so that in the future people would have
a place to go get answers to these
things faster so one thing I use a lot
and I'm not sure everyone realizes
realizes is that their disposal is the
include flag this up again
so include and exclude allow you to
control which data sources are being
used went during your enumeration
so perhaps you you know for sure that
you just don't want to use some some
data sources maybe you know that you
only want to use a few or you'd like to
see only what comes back from from those
so there's some some ways that you can
leverage this in order to I would say
get finer green control over what
happens when you execute a mass so for
instance as an example if I I say a mass
you know so actually let me let me
mention one more thing if you say
passive what this will do for you
when you're using the include flag is it
will allow you to say I'm only going to
mention one data source and I I just
want it print it out I I really don't
want anything else done with it or
almost pretty much nothing done with it
I just want to see the results that come
from it so if you say passive and
include and let's just
fire that off what should happen is that
it's only going to ask that one data
source for the subdomains for OWASP org
and it's just going to print it out so
there's there's some things that happen
anyway in the the engine the amass
engine that you really just can't avoid
like for instance it's gonna do this in
Iowa this uh first one here but for the
most part all you're gonna get is
exactly what you requested
mmm so that can be a helpful feature I
mean I use that all the time when I'm
testing if I want to say look I just
want to see what happens when I engage
that one data source and that it's going
to give me what I'm expecting it to give
me but I imagine that could be pretty
useful for people who want to have that
kind of fine-grained control over their
enumeration process the other similar
thing here is now let's say you wanted
to do something like that but you didn't
want passive one thing that I don't
think enough people realize is if you do
if you were to just fire this off right
here it's it's probably not going to do
quite what you had in mind because what
will happen is you're now asking it to
go get the names for the sub domain
names for Alice org but then when the
rest of the process attempts to get IP
addresses what you will do
it'll get IP addresses because the DNS
will take care of that but then when
it's going to take those IP address as
an attempt to get network or
infrastructure information about what
network does that IP address reside in
it's going to not be able to find that
because CRTs
does not provide that information so if
you if the effect you're looking for is
I want to run a math not in passive mode
I want but in normal mode but the only
data source that produces names that I
want to use is crts H then you actually
need to do something more like this
where you give it the the name data
source and the data source capable of
looking up the infrastructure
information so that way it will be able
to get all the data necessary to to
produce or build the database so for
instance if it wasn't able to
you wouldn't see these things getting
printed out right now the only reason
they don't have IP addresses it at the
end is because I didn't ask a mask to
give it to me as the command line flag
but mm but if it wasn't using our ADB to
get the AAS information then these
things wouldn't be getting printed out
and it wouldn't be able to tell you what
ASN you know these things are on Susan
so that I think is something that you
know I've had people come and ask how
they can have that kind of control over
their enumeration but I think maybe the
project hasn't communicated all this as
well as possible or as well as we could
so here's here's us making our first
attempt
I already told Ben in previous
discussions that you know this project
has goals to clarify some of this in our
documentation in in the future we just
have a lot of things that are going on
and haven't managed to do this as of now
all right so that's what I wanted to
show at least with the include exclude
and just having better control over your
your data sources you'll probably find
this all very useful too as we move to
the discussion of the scripting engine
because when you want to only fire off
your script your custom scripts you're
gonna want to know how to do this
otherwise you're gonna find you're
running your scripts along with all the
other data sources and it'll be hard to
tell what kind of performance you're
getting from your data sources so you'll
probably like this as time goes on all
right so another thing
gonna mention I don't think I'm gonna
spend a lot of time on this I was gonna
show it is so a mask is not by default
perform brute-forcing but it will so if
it's not that difficult to do right so
if we're doing our typical enumeration
you know we say yeah we want to see
where these things are coming from
you can just say brew and what this will
give you if that's all you give it hmm
is it will turn on brute-forcing with
the default configurations and with the
default word list that being the big one
right because most people of course have
their own word lists or ones that they'd
prefer to be using so if you give it the
W flag then you can provide any word
list you like and it will use that
instead keeping in mind of course though
the default behavior of this
brute-forcing if you if you execute it
like this is it's recursive
brute-forcing so the default value which
i think is in here if I'm not correct
about that if not then we
to make sure it makes its way in all
right right here so brute-forcing it is
not enabled by default because these are
commented out but if you enable it it is
recursive by default you can turn that
off let's see number of all right so
this is actually out of date oh good
think good thing I'm going through all
these burn up is update these but this
value by default is 1 not 0 so what does
this mean so the min for recursive value
is it means come up here if I if I have
you know example.com or something like
that that's our domain now that is going
to be brute-force right away like we're
gonna we're gonna end up for instance
trying you know these kinds of names no
matter what but what happened the
question becomes so what happens if it
discovers a another name I'm just
thinking of one like let's make make
something up but discovers this now
people have often asked the project so
what what does the recursive
brute-forcing do does it find that and
then just automatically start forcing
you know for instance trying something
like like that so the the
answer is the default is no the default
behavior is until one label shows up off
of this one like that when that name
shows up or something like it then it
says okay we've now seen evidence that
there's names off of this label and
let's start the recursive or forcing
meaning let's take the entire word list
and apply it to this so if this was
still zero the answer would have been we
just start right away through forcing
the default value of this is one so like
I said it has to see one before will it
will start the way I think of that is it
needs to see evidence that it's worth
doing the recursive enforcing before it
does it but what if for instance for
your target organization that you're
working in you know you're doing your
bug bounty what if you happen to know
that one isn't enough
maybe maybe every subdomain or far too
many of them have www but it doesn't
necessarily mean that it's worth doing
the recursive forcing well so you could
change the value to two or three but
what if
what if you're in the different position
what if your your attitude about it is I
want to do it I want to perforce
everything hold it then set it back to
zero and then it will it's gonna take a
lot longer and but it will brute force
everything it can so that these are
important values that I've had a lot of
people come to me and say they're not
sure what these mean or they or they
don't know how this works
another thing I unfortunately don't have
time to cover during this talk is that
we we provide the ability to do masking
which allows you even greater
flexibility in your brute-forcing like I
said unfortunately I had to leave that
out of this talk but I'd recommend it if
this is important to you you probably
want to go find out what that what that
is because it's it's a feature that is
available to parts of our brute-forcing
all right I could probably spend a lot
of time on this like I said I I have to
cut the Porsche number forcing a little
short but like I like I said it's pretty
typical for me to use a mass where I
just run it you know like this or not
not against this target but like that
would be typical use for me mmm
where I activate you know those two
types of pieces of output that I like to
see I turn on brute-forcing and I give
it the target you can also specify a
list of targets I haven't done that
during the discussion but DF allows you
to give it a text file where you know it
could be domains dot txt or something
like that and it can ingest however many
domains you need although I wouldn't I
wouldn't necessarily encourage doing all
all of them at once if you don't really
need to instead maybe the ones that have
a relationship
each other and then because the more you
try to do it once the more memory you're
going to use so I would keep it in
reasonable chunks if you can although
I've you know we've also worked lately
to try to keep the memory consumption
down so it's been doing much better
these these days but I wouldn't say it's
impossible to overwhelm it if you give
it too much too much to do all right so
I'd like to move on to a topic that I
feel a lot of people are going to get
value out of and I only have a little
bit longer to cover it so let's move on
to that so in the past you know I've
gotten lots of questions about so how
can I get a mask to go even faster and
the speed that this tool goes that is
very related to the number of DNS
resolvers that you give it to work with
so the default number of resolvers
has to work with I believe is something
like eight and they're fairly
high-performance resolvers and reliable
but I would also say if you're using
them a lot and you only have eight to
work with then you're and you're coming
from the same ip that's another thing
that changes the game quite a bit but
assuming for this discussion that you're
coming from the same ip address they
will eventually figure out that you're
over you know you're abusing their sir
service so to speak and you'll start
getting throttled either by the
resolvers or by the authoritative name
server for your target not for every
single one but it all too many I feel
this happened
all too often this happens to me but it
won't happen quite as much or maybe not
at all if you give a mass more resolvers
to work with and if you're changing the
resolvers you know on a regular basis so
for this discussion what I'd like to
encourage is before this workshop I ran
a DNS validator so I imagine many people
are familiar with what that is but just
in case you're not
all right so this is your friend if you
haven't taken a look at it already so
what what I do with this personally is I
build the docker image and I run it just
like they say well except I give it a
quite a few more threads to run but
that's my you know to each their own
because they warn you if you bring that
number up too high you're gonna you're
probably going to regret it but for
instance like I I don't have any problem
running it with 100 or 200 threads but
this works really well and it's pretty
easy to you know you'll have to think
too hard about this when it's all over
you just end up with a file called
resolvers text and you know it can
easily have say something like 9 9,000
public dns servers to work with so I
would definitely recommend case you
can't see this but some put that right
there I would definitely recommend you
take a look at that now one little thing
I'll throw in there though I use
pretty regularly you know I appreciate
all the work that was put into making
this but at the same time it does not
prevent all it doesn't make it so all
the resolvers you get are are good
resolvers mmm so what do I mean by that
so first of all you're gonna give
varying performance right because
there's no telling so whose resolvers
are these are deeper our servers are
these were they being hosted what's you
know what's the latency on them but also
perhaps more concerning some of them
will look legitimate to the validator
and then when you go use them for a
while they could start giving you false
or malicious results so sometimes you
have to play with the your resolver list
quite a bit before you find say a
healthy list that is working well for
you a little bit annoying but I would
still say it's certainly better than not
using this because it's gonna find a you
know weed out a lot of bad ones for you
increasing the chances you can produce a
a good list but going a little further I
don't just take 9,000 resolvers and now
say amass please utilize 9,000 resolvers
what I do is so I have the file produced
already right here so I did it oh nice
okay
so I made this before the workshop but
it's got a lot of resolvers in it right
so what I do is you know for a given
target where I have an idea maybe of how
large it is and maybe I even know how
sensitive they are to you know the
requests coming from the same resolvers
or how likely they are to pick up on my
activity and throttle me and things like
that
you know I'll decide how many do I think
I need mm-hmm but to be honest I think I
I do well oftentimes with like 25 or 50
or 100 you don't you certainly don't
need a thousand least I really don't
think you do so what I do is I take the
list that we have right here and I say
sort randomize and then I just take the
number I want so let's say it's 25 and
then I'll call that 25 so now we just
have that many but that that's a
good number it really is mm-hm it works
quite well for me I if I have that many
in there working well for me I don't
tend to have problems usually against
even large targets where it could take
hours to finish the whole entire
enumeration but with that many you tend
to stay under the radar so but you but
you're gonna have to ask yourself
something when you when you start
tweaking these things with a mask so
let's assume we have we now have
twenty-five resolvers right and if we're
going to use them you would you would
use the RF flag and say I want to use my
25 resolvers but the maximum number of
DNS queries that the amass is going to
send out at any given moment is is the
default value for that is tweaked to the
number of default resolvers so if you
just fire this off with your with your
other arguments you're gonna find that
it's probably not as fast as you would
like so so you're going to need to set
this value right here if you really want
to see like decent performance I would
say you're gonna need to set that value
and you probably want it to be I mean I
would say play with this and come up
with your own conclusion about this but
I like to keep the numbers so that at
any given moment each of those
five resolvers could have between 500
and 1,000 queries being sent to it so
you know you might want to say 25,000 or
maybe 20,000 you know something like
that I mean just the other night I had
something like this set up or these were
the this is the way I had to set up I
had my 25 resolvers they were working
well for me and I had the Mac set to 20
20,000 and I was quite happy with the
consistent high performance I was seeing
but you need to be aware of which again
this is my on my shoulders we need to
get this more documented but these are
the kinds of things that if you really
want to have complete control over
what's happening with a mass you need to
be aware of these configuration options
but this kind of this is the kind of
thing that will allow you to take more
control over the performance of a mass
now I'll also say it won't necessarily
mean that these enumerations are gonna
finish lightening fast what you could
find is by having your query spread out
better you could end up getting more
results which are only going to cause
more you know events to take place
within a mass and it's going to ask more
questions so you know there's
things of course to consider like
earlier I mentioned be careful how much
you want forcing to fire off because
that's certainly going to create a lot
of additional traffic if you aren't
interested in name alterations which
personally I I really like name
alterations but if you don't have any
interest in it then turn them off so
that way you're reducing you know the
additional traffic that occurs I
personally don't really find myself ever
turning them off because I think they're
it's amazing how many results come back
from name alterations but it also allows
for the alt and sweep effect where your
alter permuting names they're finding
new subnets and then you're doing
reverse DNS sweeps in those subnets than
finding new names which then get altered
or permuting again and the cycle just
keeps going I'm not sure I would ever
give that up I think it's a powerful
effect all right so those are the things
I
show for advanced features that I feel
like these are things that you know I
don't see people talking about on
Twitter but I do get questions coming to
the discord server from some users about
how they can have better control over
these aspects of the tool so I thought
this would be a good place to share with
hopefully a lot of people I mean I could
be running these right to show you just
how you know the impact that it has but
I think it would use up a lot of our
time and what I'm gonna do instead is
I'd like to use that time we have
available to show you this new scripting
engine where I will show you we will run
it a couple times to actually see what's
happening here at this point though I
we're at a good spot we're at about one
hour I think you could do a quick just
five minute break and I'll be right back
and then we'll pick up with the
scripting engine
I know where is Jeff yeah everyone will
take a five-minute break and then we'll
continue with our workshop with a mass
while we wait since again this is the
second day we have one more workshop
coming up with Jason Haddix on the bug
bounty hunters methodology the fourth
version of it this is the first time
Haddix is actually presenting this which
I'm really really excited about but
while we wait a few announcements if you
are a new subscriber just make sure you
link your discord and your twitch all
subscribers do actually get their own
drops every once in a while if you're
enjoying the material you enjoy the
conversations you enjoy all of these
different talks and workshops and you
want to sorry my phone's going off how's
this thing on this on twitch but if you
want to donate and give back do me a
favor go to Isis org slash donate every
dollar counts even if it is five dollars
one dollar two dollars there's 500
people here if everybody donuts two
dollars we have raised a thousand fro
Isis within minutes so do me a favor if
you're enjoying it head over there and
make a donation and ask
least there's also an IOT workshop
happening so if you want to if you want
to go enjoy the IOT stuff and you want
to learn about IOT hacking go ahead and
head over to discord and go to the IOT
village and make sure you check out the
content and also there's five hundred
people here watching right now let us
know if you're not a bot Java animo
tell me what are you watching this slide
from are you in the US somewhere in
Europe a PAC let us know where you're at
I want to hear everybody drop something
in the chat that's he I mean without
actually listening and not just walking
away or being a bot see India Romania us
Chile Mars
Brazil Germany Europe hello from Jordan
Canada beep boop wassup JP Russia India
Jamaica Nashville Panama Canada UK
there's a lot of people here Iran South
Africa Portugal
India North Korea it's far Texas baby
what up Texas Indonesia San Diego
Iceland Puerto Rico all right there is
not a lot of bots in here today we're
good Alabama West Virginia Denver and I
drop your addresses but stalks
yourselves I'm kidding I'm kidding
watching from the Homme sex house all
right all right let's give Jeff a few
more minutes and take some time to
stretch get some coffee
got some drinks
Ryan will continue with the unmask
workshop
you
all right we're back again with Jeff
Foley
we're gonna carry on with our amassed
bootcamp you're up Jeff excellent Thank
You Ven
yeah so we're back and we're switching
gears to the new mass scripting engine
so this scripting engine allows you to
create your own data sources for a mass
now eventually you know what what it
means to be a data source could could be
you know just about anything it could be
your own brute-forcing
you know algorithms or your own name
permutation algorithms
it could be firing off a local program
or accessing you know your own database
or something like that and then bringing
the results in to the enumeration
process you know this guy could be the
limit pretty much on what exactly could
you pull in to a mess but it would pull
it in on request just like all these
other data sources they're receiving
these events from the engine saying we
want you know names for this domain name
and then it's listening for the answers
coming back so it would just make it
possible for your script to be one of
those services or that are listening and
able to respond to those requests
all right so what I thought I would use
as an example today is I'm sure you know
many people are familiar with Tom nom
nom and his excellent work that he's
done and his asset finder you know Tom
nom nom spoke yesterday at this
conference and you know I thought I
would use his program as an example of a
program that you could pull into your
mass enumeration so before we just jump
right into it though taking a couple
steps back I mentioned earlier that
scripts can be found within your output
directory so what I'm gonna do here is
we're going to create our own output
directory so we're not messing around
with the default one so I'm going to I'm
going to create it
just call it I know let's call it a test
it could be called anything so that's
just a empty directory but now we're
going to create script so I have a
script that I've written and what I'd
like to do it to save us some time is
I'm going to just open it up and we're
gonna I'm going to go through the
various parts of this script to explain
what are what are the critical portions
of the script what do they mean what
what does the mask to do with them
things like that second here I have a
feeling though yeah we don't want that
I didn't do it to me any good well hold
it what I'll do is I'll rename it
alright so we're going to put this in
- or scripts okay so first thing
actually I'll show you is it the math
scripting engine is uses Lua which is
also you know you're probably familiar
with the fact that that's what nmap uses
there's lots of tools out there that use
Lua so this is a very basic amass data
source script so a couple things to take
note of as you can see in the name right
here it has to be named dot EDS or it
won't be recognized by the amass
scripting engine but it is Lua so what
we have in this script is here we're in
check I'll change this we'll call it a
set finder or I suppose
could easily leave it like that and
actually it should be this type mm-hmm
which stands for external so that it's
just a way to say it came from outside
of I mean unless you unless you know for
sure that your implementation for
instance is using a certain type of data
source like an API or scraping a web
page or you know something like that but
in this case since we're using another
tool that could be doing any number of
things to get the data it'd probably be
easier to say external and you can find
details on well how do you know how do I
know what the types are it's in the
documentation in the the amass repo but
these two values have to be set so if
you create a script and it doesn't find
this global variable in this global
variable it will not load your script so
you could have you know whatever file
name DDS and then when it tries to load
the Lua chunks so first of all it's
that will quickly end the whole process
right there but if it is and it doesn't
find those two global variables to find
it then it will it will not load your
data source so these are these are very
important
then what you're seeing here and here
are two of the possible callbacks that
amass uses to call in to the scripts so
in this case the start you know callback
as you can imagine is the one that gets
called before any of the other callbacks
and gives your scripts an opportunity to
do some initial like setup in this case
it's just setting the rate limit for the
data source which actually we don't even
need necessarily for asset finder so we
could just take this out but if you
wanted if you want a rate limit that's a
proper way to do it would be when when
your data source first starts set the
rate limits because then these other
callbacks will not fire off any faster
than once per that many seconds and
there's there's a ways to within your
say algorithms ask it to check the rate
limit again if you know your invoke you
know you're accessing the data source
more than once and you need to adhere to
the Ray limit and there's a handful of
these a mass custom function calls that
similar to set rate limit that are
defined in the documentation so the
vertical call is the one that gets
called when as we've seen so far
when amass
okay I've got a domain name and I want
sub domain names it calls
vertical so in this case you know we're
all we're gonna do is we're gonna find
asset finder so we're what we're gonna
the way we're going to do that is I'm
going to create another directory under
my output directory and then we'll copy
asset finder into into there so that way
the binary is is in a location that's
easily found by by a mask so this way
its output directory slash bin asset
finder and then you know we're just
going to give it the appropriate
arguments and we will execute it and
gather the output and then just go
through the lines of output and send
them along to amass as new names or
potentially new names and then close it
and then we're done so there's a hand
although of these callbacks so if you're
really interested in doing this you're
you're definitely going to want to take
a look at this so real quick let's just
make sure everyone's aware of so where
can you find this so if we go down
documentation this is the manual
so it covers at least the basics of the
script format like I said the various
types of scripts or data sources there's
some things that are made available into
your lua environment from a mass that
are related to the type of activity that
these scripts are likely to be involved
in including for instance if you're if
you've put API key say information in
the config file we if we go down here
let's say you created a new entry in
here where you know it's it's named the
same thing as this name so I mean FF
finder of course doesn't have an API key
but or at least not I mean maybe it's it
looks like it supports supports using
API keys but anyway let let's just say
we had a way to use it so you'd write it
in here you could say TPI keep API key
and then you know put the
in here and then when you get into your
Lua script you would have this table
already exported into your environment
so you would be able to check if it's
nil and it wouldn't be and then you
would be able to go get API key and it's
going to be equal to whatever value is
over here so these are the kinds of
convenience things that are there's
gonna be more and more of those kinds of
things made available to these scripts
like for instance this isn't available
yet but we're going to put it put it in
the word lists are going to be made
available and other things that are
going to be necessary if you want to
take full advantage of scripting for
masks but moving along you know these
are these
Haldex I was talking about so you've got
start/stop vertical horizontal resolved
for each name that was successfully
resolved by DNS you've got callback
which only gets called when if a what I
call a proper sub domain name where
earlier I mentioned for instance FTP
example.com would have been a proper
subdomain
once we discovered that WWF TP
example.com existed mm-hmm so when that
happens this gets called and it tells
you how many times one of those labels
like www has shown up within the proper
sub domain we've got address for the IP
addresses that have been determined
related to the enumeration request for
ASN information and then these are the
convenience functions that are currently
implemented like logging letting the
engine know that there's activity so
essentially don't stop yet
because there's more going on as we've
already seen obtaining the output
directory checking if a name is in scope
setting the rate limit checking the rate
you know if checking meaning block until
the Ray limit has expired or it's safe
to continue find is a regular expression
pattern-matching function so a sub-match
request is for
it's a HTTP client requests grape is
very similar it's just that it doesn't
actually give you back the response it
just scrapes it for names are being a
names are of interest crawl does
something similar to that but of course
it doesn't just scrape the one response
that continues looking for more pages to
spider and then these are primarily ways
to send back discovered data like new
name associated names are for the
horizontal domain name correlation so
this would be like a another domain name
that's associated with this domain name
new IP addresses new ASN information
those are the things that are currently
available and like I said it's going to
grow as we continue to add features but
let's see what this ends up looking like
so we have our script so if we here's
the peers hello we'll keep this some
as possible so the enum Durer test
source and let's just do passive right
now include asset finder so this should
only fire off our custom script and just
print out the results without further
analysis see if it likes so it looks
like it they loaded it it rent it's
running it and that's what it discovered
and it's printing out so that of course
you know this is a maybe a little bit of
a silly example because of course you
could just run this yourself and but
maybe not mmm right maybe you would like
to take these various tool that you're
using wrap them up like this so that you
only have to actually use one tool like
a mask to drive your reconnaissance
process and you would just know it's
going to pull in the data from all these
different tools and use all of it and
bring all the names into the cyclic
process I mentioned earlier and I guess
you could say take full advantage of all
the data that you can get your hands on
and I don't know about you but I think
this is a pretty small amount of code to
write to be able to pull something like
in and like I said I mean some of it's
just not even necessary like I would
argue for this particular script you
don't really need that you could just
write this so that was a simple script I
put together just to demonstrate how you
could easily take a command line tool
that could find you say more names and
then have it called upon when a mass
wants it and it becomes part of them the
amass enumeration process but in the
future this this could just as easily be
as I mentioned earlier you could be
accessing a private database and it
could be pulling the results from that
it could be anything you want so that
using a mass now could could be
customized it could be it could have
your say secret sauce rolled into it
right things that it's not just doing
what it's doing for everyone else it can
be doing what you needed to do for you
it also could be a nice way if you're
looking to contribute back to easily now
write up new ways of getting names or
getting the structure information and
contributing it back to the a wasp amass
project because you know I would say
writing these small little Lua scripts
is really easy and not very
time-consuming and before you know it
gonna have all the data sources written
up this way about half of them have
already been ported over you know this
is how we'll be accepting contributions
for new data sources all right so that
that went pretty quick I mean I don't
know how firehose everyone feels about
that obviously I don't have time to
teach Lua it so if people you know
there's there's some really good
resources for Lua out there if you go
back to the documentation I was showing
a moment ago the OWASP amass
documentation for the scripting there's
references in there for where to find
freely available documentation and even
books for how to use Lua but honestly
it's mmm it's extremely easy and it's a
it's a it's a powerful language this
kind of work where it's just data
crunching you know it's just get me some
data put it into the format I want it
and send it away so it works really good
for this some of you perhaps are already
familiar with it since so many video
games use Ulua is there's scripting
language it's it's quite popular so
then it looks like this worked out
pretty well I have a little bit of a few
things to conclude but then we could
open the floor for about say 15 minutes
worth of questions that if that sounds
good to you I just wanted to mention a
few
going back to project centric things so
we made a couple changes recently that I
was hoping to share me bring this back
up so if you find you have a a question
about a wasp Emes we definitely want to
help you but I would really prefer that
the project who would prefer that you
you do not take the concerns or the
questions or the mm troubleshooting
requests to the github issues I'd really
prefer that most of these questions
started in the discord server and then
if it's determined that oh this this
isn't just a you know a troubleshooting
well you know let's support or help the
community this is a problem with the
project then then we can take it to the
issues and officially post the problem
so that we remember to take care of it
but what I what I don't want to see
happening is that we get a pile of
people's questions and the issues and it
makes it hard for people to use the
issues for what they're really there for
just to keep track of what we're working
on and the problems we've act you know
the that we've validated our true
problems with the project so that's kind
of
protocol I'm hoping we can achieve is
that everything starts in the discord we
can we can talk we can help people we
can you know take it to the DMS and you
know try to make sure that you're
getting it working or getting the right
experience but we only are posting
things in the issues when it's a real
issue you know it's a serious issue also
if you know that you are writing about a
mass or your ear you have things you
would like to share with the community
you know the amass community are the
people using it please don't hesitate to
come to the you know again either the
discord server or you know to let us
know or just create a PR and you can you
can add it to our Hall of Fame where
we're we're trying to do our best to
keep track of them or sorry not hall of
fame the references we're trying to keep
track of you know the people are taking
the time to share good things with the
community about how to how to use this
you know how they're getting success
with it things like that so you know
we've we've tried to keep track of some
of this stuff people have let us know
but definitely don't hesitate to bring
it to our attention so we can get you in
the list because I really appreciate
everything everyone's doing and the time
people are taking to to write about
these experiences that they're having
and
the last thing on on this note was if
you if you would like to become a
contributor so you feel that you know
you like go as much as we do and maybe
like you know now you could add a little
bit to the list but if these seem like
fun things for you and you'd like to
contribute to this project you know
we're always interested in talking with
people about people becoming
contributors so yeah I get the feeling
when I've spoken with people about this
that there's this attitude like maybe
they're not good enough that this to
contribute or they don't you know they
don't feel they know enough about it yet
but personally I don't look at things
that way I'd prefer to think if you have
the if you're excited about it or you
have the motivation you know we can help
you to say season your skill you know
get your skills where they need to be or
or that you'll just pick it up as you
put your hands on it so you know I'm
willing to invest the cycles for people
who are willing to do the same for the
project so don't hesitate to come and
and speak with us about becoming a
contributor if that's of interest to you
alright so with that I think we're at a
good point here this leaves us with well
then maybe about 15 minutes to answer
questions yeah sounds good so again
thinking if we're doing this with us
Jeff chat if you have any questions make
sure you drop them and twitch out right
now and maybe we can get to a few
questions before we head out and take a
quick break for our next workshop with
Jason Haddix
yeah Ben I'm not watching the questions
coming in so if you could maybe do me
the favor of picking out the ones you
think are should be answered yeah just
let me know somebody's asking they said
what is the difference between a mass a
new active and only a mass a new mesh D
yeah no that's a good question yes so I
guess you could say there's there's like
three different modes that a mass
supports right there's passive there was
just normal which is when you just say -
D or you don't specify the mode and then
there's active so you know I already
mentioned earlier passive is simply
grabbing it from the data sources and
you know creating the unique list and
printing it out normal is when we're
we're taking the data sources mm-hmm
we're getting the names and we are
resolving those names and getting the IP
addresses so that's where it becomes not
completely passive anymore mm-hmm and
we're doing you know we're finding out
all the other infrastructure information
but we're not sending any traffic
directly to the target organization
right so let's say we received a name
and we got an IP address and we wanted
to do something more like ask their web
server directly for TLS certificates
that's something that the active mode
will do the normal mode won't mmm the
act
mode is also a bit more aggressive with
the reverse DNS then it is in the normal
mode also
active mode will attempt the DNS zone
transfers but it will not do that in the
normal mode very cool
you mentioned the DNS sub command was
kind of in beta testing what are the
future plans for that future exactly
yeah so that the sub command I think
they're referring to is the the DNS of
command so I the future I think it has
mmm it would be a way that you could say
so I just have a list of names and I
want to resolve them similar to perhaps
what you would do is like mass DNS or
something like that but the point of
doing it with a mass would be so that
the findings can be put into the
database so it's it's not really you
know I'm not trying to replace existing
tools like mass DNS we were thinking of
rolling it in for the purpose of if you
have that list in you and you want to
make sure that all those findings are
being brought into your database then we
are providing a way to do that the
secure B asks the question about what
does it benefit to limit the amount of
resolvers is that the shorter runtime
anything else besides that maybe that's
a good
question so a couple things that
the current situation when it comes to
obtaining the list of resolvers in my
experience the larger the list you give
it the more you're inviting malicious
resolvers or not you know unreliable
resolvers to get into the list so I you
know I I always ask myself the question
how many do we need but you know we
don't need to be going higher than that
because I end up the larger the list
more I seem to end up fighting with it
until it gets to be a good list maybe
that's something that you know if if we
could work further on validating the DNS
resolvers you know we wouldn't have to
worry about things like that
the other reason though is you are also
bringing in as I mentioned earlier more
resolvers of varying performance so
while a mask does try to notice which
resolvers are performing better and then
use them more so that it's pushing the
names through as fast as I can it's not
perfect and if you bring in a lot of
poor performing resolvers you are going
to slow down your process a bit the
other thing of course
there's only so many of those you can
fire up in a single process before it
just kind of gets to be too much like
you can't have all 9,000 of them running
at the same time not likely I'd have to
double-check what the exact limit is but
every resolver you instantiate with in a
mask creates two file handles so while
that's not that bad it could be worse
mmm there is a limit to how many you can
create in a single process at least in
some os's you know I suppose for
instance I think on Kali look there is
no limit hmm so maybe it wouldn't matter
but it's also just more work you know
more resolvers equals more messages that
have to be passed around I would say
there's really no reason to have more
than say like 500 of them yeah Jason
see if there is any options coming to
distribute a mass over a cluster to
avoid rate limiting and other badness
yeah so I've been speaking with some
people in the community about so there's
already been some effort put into the
amass project to make it so that in the
future we could easily have what you
might think of as like a mass agents so
that only a slice of your enumeration
process would exist within each agent
and they would work in a distributed
fashion and the fact that we're already
using messaging like event based
messaging within the architecture makes
it so that lets say you were to you know
put this into the cloud it would be
quite easy to then send the messages you
know in within the cloud to the various
like micro services or places where
these agents are being run so we've
definitely thought of these things it's
not ready to do this yet
but I'd like to think that that could be
part of the future of this project is
that eventually you could deploy this
you know across more than just a single
hosted environment or a single machine
and you know by running it that way it'd
also be easy to rotate ip's things like
that so that it would be pretty hard for
people to start throttling your activity
I don't know if that's where he was
going with it but those are the kinds of
things we've been thinking of yeah and
then there's also a question about the
scripting engine is it going to be an
option to use other languages or does it
have to be the same way that you have
demonstrated yeah right now that's a
embedded Lua environment so similar to
how an map does it so it doesn't allow
for me to say let's interpret a
different language
and I don't know if I'd want I mean I
haven't really haven't given it much
thought but I'm not sure how I feel
about claiming will support all sorts of
different languages
hmm I like the simplicity of Lua how
just about anybody could probably pick
it up and it it's easy to look at easier
to read I think so but of course who
knows I'm open to anything people want
to talk about as far as possibilities I
like the way nmap does it so I was and
I've used loo embedded loo environments
in previous projects in previous lives
and it's worked out really well for me
so I'm kind of biased I guess you could
say it's doing it this way let's see I
think we have time for a few more
questions how to make sure resolvers
giving good results with time if they
start to act bad do we have any way to
detect them using no mass and exclude
them in the next run interesting so
currently a mask does have some code in
there that as I mentioned it watches the
performance and it does try to fun it
tries to notice if some of them are just
not answering the queries anymore and
eventually just not using them any
longer but it doesn't record that as the
person asked the question said in order
to say make a bad list or something like
that so while it's not impossible it's
not currently being performed also a
mass used to have the ability it was
removed at least temporarily mm to do
this kind of like voting system where it
would ask it would query the same query
to three different resolvers and then
pick the answer with that two out of the
three provided and mark the one who gave
the false answer you know as less
reliable or something like that
hmm there were different reasons why it
was taken out at least for now but if
assuming it was be you know
reimplemented safely it could be useful
to further catch these unreliable
resolvers even the ones that slipped
through DNS validator so there's
possibilities of room for improvement in
this area especially if again we maybe
had people that wanted to dig into it
learn more about it and implement it
really well for us
yeah no worries
there's one last question I think you
already mentioned this but for people
that have more questions want to
contribute where can they contribute to
the project or how can they contribute
to the project and if they have any more
questions where can they ask their
questions yeah so if you go to the repo
readme you know that the chat link is
right there and it'll bring you to the
discord server that's where all the
questions are being thrown around the
debates potential debates about why is
it being done this way can we do it
better and it's it's really the place
where if you want to get the
conversation started you want to you
want to get the debate going and
definitely come there and usually these
discussions end up ending with someone
saying yeah that sounds like a great
idea or that's probably what we should
do
can you write up the feature request or
do you want to write as a contribute
that
yourself and raise the PR and things
like that so definitely the discord
server well it sounds good
again if you have any more questions as
you heard head over to D on my discord
server before we like Jeff go please
give him a big THANK YOU in the chat it
was an honor to have you on here Jeff I
appreciate all their work and I look
forward to seeing where our mass goes in
a year from now yeah thank you this was
a great opportunity to you know reach
out a little more to the community help
the community in the process and yeah
please don't hesitate anyone to come
visit us at the discord server Thank You
Ven awesome thank you so much Jeff
you