so I decided to who is in itself and
pixel
more so what what I did
earlier with proper to funding on the
this has cost that I used here
so that the same with I A and now I want
to look where the
are used spiffy lexus re this obviously
interesting because the flexors
open right so
the scoffers would cause re
will call read
that's pretty early
okay so
what's happening
this is obviously a group so this will
we
from
can reading
one sir
became willfully exits year
nothing threat or euro
basra so month the rules doing that for
writing nixon
them
sis reading no calling
health the
okay don't know analyst
see the other one but see exited with
the third with first
open
this is
this was month call
phone
them
all and health
that okay so
call this probably exited X
also called
well jumping from years so
interesting
well the
he
overhears characters that have come
maybe I should
trainees allard so
ditsy its mmm
percent
have
now I see okay are I suspect that that
a.m. okay so 3
time three times for what is called has
a special name
this this
this kind of order Russian
only birth in the car like that
but it hasn't name
no russian pop Russian on the
Russian cock eliciting me
mmm whether operand is
this last month call poll
a polish notation whether our bus
Russian Polish so sorry
answer I offended anybody oh no its
prefix notation okay that this obviously
not what is happening
for the prefix for its
the other one weather
reverse polish notation pro
then yell okay awesome where
her this before sounds familiar I think
you're
writer somebody barth hanoi
came across as few weeks ago to
okay so a that's great so
for example 25 model cantana
its 20
divide it by for working
okay cool well
net is at least know I know a little bit
what's happening
so this is 17 paid he want to see you
known he de-
that's what it's called
kids Harper yeah
you
email
well
I okay so these are the characters
so for the at SeaWorld
the what's the cost
awesome for them so that's would be to a
I'm then
me follow this feel like thats assume
it's really like comparing them
that would be then %um
you
you the the
the
window change what the hell
when I
doing minerals system and
you would interest no the
that the
which
so I'm out of ideas again
includes know it's rumors
polish notation calculator but it don't
know
thank so disturbed thing
some harsh today analyzed this
as a what's up with the specs which case
I don't know how triggers song
year me
that's to the
eroded not get recognized the aero kit
I have a reference from here no
awesome but let's see where
personal reference to quit reference it
really sucks
in
mine
it I'm out of ideas 10
him