okay let's
let's try this so mmm I am see
it's working like dead T the and
I think the string here I think the
first character
weyrich for example could be 0
because it's always the same right
so just just take the
with Ecuadorian make the expected
the first one already set okay so and
then
I'm going from from the second one
hi take the you well I
and take the current value
and mmm
I'm gonna do this properly
what'd
current value and subtract from
head I am all previous all previous
values so
network the
and
with that make a
million star the
of a bit of first
or food
okay just
wondering about something sorry atticus
string to pick the first
that on not know no well yeah
okay that way thinking happy element
that am
so i sux track the
some of
all previous one so some
from -2 some from me and then
hi
I hand the
previous value to
a in
this so
see if it to dick to
to
be at them mind
key predict who
from a is a
great the the
that is not correct so
the friend
the current character number
number of the current her for the
a and the
some day
20 the
then
away no sure I else wrong
obviously I wanna go to this one the and
the
but I'm predicting one day this one
expect
inner self is BBB great if this is long
make this still works
age also work obviously
in yeah
in at some point to big but
yeah
II will do it