K pic am so this
buffer there's also a buffer great okay
so now I can copy
this should be able to
right
the the the stuff that I want to move
into
the registers here so that's testers
them on earth
mmm name
on a break coda run
wait
damn break it called again
its run yes dresses
feeling well
minutes me 10 these cc
K
or register them it
no
wise
this
okay in a way it's right now
parent that should work I don't know
why it's well sick by Sarah
well
thats copy this code to well on the
front
platform the of that might be different
and I'm
Richard work you know with that she can
run it
yes and like that but Sarah
weird mmm
well thats also put at the end
see 3 which is return
and its comparison
open this
me Creek in G opportunity for that
everything is the right
so here's code
that looks right
nope not and here's a return it should
nicely return
and she is the book for this reference
nicely
okay
why indicating ambassador I need to re
sick for us
okay let's look at this and GB again
very weird
break in Maine okay
so break point here that's fine
so now we about to call
Rd X is pointing
to oh I think I know what the problem it
it might be in not not excusable yeah
that's probably the run I am GV
a Niksic q2 both then
she's p.m.
no lists
their protect mister
x6 dick you think that's what I mean
dement DeMint's
sheezy on
in it
see same with of am you know
the
key it's in the middle of battle and
that's fine I mean I can
can make can make this
a little bit longer
okay not pointing to bob franken great
arm
so I'll
the AM she's the XD day
can news
no
no no warning
okay so I a posture and in traffic