reduction thank you for taking the
copper climbed but part of the
application could get through the work
we do it in a very very important and it
all on the same there are no application
tomorrow after my meeting know a lot
about the face and then I think I know
you know it's life I think my show me
how much I know I don't know or lowered
be described by so I really depend on
the inquest in the feedback and the
contributions about it to keep myself
level 2 923 which is why I already have
given me a lot but he's a pretty had a
lot more maybe maybe maybe he see people
I think it probably would have wanted an
important part in all about people so i
don't realize what you were directly
oversaw next week back
94 I was kind of happy young man and
find the need for kind of figured it out
there
everything that I learned there look for
parody of these very large problem and I
think my safety probably all of it by
far the most important and you know I
met you yet to secure software like
crazy good results found that there is
and there's no bus there are no books on
the subject there are no lights bigger
things here and there were rumors that
day but the acting was that we can be
anything you want to get in for nearly
two decades now it's not quite so and
it's not but it's not so remember
reading mostly because people they get
the issue and that we deal with the
problems that way there's go to get or
do their work on that yet we must do
security lifecycle that implies it
started as a weirdo software written and
directed at security code going to buy
the crime of this terrible weather is
already one billion websites on an old
number occupation and so a lot of the
risk that we've seen repeated come from
the legacy issue so we find ourselves in
general for your world and what I find
it a lot of people out here and you're
something like that he had read the
briefs or briefs right thing that I do
can you just like any of our ability to
reach where the vulnerability is not
understood the collapse of it or not we
could not find this long ago did we do
not assume liability exceed a single one
we don't know how
working in different ways but you're
right I thought I was the only one left
and yours but why did he could be known
problem I think that make up your mind
it's not a knowledge eg Roberts
illusions lack of standard water bottle
we have laughed it off work at it we
know how to cure generally see what we
are doing it right here
going to challenge conventional thinking
better probably from the industry and
the vendors are not going to like it I
do not care what other people about
their microphone for the record my
little bit about life and it's not you
know like that before you sent the
company how long we've been around
things like that I guess in normal our
job is to find the volatility and the
bad guy who eventually what and the
whole idea of 47 or if you prefer if you
increase the guy who experience already
in the system if we do our job here are
two great idea what the presentation and
by began going to show your home today
are so popular but more on that we know
who's available and how often and 2006
were sharing the broad trend in the
industry actually see it how many people
in Jackson how long
Daily Show to figure out that it's a
required flying friend and he wanted it
and they contacted them over now what
did I do like it needed to be done but
got broken up into third on whether it's
like a walkie clause Robert into the
article does not compute limited to be
looking at these are my understanding
right actors understand if their
candidate for Singapore pool so I the
bag lady do they have to find you would
have put heber go into the city or do we
see them more skin tissue and broader
market well I think you guys are mostly
standing because the weather is very
little bit longer in their Articles
remaining looking at what they're going
to action everywhere
whenever our guide says you know
products will be profitable whatever
they have to be a two-out seal the bag I
get out there and what they're up there
I also one of the intersection of
insider insurance on a really hard on
the votes to intersection of security
blanket inside her strengths because I
will in fact it won't be today and
tomorrow and next week I hear what our
industry does we're going to have new
masters and like it or not I'll get into
that would be easier burden upon going
to be Asian are 2384 they want a flight
at a park we have developed ease we have
no problems and hundreds of other people
and we bury development
what we're not currently has succeeded
in the grand scheme of things what good
is it if we're going to millions of
homes and 6-1 and so right now what
would that do they pick so I mean do the
tracheotomy general features that the
business off the money order they take
too long ago put it in a box and really
know what they choose not to reduce the
burden of one billion mediate you do
that you are equal measure of security
and out of this is what I kind of
figured it out for that I'll be dead he
does have a lot of it on this is we have
become better track the QA thought that
goes out for training can go now to try
and be more direct but I never happen
we can list all the time but where is
the day that if we do these things
the metric to me if we do these things
and do the board believe all the time to
fix it shouldn't happen when they do
things we don't think so but our
industry had 20 data backup the stuff
that we go to the vet tomorrow we should
do better than that the other day that
sounds like a good idea
ok I finally got underway get out there
and we don't have to you know we have
seen it work at 11 we don't really so
what we did was allow that in a little
bit more like how vulnerable they did
but I didn't know we didn't know what
you're doing it so we can regress and
how it impacted the out what we can to
try that if they do this outcome I think
we're much better than the applications
that he showed his company here that's
not hire out that everybody would like
people so we gotta bring more and more
people into the state of the economy
right model in source code reviews
dynamic at the you know that we are
never ever catch we're never going to
eliminate many of us that all humans
were going to be an expert no matter
what we do something tomorrow but we're
going to need more people coming in
builder greater gender what had
read it we're really doing baby so very
very productive right after I think
mostly mostly got to be the same using
the same I figured I do too broad
popular right actors wherever we have a
half of us anonymous things like that I
classify them more than they have to get
a political message out there I don't
pay too much attention because they're
going to make their presence known not
possible I would say so I can see myself
more with the organized crime ties
ninety percent of the time in a little
bit as you say just of my device the
organized crime they're much more
sinister you're not doing anything to do
with featured at this exciting to be at
the ceiling your money and there are a
lot of money they do that building so
for your sake I know and everybody
together in major cities often
capability for japan's economic
advantage of all over the place again
really think we might see some activity
thought they were trying to instill a
popular computer so that my humble
myself with a needle now I'm gonna get
the data like your BBQ but first I
thought it was a little small but that
we want to know what areas are most
affected by what does this come from the
right
writing data breach investigations
report in my opinion it is the same as
well as part of the only required
reading in our car industry if you have
any
prepared for it all to you what's going
on in the right place on the web
application by air and on the vertical
you have all the way everybody that I
can get information
45 percent of their brief me to do it
financial services 31%
most beautiful web security number one
or number you get the manga it works we
got through that and then we could be
putting our resources where they're the
most impact
repair only five percent don't know what
that means maybe people that are going
to the point of sale 2013 how the back
of breaking into into the system but the
guy who won their heat here again this
time from the ground it right and a
brief report this is the last year to
poor they're working on the latest album
out this year organized crime became the
most frequently see reactor or web
application now you can see me but what
does your credit card back to do it
without the feature but people going on
here talking about this
they seek yeah you know some other
unrelated system breakdown of your
credit card number or password and use
those Catholics to go out to the artist
releases a very tasty sequin jacket at
number three what happens when I get to
market a secondary plan you will hold
you in certain on for this is the method
could be a hit they want and extracted
and it's really just a couple so we
think a lot of times we should walking
down the front door but it's not pretty
enough
and you know anything about the video
that most companies out there have no
idea what website owner Mark problem
that is unsolved in the industry no one
knows how can you possibly like a
beautiful evening profitably showed that
63 percent of the web and you know a lot
of people out with a small profit $50
for people with a number of recent he'll
be back at you seem to be using and in
addition of energy department that are
out there maybe your songs this week
maybe somebody gonna play some of those
that don't know how people to do so but
the assessment there is that if I could
probably I don't have her back because
of what happened in the case of arriving
departing now that we have that they
don't have to go into the reported
seeing how was a primary or a third
party suppliers they probably help you
not appalled
what we gonna do now and higher keeping
or whatever that require other riddled
with balls and they may or may not get
the bad guys are doing the web
application now let's look at the
numbers you know capital that's right I
want to know how much you want to know
what they find it boring but that is
where they swear they sent so you're
back all this idea how their five
billion dollars on every single year you
now have full access to me by here and
it's going to lead him into this market
five billion per year and the industry
breakdowns on what industry you know
whatever the case may be important now
that the broad members there had been a
report I don't like this is how many
vulnerabilities and what types of planes
this is different from what I've
actually I can tell you what I can tell
you what the back to you tonight what we
need to do it all I give you a possible
motive you act like that so it's like
you're in a likelihood popular way to
realize that what happened but at least
11 people in one body looking at profit
which is one of the most popular guy not
a number of numbers by the eighties and
nineties right now
profit for being in our customer base is
about 45
have one more likely a lot more about
the way to stop this chart because the
top of the bag I wonder what are you
going to market open to whatever what
are the odds that I didn't think that
far and it is now following code to find
a vulnerability describe what it is and
go please tick this hired a name for
those issues we want to start measuring
60 feet hurt them a window of
opportunity for the bad guy so when we
find more abilities born believe this
website is this that you're those
affected more measured adult in between
this is the actor David Boreanaz
industry again delivery this is what
they think the work of the worse the
retail industry when we find face high
critical or the one you really should
average time to fix these two hundred
and twenty seven days a medical report
what the transportation middle of the
road that say they plan to ensure a ban
on adverse 1868
six months while we consider cost of
remediation numbers while the armed
robbery they are we to do better and
this is in the room
we don't buy that way we don't like we
don't write nothin
industry operates drops it all here for
you guys
one-in-three chance that you're gonna do
when it comes to work again let's say
you're gonna happen when the Board of
Directors when the when they win the
popular said Board of Directors help
with that added number when the security
department was that could be a good one
you could order to record properly
accountable here for another we don't
want that when the security people make
you a much better job all right so it's
hard to read and put it on the border of
record with a countable
to fix the department had 14 days but it
didn't seem to a record one of the dryer
prior year 2013 in fact one of the main
drivers with plant number one driver was
quiet now
35% the 130 work with that story when
the media writer by a large number
probably really going out with a plan to
the only fighter bombers and remediation
that these policies will only be one
more slide here and say when you start
learning these when it really matters
here and we can't let me know if you
want your number of hope and belief in
Peru even drop the average number of
older why not
mediation
AdvoCare everything will be in the
environment for mediation but not this
will lessen that we've been working
there are no that there are more when
you better come with one another bowl
mix of mediation backed out not sure yet
where we're making believe through all
my might
no one can drive it down but they would
pick $500 abilities when the right very
good because it today because he had
always there like that what's going on
in the eighth at home they're probably
wait and they know they have so many
smaller or maybe you a few framework
issue or something like that might be
one of the issues in the case workers
here now back on any given that this
might be a party issue where the
volatility is a lot more going on here
to earth and then pick the most likely
to go back to the web
everyone everyone will be on that
everyone got over two million people
shop here we got here every part of her
life at all
those shares local times is that they
also see those questions what they did
is they hate you have somebody security
firewall testing its primary those
executives and saying I hope we going to
have controls yes the questionnaire will
be submitted yes the previous will be
paid but I think there is a benefit that
they see all those questions that not
only the security changes
there
goals