talk to people they connected cars what
could possibly go wrong
secular the presentation from many folks
are not aware of all be called the BB or
bugle vehicle program before you get
started just a quick housekeeping things
if you could please turn itself off the
fire you're gonna be affecting open
defined by the balls are allowed back to
the police and the diversity of
questions just read this is by no means
a scripted presentation this is as much
a community education presentation more
than anything else about the vehicle to
be able program and making presentations
and 2015 or similar property be six or
seven provinces usually better tell me
some explaining what the vehicle to
vehicle program is people started asking
questions about that will create an open
source of all i'm happy for those 5 p.m.
and will be followed here everybody will
you drive in a car right right ok so
this presentation will provide
and then later in the program i'll be
talking about Fort Lee will also have
everyone in the room now it's not really
connected parts connected to the
Internet that are actually part of the
internet just like everything else
connected to it and I actually heard
back in a couple of Toyota engineers
when they were talking at me and he said
he looked around callers are part of
that they already is not here I love the
subtle difference but I have completely
if you accept the assumption that
would've known as the Internet of Things
a physical object that can be connected
to the Internet essentially happened I
was part of the effort from cell phones
to washing machine to our automobiles
that we have one of our engineers very
recently bought the refrigerator her and
he notice that one day his network
traffic was light and everything was
very very slow and he being a security
point that it is refrigerator because
refrigerator a little LCD cable walk-up
interview with everything ok it was an
IP addresses fortunately only being used
as a mail server
bad enough to make it for them I mean
that's what the internet things is
certainly vulnerable everyone here knows
that both their folks about it baby
monitors you can tap in
take over the video training to concede
that what's what's being monitored the
Stuxnet attack on your back and in fact
18 months ago I told you that hackers
heat uniform watching a crowded movie
but that happen what enables the
internet now that are related directly
to the Internet software and the magic
of software because even the hardware
drivers talking with the hopes of Asian
business morning about the new castles
and one of the engineers who have just
recently Castro Castro 85 D and he was
very excited because they hadn't yet
have the power to limit is five miles an
hour with software they had passed the
popular software to limit our our world
here to put will that dream wire coated
it you own it
rapper 1.7 million line the software in
it and you got to go over 1500
today over a hundred computing
five networks miles seized in my head
about operating systems in approximately
50% car adapter
possible
introduced in 2002 the power of the
Internet
also join with me in turn it around the
only reason we put the wheels on the
cars these days is to stop the computer
working on the ground at the party and
if applicable to the $350,000 imagine
how many possibilities riding around on
a bit what a wonderful ability for about
a month ago to the way that they would
be connected powerful mobile back for
what has become however there are some
differences plastic network computer
typically turn it over 23 years we've
all seen our our company that every two
years you get a new computer at least in
part over 10 years what about all the
other thing that outside the automotive
industry almost assault problem with
respect to security authentication not
automotive struggle with this fact the
latest version of the software is going
to all of you for your caller to your
home wi-fi
at work yet thought you would reduce all
the best of our abilities in your home
network and Tarmoh you can be harder a
lot more this year than 45 million
power on the roadway in another five
years were $150
external threats threats have a vehicle
and all of these
you might think well how reasonable is
it really a higher that the most side
where you can within 3 p.m. are you
actually get access to that particular
monitor is right now
lot of over $100 level quote in modern
days and I'm also a research fellow at
the pony and recently conducted a survey
in the automotive industry the software
engineers in the almost manufacturers of
questions about you know my software
company takes priority
yes but one piece I found most
interesting question how difficult is on
those occasions and 69 percent of the
respondents difficult or very difficult
these folks that are writing software
companies these are not security control
these these are the folks are writing
software more than two-thirds of them
being difficult or very difficult to
figure out of course present how many of
us feel very familiar with the recent
past
trying to call this is the 2014 edition
little later different almost finish
right now it's literally a book that's
freely available on the internet you can
download by the only good guy but I
really wanna hurt the religious reason
he wants to know where this all really
helpful there is more like a star on
certain amazing story actually beyond
our system
general motors fire was founded in 2005
allows remote control of everything
except the ceiling in the braking system
in the
your motor homes are you don't it's
alright it's alright all the volatility
37 2005 when do you think
2006 2014 guy and you're definitely
actually they have been fixed
laughs and says may twenty years later
between those vulnerabilities in the
vulnerabilities that were found that the
crisis is all possible to slaughter the
security researchers found to be
all-star vulnerabilities caused it to
all star but did not go public with it
general motors actually acted
responsibly and I know you think it will
take years to pay phone bill possible
they actually acted responsibly dubbing
straightaway the reason to fix all the
problems is because the system so
antiquated
they have to do a whole lot of
architecture and fix them just like any
other system actually did take them ten
years to resolve all abilities but again
there are being proactive about it there
and was a force as well as Jeep Chrysler
but it just goes to show a range of
security vulnerability and responses
that are available and again just
building that works here
35 device unlocked almost anything
really
lot of a lot of talk about the eponymous
driving cars this is actually a security
vulnerability was found by researchers
at my company security innovation with
about $40 off-the-shelf equipment and
laser pointers and things like that the
reason they essentially take the car
because we're prob gonna kill those
officers around the park nothing around
leader images now but practically be
there in this country in nearly four
million injuries from automobile
still the number one leading cause of
death for people
85234 get high school but part of the
reason that all of these associations
like Mothers Against Drunk Driving Do
you get from try to form is because
cystic because twenty-five thirty years
ago led the country was today so what
does the government want to do about it
but i wanna put more thought he did a
great idea but I know this is horrible
the folks there certainly think I got my
car let me know what the objective here
is that matter
get practice is the reason the entire
program we're talking about coming up on
the program evolution of automobile
safely back in the nineteen fifties were
driving around while no seat belts
laughed wasn't shatterproof
are pretty unsafe volved in like seat
belts and Natalie devolves into the path
of restraint this is taking it to the
next level to try to move it from after
two prior short video here to talk to
explain that to do so here it is a
database that can be detected but
centers are you going to do with the ECB
we now have the technology to avoid
these using it for 80 percent of
impaired driver
making it and being most important
traffic and the police
than it is today can be tracked the
technology for high level of production
now before I get too much further
details of what I do not work for the
government department transportation my
family security has been involved in
this program
2007 role is to help the fire security
and privacy components of the system to
make sure that it's not only anti tamper
but protects the property of drivers and
also claimed that will be more later
just be you know how does this setting
up your total order book this program
that is why we've been involved were not
nine years but let me explain what it is
he may have gotten to be here this is a
mandatory program mandated by the
unabomber reputation as a factor in this
country is going to carry hardware and
software broadcasters the location of
the meeting at Allmusic manufacturing
automobiles care equipment that
broadcasters and location
why are they doing
wife based on a wire protocol including
11 P
this going to be your party gonna be
broadcasting your location and about 300
meters radius doing that all the readers
doing that is so you can have a great
reputation system to avoid the
high-speed pollution and again backlight
metric is really the driving factor here
Department transportation estimates with
26% of non he paired my feet practice I
don't know where they got six percent
they do some study back the
transportation moral transportation
secretary boss all this most important
thing about a pretty big statement for a
politician and I don't because a
politician I think he's actually pointed
it also happens to be the world's
largest city management this is ever
going to see which are going to be a
jacket here is to notify drivers General
Jack Jack was recently
driving very fast car now begun when I
don't care what they can drive or both
possible he's driving the middle of
downtown Los Angeles going through the
Japanese test law is going to 35 miles
an hour in the photo below through the
red light and smashed in the forecast
in a Ford Focus this system will notify
both drivers but there is a danger of
ending crash on the automobile
manufacturer
goes far to prevent this freaking out
what did you can stop the car to be
drilling program is of course which is
why security problems begin when I think
he to be asked because it's not just
people would be appalled as also be able
to infrastructure right now for example
with started a program in committing
five of the main avenues
all the stoplights interchanges be
equipped with your car
powerful constructor politely doing that
is to increase the federation but also
to measure anything like that little bit
more like everyone will be able to
finish it off the assembly line with us
as you're driving along as you could be
used all the time as those numbers are
difficult start to get depleted it a
little bit easier to use the system of
them so you get off how it's going to
cost them off you go to you you know
you'll get your own certificates are not
known to do that they were building into
the infrastructure
folks can get pop up automatically the
Catholic Ford Focus county of down and
less than 30% certificate repopulating
also wrote that be there shortly after
market devices though just got home
where technology network a few Ford
Focus might not because it was built for
them and they can't even buy aftermarket
device is more focus with the CD
technology but you have to offer
do you have the ability to do not
location from the tachometer
that's always a concern raised had one
of these aftermarket devices love you
Phillip put it in a fall asleep in the
car was gonna create habitat is also
concerned about what are known as the
are vulnerable road users government has
borrowed that users are things like
bicyclist motorcycle you definitely want
to protect those thoughts as well
because they're part of that leading the
market devices that are read only
broadcast system because a mobile device
can be anywhere but they can also
privacy concerns will be in SA be able
to spy on us even more because the
patient cannot be issued automatic
speeding tickets again
jackie jackie is driving 75 miles an
hour they write the answer is No
these messages are being broadcast but
they're not even be why do you think the
message
of information if nothing else if things
are going about to collide with this car
park settings because there are certain
vehicles that you want to be identified
things like police cars fire trucks
ambulances and painted problems but also
know if you need to have JavaScript law
he likes to play Metallica maximum
volume can hear the thunder but we can
get notified him to come about and you
know people that are trying to you at
all times are just malfunctioning we
have to be able to identify and remove
that the repudiation an early gotta
leave the boat so freaked out about
their privacy and public information
the fact is there are may all the way
there or happen to you and your
sensitive information
the program is part of the reason I
thought about beginning about how
vulnerable the system yes it's
introducing new stopper into your cart
it is not necessarily make me any less
secure network that is making more safe
for sure we talk about the pilot project
has been going on in Ann Arbor starting
in 2012 and just last year we did a 6000
our study of course is a greater in our
area up to $8,000 like it a lot of great
information
the program is a standard no I Tripoli
standard 1609 you're looking up the
security and privacy pieces are I could
only see this year IRA mention that
pilot New York City 2016 basically going
to be 2017 2018 20,000 be a pilot
project in New York City first far as to
roll off the assembly line with what
they are going to be the general motors
català anyone there was one of the
better games you got it would be great
but at that point will only be able to
look at the forecast job they're not
part of this is the reason that General
Motors Cadillac because of the higher on
this list will add approximately $200 to
$250 to our little drunk driving another
$200 no big deal for focus for Casio in
a bit of a budget
the automobile manufacturers are rolling
out the higher parts for us
prices drop down below rhetoric however
the government has already been at their
interpretation of a day late last year
and the date by which will be a major
factor
be complying
be compliant by 2015 and 2019 taking one
hundred percent by 2020 to secure the
way between now and 2020 to the next six
years the automobile manufacturers are
going to start the program slowly mostly
high and there's also a lot of
government interest in the rest of the
software running on your part
this is senator mark he received conf
cheeses and it really took up the charge
here and you can see the study call
tracking and security gap year old
driver should not have to choose between
being connected and protected so he
believed in five acts not the best names
in my opinion but for the security and
privacy in your car I don't know why
they come up with any but Bethany the
Act going through right now will become
a lot of your future one of the things
that I find it interesting this is last
bullet your desired dashboard features
of it tells you that my four hour how
much you're consuming that they're
recommending for cybersecurity that's
also has to have some type of
attestation security due diligence the
automobile
factor in put on the supply and as you
know you don't supply a very broad
always down to you
chipset manufacturers like ZTE
blackberries in office through
graders Panasonic AC a larger system
integrators like Delhi Daredevils and
all the way from automotive
manufacturers themselves before the
General Motors the crisis in 2014
for the first time that I would more
software engineers hardware engineers I
was a tipping point before another
tipping point that we had in 2015 is
there were more than the planet but
nonetheless I recently watched Marvel's
Avengers
that pretty good about more connected
than what the order the government is
taking out the public key infrastructure
against your vacation and he's gonna be
challenged you didn't just football and
communicated its massive absolutely
massive and the witnesses his family
right now so you can call if you choose
to accelerator you can choose to filter
messages back the only likely to call it
a lot more efficient celery you have the
choice program so many as you have to
have the equipment installed happened to
notify the driver of the automobile take
it further
this is why earlier yeah designed so can
stop the car there are so many factors
that we always felt that are planning to
integrate this late
the braking system and author of that
automatic vehicle stopped just in a
meeting the minimum required to drive it
at the case there are also some
cross-border issues you're the USA and
EU programmes are hardworking practical
the standards are nearly the same but
not quite surprised in the day another
major continuous use it in the USA
transportation to government mandate in
the EU off any program led by the
automobile manufacturers themselves very
you're being opposed to systems need to
work together because Joe Jonas BMW so
he goes to Munich by the BMW driver few
weeks in the ship it back to the USA
that BMW better work USB devices that
organization that were talking about it
and it will then reason for optimism
got we've got plenty of interesting
examples know then particularly like
threatening but be aware that much much
for even a year ago two years ago and
that's a good thing there are parallels
that we can draw on a party to the
actual and the car dealers are finally
being so we can keep calm and we can
drive but I want to falsify anything
connected park to the b2b system some
details about this what about security
on ya
question for those of you who put in
here as well the insurance companies we
tracking all these speeds the answer for
this program to be programmers know they
can always do that for us off into one
of the programs we take double or triple
A so the reason that they can't with
this program is because there is no
central body of information there's no
there's no local story from Asian black
box in your car for example where ya
just refuse to Castillo they can do for
ethics and look into the program to see
how fast he was going about that
information is not a lawyer for ya
again with a killer was my fault
insurance companies offer any to their
dog program they could use that won't
worry about not raised according to this
year they were going to get there
the arm using GPS primarily the arm
using a higher definition version of GPS
quite accurate as you might imagine
because you're talking about high-seas
talking about three dimensions jeff is
going over briefing kathy is going to
get no problem there if they if they
refining the empathy but there's
actually a lot
poverty right now there is no
certificate or party in the program
overall the pilot programs whether it's
an arbitrary York City others there has
been one of those of their have not yet
to find a nationwide authority for this
program will likely be the government I
think actually probably one of the
for-profit organization to get a
contract provision and all the work that
the program has been done by third
parties of the contract with the
government so although it will pay for
the double major from a theater
but they did
paraphrasing do you think that because
the new airliners and fighter jets at
significantly lower number of software
lines in their systems compared to save
up with these is that because they are
writing very efficient software because
they are being questioned later be
automobile the 787 Dreamliner had the
luxury of rewriting from the ground so
efficiently they were able to start from
scratch essentially similar to what they
had to do it and they do have some
pretty darn good engineer in the
automobile world with respect the
software though the automobile fragment
is that the folks at Villa braking
systems that we don't have a lot of
interacting with the folks of building a
consistent intractable to build each
system as rape you move from mechanical
hydraulic manage the late notice
software I think happened with an
independent this moment fuel injector
and that is part of the problem for the
second part of the question again was
other so they can use their own set
their own engineering because they hit
the Standard Bank really will be part of
the medical transportation safety
standard standard by which all defective
automobiles happy with everything from
the show last year back these systems
will be part of that and the right now
the mandate minimum requirement you have
to meet you can meet them however you
need to lead them to validate the cats
but there will be two gotta be that you
follow those any transportation safety
standards they're all felt at a station
and many don't realize that the air bags
class all the other factors South attack
yes I don't get the ball back and then
there are random pop any automobiles
found to have failed one of those
standards that when they recall anything
that will be part of that