intuition why this is the case comes
down to the fact that developers write
code on top of API's are inherently
prone to particular class of all
abilities right so if you're writing
code against a sequel teary API and
you're not careful you'll enjoy it as a
single injection bug similarly if you're
writing code against the web platform
API you're dealing with a very
complicated if you are that's full of
sharp edges and there's very very many
opportunities for you to introduce
mistakes that end result in liability
about availability security bugs are
vulnerabilities and so basically what we
have a decision we have is that we
expect developers to always in every
single one of those cases where the
UCI's API's be very careful and beware
of all the security considerations which
by the way too often orthogonal to the
primary purpose of this API right to see
quicker API doesn't really have that
much to do with security it's about
creating data from a database and web
platforms about rendering you I and the
fact that there is actually security
considerations is sort of a secondary
concern is that it's very easy to forget
that as you develop it right and he's
API's often vary widely used if you look
at the web platform API is in a
large-scale web application you'll find
probably hundreds if not thousands of
code sites that could potentially result
in about and so democracy human they
make mistakes so we're basically in a
situation where we have many potential
bugs and then therefore some actual bugs
it's it's it's very much as inevitable
and what we have to do is because we now
have code that has bugs in it we have to
try and isolate those find those
eliminate them before we ship the bugs
before we ship their the quarter
production of course unfortunately the
approaches that we have at our disposal
there are inherently incompletes relying
on static analysis tools are inherently
incomplete relying on testing relying on
human quarter of you will never find all
the bugs once they're introduced and so
we're going to ship something productive
to production and we're in a in a bad
place so what I'm proposing is to
instead take the view that really the
problem is with the API right the
problem is not with the developer who is
making mistakes the problem is that we
have designed if you guys that permit
the introduction of bugs that are kind
of secondary orthogonal to the primary
purpose of the API and in particular
then are bugs that result in security
vulnerabilities and that's really an
unreasonable burden that were placing on
the developer and it doesn't work right
so what we need to do is intact put the
burden on the API and the API's design
the API's implementation to ensure that
it's impossible for the developer to
make these mistakes as are using the API
so we want is what I call inherently
safer because I guess my slides are and
what what that means is basically an API
that has roughly the same or has the
same functionality as the one that's
their to date but also has the property
that it doesn't allow the developer to
accidentally interviews blogs at the end
result in security vulnerabilities and
of course we have to make this API is
usable so we have to make them
approximately as convenient to use as
the original fallibility prodipe I
that's an interesting question can we
actually do this right is this practical
can we come up with API is that are both
constrain enough to prevent application
code from being written on top of the
API that might have security
vulnerabilities but at the same time
expressive enough so that our developer
can still write the code that you used
to write and do so
productively right so we're we're
we have to make sure that you guys are
actually usable so what I like to do for
the remainder of the talk for most part
is just talked about two areas where we
worked on this problem and where I think
we actually reasonably well succeeded in
in coming up with solutions that the
first thing i wanna talk about single
injection I don't think I need to
explain this but you know how to make
sure that the right way and I can
explain
injection diesel I think everybody here
knows what what the problem is what it
comes down to is that basically queries
are assembled from strains in program
code and then in a way where
untrustworthy data externally controlled
data is somehow introduced in the query
and then results in an attacker's
ability to modify its use in tax and
semantics of the query
so far the existing best practices to
try and avoid these types of birds is
that we tell developers well you should
be using prepared statements which if
they're used consistently prevent the
bog because all the externally
controlled data the parameters to the
query are introduced sort of out of
bands will bind variables and so they
can't be any injection unfortunately as
we've seen development as we all know
developers are humans and they are
sometimes make mistakes they forget
about the guideline or they just aren't
aware of it when they start coding and
so then we end up with code that doesn't
use prepared statements and so therefore
is potentially vulnerable and then
sometimes I actually believe all we also
may sometimes run into situations where
they follow the spirit of the rule so
they're using prepared statements but
the sort of miss the whole point and we
end up with cold like this that you know
its injectable despite the fact that
it's using the prepared statement if you
I the other approach that when you sort
of asked developers to consider is to
use structural clearly API substructure
CareerBuilder API is things like
hibernate criteria where you actually
use the programmatic if you have to
assemble the structure of the query and
then that's also inherently safe from
Jackson unfortunately that's also pretty
cumbersome for a more complex query this
gets quite tedious as opposed to the
convenience of ratings equal so the
question is can we come up with their
with an API that allows developers to
basically still build queries from
string concatenation but in a way that
prevents the introduction of injection
vulnerabilities and here's an API that
basically does that it's a very very
simple API it's just a wrapper for a
StringBuilder and the only thing it does
is that it has an append method that
says you're only supposed to append
strains that come from a constant
compile time constant expression
expression is part of the programs are
inherently trustworthy and so what we
basically then end up with is the
invariant at the result from using this
builder is a strength composition
contamination strings which means they
cannot the NE
entrusted data flow dependent or any
dependency diferencia entre the data
into that period which means they can be
an injection right you can only depend
constants to the query time constants
which means you can't write code inject
anything that's not trustworthy of
course the problem is you know as we
know developers don't always read
documentation if we just had this this
API documentation please only call this
with compile-time constant expressions
it I can guarantee you that within weeks
or months we have code like this right
where somebody gets to do that doesn't
read the documentation then we end up
basically in square one we end up with
code that is injectable answer to
prevent this what we did is we added a
study checker to our Java Java toolchain
that tees off on this at compile-time
constant rotation there and potentially
enforces that for any cause side of a
method with a parent parameter thats
declared at compile time constant we
enforce that compile time that the
actual parameters actually competent
counsel expression and so we implement
this and so if you do not try to compile
the code in the Google tool chain in our
job at all chain that has this check our
plugin built into it it won't compile
it'll give you a compiler error and so
without you really cannot write code
against this API that has even a
potential sequel injector and it
basically enforces by the design of the
EPI in combination with his little check
our that's the that's the decree is a
concatenation of time constant strings
and therefore not injectable
now for a look at the resulting codes
are in the before and after world we
also see that the structure of the code
is basically the same right
the old API is using string
concatenation to build a query and the
new state API is still doing that we're
still a pending strings to the query the
only difference is that we used
variability depend instead of plastic
balls on a string and then of course we
can see that on the left side there is
actually a single injection
vulnerability in their code because
we're dating
untrustworthy the external input to the
query so we have to have a bug here and
now we try to translate that into the
new EP I wouldn't compile and then that
compels us to use a so you can see this
but I mean here a little basically be
using a binder a matter for this rating
right so basically the API compels a
developer to actually follow the best
practice that they're supposed to be
following anyway and if they don't get a
compiler error that tells them went into
the documentation for this builder and
tell them what do you think you can see
here is that we added a little bit of
additional syntactic sugar to the if you
will to the API so the API since we now
have a builder doesn't only assembled
the clearing itself it also allows us to
add code methods to assemble the bind
parameters which then allows you to move
the statement that binds the value for a
particular primary right next to the
place where the parameters introduced in
the query so for instance this finds a
user ID you that's in this code inserted
into the clear here but over there we
can actually move this right next to
their statement where the user ID
parameter is introduced into it very
fortunate Kansas so how did this turn
out in practice we basically went and
implemented builder API's in the style
for databases that are used this
includes f1 and spanner which are
planets gael highly scalable databases
that are used to back and use our facing
applications and there's various papers
at conferences about them and then
hibernate which is more frequently used
it doesn't lead to that scale but it's
quite frequently used in internal facing
applications as we implement these
builders and then we did a global
refactoring of all the existing client
code of the original creepy eyes and
changed it to use the new rules saves
CareerBuilder API this was a couple of
water person quarters worth of effort
but in the end it was not hard because
as we've seen the structure of the old
code in the new code is basically the
same so it's an almost I mean it was
actually in some cases are made about
the refectory but it wasn't very hard
way it was somewhat tedious and then if
you consider that you know there's like
probably a couple of thousands of
developers writing
Google against these API is the fact
that it was like you know a few person
quarters to clean up is really a very
modest effort was actually very
reasonable and then once we're done with
that factoring we removed the original
execute query of a string method that is
injected that's inherently prone to go
with that might be vulnerable from
injections from the API altogether is
gone and so without the public API for
those databases really does not allow
you to write code that is even
potentially injectable right adjustments
even compile its so basically in return
for the present quarter efforts we now
are completely done worrying about
single injection just can't write code
that has single injection so this was a
very nice result the only thing I want
to stress is that the implementation is
really very very straightforward right
so there are no like complicated whole
program ten static analysis checkers any
involved it's that builder that you
basically saw the essence of it on one
slide and then the static checker which
is implemented in error-prone which is a
open source static checker pluggable
framework that allows you to write
products on the type and rotated Java
syntax tree and in that framework it's
probably like fifty or a hundred lines
of code to write the shakers very very
simple it right so basically in return
for a couple hundred lines of code
implementation we could actually very
rigorous scanty that single injection
simply can't happen and all this without
any kind of complicated static analysis
is actually a pretty nice result now you
notice maybe this little asterisks here
when I said we have removed this execute
query the thing is there's always
exceptions right so there's there's
certain scenarios where
this API because it has a constraint
that the query is a concatenation of
program clinton's essentially is not
usable to implement what you're trying
to implement canonical example would be
a command-line utility for the database
which by design gets to query from
standard input and i cant be a
compile-time constant string in that
case injection is not a concern because
the principal who is providing the cree
is the same as the principal that's
added to the database and thereby design
supposed to be able to execute any query
against the tables at the access to at
the database level right so we still
need to be able to implement this and to
do this what we did is essentially a
provide a a a restricted but
unconstrained API that effectively still
gives you the execute query of a string
behavior that's potentially injection
prone but we made it subject to security
of you and we actually because we have a
lot of developers that may not always
read read the documentation that tells
him that he should be getting a review
before using this API we actually put a
mechanism in place to enforce that their
review took place to do that we used a
mechanism in our bill system which is
also open source as baseball that allows
you to specify for certain libraries a
white list of packages that made you is
that right and so essentially if
somebody wants to uses this backdoor epi
so to speak
they have to get a widely-used and for
that they need our approval because we
own that directory and so they can just
started using they have to come to which
is what we want right now but once
they've convinced us that they use cases
reasonable it's very very lightweight we
just added to the white laces one change
and they're going to go and what what is
essential for this whole thing to work
or to be practical is that this
exceptional API is only necessary in the
very small number of sites in this
turned out to be the case so we found
that when we did this for factoring
almost all the code that was there could
be a factor to use the CPI and there
were only a very small number of
exceptions where we had to use the
unsafe API that requires manual
do well to talk about scripting a little
bit so ok so I think the the the reason
gripping as such a particularly
intractable class a bug in my intuition
seems to stem from the fact that there
is very very many potential in Jackson
sings but many but potentially
vulnerable sites in a in a large-scale
about often hundreds if not thousands
and then on top of that the data that
flows into these injections think sinks
very frequently comes from far away in
the program so we are dealing with
complex whole system data flows into
those API's which are very difficult to
reason about so as an example I have a
little slice of a typical bad as it
might exist at Google where we see some
code that implemented in JavaScript that
render some UI and then the data either
goes into that you I comes from a bunch
of back into the web application
front-end and back-end and then there's
some stories later now for a unfortunate
security engineer has to review this app
for cross-site scripting bugs what will
basically do it will start with the
injections things will start in goal and
we look for things like assignments to
compel because that's where the trouble
starts us and so will find one here we
see that what goes into that is its
general mark-up that's been composed
using ad-hoc string concatenation so we
look at what happened here and we can
see that there is to sort of subsidiary
injection points if you will
where variables are introduced into that
marked up that's been constructed here
we can see there's one here which is a
whole is called profiles as profile I
can holder is like a message object
or whatever that contains a bunch of
fields of user data domain object I
guess you could call it and we can see
that they actually went and HTML escape
this before putting it into this href
attribute but the emitted code that does
any kind of validation right so we don't
know what would happen if this homepage
value could be JavaScript Poland's
largest code in which case there would
be an injection and there's no code here
that does is validation so we sort of
have to guess that maybe they relied on
input validation of that field of that
data when it somehow made it into the
system earlier but we are really don't
know said something about it right
because there is no code that does the
actual validation at runtime right there
and then the other thing we see is there
is a field called about HTML that gets
inserted into a div and so this whole
thing is like a part of a profile page
it renders a piece of a user's profile
in some way you know photo sharing
application or social network or
something like that and so the intent
here is that this contains a subset of
HTML markup that is hopefully safe
hopefully inert and will not cause
JavaScript execution intended as sort of
a future perspective that users can
write about themselves they can use
fonts and they can use inline images of
that kind of stuff
emoticons whatever and so we expect to
see a subset of html fonts and stuff but
there shouldn't be any script tags in
there but again there's no cold here
that validates this right so if we're
doing a review of this piece of code we
have to validate we have to ascertain
whether data comes from in and make sure
that somehow along the path into this
into this code validation to place right
so we'll see where does it come from
well we're getting it past year we get
to see this profile object this domain
objects from an RPC response to an
XMLHttpRequest from a web frontend so
we're here we're now in Java code and in
this is the Google protocol buffer that
is what generates system an object but
this could be a piece of Java code
either
also seen here there's a bunch of Java
code that just gets his profile object
from about against which is not written
in C++ and hearing it from a database
from a storage database schema and then
we're still not sure if there is about a
billion not because we haven't seen any
validation along the way here right so
presumably this application relies on
external input validation but now you
can see there they might actually be
used like several front and side right
to this profile so right there might be
a backend for a mobile app that might be
a developer facing REST API and there
might be a profile management front and
they might be internal customer service
applications windows right now we
actually have to look at all of these to
figure out where the hell does that come
from so this is very quickly
their deep down the rabbit hole is
quickly becoming intractable right and
is also something if you look at it
that's essentially a hopeless problem
for an automated it static analysis
system to try and reason about this
whole system data flow because we're
going like across three different
languages different RBC mechanisms
storage schema and then who knows what
goes in here right so this gets very
very intractable and they're very
difficult so what do we do about this
well the first area want to address is
the construction of HTML
so the the the first thing on addresses
the ad hoc concatenation of HTML markup
what we did is we introduce tempting
systems that are contextually auto
escaping which means that the template
system actually understands HTML markup
and he knows in which context in the
HTML markup substitution takes place it
so that the template system will
basically parse the HTML markup in the
template and then figure out what
context all these substitutions take
place and then infer appropriate runtime
sanitization and escaping to ensure that
no scripting can take place and so in
this case competition would infer these
escaping directives which in the old
version the developer might have had to
actually put in there manually but now
that enforces them and put them there on
its own and we can see that it worked
out that here this is basically the body
of an element so we just need to HTML
escape this one appears in a valued
attributes so we first need to validate
that this is a savior lol its not
Javascript something something it's
formed HDB euro and then we cannot
escape and then again in inside a an
element so we escape so this is great
because now the template system
basically makes a promise it has again
to you that for arbitrary inputs into
the template system as long as a
template itself compiles we have the
guarantee you that the resulting mark-up
cannot result in excess because the
template system guarantees that it
always perfectly valid and escape the
data at runtime so that they can be
accessed bugs from rendering this
template so this is this is wonderful
except we have a problem that's here
there's actually a feature that expects
us to render HTML that we're getting
from somewhere right so for you just
leave that left us as is we'd be
escaping the HTML markup that's in here
like the poll tax that are in the use of
rich text format HTML that should be
rendered here so we need a mechanism to
turn off the automatic escaping hear
what you have to do is we had directives
like no other escape that the developer
putting here that would turn this off
but we found that then again we're back
in this place where you still have to
analyze this long data flow into this
field to figure out if the appropriate
sanitization of that markup safe
construction of that markup actually
took place so this didn't really help us
and it actually resulted in a number of
bugs so we did instead is we came up
with a different mechanism to instruct
the template system to suppress the
automatically inferred escaping or
sanitization and it's based on type so
interviews vocabulary of these types
that are basically a string like objects
but the area along with them
contracts promises that say that their
values have to be sick are safe to use
in a particular context so that I
tickets to mel is safe to use in HTML
markup in an HTML markup context inside
an element in its been a template or its
safety assigned to enter its tomorrow if
your name is it for context and
contracts are insured by those those
types public API so we have factored
methods and builders and sanitizers that
themselves ensure that if you get an
instance of one of those types back from
that API it guarantees that the value
actually it here so its contract so we
can then basically use these type
contracts as assumptions in the sinks
222 basically suppress automatic
escaping because we know that the values
are easy for that contest so the the
template system keys of these types and
we'd see the value of types if it's
gmail it'll not run it through the
automatic escaping that it would
normally do because it knows it sorry
safety using context so that the
mechanism that we use to suppress the
automatic escaping the other thing that
goes without including rules that
essentially prohibit the use of the
regular injection vulnerability
prominent Ahmeti so for instance
assignments to enter HTML and
assignments location href are basically
banned from application code and instead
you're supposed to use a safe harbor for
instance rendering one of those
templates or using a little wrapper for
assignments to a location href that does
senators Asian at runtime so we
basically layering across the top of the
Adamo API that's full of sharp edges a
wrapper API that is safe and mostly
relies on these types to achieve that
city and the those those constraints are
enforced by a compile-time check which
is basically just a white list of sites
where we're essentially the only
assignment to enter it should occur
inside those rapper libraries but it
should never occur in now and then when
we now look at the same slice of this
application in this new models in code
that is conformance to this could enroll
we see that the situation looks a lot
better so we we now find that because
we're hearing to the coating rule that
no more assignments two interesting
things like that are allowed in
application code well they aren't any
right i mean they're gone
instead they using the render their
using one of these templates
surrendering to save template which
again is something that cannot buy
design result in excess so from a review
of perspective not something we have to
look at in order to suppress the
automatic escaping of this particular
field the developer now had to do
something special which is to use one of
these types so in this in this domain
object the had to change the type of
this field from string to save HTML
which is then what has the what it
struck template system to suppress the
automatic escaping because it basically
tells it rely on that type contract
don't your automatic escaping because
the type promises that its values are
you safe to use in that context now if
we go and then basically this domain
objects threats the whole way through
across all these are PCs across the
different languages and now is we're in
the back end where we read the data from
a database things get a little bit
interesting because of a type mismatch
right the the data that comes out of the
database out of that column is is a
string but we actually need to put into
that domain object
is safe it so we somehow need to make
that conversion and we don't have a
public API design that just lets you
promise that just let you bless us
training as as the types of HTML because
we know that that would be misused based
on experience for them what we do is we
have a bunch of the library is that
allow you to instruct HTML using sort of
like the API or we have a sanitizer
module that is a commonly shared library
that takes as input an arbitrary strain
that is assumed to contain HTML markup
but we're assuming militias and then the
whole thing it's parsed and reduced to
two basically as safe subset subset of
its remarkable and then the result of
that gets returned to you the caller the
application in the form of this type
safety now because I designed the
sanitizer reduces an arbitrary input to
a string that satisfies that I contract
in this case that it's safe to use it
you know so do you back and no change to
basically read the data from the
database passage for the sanitizer and
then we have the right type to stick
into this domain object and everything
trickles through and everybody's happy
and it it just works now we look at this
from the perspective of security viewer
gets very interesting because there's
not very little for us to look at to
establish the property that these
applications for your excess because
what we need to do is we look at their
compiler configuration make sure they
are using our site listing rules and we
we we double check that they don't have
any extra entries on the white list
basically but if we don't see that then
we know that their JavaScript franco's
not using assignments dinner HTML so
there's nothing for us to look at
we know that the only way they can still
render into the DOM is using safe
rappers such as for instance using
strict template systems or these other
types of API's we don't have to look at
that the types of flow through the
system we don't really have to look at
that the only thing we actually have to
look at is to direct vent into code that
makes conversion from a plane strength
to this type because that's really the
security sensitive operation where
basically claiming that
string actually has a type contract this
case the only place where we see this
user is actually this common library
that or even viewed obviously and so we
don't have anything to look at where we
effectively are now in the position
instead of having to read pretty much
the entire all the front-end code and
reason about these complicated data
flows we're pretty much done with
looking for exercise in like 15 minutes
right because all we need to do is make
sure that they are hearing that they
have the study checks in place to adhere
to the guidelines and we have to look if
they have any application specific fan
in into these unchecked conversion
methods that blesses string as one of
those types and if they don't there's
really no way for the application code
to be responsible for a Nexus S so
there's nothing for us to look at this
is really very compelling because it it
actually makes our code review task
tractable gotta get up a little bit I
think
so in terms of practical application we
basically implemented as we implement a
strict contextual tempting systems in a
couple of template systems including
some open source ones there's also a
couple of internal ones and then work
with some flax products Google+ gmail
and so on
to up adopt this approach and the oxygen
a lot of work to refactor the existing
front-end code to follow this coding
guidelines and we did see very drastic
reduction in bugs right so bugs are
excess stocks are pretty pretty
prevalent we probably across all go
several hundreds every year and then we
saw that in these applications that
adopted this approach there but count
went down drastically right so in one of
those cases they had something like
thirty exercise in 2011 and then took
them like a year or whatever to to the
recycler in overtime and then they
really have had no approximately zero so
I'm watching a little bit exercise since
2013 after they were done with us
the fudge is due to the fact that there
were some exercise but they were ones
where you basically are still within the
confines of our goal which is to make it
so that application code cannot be
responsible for exercise so we had we
had one or two where there was actually
about in one of these infrastructure
libraries and the template system and
then there's a couple other classes of
exercise that are not related to
rendering HTML markup the use of the DOM
API so things like rendering
entrusted data in your domain without
the right stuff right so we've had a
couple of those but they're sort of
outside of the scope of this effort but
within in terms of bugs that were really
you know that would have been there and
would have been the fault of application
code that's engaged in rendering you I
really haven't had any after that this
has been about it so this is pretty nice
course are in the last couple of minutes
I just wanted to summarize and
extrapolate a little bit on some of the
approaches to the API design that
underlies this this this work basically
what it comes down to is that we're
introducing these these guys that are
designed to make it impossible for kind
code for application called built on top
of them to have certain specific classes
of security bugs right so what we're
doing with that is that we're
effectively eliminating the potential
for bugs that are otherwise was there
because the underlying originally I had
a potential bug in every single one of
its uses so all over the application and
we're now eliminating that potential for
those bags because he is being used that
simply doesn't allow the bug to occur
and so we're done effectively is we've
eliminated these this bug potential from
all the application code and have
confined it in the implementation of
those API is right there still of course
potential bugs there but it has to be in
the code that implements as if you guys
which is sort of you could think of it
as the trusted computing base base with
respect to this particular property and
so this of course then in in practice in
large-scale application constitutes a
huge reduction of potential for bauxite
because previously we had potential bugs
all over application code and now we
just have them inside the API which is a
very small fraction of the code base and
then as we've seen in particular in the
case of excess is really results results
in a
pretty drastic reduction in many cases
of the actual bugs that we see resulting
from that potential a key principle in
the design of these API's is that we API
designer don't allow us don't allow
ourselves to make any unsupported
assumptions about data that comes across
the EPI boundary to us so in particular
we're not allowed to make any
assumptions whatsoever about values of
basic types in particular strengths
which in turn means that if we get a
string and we're using it inside the API
in a context that is prone to injection
for instance it's strange that way then
using in an HTML element or something
like that we are responsible for taking
that data and making it safe right
solely responsible for applying the
necessary runtime validation or escaping
or whatever is necessary to make the
data say it's it's our responsibility
it's no longer the responsibility of our
client and we're not allowed to make any
assumptions about our clients doing the
right thing sort of on their own basis
right because we've seen that asking
developers to do that just doesn't work
so it sits squarely on us what's
interesting is it might think this
results in a lot of extra overhead but
actually really doesn't because this
runtime escaping which is more for the
most part what we're talking about is
something that anyway has to take place
so it doesn't really matter if the data
is trusted and untrusted if we're taking
a string that presents represents text
and we're using it in an HTML element we
have to HTML escape it if it's not if
it's a trusted string if it's a string
that's controlled by the application for
getting that results not in a security
about but it could still result in a
rendering era because we're not escaping
so correctly right so anyway have to
escape anyway and we have to escape the
data irrespective of whether or not it
came from an untrusted source of it came
from a trusted source and this is sort
of mostly the case which means we're not
actually doing a lot of extra work which
is moving where that works takes place
and who's responsible for it right
previously it was sort of the
responsibility of the application code
to do this somewhere and now it's just
basically our job at CBS job the other
sort of interesting things I think about
is that this is sort of this approach is
kind of a
do all to the change tracking approach
that is usually used to think about
injection problems I'd injection
problems are really problems related to
untrustworthy data flow that comes from
somewhere and then makes it an injection
injection sink where causes trouble and
so it's natural to think about this in
terms of techniques that rely on
tracking that tent right so we have
static analysis which is basically
studying whole program analysis and we
have maybe dynamic tension alice's but
it turns out that is actually not a very
efficient way to approach this problem
because in an interesting application
most of the variables that float around
are you there
entrust the data right so we're
basically trying to track all these
various variables that are coming
through very very complex whole system
data flows and so we're setting us up
for a very very intractable problem and
what we're doing here is sort of the
exact opposite we're just assuming that
everything that gets to the API unless
proven otherwise is potentially unsafe
and we just deal with it at runtime it's
a much much simpler approach that it
also gives us more rigorous guarantees
because it is something that we can
reliably whereas hope program changing
is is is basically always a heuristic
right i mean we can't we can't do it
reliably and now we get to the unless
proven otherwise
aspect because there are some cases
where our API actually has to make
assumptions about the data because
otherwise it just wouldn't be able to do
what we expect from it and the way we do
this is through these types right so we
use types to substantiate assumptions
about data that comes into the FBI and
so we kind of see is that basically the
type contract is sort of a mechanism
that allows us to if you will teleport a
promise or a property of the data that
we've established somewhere at its
source in the example of that was in the
back end where we ran it through the
HTML sanitizer library and then we
teleport that promise about the data all
the way to the sink where we have to
rely on it which is in this case in the
template system where r inserting it
into the template without without any
kind of escaping right and
so we basically use a mechanism to allow
us to reason about the whole program
property that there is no escaping or
validation that had to take place but
using a mechanism that allows us to do
this without having to read the whole
program right so we can we basically
used types to give us a reform of local
reasoning to establish whole program
properties and that's why I think it
pretty pretty powerful mechanism there's
of course one key assumption in there
which is that these types of integrity
right so we rely on no application codes
digging behind the public API's of these
types and messing with their internal
isn't just you know writing an arbitrary
string into the strength that trapped
inside a city that's generally a
reasonable assumption because our model
for this is that the developers not
actually militias they're they're just
human and make mistakes right so we're
not worried about developers that
actively try to subvert this situation
where people were getting a little bit
overly creative but you know we deal
with that on a case-by-case basis just a
few words about these sort of practical
ability usability of this the
practicality of this approach is of
course key right i mean this homework
will be pointless if it wasn't usable in
real-world software development one
thing that i think is key for this is
that we we we've come up with API is
that are very similar in terms of the
API itself and result including patterns
as originally a sequel case for instance
we're still allowing the developer to
use string concatenation to build it
frees the code really has exacted
structure as before just adding this
little constrained to make sure that
these stick to the best practice of
always using bind parameters and using
queries that are themselves trustworthy
same thing in the in the excess case
template system is the same one that the
use before so for instance closure
templates we just strengthened its
properties in terms of the escaping that
it applies to all the data and we made
sort of a
very simple and straightforward contract
between the template and its users which
has the templates always responsible for
security properties for absence of
excess other aspect is that there is
always going to be exceptions and so we
chose not to try and make the primary
API more complex to accommodate all
these exceptions which kept this very
simple in the case of the sequel example
it was basically utterly trivial and
instead we just rely on a lightweight
mechanism to accommodate these
exceptions where we allow developers to
use the previous effectively
unconstrained API but make it subject to
a mandatory review and if that doesn't
happen very often it's alright so for
instance in the sequel realm it's
basically like you know probably three
percent of my time to take care of this
for the whole company because I get like
a question about this doctor ABI
whatever every couple of weeks and then
have the time they need it at the time
they don't be talkin and that's it right
so it's very lightweight the other thing
that we found to be very helpful is that
in this approach we are surfacing
aerostat pertain to potential security
bugs at compile time so that most of the
time these are just tight areas that
happened from incorrect typing correct
usage of an API or it could be you know
this incorrect use of this API that once
upon a time constant expression which
really is kind of a it's a custom type
out his nephew also it smells like it hi
there it's very easy for developers
understand its compiler that they used
to getting anyway and it's it's also
very clear-cut right it's not like a
potential but that you getting from some
tool that comes on later on after
checking the code and then the data
analysis ran on it and then you have to
deal with these potential issues you're
just using the API wrong the
documentation says you're supposed to
give it a compile-time constant
expression you didn't it's it's a clear
coherent and so that makes it very
straightforward for developers to reason
about and also you don't get into the
situation where cause already checked in
and then you have a potential bug and
then you have to argue with people
whether or not that merits
refectory right it's it never even get
that far because it never even compile
so that's actually I think very helpful
in practice and then finally there is
sort of another angle to look at this
which is this is really about designed
for reader review ability by which I
mean so their property if you will
how much of an overall applications
codebase throughout you have to look at
you have to understand and analyze and
reason about to establish a particular
property of the whole program in this
case absence of a particular classifieds
absence of sequence action absence of
exercise how much of the whole quarter
after read and sort of thinking about
this practically if the answer to that
question is asked to read a pretty good
chunk of the overall app right of the
application code then this is just not
going to work because it's a lot of code
I don't have time to read it I have i
dont have tools that really can
understand it accurately and it's
constantly changing underneath of me and
so that approach really just makes it
almost inevitable that there will be
bugs raised in this case we end up with
by design a situation where the Dakota
you to review is the implementations of
the API which is a very very small
fraction of the code base and so we we
actually end up in a situation where
it's possible for us to read all the
coat in depth and analyzed in depth and
test and do whatever we need to do to
get confidence in its correctness for
the code that is responsible for
avoiding the bug which is the
implementations of these APIC template
system that's equal period older and so
we we basically are now in a situation
where we can be very very
sort of in-depth review the code that is
that pertains to that particular
classifieds and hence we can get high
confidence assessment out of that where
as in the previous case we kind of had
to sort of hope we kind of caught some
of the bugs in the pay gap that we kind
of read part of it right and so it's a
it's a very very different game without
and with that I'm done time for a few
questions as I mentioned a bunch of this
work is is in open source projects or
there's budget template systems that
we're open source and so that the code
we added to it is is there as well I
think these lights will be published
these all links to the respective pages
and without its time for a couple of
questions
rely on on types and statically typed
languages not really I'm so in fact
included templates is dynamically typed
so the decision whether or not the
values of types if it's a male or a
plain string and then handsets be
escaped happens at runtime all we need
is that these types are reasonably well
encapsulated so and that sort of depends
a lot on the idiomatic lose you saw the
language rights or incident in Java
somebody could use reflection to poke
inside those types but you don't really
see reflection based coating application
code if you send out for code review
somebody will go after you with a big
stick right now in other languages I'm
not familiar with Ruby all that much but
from what I can tell you is like the use
of nixon's is pretty pretty sort of
romantic and so therefore it's kind of
more likely that maybe somebody will
write code that cracks open type and
then at behavior toward that actually
makes it unsafe and violates the
contract but but there is no inherent
reliance on static typing I'm personally
a big fan of static typing because you
get your your errands earlier right but
if you like to live dangerously and only
find out at runtime that you have to
type it still works right i mean just
know later in the stage of development
so this is interesting so basically the
the the property we needed to enforce is
that the actual parameter to a
particular method is a compile-time
constant expression and we couldn't find
a way of expressing this in the Java
type system if anybody can think of one
at the happy to hear it but it turns out
we were actually able to do it in C++
and then go there's like some obscure
ways that will hopefully at some point
open source that let you do this in in
C++ he also relied on so clang clang
compiler has this enable if attribute
which the clan custom thing that
actually kind of allows you to express
this property in a somewhat convoluted
way but it it works and then goal there
some trick with I forget exactly exactly
exactly exactly how it works but there
some trick with package visibility that
allows you to make a type that cannot be
constructed that is basically a strain
but it cannot be constructed by code
that's not in the same package and so
you can you can basically a property but
in Java couldn't so we need to resort to
a custom checker
yeah that's a good question so the
question is what control do you have
over the library is that people are
using I think that is one of the
advantage we have a Google is that all
development comes out of a single large
repository and that allows us to to keep
some leftover what's being used right so
there is basically a process for
importing for instance third-party
libraries that involves people that
check about the license and archived
stuff but the security team is plugged
into that so for instance somebody went
and wanted to introduce another sequel
or AIM later or another template system
we kind of get to at least say that
that's happening and then in some cases
we either find that we need to deal with
it and and argue with them tonight do
that or find an alternative solution or
maybe in their particular case it's okay
and then we we often use this mechanism
that have mentioned build visibility
which allows you to whitelist users of a
particular package right so he said okay
fine you're an internal tool use your
favorite template system it's not really
worth our time to to deal with that but
before anyone wants uses in a external
facing application they have to get on
that widely-used and you know we put a
comment there says please talk to the
security team and usually the owners of
these things are responsible and do that
so there is some sort of makes a process
and just hoping that people are
reasonable and and some speed bumps if
you are our measures in the system
itself for that
thank you