hi everyone thanks for coming I'm stand
me and this is driving like you acted
this is a fun talk business continuously
working on improving as I'm doing
research and a couple of different areas
a couple really fun areas for me have
been vehicles vehicles radio hardware
and we're going to focus a little bit on
some of that stuff which is really fun
to me
will cover some web stuff as well and
then try to bring it all together in a
fun way so we all love Nicolas Cage
right yeah okay I love nicholas cage so
I thought gone in 60 seconds like one of
my favorite movies so I've spent my
entire life trying to be like him so as
gone in 60 seconds happens you know
basically Nic Cage's going around
stealing cars spoil it for anyone but to
do that the first thing you need to do
is you need to get into a garage which
has like some really cool cars so in the
last year I've been looking at how can I
break into garages like how to Rogers
work and garages are pretty cool we all
have sort of we've all seen the clicker
right little garage clicker have one
here so I started learning about how
these things work and my goal was to
break into my own garage I like I'm in a
condo units so there's a bunch of
different cars down there and I want to
see how this thing works so I started
running a little bit our radio frequency
and how radios and communicating with
devices like garage door openers works
so the first thing we're gonna be easily
go in depth here and I'm gonna show you
how how this stuff works let's do some
live demonstrations the first thing you
do when learning about something with
radio is there something really cool any
device in the USA that transmits that
actually transmits radio frequency has
to have an SEC I D so if you put your
phone all of our phones actually have an
FCC idea on the back here so like my
iPhone I ICNS TCID so same thing with
this garage door opener which opens my
garage so what we can do is we can
actually take one of these things and
open up our garage and if we look at
CCAD
the cool thing about the FCC is what
they do is they regulate transmission
and EUS so if you want to transmit on
radio frequency the SEC has to allow
that device manufacturer to do it and
what we can do is all of the information
about that ideas actually public
information so you can actually go to
the SEC is website which is really
really hard to use and search for these
IDs fortunately someone named Dominic
still has created a website called FCC .
I which I use all the time and basically
on SEC . I owe you can just type in the
identifier back on either this garage
door opener or your garage door itself
or your phone so he actually pull up
your phone and you can look up the FCC
idea and you can learn all about what
your phone transmits all is actually
very cool and inside of their will see a
few things so the first thing we see is
often you'll see pictures of the actual
device both the outside on the left here
and the inside so you actually see
inside of that circuit this is really
cool if you're trying to look up
information on say a device that you
don't necessarily have access to or
device that might be out of your price
range or advice that's not released yet
rights and that's coming out you can
actually go here you can learn a ton of
information you could probably produced
you know you can probably discovered
vulnerabilities are issues with the
device before it even comes out it's
pretty incredible so here's an example
of actually my garage door opener I
looked it up and the first thing we see
here is we see kinda like where it came
from
came from China obviously and you'll see
the the range here the frequency range
so this is the frequency that
communicates on and on this one it says
the lower frequencies 390 megahertz in
the upper is 399 yards so that means
this communicate on 11 frequency 390
megahertz was pretty cool so what else
we see on on FCC we see stuff like the
cover letter is a nice little formal
letter today right external photos like
we saw internal photos couple different
things one of the more interesting areas
is the the test report so what the FCC
does that hire someone to come out and
actually test your device because the
thing with the with frequencies were
such as sharing the spectrum like you
don't wanna device just constantly
transferred out and prevent other
devices from working for example if I
just held this garage door thing it is
reduced transmitting all the time it may
prevent other garage door openers from
working and you wouldn't want to
interfere with say someone across the
street so they do all these tests ensure
that it transformed the frequencies it's
allowed to not more powerful than it
should
so on and so forth so he pulled it up
and see like the internal report week
actually often see spectrograph actual
recording of that of the radio signal
transmitted by the device and there are
some different devices I use to actually
listen to this kind of stuff
one of the races really cool it's a car
F it's capable of receiving entrance
transferring from one megahertz all the
way up to 60 Hertz really wide range
totally open source open hardware couple
hundred dollars you can also transmit
which is really interesting people have
done some really crazy stuff with this
thing for example spoofing GPS GPS using
this device or similar devices have made
ships go off course ship slurry going
off course because we're depending on
the depending on GPS has GPS works it's
from radio signals getting sent from
satellites down to the earth and we're
using that to like figure out where we
are and someone comes along and
transmits a signal and you think you're
somewhere else are you going somewhere
else I mean the amount of dependency
that we have on these radio signals is
massive and growing every single day
there's another reason that this is like
such an interesting thing and I'm so
interested in this right now and now you
may say okay well I don't know anything
about radio and I know very little about
radio personally but you can do some
pretty simple things for example if
you're dealing with something that uses
a fixed transmission something that
we're it's like a password so if you
open your garage door opener a lot of
our garage door openers basically have a
bunch of DIP switches which is
essentially a password and that opens
your garage now if you don't know
someone's like if I were trying to
exploit some of the garage trying to
break in what I might do is I might
record that signal and replay it and
often do that now not all devices are
capable of recording and replaying often
you need to know a lot more information
about the signal which will learn a bit
but with nearly two commands you can
record and replay recording you know
taking a microphone and speaker Andrew
reproducing some signal now this will
work in some scenarios none all
scenarios for example cars are you
something called rolling codes that
later where the passwords changing kind
of like to go authenticator or to have a
right you might get to have a is
essentially rolling code where every
time you get a new identifier a new
password to login something another
device they use is RTL SDR this is
awesome I have it right here it's
basically another antenna it's a soft
STR means offer defined radio RTL from
Realtek and suffer defined radio is a
corrupt is also a software-defined radio
it allows you to use software and
inexpensive hardware to analyze the
radio spectrum and also often
transmitted RTL SDR is great because
like $20 in the Amazon you can go right
now for 20 bucks get into it you know
start learning and you can do so much
you can see planes going overhead
there's actually someone in LA who did
who has been recording planes so its
public transmission whenever a plane is
flying it's sending radio signal of
where it is
of its GPS coordinates information about
it unique name and he started mapping it
out as a hobby and he found that there's
these planes that are just circling over
LA It's going in circles right they lift
off the fly around in a circle why are
their plane circling over LA and said
look what that correct FBI planes he's a
guy who discovered that these are FBI
planes going around probably using
something like stingray to listen to
your phone calls and text messages so
always say hi FBI when you pick up the
phone so RTLS yours another really cool
example he did that with RTL SDR to $20
device you can use free software open
source software on your computer no
matter you know in any major operating
system
new radio this is like this is a fun or
the complicated piece of software
that is prolly not complicated is really
hard for me to learn so I'm still trying
to figure out how to use the same but it
allows you to take a radio signals are
actually any signal technically you can
just type audio into it and you can
manipulate it you can run different
filters on in extract information or
transmit information so this is another
really useful tool GRX this is awesome
tool actually uses in a minute I'll show
you how it works basically this allows
us to see a waterfall view of the
spectrum of the radio spectrum so we can
say all right I want to see from 302 301
megahertz MHz everything that happens on
there this would allow you to that made
it so you have a device and you don't
have the SEC I D
let's say you don't have access to a
device let's say you're outside of
something and you have a black box or
you know someone is driving up to the
garage and they're about to hit about
you but you don't know what frequency
devices using you can use this to
essentially watch watch a waterfall of
radio frequencies and you will see when
there is something with a high amplitude
when there is essentially a signal its
getting transmitted really cool this is
for Linux and OSX only if you're on
Windows you can also get str sharp
another similar tool to do the same
thing very cool and the cool thing is I
mean they're people out there like on
reddit there's a there's a subreddit
called RTL SDR and you can actually go
on there and people are just looking at
the spectrum because there's all these
radio frequency out there and we have no
idea what a lot of them are right a lot
of these you know this is this is
something that invisible right
essentially invisible to us and usually
when there's something invisible people
just assume insecure because we can't
see it we don't know how it works and
more and more people are now playing in
this area and researching and trying to
find what are all these invisible
signals and a lot of it
lack security I mean really interesting
some of the stuff that's coming out of
here
RTL FM this is like a command-line tool
that allows you to record signals with
RTL SDR so these are some of the tools
that I use the presentation will be
available
our minds of viewers want to grab it and
and do any research in here you'll have
access to all of that so let's go back
to the SEC report there are three things
I usually look at when I'm looking at an
SEC report for
for a device internal photos because you
see inside if I can see inside I might
be able to make out the chip that's
being used by a look at the chip I can
probably look up data sheets available
for that chip and I can learn all about
what the chip is doing the frequency
communicates on the modulation all sorts
of information about it I can look at
the test report as well and the test
report will will often provide some
useful information such as what
frequencies it uses perhaps we'll
modulation and then also the user manual
there's always like incredible piece of
information in user manuals that I find
a friend of a friend I was at Coachella
he's like yeah I came back to my card
all my windows were down there was
anything stolen is like no luckily also
like someone broke into my car and
didn't take anything that seems weird so
I looked at the FCC ideas like maybe
someone hacked his devices like radio
thing for his his car key and it looked
it looked it up and looked at the user
manual and it's just a section of how
the car key operates and everything
about the car key and apparently behold
one of the buttons down far enough
seconds all your windows rolled down
I've been told them I'm going to use
against them so here's an example the
test report from a from my garage door
opener and you can see we can see
something called the frequencies 390
megahertz we see the modulation type is
ASX rascal will go over that in the
second here and a couple of things about
the device so it's a great modulation
little bit here has listened to the
radio ok younger people may not know
what that is like Spotify so we now have
things there there's different types of
modulation is basically how we encode
data in a signal there's asked which is
amplitude shift keying there's a FSK
frequency shift keying and PSK
phase-shifting these are common
modulation schemes are used now these
are specifically for digital data when
you're trying to communicate digital
information over over the radio spectrum
now ask is actually amplitype of
amplitude modulation amplitude
modulation is a.m. it's little the a.m.
radio
when using your AM radio Radio is taking
the radio spectrum at whatever frequency
or listen you to say 200 killer and
amplitude which is essentially if you
listen to let you sound file right the
amplitude is the volume is essentially
how strong that volume is the amplitude
defines where what kind of sound you're
hearing or what frequency to sound is
that frequency shift keying is frequency
modulation or FM FM radio in 2010 2.7
actually listen to 10 2.7 measures and
we can use that we can see that RTLS Dr
and the frequency is actually not 10 2.7
it's actually a range so it's actually
more like one or two point five to 10
2.9 and the frequency changes depending
on where you know what that sound with
their frequency should be something like
RTL SDR we can also if we don't know
what devices transmitting we can look at
it here and on the left we see that
there's kinda like two signals coming
whenever I hit a button so that's public
something called two of us ko
frequencies 15 where the frequency is
changing and because its digital is just
100 rose so left or right means 10 and
then on the right we have asked which is
amplitude shifting we're just either
there's a signal or there's not a signal
which represents a 10 so when we
actually I don't actually see what this
looks like I'm going to open dq iraq's
enemies the Sartorialist yard so we can
take a quick look at see this works here
right so so we can see here I met three
hundred megahertz which is what this
garage door opener is at and whenever I
press we can see data so that's pretty
cool like if I fighting know what
frequency was that we could like go
searching through you know we could go
to say here we have we have actual
stations writes about 100 megahertz now
so we can actually see FM radio stations
and I can actually modulate this data I
don't see that
so we'd have to tune
executed different facing fear
that's right there 'cause so we actually
know that this is that three hundred
megahertz now this is really cool we can
be modulated state are right here so now
that we know it's again we'll look at
once more here
393 her megahertz and because it looks
like it's just 16 turning on and off
that tells me it's probably amplitude
shift team or a.m. amplitude modulation
so we can then use RTL FM's quit that
let's see here on my Windows alright so
that's gonna be hard to see but their
largest recorded first so I'll say RTL
three hundred tests always a press this
once or twice
great control see and what this actually
does this produces an audio file away
file that we can then inspect so I'm
gonna pull this up in Audacity free
audio tool let me find the file here and
I will throw this in here right now
there's other city so here we can see I
clicked I hit it twice it wants here and
then once here so let's take a look at
what the signal actually looks like you
mean it looks like it's a repeating
signal looks like the same information
now who is open one of these garage
doors and had to accept the DIP switches
he had to do that
alright so we've seen those usually it's
like 10 or 12 the switches let's do man
can you get with these relate to
so if I open my right here the thing is
impossible open right now I'll tell you
what I have here on and off that
switches mine is on on off on zoo man we
can see if there's any correlation at
all on on off on off on off off off off
so basically we're seeing influence you
actually seeing a signal in this case it
looks like a long signal followed by
nothing long is 01 and sort they're not
followed by nothing is as Europe so
literally just by using this $20 device
I recorded and I now know the code to my
garage door you could go around like
recording Co like just like in gone in
60 seconds right they go up to the
garage they use their little device
would probably didn't exist and they are
able to record the code that's so
interesting right so let's go back to
all agree is going with that
figure out how to open I'm not marrying
here so all windows
back to the side so we decided heroics
and we saw this right so we actually
analyze that signal we saw this
repeating signal he repeats a bunch of
times because amplitude shift keying
like if you've ever listen to audio
sucks it sucks it's it's very easy to
get the most inexpensive way to transmit
information but it's also the most prone
to interference people's nothing you can
really see if anything they are so
someone had a good suggestion
brute force that how long will it take
well if you take a look at these
different garage doors there's a couple
different things
summer summer ten bits 12 it's right
there just on and off so I recorded this
one and it looked like he was two
milliseconds per bit with the two
millisecond delay for each bit and it
sent five signals trooper transmission
minimum so if we calculate that for all
the possible garage doors that I've
looked at your pics codes it looks like
it would take about 2929 a half minutes
to boot for us so easily 30 minutes but
for some of the garage which is pretty
insane
looking at this and I was like well can
I do this little faster because I have
stuff to do to sit outside of people's
homes thirty minutes and do this and i
was looking and I thought ok well if
it's repeating the signal what if we
stop repeating the second it's repeating
just so that it can be more successful
but for the most most part we're not
going to have interference so if you
actually take out the repetition
we can actually reduce the 26 minutes to
brute force any fixed code garage that's
pretty cool but looking at this further
I saw that there is basically this
massive period of weight of delay
between every time it sends a signal so
what if I took out that delay we're
sending one signal followed by like one
Password followed by another password
instead of Adelaide between them what I
just sent password password password
password and that worked to open my
garage so that reduce it down to three
minutes to open any fix code grass and
then I was thinking how does it know
where one Password begins in one pass
programs what if it's using something
called a bit
shift register now a bit shift registers
basically register where you you pull in
data one bit at a time and as it's
essentially perform the tests would say
it's a four-bit register it looks the
four bits and it performs a test is this
the correct for a bit if not it then
takes one bit off pops one off and then
shifts one in well if that's the case
you wouldn't actually test all possible
codes you can actually just pop up for
example if I used let's say let's say
I'm looking at this is a two-bit code
but they were just looking at a two-bit
code right here
00011 1104 options that's a total of
eight bits however if we create
something called the debris debris in
sequence deploying the mathematician who
discovered this algorithm to efficiently
produce all possible codes over that
overlap so we overlap these we can save
00 110 now he put them in which have
registered we get 200 is the first two
bits and if we move over just one bit
then we get 2011 bit we get 11 and in
the last 10 so we'd actually gone all
eight bit out of 5 bit sequins now if we
do that with every eight to 12 bit code
we actually reduce this down to eight
seconds to brute force any fix code
garage between eight and 12 its long
eight seconds
yeah
gone over all of the infrared codes that
are basically public information from
the televisions TV B Gone you could do
that but TV began specifically turns off
TVs so if you're a brute forcing what
you'd actually end up doing is like
changing the volume changing the import
store is doing all this other stuff
TV B Gone specifically has programmed
all of the IR codes for different
televisions but you can definitely do
something similar because you will hit
the auth code at some point right so at
this point we have eight seconds now
this is just how to transmit RTL SDR
does not actually transmitted this is
just an assumption of how we can mess
with with this garage now we need a
device to actually transmitted one
device i'ma fan of his yardstick one
also by Michael Austin this has a nice
radio chip receiving and transmitting
its not software defined radio
defined radio allows you to take a very
a single you know nothing about and
perform all the modulation demodulation
and accessing and reading it in software
this is all hardware there there's pros
and cons the con the major cause of
something like this is that if you don't
know what the signal is if you don't
know if its frequency modulator
amplitude modulated or the frequency
this is not going to be too helpful
because you have to tell this to tell
the hardware I know it's FSK a note on
this frequency i knows this data rate
and show me the data or transmit the
data but if you know what you're looking
for or you know what you want to
transmit you can use this device and you
there's a Python interface that you can
use by something called our Afghan and
there's another device that that I like
to use from this from one of the most
amazing technological companies of our
time will tell
so Mattel creates all sorts of awesome
toys for children and one of their
devices one of their toys is called the
Mattel Miami this is a texting device
for tweens to basically communicate with
each other without being on the Internet
where people hang out so I M E
you can actually text someone and it
wirelessly transmits to a little dog
along on a USB stick and then it goes
over the Internet to your friend who
also has one of those USB dongles in NYC
transmits to the this little device to
the IME the service is no longer active
they don't sell these anymore so you can
get them off ebay for like 10 $20 and a
couple of people have found that inside
of this device is a really cool chipset
from texas instruments and it's a sub
gigahertz transceiver that means it can
receive and transmit on virtually any
frequency under one gigahertz which is
actually amazing if you're trying to
build a device like this yourself by
cost hundreds of dollars thanks to
Mattel and massive production you can
get it for like 10 bucks on eBay so
Travis Goodspeed and some other people
found out that you can connect to the
back of this thing and reprogram it and
do whatever you want with a transceiver
so this is the device I chose to use for
transmitting across all the different
garage frequencies performing this
attack and I call this the Open Sesame
attack they are
now we get this video here I'm sorry so
that's an example of the open just
running on my friend garage it takes a
total max amount of eight seconds which
on average is 4 seconds so awesome 11
step down so I've released almost
everything to do this obviously I don't
people breaking into people's garages so
I did not I bricks the codes that it
would not work however I released most
of it so that people could understand
how this type of attack works and also
how to how to prevent it
unfortunately since I did that the
prices of raids of the IME so if you do
want one reached out to me I'd be happy
if anyone ever going to do some research
in this area I bought them before they
they became kind of ridiculously priced
so some lessons here don't use a
ridiculously small key space just
because it's invisible rages over radio
and people aren't looking doesn't mean
people aren't going to look right at
some point people will look they will
understand the technology your
proprietary method is not going to help
you so have the there's plenty of
information on this require preamble
rsync word which is basically something
that says the password is about to start
that would prevent the brain attack
where you can actually have all these
passwords for the ball rolling over each
other and enrolling codes that's another
thing we'll talk about throwing codes
will prevent the site of the attack on
our site of the crash and some cool
stuff when you hear one thing that's
happening is over cars are becoming
connected so great so a lot of new cars
now have all sorts of different radios
inside besides am/fm SiriusXM radio's
they have some other things they often
have GSM they'll have GPS receivers and
they'll communicate with the Internet
has OnStar OnStar yeah ok a lot of you
have us are not raise your hand that's
ok
so actually negm vehicle GMC Buick
Cadillac were actually has OnStar
built-in now you know whether you like
it or not is irrelevant you actually
have these features and those features
are connected to the computer of the car
the ECU and various other our cars are
no longer cars that are no longer
mechanical vehicles right there now
essentially
computer with wheels so the computer
control so much and you have so many
awesome features coming out our vehicles
like assisted park and all these things
if if there's something called assisted
park that is the vehicle the vehicle's
computer has controlled the wheel well
before it used to be simply mechanical
now to actually able to turn your real
so far has a very cool feature even iOS
and Android app so a friend of mine had
the same car he had he had on star and I
was playing with the Stephanies you can
play with my vehicle if you are so with
the app downloads are just cool stuff
let you see where your car is
lets you do a couple things there's a
key fob access you can lock you can
unlock remote start hit the horns and
lights I tried that a few times while he
was driving but they they fortunately
they don't allow you to activate the
warning lights while you're driving
which is that ok I'll check out this
communication I assume it's encrypted
with a cell so I installed my own CA you
know my own certificate authority on my
phone and ultimate the traffic you know
lo and behold it was encrypted I
installed the CIA and RI I usually have
my own sort of authority installed on my
on my mobile device and I started
sniffing and because I was using my own
CLK actually performed as a cell
man-in-the-middle attack again this is
only my own device I can't do this on
someone else's because they don't have
my certificate authority installed my
certificate authority tells my phone
that OC emmys you know house of cards CA
is a legitimate authority you can use
his key instead of the legitimate GM's
OnStar SSL key so once I decrypted the
traffic I thought you know
HPS request in plain text has also be 64
pulled out the base 64
and of course the password and username
right there like okay so make sure to
not use you know the answer app on a
network that you don't trust but as long
as as long as you don't have someone CA
they shouldn't be able to decrypt that
traffic and then I realized I had just
reset my phone I forgot like something
happened i reset it actually didn't have
my certificate authority installed which
means the app allowed an invalid
certificate authority to decrypt traffic
even though it had no recognition it had
no idea who Sammy's house of cards was
so the G EMAP was not looking at an SSL
CA it was blindly it will take accept
any SSL key that means as long as you
have someone on your wi-fi network which
is very easy to do and they open that
app you can decrypt all of their traffic
for that up I thought wow this is this
is absolutely insane how can exploit
this and I created a device with a
Raspberry Pi computer fun and yes I'm
bored Mallory which is open source of a
salmonella tax software some DNS
spoofing so that the user would actually
detect anything only took over
eighty-eight ign.com so anyone using
OnStar but all of their other traffic
would still continue to go through their
correct servers and practices all
certificates and a couple other things
like a wireless card and then I thought
ok how do I take my friend how are we
going to jump onto my network now
fortunately you can do things like you
can use your own or use common WiFi
network names like ATT wifi or Starbucks
things that you know that they may be on
but there's actually something pretty
cool here another thing that our phones
do is they sent out probe requests so if
your phone doesn't see your network it
will actually send out probe request
saying hey i'm looking for a network in
this case named to Darling is there a
network name to dog out here and you can
say yes it actually told you the network
name it's looking for and with that
information you can generate a network
on the fly which it will then join
assuming that the correct
work it's actually our phones are
devices are computers or laptops none of
them actually look at the MAC address
they're only looking at the network name
now this is only for open networks if if
your phone has only connected to
encrypted networks fortunately this
attack will not work but I'm assuming
almost everyone has at least connected
to one open encrypted network before ATT
wifi on almost all iPhones absolutely
Netgear Linksys I mean you can end the
cool thing is you can just launched all
of them died so if you come near my
house he may actually just see like 10
different network names for all the
common ones so with under $100
we have a little device that I threw
under my friends car and was able to you
know at some point she won't start this
is now called on star now so here I am
and what I acquired his credentials I
was then able to unlock his car remote
started and basically do anything to his
car that point and then I tested BMW
which also did not check SSL
certificates and I checked mercedes-benz
which is not check as all certificates
and then I tested Chrysler Jeep which
not yet test as a sort of gets this is a
matter of issue in virtually every I
think this was like five out of 10 of
the car apps that have the ability to
unlock a vehicle right now only cared
about the apps actually did something
you know important 5 of 10 did not
perform as a cell Ca validation so the
lessons here if your gonna do this
either validate certificates from the
CIA which actually I wouldn't
necessarily suggest any more than I see
my CA you can I turn off your keys if
they ever get stolen
there are a lot of certificate
authorities out there for example like I
don't know you wouldn't want the hong
kong you know post to be releasing CA's
releasing keys for you but they have
that full capability they can say they
own gmail.com if they want and we've
seen be seen CA's get back before or
accidental keys for gmail.com your
release before the better yet use
artifical pinning this way your
both the after you release has a key in
it you have that key those are the only
people who know about this key no one
else can you know avoid that also has
the passwords like don't just basically
for everything right hash your passwords
use assaults make it difficult even if
someone does obtain this information who
knows how someone will break into your
device sometime in the future there will
be new attacks the exact information in
different ways and always assume you are
hostile network just always assume that
so now we've broken into some cars will
go through this now there's another
interesting thing I've seen a lot of
these vehicles use and a lot to keep
rolling codes so wrong code is like we
talked about before with the CIA the
code exchanged every time kinda like two
FAA you get a different SMS message or
Google authenticator send you a
different number every time and that's
great that's actually a really good way
to prevent an attack like the key flow
like the garage door attack right Open
Sesame
where we have a fix code also rolling
codes are much much longer they're not
like silly 12 it goes that you can break
in a couple of seconds so that's a
that's a nice thing I quickly run
through some hardware attacks that if
you're ever looking at hardware that you
don't know some of the devices I was
looking at I was actually finding that
they would actually market the chip off
actually scratch off the name so you can
look up the datasheet and see what it
was using so in that case what I use is
a use a couple of things he's a logic
analyzer logic analyzer just look that
information with the digital information
going on a wire so you can connect pins
to each of these pens azz SMD microbes
microprobe act like really small really
small pants off of chips also use a
multimeter can measure voltage with a
multimeter of different different pins
on a chip and when i'm looking at a chip
that I don't know anything about mapping
now I can use a multimeter to find the
ground and define power so I can mark
all the ground and our parents also I
can use the logic analyzer and I can
look for certain things that look like a
clock signal Cox acknowledges that like
a square wave pulse width modulation
once I do that if I know what frequency
it it's communicating on which I should
be able to learn with something like an
idealist
er i can download all the data sheet I
can find for something that does not let
these communicate and 2.4 gigahertz
download all the data sheets of
transceivers on 2.4 gigahertz and I'll
take hold their pinout pages and I look
at them at all compared to any look
similar to what I have you any have the
same number of pins do any have the
grounds in the same places the voltage
in the same place as the clock in the
same place and if so I'm not discover
what chip that devices being used
despite them trying to you know scratch
it off using the logic analyzer
datasheet I can see how that chip is
communicating with the device what
command that sending then I'll learn all
sorts of other information like it bears
encryption I might learn a key I might
learn you know what what it's using I
can extract all the serial communication
how it communicates with that device and
I can then build an interception device
which is pretty fun so at this point
let's take a look at my car my car uses
something called ruling goes if you look
at this there's a ton more data in this
code so this would actually take years
and years and years to brute force and
it's only good ones so as soon as you
use this code it will never work again
so I hit the clicker on my car to unlock
that code is used in my car knows that
this code is no longer valid
which is great so let's understand how
ruling codes work is basically a random
number generator in your car and your
key and they're synced actually like a
rolling window when you press the unlock
button your car expects that unique
identifier that unique code but now that
the cars her tits as I will never accept
that again so if someone was sitting out
this Nicolas Cage's outside your home
and he likes this this identifier and he
tries to use it later on to replace its
not going to work because the cars as
i've seen that code before I will not
accept it I only accept the next code
and there's a rolling window so in case
you know in case the kids here in your
pocket and you get a bunch of times out
of range of the car then you go back to
the car the car will say oh you're
actually out of range but it's ok you
know you're on you're in the future
right you're not using a passcode you're
just a little bit in the future you
probably the next few times that's ok
now that's only a small window so it's
it's hard to use that to attack so
trying to find ways of replaying rolling
code of attacking that the only you know
the major way I could think of was the
only way is to capture signal while
you're out of range of the car so if you
like break into someone's house take
their car hit the bun record it and then
go back later and then replay it now
most cars these days also use this for
starting the vehicle as well so these
attacks are actually not only for
unlocking vehicles but it'll also
starting now this is really lame attack
I think if you're in the house and you
have access to Turkey should just take
it so how can we get around this what if
we jam jam the code now again these kids
are inexpensive so they don't charge you
like $300 by one but they're actually
really cheap so it's actually very easy
to interfere with this communication so
when someone hits their button if you're
actually transmitting as well in fact if
you can have the same dissimilar key and
you hold down the unlock or lock button
of your key while someone tries to
unlock their car they won't be able to
lock their car usually do this for kind
of a wide range it's kind of funny to
watch but you can basically easily
interfere with this communication so
worst case scenario they might have to
like pull out their key now he was hit
there but another key and it didn't work
once that happens right and you just did
it again and it typically works right
there was interference even hold long
enough so what if I jam just slightly
off just slightly off the frequency and
i also listen I also use a similar
device to listen I can actually be very
specific and listen to just that signal
and listen to their code and ignore my
Jimmy and I know where I'm jamming I can
ignore that the signal the problem is
once I've recorded that signal that the
car's not heard I can use that so I can
use to unlock however they're gonna keep
hitting it until it works and when it
works when the card does hear their
unlock code all previous codes get
disabled so the code that I've acquired
now no longer useful however as we're
human we all follow simple pattern if I
gym and I listened and I get one coat
and I keep jamming so you go to your car
you you've hit unlock it doesn't work
you had a lock again it doesn't work two
times in a row but I've listened to both
codes and I've extracted those two
passwords I now take those two and I
only replay the first one now the car
doesn't lock on the second time but I'm
using the first code so later on when
you go home and you lock your car I
still have an unused future code that I
can unlock your vehicle because there's
actually no timing right it's all about
just the order of the sequence of these
Co's so you can essentially trick the
user by playing the first one on their
second time and of course you can
automate this so this is an attack I
call roll jam have demonstrated with
about $30 and hardware and so many other
attacks in this area means such as I
think it's such an exciting area because
you have cars coming out this year in
2016 now actually communicate with other
vehicles on the road
VTV so there's so much other radio
communication that's gonna be happening
no cars are able to use ultrasound to
see if there's something in front of
them but what if you send your own
ultrasound right but we can generate
ultrasound it just sound at a higher
frequency what if you send that to a
vehicle you can make it believed that
someone is in front of you you can you
can send me occasional chorus thing that
oh it's it's really rainy so slow down
because make everyone slow down around
you do all sorts of stuff I'm it's crazy
it's scary and exciting there's still so
many other interesting attacks I was
also looking at my my car and I found
that they're locking the vehicle 13 Lok
Lok Lok and a record that data or
endorse interviewer that data will I
can't use a lock to like that's no good
account what what fun is locking their
car however I found in the signal as I
was looking at the data sheet I found
that the rolling code is one part and in
the command is a second part so I can
change the command from lock to unlock
and use the same code as long as I
jammed and they're locked command then I
can use that lock command to unlock even
though hit be a lot later wanna come
over I said I sent an unlocked just by
changing that bit because it's just a
commander not tied to the code and
anyway here's the devices
self attested on a lot of cars it
unlocked a lot of cars and it was
beautiful
lessons I mean you know encrypt ash
those buttons together so if you're
sending a lot command for example and of
course this this works anywhere this
will work on http liked you should use
these same the same methods that encrypt
your house that communication together
right hash the key has the key with the
command use H max time based algorithms
there's actually something called I mean
we've had security for twenty years now
right
Zara seid RSA tokens which are
essentially two FAA that this for 20
years and every 2015 car I've attacked
has had this issue we can implement this
stuff the stuff exists we know about
these we know about these problems and
we know how to solve them to challenge
response with transceivers rather than
just cheap receivers so their ways of
fixing this and that's that's about it
that's that's what I have for you thanks
so much for coming enjoyed it and happy
to take any questions
what do they do that they all came out
with new routes
well the first 1 p.m. did not reach
reach out i mean it is impossible to
contact them they had no like they had
no way for researchers to reach them so
I called them I want to support I asked
later emails went to their website I
mean literally never heard back and then
I then I released a demonstration and
release the code or anything and then I
got called you know within 24 hours and
then bands B&W etcetera they'll fix
everything everyone fix it within a few
days which is great because it's an app
update yes
none of them had none of them had been
programs or in another security presence
is that I could actually communicate
with his literary I mean literally all
these companies I had to just they had
no security response right this is a new
areas of these vehicles now GM's does
now jim does have a security program I'm
sure they do
yes
correct
because so this is this is the device
actually a new device that created that
smaller and cheaper than $30 and you put
it under their cars so it always has
been Xcode yeah so you just it literally
they have to press the button twice
every time and we had a pretty quickly
we just get used to it right now just
hit it twice the second time every time
that's a great idea actually you could
do that so you only did greens than one
that's a good point that correct many
many feel that you actually see the
lifelike happen to know thanks for
coming
questions yes
attacks really interesting right a lot
of us have keys that we keep in our
vehicles keeping our pocket and we can
go up to our carpool the door and it'll
send a signal out that are key to text
and then it will perform a challenge
response back right and for starting the
car it actually use the signal strength
so it knows that you're in the car so
the signal strength is too low it says
oh you're out of the car magnets are the
vehicle had to be inside the car but as
you say you can perform the implication
attack we actually have two people right
and you go up to the car you pull the
door it sends the signal your device
amplifies that signal or sends it
wirelessly somewhere else that gets
retransmitted near the door or near the
near the persons car key in a restaurant
or outside of their house and yeah you
can then unlock and start their vehicle
and drive away in vehicles cannot stop
if they detect the key is no longer in
the car would be too dangerous right if
you're on the freeway is what happens so
the car will continue going to take it
you're tops up
that's correct all of them do have some
amount of timing but its lacks enough
that you can perform the attack in every
case that i've seen
yes yes
know the same company attack yeah yeah
yeah
absolutely i mean I feel like I think
we're talking about earlier like this is
the web 10 years ago right ten fifteen
years ago everything out excess as
everything else equal
school I everything had RFI now most
things and see what I and our high so I
think in another 10 years hopefully
we'll have a lot more hardware and radio
security so I i suspect well yeah
I don't think they have security people
I think it's a new thing right
interesting very cool
okay well thanks so much everyone