afternoon and Caroline thanks for
joining me I suspect though at this
conference
you know there's a lot of folks who are
responsible for sort of doing
application security and folks are here
to figure out
am i doing the right thing how do i do
something new how AM learn about
something that I might end up doing and
then there's some of us who are
responsible for talking about
application security and and maybe you
find yourself in both of those
situations both doing application
security as well as having to talk about
it and there's all sorts of people that
you might need to talk about it with
maybe your boss may be your boss's boss
may be a regulator or an auditor or a
customer who wants to know what you're
doing and application security as folks
are sort of trickling into the room I
started with the slide from one of
actually our clients my eye I work for a
consulting firm called digital we
specialize in software security and this
is what one of our clients had to say
you know she said a lot of people use
this like red light green light approach
you know that's really a major
over-simplification of what's going on
typically another thing that happens is
that you know we overwhelm people with
data there's a lot of data and if we
present that data sort of unfiltered and
without context then perhaps we confuse
the reader and I'd actually like to
point out what she says at the bottom
here she says you know for most
organizations the red light green light
thing the information overload that
doesn't work but and what if you do
nothing you know then you have little to
no understanding of the effectiveness of
your application security program and
today I'm really going to be talking
about effectiveness of application
security really meaning risk management
and we'll dive into that quite deeply
Caroline i've i've been an information
security now for a little
more than a decade it's funny I actually
the last time I was in Santa Monica I
realized as I was taking a cab from the
airport this morning was when I was in
college and a bunch of my friends are
going to UCLA to reserve a nice a nice
memory after college I i worked in
information security and about a decade
ago found myself working at eBay as the
chief of staff for the CISO at the time
they've colony and dave was sort of one
of those really brilliant leaders who
had this ability to go to the finance
organization and the executive
management of you know eBay and say look
we're not investing enough in security
we have this platform where strangers
transact on the internet securities
really big deal and you guys aren't
putting enough money into it and they
listen to and they gave him a bunch of
money and they gave him the opportunity
to hire a bunch of headcount and he
turned to me and he said Caroline now
that we've got the people and now we've
got the technology and we've got the
projects and place now what we need is
the metrics to ensure ongoing investment
in the program you know he said
executives don't understand security
it's not their job to understand
security it's our job to understand
security and tell them what they need to
know and he said I need them to
understand that this is not a one-time
thing so that's kind of where my
particular interest in the subject
started since that time I led
information security teams that eBay and
that it before transitioning to what I
jokingly referred to as the dark side
when I joined the vendor community
working in product management at
Symantec and for the past two and a half
years during management consulting at
City Hall and I and I really enjoyed
consulting for me it's it's very cool
cuz I get to work with clients to solve
really interesting problems
mostly in how to measure for security
initiatives or how to build them or how
to improve them so today we're going to
talk about some questions that
executives may ask our gonna talk about
abstract capabilities and metrics that
are associated with those capabilities
I'm gonna tell you some stories about
metrics and areas that i've seen our
clients and not all of which are you
know sort of optimized and then I'm
gonna tell you about my approach to
developing key metrics we're gonna go
through a very detailed example so
questions from executives more often
than not company executives ask the
wrong questions about AB sec because
company executives are on a plane
you know they pick up hemispheres
magazine or fortune and and they read
this blurb you know and they're like oh
you know a jeep got hacked Ashley
Madison got hacked you know what does
this mean for us and then they think
about the way in which they measure
other parts of their business and they
trying to plan out to upset and it
doesn't quite fit so if an executive
said you how does our bug count compared
to that of our competitors that might
not only be a difficult question to
answer but perhaps you know the folks in
this room know that that's that's really
the wrong question to ask you know but
but how how awkward is that to sit in
front of potentially your CEO you know
maybe your vice president risk you know
somebody was kind of a big deal the
company and that's not the right
question asked but it is and the reason
is because as we know you know my apt is
probably different from my competitors
up maybe it's written in different
language maybe it's it's on a different
technology stack maybe you know we have
very different philosophies when it
comes to the use of free and open source
software for all sorts of reasons number
one are apps are probably different
number to our application security
activities are probably very different
you know maybe I have an extremely
mature static analysis program that I
apply to our entire code base and my
competitor
ur does pen testing only on their
critical applications once a year
you know there's just there's no way to
say our bug count there but count
anything useful
another question you know an exact asks
because they don't know and again it's
not their job to know might be what's
our mean time to recover from a security
and so you know I'm maybe the intent is
maybe we can make that better and we all
want to recover from security incidents
better but probably if you have an
incident response plan in place if you
know who to call for what kind of
scenario and maybe you're doing tabletop
exercises to practice various types of
incidents you know beyond that the
incident is beyond your control and so
this is just it it's something you can't
accuse Iran have control over it
there's not gonna be any consistency and
gathering this type of data
what about when they're asking some of
the right questions we've invested so
much money into the absurd program
what's the impact on a risk posture what
value are getting out of the dollar
spent these are actually really legit
questions to ask but they're not easy to
answer and so today I want to talk about
an approach to answering these types of
questions
planning on how you're feeling this
could be like a guy talk to you kind of
talk or this could be illegal we talk to
each other and it's completely up to you
because I have signed up to talk if you
want I'm curious to know what kinds of
questions folks might be getting from
from their executives you know that
might be easier hard to answer anybody
talking executives and want to share
talking to regulators share yes
I we've honorable to heart bleed maybe
because they read about it in the news
maybe because their CIO buddy is worried
about heart played what are you doing
about hardly which of course we know
sorry I do I want to talk to you next
which of course we know is a software
application security is not just hurt
you know there's so much more about it
yes
yeah because because I mean so this is
interesting maybe my sister is a
pediatrician and I am the new mom of a
10 month old baby girl and so when
something happens I will say to my
sister on a scale of one to 10 how
worried do I need to be you know when
it's kind of the same thing but but but
but maybe not you know there's there's a
more detailed conversation that needs to
take place in maybe you give an answer
but then what you know you're like well
over 300 time in their life well why you
know why that you know like so how does
the rest of the conversation any other
questions from executives that might or
might not be the right ones
why does it keeps the same things keep
happening to us again and again and
again you know some of that in our
control some of its not a hundred
percent secure thats the thing not
really at all so you know there's
there's a lot of opportunity for
education and it's unreasonable for us
to expect that our executives understand
application security that's not their
job that's our job but they do trust us
we hope to help educate them and to do
the right thing thank you and we like
one of those we talked on sessions
why do you need metrics why would you
consider doing metrics executives want
to know
bottom line they want to know about risk
management and and today is talk is all
about how do you talk to them about
absurd and risk management the easy way
the simple way perhaps one simple way is
to say look good software helps our
business bad software hurts our business
and if we can try and do things to make
software good and prevent software from
being bad thats risk management and
that's a really that's actually a really
good place to start but then what how do
we know we're doing the right things how
do we know if we're not doing enough
when I was single
we had a lot of really smart people on
the team and we were doing a lot of
really smart things are CIO said I know
you guys are smart how do I know you're
doing the right things and and you know
we didn't have a great answer for her
and so she said I want I want us to
follow the ISO framework right so one
way is to choose an industry best
practice our framework can say look
we're doing that that's not what I'm
here to talk about what I'm here to talk
about is starting with risk management
objectives so if risk management for
application security has to do with
making software good and not bad there's
a lot that comes underneath it and I
actually have like a twenty point they
were going to get to you later in the
flight but maybe you start out with
saying hey exact here are some of our
risk management objectives that are more
detailed than we want to make good
software about software then we can
think about those risk management
objectives and we can ask questions
about how we get there and finally we
can answer those questions with data
based on whatever it is we're doing or
or may be based on what we planned to be
doing in the future and maybe we could
even use this to help us plan what we're
gonna do in the future so we're gonna do
some vocabulary measurement vs metric
what's the difference
AV Security Agency so is you know what
they do in europe you remember things
and inches so ha a measurement is a
value right it's probably like 70
degrees I had one cup of coffee this
morning which was not enough
a metric is the aggregation of one or
more measurements a lot of metrics are
going to be ratios to create a piece of
business intelligence so a metric should
answer a question a metric should
support a decision and a metric probably
has some environmental context I was
what's the point
so here's where we could talk about
metrics if you guys want is anyone
interested in sharing the types of
metrics that they used today if if there
are any number of bugs found time to
patch
percentage of systems unpatched vs
packed these are all good numbers speak
collecting and the last one is even kind
of a ratio percentage of developers went
through security training percentage
that's cool thank you harder question
maybe what types of questions and
decisions do these measurements help to
support
what we do next
how do we expand our training coverage
what are you going to give me more money
to do next year so there's lots of
different visas to doing metrics first
you have to figure out what they're
gonna be used to define what they are
and then you get some data may be put in
a dashboard and then you and then you
talk to people about it on today we're
really talking about this first part I
think it's really important to get the
first part right and to figure out how
to how do you define your metric the
rest of it there's there's all sorts of
interesting things about phase 2 and
phase three but today we're talking
about this one so this is a slide that I
put together and it's just you know a
way that people grow a knapsack a lot of
folks start out looking for and finding
defects maybe they evolved to a point
where they require that you do some
defect discovery may be certain types of
different discovery are required at
different times under different
situations you know for example high
risk apps need to have me or defect
discovery low risk apps you need to have
less maybe certain types of defects
covering me but need to happen on a
periodic basis whether that be
quarterly or year or once every three
years
you know some organizations once they're
looking for stuff
finding it requiring that you look for
stuff and find you know get to a point
where they're fixing it I think a lot of
us in this room know that those are
those are not always not always a fair
assumption to say they just cause we're
looking for problems were also fixing
them but some organizations you know
grow
along this maturity curving get to a
place where they're fixing them and then
finally you know some people are
preventing defects and this is not
necessarily like this is the way or this
is the one way but these are some ways
in which application security programs
grow and correspondingly you know I
think that metrics should change and
should grow accordingly so if you're
looking for defects you know maybe it's
interesting to say well how many of our
development teams are participating in
whatever defect discovery how much
coverage we have you know later when
you're requiring it of people you know
who is who is meeting our requirements
you know if we have requirements around
fixes you know maybe you have you know
remediation time frames that are
associated with severity of defects and
then you know you could get to things
like effectiveness we've got a
penetration testing capability how
effective is that capability was that
means for us and then finally risk
prevention metrics you know maybe we've
got like a top end bugs Louis you know
these are the top classes of bugs that
we tend to find in our code base maybe
we'll take the top one of the top two
and we're really going to target or
training you know to teach engineers you
know this is a type of bug that you need
to know about you need to know how not
introduced in Unicode if it is if you
find it you know this is how you fix it
and maybe you even do things like builds
custom to find it automatically with
tools so I don't like headers and here
but the next section of this talk I'm
gonna talk about some example certain
areas that I find people and when they
do when they're doing metrics and maybe
the user for the most part not the ideal
scenarios one of them is when something
bad happens and the first as this is an
executive question right something bad
happens in the executive wants to know
what happened
how do we stop it you know and and what
do I tell people about it you know maybe
it's in the news maybe you are regulator
has a lot of questions for us maybe
internal audit has a lot of questions
for us what do I tell people and then
and then the response is usually well
this is what we're gonna do in the
future and we're gonna do in the future
is usually some sort of minimum baseline
you know here's the standard of due care
you know maybe we're gonna penned test
all of our apps that have regulated
information in it you know once a
quarter and they were just gonna do that
and then and then there becomes sort of
this idea that maybe app seconds only
hurting the most critical absence
quarter that's it so that's one scenario
and maybe you know every quarter
executive says you know I have the
pretty graph that shows that we in fact
our pen testing of our most critical
abscess quarter you know sure but but
it's a really useful it's not really
managing risk better scenario the
scenario or two is what I call vanity
metrics so in this case folks are
counting things so for example you know
we've got eight people on our team we
spent a hundred and nine percent of this
year's budget and last week we found 12
bugs ok so I you know this app you know
we found sixty facts and on a scale of
one to five each level 23 Tabata 12 and
thats yellow colored you know a lot of
people find themselves in this situation
because they're like I wanna talk about
my program i wanna talk about it in a
quantitative manner but maybe what's
missing is some context you know and
some meaning and and
and something that could be used to
drive action in this situation gets
pretty bad which sometimes it's an app
seconds counting a lot of things I've
worked with clients who produce like 300
slide PowerPoint decks full of numbers
and they're measuring everything but
they're not really saying that much and
so without context maybe there's not
understanding on the part of the reader
or the executive that you're giving us
300 page PowerPoint doctor who has time
to read three pages PowerPoint much less
you know every quarter of a year
probably not probably it's not be read
maybe it's just being ignored and the
other thing about sort of scenarios to
an to be without contacts and sort of a
narrative to the company's some of these
numbers you know what could happen is
the executive of where you're talking to
my respond positively or they might
respond negatively how do I know the 12
defects is good thing or bad thing I I
have no idea I have no idea how to react
and I'm just going to react and then
we'll go from there
not ideal and then you know maybe this
goes on for long enough that you get to
a point where you know AB seconds
talking about stuff and it's just being
totally turned out you know I've worked
with clients who say you know we've got
metrics and where we're talking to
people about it you know we're giving it
to our executive committee or giving it
to enter on it and we'd like you to come
in and take a look at our metrics and
give us some advice you know one of the
things I like to do is go talk to
internal audit and go talk to the
Executive Committee and say so what
metrics are you getting from AB second
there like we're not gonna take a nap
circus-like we send them this report
every week it's in their email you know
but they're not reading it or maybe you
know in a not great scenario which
actually happened to my client who had
that quote on the first page
maybe they just stopped attending
meetings and they just don't show up
because I like why would I go to this
meeting I have no idea no I don't know
what they're saying it doesn't make
sense to me and then finally you know
maybe maybe if you are being effective
at doing metrics you know there's
there's an opportunity to to go to
executives and say look here's our plan
here's our progress against that plan
I'm gonna let you know if there are any
issues or any risks you know hey we
found 9 critical bugs this month that
was expected because we just rolled out
a new defect discovery capability we
consider that to be acceptable because
the bugs were found in development and
on in production and median remediation
tasks have been assigned and it looks
like all the bugs are going to be fixed
within the recommended time so we found
9 critical bugs but we're letting you
know that we have a plan and that that
was a good thing we found them in the
first place so it sort of in the
beginning of this talk I talked about
risk management risk management is about
making good software because good
software makes better business and
avoiding bad software because bad
software hurts the business and so how
do we get to more detailed than good
software good bad software bad we
thought about this a lot and so we have
like 20 or so
risk management objectives that I want
to share with you the way that we talked
about the way that I think about metrics
the way that social things about metrics
is to start with these objectives and
then to look at ok what we doing you
know against those objectives and the
news that to say we'll hear some metrics
ok so we talk about this
so some objectives and on this line
we've got six objectives so you could go
to your exact and maybe you know you
care about all these six maybe you don't
but here six that you can pick from and
talk to that that's that's more detailed
ban good software good bad software bad
so maybe you can go to your executive
and say look we are not appropriately
managing absurd risk if we are not doing
the following things and this particular
slide is all about visibility into the
portfolio because most organizations
have more than one at most organizations
have more than one piece of software and
for the abstract people you know
sometimes there is focus on like a
critical high risk god's what about all
the rest of the apps or maybe there's
just one more out but if there are apps
that were not doing anything to from a
software security perspective maybe
that's something to be concerned about
even if the thing that we do is to
evaluate that piece of software
designated as low risk and decide that
you're not going to do anything but this
says if we're gonna do risk management
then maybe we should know all the
software portfolio maybe we should know
you know and maybe that includes you
know open source software maybe we
should be able to enumerate our
applications in our databases and maybe
that includes no way world a sensitive
information is stored or process maybe
we should make sure that we know what
the appropriate security posture is for
every application maybe we should for
every ask every software asset have a
risk ranking assigned for every software
project have an impact rating assigned
for every software security defect have
a severely rating designed for everyday
tasks that have a have a classification
assigned maybe we need to be managing
risk across the entire portfolio and not
just this tiny part of our portfolio
that's the critical apps so that we can
provide a complete risk picture to
executive management
and I'm not saying that if you're not
doing this you're not doing your job
application security is this thing that
grows and matures but maybe this is
something that we can strive to cause
we're talking about a risk management
objective then then maybe we can set
that bar quite high and then put
together a plan to get there the next
set of risk management objectives have
to do with a secure software development
lifecycle so maybe every project goes
through the secure software development
lifecycle maybe we're making sure that
we're doing appropriate levels of defect
discovery and that you know appropriate
is sort of this term that allows you to
not have to do everything to everything
but you can apply various controls and a
risk-based manner you want to make sure
that your defects are documented and
that their fixed and that variances any
exceptions to the mediating the effects
are documented attract we'd like to tune
our secure a steel see so that we're not
pissing off engineering and so that
we're going as fast as engineering needs
us to go we want to move efforts left in
the secure software development
lifecycle so that we're not using our
prevention efforts to analyze the risks
associated with hundreds of medium
security defects in production you know
a lot of organizations say well we're
gonna fix the critical defects if we
have time to fix the high defects you
know but as far as medium or low
severity defects go we're not going to
get to that in 10 years there's just not
enough time you know but maybe if we are
holding ourselves to a really high bar
when we're talking about risk management
objectives then we could even think
about considering if there's like
hundreds of mediums very defects are not
doing anything about that you know she
think about that
using threatened attack intelligence to
continually improve our secure SDLC so
we've talked about this a lot like a lot
of objections to talk about
this next set has to do with policies
standards in our outreach so what sort
of expected behavior how do we talk to
people internally about what we're doing
we may not be appropriately managing the
risk if we don't have policies and
standards if we're not incorporating
every stakeholder and the software
security strategy is so maybe we're not
just talking about developers maybe
we're talking about QA folks architects
project managers business analysts you
know I T folks who were deploying the
software environments are applications
gonna sit on or not appropriately
managing our application security risk
for not reaching out to talk to
executives about it and talking to all
the rest of the stakeholders about it
maybe you know less technical for
executives more technical for everyone
else and ensuring that all stakeholders
have the appropriate level of training
and I and we when it comes to risk
management of application security you
know there's there's other things other
than the application other than the
software that we have to worry about
sometimes this offer environment making
sure that you know the IIT team whose
deploying the software environment the
my application sits on is not screwing
things up for me and also making sure
that the software vendors that I work
with you provide me with software are
not screen comes up to me and finally
you know making sure that you know if
we're really talking about risk
management
we're going beyond compliance and maybe
we even have two metrics to talk about
what we're doing so the next thing once
we need to figure out what our risk
management objectives are going to be
might be just say what we're doing today
and what we gonna do tomorrow and this
is for anyone who saw dole talked
earlier this morning
sort of 20 software security
capabilities what are some things that
you could do for a pSET
it's not just paint are saying you know
pen testing being one of i think we've
got like six or so defect discovery
methods listed here but there's other
stuff that people do a nap SEC and
here's a list of all the things we could
think of so here is where the rubber
meets the road and we talked about 20 or
so upset risk management objectives I'm
taking one of those so this one says
we're not appropriately managing apps
suck risk if we are not guiding every
software project as secure as you'll see
that the term that determines whether
the software is acceptable scare so why
is the secure as DLC you know out of
very bare minimum maybe there are two
dates on our secure SDLC you one that
says permit to build and one that says
permit to deploy maybe the permit to
build gate so you know we're going to
evaluate the risk of this particular
software outside and depending on if
it's high risk medium risk low risk you
know we're going to dictate that certain
types of controls be applied maybe more
controls for the high risk apps may be
fewer controls for Lois Capps may be
different controls may be cheaper
controls for low-risk apps and then
you've got your permit to deploy gate
that says well you know if you did some
threat modeling or some architectural
risk analysis and you identified some
flaws you know did you actually fix
those you know we want to check that
before we go live or if you found some
bugs in static analysis and you're
supposed to fix them you know we want to
make sure those pics before we go live
if you were supposed to use some secure
libraries or or adhere to some secure
quirements you want to make sure so
secure a steel see sort of a minimum
perhaps is a permit to build and a
permit to deploy checkpoint so that's
just one example of how you could do it
so given this risk management objective
of which we talked about 20
here I'm gonna share with you maybe five
or so questions asked about that risk
management objective and the data that
answers these questions hopefully
actually begins to pick paint a picture
of what's our risk situation and her
when managing that risk in a way that
more interesting than good software good
bad software bad how many what
percentage of the applications in the
portfolio have been reviewed and signed
off indicating an unacceptable level of
security because we're talking a
percentage got a ratio and there's also
ways to kind of slice and dice that data
so that you can really zeroing in on
problem areas maybe you could look at it
according to different risk rankings of
applications or maybe just one risk
ranking what about just are critical
risk applications per for various
technology stacks across different
business unit four different software
project types you know internally
developed comments you know free and
open source software so the idea being
that you've got your risk management
objective you got a question about that
risk management objective and if you're
able to gather the data to answer that
question and slice and dice then maybe
you've got something that can tell you
about what to do next
another question for this you know every
piece of software should go through as I
still see how many of the software
projects in the last 12 months have been
reviewed and signed off how many of them
haven't and then we can again
slice and dice that according to risk
ranking technologies tank business units
offer project time and hopefully zero in
on areas that we want to focus on the
future or you know get some visibility
into potentially glaring holes in our
response to her if we decided that you
know we want to live up to this risk
management objective what percentage of
software projects in the last 12 months
did not go through the security I'll see
and then slice and dice
what percentage of software projects in
the last 12 months have passed all
software security checkpoints so you
know one example of software security
checkpoints is that permit to build
permit to deploy gate but you know
there's all sorts of different kinds
what percentage of the applications have
one or more open exceptions for not
passing and as a security gate and I
think there's a las 14 today's
discussion for each security checkpoint
in the security I'll see what's the
average percentage of artifacts provided
vs expected for all the software project
last four months so the point here is
that for all of the 20 or so
risk management objectives you can come
up with a bunch of questions to ask that
are pretty specific and you know I'm not
standing appear saying these are the
questions you should ask this is Sara
Lee you know because that this might or
might not be a risk management objective
that up last year but for every
objective you can define a lot of
questions and then you can begin to
gather data to answer those questions
and that is sort of a methodology for
creating metrics that hopefully are
meaningful and that you might be able to
tell a story about because you've been
going in you can say look good software
good bad software bad how do we get to
that stage where we're getting more good
software unless bad software you know
we're going to manage the risk by
putting everything through security I'll
see how do we do that you know I'm
asking five questions about it you don't
have to ask five you guys just one and
so it goes you know and as things change
in the program so things change in the
metrics and then you just you just keep
on doing it you know every organization
is gonna have different risk management
objectives and ask different questions
about it but today when I was hoping to
resign was sort of a methodology and one
example of how you might do that we
thought there was a lot we're actually
in the process of building out a tool
all that has for each of these risk
management objectives you know sort of
all of the questions that you might ask
and the various pieces of data that you
might gather in order to answer the
questions you know if if you're looking
at one of these objectives and you're
saying yeah that's something I want to
do and then you're looking at the
questions and you're like well not
really able to answer them then maybe
that in itself is sort of marching
orders to say well how do I put the
processes in place to get the data to
answer the question to meet this risk
management objective and that's all I've
got its its 40 after the hour so we've
got 10 minutes for Q&A if folks have
anything that they want to talk about
so you know I would say that every
organization has a different risk
tolerance what kind of questions can you
ask your executives in order to figure
out how they feel about what your risk
tolerance ought to be so this list and I
think like all the slides are gonna be
provided see you guys will have this
list this list is a decent place to
start
you know and you could kind of go
through this list and say are some of
these wildly out of our reach in which
case you're probably not going to get to
them this year you know or some of them
may be there they are within our reach
and and the other way to do it would be
to say for these when I kind of call it
metrics refinements for risk ranking
protects stack for business unit per
software product type you know maybe you
choose a risk objective and you ask a
question about it but you're only
focused on Oracle Apps you know you're
only focused on this particular
technology stack so there are ways to
say it's impossible to boil the ocean
and we can't do everything it wants but
how do we start and then and then the
ways to do that would be to pick some
risk management objectives and then
decrease the scope by using it and then
i'd say you know how do you have that
risk tolerance conversation with the
executives one way that I would
recommend is you know out of these
twenty or so risk management objectives
you know you pick the three or the five
you know that you think that you care
about and that maybe your exact care
about and you say to them you care about
these things you know and and then maybe
they do maybe they don't and then but
but then you have something to start on
you know if you go into a conversation
with your executives alike so we're you
know how r scale of one to 10 we're
serious talk and you know that's that's
a hard thing for them to necessarily
respond to in a productive way but if
you take this list of twenty you know
and you pick three to five and you're
like you know those really kinda
resonate with me
resonate with my organization and then
you presented to them
you say what do you think maybe that's a
good way to start the conversation
yeah I think I think that's a good point
right so these metrics are not
predictive you know and I don't claim to
be able to tell you who's gonna win the
Super Bowl
you know similarly I don't claim to be
able to tell you what kind of incidents
going to happen tomorrow you know I
think if any of us could do that I don't
know if we'd be here today you know
maybe we'd be doing something different
because we have like a ton of money a
lot of our data so I think that's a good
point and i also think that that an
opportunity for education right if
you're executive comes to you and says
why are you able to predict my neck
security and then that's something that
you can respond and say well that's not
possible
yeah
yeah i i agree agree agree I think yeah
you know there's other industries like
insurance or financial they have all of
these like quantitative models and
they're like we know that like you know
one out of 20 drivers is gonna do this
damn thing and that's why we charge this
month for insurance I think I'm not
mature yet but I also think we're not
completely done right so there's lots of
different ways to do that and I would
actually go to our slide about various
activities you know I think a really
high level you know it's proper to say
the if you have controls in place versus
if you don't have controls in place if
you have controls in place and those
controls are good you're probably in a
better place than if you had zero
control so there's a coverage thing and
and their coverage thing you know
breaths why so you can look at this
church you could look at this page and
you could say you know I have a security
or so
SCLC with gates I don't have a satellite
I don't have metrics I don't do
portfolio manager at all you know I do
this I don't do that there's so there
are these gap analyses approaches to say
you know do I have controls coverage
another way to do it is to save maybe I
take a threat and attack intelligence
way of looking at it you know when I'm
brainstorming different ways in which I
could be attacks you know maybe I'm
looking at companies that are like my
company and I say well you know who got
attacked last weekend and how did that
happen to them and AM I am i protected
in that way so I think we're not totally
dumb about predicting if you have no
security control in place you're likely
to get attacked me and then if you have
some in place you know but the funny
flip side for us is if you're not
looking maybe you don't know so
sometimes you know we meet with clients
and and as part of Use amor or whatever
sort of interview data gathering thing
we're doing we say you know so what how
how does a software security incident
for you and they say to us we've never
had a software security and we're like
ok well maybe you don't have detective
controls in place to know that you're
being attacked because he's probably you
are so there's this funny thing where we
also don't know we don't know I'm I
don't have a good answer for you
unfortunately but I do think it's a good
question because it's a it's a really
interesting question and I think if we
could get there that'd be really cool
but we don't as an industry have the
data get are not mature yet to that
point I think I think if we wanted to
get there and maybe O wasp is a cool
platform for talking about something
like this you know maybe there's an
opportunity to say well if we are
collected the same credit metrics and we
put our data in a place you know we'd
have something so there's an
organization CIS the Center for Internet
Security and they're the ones who do as
host hardly standards and it may be like
five six years ago they tried to do that
actually they they said hey we're going
to develop you know we're gonna talk to
like seventy people who think
information security metrics are
interesting and know something about it
and we're gonna put together these like
10 or so
information security metrics and they
did and it's available you can google
the IRS consensus Metrix definitions and
there's a group of people myself
included who tried to do that and the
idea was that if we could get you know
all the organizations to gather these
metrics then maybe we can get to a point
where they were all putting them in
place and we could build these types of
data sets but no one was interested and
I think the reason I was interested with
because these 10 metrics did apply to
everyone not where they were you know
for their particular maturity or or they
were focusing on so we're just not the
area where like your new you know how
new is software how new is it that
software is used for everything you know
it's pretty well as insurance has been
around for like a really long time
financial turnaround for even longer
but there are so many interests so you
should read the fine print because
there's like all these scenarios under
which it doesn't apply but yes I bet
they didn't I bet they do I'm yeah yeah
I think it's kind of a con to be honest
this is my personal take I know it's
cool I I will stand behind my opinion
but it's my personal opinion
I think that's an excellent point I
think if you sort of you know reduce the
scope of the question you know instead
of saying like predict the next security
incident you know say well here's one
specific type of bug you know the way in
which it occurs is discreet and we can
sort of manage that and we can serve
manage the various things you know we
can we can reduce the attack surface and
so forth
I also think that in general most
application security organizations are
not mature enough to where it's the best
call to jump and try and do predictive
metrics when most likely there are not
very basic metrics such as coverage
metrics participation metrics things
like defect density things like here's
the plan are reacting on that plan are
we seeing any effectiveness from my plan
my personal opinion is that predictive
metrics are like really far-out on
maturity curve and the i've seen very
few organizations that are there
the insurance question is interesting
I'm pretty sure they have no data and
again I will stand behind I kind of
think it's a con because there are so
many loopholes I bet they look like
hardly ever pay out about they hardly
ever pay out and have a question its 350
so you can go if you want to thank you I
really appreciate you being here