cost of course the capability to Philly
is capable of doing different types of
Florence
so cool
customize this year so at all don't
customize it to do and what the tools
have capabilities you need to take a
banjo read out of the box but it may be
happy and there is going to be running
on a workstation environment where these
are different factors about my people so
all schools not also vs he has a very
long time
sure there is being tested
tested
personal doing it we're located so
house number one skill set to become
better people skills and people skills
and sometimes so these are so low that
security is not the same thing
make sure you're supposed to go to
ensure that the code is actually kind of
exciting things happen checklist for
only publish and back we may even have
somebody that is draining so you know
there's lots of this crisis John sure
there's other published works there this
is what we know now had a certain length
again this is a very much you were
talking to us back for analysis tool
tools
customize all these things come into
play and these are huge
just like you are so certain want two
things how can you be so it's going on
to agree with your continued there's a
lot of factors can really use a tool
that's going to take him two days just
came home base so some told him a set of
tools more so this is actually done
security code use as we have bad days
sometimes receiving sometimes you don't
see thanks so myself and personal to me
checklist checkers different way we're
going to see types of problems
things differently and so that's just
part of the peace
third kind of interesting start of the
messages I is another word for word for
this desire to do so
so many back to be completed this topic
types of analysis so sites all these
things
risk rating system where you can imagine
being only accessible by production
staff are well should call then you're
so even if she goes that loss so we can
use whereas I'm looking at you
I'll tell you at this point that I but
if it doesn't know how it's being so
when we talk about work online and about
so this is trying to do things like this
is all so called was easy but I think
you talked about this and not everyone
can do this and it doesn't matter that
you have a very good one of the reasons
that is exactly the case of this total
war and so don't waste time control and
focusing on a compliment you see the
same go with mister vote on some very
big fines so try to figure out with us
you can see the poorest countries there
will be no doubt guess not so much what
I was doing things as far as I know
there is no this piece of code too good
but if I point it will get better but
there is no and then tell them to you as
a person has to
I think that kinda like that so many
gallons
cool how this is playing out what's
interesting about to have so does
anything that can be created and create
this look up all involved in all that
that person internal internal we use
your responses
oh yeah people
something really special for Microsoft
is not at all when basically forays
described this as and there's a lot of
work to you so we built around us there
is deciding how it felt that I needed
quickly get it means