going into a network rollout a long
stint as a security research here most
recent websites before that and then
ended up as one of the early application
security employees at Facebook and what
are the
when I arrived at Facebook I had already
had a pretty miserable set of
experiences with responsible disclosure
and vulnerability coordination over the
course of my career before that and one
of the first things that I helped set up
a Facebook was a formalization of a
responsible disclosure program which was
just coming out and saying we're not
going to be jerks to security
researchers we want to work with you
probably would like to have a process in
place for measuring that we ran which is
responsible disclosure program for three
or four years before we kind of naively
decided to start offering bounties we
were the second web property on the
Internet to start paying cash to
researchers and it was pretty
overwhelming we feel pretty confident
going into it hadn't had too many
problems at work wrapping up we thought
we were doing our jobs pretty well we
announced cash bounties under the night
before death kind Friday and receive
more vulnerabilities in the next 48
hours then the teams all of our tooling
in internal been tested found over the
last year we stayed very busy with a
very humbling experience but it started
thinking a lot about how we
operationalize are responsible
disclosure program and then later the
bug bounty program fast forward a few
years from that and I founded and now
run the product engineering teams for a
company called hacker one which as the
top of this talk to give a brief
interview of what hacker when does and
how some of the metrics are talking
about the day work were collected our
core use case after one is to enable a
security yet we call this vulnerability
coordination and hacker one at its core
is availability coordination platform
there's a lot of different names for
this in the industry you just heard me
using responsible disclosure we called
the program at at Facebook I'm still a
little partial that term even though
there
very good reasons not to use emotionally
labeled descriptors for what we're
talking about here or coming here called
vulnerabilities Gordon coordination
school year but we simply refer to it as
security at this is as simple as setting
up security at your company dot com and
having a clear defined process for
researchers to contact you with pencil
vulnerabilities identified we hold about
500 of these ongoing programs now at
this point
little over two thousand individual
hackers have disclosed vulnerabilities
to our customers through this process
and there's been over 17,000 of this
unique vulnerabilities identified in
those 500 companies connected into this
I need to do a little bit of a caveat
here in this is a point that I like to
hit on pretty regularly we are simply a
platform our customers do not grant
access to their vulnerability
information
none of what we look at and analyzes
content were strictly looking at
transaction data here the state to bug
reports and helping measure how that
relates gets everything else the
programs that are being run on how can
one are being run by the customers and
companies that offer those programs it's
a direct relationship with with the
researchers and finally we're coming up
in about six million dollars in bounties
paid by our customers back to the
security research community and it's
important to note that a bug bounty is
optional and discretionary not all of
our customers do it a huge chunk of them
do not and it's helpful to think about
why those companies do or do not choose
to offer incentives in particular areas
which brings us to the topic to talk
about today is the question that I hope
you have a little bit easier time
answering at at the end of this I want
to give it a little bit about the
audience who I think this would be more
useful to specifically talking to folks
who are running some type of product or
service that is externally accessible
over the Internet or in some ways
physical possession the areas of your
security infrastructure that are not
internet accessible or
directly exposed to the outside are
probably not if you're not responsible
for any infrastructure like that you
probably aren't asking yourself this
question
additionally if you're already running
about money program neither to answer
this question and you're probably not
going to get a lot of talk sorry but
that there's a lot more than we can talk
about about but many programs I would
assume here that people are generally
familiar with the concept and we're
going to specifically focus on just that
initial question of do I offer
incentives in this particular area
yesterday and we're defining about here
as a monetary incentive offered in
exchange for mobility report there are a
number of different ways you can get an
answer his question there is no simple
one surefire path of this not all
technology stacks are created equal
this is not one size fits all as a
little bit of analysis then used to go
into whether or not this makes sense and
it's a little bit subjective at the end
of it but there's two methods that I
found work the best there's other ones
that we can talk about them know that
I'm talking about just these two the
first one is look at the data that's
coming out of your security program
hopefully you've received the
vulnerability apart from somebody in the
past and what that process looks like
you should be measuring how that is
going and you will learn a tremendous
amount from that it's kind of nice thats
Marcus warmed us up with metrics and
stats this morning because I'm going to
be reiterating that this the best way to
answer the question is to get a very
tight control over the metric and snacks
that are being generated by your
security program particularly those
vulnerabilities are coming from the
outside one of the first dimensions that
is critical for all of us to pay
attention to is around vulnerabilities
there is a lot of ways to slice this we
can talk a little bit later about how
hacker once licenses for the customers
that are there but you don't need a
platform like that to be able to start
answering this question for yourself
it's important to start measuring the
total number of vulnerabilities that are
coming in particular source we're gonna
just be talking about those external
vulnerabilities here but it was found
that the outside but your team and then
breaking them down by type
severity is equally relevant and for
your particular area you will know your
application far better than that I ever
will perform well and there's going to
be additional metrics here that will
point towards whether or not the overall
health of your own abilities are looking
and the important thing to ask when
you're asking so should you bernie is is
this trending down you look at your own
abilities for a period previous period
of time for a particular application or
service a specific product or service
and it's going up if you open up your
polish colors dashboard every month and
you look at these quarter and there's
more and more red reasonable time you do
not want a bounty program yet for that
you need in STL and a lot more
investment in your SQL before you're
ready to start looking at a product or
service hopefully not everything in your
environment looks like this there's
going to be areas that are better off in
Warsaw and abounding is not one size
fits all across the organization but you
want to try to narrow it down to those
specific areas where your
vulnerabilities have trending down
you're looking for places where all your
existing security tooling and automation
and investment in the past has started
to produce diminishing returns you had
amazing results from a penetration tests
the first time you run one ten years ago
and you're looking at in the past I'm
and it started to turn down a bit to the
point where you're you're not running
them as aggressively in that particular
area
secondly we're talking about external
vulnerability reports that the next
dimension that we like to pay attention
to his attackers a security researchers
lenders the outside wherever it is have
some metric of how many vulnerabilities
have been reported to us or we learned
about through somebody that was another
payrolls rose another set of most
importantly tracking just the total
number the total number of new
individuals for purple color time period
if you look at the how many times we
contact for the very first time by an
individual per quarter
most importantly the number of repeat
hackers that are coming back this is the
sole metric that mr starr said I'm src
optimize their process for in measuring
whether or not the AM SOC security
was effective they wanted to pay
attention to how many one hit wonders
how many times it somebody send us a
vulnerability and then disappear never
be heard from again and by focusing on
that one single metric and optimizing
for that they made tremendous strides in
the AM src and started to identify areas
where they need to improve upon their
their overall process but should you ask
yourself that question you're looking
for
metrics here that are trending down you
want to have heard from less hackers
this quarter when you heard from last
quarter you want to particularly pay
attention to the ones that are reporting
high critical vulnerabilities if you
happen to have a product or service
where you are getting a consistent
regular number of hiring critical
vulnerabilities from the researchers
without giving them any type of
incentives it's probably not an ideal
candidate for let's go back to that area
and again we're looking for particular
products and services not necessarily
the entire third and we're talking about
there's two parties involved here you
need to have a very good handle on what
your response efficiency looks like this
is gonna be defined differently at every
single organization and hopefully you
already have some type of response
measure how long does it take us to fix
ex the one that we pay attention to it
after one are the mean time to respond
to me time to triage and the mean time
to resolve the incident is a very
subjective area there's no clean answer
for what this should look like for
everybody but you should ask yourself
are you happy with these metrics if you
look at them and you're like a pretty
good about that one
do not feel good about that one one way
to think about that is how many of those
vulnerabilities took longer than 10 days
to resolve and and is going to be
different for every single product line
there are products we're perfectly
reasonable value for and is a hundred
and eighty days and there are product
lines were reasonable value for N is 18
hours and you don't know the difference
in to you have started to measure your
baseline trying to get over time
are paying attention to how long should
it take us to resolve here and the
litmus test that I like to use for this
is if you said an internal SLA for it we
want to resolve all vulnerabilities in
acts in an hours would you be
comfortable talking about it publicly is
it would be proud about it would feel
good would it be something that you'd be
comfortable talking about it not
necessarily that you have to it's just
that's the frame of mind that I like to
get in when trying to assess is it do we
have a responsibility here that were
happy with the way we purchased one is
based on that realization that this
isn't one size fits all there are many
different types of products and services
out there that come from a number of
different circumstances that we can't
possibly come from our mistakes we
devise a success index that measures key
aspects of security a performance across
a number of different mentions but most
importantly the technique that we use
benchmarks trends here against all the
other organizations on on the platform
so we're not trying to answer this why
is this a good metric for you you're the
only person who can answer that question
will certainly show you their all the
raw data and encourage you to click the
raw data but the one that we highlight
the most is how does this compare to
other organizations that look like you
to publicly available data or get it to
develop on the platform is one of the
most objective ways of identifying
whether or not a particular network it's
good for training in the right direction
is by looking around at appears in
working with industry best practices are
there are six distinct but pretty
tightly connected to mention that we are
monitoring pay attention to here we've
we've touched on three of them and some
of the input that you could use in your
own program to start collecting similar
dimensions but the first one you need to
understand your vulnerabilities going up
are they going down in what areas of the
coming up are going down we break out
into two dimensions the first one its
breath just the number of the range of
hackers and particularly the range of
skills
that your that you're attracting if
you've got a large number of hackers if
those hackers are only reporting
bilities you do not have a great actor
breath and we can talk a little more
about what that means in a second but
we're trying to capture here do you have
a diverse skill set across across the
external factors that you have a good
looking after death this answers the
MSRTC question of how many one hit
wonders do we have how many people are
sending us one vulnerability to never be
heard from again is that a good thing or
bad thing
are they not coming back because there
simply are no more vulnerabilities or
this was exhausted their skill set or
they were unhappy about something in the
process and decided that it wasn't
positive experience for them or was it
worth their time or whatever it was a
range of things that goes into here but
this is something that we encourage our
customers pay attention to because
repeat hackers get far more effective
over time and we see the most successful
programs that we have do have a loyal
set of security researchers that they
hear from our regular kids and
responsibility in this again everyone
has different places like to stick to
hear differing definitions of equality
are but it's something that you should
at least be paying very close attention
to that the you can know if it's getting
better or worse and how to important but
they still want to talk about today when
his underwear competitiveness how
competitive is your bounty assuming you
already answered this question and the
second one to signal ratio there's a
number of ways that we visualize this
this is a lot that Marcus said that
anyone who shows you a pie chart is
lying to you and I'm lying to you right
now even those in a pie chart it's a
it's a spider charged with this is a
point-in-time snapshot of the six
different dimensions plotted against the
average enterprise which is the the red
box in the middle of the blue box is the
example program they were talking about
here this is a real an itemized live
program from her one and what to really
make the most of this you to try this
every time you know what they look like
last month in the month before before
our example we're taking a point
sidesteps I'm trying to answer the
question should I offer about it
here if you break this down into the
individual dimensions that we're looking
at on the vulnerability 6 I'd
about average you look at the average
enterprise from their external finders
they getting about that many
vulnerabilities coming in normalized
across the across the entire dataset
in a weighted average if you look at the
researcher breath they're also doing
quite well they're getting a range of
researchers a larger number of them then
they're in the industry average and
they're getting a diverse set of skills
coming out of here meaning there is a
multiple backgrounds and skill sets and
different creative use on the problem
being lovers and finally the
responsibility is is above industry is
doing much better here than their peers
are so if we don't take a step back in
and capture this we do see that there's
a massive chunk missing on their
underwear competitive side and I don't
mean that as a bad thing if we they're
just not offering any type of financial
incentive for the reporting of a
security vulnerability now but they're
clearly doing something right in that
they're getting above average response
is on every other metric so we ask
ourselves the question should this
organization or there is this product
offer but many program the time to meet
this need not like there's there's still
room for improvement you could get up to
a 10 on vulnerabilities found but if
you're still getting vulnerabilities for
free and you're getting a wide range of
researchers and the repeat customers
viewer value in offering a bounty is not
going to be as strong as it could be and
there are probably other investments in
your in your STL or your team or your
security program that are gonna be a
better return than an offering about it
but all of the starts with collecting
this in getting a sense of how do you
feel about response efficiency how
mental abilities trending and how many
external researchers in my engagement
with and ideally you can use some type
of benchmarking I but even if you don't
have the benchmarking capability you can
answer this and assess whether or not
you relatively happy about it
particularly by looking at how this is
twenty if you pay attention to this over
time you can get a very good sign
are we getting more finders or fewer
fighters than we did in the past and it
helps to answer that we take a second
example here is another live program and
one that is a program know no boundaries
offered yet but it's right around
average it's not terrible you still
getting vulnerabilities from the outside
to identify and responsibly disclosed to
the to the scheme but if you look at the
researcher breath there's not a not a
great distribution here the relatively
small number of fighters with a finite
set of skills and they're not fully
attracting the diversity of backgrounds
and experience and expertise that would
show the most value in these programs
and help get that one critically on the
good and they're very responsive program
they're responding quickly resolving
issues quickly and the response
efficiency looks pretty good
pose the same question again probably
spoil at this point for bounding here
starts to look a little bit better
you're feeling good about your response
time you're not engaging hardly a large
large number researchers you have some
amount of emphasis on upward movement on
both the depth and the vulnerabilities
fix and this is a perfect candidate for
offering bounties will probably drive
those are the three metrics higher it's
a little more nuanced than than that but
you can look at something like this and
say if we offered bounties we are
probably going to get significantly
better than we were getting before and
there's a really interesting topic of
conversation I'm going to not spend
eternity in today is how come some
organizations and the plague this and
some end up like this there's a range of
factors that go into that both from the
complexity of the challenge presented
the amount of credibility that they get
the response efficiency how respectful
you are to them how sexy it is two to
hack your particular product and that's
just the reality is that not everything
is created equal and some organizations
have to be any sooner
others simply because they're not
getting that extra attention that some
companies just get rather naturally
about trying to understand that is those
the first staged you may be looking
around in a problem with number one and
if you are gonna have a problem with the
only people have a clear channel for a
security researcher to send availability
report to them I've got a vulnerability
report and they descended that company
there's an obvious way to do it
usually don't get that many coming up
with got some advanced folks in the room
here and so if you're not already doing
that I would have a biased answer to you
and to say before you start asking
yourself the question do we found me or
do we not been any focus on asking the
question how come we just don't have the
security at inbox that we monitor and a
process for reporting vulnerabilities to
us is anyone wanna volunteering answers
to why they don't do that yet
Internet access you have internet
accessible product or service and no way
for viability be reported
you don't know what the response time is
going to look like even if you're not
offering cash incentives you going to
get something from the outside and
measuring that to start with his kind of
stuff but you're not even noon yet
another one unless you have this yet you
you need to understand your metrics you
need to know what is coming into your
program and what people are finding in
order to do it one of the big policies
that I worry about I'm a huge proponent
of a response or disclosure is something
that we have been getting for for a long
time and there is a big fallacy that if
no ones reported vulnerability to us or
we don't get that many there's just
nobody finding them and there's none of
them out there
the reality is that if you do not have a
clear process for reporting it there is
a huge amount of anxiety in the mind of
the individual before they go to submit
it to you are they going to sue me am i
sending it to the right place and by
using the right process am I doing
something wrong is this worth my time
and the answer unequivocally if you
haven't said here's where you send
security vulnerability reports is a very
very painful experience for the
researcher and they are far more likely
to just sit on that vulnerability and do
nothing
regardless of how they found it this
isn't about giving permission to hack
stuff or asking people to repentance
your service for free just no questions
asked if you found a vulnerability where
does it go and if you haven't answered
that question yet in your organization I
would state that it's a pretty heavy
prerequisites answering the question of
should you offer about me or not
deputy engineer in that the industry is
currently in a pretty sad state we get
this question from researchers at the
time like hey I use this product I was
signing up as I normally do on a putback
tick in my name and I think I just found
remote code execution I mailed their
customer success team I've mailed their
support team I sent there's CEO a diem
and like no one's responding to me what
should I do with this thing and it's
it's frustrating to me to hear something
like that like not just having anxiety
about what they do with that
that one of the things we launch the
summer was a community resources for
contacting security teams is a place
where research go time domain name and
if there is an established process for
disclosing a security vulnerability
it'll come up and show you like go to
this email address go fill out this web
form
here's what they want you to do before
they submit it here is what their legal
team says about vulnerabilities that you
might have found and I would encourage
you to think about what's stopping you
from getting a security out before you
start answering the question around
getting about me if you're in the case
of you can't use method number one and I
i hit on this little more because it is
it is kind of shocking to me the state
of the internet is in right now we did a
survey of the Forbes Global 2000 over
the summer hiring people using
Mechanical Turk using multiple
consulting firms trying to answer the
question if you had a vulnerability in
this domain could you find a place to
send it to this is from the Help Center
we reset the press teams we kind of
security addresses and just focusing on
the Forbes 100 it is it said there are
only 13 companies of the largest hundred
companies in the world if you found a
vulnerability and today they would have
told you what to do it I'm actually on a
happier note the slides a little bit
outdated there's no fourteen companies
in the center because General Motors
launched a security at program a few
expect we're down to 86% not having a
disclosure program at the time but this
is this is a frustrating to me
personally from someone who has really
been on some undesirable experiences in
in responsible disclosure and I i think
we need to have a stronger emphasis on
fixing this before we get hung up on the
should be down stuff yeah
yeah it's it's a slice the directory
it's a wiki style in with your account
can edit it there's an audit trail we
asked researchers 22 populated and keep
it up-to-date and there's a set of
operators that do it so that the domain
name is this even there yet it's
probably already there if not it's it's
with you create an account and created
or just email us for the moderators know
they're created for you if it's not a
real estate and you have a public
contacted us and so if we expect I am a
little more in that it is it's kind of
sad that people find vulnerabilities
today and don't know if they're going to
get sued or not as a as a result of
anything we should worry about sixty met
i plead with a relatively emotion like
every once in a while then I like to
lately and leaned on her friends at the
FTC you with a bit more of abrasive
approach to it the FTC is one of the few
organizations that is actually charged
with regulating security and enforcing
people who have had irresponsible
security practices they released a
summary in
again in the in the summer last year
around analysis of all of the enforcers
they've done over the last decade and
the common trends across them and one of
the ones at the top of their list is the
lack of an efficient process to receive
an address on ability reports and I
would like to dive into the challenges
that are here but I would start with
trying to answer this before the
question
yeah this is about ways in to report
yes sorry that it's kind of a funny
memory that whether you got a response
to disclose your program or security yet
in this graph we're still calling that a
the disclosure program it's being
disclosed to the company it's not public
disclosure it's the researchers it goes
into the company that made have a public
disclosure policy not to tell everybody
that no no judgment on that this is
purely disclosure between the researcher
and the security team and for many of
these there is no valid on them like
number 12 of their right like that's not
a public disclosure program in in the
sense that there's notices for
everything that goes out there with
their subsets of products in there that
you have seized a sign in to have public
disclosure requirements with the
majority of the vulnerabilities
disclosed don't have any type of public
disclosure component to it whatsoever to
this is simply the reporting process and
you should use different security yet
programs but that turns a little even
less clear
get a Forbes 100 rank list you have to
plug in what it's meant to be not a
listing of everything out there it's
meant to be a search for a researcher it
I already have a vulnerability in this
domain and I am trying to figure out
what to do with it is the specific use
cases the directory choices so it's a
certain point it looks like this it's
meant to put into domain name and/or a
company name and find the result for it
like published the dataset is no real
American people could scrape it really
should just publish it in a
machine-readable format for people to do
that
oh yeah there's this other list out
there that tackle that problem of who
pays money for vulnerabilities we don't
do that through the director me that
thinks that democrats alright I'm done
harping on on the lack of security at
addresses on the internet sorry sir but
the ten-cent
the second method if you do not have a
security program and you do not hearing
from researchers regularly is an invite
only program this is not publishing a
public method because your organization
has encountered fortunes are robots are
unanswered questions around how do you
run a security at program and so you can
start to gather data in a limited
invitation only but it's a pretty low
risk method for gathering data there is
no bugs that come in there's no
boundaries to pay because of the
unknowns around your response time of
all abilities
this is easily pause in a boarded you
have take control over volume meaning
you can say with a high degree of
accuracy how many vulnerability reports
you're going to get to ensure that
you're not taxing any metrics to you
haven't defined yet and the goal coming
out of this is to assess the readiness
of your STL for abounding in a
particular product or service so let me
give you an example scenario of what
that
or Oracle is not but they are in the
directory they have a security program
there are five hundred programs that are
being run on Hacker 1 I'm there is a
much larger number of security at
addresses such as Oracle which are being
run outside of actor and that that would
be the case
hypothetically
afterwards I'll try to pick up a better
so this this starts by setting aside a
small budget similar to what you would
budget for a penetration test and a
scoping of one of your more secure
applications on your most secure
applications you should be looking at
those metrics that we talked about in
the top three dimensions of where my
getting vulnerabilities where am I
getting reports and where do I have
confidence in my response efficiency and
target that don't use a bug bounty to
target this horrible area of your
committee you don't wanna touch this
isn't about outsourcing your security
this is about finding the most secure
applications that you have in trying to
answer the question is this is my STL
here ready for external incentives and
we recommend starting very slow with
these you can do this through a platform
pretty clearly or if you have extra
researchers have said in the past you
can do this manually on your own invite
five to 10 of them just a small number
of people that you know is is the
recommended range that we start with and
we find that other these eighty percent
of our customers who run these programs
find a new critical security
vulnerability in the next 24 hours and
practically all of them find a new one
within three days that's a pretty
surprising I wanted to always use the
three day one everybody finds a critical
vulnerability in three days and
marketing people relate no one's gonna
believe you it's it's a lie you can't
say can say 99% you gotta get to go with
the eighty percent number so we're
sticking with 80% in the in the first
day these programs are incredibly
effective at identifying stuff that the
rest of your STL completely missed
there's been nobody out here is launched
a program that didn't find something
yeah
for these invitation-only wondered about
350 that's correct
but to really take a look at this you're
gonna want to benchmark your deviation
from the key metrics that arise in this
program in that that first time period
meaning you don't need to run these for
very long
the goal isn't to run it for a long
period of time it's the start measuring
what are you getting in a short period
of time to assess whether or not you
want to continue the program scale back
the program wrap up the program canceled
entirely and invest in some additional
areas that came out of it for example of
those 350 and that the hackers that
participate we see that on average each
actor is going to find 2.7
vulnerabilities across this process
dataset if you're running this and
you've invaded fight hackers and each of
them found five vulnerabilities you
probably don't want to invite the next
five hackers right away it's time to go
back and recesses metrics and look at
why were so many found from external
finders instead of all our internal too
willing to start with so take give you a
sense of what this looks like
externally again we recommend that
people start very small and they're in
their first month and invite just five
to ten we find that overall in the first
month of the 350 programs we see 22.6
researchers invited so what this is is
cohort in that first batch of the 22
researchers and just saying what if you
did nothing just invited them and let it
run for six months what is going to
happen with the initial incentives set
and over the six-month time so on the on
the right we've got the vulnerability
graph again we said you see 2.7
vulnerabilities per researcher even
though you invited 22 hackers to
participate you only get submissions
ballots emissions from 12 of them in the
first month in between all of them it's
about 33 vulnerabilities that come in in
those first in his first 30 days if we
look at month to this drops off
dramatically if you don't change
anything about how you're engaging and
you just stick with that first 22
researchers and the same amount that you
started with it drops off pretty quickly
we see a little bit of a spike in month
for because we find that for the first
of all watching these programs
their response time for
a resolution is usually somewhere
between 60 and 90 days which means that
in the third month you start seeing more
of those reports is often more the
county's paid out which is a trigger
point for that said I researchers to
come back and participate in the program
again or to follow up on things that
they found a workaround for and so you
see a little bit of a spike just because
you're naturally resolving stuff that
comes out this but by the time you get
six months in you are on that initial
set of 22 researchers that you invited
to the program you're only seeing
submissions from about four of them and
they are not finding as much anymore you
have started to exhaust the attention
span or the expertise disorder
researchers and there's a few of these
in here that you want to do engage with
but you are feeling relatively good
about using this initial cohort to
answer to gather enough data to answer
the question of the racial good about
the vulnerabilities are being found here
doing so good about my response time and
my finding the right of hackers and I
want to engage with normal if you're
running one of these programs in in life
you can have multiple these points
introduced at each set like you gonna
run with the first 22 and then by months
three you might decide if you look good
you invite another batch of researchers
and this trendline kicks off again but
what you're looking for here is that
your land line of what you're finding is
below the average that you would expect
and well within your threshold for
response efficiency so if you invite
again those five hackers and they each
fined 50 abilities your blue lines will
be much higher and there's work to do
before you invite more researchers and
expand the scope of this program
aggressively is going to be a very messy
side that I wanted to put it on your
people to look at this is that same
graph but with the main things that we
track going into it you running
additionally program invite 22 hackers
this is what it tends to look like on
average with a pretty way deviation for
customers out there by the end of the
six months you've found 6276 new
vulnerabilities and paid around $37,000
in
vulnerabilities downey's again these
trends pretty heavily if you're someone
who was only getting one submission per
hacker you're probably going to have a
higher amount here and lower bound the
average but just a sample cohurt this
gives you a pretty good idea of what you
should expect running a very small
Invitational in bodybuilding program
over the course of six months and from
this you should be able to start to
answer what areas do we want ongoing
incentives and said this is what you
want to success in to start looking like
as time goes on
normally we don't share these with
attribution but David were carefully
tweeted about it and I get to be able to
make it to use it in in slide decks but
right games does run a public security
yet they have for for many years they
accept report from external researchers
they go through this process of inviting
people in certain measuring how this how
this comes about and you see their
responsibilities right around average
but a very competitive reward pretty
loyal set of researcher participation
and has a ceiling that large number of
vulnerabilities found in the past so we
wrap this thing up this all starts with
your your SEO
found your not to bonnie is answered by
looking at your ass yeah I view bounty
programs as the ultimate measurement of
whether or not you're ICL is effective
in the ways you expected to be effective
it really helps you benchmark whether
not everything else you're doing is
working if you are relying on bug bounty
programs as a source of vulnerabilities
that should have been caught by known
systems or tooling in your STL it's not
effective use of researcher time you
want to leverage is defined as scarce
vulnerabilities not is more
cost-effective way of finding the stuff
that should be solved through frameworks
and you want to leverage stuff coming
out of this in a more people so measure
was coming into your to your security at
don't serve offering incentives right
away
want to track everything coming out of
here is kind of ridiculous to say so
much but nobody really pays a huge
amount attention to the metrics coming
out of their their security added a few
examples of companies to do this well
but if you're not monitoring that you
have a very hard time answering anything
else coming out of this and if you find
a bunch of stuff to go work on for
bigger product and service after you
measure this it's not time for bounty
program that back into your ass yet
we're all about finding stuff that is
going to improve your SEO process but as
you repeat the cycle you're eventually
going to start finding things where it's
like for this particular area were only
hitting diminishing returns we are not
getting everything we want our security
tool and it's time for additional
testing on it that we're going to
provide the most effective it is that
final my defense of everything else on
the outside and I want to find more
inputs back into my style I want to know
what I miss and I need humans to go look
for that on a ongoing recurring basis so
I've got three
based on what it looks like there are a
number of companies that will launch but
many programs because their security
comes person said hey other people are
doing this we should go do this to that
is a very bad answer to the bug bounty
of this or not I would exclusively use
how effective your STL is as the
measurement to should we found here and
so the question is if you run about
granny program before your STL is ready
for it it will probably look bad if you
are not running a bounty program I don't
think it particularly says anything
strange about your application or the
discrete about what I would focus on is
even if you haven't asked anybody yet
are your customers finding
vulnerabilities in the security product
are researchers finding it have any
other been found from the outside and
and how does that process tieback India
India SEO
yeah so the question is largely if you
run one of these ppl disclosed stuff
that doesn't make us look bad and how do
we get more control over it and you're
touching on a very pretty nuanced point
is that it's usually not framed in the
company's bests doesn't paint the
company the best point of view we have
much longer discussion around however
one deals with this but the answer on
our platform is we have a very
customizable defined workflow for how
public disclosure happens it is an
explicit request the researcher does to
say I want to publicly disclose this
here's the day that i'm gonna publicly
disclosed and the customer configures
what their disclosure policy asst some
customers say there's no public
disclosure here for this category issues
there's there's no disclosure date for
it and they define that ahead of time in
the policy in force it through other
customers say we want ninety days head
up heads up so the research when they go
to disclose its ninety days out and if
they wanna shorter they specifically
request an exemption through the
workflow in the product the public
messaging of that is a joint
communication between the researcher and
the individual there's toiling in intact
or 12 cents or the response to that the
timeline to just the activities that
occurred to provide an agreed-upon
summary is usually told with one voice
or at least both sides of the story in
the same thread in conversation if you
look through a bunch of the disclosures
on one you'll always see someone so
requested to publicly disclose this
report and the response team agreed to
publicly disclose this this report and
that doesn't necessarily mean the entire
email thread is is disclosed that's one
of the defaults other times you just see
the disclosure timeline and advisory
posted up top particularly for those of
the story there is you want to have
control over your disclosure process if
you're relying upon if you haven't
disclosed described as defined in
disclosure prob policy you're not going
to have any control of your process and
I would start with that first and then
in the ideal case is a blatant sales
pitch use a platform that has a codified
workflow
004 disclosure so that it doesn't go
wrong and if somebody does do something
like just published a blog post without
giving you a heads up then it's a clear
violation of your your policy that I was
looking more broadly about the
disclosure in general but yes doing it
out of band disclosure that does not
adhere to your policy with certainly
invalidate them from the bounty but it's
not really the hammer this out simply
doing that we've we've done this over
10,000 vulnerabilities we see a public
disclosure requested about one out of
every 35 or so and we have not had a row
disclosure yet on the platform where
someone was just like I'm not giving you
any heads up I'm just disclosing this it
is a concern that we would move people
from the platform that did that and if
you are operating in good faith and
saying here's our user policy that we'd
like you to follow for disclosure it
goes right farmer often that it goes
right to go wrong at one point in time
but the road disclosures when there's a
clearly defined workflow for it is
pretty rare and that were closed usually
pretty well by the researcher yeah
and industry average is misleading it is
a beautiful way to lie with statistics
you need to look at
averages across product lines what they
expected their SDA SCL
isolate and I would start with defining
what you think the expectation should be
for that product if you think it's
ninety days and you have the 90th
percentile is a hundred eighty days you
should communicate to those people that
we expect to take 280 days here and if
that admission is is embarrassing to to
you or not but you're happy with start
holding the team's accountable to that
and use it as a tool for getting better
response time there and you think you'll
find out that as long as you communicate
with the expectations are is a much
stronger strategy then whether or not
you conform to an industry average or an
industry best practice and because it is
going to be so dramatically different
for every single product we have
customers that have automobiles on the
street that have disclosure timelines
associated with them and the disclosure
timeline resolution time for that is
very different from how long does it
take to fix anybody else
it depends so we just a few weeks ago
and what the average is look like that
to you afterwards that the short answer
is on average across the entire platform
it's held pretty average about $500 per
vulnerability over the last two years
but the top programs on the platform if
you look at the ones that have success
index it looks more like this there
consistently trending up and it's
currently above $1,100 average per
vulnerability but the total count of all
abilities to significantly down from
when they started and that should be the
goal you should be looking for the total
number of vulnerabilities in finding is
going down and the total amount that i'm
paying for them are it amounted to an
individual basis is going up I don't
think everybody