my fellow colleagues modelers they're
all there's only four of us who've
written books about this and you know
you can decide which ones you think are
are decent but it's not a huge body of
literature I think maybe six people have
actually read my book and you know I'm
sorry we can do that after ok I'm gonna
get started with some of the stuff but
will give you know will let people
filter in as as they want let's get
started so this is a little bit about me
why you should listen to me or not and
I'm not gonna read all this stuff but
I've been around for a while for about
30 years making trouble and my feeling
about this is blah blah blah show me the
money let's see you can decide after
this presentation whether whether some
of these things you know where they're
not a couple of things I have to tell
you in order to speak and follow my own
policies that I work for Intel otherwise
they shoot me and but this is materials
and other properties in Delhi started
long before I work work for them and
it's my material but feel free to use it
really
the idea here is to help people get
better at this thing we need to do
called threat modeling or secure design
of which threat modeling is a piece and
I'll explain that a bit so this little
mnemonic that I use or pedagogy is not a
hard piece of theoretical or otherwise
it's not really a method to go talk to
his name I just saw Tony UV he has a
real method and I do not I have a
pedagogy because I've taught this to
hundreds of people literally by now
absolutely hundreds and so it's just
another manic or a pedagogy ok so here's
some expectations from this session if
you're entirely new threat modeling at
least you'll understand what it is and
you can get started
that's the point for learners were gonna
dig deeper and maybe get some more
skills for your experts maybe you'll get
some tricks and get out and teach threat
modeling we really need people to not
just do it but teach it is we are need
people who were involved in software
security need to be working on design
and I'm going to make some points but
that so let's start with the
participatory part of this just shout
out or raise your hand and all columns
what do you get out of this set of boxes
and arrows anything at all in fact let
me ask you this has have any of you ever
gone into Architecture Review and seen
an architecture that looked like that
few people right and what did you do
with it I mean literally there's not
much there right
pretty scary about this one
do we know a little more
well we know there's some kind of thing
someone thinks is a firewall we know
there's a back in and something that we
think of as a user
at least that's something we don't have
some data flow right because the thing
about threat modeling is that it's about
it's about understanding and
understanding in a certain way and so
this doesn't this this is actually a
real architecture somebody actually gave
to me which you know I couldn't do
anything with so let me set the problem
the central problem we're working on
here we have a design problem in
software security we have to build
appropriate security how do we get there
let me make some point here everybody
know about the GPAC anybody not know do
but the GPAC ok well my friend Chris
valla second someone else got onto the
entertainment system and then started
working with the brakes in the ignition
on the car while it was going down the
road so so is that a coding problem I'm
willing to bet that that Jeep Wrangler
met them israel coding standards and got
all of the other stuff that it passed
all of its stuff that it needed to why
did this get out there because they did
not talk about secure designed this is a
design problem you don't put and
entertainment system open to the world
on a life-or-death bus that's a design
problem not a coding problem we clear
about that
here's another one you don't get a
universal password that's going to go
out everywhere in the field and
thousands and thousands of things that
are designed problems no coding problem
and then we'll go to this one different
kind of design problem and that's why I
want to put this up here this is a
different kind of design problem
everyone knows what the target hack
right right they lost forty percent of
their business from this so highly
impactful and this is a situation where
r one vendor had access to the entire
network that's a system-level design
problem it's not a coding problem that
we made any coding mistakes they have to
mean maybe there was something in the
HVAC vendor that got them in I don't
know about that but the fact that they
had all this access is the design
problem in fact whose company uses the
same bpm profile for for everything for
everyone when they get in
vendors whoever no no hold up your hands
will break your NDA's but just think
about that right
don't hold up your hands we don't want
to see those hands thanks because she
will break you violate your NDA's with
that alright here's a start tellin I
worked on this Christophe is here who
worked on this thirteen architects two
and a half months a small book I don't
think I Tripoli is everything you like
but nevertheless it's a start
if you're if you're wondering what we're
talking about in terms of secure
designed this is a start it's Creative
Commons so I stick the same here because
I encourage you to download it and read
it we have a design problem now I wanna
I wanna switch gears here a little bit
and say that the point is you gotta get
the right requirements
how do you get those how do you get the
requirements in so that its people are
designing and architecting software to
come up with the right security stuff
the authentication system the way to
handle the credential as in the Juniper
problem or in the sense of thinking
about about VPN profiles for instance to
get the right structure of different
kinds of access how do you do that well
one thing you gotta remember as we go
through this is just a little tip the
early requirements get the worm so to
speak because there's a mindshare thing
that happens over time when the security
person comes in and does the analysis
after the thing is darn near built what
happens everybody has mind
air and it seems like an interjection it
seems like an insult sometimes so when
you can get in there early so there's a
timing part of this but we're not going
to delve into I do delve into a little
bit in core software security which is
the book previous to my last one but
we're we're not gonna we're not going to
develop delve into this much but I
wanted to make the point so you're on
top of this earlier is better but too
early you can only do so much so there's
a nicely balanced there that's an
experience thing and just you know talk
to me later write me give you a bunch of
links to contact me with we're not going
to go into this much I just want to
mention it now let's take a look at this
slide here is this this bear some
thinking architecture the reason we use
architecture and call it architecture to
tool for managing complexity complex
systems and we you know a couple of
architectures where you see a lot more
complex systems are too much when it's
too much to hold in your head you know
beyond help hello world then you start
playing with a larger blocks that say
okay I'll group all this stuff together
and I'll group all that stuff together
and then I can sort of look at it and
understand the structure of the thing
okay so it's our tool that's important
threat modeling is the tool for secure
design it needs an architecture it needs
to understand structure and as we will
see you look at things in different ways
so you know architecture is our our
thing for understanding complexity and
also for playing with change what if we
do something this way we can take the
blocks and move around you can move the
arrows around and say ok what does that
mean how does that work and so it's both
a tool for managing complexity for
understanding it and a tool for playing
with change potential change threat
modeling requires architecture you have
to understand the structure of a thing
while at the same time understanding it
from the point of the attacker
ok let's move on modeling I like to say
is applied security architecture so few
security architect where the rubber
meets the road where you apply all the
stuff you know is when you threat model
ok good with that any questions about
that just yet are you with me
ok so let's go on I put this in every
one of my slide decks because when I say
secure software everybody thinks of
something else
one person thinks so the pen testing get
the vulnerabilities out the
authentication system I'm using HTTPS on
a secure how many times have I heard
that
HTTPS is the architects peanut butter
for security I mean I'm seeing a lot of
people are laughing and if the other
folks don't get the joke the inside joke
here is if you've been to a lot of
architecture reviews
time and time again the brilliant and
fabulous Solution Architect when you
come in and say one look at the security
will look at you and say we're using
HTTPS as though that's the final answer
to all things so I put this up here
because I want I want I want to
establish what I mean by secure software
and interestingly all of these are
designed problems only one bullet point
up here has anything to do with
vulnerabilities I'm not suggesting the
vulnerabilities are important and I
don't really care what the number
distribution is because the attackers
only looking for their leverage they got
one good design flaw they can manipulate
you don't care how many vulnerabilities
are there or not you know weird bugs
coding implementation problems and if
they can find one good coding
implementation of problem they don't
care for design is rock solid it's not
that's not the way for attackers think
ok so let's get started here
get rolling here is an architecture I'm
not gonna tell you anything about this
architecture for a moment
folks
feel free to shout out except for Dell
and maybe christophe casinos he knows
but feel free to shot out and say yeah
and also robert is a brilliant threat
modeler you guys the word what do you
see hear anybody what is this
shut up Yeah Yeah Yeah right everybody
see that usery on internet yet web
servers you got application server and
data bases this is actually called the
three tier architecture
pretty standard but what don't we know
which is kind of interesting when we
look at that we don't know the context
and the purpose we can infer from this
certain things because I will tell you
one thing that is 100% certain in the
security world there is one thing that I
can say with absolute certainty if you
stick a web server up on the Internet it
will get whacked maybe not successfully
but it will get whacked and it will be
between seventeen seconds
approximately eight hours depending upon
where this week's are hundred percent
certainty it'll get it'll get attacked
not necessarily successfully if you've
done your job right but it will get
whacked so that's the one thing we know
we know that that front end is going to
receive a lot of nasty traffic
irrespective of authentication
authorization any of those other things
we know that that front Nick right there
this one right here is gonna get 100%
alright so knowing that that gives us
some information but we don't have the
rest of this context now I made up this
lunar mining because i'm dumb and I can
never remember anything and so I need
something to help me climb into it and
say what do I have to ask about stuff
and these are the things you have to ask
is all in the book by the way these are
things you have to ask in order to have
enough information to do a threat model
well and so you've got another threat
landscape that's peace will spend a
little time at but if you go and talk to
Tony UV and Marco Moreno they actually
know a lot more about this they are
really really good at this stuff but you
gotta know your threat landscape what's
relevant what's not relevant as we said
the reason I put a web thing up there is
because there's a hundred percent
certainty it'll get attacked by somebody
and lots of somebody's ok you have to
understand what risk posture your
organization requires and I give you an
example if you only see your customer
once and you are always just seeing a
customer once and you don't care about
whether they like you or not do you care
about cross-site scripting because costs
like scripting is an attacker using
misusing your website to attack your
customer so anybody who cares about the
customers nothing like it but if you
don't care you but your customer I would
argue morally you two should care about
it that's different point but as a
business thing you really care about
that cross site scripting will it really
harm your business model answer is no
cause you only see your customer wants
you don't care they get whacked or not
so that might be off your radar your
risk posture that that your customers
get whacked by your website you might
not care I would argue morally that's
wrong but from from from a pure business
standpoint I'm sure there are businesses
that run themselves that way and so what
i'm all i'm suggesting as you got
another risk posture gotta understand
how much risk tolerance and what's
important what's not a speaker this
afternoon
Tony UV made some really strong points
about this so I'm not going to go into
that but it's a whole long how you find
that ours is not that easy
you also have to know what's already in
place what can you use and what are the
limitations that you have to put into
your threat model so if you already have
an authentication system you know like
in a web environment
why would you build another one you need
to know how that works and you need to
know how you hook it but you also need
to know if it has some weaknesses you
might need to make up for in your code
so you want to know what the structures
are and then you gotta know this stuff
the data sensitivity that you're playing
with and I would argue that whenever you
ask that question data sensitivity you
always want to say what is the highest
sensitivity here is if you just add you
know people answer things like well most
of its public what about that other
little bit that's top secret ok but you
have to kind of build for the stuff
that's you know most difficult you gotta
know about execution environments
because she executes really differently
than Java and it has different problems
and you have to know how things are
deployed ok with me there is no book of
correct answers to any of these
questions each organization is different
you have to do your organization
investigate your worse ok now we're
going to play with some architectures
one thing as I as I looked at the way I
work in the way that real practitioners
work and the way things really evolved
in real situations is that I end up with
a lot of different views because it's
too much information to get one view
under one viewer not have seen a couple
of interesting ways to do that but
basically you come in and you get
something like those three boxes and
then you make them draw more right so
here's here's here's here's an
architecture cold call you a little
unfair but cold call what can we infer
from this if anything from a threat
model from attackers perspective we know
at all what's being protected
sure
good point but how we get at it do we
know what it does it mean for anything
about what it does go Christopher this
guy this actually some architecture I
had it redrawn for the book because they
don't wanna get sued actually taken from
an actual real market xterm architecture
is in marketing architecture it told me
nothing I couldn't threat model it and
that's why I stuck it in the book I had
it redrawn though because they don't get
sued for anybody to know that I was
actually using a real architecture we
changed the name to protect the maybe
not so innocent but it actually Chris
office right it actually came from a
business intelligence thing and these
are sources and whatnot
we're going to actually threat model
real business intelligence not real one
perfect ational but one more information
than this I hope but nice but it's still
it's not enough it's not the right stuff
you got it the right stuff that's my
whole point here so let's come back to
website Karama let me tell you about
this let me give you some of the 3 S's
here
website aroma is an apolitical stock
fictitious this all fictitious based on
real stuff but fictitious web web
cyclorama is a supposedly a sock online
stock retailer and fictitious thousands
of socks catalogues of socks every stock
you can imagine bicycle socks knee socks
toe socks yeah this is their business
and they're fairly successful and giving
you those sort of business stuff they
want to protect their customers they
feel like their customers whether they
bought anything or not any visitor their
site is precious because someday they
might buy songs they are apolitical
though the reason I tell you that they
try to avoid controversy is not all
retailers
do because that's their business model
so their risk averse to adverse like
activism or or adverse publicity with me
I'm just setting the stage here this is
the stuff you gotta know they're fairly
risk-averse about taking they want to
protect their customers data and their
and their catalog anybody coming change
the catalog they sell the stocks they
sell anybody come and stick pornography
in there anything else
ok and they they try to avoid anything
but socks that's all they're interested
in selling socks and doing a good job
the way this architecture works as a web
server up in front
this is an application server that also
builds applications anybody ever hear
those things they were popular about ten
years ago there were things that would
build applications no coding involved
you just go in big bunch of stuff but
phrases together and it builds on the
application that's what this is but you
can also add your own Java applications
Java web server with some other stuff on
top of it that's also job it's running
in a Java web server container
pretty standard and this is data base
server which has a whole bunch of data
bases it serves ok with me
ok so let's play a little here where do
you see what's the stuff that's worthy
of protecting here where do you see that
good anybody else can we protect the
user's browser how do we do that yeah
yeah we want we want to make sure that
they don't people don't get attacked
right very good others yeah very
sensitive to that
yeah very sensitive to that these
configuration things here but if
somebody can change the way an app works
that's very true
yes very true how about somebody
inserting a nap into this into this web
server into this app server think they
did not like that very much having their
own app in there too who knows what
siphon off financial stuff and whatever
it is a bunch of we've got a bunch of
targets here where are the ways the
attacker can get into this let's imagine
that a minute how does the attacker get
to these targets and why might they go
after these targets
the whole back in for every one of these
systems isn't there in order to
administer it when you get on the
employee net which is let's say for a
moment it's a little bit open and you
you are you fish in employee go go
this kind of system could point or other
things about this kind of system is that
the messages walk right through whatever
firewall and you have it has to work
that way and so you've got you know
you've got a perfect package for sending
attacks and they can flow all the way if
you're not careful to the database
server or even into the database and sit
there and black people picking up
product so there's a whole flow that
happens here where you can you can get
some stuff here you might get some stuff
here you might have to do some work here
and so on through the chain because in
order to process the message you have to
take it backwards through the through
the layers I think that's what you were
meaning good point ok let's move on how
do we do this I like to start at the
organization's purpose of first time I
get to an organization I sit around and
I talked to a lot of people
luckily I'm now a senior enough that the
top people will actually hear me now
hosting always the case and took years
originally you know when I started down
this game who is this
Schofield guy I met at a time to answer
his email important but you know over
the years it's gotten a lot easier but
you need access you need to talk to
decision makers in leaders to get the
organization now if you work at a place
a long time you already know this stuff
you know you you've seen the vision than
whatever but you also have to know what
is the system's purpose what goals as
its serb for the organization what part
is it going to play and then you start
looking at the architecture I like to
look at things that are functional think
I've got a good wow these slides
together is that actually works this is
a fictional again all the architecture's
in my book and these are all drawn from
a book are fictional to any any
similarity to living or dead system
is purely coincidental I don't wanna get
sued so I took all the real
architectures and turn them into
something else
changed the names because i dont wanna
get sued by anybody but it's actually
you know pretty close to a to an
enterprise conceptual architecture that
I actually one side so you can also
count on these things are based on
reality so this is the way the
Enterprise Architect me look at a
enterprise cause what they're interested
in is really different than what you're
interested in as a threat model or so
here's the little problem is the people
you work with who you need to explain
what's going on are not going to be
looking at security the way you are
there could be looking at their thing
their views are going to be really
vastly different notice how things are
really clamped in very business anyways
here very business away supply chain
e-commerce the only thing they broken
out his presentation layers and then
there's this troublesome little box at
the bottom
anybody ever seen the security box in
architecture you know for years this bug
me and I was I wouldn't really kind of
make fun behind people's backs and then
I checked myself and really slammed
myself and said wait a minute if I were
an enterprise architect I need to box up
this very messy and and cross-functional
thing called security and put it in a
box and put it to the side because I
can't deal with it and that's why they
do that it's so inaccurate it's
laughable right however if you're the
enterprise architecting you're actually
trying to work out how all of these
things are going to get integrated this
is a problematic so you stick it in a
little box and put it the side so you
can manage the complexity that's why
it's there but obviously we can deal
with it that way to this is a break out
of that same architecture in a
functional manner when I can spend a lot
of time on it because I want to move
along one thing I want to point out
because we're gonna get into a new
middle is the message bus goes across
the security layer the trust boundary
see that in other words this is the
thing that
breaches are security model just
remember that will need that in a minute
but you see it starts getting really
busy when you break it out functionally
and you break it down into some zones
maybe it's not too busy just yet we're
going to just take one system out of
this and and threat modeling so don't
worry if you can't get to everything on
that screen just gonna take in how busy
it is and how I have broken out the same
stuff now we have these e-commerce
section is one whole section and it
starts to make sense from a functional
perspective and the supply chain is
separated out as a separate set of
systems which is very typical scalding
extranet now if I stick overflows in
their look what happens is pretty much
impossible it's a nice charge and this
is why you want to start breaking stuff
down when you get to their new trying to
get every bit of information on this
thing no break it down because you won't
be able to you you won't be able to
understand it
ok I used this mnemonic at Haslam the
reason I stuck architecture first is
because it sounds better than tad really
was there any anywhere you go in this in
fact a really great threat Marler once
said to me very recently wherever you
start here you have to do all these
things and it's a circle and so you
start anywhere that's convenient that
you like and then you move through all
of these things I like to start
architecture cuz I like to know what I'm
talking about but you could start
elsewhere you could list all the
relevant threats you know are all the
defense's you just have to do all of
these ok unfortunately these hide a
whole lot of steps will we're gonna do
these so so don't worry if you don't
take it in but you know I think they'll
post that the deck and what not to do it
don't worry if you if you can't take it
in and this is just one high-level
outlying these things break down
and even more stuff I point out it is
and highly recursive process and it
tends to be fractal as John Stevens says
and so you really the way this tries to
show you as you really you can get
anywhere in here and discover a whole
new bunch of stuff that you have to dig
into and have to go back to the top and
start again so its nonlinear a lot of
the time so those of you have really the
definite engineering mining you gotta go
step by step by step by step where to go
when you threat modeling it's much
better could threaten others sort of
know where they are and can pop back to
a different place yes please
yes that's very true and that was
actually a good piece of the target hack
I would I would argue good point and and
a lot of times you do deal that a lot of
times defenses are sometimes process and
not technology to so process definitely
comes into it so let's think about
threats when I teach this at Intel
security I actually spend a half an hour
total half an hour listing all the
threats always the same threat we know
who the threats are at a gross level but
I make people kind of go through it and
get their brains wrapped around it cuz
it somehow helps to unlock the whole
process a bit I don't have time to do
that today with you but this would be
kind of a matrix III actually based on
some work by Jack Jones who wrote fair
and I'm a big fan of fair but i just
want to show you that you can actually
understand the threats and how to defend
them by categorizing them if you pick
out the attributes of a certain length
is a big class you can you can poke
holes and there's this is a stereotype
any single cybercriminal might be more
or less clever than this but as a
general rule they're very risky third
aversive they usually don't have much
exposure to the you know only through
the web interface and that's how they
try to get in you know there they have
limited unless they're you know social
engineering your your employees or
whatever they don't have inside access
and they're very risk and then they tend
to use very medium to low sophistication
attacks and really it's about if your
house is is more secure than the one
next door that's the one that keeps
getting hit
absolutely in place if the system that
you're looking at is using that stuff if
it's a complete exception then all bets
are off that's one of those things in
that first that slideshow 23 @ sense
that you have to assess but that's basic
before you start threat modeling yes
it's understood absolutely ok so this is
a summarization of that of a couple of
different threat agents it's in the book
it's you know I just want to point out
that different kinds of threat agents
may or may not be relevant in the way
the attack is different their
sophistication is different and that
kinda helps if you only have to like we
take website Karama their only worried
about cyber criminals really you know
there's not much intellectual property
in the world of socks is why I used that
as an example
until they are worried about about you
know some third you know nation states
dealing with stocks our catalog so its
public anyway they just don't want it
changed very different ok so there's not
much intellectual property in a in a
standard web system they just want to
sell stocks online oK so that's very
different than someone who maybe makes
routers and has crypto routines in those
routers very different looking example
like that in a minute so what you want
to know is who who are are your
attackers and what are their goals what
are their ultimate goals and then it's
good then you break it down to say okay
well how do they get to those cold
weather system objectives I'm not going
to go into this stuff will deeply but
this is the kind of chart you might make
for yourself and you only need to do
this kind of once each you don't really
need to do it like for every system if
you have a fairly well known set of
threats and and and attack types but
it's good to do that ok let's talk about
risk a little bit anybody ever seen this
equation here
risk
equals probability times annualized loss
it's in every InfoSec 101 course right
we can calculated we don't have an
actuarial tables so what's a poor
security architect to do well I'll
propose the first you have to know
something about your own risk tolerance
because it's not your risk tolerance
that's important it's your organizations
as a professional ok you gotta know what
risk posture is required so get yourself
factored out and then I'm gonna propose
this this is based on fair but I have
simplified it tremendously jack jones
did read that chapter he did make lots
of comments I did change the chapter in
favor of his comments however he did say
it was acceptable so I feel I'm pretty
good solid ground here as a practitioner
that I've got some reels rounding here
all you need to do is treat each one of
these as a binary for our purposes you
can calculate the stuff but you don't
have to
practitioner just need to treat those as
a by as a boolean if you can interrupt
any one of those you've interrupted what
I call a credible attack vector ok so
here's some very light logical stuff
here you can interrupt exposure which is
the usual way to do this then you've
killed
credible attack vector and thus you've
lowered the possibility of exploitation
is a very in you can do this very fast
you can do hundreds of these in a few
minutes in your mind you know this stuff
and so we can say that credible attack
vector is risk rating is something times
impact and so remember there's no risk
none if there's no impact on give an
example
how much impact is therefore a buffer
overflow on a Windows machine that can
only be exercised at debug level
privileges actually argued with a
security guy by this very good one how
much risk is their impact 0 because if
you already have debugged privileges
you're having your way with the machine
high-techs exciting buffer overflows
you're doing what you came to do
whatever that is as an attacker you're
not sitting around doing buffer
overflows that's what researchers to
anybody's researcher I don't mean to
insult you but that's what researchers
do but that's not what it
attackers do they're already using the
machine for botnet or looking at your
keystrokes or whatever they want to do
so you have to have impact you don't
care about vulnerabilities that don't
that's a way of doing this really fast
gotta be fast because that's the game
sometimes threat model will see 45
systems of the day
yeah well you can you can set this up
now that gets into just good enough risk
rating can I talk to you about that
afterwards because what we did is we
took all these things and then we gave
them numbers based on situations between
0 and one and then you can treat them
that way that's what I said and that's
for the quick mental but if you wanted
to play with this in turn it into a
rating system then you take those and
give them a number between 0 and one and
then you multiply it against some kind
of rating of impact and boom you've got
a number between you know you've got a
number that you can repeat yeah yeah
it might be greater than 0 yes less than
zero and greater than one yes absolutely
perfect number you ok so let's have some
fun this is in fact I'll let me tell you
a little bit about this so you have the
right context this is in fact supposed
to be a business intelligence system
fictitious again
name changed to protect the innocent or
guilty or something it's a business
intelligence system and i wanna play
with it with you all if you will
it's behind its on the corporate network
in behind the public firewalls and the
public sections so all on the local
network except if you recall from that
that other thing embrace it pay
attention this one bus goes into the
public sector and carries messages
somewhere not to the business
intelligence but to the data that's an
important piece here you have to know
this is a router manufacturer something
like a famous couple of famous router
manufacturers that Sumlin name shown
field might have worked for some at one
point or another and they are very
risk-averse their sales model is youself
highest-quality routers in the world the
most dependable so that you can raise
your prices that does sound like some
real-world company doesn't it
and that you know entirely fictitious
name is digital discus I made that up
and they sell routers and this is their
business intelligence system together
stuff about their business it's all in
the internal network but these data set
due to get data from from external
applications do you know enough it's
it's monitored their security monitoring
there's an identity services here so
this is the thing it pretty much touches
every datastore behind the firewall in
order to put stuff together with me now
let's look at the actual system anybody
want to try playing threat modeling with
this one to look for attack surface
let's just find the tax services and
digital discus has been the subject of
nation state attacks they have been the
subject of hacktivists attacks of the
try to avoid all controversy they still
have been labeled a big global
corporation enemy by some activists and
they have they have of course many
competitors in many countries and who
would love to get their intellectual
property so that's the threat landscape
and the ever-present cybercriminals
stuff going on
always so now where do you think the
attack services here are what do you
think
do you need me to explain this I guess I
can do this is system and it touches all
these guys all this data and it pulls
all this data in this article relating
attack surfaces you see any just
immediately by where the wily attacker
how do I get into the system thank you
I'm sorry yes take the bus that's good
and get into the data stores so what
you're saying is any attack has to get
in here from the data yes true you see
these two things are obvious attack
points as john said anybody else let's
go on the system as it stands that's
probably small enough
so now let's try to find it so how would
you defend against that you got data
what are you gonna do you don't
necessarily trust that you have to suck
in and parse what are you gonna do
protect that with walk through the whole
thing with only five minute
from the expert right there yeah input
validation is critical and this is a
very hard input validation to do the
data gathering peace has to do
tremendous input validation and this is
actually a very difficult problem why
because it has to be a general take dad
in many many different forms so as to
understand one of the hardest parts and
problems we have is the general file
parser because you have to be general
enough to take anything but you have to
know all these different formats and
know whether it's legal go
and general general even more difficult
very difficult problem however that is
the answer there you can trust the data
rate answer so this is I'm gonna talk a
little bit about why I used these red
things which I've done like tons of
times in my life teaching this is I have
a lot of trouble with long lists long
lists which a lot of modeling methods
they may work for you I know robert and
I were talking about this earlier it may
work for you to see a long list of
assets are a long list of attack
surfaces in words before me about the
second or third attack service I begin
to glaze over and forget what I'm
thinking about and how it matches to a
structure so I like visual that's just a
personal stylist thing I don't want to
suggest that's the right way to do it if
you like stride and red do it get
started and I are gonna talk about that
tomorrow just do it I'm not a big fan of
those but that is not a comment about
their efficacy it's only a comment about
stylistic preference ok but I like
visual because it puts me understanding
where my attack surfaces in the general
structure of the architecture and so I'm
very fond of visual representations and
I also tend to take whatever
architects give me and then try to work
with that so that they understand where
I'm going so because it's an interactive
process that's a stylistic thing based
on my kind of work and the way in the
kinds of architectures I need to look at
but you may be different so you see I
use these little red hearts and
literally I do that again a red marker
and I mark on the thing and I say I
think that is back surface here I think
there's an attack surface here ok don't
ever forget your date you're you're
controlling data like configuration
either alright I'm just gonna go through
this a little faster the data sources as
was pointed out by John are wickedly
important because they might hold
attacks as they take on trusted data
alright
where am I now we put some users in here
are there some attack surface is here I
was gonna go through this really fast
obviously there are so this system has
to protect itself from those things as
well and that pretty much gets us to the
thorniest problem here I don't think I
have time for this but you can talk to
me afterwards the identity services is a
very thorny little problem that would be
worth if I had lots of time to go over
well sure that's very true but its
identity oh yes it is thank you this is
this is a this this flight deck is a is
a class in information so as I said Saul
experiment alright I will say one last
thing and then I'm just gonna turn it
over to you getting requirements into
implemented as an entirely different
story and lots of work needs to be done
there
composing the requirements well will
help but that's a distinct discipline
I'm not going to go into it today you'll
notice I just dodged a whole bunch of
typical threat modeling issues dodge
those bullets I have those are stylistic
preferences not necessarily writer on
and little shameless self-promotion have
books out there yes I will sign your
books if you can catch me and here's a
bunch of ways to contact me and to find
out about what I'm doing and where I am
I will tell you one thing though if we
haven't had a meaningful interaction and
you send me a LinkedIn friendship I will
ignore it because I try to keep my
LinkedIn to people I actually have
interacted with real and so when you
look at who I'm connected with on
LinkedIn those are all real people that
I know they're not you know people who
just want to be cooked to me because I
wrote a stupid book so we're we're
supposed to be done but it's the end of
the day so I think we can carry on any
questions
I would you know what John from you I
would say yes because we've had lots of
meaningful the directive yeah yeah yeah
you know let's go back because that was
actually hold that there are there are
in fact I dodged that bullet in this
talk because they didn't want to go down
it because message buses are a whole
whole thing in the book I talk a lot on
this architecture about a good security
model would deal with this problem and
actually a good way to deal that a good
defenses you have whatever you take in
from here you never pass through here
you recompose as a as a you know you use
of course use light bedded libraries and
whatever but you recompose and you also
have to have a lot of somebody else said
it you have a lot of restrictions on
this guy so that only traffic only goes
to intended places and its limited NURS
authenticate to the bus all of those are
message bus you know security things
that you need to to conscience and I
kinda skipped over that because I felt
like you know I can only do so much in
15 minutes or whatever but you're
absolutely right
any other questions let me go back to
the question answers like yessir
that never happens does it that never
happens
yes so that's where the fractal part of
this comes in where you have to look
holistically and then that opens up
another threat like that happens all the
time and you have to then say okay my
threat model is incomplete life retinal
needs to account for just as it needs to
account for the message bus in fact you
also need to account for that I actually
go into a situation like that one of my
examples has that kind of thing where
they had a payment processor and
suddenly it changes the whole threat
model yeah very true and really I what I
do is I step back and say okay here's
more stuff so people often ask me so
what about when the threat model happens
at the very end we're going to talk
about that tomorrow maybe I shouldn't
give that away now I won't give it away
come to our talk tomorrow we'll talk
about what happens we get the threat
model or when you get a big change at
the end
and then shipping it to gosh knows where
ya i you know i play a really long game
and only when something is really really
terrible do i do I call follow and say
no that's a personal style because I
have to get along with my sister and
brother architects or they will just
disinvited from the party was a lot of
little personal stuff here you have to
find your own style so I play a long
game I say okay well we'll write an
exception now but we're going to we're
gonna threat model that we're going to
find out what did you know because it's
already exists you know and and I kind
of try to play a really long game
your style may be different or your
organization may require a different you
know response than that I think that's
very very unique to the experience you
know if I found out that you know the
data were all sitting you know on public
web server and that's where it was being
shipped to with open FTP anonymous FTP
my reaction would be very different like
over my dead body and we're going to
move one inch further you know I think
it's very highly dependent you know but
but I would caution anybody whatever
powers you have to say no use them
wisely because if you get disinvited to
the party one of my metrics that I use
because I have seventy architects that I
actually work with and lead and one of
the metrics I use is do they get invited
after you know I think continually being
invited and seen as as adding value
because that's a problem so if you get
to what I want grumpy with people
yeah yeah that people just this invite
you smart developers disinvited any
other questions or you can you can talk
to me after the session if you like I'm
here and I'm here tomorrow to ordering
reception