hello everyone
thank you for all the British people
that are still there at 5 PM let's talk
so I make the assumption that you're
there because you really want to listen
to this talk so I'll try to give some
let's say crunchy details
and if you don't find it detailed enough
like um and we can speak uh afterwards
so I work at Wi-Fi Labs a company about
dashboard so
and he had like really
strong opinions about dashboard but I
don't take it personally because I at
grafana Labs we are a dashboard engine
company so basically we're building an
engine to be nice nice dashboard so that
people can build useful dashboards
meaning like for music videos dice ball
dashboard where instead of data maybe
you have some signal some useful stuff
uh
so uh
again uh we'll try to give those details
grafana lab is all about transparency
so basically we're going to talk about
mistakes we make uh we use go
and
yeah when you make mistakes you you can
have like security issues and all that
and the goal today is to share
uh again about the Keynotes yesterday we
discussed about misalign incentives and
all that
and Bug Bunty uh
uh background chili Hunters like pen
test and all that and we can especially
in those conferences to glorify hacks
but what interests me more as an
engineer is
how can make how can we make make it
hard to happen how can we make things
secure enough and all that how do we
make the life of bug Bounty Hunter's
powder
so that's kind of my daily job upside
engineer used to be a back-end developer
10 15 years ago
and uh I worked at g-club also as absec
and basically at grafana Labs I try to
make sure that the software
we are writing is secure enough
meaning that we don't have for it to be
perfect we want it to be
somehow like safe enough I thought he's
better than most of the competition and
all that so that
if bad things happen we don't feel
ashamed we we feel we've met
a job that's good enough
so uh we will see that like just a few
words about go and why if you hear about
it it's nicely connected and
anytime you talk to people or not like
you hear the message that yeah if you do
something in go
it sounds it's going to be secure but
you can still like make mistakes because
there are a few things that are
confusing and many vulnerabilities occur
when there is confusion
so what we're going to do we are going
to analyze in details two series first I
where we are the first rehearsal
because of a confusing method
we'll see what we've done to try to make
sure we have properly fixed because we
didn't want to play wakamo we wanted to
make sure that once we patch it we are
not like
pinged again at the middle of the night
to fix it again because the fix is not
like uh
let's see
wide enough regarding like what you're
trying to protect from so we'll see how
we've decided to use go first thing to
try to build confidence on on our fix
and after that we look at something uh
that's what critical 9.x score where we
have suffered from a race condition and
things that where you don't think they
could be happening in go but they can
happen
and there we'll see how we use load
testing
to exploit the issue we had and also to
make sure at least again reasonable
confident that our fix was again
fixing enough the issues so that once we
deploy it
like burgundy Hunters don't just don't
look at it and just trying to find a
similar bypass and then we really look
stupid and then we will finish here with
something more surprise for the end just
to keep you awake and so that people
don't leave before the end
so
if you love to go.dev they say yeah well
which go you can build simple secure and
scalable systems it's kind of really a
strong assertion like simple secure
scalable
it looks like yeah it's a perfect
language like you you should pick it and
you can do whatever
you're in good hands and yeah if you
look at knowing the details here first
it's memory safe so no birth or overflow
issue and all that it's statically type
which means like it's going to be hard
to get like things like remote code
execution that we just saw before uh
with this blockchain stuff and all that
and they also have a nice long security
Checker so by default you get the Linker
that gives you
rather good warnings on when you are
doing dangerous things and all that yet
as I said in intro
we had sevolving abilities we look at
two because of what I call unexpected
Behavior which but it's not unexpected
behavioral like C where depending on the
copilot and the CPU it doesn't compute
the same thing here it's well in fact
it's deterministic and if you look at
details in the dock it tells you exactly
what it's going to do and it's
deterministic whether it's like running
on x86 on arm 64 and all that Mac
windows or whatever but it's surprising
to the developer so it's doing something
that when you type it you don't think
it's going to do
and so that's why you can have bad
things happening and we'll start with
something really bad
or for zero day December 2021 I was not
there at that time uh
but what's interesting because we're all
about transparency I could find all that
information on public blogs posts and
public purpose and some of it was useful
for me for the interview process because
some of them were asking for that uh so
what happened
December the 2nd
a researcher finds a past traversal okay
very super excited about it
if you brought it to us like responsible
disclosure and all that that's fine like
gpg encoded and all that so all the
cleansing and then just after that he
said wow
I found the price to Amazon and you can
see like all those links the links work
so you take those slides and you see you
will see all the comments all the tweets
all the details all our comments on PR
and all that so he tweeted about it and
of course what happened a few days after
well you tell people hey you know
there's goldier and and people
try to look at it and after a few days
we saw that our ostead instances uh uh
well people were actively using the bus
drivers also just because someone said
there was a past reversal several other
researchers found it and they didn't
tell us and they tried to exploit it uh
so it was clearly a zero day
and we released a fix on December the
7th so basically we were working on it
and then when we saw that it was
actually exported all the company
stopped working and just like focused on
getting it shipped
another question was when we did the
first incident review like
like what the hell how could it happen
like we are using like standard gold
libraries how can we have past reversals
stuff for things where the languages
that it's secure and it's simple
well here is a culprit
you will see why
so
file past those clean like just reading
the name like that song like if you're
lazy and you just look at the name of
the method you say yeah it's gonna clean
everything if you look at the dock and
you just read the first sentence it
tells you like it cleanly Returns the
shortest past name equivalent to pass
which seems to be like exactly what you
want if you want to avoid past reversal
you get your input you you give it to
this method and then the fast is clean
shortage pass
no problem but
in fact instead like purely like sickly
processing blah blah blah those four
rules I won't tell them it's super
confusing
you read that three times you are still
not sure what's happening uh I know that
I don't want you to read all that again
all the links are working and all that
when it gets like complex I had I like
to play with a few God samples to be
sure I understand the dock uh which has
a lot because when the dock is unclear I
need to really bad source of confusion
so basically my understanding when you
read that it says like it will remove
all those dot dot sequence which is
perfect when you want to get rid of past
reversal and it will do that for all the
Inner Elements
and also for the first element if it
starts with a slash
which means then
it does not remove the first dot dot if
it does not start with a slash so for
that making sure you understand the dog
you go to the go play around write it
simple like Snippets
and then you see that yeah in fact if it
starts with a slash then everything is
clean as expected but if it starts with
a slash slash
and it's not going to be
cleaned up as expected
so
what we were doing yeah well
classic past reversal stuff I guess
we have a web parameter
we have plugins in grafana where we need
to load extra files and then uh what we
were doing we were then just okay
cleaning these parameters say hey yeah
we're not stupid doing some input
validation let's clean it and then that
should be fine
and then what's again you click on the
vulnerability tuning you see the all
commits that are the broken code because
of course today this is fixed uh
but you can see also because it's all
open source and public purpose you can
see also all the comments on the pull
requests I know that and there's
something that's interesting even in the
source code
there's a comment that says like yeah
well goseek this security linter it's
complaining
but but one of our software engineers
said yeah well we can ignore this
warning because we are cleaning things
as we should so we are the winter that
wonders but we were sure that we were
doing the right things and we kept track
of it
so at this stage it looks like well you
know everything is under control you
have like a some security linkers in
your cicd pipeline
people spend time looking at the results
Sev like in ask comments like why they
decide to ignore something and all that
and then what's even more
funny
if you look at goes like and then what's
about like these g304 finding it says
yeah well you know you're giving
something as five pass yeah and then
there's a link in this goes like warning
that's called the right way and then
what's the right what the right way is
telling you to do well use five pass DOT
clean and then yourself
so uh
so we are like we using codes the
interior compliance
but we are using file pass.fin and the
Dock of the linter says you should use
fivepas.clean so like someone reviewed
the pr review this command and then say
yeah well and yeah I'll go sex tell me
like this is a way so we should be fine
we were all notes
uh so what we did again you click on
this link and you see the fix uh we just
open the slush and it seems to be fine
uh
we saw that before like if the first
element starts with the slash it seems
to be okay we added some unit tests and
then we created like a few
follow-up issues uh in our post incident
review process like you
have let's say
more control about this kind of of like
science Rules uh and all that
okay that's fine so that's how you fix
that went out on December the 7th 2021
and then fixing the zero day and all
that
but everyone was still
like troubled let's say like is it
enough it kind of looks over hard like
we need to put a slash in front of it uh
why go is not doing it and then like
maybe bad things can happen like with
Unicode characters or whatever like uh
are we doing the right thing because
it's already exploited people know we
have a past reversal now that they're
fixed like that so it's going to be
super easy for other people to try to
say hey okay now I'll I'll try to all
I'll I'll try other pass injection and
insightly likely to succeed because when
you look at the fix it's it it doesn't
seem that strong
so here comes good fuzzing
so the goal uh of fizzing in general uh
and then you go you see the context it's
a bit different but basically it's your
right predicates
and you expect
to write uh those predicating like those
things should never happen and you want
to throw an engine that will try to find
contour examples that will break those
predicates so it's kind of the opposite
of security requirements where security
requirements are telling you like yeah
you should do that well whereas like
here we are writing
think that's that this should never
happen and and that's it and then what
what will the floating engine do uh it
will generate many many episodes of the
random input and see if the predicates
are broken or not and if it finds a
predicate it stops and they say hey your
code is broken security wise this bad
thing can happen
so what's what's cool is go into uh
included natively fuzzing from version
1.18 which is about like one year ago
uh and the way they did it is super neat
from a developer perspective because
it's on top of unit test so it's almost
uni test by default the we have as uni
test and then you activate the fuzzing
flag and then they start to do all the
magic of a never-ending Loop
multi-thread it so that they can test
like a lot of findings and all that
meaning that you can have
your unit test you just need to like
write them a little differently they're
running your pipeline as usual and at
some point you want to get confident
that your helper works okay and then you
say okay now I'm gonna spend like 10
minutes fuzzing I switch your flag I run
it and then I see if it finds something
or not uh
there's a tutorial
which is
not a crystal clear so let's just use
this vulnerability as an example uh
to make things easy I extracted all the
code just put or clean pass method here
where we do this Arc of
putting a slash in front of it
again if you're interested to play with
it later on I created a public repo you
download the source code you play with
it and you tell me when it gets broken
because of whatever you go version
things can happen
the phasing test
we don't care about the syntax here and
all that what's interesting is you see
test cases
basically you give let's say
input as starting points like things
that should look okay and things that
shouldn't really look okay and then from
there first thing we'll start doing
minor mutations and move things around
and all that and up until it finds
something
uh uh and what's important are uh
uh the predicates
so here we are saying that
once cleaned
all the inputs should start with a slash
if it's not the case an input has been
found that that is breaking the
assumption
and we'll try also to say that
uh well if we see a slash dot slash in
the middle of a clean input like our
input validation is just bad it's not
working and we we we have found like an
input that's breaking the rules and we
want to be aware of it
so we launch it super easy you just need
the correct Go version
and to activate the floating Loop you
just put like minus first equal first
and then it starts throwing things at
you uh
when you do so you'll see that in fact
you're wrong when you're writing the
predicate and that's that's really
interesting which means like sometimes
it's harder to test your validation
logic isn't to write the validation
logic which means that most of the time
your validation logic is incomplete
because you didn't think about
everything so it's trial and error you
say hey here here are my predicates you
learn them two seconds after violation
you see an input that they are this
input is Val is like obviously
wrong I need to fix
my predicate
because most of the time it's a
predicate that's wrong uh and then
sometimes you get stuck uh we'll see an
example just as well you don't know if
it's like
if the input is legit or not should you
process it and is the output like
something you should expect or not so
for example if you reuse this example
and then we use a predicate which is
like uh I don't want a dot dot slash in
my clean string then after
0.00 seconds so like almost uh right
away go says hey I found something like
if you give it like zero dot slash zero
then you end up as a result which is
like slash zero dot slash zero
like is it alleged input is it a valid
output it's like it's super hard to know
so that's where like fuzzing has proven
like super useful so that you challenge
yourself and say like which kind of
input you should accept uh and so before
pass traversal what we want to do is
making sure that the input like like
really does it does it ever make sense
to have this kind of pass zero zero dot
slash slash and all that so it help us
fine tune like or validation logic and
all that with all those Corner cases
uh
I don't know when we saw there was value
we use it for like a bit more complex
things
where we didn't have zero days we said
like maybe it's a good idea to try to be
a bit proactive uh
again uh
we are using fightpass.clean at other
parts of our source code and especially
we have plugins and we sign those
plugins to make sure they have not been
tempered with and all that and for us
when we do this signature it's super
important that all the file paths in the
plugin match what's in the Manifest
uh so we are using fightpass.clean and
then we have like a bit different logic
and all that again here you can click on
the link you get the example I'll just
copy paste
the code here to make it like easier to
read we write a phasing test for it uh
and there it gets harder uh to write uh
you soon see that when you try to write
predicate if the logic starts to be a
bit more complex
it's hard to write it in a clean Manner
and all that that's what we try to
achieve there we try to wrap that in
method and all that so it can start to
be like to be honest it can start to be
hard and it's looks like it's gonna work
in 10 minutes and then you feel safe it
requires like engineering bandwidth and
all that to play with it
uh
so you have to like work on methods
trying to see what it does and then and
then you start getting stuck because you
say okay
native Library
but I'm not sure if it's really secure
now because I don't trust their dogs
anymore so somehow you have to
re-implement like all those small
things yourself so that you compare the
go implementation with what's your
definition of what's this
code should do so it takes quite a lot
of time
but yet is still useful because you find
things so for example we saw that we had
something broken in our signature plugin
if you put like dot slash dot slash so
basically you could
inject kind of an anti-file in the
signature which was not a big deal but
but yet it proved that our validation
logic was broken
and we were expecting
people to look at every each and every
five pass DOT scene we had in our source
code because it has proven or value so
we fixed it click on the pr you see it
and all that so good first thing was
super useful for that
Barbara use terms now this is going to
be getting hard
[Music]
again you'll have the links and all that
but before diving in
if you click on it there's the advisory
and to be honest when you read the
advisory
you don't really understand what's
happening behind the hood like the
adversary says yeah there's something
there's a rest condition where which can
lead to privileged escalation like you
you understand it's bad because his
vulnerability is a critical it's a 9.8
but you don't know how it can happen
and then you'll see how the code has
been fixed like even if you look at the
fixed code you don't really see the link
between the description of the of the
advisory and like what's happening
behind the hood
it's because
yeah even though we are on open source
company we still have private customers
and they want the advisories to be
as generic as possible
uh
that's life uh what's more interesting
there is
how did we learn about it so this time
it's not someone tweeting about it we
were lucky uh
one in fact it was unhappy customers
like in Oakland versions they're
starting like
sending us like contacting support and a
ticket and say hey I don't understand
like sometimes like some data on my
graph is not appearing and then when I
see a log files I see like access deny
40 series 401 errors this is range we
had nothing like that one weeks two
weeks ago like it starts to appear like
well that's strange
so our engineering team like walking try
to understand took them a lot of time
and all that and then
a really good developer from us like
found it
said hey yeah it's a concurrency issues
I tell you the first sentence
I read about it
we have found a short slice rights race
condition when initializing handlers for
the middlewares good night
we try to suffer decide for that and a
lot but what's interesting there is well
that was a concurrency issue
but it's about something like its
middleware but but but what are
middlewares will see that their ability
to authentication and then what's really
nice here like with the culture we have
is
a developer finds something a rest
condition you see that it triggers like
you
bugs regarding access access denied and
all that and then it pings us the secret
team saying that hey yeah maybe you
should have a look at it maybe there is
a security impact because the bug we are
saying is customers are complaining that
they don't see their data but maybe some
customers are seeing data they are not
supposed to see
and no one will ever report you
something about that except if it's
really like obvious that you shouldn't
see it
so let's see what can we do with that
uh
before that a bit of vocabulary and all
that we use internally API roots
middleware
an API route is just basically
the mapping between the URL the public
API like
if you already you can contact it and
then the business logic that it's
calling
and then the middleware is shared shirt
code that can either be called before or
after the business logic so basically
instead of copy pasting each time all
the same kind of authorization checks
and all that when you call a method you
put it in command components and then
you make sure they are applied
systematically and for example we have
middleware for making sure the user is
logged in which is kind of useful we
also have that's before the business
logic and after the business logic we
have some middleware that make sure to
filter out the resulting data to make
sure you only see what you're supposed
to see so you have two examples below of
our source code where one is middle one
say hey you should be signing and then
you have something strange about
snapshots here why it says like it's
public mode or sign in which kind of the
first time you read it is kind of
roaring because it's a hair well it's
something the easier you are logged in
or you're not logged in uh
we'll see that it's it was a poor design
choice
getting to the
art
here
while opening two slices dangerous
first there is a really great article
and just not not just before because of
this picture but it really explained
like suppose like one big page like
white slices
Ingo are not always slightly slices
basically seems like if you have to say
in a few world it's like you you have an
array of data and you say like I want
this part this third part of the of the
array like I want to starting from three
to five just give me this web array and
as a developer if you don't know go
enough and all that it seems like yeah
well you have an array it gives me a new
array which is just the only important
interesting uh and then it's well first
in the article that there's a common
misconception about uh our slices walk
in go
that leads to unexpected program
Behavior so that's the confusion we were
talking about at the beginning and all
that which is surprising to many
developers so that's it uh so it's
unexpected not because it's not
deterministic it's unexpected because as
a user of the language you don't think
it should do that in that case
and then look all of that he said it's
because slices are references
pointers basically all of go almost
everything is copied by value so that
you don't get all this kind of transfus
pointer stuff you can have in C and all
that
except for slices because they and
they're doing that for performance
reasons uh I know that so again if you
want the full details the article is
really nice but as a tldr well
a slice in fact when you when you when
you ask for a slice
a new object is not created most of the
time the slice is using the real array
behind uh
and only when the Arabian does not have
uh let's say the correct size so and and
you don't really know because it's like
comparable stuff and all that it decides
to clone your slides so which means that
sometimes your slice which is a
reference gets cloned automatically
which means like it is passed as a value
by chance and sometimes it's still a
reference and it's as dangerous as a
pointer in C so
foreign
we don't know if it's vulnerable yet
like we know it was broken there was a
bug
and a fix Again full transparency you
have access to the pull request where it
was introduced I don't want to show you
15 pages
of code that was in this pull request if
you're brave you click on the link but I
just show you what's important in the
pull request a summary of what is this
change doing it says while we are
changing the middleware execution model
from web unders to you know slice to web
dot middleware okay we are challenging
something about the middleware and
there's a slight interloop another
comment is interesting like why the l
should we change that like you know we
have many more features to work on and
all that well in fact there were like a
few uh improvements and all that a bit
expand their middle words are
temporarily kept in a slice to preserve
ordering blah blah blah uh because
before that when you are two three four
middlewares
you did not have the guarantee that they
were applied in the correct order which
can be kind of confusing because you say
hey I want to be login then I want to
have permission a and then I want to
filter data like that if you don't do it
in the correct order you start getting
your own messages that say wow sorry but
I can't tell you if you have permission
here because I don't know who you are
yet because the login middleware hasn't
like kicked in yet and all that uh
okay so something
that made sense that's hard when you
read it and all that a change that has
to be done a change but that was done on
authentication logic so something super
super sensitive
but the the pull request was approved
all the equipments were fine and then
when you look at the source code and to
be honest even if I'd reviewed the
source code for me it would have looked
nice it looks clean it makes sense we
need to change and then when you when
you read it
like you don't spot anything and of
course like we are talking about
cultural before we can talk about some
web or any SAS engine there is no way
this kind of thing like will point it
out it's just like business logic but
it's business logic about authentication
stuff
uh
now the bug fix which you you can see
there uh the comment is more useful they
say hey well we have to explicitly copy
the middle version to avoid by single
shot slides to the context so now wow we
don't see in command that we are the
vulnerability but yeah if you just like
look at the cve that the death of this
PR you already find it like within five
minutes you know it it's called this
this charge and basically what we are
doing well we are just
and forcing the copy so that we are
making sure that we are not using like
slices as reference from time to time we
just like make sure to copy them
explicitly and then it should be fine
should it be is it enough
well you know this build fix was taken
in production we don't see any more
errors about like access denied and all
that
but you never know especially when it's
a rest condition maybe you fixed 99 of
it and in one week someone sees it but
then now with that
we've leaked openly that we had
something broken in this authentication
middleware and we know that people are
already following grafana and they are
like actively looking on us here just to
figure we have more than one million
instances deployed in the wild that's
quite a big number uh
so
that's why I was at Peach who have been
like contacted and say okay now
we've made this fix
was still called exploitable before this
fix
and if it was exportable is this fixed
enough
what can we do about it and
especially how can we decide quickly
like how how do we do that in a few
hours so that basically you tell all the
incident responses team and all that
yeah well if it's exposible maybe you
have to look at your log file for the
last two weeks and see if any
let's say ill internal person asteroid
to exploit that
so
I'm just like I like to take a step back
and what I do well it's full remote
company so
we work from home and all that but I
just go away from the computer and I try
to take like 15 minutes off and try to
just focus on the problem and not on all
the like mess and that you trigger so
the root cause is well
because of zero slices are working
sometimes they can be shared instead of
being a copy and then it depends on the
sizes of those slices and all that so
it's kind of meaning that okay if we
want to exploit it we must like force
those slice C's to be shared and we know
it's possible for them to be heard
because we had this bug so
it happened in real life so it shouldn't
be that hard to reproduce uh
so in practice it means like if we want
to exploit it what we will be trying to
do is okay so
let's say we have request a
either a way so that we cross a will
receive the middleware lists of request
B if boss requests happen about at the
same time
can I get to execute like something for
user a
but with the checks of user B
so when you do that of course
you never know if you get a yes or no or
I don't know
and maybe you you could spend yours on
that and never being able to prove it
uh so trying to optimize this the chance
of let's say minimizing chances of
failure let's be honest uh so first
point is yeah because it's going to be
rest condition and
it's never going to be deterministic and
all that first decision was to test it
locally so that you like avoid all these
Network latency and all that that could
make it harder to exploit
uh and then the decision to make things
easier and because there's like this
size parameter I know that was to focus
on endpoints with only one middleware so
that if you make the switch you are
switching
from A to B and you don't have like ABC
and Def and all that and you don't know
what's happening uh and all that and of
course if it's a vulnerability
you want to maximize impact and so for
that that's something when you know the
application there's something which is
unconventional let's use let's use this
word where uh there's an API endpoint if
you have server admin access you can
reset the password of anyone without
knowing their password so normally only
those super admin can call it
uh but it's kind of or I just said there
and we also have a few unauthenticated
endpoints uh there is a public dashboard
feature where anyone can see dashboard
of public data uh which means that if we
can do that if we can have
uh
the reset admin password endpoint called
with a public middleware it means like
someone not logged in may be able to
change the super admin password for
example which will lead to this nice 9.8
score
so now
how do you do that in practice
okay you can try to maybe like write
python script
launch verb whatever and then cross your
fingers or
I was lucky
there's a tool called k6 so it's on a
process tool that's now part of the
grafana labs umbrella uh its goal is to
provide the best developer experience
for load testing so basically load
testing Made Easy basically you don't
need to spin up 17 Dockers with 45 pages
of talks resolve 15 broken dependencies
and then you launch something and then
you get network errors because like
queuing to optimize and all that uh so
it was kind of a no-brainer for me to
try like and then say okay now let's try
to reproduce it to sk6 uh
are really great dogs first time I use
it it wasn't how to do this I said yeah
I need to have a look at it we wanted to
dog food it for security use cases and
all that but then like well there's
never a basket that Under Pressure to
test if the tool is good and if the
results are good it's like the tool is
really good and yeah and what's nice is
yeah you know load testing tool had
really bad experience with or previous
ones now it's an internal team it's
teammates and because it's kind of a
highly visible incident if we need help
like they will help so that was kind of
nice but I didn't
even needed help
so there's a demo here
and if you don't see the details going
to be shared
this one is super sensitive
I'm sure there are still hundreds
thousands
of
instances that are running this broken
version they shouldn't be
please don't play with it against
instances that are not yours so what we
will try to do with k6 what's really
nice it's
they have a simple JavaScript
uh let's say library to express what you
want to do so what we are going to do we
have this admin reset password endpoint
we have a public dashboard endpoint
we prefer a payload where we set the
password to the me password
here we Define scenario that that's what
nice really nice with k6 you say okay
now I want to have the first scenario I
call it protected
and I'm going to run 60 views views in
fact are virtual user so basically it's
going to start 60 threads
calling that
so that would be 60 virtual users
trying to call
the reset password endpoint and there
will be also at the same time 60 virtual
users trying to call the public endpoint
so
quite heavy load there and we say okay
we test that for two minutes and we we
see what happens so that's a description
of the scenario and then you define
again
predicates while you say things that
shouldn't happen so you say for the
reset password you try to reset the
password
and
because you try to call yeah the reset
password without any credentials you say
hey this shouldn't work because I'm not
authenticated I'm not supposed to be
able to change the password of anyone so
you expect the statues to be not 200 and
if it's 200 you say okay stop
password has been updated that's really
bad
so that's for the predicate for the
protected route and then for the public
endpoint you just say well
it should return 200 and if it doesn't
like something strange is happening also
there's no reason for for it to fail and
so now let's do something crazy let's
try it you should never try your demo
something that's random but
yeah Friday night and all that
let's give it a try so
what you do
you need to run a Docker version as try
to zoom in
well there's nothing magic I know you
run the docker image of a renewable
version and then the only thing you have
to do
k6 run the name of the JavaScript we've
seen
starts running
boom
lucky normally it's five seconds it was
quicker
so like yeah after a few dozens calls
you have statistics everywhere it
changed the password to the new password
let's try it
I mean
so
[Applause]
which things like uh so what we did so
then of course
we test it for a few hours with the same
script the patch version to make sure it
doesn't happen or at least that xr2 will
produce so it's kind of easy to
reproduce locally when you have Network
and all that it's much harder to try to
web shoot this seat and all that but
that's enough to prove that yeah it's a
vulnerability and then it's it's a 9.8
the biggest villain we ever had at the
company uh I need something
no security researcher found no one from
the security phone it's all it's
developers because they had to work on a
bug because of access issues
at customer deployment that we figured
it out
so maybe there are other rest conditions
and it's something that if people tell
you like Growers versus art and all that
worst as much better guarantees against
race condition whereas goal is well as
long as you copy things it's okay but if
you start sharing things by reference
you get things wrong we also add other
rest conditions with map single because
maps are also passed as references
because they are too big so things can
happen but they didn't have any security
impact
as far as we understood
but maybe we didn't understand well
so we just launched a backbone T program
we'll handle it ourselves
official announcement has not been done
yet so feel free to have a look at it
first before the too many people uh
we are interesting that this kind of
finding the big one so something like
that is clearly was twenty thousand so
we've tried to
to better align the incentive so that in
the policy of this bug Bounty program uh
we are optimizing for good quality of
reports and all that so we will pay
bonus points for
really
for people that are really well written
while there is a clear POC and all that
we are not interested by automating
findings which is just like copy pasting
of uh noise and all that
so what we learned
well
fight past those clinics like super
tricky and you can think that you're
protected from Pastor also lingo but
you're not
but go fuzzing can help you
quickly spot that
and then you can include that uh As Nice
regression test in your pipeline if they
are not too complex
and then you also learn that slices are
a dangerous Beast
uh Ingo
especially if you start implementing
like authentication logic yourself in
multi-threaded context and all that and
we've seen that we've seen that well if
you need to
exploit race condition like even in
different contexts and all that like
have a look at k6 it can help you like
be super productive you know validating
that and then I'm happy to take
questions
[Music]
[Applause]
well first of all thanks for talk and my
question is do you think go should
update the method the one from the first
vulnerability to make it
not possible to reproduce what happened
to you
I would say so but if they've done it
this way they have a good good reason to
do so and why the algorithm is there
uh and it's kind of
but they know they got it wrong because
they have a good sex rule which is a
hair it's not that good so
but then now I think it's too late for
them to change
so basically they should need to have
something which is like file pass DOT
clean safely or something like that and
then they can have this goes like rule
that say Hey you you should rather use
clean safely and if it breaks things
yeah just use a dangerous version and
beware
thank you
thank you for interesting uh
presentation said yesterday that of
course gravana dashboards a lot more
informative than kibana dashboards yeah
that's why we fought kibana of course
yeah we change recorders so and we don't
like pie charts
well said well said but Jokes Aside I'm
not a developer what I'm not what I
didn't get in your presentation and
please explain it like M5 is you have a
race condition in your code you fix the
race condition why would you need to run
performance test whatever you did
can't you prove that the race condition
is gone or could you change the
architecture so it's really gone because
it's for me it feels like you you don't
really trust your fix
yeah and that's true and and that's true
and and it's like basically with multi
shredding it's out to prove and if you
want to prove it
use rust basically and that's the only
the only solution like for me otherwise
it's really support either you need
support like limited programming
languages that are only focusing on
multi-threading and they are like let's
say rest condition proof
by Design but they are super hard to use
super super hard which means you're not
productive which means you will not be
able to deliver enough features uh uh
and all that uh
we've like I was like to be totally
honest
I think the original scene here is we
have too many custom authentication
logic
and maybe we shouldn't play with that
we've played with dangerous things and
we were not mastering them enough
so that's the cost of doing
multi-threading yeah okay thank you and
that's the cost of doing multi-threading
without realizing you're doing
multi-threading
um
thank you
foreign
thank you for the talk
um go the framework itself has a data
race detector it can have enabled with
good test minus race and but you
recommended another one so I would like
to know how it Compares and if you
prefer the other one because
data arrest detector was insufficient I
couldn't hear you well sorry uh sorry so
the go binary itself has a data race
detector yeah it cannot it cannot spot
it okay thank you we tried yeah uh but
it's like it can find obvious things
which is good because it catches if you
start doing multi-threading thing and
then you say yeah I don't get it I don't
even understand the error message like I
shouldn't play with it but this kind of
thing is much more subtle
that it cannot find it like basically it
runs forever and you you don't get any
results from it
well thank you for for your presentation
thank you for the talk
foreign
[Music]