good morning it's a real pleasure to be
amongst you today so my name is
Charlotte Lindsey and I'm the chief
public policy officer at the Cyber peace
Institute
and hi everyone my name is Emma raffray
I'm the chief research and Analysis
officer also at The Institute it's my
first time at insomnia so be kind to us
today
so the aim of today we're really going
to talk about the harms and impact
methodology that the Institute has been
developing to do that we'll take you
briefly through Who The Institute is
just as an indicator how many people in
the room have heard of or know of the
work of The cyberpiece Institute
okay and so I will give a very brief
introduction for those who have not
heard of The Institute before and then
we will walk you through
um some of the approaches that I use to
currently use to measure harms and
impact and why that's important and we
will take some examples from the health
attacks on Healthcare sector attacks
currently in Ukraine and then where
we're taking this methodology and and
its importance going forward so with
that I will just kick off on
um on on The cyberpiece Institute so the
cyberpiece Institute is a
non-governmental organization based in
Geneva which is independent and neutral
and its work is very much to to try to
build stability in cyberspace and
greater accountability towards
um against thread actors and to to to
support really vulnerable communities
who are affected by cyber uh cyber
incidences uh it's only three years old
The Institute and we have a real
multi-disciplinary expertise
and that really looks at an Evidence and
data-driven approach to try to
understand how we can assist
particularly vulnerable communities and
in that we have a cyber peace Builders
program which is supporting humanitarian
the non-governmental organizations to
build up their cyber security resilience
and we also assisted Healthcare and also
we look at a particularly vulnerable
communities linked to for example
critical infrastructure so that also
helps us to to gain primary evidence
about how cyber incidence is cyber
threats are affecting particularly
vulnerable communities and then we
analyze that as a lot or in also along
with open source intelligence that we
can we gather and aggregate from a broad
variety of of actors and and
um means of collecting data that we can
really then look at analyzing along with
that primary evidence how cyber threat
landscape is affecting particularly
vulnerable communities and then we use
those insights to inform policy and
legal discussions that are happening for
example at the United Nations to build
um a more stronger normative framework
for the use of icts or against cyber
criminality so there are several ongoing
processes at the UN and in other foreign
the osc and others that are developing
Norms to strengthen the protections of
against the Cyber criminality or the
protections of the use of icts so we
work in this holistic way to really try
to use this evidence to have an advocacy
and policy-based approach to try to
effect change
why are we interested in harm I think
the critical aspect around that is that
the current Focus around harm primarily
is linked to the operational or
financial downtime and impact of a Cyber
attack
and all the public reporting obligations
that are required in certain in certain
sectors or in certain countries and that
differs across sector and differs across
country and so it really is focused on
what's the time to restore what are the
financial costs or penalties what's the
number of records that are breached what
is the personal identifiable information
which has been accessed
um what is not really for the focus
currently is what's the harm that has
actually caused to people and because
there's really no standard methodology
in place that makes it very hard to
understand those harms and without a
lack of real metrics tools and
Frameworks to understand and track that
harm over time it's very difficult to
then work at how we can build stronger
um normative and policy making processes
reflecting that harm how we can better
support the victims of of cyber
incidences and how we can learn for that
in terms of building Greater greater
resilience so that's what drove us to
look at why measuring harm is important
so that we can then use that in that
cycle that I mentioned uh in the slide
previously around assisting those
communities analyzing the attack through
a more methodological process and then
using that to inform uh diplomatic
processes at state level
thanks Charlotte so trying to put a bit
of an analogy into place and how to
actually differentiate a little a little
bit what we mean by the terms impact and
the terms harm
and I want here to use the notion of a
car accident we all know what a car
accident is it's an impact between two
vehicles
a car accident can have different
impacts it can have an operational
disruption it can increase traffic at a
particular time of day and it can lead
to to delays in you getting to work and
it can lead to disruptions to services
that have to intervene to be able to
um to resolve the accident
we've got Financial costs and costs that
really are impacting potentially both
persons are both drivers of the car and
in terms of the insurance that they have
to pay and things of this nature
then we look at the physical damage to
the vehicles what has actually happened
in terms of an actual damage to the
windscreen or to the to the wheels and
then we have such things as geotemporal
factors how long did the accident Cause
A disruption how big of an area did that
um did that accident actually
um lead to further disruptions
if we then look at the harm components
of that car accident we come at it from
a human-centric approach and we're
looking at what was the physical harm
that was caused to either the drivers or
the passengers in the car or the
bystanders who might have actually
witnessed that accident what does that
mean in terms of potential psychological
impact to the driver who might not be
able to drive that car then for a
subsequent lengthy period of time
we look at the community and societal
impact how an entire family has passed
away as a result of an accident and how
that impacts the community
we look at the reputational damage that
could come from that if the vehicle was
a company a truck for example an Amazon
vehicle that is then involved in an
accident what what might be the result
from that and then with a look at the
environmental impact with Zone oil spill
on the road how did that impact the
environment around it
if we take that example and we sort of
pivot that onto a Cyber attack we can
see similar divisions so if we take an
example of an attack on a hospital what
is the operational disruption to that
Hospital's ability to deliver Services
have the computer systems gone offline
has the website gone offline is it
impeding the automatic opening of doors
for example what is the financial cost
of that hospital to actually recover
from the Cyber attack or to actually
respond to the Cyber attack in the first
place what is the physical damage that
has occurred in terms of physical damage
to the actual infrastructure the
technical infrastructure that was in
place and then how long did that attack
go on for how long were operations
disrupted did it affect One hospital did
it affect 50 different hospitals against
50 different states for example in the
US because they're part of a wider
Network
and then we look at the harm and we look
again from a human angle from the
people's angle and here it's not just
the patients who are affected it is the
healthcare professionals who are
operating within that hospital who are
having to react in circumstances where
they don't have access to Patient data
where they don't have access to
computers where they don't have access
to imagery for example
and what are the physical or
psychological effects of those
particular that particular Cyber attack
and the delays that it's caused in terms
of access to and to Patient Care
and then there's the community and
societal implications surrounding that
has the hospital has to divert patients
to another hospital so it's causing a
knock-on effect within a geographical
perimeter of a city for example what is
the reputational impact when critical
data is leaked from a hospital and
patient records are made available
online and what is the environmental
impact if we take something perhaps a
bit easier to imagine here is a Cyber
attack on a water facility and
contamination resulting from that you
know what what broader implications does
that have
so taking in mind this kind of notion of
impact and harm
um we then started to look at what
actually exists today what are some of
the literature some of the studies and
some of the work that is being done by
different actors multi-stakeholder
actors looking at impact and harm
so we've got a report that was published
by the icrc for example that really
looked at the effects of cyber
operations in times of armed conflict so
it's a very specific and it's a very
specific use case relating to cyber
operations and they're really looking at
an assessment of how traditional Notions
of impact actually rely on a risk
assessment and they look at a comparison
of the likelihood of an attack taking
place and the severity of those events
so in terms of severity they're looking
at the type of of effects of an attack
they're looking at the scale in terms of
the people that are affected or the
number of computers that might have been
affected as well as the duration but
then they actually look at the
likelihood and what is the probability
that a certain cyber operation actually
causes the effects and that they're
setting in the severity component and
not just looking at the likelihood of
that happening to an intended target but
it could also be a an impact that is
happening
incidentally or accidentally in the
context of a cyber incident
what else exists today there's a number
of different uh companies notably in the
private sector that are looking really
at the business impact and these are
coming from the likes of Deloitte but
there's also insurance companies that
have been doing a lot of work on this
that are actually looking at the
business impact so what is the impact
for example of a technical investigation
that has to result as a um that results
following a Cyber attack
um how does it affect public relations
for the company
um how are my insurance premiums going
to change next year as a result of the
fact that I've been a victim of a Cyber
attack and I've had to claim of that
insurance
have I lost any intellectual property
when the Cyber attack has taken place
but what we see in this report is these
kinds of reporters are significant and a
lack of
um acknowledgment that actually the
Cyber attack beyond the organizational
impact is actually the the impact that
that has had on people be it for example
their own employees or be it their
customers who who might have suffered as
a result
then we looked at a report published by
unidea which is actually a bit broadened
looking at the impact and the impact and
harm of cyber attacks but it actually
looks at the taxonomy of malicious cyber
incidents
but there's a couple of components of
that taxonomy that are actually really
interesting when you look at the victim
profile where they talk about whether a
victim is intended instrumental or
collateral
um they they also break down the victim
into different components the victims
can be an organization but it can also
be an individual within that
organization or in and of its own right
if we think about for example a
individual whose phone has been targeted
by spyware that individual themselves is
actually a victim of a Cyber attack
they also break it down into what is
critical infrastructure as a victim what
is a country as a victim and you know
we'll address the sir where we go on to
the topic of Ukraine later on in the
presentation and then it looks also at
International systems in place
but it also breaks down things such as
targeted assets
um and on the other Spectrum in terms of
the output what happens post Cyber
attack and they break it down into the
effects which is what we're calling
impact on our side but it also looks at
the harm where it's broken it down into
physical psychological Economic Times
um but it also looks at gains which is a
really interesting
um aspect of it which is looking what
has the threat actor actually gained
from committing that Cyber attack and
for us it's asking questions of can that
actually be transformed into some kind
of measures of impact as well if if the
um if the objective of the threat actor
is of a particular nature and he manages
to gain something from the Cyber attack
what does that mean in terms of
assessing whether there's been a
particular impact or harm
then the academic world we've been doing
quite a bit of digging into this and
they've actually started to propose some
taxonomies or classifications of harms
and these this particular study here
breaks it down into physical
psychological emotional economic
political governmental reputational and
cultural components and these come
together and they actually reuse quite
regularly Now by different uh different
stakeholders and across different
sectors in terms of actually used as
classification of harms but there's some
open questions here can we talk about
community and societal harm is that
something different from the
classifications that have been put in
here can we talk about the
disproportionality of harms for example
when we're talking about particular
communities targeted through cyber
attacks if we if we're looking at
gender-based targeting for example how
is that taken into consideration in in
the existing Frameworks that have been
put forward what about environmental
that doesn't seem to quite feature that
yet is it coming under economic is it
coming under cultural perhaps
um and then there's some fundamental
questions how do we actually access and
collect data to be able to understand
this harm it's difficult and that data
is not so easy to collect and we're
going to go through that in a minute
so the healthcare sector so we've
touched on an example earlier and the
the particular visuals here are on the
two sides if we imagine the car
accidents we've got on the left the
hospital fighting the Cyber threat
actors it is the operational disruption
what is being done to actually contain
that incident to actually try to
minimize the impact of that incident
over time and then on the right hand
side we see what's happening to the
patients and to the healthcare
professionals who are operating with
systems that are being disrupted or data
being exfiltrated related to Patient
sensitive patient information
so since um June 2020 The cyberpiece
Institute we've been collecting and
documenting cyber attacks against
organizations in the healthcare sector
across the world and we're doing this
through open source data collection and
we've been focusing predominantly on
disruptive cyber attacks so notably
ransomware and we've documented up until
September last year 501 incidents
specifically disruptive attacks against
the healthcare sector that's across 43
different countries it's an average of
4.1 attacks a week and that is barely
scratching the surface this is what we
publicly know about
so what we decided to do when we were
collecting this data is how do we
actually start to Define indicators to
actually measure the harm and impact
that these cyber attacks are having
and we're looking at Global numbers such
as 21 21 million records breached we're
looking at uh 1 400 Days of disruption
in total and again this is just what is
actually known in terms of those
incidents
so what were we able to actually capture
from our data sets we were able to
capture from what is known so there's a
big question mark at the bottom of this
of this slide it is what about the
unknowns and there are a large
proportion of the incidents that we've
documented for which there's no publicly
available information on the impact at
harm that they cause
but on average 163 000 records are
breached and enjoying a cyber incident
on the healthcare sector
in 13 of cases incidents resulted in
patients being redirected from the
facility that they were in and in 15
incidents resulted in canceled
appointments this is significant when we
think about the number of people that
would have been using those services and
those resources uh during the time of
the Cyber attack
and then we look at the organizational
side 19 days on average of operational
impact on that hospital or that
Healthcare organization's capacity to
deliver its services
52 of incidents led to Healthcare
Systems going offline which means in
limited access to certain types of
information certain types of tools
during a cyber incident and in 70
percent of those cases we're talking
about disruptive incidence here in 70 of
those cases data was exposed Elite
what can we draw from qualitative
information so there we were looking at
the quantitative aspects what can we
numerically calculate what is the
qualitative data saying so I'm not going
to necessarily read through all of this
but I wanted to pick up some key words
in the slide here this is a real case
example of a Cyber attack against a
hospital in France in August of last
year
medical images devices went down patient
admissions were inaccessible seven
hundred thousand people used that
particular hospital they were unable to
register new patients there was
redirection to nearby hospitals there
were precautionary measures that were
taken to transfer infants in intensive
care precautionary measures they didn't
even know if the Cyber attack would
impact the ability for that child to
receive care but they had to take the
precautions to do so how do we start to
measure these things there was Emergency
Care intake was decreased by more than
half
um certain patients couldn't be operated
on
there were 11 gigabytes of confidential
data that made it online that included
scans lab results and Social Security
numbers let's have a think for a moment
what that actually means that's one of
those 501 incidents
in other space
who in this room has actually heard of
estamo
I'm hoping by the end of today you're
going to remember them
their Psychotherapy Clinic that's based
in Finland
and they were targeted in a system
breach back in November 2018 which was
followed up by another one in 2019.
attackers came back only in September
2020. uh contacting the starmo
requesting 40 Bitcoins to be able to
protect that data so it doesn't get
leaked online
they refused
and what happened subsequently was the
actual targeting of specific patients
who were requested to pay 500 euros for
their data not to feature online
this resulted investamo actually having
to declare bankruptcy in February 2021.
staff and patients had to be transferred
to new services
they were fined post bankruptcy by the
finished data protection authority for
violation of gdpr
and then there was a suspect that was
named in October 2022
and they were arrested in February 2023.
that arrest is extremely rare in terms
of cyber investigations
the accountability aspect which Charlie
will touch upon later is actually
extremely rare that a cyber incident
actually results in somebody being
arrested
but this case had a significant impact
on the finished Healthcare sector on the
Finnish government who had to revisit a
whole number of different aspects of the
way that they were protecting patient
data
all the way to going through to new
systems to actually allow for their
citizens to actually have new identity
numbers in the aftermath of a
significant attack
so we've taken these kind of case
studies as part of building a
methodology where we actually break it
down break down the incidents into
different categories such as
geographical societal operational human
and legal impacts of cyber attacks I
won't go through the details just for
the sake of time
so our methodology then is taking up the
notion of identifying indicators of harm
based on the quantitative and
qualitative data collection that we're
doing
and we break this down into uh into
different columns or categories of harm
that could be applicable to any Cyber
attack no matter what sector what domain
what type of Cyber attack it is to
indicators that are sector specific so
for example the healthcare sector and
then indicators that are attack specific
such as the notion of ransomware a
ransom paid is only going to be
applicable in the context of a
ransomware attack
and what we're then doing is identifying
different weightings of indicators based
on and those Notions of harm that we've
identified so we're looking here at Raw
numeric values that we could use as part
of a future formula
we then also use categorical indicators
so here we mean we're transforming what
would be potentially a yes or no answer
to a question or a category for example
whether an incident is actually
confirmed or possible and you know what
weight does that particular category or
value then hold converting that into a
numerical value
and the next step and this is where the
methodology is working progress and
where we want to engage the community is
to actually figure out how do we
mathematically combine these different
indicators together to be able to
compare incidents one against the other
in terms of the impact and harm that
they've had
there's also complexities with regards
to this and we mentioned this earlier is
how do we actually access the data and
if we're looking at certain things like
the geographical impacts of a Cyber
attack the likelihood of us being able
to acquire that data is actually very
high but then if we're looking at things
like psychological harm it's actually
quite low how do we go about actually
collecting the psychological harm that's
resulted from a Cyber attack
so these are just some of the
complexities and things that we're
thinking about
I'll whiz through the work that we're
doing on Ukraine so since the beginning
of uh last year so in the in the month
leading up to the invasion
um we started to document cyber attacks
and operations in the context of the
armed conflict
and to date we've documented a thousand
three hundred and thirty cyber attacks
that have happened either against
organizations in Ukraine organizations
in the Russian Federation or
organizations
um outside of the two belligerent
countries that that are taking place in
the context of the war
and so here we're back to some
quantitative numbers we're looking at
roughly 21 attacks a week 87 different
threat actors 23 sectors impacted 45
countries but what we're starting to
look at is how does the aggregation of
these different cyber attacks together
actually cause harm in itself
what is happening in terms of the
persistent need for organizations to
defend themselves and the fact that you
they are operating an environment where
they actually have to expect to be
attacked and how how is that impacting
their ability to operate in terms of
persistence persistent defense
we've looked at also some of the um the
qualitative aspects of what it means
when organizations are targeted within
certain sectors so the energy sector for
example what is happening when the
electricity goes down what is happening
in the financial sector when um when we
have cash machines that are not
available for people to be able to
withdraw their money
what is happening in the context of the
media and when we talk about the media
we're really talking about the uh the
impacting of informational space and how
um the information narrative is actually
being skewed in the context of the
conflict
and then Transportation what is
happening when certain Transportation
networks can't operate or when when
their customers can't buy their tickets
to be able to to to to take the
transport Networks
because I've covered all of this so I
will move on so why is if we look at
something like the contact of in context
of Ukraine or the healthcare or the
humanitarian sector why is it important
to measure these harms and what we see
is that it is partly about busting
preconceptions if you look at something
like the war in Ukraine people will say
that war is happening between Ukraine
and Russia but we've monitored attacks
happening in 45 other countries and
those attacks are countries that are not
necessarily involved in the conflict but
they may have made a statement for
example that they have stated that they
believe that you had that the sanctions
should apply
um to to Russia for its illegal
annexation or occupation of Ukraine and
then immediately you see cyber attacks
starting to happen so even if you are
not involved in in that conflict as a
belligerent country or as an
organization that is involved in any way
shape or form your still becoming
vulnerable so it is important to bust
some of those preconceptions about who's
affected but also how people things are
affected it's not just about financial
shutdown it's not just about
um operational downtime
it is also important to use that in
normative discussions so there are
ongoing at the moment un negotiations
around cyber crime for a new convention
and on the open-ended working group
which sits in New York to discuss the
use of icts where there have been
discussions ongoing for many years to
develop normative framework the Norms
that should
ensure the appropriate use of of
technology or the the appropriate
responsibilities in relation to to cyber
crime
what we find in those discussions have
started to have been really looking at
actually undermining some of the
existing protections that are there
because of the negotiation stance of
certain countries who are actually
informing those processes and saying
well look it's not an Attack under in
Ukraine unless there's actually been any
harm and because it's only a temporary
shutdown of a system there's no harm
Ergo it's not an attack well if you're
only measuring harm in a very limited
way then there is a risk that those
normative discussions end up developing
policies and Norms that we should be
following which actually do not reflect
at all the operating environment with
which we're in
it's also how do we look at reducing
impact and increase accountability
because uh for victims of cyber attacks
how do they go about understanding how
they've been affected communicating how
they've been affected knowing what
redress that they may have whether
that's at an individual level or a state
level for for example criminal
prosecutions that might come and we see
a lot of the threat actors today for
example in Ukraine there's been a lot of
self-attribution if you see that on the
slide that Emma showed before many
different more than 80 threat actors
many of which have self-attributed and
said we have carried out the attack so
if we can manage measure the harm that's
been linked to that and then look at the
impact really of of that Cyber attack
that could lead to a prosecution either
domestically in the country where the
attack has happened to also at an
international level so those things are
going to be very important to understand
and actually be able to frame what those
harms mean
uh increasing public awareness is
critical because we've we hear a lot
about it's not just when it's if a Cyber
attack happens but people don't
necessarily understand what that will
mean for them and so if we can raise the
public awareness about all of the things
that we were just discussing earlier
then it will really help to to bust some
of those myths and actually have a
greater recognition of what harms and
impacts are
we're also moving into an environment
where cyber risks are increasing and
there is a permissiveness around
accountability for those attacks that
are happening it's allowing uh
perpetrators of those violations to
continue to not be brought to Justice or
or to um to create an environment where
attackers feel they won't be held
accountable
if we can frame better the harms and
impacts it is clear that these are not
victimless crimes they're not computer
crimes they're not crimes they happen
just about technology they are affecting
people I think that is very very
important particularly for decision
makers who are framing policies and laws
today and in the future and it will help
they'll contribute to improved stability
in cyberspace because there's a growing
distrust in the use of of Technology the
fear that our phones spy on us or that
we shouldn't go online or because of of
of the risks to us or that certain
technology is a worry and so or
countries worrying about back doors to
use certain technology so understanding
harms and impacts and being able to use
that to frame the the
um the public awareness the policy
decisions and hopefully greater
accountability can all lead to improved
stability in cyberspace
and then there are some wider broader
implications that we have to look at so
I mentioned you know there is a lack of
accountability there is this changing
normative environment the regulatory
environment is changing quite quickly
dependent on our different regions or
different countries but where you do
have to report like for uh on gdpr for
data breaches uh where there are high
fines
um for those organizations that haven't
reported breaches or on attacks on the
healthcare sector for example in in the
US where you have to to report on those
above a sudden threshold all of the
implications of those
um that more tied to regulations and
then compliance with those regulations
will need also an increased awareness of
what the harm is
um we know the risk of attack is high
can we reduce the impact if we
understand more what the impact is
um and then there's also the wider sort
of sense of of trust in technology
energy if you look at the the fear or
the the awareness around cryptocurrency
and the perception that that's the the
the currency of choice if you're going
to carry out a ransomware you know that
also great builds um or prejudices
certain technology and and that's also a
risk for for society and risk for for
technology and then look at the enormous
costs that organizations and individuals
are having to to to deploy in order to
prevent cyber incidences defend against
them and respond in terms of our own
capabilities inside to build a more
resilient organization and all of those
are the broader implications of of the
recognition of the harms and impacts
which go far beyond those which are just
the risk to the organization of its
Financial
um or operational shutdown
to conclude therefore we've been working
on this methodology we are now engaging
with the wider Community cyber Security
Experts governments International
organizations the private sector other
civil society organizations Academia
Insurance to really look take the
methodology that we've been working on I
think the questions that are still there
and then work with this with the
community to really try to to look at
how we can reinforce this methodology
how we can build on this methodology how
we can strengthen it around the data
collection around the identification of
indicators measuring over time or
measuring different types of attacks
with a view of then looking at also how
would we be able to make this
methodology something that does become a
reference point so over the next months
we we are engaging with different actors
across at different sectors and we're
very interested to have any feedback
that you may have on on this work and
with that we will then also obviously
clearly be making this methodology
public later in the year so thank you
very much for for your attention and
we're open for any questions thank you
[Applause]
please raise your end for questions
hi thank you
um I am a big fan of trying to
understand
impact and harm sorry those terms are a
little bit uh close to one another right
so I might not use them the same way
that you do at the same time I'm trying
to figure out
um who's the primary audience of this
message are you trying to convince
policyholders to to implement this
framework are you trying to convince
industry are you trying to come up with
a new vocabulary for ngos to use can you
help me understand where this fits in
suddenly the the big gap today is that
we all talk about these things in very
different ways and I think that's a
challenge particularly when we're trying
to inform both victims of of those
attacks which is primarily for us the
the humanitarian sector Health sector
critical infrastructure sector but also
states that are making
um decisions about this and are
influencing or the only ones who can
really take positions uh at in these U.S
fora
um about what these harms and impacts
are because that will help inform those
policy decisions so definitely at a
state level it's very important and we
see and the feedback we get is there's a
big gap for them in this regard and they
would like contributions that can come
but Civil Society organization like we
can't and shouldn't be doing this alone
we should be engaging with all the
different actors that can help inform
that but also can build on work that's
already been done so I think our appeal
is really to have a wider sense of
Engagement from different actors so that
it can then be used as a as a
methodology which is going to help
particularly in in decision making and
for stability
Emma and just a touch also on the notion
of the the ngos and the non-profit
organizations that we're supporting as
part of our assistant services at the
Cyber peace Institute it's actually
there is still a lack of awareness of
what a cyber security incident can
actually do to your operational
activities this is happening every day
and it seems to be let's react post the
major incidents so to be able to
actually measure that impact and harm in
a way that is more tangible and the idea
is to raise that awareness to get people
to think about how they actually
increase their cyber security resilience
and to be able to to reduce the impact
of a Cyber attack we can't prevent every
Cyber attack from taking place but we
can certainly raise the awareness for
them that for the need for them to
actually act before it's too late
and to build and I think one of the
organizations we've helped quite a
number of organizations that have been
going through cyber attacks
interestingly they came back and said
even after the attack was over and they
had whether it was a a fraud or whether
it was
um a breach into their systems and
interference and disruption of their
systems looking about said the
psychological impact has gone on far far
longer than the actual recovery and that
that was completely underestimated they
didn't and they needed to also use that
sort of information to help inform and
support the staff as they were going
forward not just then to to have process
in place to build a better resilience to
that but also looking and saying wow how
do we overcome that how do we manage
that and a lot of the the leadership of
those organizations which are often
being targeted to say we are not armed
to be able to do that at all so I think
on many different levels we can we can
play this but I think for the
organizations themselves also to realize
it's normal to have an enormous
psychological impact of an attack that
would be part of it and that is an
impact or harm that's really important
thank you
hi uh thanks for the talk um
so I fully agree with the message that
you're trying to conveying about the
importance of measuring harm though in
my experience every time we try to
propose like a policy change the people
in charge ask for sort of a real
measurable number uh like you you seem
to agree with this do you have any sort
of advice or a preferred framework to
attach a number to you know the
predicted harm cost
uh thank you for prediction or foreign
is the notion that what is a matter and
that measure can be a numerical measure
a quantitative value like it can be a
qualitative one and sometimes the
message that is clearest to get through
is what qualitative information is
actually telling us and it's converting
that qualitative information into
something that people relate to and so
so the way that we are really
constructing this from our perspective
is to say we need to pull on many things
we need to pull on the fact that there's
a financial cost to an organization yes
that's going to make the CEO wake up but
there are going to be other components
where we're gonna be able to say to an
organization if there is a Cyber attack
that's happened on a hospital and you
have five doctors that are going to be
unavailable for the next four weeks
because they are so traumatized by what
has happened and the fact that they
haven't been able to deal with emergency
emergency care patients that is
something that should should speak to
many people and I think actually by by
using the business impact so so the part
that I was talking about the the really
the organizational impact of harm we're
so removing it from the human impact
that actually is difficult for us as
humans as individuals as people to
relate to so it's so I don't know if
that answers your your question
specifically with Charlotte yeah and I
think we we looked at the healthcare
sector for example and we brought uh we
we ran as a process of multi-stakeholder
uh engagement where we put in the room
cyber Security Experts we put into those
responsible for hospitals the
administration Finance we put
governments we put Civil Society
International organizations and what was
very interesting would say hey they're
all speaking very different languages
there's very little engagement and those
that we were um that we brought together
with actually the those who were making
decisions about budgets on security or
um because they were very much reading
the notion of risk very differently and
also the the potential in impact so by
putting different stakeholders together
it is a way to help build some sort of
methodology that can inform and speak a
language that could combine or unite
um going forward because so far this
very siled and I think these coming up
within a methodology that can help break
down those silos or where at least
they're speaking some sort of common
language so that they can unders that
everybody can can adhere to I think will
help as we move forward thank you
yeah
any other questions
thank you very much for your time for
your insights thank you