okay this talk is about target targeted
social engineering attacks how
psychology is being weaponized against
people but really it's also about what's
coming what we have been observing in
the sphere of social engineering attacks
how the attacks have been evolving and
what we will have to face in the coming
coming years we already see different
types of attacks we will see more of
those in the years to come
let's face a couple of words about me
who am I to talk about that my name is
Christina lecate I have a background and
degree in Psychology but I have been
working in cyber security
specifically I have been working for a
cyber is based in Zurich as a trainer
and consultant on the human element of
cyber security
I have been conducting the social
engineering awareness training trainings
for the both for the board of directors
we specialize in custom
specialized trainings for specific needs
but I'm also the lead investigator when
it comes to open source intelligence
vulnerability assessment for high value
targets and corporations
last I have been a very happy and proud
member for the ocean curious project
but let's Dive Right In we start with
the case a case that we had the luck to
have a reported case on these types of
attacks this came from proof Point uh
it's a very good report if you want to
read it the link is there
it's about myself Martella Flores a fake
online account
who behind this account actually was a
state-sponsored trade doctor very well
crafted Facebook profile with this
inviting lady who had a very soft spot
about people working in the Aerospace
defense industry
most of her contacts were employees and
people working in the airspace defense
industry and
yeah she was connecting with them
talking with them and at some point
let's say in 2019 with one specific
individual we observed that there was an
initial contact friend request he
accepted
she stayed there didn't do anything for
one full year in fact it's one of the
very few long-term social engineering
attacks we have been observing and fun
fact these are the types of attacks that
we had so many people thinking oh this
would never happen
but it happens a lot more than we think
it doesn't see the light of day that
often
so for one full year she didn't do
anything why
we
2020 November 2020 almost many months
after she initiates contact with her
Target that individual we are examining
the report
um based on just one common interest
something they were both interested in
he responds he likes it let's also think
it was November 2020 the time of the
pandemic where everybody was a bit home
and alone
I they started talking they started
building a relationship escalating from
one social media platform to to the
phone WhatsApp messaging exchanging
little pictures exchanging little videos
having nice conversation and that goes
on for eight months
eight months for a social engineering
campaign uh wasting so much time why we
will see
but here's the first thing we have been
observing in the way social engineering
attacks have evolved and in the way they
are starting to go
they are not this quick hit and runs
anymore and they do start targeting more
and more what people want and what
people need
we have massillos higher here of needs
and we see that yeah we all need to feel
love and affection we all need to feel a
sense of belonging with one another we
need a Social Circle that's going to be
around for us and that raises our
self-esteem that makes us feel confident
that is a reliable
uh listening ear a shoulder to lean on
is this a human weakness we have been
hearing so often this um
the same thing again and again all
people are the human the weakest link of
security uh they you cannot but stupid
but is it stupid to just have your human
nature and have social engineering
trying to exploit it this is the name of
the game it's not about people being
stupid it's the simple fact that we are
humans and some will try to exploit our
human nature
so yeah sure we still have a lot of the
facing Hit and Run campaigns the ones
that have time pressure the classic
funny looking email address from the
sender the the awkward grammar yeah we
still get those and where I keep going
to getting those these are not going out
of fashion all of a sudden because they
still work
but we also see that
Sam some organizations have started to
become a bit more sophisticated they
start to recognize them but we also see
the attackers evolving into a more
elaborate campaigns because they are
much more successful ones that involve
longer reconnaissance ones that have a
more tailor than personalized approach
to them so not just these random numbers
game phishing emails being sent out or
those um
rather standard spearfishing they're
really really tailored
they use more elaborate mind games they
exploit our psychological nature and
slowly we start seeing deep fakes
getting into the mix as well
and we see those especially from
state-sponsored threat actors
now if some of you are in companies that
belong to the highest risk profile
the ones that have sensitive research
the ones that belong to the critical
infrastructure yes you should be very
much worried about this
but let's see what happened with
somebody yeah she was talking with that
person for eight months how did this
conclude well in the report and what
ends up in the report are the results
like just the fact and there are a lot
of uh things that happen in between the
airlines that get missed so in in the
end my sailor sent out an email they
were talking about the pandemic they
were talking about diets and she said
hey my dear
um this is a diet survey it should feel
loud you should fill out your
experiences especially during the
pandemic period at home please please
press enable editing
and to enable content and to see the
full page this is the link it was a
Google Drive Link
uh send me soon thanks for your kindness
and your participation cheers Mercy let
me tell you of course there was some
flirting added to the mix
but so he did he said yeah I'm gonna
help this friend and who knows what it
is
um I'm gonna help her out she clicked on
the link yes there was a trusted
relationship by then which was the whole
point of this engagement lasting so long
and enable the the content downloaded
the macros and eventually downloaded
what was done as the lambo malware which
was designed to establish persistence
perform reconnaissance
and accelerate sensitive information
and as we say there is this history
was there one case scenario was did this
happen just once is it the Black Swan
one of the things that you cannot
anticipate no
this is something that we see happening
a lot but doesn't get out in the news
all that often there were more cases
Facebook reported a whole set of similar
accounts trying to do the same LinkedIn
is full of those you probably have heard
that there are many many others as well
the kill chain is usually the same they
target specific people in key positions
they perform long reconnaissance mostly
through social media because social
media is a gift that keeps on giving for
reconnaissance and now if you are
wondering what did it take her so long
to establish a connection well they were
studying their targets and they do study
their targets nowadays
so yes of course then you have the
online Persona which is the medium
through which the attack can happen
the approach is personalized like we
said and very very often we see them
escalating their targets from one
platform to another to appear more
legitimate than believable Facebook from
Facebook to LinkedIn to a missed
Instagram because if you have an online
presence you must be a real person no
a of course then eventually to Whatsapp
phone numbers email addresses work email
perfect
and through this casual relationship
building that looks a lot like the way
we make friends in everyday life they
take the stress building and explode it
exploit in a very
regular casual everyday manner nothing
out of the ordinary
these were the details you don't have to
read them whoever wants the slides can
ask me for them after the talk and I
will be happy to email them to you or
send them
but
or they all have common common
characteristics the end the difference
is only like in the exploitation how
they decide to exploit the contact did
they want to harvest great danger other
times they want to to send out a
malicious email that downloads malware
and of course the goal sometimes differs
this way most of the times the case is
epic what's behind it is an Espionage
operation and they need to collect
sensitive information
why go through all these tables for so
long what do they gain out of it what
what is it in there for them because
don't forget threat actors they also
care about return of investment they
care about how they spend their time so
yeah there is the case where there's an
attack that harvests credentials in the
end or malware infection but this whole
time there is also an effort to elicit
sensitive information human intelligence
tactics that we used to see in Espionage
operations are now happening in
cyberspace through virtual human
intelligence operations through these
fake profiles through casual
conversation whose goal is to blending
specific Target equations we're going to
talk about that a little bit later but
yeah eight months Marcela Flores took
eight months to exploit the relationship
imagine how much informations you gained
on the target that time
about Technologies about things that are
happening at work I've seen these
conversations and
people talk
of course in other cases we also have
inside their thread grooming this is not
random they spot the ones that are
unhappy at work that have needs in life
that a third doctor or some more money
could failing and by establishing a
connection in a relationship eventually
they groom them into willful
knowledgeable Insider threads
again
it supports long-term Espionage
operations as well but once you have a
connection with someone in a key
position imagination is the limit any
number of things can happen and what we
know about social engineering is that
there are no rules
and this is the whole point of
weaponizing psychology
yes we deal with a lot of technical
challenges and we must it's an essential
part of the work but this is also a
behavioral problem how do you go around
telling your employees you shouldn't
talk to strangers you should keep a
secret secret
this is a behavioral issue employees and
managers that can provide access to
technology information or assets become
targets
and they have the responsibility to
protect those assets can they do it do
they have the skills and knowledge
necessary to detect those attacks
not always
and that's the thing cyber security and
security technology has been advancing
but identifying and exploiting human
vulnerabilities also human psychology it
has remained the same across centuries
and across the Globes
the human stimulus response in human
triggers is consistent
and exploiting these figures is also
consistently successful and if you just
think about it from the side of the
threat actors it's efficient it is low
cost it is low risk
and it's high reward because
it works consistently
is it that hard to find somebody's unmet
needs is it that hard to find this one
thing that triggers them
no
we said before that social media is a
gift that keeps on giving we can scout
somebody's digital footprint and we do
that when we conduct vulnerability
assessments and find exactly what makes
them tick because they share it either
explicitly or implicitly in one way or
another or another if there is a digital
footprint there will be traces of
behavioral patterns as well
people that are that have addictions
people that need more money for whatever
reasons for reason people that are
lonely a very human thing these are all
gaps and needs that the third actor can
spot and try to see
and since I have conducted this profiles
on high value targets again these are
the sum of the data points that we have
found we can collect on individuals
only from social media profiles yeah the
locations where do they go where do they
frequent do they go to the gym every so
often do you think attacks only happen
during office hours
no they also happen at the gym they
happen at the golf club they happen
annually at conferences during travel
you have this danger that's suddenly
comes in and starts talking to you
we see what their connections are who
are they key people who do they trust do
they have a family are they lonely they
have nobody did they just divorce
all these are the points that are
collected and could be weaponized
against them in one way or another and
then of course you have the whole
psychological profile you see these
individuals are they extroverted again
there is no problem with you having an
online presence
but the point is you need to know where
to draw the boundaries when you
communicate with others especially when
it comes to practicing certain cyber
security Habits Like downloading
attachments or disclosing sensitive
information
because I know this sounds a bit too
much it is too much
people say against State actors with
spots if you're an extrovert if you're
willing to talk to others which is
perfectly fine they will try to exploit
it though what are your interests what
do you want what do you miss
they go like that
but let's go back to sensitive
information because I feel this gets a
bit overlooked at times
and yes there is a digital layer to what
happens with information but there is
also the human layer of what happens
with information the people that know
about things
it has a very high value think about
business plans strategies biddings
negotiation strategies
also credentials of course also
passwords and access to Systems
Technology and giving entry but yeah
according to the U.S Department of
Defense classified information on the
unauthorized disclosure of classified
information is a communication or
physical transfer of classified
information or controlled unclassified
information to an unauthorized recipient
and this can happen intentionally in the
case of a mistake or in the case of an
Insider thread but it can also happen
unintentionally
when an individual releases this
information out of you and draws them
out in a casual conversation
it has many attackers like cyber
criminal organizations
activists that oppose your company's
moves and what your company stands for
nation states with a geopolitical agenda
journalists that want to to get a good
story out of your business operation and
corporate espionage operatives
again it's not in everybody's straight
model but
critical organizations will belong to
the critical infrastructure are an
extremely attractive Target for these
types of operations
it's like another case study Mia us
who was a fake profile again behind this
fake profile was another state-sponsored
fit doctor likely called kobal tipsy
telecommunications government defense
oil and financial services organizations
in Middle East and North Africa now
miyash was not the original plan the
original plan was simply to send out a
set of fixing emails the numbers game
um yeah massively to a number of
individuals it would eventually deliver
a remote access tool
um but this didn't work they sent out
the phishing email it was royally
unsuccessful and they thought okay
we need the plan B we need to do
something better what would that be and
it was me
it was this
sweet Persona that you see on your
screen right now
side note it's not only women targeted
men they are also males targeting women
it just happens to be that the ones that
are public right now happen to be women
female profiles are getting men but it
can happen to anybody it can happen to
all types of individuals no matter what
their preferences are
so me as again fake identity using
several social media accounts use and
she was used to perform reconnaissance
to collect information on the targets
and to establish their relationship with
them
based on specific Hobbies once again
see who the start the conversation based
on their common interest in photography
and then it would escalate like we said
before to other profiles to different
communication methods
um and you should build a relationship
very casually
and once the email work the working mail
was provided so you would find a rules
she would say something like hey I
really want to deliver my portfolio to
this Challenge and
I would appreciate nothing more than
your opinion can you quickly take it I
have like a 10 minute window to submit
it I was so stressed out to send it out
and now I'm running late with my
deadline uh yes but I'm at work it will
only take five minutes I just want your
precious opinion
the targets downloaded it was like an
extremely successful attack they
downloaded the the attachment and the
remote access tool was delivered to
their machines
what a mess
and how do we defend against this threat
as a general rule there are no rules and
no one is exam that goes to say that oh
everybody needs to know
basic cyber security
uh habits good cyber security habits and
apply them from from the services the
call center that has certain access
information to the high value targets to
the people higher up in higher hue
we talked about elicitation how does
this work yeah we say that schedule
conversation but
there is a technique behind it
a hesitation is an effort in which
seemingly normal conversation is
contrived to extract sensitive
information about individuals their work
and their colleagues how does it sound
like three of the most popular methods
are flattering
this oh you are the only one who can
help me with this one thing that I need
and I value your opinion so much please
help me
flattery second is the familiarity and
the tribe insect
this wasn't another case hey we are both
in the same industry so from one it pro
to another what do you think about this
technology
I don't know I just I just cannot bring
myself to decide whether I want to buy
it for our organization have you used it
was it good do you have some something
else to recommend
I'm just so lost
that's an elicitation technique
and then the third one empathy and the
tendency to complain the tendency to
want to share our programs with others
which is perfectly fine but if
they contain sensitive for information
to ask it to the people that can be
trusted with it
so it goes like this oh you had a
terribly day at work
I know I had one too my boss I don't
know it's just cannot understand the
demands of my work but I'll tell you
about it but first about you what
happened
oh
yeah oh you have this acquisition your
stressed yeah we had one too what's
going on okay maybe I can help
elicitation technique
it's not unknown in the field of
Espionage we are seeing more Espionage
techniques coming and have adapting to
the cyber security
industry to cyber attacks
the defense counterintelligence and
Security Agency gives guidelines on
those but three main rules we don't have
to over complicating things three main
rules to avoid being a victim of
elicitation techniques is knowing what
information should not be shared
being suspicious of the people who ask
or pray around this information
sometimes when you don't answer the
first time around you will notice that
they persist no really tell me now I
really need to know
and you will notice that they have a
particular interest eventually
and yes simple do not tell people of
things they are not authorized to know
even the defense content intelligence
Security Agency they say they say it so
simply don't tell people uh that they're
not authorized to know things that they
are not supposed to know
high value targets the executives
they sometimes need to be handled
differently both because they have an
extremely high they have elevated access
to Information Systems of everything
so they are lucrative targets but they
also need to be handled differently
sometimes
when we work a vulnerability provides on
them and if you need to run
vulnerability profile on them how do you
do it what do you focus on
five main areas what is the criticality
of the role
are they what's their degree of
importance what happens if they get
compromised to a whole lot of things go
wrong after that this is what
criticality points you to so that you
can prioritize a little bit because we
cannot we cannot be everywhere for
everyone and you know
we are limited in terms of resources as
well what's their level of
recognizability do they have a public
profile and by the way by high value
targets I don't normally mean Executives
these are also the people that work in
sensitive projects
are they recognizable would you be able
to find information on them online would
not necessary be able to find out who
they are who are the key people working
in key positions and what is the what
informations out there about them
accessibility is the ease of approach so
if I know they are critical and I know
who they are
can I spot them at the conference okay
nice spot them at the gym can I approach
them online
do they talk do they engage with
strangers online would they have a good
chance with them
and to that place in the their level of
vulnerability as well do I see clear
weaknesses on that individuals like the
ones we talked about before do I see
something that I could readily explode
your adverses will go through this
process and you see they did
and last the key piece if they do
receive this type of attack
or they've been knowledgeable enough to
detect it or know how to handle it or
would they get lost or possibly not
recognize it
uh one important thing is that these
attacks play a lot on ignorance like
most social engineering attacks if you
don't know what the threats or danger
looks like you cannot protect against it
it's a thing how many of you have
educated your boards on these types of
threads or an instantly Security in
general I know that some of you probably
have to deal with boards and Executives
that say oh no no no no no no uh
ignorance is bliss knowledge is a
liability I don't want to hear any of
this I don't want to hear about the
threats I would never be a Target leave
me alone I have other things too other
more important things
to pay attention to like my profit
please
but there are also the boards that are
interested they want and they need to
know about these threads or when you
when you're facing resistance again
don't drop it we should in this is about
their safety the organization's safety I
think we should insist a little bit on
on getting the message through to them
on why cyber security matters
some others will think
this is a way to advance our employees
fall for the simplest fishing attacks I
cannot bother with targeted email
attacks as well I forget it
no I need to come too complicated what
am I gonna do go around and tell people
not to talk to strangers
it's not about that
first of all it's not obvious simplified
complicated threats reports that come
out about social engineering for example
they have for the sake of word count
they have to say that phishing emails is
a top threat
but you see that the way this fishing
email is being delivered also matters to
its effectiveness
so and it's also not
oversimplify now over complicate Simple
Solutions in the end of the day
they need to know what to protect and
where the boundaries are you don't have
to go around and tell them stop talking
to everybody online but you have to tell
them now that what should not be shared
and do not share it for reasons ABCD
I know how to exercise basic cyber
security habits and stick with them and
the way you deliver this message also
matters I believe the keynote speaker
earlier today mentioned a little
something about
providing very boring video trainings
that people just want to click through
and they eventually get totally fed up
with hearing about cyber security
because it's all being a drug and a
necessary evil a necessity they have to
go and click through the slides and
click through the videos while they have
other things to do
no you can provide something more
engaging for them and we should do that
as an industry
and if your employees are safe or
anything for them
simply facing image and this is still a
problem don't just let it be we have to
do something about it attacks are not
going to get any simpler they become
more complicated and more advanced and
we have to be able to catch up one way
or another as a as an industry
it's not a
it's not an unusual I say that might not
happen the probabilities are high that
you will encounter it so yeah
in most case scenarios what have people
that fail victims to cyber attacks
whether this was an elicitation
technique somebody malicious engaging
them online and then falling for it or
spearfishing emails they say and these
are very common quotes by the way oh uh
yeah I thought that something was off I
was not really sure how to respond in
this pair of the moment I just went with
it
that's because of bad training usually
oh yeah I spotted it but then what I I
learned about the threads but
how do I handle it once the person is
pressuring me
that's bad training I others say oh yeah
so it happened I downloaded the file I
knew it was bad but I didn't report it
because I I think they could be
implicated and I didn't want to get
fired
what a bad message what about security
culture it's Such a Pity if your
employees think the thing that's
reporting it we jeopardize their curries
instead of saving their organization
that has to do with again
awareness but also your cyber security
culture
other other people say I was under a lot
of time pressure and my manager was not
appreciate that verification call
why does your manager think that it's
not important to verify certain requests
you see you see the quotes and you spot
the weaknesses that you need to work on
I don't expect anybody to have the
perfect plan and not to have any
weaknesses but these are things we need
to work on security is a process
but we have to do something about this
process and not just let things be
and yes I oh it did not even cross my
mind that I could actually be a Target
I'm not that important
there is a lot of bad training there is
also a bad cyber security culture or
just doing like 15 minutes per year on
what social engineering attacks are and
how they work
in an effective way
if I had only five tips for the
employees they would be yes technology
is still important it does matter to
minimize employee decision making and
use the principle of least privilege
when possible but it's not going to be
enough because we see that retractors
Target them through private channels
so then on top of that good quality
training that actively engages people
that doesn't have them sit passively
behind the screen and just clicking
through clicking through clicking
through but actively engages them and
makes them interested in what's
happening because they are personally
implicated that would go a long way and
seriously if you're going to spend that
money on awareness training make it
worth it get something that's
Interactive
in extend this will help you reinforce
and security mindset within your
organization you will have a trainer and
Advocate coming and building that
mindset within your employees and saying
when in doubt go to this guy right here
who's in your security department and
can talk to you these people are not
strangers they can also communicate with
you I hope you do
and
and ask
and in the air I was on a practical
level it helps to run simulations around
exercises and reinforce good practices
for people to know how to in to detect
and respond to an attack
if you want to take it a step further do
conduct the vulnerability assessment
open source intelligence is essential to
cyber security both on a corporate level
and an individual level for high value
targets if you can have a vulnerability
assessment done on them internally or if
you turn external whatever you prefer
based on those five factors we saw
before it's worth it it can go a long
way and you can take the results of that
assessment put them in the report put
them in the training that they take and
I guarantee you they will be so much
more interested to see that training
that has a vulnerability assessment done
on them in a diplomatic and non-usatory
manner they will be so much more
interested to hear what's happening than
thus getting an out of the box classic
standardized cyber security awareness
training that has
some things that relate to them some
things that don't relate to them and in
the end of the day I want to do other
things
the good news
neuroplasticity I'm so thankful for this
part of my studies
so we learned that
our brains are capable of creating new
behavioral Pathways that can become
automatic so for everybody that is
totally frustrated and defeated with the
fact that oh we've done so many security
trainings and the materials just don't
get through this just tells you you need
to find a different way to communicate
the material neuroplasticity says that
you can teach Old Dogs new tricks you
can create new a new neural Pathways and
if you do it in an engaging way
eventually people will be able to create
automatic mental Pathways they see the
trigger they see the red flag and they
automatically think okay I've heard
about this before I should be careful
let's
stay on the safe side
that's the whole point of
neuroplasticity these things will
eventually become automatic and your
people won't have to spend mental energy
on them I've seen this happening
thankfully there is hope
this is a topic that in general explains
both deep and wide
we only have a few minutes here but if
you are interested I definitely
recommend you read the excitation guide
from the defense counterintelligence and
Security Agency they talk about the
elicitation techniques you could I lent
parts from these guys and put them in
your awareness training if you want
or if you're interested in the keychain
and more details about General Social
Engineering attacks I also wrote a more
a length year article that you can also
get some information from
overall I hope you take it seriously I
know it's difficult I know it's a
process Nobody's Perfect it's fine
but don't just let it be and don't give
up on your people thinking they are just
useless
there are things we can do
thank you very much for being here
[Applause]
and I think we can take a few questions
while we still have five minutes yes
hi there's one thing I was really
interested thank you for the interesting
talk by the way but there's one thing
you said that I want to hear if you
could explain why this is you said that
we should expect more of these attacks
in the future
what are the mechanisms that are driving
that what are the mechanisms of that are
driving an increase
the mechanisms are driving the increase
there they seem to uh reward that they
get the fact that they are successful
makes their doctors say that okay this
is something that works more
consistently so I won't be spending time
and resources on attacks that have a 50
rate of success when I can just get this
type of attack that has a way higher
rate of success and I can do more things
with it
yes we have been observing it we hear
more and more cases like three or four
years ago we didn't have as many cases
as we have today with people being
approached through social media and
getting Pride I to complain for whatever
reason about their companies we see a
lot more of this I think I think they do
it because they say it works and they
see they can do a lot through it
yeah I I got a question I got them in
microphone sorry
um I am a pen tester and when I work to
assess vulnerability on the system it's
usually not the the one who projects uh
the project but some platforms that are
used to development integration and so
on
uh my question is when you do the
vulnerability assessments on human
beings there is not a platform on which
you can test whatever you want because
you can do some eventually damages uh
including psychological damages if you
try to threaten
or try to flirt with someone that is
married or I don't know so I believe
that you draw a line somewhere
that's real attackers don't so how do
you deal with that and where is the the
line you most certainly draw a line you
cannot approach it this is a a fantastic
point of view exactly because we deal
with some ethical lines here but this is
why you draw the risk profile and you
have the people you explain to the
people why this is important for them
they have to give you their approval on
running a test and using their social
media and they do believe me the ones
that feel uh that understand the threat
and they know what it can mean for them
if they trust the service provider
they're going to say please
but of course you ensure confidentiality
of course you ensure that you have a
trusting relationship and that you treat
them with dignity and respect
but it is it is happening
the vulnerability profile uh the risk
profile these things do not you do not
have to engage with um with the Target
in a way that involves them
psychologically but you just take out
the information you find online from
their own digital footprint and you tell
them look uh this is one attack Vector
my abc these vulnerabilities this is how
we have been observing three doctors
exploiting this information what do you
want to do you want to eliminate them do
you want to also gain the knowledge that
you might encounter ABC types of attacks
this is usually how we go about it
they know they will not be they know
they will be researched but not engaged
with
no because you don't ask them to respond
to it you ask them to to give you
permission to go through their digital
footprint
and show them what could be used against
them
so there is
now I'm not gonna chat with them I I
know that if I chat with them and I use
ABCD trigger points they are likely to
respond and this is how we approach it
but you do not have to pair it with them
yes I wondered while trying to protect
your company for example
there is
we might have a risk maybe to change the
mood inside the company because while
saying to people okay be aware
of the question you are asked
they will change their behavior also and
maybe your company might become an
company less
friendly regarding the outside and also
inside there is a
valid question what happens when we uh
when we rain threads on our people and
tell them don't don't engage online with
strangers but this is exactly where the
danger yeah lies you do not want to tell
them remove your social media profile
don't talk with anyone online no it's
what the what we talked about
right here from the defense
counterintelligence and Security Agency
talk with them talk with everybody have
your online profile but
nowhere to when to draw their boundaries
and what boundaries to draw what does
that person that is talking with you
what shouldn't they know about your
company and maintain that boundary
in a healthy way
that's what it is about because of
course many of us need to have many
companies as well they need to have an
online presence they need to engage with
customers online or with Partners
business partners but the boundaries
this is a my last point we talked about
not over complicating our Solutions in
the end it is about maintaining
security best practices
thank you
yes we can have one more
you choose
I'll take one thank you very much for an
interesting talk it's good to be back at
that slide do you have any evidence that
that works do are people able to set
boundaries and maintain them once
they're approached with the right
trigger points aren't they facing with
professionals who can try out n
different trigger points with different
online fake personalities until it
finally Works
uh yes there is evidence that this works
because people end up reporting it and
saying hey I've been receiving these
communications and I feel extremely
uncertain about it and then
they go and ask their cyber security
department which comes and asks us
sometimes I also we have evidence that
it works now of course you can have
persistent threats that try to find this
one angle that will work but it comes
down to how
a perceptive the target is how
knowledgeable they are in terms of
spotting
it is about risk management in there and
increasing your defense probabilities
against cyber threats you hope that they
will keep recognizing suspicious
activity when it happens also sometimes
when you have the state doctor trying to
pry from every young different profile
these individuals end up realizing that
okay I must be
pretty valuable for them and now
I don't want to have to deal with this
anymore and decide to must block
everybody for a bit
so there is also that happening but it
works
okay one thing it won't work with
everybody because
people are people but it's about raising
your probability
yeah okay thank you very much
was very interesting and thank you for
the questions we'll have 10 minutes
break before the next talk so feel free
to
to work around if you want