um good afternoon and Welcome to our
seeing your way to the blockchain as we
will soon learn uh this is what a
decentralized identifier looks like and
this is here as the obligatory Omi slide
um my name is jacket Raynor I'm a
principal security researcher at Cyber
Arc Labs where recently I've been doing
a lot of blockchain and decentralized
Technology research but not exclusively
here are some of my interests in case
you want to start a conversation after
this session I highly highly encourage
you to do so
let me start by asking you two questions
and then I will tell you a couple of
short stories
the first question is who owns your
identity
now you may be thinking what do you mean
eye on my identity but it might not be
as straightforward as that
the second question is by show of hands
do you use any service by the following
companies
yeah almost everyone not surprisingly
um now now I'm not saying that the two
questions are necessarily related
however some of you may already see
where I'm going with that
now for the two stories the first one is
about an Australian artist she had been
documenting her life's work on Instagram
um under the metaverse handle on the
platform
and as you know not too long ago
Facebook changed their company name to
meta and they also launched the
metaverse product and they really wanted
the metaverse handle so what happened
they just took it from her and of course
he had no say about that
and the second story is about a father
from the U.S he took a few naked
pictures of his child for the doctor of
course he was using Google Images at the
time and Google flagged his account as a
criminal account or something along
those lines
um and he got completely locked out of
all of his accounts and those of you who
use Google you know just how devastating
this thing might be
so now let me ask you again who really
owns your identity
now let's keep thinking about that while
I covered the agenda for today
first we're going to have an
introduction for decentralized identity
and try to understand what it really
means after that we will take a look at
a couple of decentralized identity
implementations and see how they work
then we will try and break one of those
implementations and finally we will wrap
things up with a summary and we'll speak
a little bit about the future of this
technology
and let's get going with the
introduction
so in order to understand decentralized
identity we need to First Define what
our identity is
and it can be a bit tricky
um in the real world for instance our
identity is comprised by a few things
like our finger prints for instance and
a bunch of papers that we hold like a
passport and so on but it can be even
trickier to Define our identity in the
digital space or in cyberspace or online
however you want to refer to it
we can look at identity as if it's
comprised out of two layers online the
first is the identifiers layer this is
pretty much anything that points other
people to us so for example a Twitter
handle or an email address
on top of that we have the actual
identity data and this is pretty much
anything that is part of who we are
online it can be photos that we upload
um messages we send to our friends
tweets we post and so on and so forth
and today most of those identifiers and
the data if not all those are controlled
by the companies that we mentioned
before
and by no means I'm saying that those
companies are evil in any sense however
we do know that they have a completely
different set of incentives and
interests than the one we have and we
saw that it can be problematic and this
is exactly where decentralized identity
comes in and the idea is to take our
identities back in our own hands and we
can do that by storing them in some sort
of a decentralized and distributed and
secure location and today the best thing
we know for it is of course the
blockchain
now in order to understand the
difference between between centralized
identity and decentralized identity we
can look at a similar difference between
our traditional monetary systems and
cryptocurrency
where in the traditional sense let's say
we have a bank we know that it is a
centralized entity controlled by one
entity we know that they are the only
ones who hold let's call it the database
of the balances of everybody's accounts
and we don't have a physical or
technical access to our assets even
though we own some money in it
and with cryptocurrency of course we
know that it is decentralized and the
database of balances or The Ledger is
distributed across many different nodes
in a network and we know that we are uh
in control of that money
um using of course our private key that
we keep safe and keep secure and this is
the only way technically to transfer
money out of our accounts and this is
the main difference between the two
now in an identity context it would look
something like this where we will still
have a wallet of course and this wallet
will contain our private keys that are
associated with our identity
but instead of monetary transactions we
can have identity operations so things
like creating an identity updating it
revoking it and so on
and both those operations as well as the
public keys that are associated with our
identities will be stored in some sort
of a distributed Ledger or a blockchain
and the simple use case will be as
follows first we can create an identity
by just generating a pair of
cryptographic keys then we publish those
keys to the blockchain publish the
public key of course and we keep the
private key safe
um then we can use those keys we can
either sign or encrypt information using
our private key so that later others in
the network can ver verify and validate
the information indeed originated from
us
now decentralized identifiers are now
already standard by w3c alongside
verifiable credentials and they look
something like this where first up top
you can see here we have the identifier
itself it's comprised out of the ID
which stands for decentralized identity
then we have the example here stands for
the did method or we can refer to it as
the did implementation or protocol and
after that we have the actual identifier
the unique identifier of our identity
we can treat it as if it's a
cryptocurrency wallet address if you
want
then this identifier resolves into a
decentralized identity document which is
some sort of a Json which will primarily
contain the public key associated with
our identity and depending on the
implementation it can contain many other
types of information
now a quick word on the ID method so as
I mentioned
um there are many different methods and
the standard is implementation agnostic
we can go all the way from just using it
statically so I can generate a pair of
keys write my private key on a piece of
paper and just start to use that this
way but we have a lot of other types of
implementations and we will see a couple
of those in just a bit
now finally for the introduction part in
terms of use cases what can we actually
do with decentralized identity
um in my opinion at least the sky is the
limit and we can do pretty much anything
we do online better with decentralized
identity
think about verifiable credentials where
for instance your government can issue
you a verifiable credential as your
passport so it will be cryptographically
verifiable and you can store it on your
phone or maybe you can securely message
your friends directly without the need
to have some third party in the middle
like signal or telegram or Whatsapp or
even social media where nobody can get
censored and of course no Tech
billionaire can just buy the company and
do whatever they like to it
um again the sky's the limit
so let's take a look at a few examples
when I started to work on decentralized
identity technology
um a couple of implementation Studio
the first one we will cover it very very
briefly it was a layer 2 solution and
Layer Two in the blockchain sense it
means that we have a new layer which is
built on top of an already established
blockchain
and this one it stood out because it was
by the tech giant Microsoft it was
called Microsoft intra and basically
they built a network called the identity
overlay Network or ion which is an
identity layer that sits on top of
Bitcoin which is an already established
blockchain
so I don't want to get too much into the
details here I was able to find two very
minor issues in Microsoft intra I have a
blog post on that if you like to learn
more about the technology and the issues
I will link it at the end but I just
wanted to bring to your attention that
we have a lot of types of decentralized
identity networks and implementations
and this is one layer two solution
but the rest of the session will focus
on a different one and this one is an
actual identity Ledger or it is an
actual blockchain that was developed
specifically for identity purposes
and this is what is called Sovereign or
The Sovereign Network
it's operated by The Sovereign
Foundation which is a non-profit
organization and they aim to build a
public service enabling self-sovereign
identity on the internet
um and this project stood out because it
was by far the most mature one
um recently they celebrated five years
of being in production already so this
was the reason I chose to go with it
um and basically The Sovereign network
is a network deployment of a blockchain
called hyperledger indie
it's an identity Centric blockchain it
was developed under the hyperledger
foundation they are an open source group
they build a lot of decentralized
applications and they sit under the
Linux foundation so this is the context
for this project
and the hyperliger Indy um as I said
it's quite a lucrative Target for
attackers because of sovereign but not
only that they are also the base for
other decentralized identity networks
which are already in production like the
verified organizational Network in
Canada operated by the governments of
Canada and British Columbia the national
decentralized identity Network in Canada
also a product by IBM those are the more
prominent ones so again hyperlodgerendy
is quite a good Target for attackers
um as we mentioned it is a distributed
Ledger or it is an actual blockchain
implementation
um I assumed it would have high coding
standards and high code quality and high
levels of maturity because again it was
in production for quite some time
already
um it is identity Centric and this means
that identity operations are not an
afterthought like they can be in some
layer 2 Technologies
the blockchain was developed in Python
and maybe most interestingly it is a
permissioned blockchain and let me
explain
so the blockchains that we probably all
know and love like Bitcoin or ethereum
are both public and this means that
anybody can read information off the
blockchain and they are also
permissionless and this means that
anybody can set up a node and start to
build blocks and validate transactions
and actually write to the chain but we
also have some private blockchains for
instance like Enterprise ethereum where
not everybody can read information from
the blockchain
and in hyperledger Indie we see a
blockchain which is public so anybody
can read information from it but it's
permissioned and this means that only
very specific organizations are allowed
to operate a node and to participate in
the consensus algorithm
and those organizations are set are
defined by the network operator in a
governance document when you create the
network so
Rick does raise a good point here and
you might be thinking kind of the same
thing and it is a valid point however
permission blockchains are being used
currently and they have their use cases
of course they also have some advantages
so first of all if we look at efficiency
and cost effectiveness of course they
are more efficient because you don't
need to have as many nodes in order to
operate the network properly it's quite
clear
they also add a layer of client trust
because if you think about it let's say
we have a permissioned network we can
have let's say 20 or 30 nodes that are
actually validating transactions and as
end users we can know those nodes by
their public keys and this means that
whenever we try to read or to ask
somebody to read information from the
chains and give it to us we can make
sure that indeed all the nodes or that
enough nodes agree on this information
that we're getting and it's not being
modified in the way in any way
and of course in terms of disadvantages
we have the centralization factor which
is of course uh permission networks are
more centralized there's no way around
that
um and also security kind of suffers
because if you think about it let's say
as an attacker you get control over 30
Bitcoin nodes doesn't help you very much
unless it's 50 or more of the node in
the chain however if we're talking about
a permission chain which only has like
30 nodes in some cases we are looking at
a different scenario
so hyperledger Indie the blockchain
itself or the node itself is operated by
two projects
um the first one is in the planum which
gives it the the consensus layer of the
network and the second one is in the
node and we denote is the actual
identity layer and this is what we're
going to focus on in this session
and in a high level overview the network
looks kind of like this where we have
the green nodes which are the validator
nodes or the permission nodes that are
set in the governance document
those are the only nodes that can
actually write to the network
then we also have some read-only nodes
and anybody can set up a read-only node
and start to read information from the
chain you don't need to have any
permissions to that to do that
and the number of nodes is set by the
following formula is equals to three f
plus one uh F being the maximum number
of malicious nodes allowed in the
network and this is a feature of the
consensus algorithm
the nodes communicate with other nodes
and other clients in the network using
the zero mq protocol which is an
authenticated TCP based protocol and the
consensus algorithm itself is called
rbft
rbft stands for redundant Byzantine
fault tolerance you may know bft already
it's a consensus algorithm from 1982 a
bunch of generals were trying to uh
trying to decide whether to attack or
Retreat and they try to do that even
considering some of the generals were
malicious or Byzantine and this is what
allowed them to do that and this is also
what allows the network to come to a
consensus even if some of the nodes are
malicious a small fraction of them and
we're doing it redundantly it just means
we have a few instances of BFD running
together and it helps to increase the
network throughput and latency
so this is about the consensus algorithm
now in terms of The Ledger or the
database itself it's actually comprised
out of four different ledgers each with
its own role the first one is the domain
Ledger this one is the one which is most
relevant for us today
um this is the one that actually
contains the identity operations or
identity transactions
as you can see here then we also have
the pool Ledger pool being the group of
all the nodes that we have in the
network
then we also have the config Ledger
which holds some configuration Global
configuration regarding the entire pool
and lastly we have the audit Ledger and
this Ledger is just here in order to
synchronize the other ledgers together
because we need to know whether one
transaction in one Ledger happened
before or after the transaction in a
different ledger so this is here to do
that
and now we have enough Basics and we can
start to look at some vulnerabilities
and try to find find out how to break
this kind of network
so whenever I approach a project like
this it's always important to have Focus
um because again we have a lot of moving
Parts here and it's important to to stay
on track
um and this time I chose to focus on the
Indie node itself on the identity layer
um first of all because when we're
talking about blockchain the most
interesting code is usually the code
that operates the node because this is
what gives the the blockchain live
um and this this is what I chose to work
on
and the first thing I usually do is to
look at some prior work that was done in
this field and in decentralized identity
as a whole I only could find two
vulnerabilities two CVS and
coincidentally they both were in hyper
Ledger Indie
um so this is an example for one of them
I don't want to get into the details but
the node just gets an invalid request
that causes it to misbehave in the
consensus context in some sense
um here's just the the diff of the code
you can see that an invalid timestamp
was handed to the node then it causes a
Havoc but we only need to keep the type
of vulnerability in mind while we
continue
so before starting to actually look at
the code I also like to map the inputs
and outputs of the system and see what
the attack surface for attackers is
so first of all of course we have The
Ledger uh we can cause some information
to be written to The Ledger and later
other nodes read from the same Ledger
this is one attack surface and the other
one which is a bit more substantial is
the request handers so the node
implements a lot of request handlers uh
that it can get both from users in the
system as well as other nodes and this
was an area which was also pretty well
documented so it's a good start and
generally speaking we have two types of
requests the first one of course is a
read request and uh you don't have to
have any uh permissions in order to to
do that of course because we are in a
public blockchain and both other nodes
and users can perform those requests
and then we also have some write
requests and those ones of course are
authenticated because you need to have
permissions in order to do them
and also some of those are authorized
and this is because we have different
types of roles in the network which I
haven't mentioned before
so with the request handlers in mind I
wanted to start by statically analyzing
the code
first because it's usually easier to do
than to look for vulnerabilities
manually and we also have a python code
base and the code was fairly simple and
very well structured and I tried to do
that and basically I uh I used codeql
which is a static code analysis
framework by GitHub it basically lets
you treat your code as an SQL database
and I ran a few queries of generic
python vulnerabilities and I also try to
characterize the vulnerabilities we saw
before
of the node getting some untrusted
information and then pass it passing it
on to another external function let's
call it
and unfortunately this time it didn't
yield any results
um I just wanted to leave that here in
case for you to know that I do think
that it's a very important uh stage in
the research process and the potential
is very big because you can find some
low hanging fruits this way but
unfortunately not this time if you're
interested in talking a little bit about
uh those queries please come and talk to
me later
um but now there's no choice and we have
to take a look at the code up close so I
cloned the repository and as you can see
everything was very nicely organized and
again very extensively documented they
even had some flowcharts of the request
handling process of different types of
requests so again very nice and some
documents about how the request handling
is done so I started to go over all of
the request handlers one by one and I
started to look for some interesting
areas in the code and by interesting
areas I mean the following
first the use of uninitialized data or
maybe
areas where the node doesn't check
whether information actually exists in
the request and just starts to use that
secondly a lack of input validation
which is kind of straightforward
then a requests that have high code
complexity as you know those areas tend
to be more prone to vulnerabilities
and finally I was also looking for
discrepancies between uh what the code
ultimately implemented and what the
documentation specified the code should
do
this is one of the request handlers just
to give you a feel of how it looks like
as you can see again everything seems
very well structured and it looks like
the developers really know what they're
doing every request Handler inherits
from one of two abstract classes either
a read request Handler or a write
request Handler and they also need to
implement some virtual functions for
different checks and validations
so soon enough I encountered one request
Handler called the pool upgrade Handler
which was very interesting
and it's for a few reasons first of all
it's a write request Handler so
inherently it's a bit more interesting
than a real request one then it has
upgrade in the name and upgrading the
system is usually a very sensitive
process
and most importantly I found the
discrepancy between what the
documentation specified and what was
actually implemented in the code so
let's have a look
on the left here we have the
documentation and we will start with
that we see that the full upgrade is a
command to upgrade the pool again pool
being the group of all the nodes it is
sent by a trustee which is a very
privileged role in the network
and it says that it upgrades the
specified nodes
um okay
based on the parameters documented we
see that we need to supply a version
string and this is the version of the
Indie node package we want to upgrade to
so it seems simple enough we will
provide some number as a string in the
request and the in the node package will
get upgraded to that specified version
okay so now let's have a look at the
code
and doing that we quickly see that we
have one undocumented parameter being
processed by the node
and based on the error string it looks
like it is a package name that we want
to upgrade so maybe we can upgrade
another package not only the Indie node
one like the documentation specified
so at this point I was already quite
intrigued and I wanted to find out
exactly what's happening with this
undocumented package parameter so let's
do that
so the first thing uh done here is the
node checks whether the parameter exists
or not and then it passes it on to the
next function that is called check
upgrade possible to probably check
whether the upgrade is possible
um in this function we see that the
parameter is just being passed to the
next one to get probably some current
information on what's now installed on
the Node
and let's follow that
and here we can see again it's just been
passed to the next function to get
current info on the package currently
installed
and here we can actually see some
functionality finally implemented
as you see the node composes the command
dpkg minus S Plus our supplied
undocumented package parameter and then
it executes this command as a shell
command
so at this point I thought
um okay this might not be the way I
would Implement something like this it's
a bit weird but let's go ahead and see
what kind of sanitizations or checks
they implemented uh on the input that we
provide
so
in the compose command function as you
can see we have no sanitizations
whatsoever
and if you continue to the Run shell
command as you can see we're simply
running it with sub process and no
checks are being made here
so
um at this point I thought that I must
have missed the sanitizations or input
checks
um and uh because again this can't
really be a 90s style command ejection
vulnerability kind of thing right
right
so I decided to to write it in my notes
and to continue to finish going over all
of the request handlers
and then at the end I will set up some
testing environment and execute this
command and I see exactly where the
checks that I was missing were
so I try to do that and it turned out to
be quite of a hassle because
um of course I cloned the repo and just
try to execute it as they mentioned but
it didn't work and finally I ended up
using a different branch of this in the
node repository that they uh suggested I
would do
finally it was working inside of a Dev
container
long story short I had a testing
environment running and lucky enough
luckily they also had a quite an
extensive pie test framework for their
code and it allowed me to easily start a
new network run a few nodes locally
create client wallets send requests and
so on so it was kind of nice
um so this is the first thing I did uh
this is one uh testing file I wrote
um and as you can see we are sending a
pull upgrade request with the
undocumented package parameter we Supply
a package name then a semicolon and then
a command touch slash Pawn to create a
pawn file in the root directory
so spoiler I tried to execute this and
no Pawn file was created
um and I said okay that makes sense
let's find out why let's find the
sanitizations that I was missing
um and I started digging into the logs
and the code but I couldn't find any
sanitizations
um so naturally I added a few print
statements in different places in the
node and also then weirdly enough my
print my printing weren't working
um so I dug in a little deeper until I
found this file this is a confist file
and if you're familiar with bytest you
know that this file is being executed
every time you run some tests
and as you can see what they're doing
here is basically patching out the very
function that I'm trying to test and
this makes sense because in a testing
context you don't really care about
packages that are installed on the on
the server you're you're testing on
um so I had to patch out this batching
function and then I tried to execute it
again and let's see what happened
so now we're checking that there's no
Pawn file first and this is the test
file I showed you before with the pull
upgrade request
now we're going to uh start the test
and the network is now being Genesis and
a few nodes are being executed locally
then we create a client wallet and send
this request and now once we're done we
see that we have a slash bone file so
this means that we have code execution
um okay thank you thank you
[Applause]
so first naturally I was very happy
because this is an rce but then I was
also kind of concerned because as I
mentioned hyperhead during the is the
base for many different production level
decentralized identity Networks
um but then I remembered that the
documentation said that the pull upgrade
request should only be sent by a trustee
right
so
those of you in smart contract security
probably know the secure coding pattern
checks FX interactions this is basically
just a guideline for programmers on the
order they need to perform specific
actions in order to reduce attack
surface for attackers in re-entrancy
vulnerabilities
but you may not be aware of a much more
ancient uh secure coding pattern that is
reserved only to the most secure
applications it's called the authorized
do
where first you authorize the action
you're about to perform and only then
you perform it and if we take a look at
the uh pull upgrade request Handler I
know you cannot read it but this is
where we can trigger the vulnerable code
and this is where the authorization
happens
so again this is where the vulnerable
code lies and this is the authorization
part so unfortunately anybody in the
network can just send this and Trigger
DRC
so I don't mean to disrespect the Indie
team because they are authorizing the
actual upgrade process but as you saw
the vulnerability lies in the let's call
it pre-processing of this request
so um let's try to get out of the um
testing contest context and
um build an actual exploit So the plan
is as follows first we're going to
create a new did because we have to have
a decentralized identifier in order to
send requests in the network but again
no permissions are required for that
anybody can just create a new random
identifier
then we're going to construct our highly
sophisticated payload with the
undocumented package parameter semicolon
and then let's put a reverse python
Shellder
then we need to set up the zero mq
socket um
to the node we want to to exploit and
send it using that
after that we have stage four and then
we make profit of course
so this is the exploit the most
important part here is the actual
request that we're about to send as you
can see we have the package parameter
with the payload we also need to supply
some schedule for this so-called upgrade
these are just public identifiers of
some of the nodes and a timestamp in the
future
um and finally of course all of these
need to be signed by our newly generated
identity which again requires no
permissions at all
then we're going to construct the zmq
socket and in order to do that we also
need to know the public key of the node
we're about to communicate with
um but again it's just public
information and finally we just send it
so let's see it in action on the left we
have uh everything running inside of the
dev container and this is where I'm
going to run the network and a few nodes
and on the right we have the attacker
um down the attacker is listening with
netcat of course and we are in a second
about to send our malicious payload
and as you can see we have a connection
and we do have a reverse shell so it's
quite a success for the attacker in this
case
um
thank you
so after that I was again quite happy
and concerned at the same time and after
a brief look at the logs I found this
so as you can see it says something
about
propagation being made so I turn to the
documentation again and as you can see
it says that if the node has not seen
the request before it broadcasts the
request to all of the nodes in a
propagate
so this means that an anonymous attacker
can send just one request to one of the
nodes in the in the network and
compromise the entire network so this
was quite crazy
um okay so if we go back to our exploit
plan we had uh stage four and because
we're not in a decentralized finance
system and we don't have a bunch of
tokens to steal and get rich what can we
actually do with that
so basically
when we have this capability there is
nothing stopping us from compromising
any identity in the network
and I'll tell you exactly how first of
all of course we can execute code on any
of the Indie nodes either just by
sending them our payload or by using the
convenient propagate functionality that
we just saw
after we have code execution on the
nodes we can again nothing stopping us
from actually changing modifying our
domain Ledger our domain Ledger database
locally because it's just a local
database on the Node
and of course we can also plant a back
door in the Indie node code itself it's
just some python code that is running on
the server and there's nothing stopping
us from doing that as well
now we're still not done and because
this is a decentralized system
in order to compromise an identity we
can't just steal the private keys
because they are uh
in the hands of the user and not
anywhere in the network itself
um however by changing some uh by
writing some new or changing some
existing
um transactions in the database we can
point the user's identity the target
identity to a set of keys that we are in
control of and also we can insert a
backdoor again that will accept invalid
key rotation operation for the Target
did that we would like to to compromise
so again nothing stopping an anonymous
attacker from compromising any identity
in the network
so it really is uh Our Roots that give
us our identity
um and of course
um this issue was reported and fixed by
the Indie team
um I just want to bring to your
attention the CVSs score of this issue
as you can see it's a 10 out of 10. so
on the one hand we have a very simple
vulnerability however the impact on the
actual network is devastating and this
is why we see a Discord
so now let's wrap things up uh with some
thoughts on the future of this
technology
first of all let me tell you that I am
rooting for this technology though uh
the state of decentralized identity that
we saw today seems kind of Bleak I do
think that the future is right for it
um but as you saw we do need some more
security people working in this field so
please come and join me don't leave me
hanging
um next in terms of the security of
those systems decentralized identity
systems and decentralized uh systems as
a whole and blockchain systems they come
with big promises like being completely
decentralized and more secure and we
know that this is not necessarily the
case as with every new technology they
bring new attack surfaces and present
them to attackers as well as like we saw
still remaining potentially remaining
vulnerable to some of the old more
traditional attack surfaces
then I also think we need to reconsider
our modules I really don't think that
the tech giant like Microsoft should own
a decentralized identity system if you
want to see it getting popular and I'm
also not sure that a permission model of
a blockchain is what is suitable in this
case
then in terms of future work there has
been some developments in the field uh
since I last worked on that so I am
planning to work on some new
implementations of decentralized
identity that came out recently and
again please come and join me
um so I'm going to leave you with this
quote
um
this is my Twitter handle please talk to
me about anything blockchain or
decentralized identity related here is
the blog of cyber collabs where we have
a lot of information on what I discussed
here today and also some stuff I left
out
um and like to thank you very much for
joining this session
thank you
and now if you have any questions I
think we we still have time
yes we do
uh hey thanks for the great talk
um so I was wondering how did the update
process went because when you have such
a vulnerability the problem is that
people need to update and if they've
done this you can still own them yeah
actually that's a good question and this
is another advantage of a permission
Network
um I I talked today in the team and they
were able to of course create a fix and
before they disclosed it publicly they
were able to coordinate with all of the
network operators of the the major
networks and to to make them fix the
issue before uh making it public so
again it's another advantage of the
permission model and I hope that you
could also see that if someone else
exploited it because the transactions
are public
um are known at least think about this
no this is not the request Handler is
not handling the transaction oh okay in
this case this is like an API just yeah
exactly so that's not great
unless well some of the operators maybe
monitor the network and look yeah I
guess so they haven't uh told me that it
has been exploited in the wild but I
guess we can never really know okay
thanks
any more questions
all right
thanks for the talk
um have you checked by code ql didn't
find the sub process call yeah this is
another good question
um
actually it was my first time using
codeql with python and and it had quite
a lot of issues
um essentially the idea behind the the
queries that I wrote should have found
this issue but because of a lot of
issues with with python it just didn't
work so not not exactly sure
any more questions
all right thank you very much
[Music]