okay i pronounced hey sandy do you want
to run with them with the minutes
or jeffrey
i have a
presentation
two presentations
okay true
i send it here
yeah but you don't like maybe hard for
her
yeah okay
yeah the problem if i open the minutes
tool i don't see anything else so that
doesn't work particularly well
and i can get into this stuff twice
it's any kind of a trick for the whole
thing that is not very well thought out
uh open a new tab okay yeah they have
something all right
good so i think it's time to start we
are on time
so
topic is 112 so we need to change this
topic which i'll do soon so welcome to
beer session at ita 113
tony p jr
so i'm the delegate and
let's start
tony p is going to talk about what's
going on and provide an update
all right so you're sharing the slides
jf right
yep
and you can show up your face as well so
we remember how you look like nah my
office too messy
okay the usual note well i think we've
seen that in every group about a million
times so i won't you know chew through
that stuff unless jeff wants to go once
over in the game
[Music]
so please read not well it defines how
your contribution to atf are treated and
before you start contributing to atf you
really should know but not well
all right
uh yeah
yeah no the media echo is good yeah
buttons are changing it's getting better
and better
so if you
if you participate in
person please check in so your name gets
on blue shade
if you want to talk at the mic please
get in line draw the tool and then come
to the mic and don't forget to state
your name
for remote participant don't forget to
turn video and audio off unless you're
going to speak
and
yeah
so minutes are
at the
url provided please make sure that
whatever you say is correct
please pick stuff if you see it's wrong
funny
yes sorry since i have to take minutes
out of the over typing all right so
agenda simple we do the status then uh
we have small prezzo
jeffrey this is the stuff that was
non-ether now the code's non-mpls um so
this is all the stuff that we need to
encode in non-mpls case then let's talk
about the um io am stuff that was
suggested in basically oem in general
classes minuses because there's a couple
of proposals
um uh being tossed around um
then uh the brfr stuff comes up again i
see
uh actually
i'm i'm lost where i said on the agenda
okay i'm kind of i lost it here then we
talk about the brh beer stuff i guess
again
if there is anything to be talked about
and then we do the general delivery
function with staff is interesting
especially with all the oem suggestions
and fragmentation coming up with you
know goes across multiple different
technologies um all right
so we fire off the status
all right so there
be a bar
ipa i think jeffrey closed all the
comments it's on alvaro
um
pim single is waiting for a document to
be referenced the the architecture is
kind of all sued up i saw everything has
been addressed pretty much
um
the
ospf b3 is hanging
in publication
next one please
uh all right so yeah that is the
ethernet goes into non-mpls jeffrey will
be talking about the stuff next one
uh
right so the pattern q discovery is
waiting for uh write up and ping is also
waiting for the write up so i assume
there'll be some kicking needed okay
the uh bgpls vr is expired idr didn't
react um
the ibr extensions
uh the draft has been expired so we you
know we have to go and look for authors
again or revive the stuff
um
and the multicast hp response yeah sorry
also exactly so that the draft is being
replaced replaced as a presentation
today sorry that's where i got lost
because i still have you know the
multicast http response the
brfr has been merged everything is kind
of ready there is one um
mailing list
stuff uh oh yeah i should probably talk
about the git quickly
which would need to be addressed uh for
the adoption i think it has been brought
up during the adoption call
and multicast as a service will be
presented today
uh we'll see what the author calls for
adoption
i'm i will work the queue over once
withdraw the status next one please
all right so that's kind of the status
uh jeffrey you have the mic
um yes the
our ipa drafts um
thanks for alvaro to review it and we
had quite some uh rounds to discuss
what's the best language there
um and yet need to do it one more
revision i haven't got that done yet
should be simple change and then
we should you should be
able to move forward
so about the
um
martingales as a service uh
well i'm not presenting it today but
indeed it was presented before and we
call uh we wanted to do an adoption call
by that time there were a lot of drafts
to be to be called and so
we were we uh i was so that we would uh
pace out and i think now it's time to to
to do it now but i'm not presenting
today uh i think
that's that's about it from me
okay so i take that stuff uh as adoption
call going to the list for the beers
multicast as a service okay
and thanks for the correction on the idr
um
okay please state uh
name and affiliation we're coming up
with the mic it will help the people
online alvaro you have the mic
hello
um
so i wanna
the deck is not there anymore but i want
to go back to the uh dear freshly route
uh draft
i notice there have been
several requests from the authors on the
list
to adopt
and i haven't seen maybe i missed in the
last couple days i hadn't seen any reply
on what are the open issues
uh now i see here that there's a link to
the github
yes sorry so yes
andrew actually uh suggested that we
have some kind of a repository where we
can have a history per draft of all the
issues that have been addressed and what
is outstanding
and we went back with greg back and
forth and with the secretary and we
decided that uh the best approach will
be basically to go on to github because
of the history requirements right that
the tracker doesn't allow us to really
have a history of stuff that was going
on
so
the best format seems to be go to get on
the github and have a git per draft and
on this draft we will keep basically
running pokemon will be committing into
git
because that will give us a perfect
history how the stuff is developing um
sure so i don't have a problem with that
so what i wanted to do is highlight two
points one is
the
lack of response on the list
that if you already replied then that's
great
so yes candy send your replied actually
with that stuff because we were
converging you think what should we do
how should we reply and we decided to
generation
that's right
the other thing that we need you to do
is figure out as a working group
how you're going to use github
it's fine if you want to
and there are many things you can do
with github right you can do
everything from the development of the
draft you can just track issues
how are the issues that are being
discussed in github going to be
reflected to the list
or not
is everyone expected to go get an
account on github and follow the issues
there
yeah they're going to happen only for
drafts that are adopted
or not
this one is not adopted of course yet
so you know
there needs to be a policy for the
working group that is clear and everyone
knows about it
there's a couple of drafts that um
the git working group produced last year
on recommendations on how to
um
do all this right only how to set up the
repository which you already did which
is great but also on on the different
decision points that need to be made
that need to be made right
because you know whatever issues are
discussed on github are not
automatically reflected on the list yeah
unfortunately right okay there's a note
well issue and you know all that other
stuff so please take a look at the git
um
yes i forget the numbers
um and it provides there a list of
things to to consider
yeah don't worry uh we'll find that
stuff so i take it up a section item on
the chairs yeah i think you pointed us
already to this good working group and
then we kind of went off and started to
think how we deal with the stuff uh
with the history issues it is
unfortunate that the tracker does not
allow you know to keep the issues per
draft and the history that would be a
good suggestion because that
starts to become you know more and more
of a pressing issue
since mailing lists are just simply too
you know
um
far-flung for
to expect
everyone to be up to date on you know
all the threats and all the stuff that
has been raised
so okay uh action night with the chairs
uh let us convert from the stove and
fire up something to the list with kind
of a official policy i mean we don't
want to make it you know too much red
tape but something that is based on the
git working group recommendation how
will we roll the stuff forward okay good
um yes
thanks
uh
why mo
you have the mic
why ammo
i need to
unmute i think
yeah unfortunately i cannot unmute him
i mean he needs to do it
actually i don't see any like
exactly
so let's move to the next presentation
and when he figures out
jeffrey
okay so this is um updates uh
uh on this non-mpo extension um
on behalf of the co-authors
next step please
it's got quite some history uh back in
we have this initial version
the name is non-mpos extensions
you can notice the non-nps keyword there
but
at that time
the scope was internet only
and because of that um three months
later we uh
renamed it to ethernet
extensions to reflect that scope of
internet only
and then later on i raised the question
why should we limit to internet only um
there is no reason to to to to limit
that it should work for all situations
but the work has thought since then
besides the working group edition
adoption
uh finally um
we recently confirmed that original
editors could no longer work on this so
i took the pen and then
published this new version with the
non-mpr extension
because we have not heard
a good uh
reasons to not to do so
but we can we can still discuss it uh
whether this is a good thing so far i've
only seen good reasons to to make it uh
generically non-mpos next slide please
since uh it's been there for quite a
while so i thought i'll just go through
the
contents uh very quickly uh the first
one the first big uh
uh topic here is uh
uh biff id uh
in case of non-mpos encapsulation
the encapsulation uh
rfc says that uh
for
non-mpos the biff ids
they are domain wide unique uh in case
of mpos
bifids are just labels so they are they
are locally significant but when it
comes to non-pos
they are domain-wide unique according to
the encapsulation
rfc
and
there are two ways to uh to uh
to specify the those gifts uh but the
brief ideas
um according to the draft i uh etf beer
now mpl spift encoding
the first one is basically just hard
encoding uh big string lens sub domain
id and set id sd5d
and when you do that there's no need for
provisioning or signaling
but that does not give you any
flexibility that mpos week that gives
to retain some of the flexibility
then a second way to do that is that
instead of hardcore encoding the bsl and
subdomain id
we heart encodes uh
a 16 bits
ibu i forgot what ibu stands for but
basically just an opaque number
uh it can be anything
to do that
then we would need
ibu
to be provisioned on each router
now notice that the beer architecture
rfc
actually does not
mandate domain white unique beef ids
so in another draft
uh it was argued that uh even for
non-mpos
uh
uh beef ids can be like mpls labels
and if you do that you do not need to
uh and to have any provisioning and you
see you still have the flexibility that
mtos way provides you
so if you go that way
then the
beef ids even for non-mpos case
they are just
opec numbers
except they are not called labors
labels the like nps labels are not
called the labels
they can be locally assigned
independently
of course they can also be coordinated
across all the
routers
and when you do do the coordination then
the consistent values can be used
just like in the
segment routing
sr srlb and srgb labels is very similar
next slide please
so in this
documents
we want to take a pro take the approach
that
you can either use the
uh
two approaches uh uh specified in that
non-mps beef encoding
spec
or we can signal the beef ids
that can be
local
or the main web unique just like how we
do it with mpos
so that's that's one main topic in this
document next slide please
um so next part is uh exactly how we do
uh signaling
uh isis ospv2 ospv3
basically they will be extended to
signal uh
dynamic and local
non-labeled beef ids and it mirrors the
way
we do it for mpos
so
in the in the bottom
there are two uh figures there the first
one is the beer
information tlv
that is already specified in the mpos
signaling
and that that remains um
that trv has some sub trvs that
in case mpos they will specified npr's
encapsulation and
it will
signal the labor bases
now we will just mirror that so we have
a new sub glv to signal
uh
the the non-mplc encapsulation
with the bf ids you can see that
if you replace the b5d
with label then it will be identical
as the mpos case
next slide
so the
we talked about the two main topics in
the in the draft and now uh changes in
the latest revision the first is the
name and scope change
we now it's called non-mpos
beer
extension
it can work with
any scenario whether it's a
beer are following the ethernet header
or follow any tunnel header or
or ipv6 uh whatever
editorial changes and finally there is
one change it's about leaking between
areas or levels
next slide please
so i have an example topology here uh
i'm uh
ospf example um
one area on the left another area on the
right
bfer12 and bfbr34
now if you look at the bfr4 and five in
the right in the right
now when it comes to
for beer purposes
the
bfrs or bfer is on the
on another area on the left side they
don't care about bfr four or five at all
they care about bf er three and four
only to the extent that they care about
those bfa r3 and force subdomain
topology
bar ipa value and the bfe are ids but
they don't care
what encapsulation
that bfvr 3 and 4 uses because um
routers in the left area
only cares about that
oh i can get to bfer3n4 through bfr3 so
as long as i know that and then as long
as i know
what encapsulation i should use to get
to bfr3 they should be all set
so because of that
when we leak
the routes into
across areas or across
levels
then for beer information tlv
um
if we if it does not have a
bfr non-zero bfr id then
then that the information does not need
to be leaked at all
of course you can lick it it's just it's
not it's of no use so we can we say that
uh
you may
skip
you may omit
the uh beer or info trv along with this
subjects if the bfr isn't is zero
and then
um you may also in emits uh omits the
increment encapsulation to the
sub glb uh
even if you do dig the
beer in for trv
next slide please
so
comments um i want to mention that uh
we we had a working group last call uh
before on the idr extension and also
bgpls extension
at that time i commented that we should
wait
until
this draft settles because uh
this drafts originally was talking about
ethernet only and but idr and bgpls they
were
money they're talking about non-mpos so
we should be consistent
now if we
if we agree that we're not settled on
this one then
at least uh
my earlier comments on those two drafts
and they are no longer there
we believe uh is ready for working group
last call
uh we uh i did have some discussion with
jin roon offline
um on whether we are
we we want to
uh uh use the uh
locally significant significance uh
before these um
so i added those slides for this
today to call that out to show why we
want to do that and i hope we
we have reached that consensus but um
we'll see
so
that's it
thank you for any comments
uh
yeah tony so what's the consensus on the
local uh significant beef beef ideas i
didn't see this discussion going on
you want to do translation between
domain when you're leaking or what's the
deal
uh
it's not translation it's uh
you you don't need to you don't need
that information basically
okay
because i mean that the the border
gateway will do the decision anyway
right
stitch this stuff
yeah it was leaking yeah okay so that's
why i was confused why you even had the
discussion good thanks
oh the discussion is actually not about
discussion is about whether we want to
signal
the beef ids at all because there is
already a organ group draft talking
about
domain-wide unique beef ids
that does not need signaling at all yes
of course
um
so the discussion was whether we need
both variants or whether we keep the
globally one that is pretty that is
basically computed
uh
both they are all okay i mean they did
the operator can choose which way to go
right
but if you don't compute them
predictably
then you need to signal them don't you
within the domain
uh correct if you don't get the unique
one then you need a signal okay fine
yeah thanks
okay i see no more question we'll move
to
beer irm presentation
hi everyone
it's xiaomi speaking
this presentation is on beer
encapsulation for iom data
this job was presented at ietf
this is the second time is presented
next slide please
firstly recap on the intention of this
draft
this job provides the encapsulation for
iom over beer
this chapter describes
two options of encapsulation
option one is beer header
plus baom header plus
iom header plus payload
option two is beer header plus
among these two options option 2 is
selected as the standardized one
because it's a
more concise and commonly used
encapsulation method
just last weekend
we noticed there is a third option
which i assume is a
via header plus
gdf header
plus iom header plus
payload
that's the slide please
here is the iom relevant to status
update
all iom options
except
direct exporting iom option
are defined in
java ietf ibpm iom data
which is currently in rfc editor queue
the direct exporting ion option is
defined in
java ietf ippm iom direct export
which has passed the working group last
call in ibpm working group
iom over ipv6 encapsulation is defined
in
draft ietf ibpm iom ipv6 options
which has also passed the working group
last call in ippm working group
next slide please
this job outlines on requirements
on iom over beer
some multicast flows such as
live video and real real-time meeting
are positive to packet loss
delay and other factors
nicely a instituto oem provides a way to
achieve on-pass telemetric information
collection
which is necessary for the beer
multitasked network operator
next slide please
this slide illustrates the
iom overview encapsulation
the im data is
immediately following the beer header
it's indicated by
a beer proto
the iom
data contains one or multiple iom
options
and each iom option contains
iom type
iom header lens
next protocol and
iom option data
next protocol field in each
iom option
follows the definition of via proto
field
when multiple iom options are present
the next protocol field
in all iom options
except the last one
is set to indicate the next iom head iom
option
and the next protocol field in the last
iom option
is said to indicate the type of payload
with this encapsulation
ionize requested to assign a new beer
proto
type for iom
next slide please
uh the authors believe this chapter
is really for working group adoption
uh however there was a
there was a big picture tdf
brought up to our attention last weekend
yeah please finish christmas
i admit i didn't follow the evolution of
gdf
closely so
i think i need more time to
learn the advantages of
gdf
if there's any
thank you
okay so let's have a vivid discussion
because i i thought that the mailing is
fired up in a very productive way right
and i think um
i would like opinion on two axes
here the first one is
there is obviously an advantage if we
stick iom on on the beer packet right
because it kind of measures the data
path as it goes and not some artificial
you know
oem stream going
now the problem is however that the beer
header will determine what is the
destination of all this oam information
and
is it desirable that the oem ends up on
all the receivers or do we want to send
basically an oam
operationally per receiver is that the
more common case because it determines
how useful the whole thing is and
the second um discussion point is here
uh the second axis is
no that's the primary axis and as
observation to the presentation uh i
think the authors may have unders
misunderstood how oem is encoded in beer
today oam is its own beer protocol so
the oam packet does not carry a payload
behind it and greg mursky will correct
me if i'm wrong but i think that was how
all oem was intended so it's in fact a
separate stream from the real data
stream so uh
i would encourage discussion along those
lines i think the work is extremely
interesting and then we can get to all
the like you know greater detail like
whether we should fragment and gdf and
assignments and so on thanks
okay all right jeffrey uh mike is yours
so please state association and name
every time
okay jeffrey or darkway from juniper
um so
about inc uh how do you
encapsulate the uh including the iom
data
of the two options uh
one requires a beer extension header
um
i suggest that any discussion uh related
to that
extension header we defer that to to
today to the uh presentation the last
presentation today
that talks about exactly that topic
um i'll have more or more
details and information
available for as part of my presentation
at the end
uh
can run
and i have showed my concerns and
objection in the middle list there are
already several iom encapsulations
and i cannot find any advantage from
this draft
okay so i think the main objection was
that
the payloads carried in the beer packets
they have their own oan but now the
question is
should we rely on that that was not the
beer architecture right based on the
requirements by providers the they
wanted oem directly on the
layer 2.5 because it would start to
stick ipv6 packets and
into beer and then assume that the ipv6
within beer does the oam
that was something we didn't discuss out
but
yes that's also a thing that is a
possible solution space data point so
i would defer this discussion to the
list
greg
i just want to point out that um
let's not uh assume that
um active oem does not follow uh the
same path as as a
data flow the beer flow that it monitors
so um
in terms of what is being monitored and
measured
uh i don't see a difference whether we
use iom or active oam
uh greg so i quickly jump in this is
true to an extent you cannot guarantee
that the oem is following the same
queuing disciplines through the boxes
and oem may have different packet sizes
which all affect delay jitter and other
stuff
right but at the same at the same time
uh then if uh we use iem trace options
up by hub so uh the space for uh
telemetry information either has to be
pre-allocated by their
ingress
bfr
or are incrementally added by their bfrs
as it transits so right
and that affects and skews the metric so
right and the ioms causes fragmentation
then the whole thing will go to pieces
anyway right so those are interesting
discussions uh yes thank you
[Music]
in this job the dear iom is defined as a
upper layer of beer header i think it is
the inner permit
for beer
for for bfr to handle the upper layer
encapsulation of br
okay thanks
i have to admit i couldn't follow that
really
so i see now please send your question
to the list probably it's
difficult to understand ciao
so the question from tony second
question uh iom is in c2 so uh the iom
header is
with the
packet the the data packet of the beer
so it's not just
uh
active om so it's in situ om it's with a
package data packet
now second today i want to say uh
currently we have
already two adopted
i am encapsulation jobs
they are im
over ipv6 im over
sfc nsh
so i think i over beer is similar to
this
to encapsulations especially iom or nsh
i i would uh contradict that go look at
all the supported beer protocol in the
registry for example ethernet
and uh
all kind of mpls things
so with you cannot rely on the fact that
the payload will always have its own oem
it's an interesting discussion of course
right but uh
your point is that the
payload carried by beer will always have
an aom is an assumption which will not
hold up
okay
hello
we can you hear me
yeah okay uh i uh came in from hawaii uh
i have this following comments
uh first i i in fact i already explained
my concern in the main list
ever before
first
i mean that's the duplicate the iom
functionality because the imprs has the
iom ipv6 has iom and also this the beer
is the independent layer it also has iom
if the beer over mpr's appear over ipv6
there's the duplicate rm this is the
functionality and the encapsulation
i think i don't know how to cope with
this situation the first one
the second one because here is the
because discuss about this iom but you
notice now this
there's also the network slicing and
there's maybe also some this the
alternative alternative marking
encapsulation
functionality that's the ipv6 is
supported i'm not sure if the
slice
for the beer or some this alternate
marking for the for the beer do we need
to go on to extend or define this the
extension header for the br layer to
support this functionality or not
the second one
the third one i think that's if this iom
is
defined for the br layer i think this is
for the ipv6 they also have this the
ipsec
and if the ipsec is used with the ipv6
so that's the br header and also this
the iom header will include encrypted so
i don't think how to encapsulate this
information in the br br header if over
ipv6 data plane
okay that's that's all my comments
jeffrey you want to address the beer
the beer over v6 ipsec
comment because the rest was basically
all the same thing excel
that the payload was already over in
um okay jeffrey from juniper
um
in the ipv6 environment
the one option to do uh to the beer is
uh
that's uh
you do not need the ipv6 uh
at all always uh
you can uh between the two adjacent uh
bfrs you could just be the beer header
following the
ethernet header so their ipvx does not
apply at all
and even when we do need to
use a
ipv6 tunnel between two
bfrs that are not directly connected
at that time
the
the iom information um which is specific
uh when if it's
specific to beer
then that should be it should go along
with the beer header itself instead of
at ipv6 level
that's that's how i say it and i don't
see how
encapsulation plays
plays a role here because let's say you
have a
encapsulation
for the ipv6 tunnel but that's fine and
beer had a beer processing does not
happen
until you exited ipv6 tunnel so even if
your ipv6 tunnel is inc
encrypted that's fine
yep pretty much
uh concurs with what i'm thinking thank
geoffrey
and more generically we've always had
different other mechanics different
players because they have different
semantics potentially different speeds
so i don't see how having i am in one
layer would substitute for beer
specifically
yeah
well that's why we have to appear less
pink and the other pink and overlay
pinks and everything going at the same
time yeah
i sorry i also had this the last
comments i want to know that you could
defend this the extension header such as
the iom and also the maybe later some
network slicing or maybe alternate
marking or apn
so if this is in the charter of the br
working group or not
because from my point of view there's
there's maybe more functionality to be
defined
you mean using basically kind of this uh
shim in between like iom is using yeah
it's a good discussion i have i have no
no enter i think it's all a very
interesting proposal to discuss through
whether that makes sense to put the shim
between the payload after the pr
i want to add jeffrey from junior i want
to add that
in case of beer over mpos
in most situation the
you uh there is no nps tunnel
um and then the label
uh is only to indicate that the beer
header follows and then
this gives you the bp5d so in that case
putting the
beer or iom information as an mqs
extension header does not
make sense either and that's one point
another thing is that if there is a a
reason to have a
beer extension header
for example for apm for whatever purpose
for slicing as long as you need a peer
extension header then let's defer that
discussion to the end of today's session
where i my my presentation talks about
that topic exactly
uh if there are no more comments i'll
propose to take this to the list it's a
good discussion
okay the new dark is being shared hi
this is dirk crosston from uh huawei i'm
talking about
frm i realize there is one letter more
than the fr i don't know presentation
that's weird
oh oh it's
it's
right
f r m
just look at it maybe this one the http
one
let me see how it looks that's the one
oh yeah sorry okay
still labeled http um so if you go to
the next one please
so this is a zero zero draft but there's
some legacy to this draft um i just
wanted to point out
the draft regionates from uh and now
expire traffic which was in uh version
six
on multicast http it was very focused on
there was an applicability oriented
traffic to realize http based scenarios
in a beer environment
uh
must have been the order of
three and a half years old i think i
still started that in my old company
uh before joining huawei it was in
be a working group last call it returned
very useful comments and feedbacks from
the application areas we had a couple of
discussions around january time etc but
we took this back to the original author
set to see if there is an interest to
continue on this and there's
the
organizational reasons why that didn't
happen so i was told by the author said
there wouldn't be any interest to
continue this
which is the reason for the zero zero
draft so i
restarted this
because of the interest in the original
trial so i i thought letting this trap
um would be a shame
so if you go to the next slide please so
what i've done in this version now is
to take the um to generalize the draft
so it's been generalized towards a new
communication semantic which in that's
done in section three
um which now is applicable to use cases
that are more than just http so we've
turned an http applicability draft into
one that is tackling a communication
semantic there so there are more use
cases being given
and then uh sections five six and seven
they are adapted from the original craft
uh uh in order to support the more
general semantics so it's kind of like
removing or replacing some of the http
um terminology
uh section eight is meant to be a
placeholder uh to incorporate the
comments and discussions that were
received from the app area that i
mentioned that we discussed in january
it's still a place where it's empty uh
i'm working currently on on on on on
putting the pieces in there
if you go to the next slide please
so
very briefly the court
change is really to introduce this new
semantic frm which stands for fault
request return multicast semantic which
defines a very which you could already
see in the original draft in the
original http draft um
a
multicast communication semantic is
extremely flexible so here a datagram
with the source address s is towards the
destination d1 to dn is formed as one or
more responses to adequate requests from
those destinations the mono requests
that come in the forward direction
2s but the ephemeral group address r is
defined through an identifying
characteristic
across all received uh requests the
identifying characteristic is an
implementation specific parameter that's
used to distinguish among different
requests
if you translate it back from the old
http case essentially the things like an
http uri was used in the http
applicability draft to differentiate
requests so if you have
one set of requests coming into a single
uri you you created a dynamic multicast
response if the uri was different it
created a different ephemeral group
address so this is the generalization of
that idea
the nature of that multicast is
inherently dynamic so the multicast
responses are formed in response to
incoming requests they may differ in
extremely short time frames and the
initial
example of the http case um was
showcasing that um with over-the-top
video people are viewing the same thing
and you're starting to deliver the
actual chunk request as
multicast responses back to the actual
clients that was the idea there
go to the next slide please
so the next steps really here are a to
firmware from the details section six
and seven um you know
based on the
frm generalization to incorporate the
comments from the list
that were received into section eight
and obviously to incorporate any
feedback comments from from the list you
know on this work and in particular if
you go to the last slide
it's the main question this is a short
presentation meant to be
um really answering the question or
getting an answer to the question from
our side if the work is still of
relevance to this group um is this
something the group feels uh worthwhile
to continue
um with a changed author set at the
moment for the reasons mentioned
i would also like to understand more if
if this work is more widely applicable
even though section
six and seven in particular are being
described but beer in mind is this uh
given that it's talking about the
general
communication semantic is are there are
there other underlay techniques that
could be utilized for that
any thoughts that anybody had i it would
be very welcome
and obviously this was being put out
rather quickly as a zero zero with
myself as the
single author at the moment i'm very
much looking for other contributors to
the work out there in particular
if the first question is positively
answered and maybe the second one as
well so willing to drive the draft
forward i would be
very happy to hear anything of that
thank you
okay so if no one else is on the queue i
jump in um tony juniper um
yes that looks interesting but it also
looks like reliable multicast
generic reliable multicast which is kind
of you know one of the famous red holes
it can be solved wonderful well it's not
the full reliable multicast but you know
from one source to multiple destinations
um
no opinion whether we should uh you know
take on anything like that um whether it
should be done some other uh context i
think it very much depends on the
interest within the group so comment
please if you're interested uh you know
uh in this kind of work or do you think
that would make sense
maybe one short feedback on the reliable
multicast on but isn't necessarily um as
you already mentioned it doesn't need to
be reliable multicast uh it really
depends on some of the service
implication protocols we've been looking
at there they're not necessarily
reliable they're relatively transmitted
that may may happen as well i'm sort of
stepping away because taller says i yeah
i'm trying to sneak through without the
stupid application and phone and so
consider myself the button to be clicked
sorry about that um no i mean the way i
was joining the original effort which
unfortunately due to the
you know main authors uh um
failed was um
that i i felt that um this this was back
then the best option to promote
the new
um multicast model that beer gives
by being able for the sender to indicate
the explicit set of receivers for every
individual packet and we haven't really
leveraged on on that opportunity yet and
so maybe it is a good thing that we can
try to broaden the scope of
explaining exactly that functionality um
to to find more interested beer and the
fact that we're forwarding through
sender defined um bits
to receivers right so
um that that that would be my very ad
hoc bad sales pitch and i'll try to join
the effort by some appropriate word on
on some other use cases so i'm not quite
sure how to structure the whole thing
but if you want to sell beer the beer
idea to more applications then maybe
join the effort and we'll try to figure
out how to structure
okay some input from my side will be
focused on basically requirements what
problem do you try to solve so we don't
end up in the generic uh reliable
multicast problem which is one of the
formulas you know totally not you're
completely agreed and that's exactly
what i mean with use cases in terms of
what is the stuff that we can do better
with beer than with the native multicast
yeah i mean the http could look simple
yeah
the http stuff looked excellent you know
as a use case yeah thanks
sandy you have the mic
hello
we hear you
oh okay i just have comments for the
previous slides
i read the repair http draft
before and i think that this draft is
using brs multicast underlay so the
http service can be
distributed by multicast way and i think
it's very interesting and
and i will
follow the
processing of the structure okay thank
you
yeah so join the draft and uh work with
tolas and the author uh on specifying
what problem do you really try to
address because it seems you know to be
more generic than before i know and
before we can even go and start to maybe
280s or you know
talk about what will be scope of work
like that
we need a problem definition right
practical use case is fine but really
what is the scope of something like this
thank you
okay very next presentation the arrange
poet right
but
for now i see nothing
beer is not extended for it but it's
very interesting use case
yeah no it's it will be purely overload
overlay on top of beer yes
thanks
yeah
okay so we are done with commands
and we are moving to the next
presentation which is the routing header
seizer why or arjun presenting
hi everyone
i'm will from china telecom
and i would just try to talk a bit
louder
oh okay
hello
hey
so
i will give a
presentation for our draft a routine
header based
beer information encapsulation
uh
next slide please
this presentation includes four parts uh
the
considerations for beer information
encapsulation in layer 3 header
the format of the beer routing header
the multicast package forwarding
procedures and the further actions of
this draft
next slide please
the msr design
consideration draft proposed the
following requirements for beer in ipv6
it should support the
basics multicast
functionalities and meet the needs of
high quality services with high
reliability
besides the above requirements
we have additional considerations
we hope the source and destination
addresses can be preserved along the
forwarding path
because the operators need to
count and monitor
the multicast traffic and the current
technologies are based on the source or
destination address
we also hope the identification of vpn
traffic should be based on the
destination
address
the existing beer encapsulations cannot
meet the above demands
so we think it is time to
define a new
beer encapsulation method
next slide please
considering the above requirements we
think use routing header to carry beer
information has the following advantages
it lied with the usage of rotting header
the
t and b can be realized in a unified way
and the previous requirements can be met
so we defined a new type of routing
header to carry beer information
next slide please
the format of
a newly defined routing header type is
showing the figure
we need to define a new routing type
the eight bits follow the routing type
field
indicates the brt algorithm used for the
rhb
beer
packet
and the encoding format of the following
brt
algorithm specific specified part
depends on the value of
vrt
algo
failed
next slide please
this scenario shows the forwarding
procedures
one all knows in beer domain support
beer routing header
node a is a bfir
when it receives a multicast packet it
will encapsulate an fpv6 header with
your routing header
then it checks whether there is fifth
correct corresponding to the fifth id
locally
if not discarding the packet
otherwise performing the normal beer
forwarding
the same forwarding procedures also
perform r node d to e to f
during the forwarding pass
the source and destination address in
the ipwa6 header
are not changed
only the
b string in beer routing header is
updated
next slide please
this scenario shows the forwarding
procedures one thumbnails in beer domain
do not support via routing header
node a encapsulates a
fpv6 header with spare routing header to
the package
and for words the package to not be
according to required
sorry
you are very quiet again something with
your microphone please
check
oh
can you hear me now yeah this is much
better thank you
oh okay
uh
and
note a encapsulates an ip wei sex header
with spear rotting header to the packet
and forwards the
packet to not d according to the bift
because note c doesn't support vr
routing header so noddy should calculate
the
ipv6 address of e
uh and encapsulates uh out
outer ipsex header to the packet
the source ipwisk address is the
address of itself and the destination
fpsex address
is the ipv6 address of node e
then it sends the
uh packet to nazi
nazi performs normal fpv
ipv6 forwarding according to the outer
fpv6 header and sends the package to
noddy
decapsulates the outer ipv6 header and
forwards the packet according to the
bift
in this uh
procedures the source and destination
address
in the inner iqs header keep unchanged
next slide please
our next steps are listed here
we plan to extend the solution to carry
vpn related information in multicast
destination address
including the generation and
transmission of the address and the
behaviors on devices to handle it
that's all for the presentation
your comments and suggestions are always
welcome thanks
how long please go ahead
solutions to encode appear in ipv6
extensions header
so i don't know why this is listed in
the agenda
i think this question is to
cheers thank you
sorry what is the question to chairs
what is the specific question
well i think you got cut somewhere in
between could you please repeat your
question
we cannot hear you
okay let's move to the next person on
the mic please bring it on
hello
yeah
okay i think
i have the similar question with fun
hong kong
my question is to the chairs
the working group had concluded a lot to
work on solutions
to include encode beer in ipv6 extreme
header
after after i think
about more than more than three years of
discussions so i don't understand why
this routine had beer draft
is listed in the urgent for for
discussion
is the working group changing the
conclusion
uh no but i mean they ask for
presentation slot it's up to us to let
things present
frankly i'm lost as well there were no
updates to the draft i think the process
ran its course all the way to the
bitter end of formal complaint against
the chairs um but you know
if presentation slots are requested
we're perfectly fine to see something
especially if there's any new arc which
i didn't see here frankly
satisfactory
thanks
hello
yes please go ahead we can hear you
we cannot hear you now
hello
yes please go ahead
don't go ahead please speak up
so i think i want to
answer the question on the list or on
the chat okay
okay
okay it's jeffrey again
on the
okay so this is basically to
the slides of uh to help the discussion
uh discussing the
beer extension headers
next slide please
some background um
there have been several drafts
already the beer that
start talking about
beer extension headers
the first one is this uh generic
literary functions that we call gdf
that
we put out a few years ago a couple of
years ago in the first in the mpos
area
an er growing group
basically we noticed that
there are several functions
that are currently defined for ip
but they are actually
applicable for other layers as well one
example is fragmentation
another one is uh security
and so
we thought that
it would be nice to be able to extract
that out
and apply it at different layers be it
mpos ipv6 beer or ethernet if they if
they want to do so
so
we um we we wrote that gdf draft and we
we discussed it in mqs uh working group
uh at that time i also noticed that the
io ioms work started there in the mpv60
this is actually also one of the
functions that can be considered as
generic
so later on
when i was
working on a draft about the beer
or solution support for network slicing
and in one case i i would need to increa
encapsulate some other information
about a slice or or even more uh
granular information
that that would need to be put into a
extension header
so
for that i
brought it to
beer working group as well um
in the last ietf meeting i refer to it
in a slide and talk about it briefly
but i have not got a chance to actively
drive the discussion in the beer working
group even though i said yes though
this when it comes to beer we need to
discuss in beer but i had not done so
then just last week i noticed this uh
beer iom drafts
where um we're talking about the beer
extension header as one of the options
to encode the iom information
so now
um it's clear that
it's time to actively
discuss the how we do the beer extension
headers
back to npos
it has a design team to look at
mqs extension headers and there is this
strapped draft song talking about
extension headers uh i think both taran
and i are co-authors of that draft
um so when it comes to our the gdf
we wanted to align the beer and mpos
extensions
basically we define one extension header
mechanism that will be applicable to
both
beer and npos
next slide please
so this is the npos extension header
format uh at the top is the regular mtx
label stack
there is some sort of indicator saying
that at the bottom of the label stack
there is an mpos extension header
um the first four objects of the
extension header is like a header of a
headers
including the number of extension
headers and total length of the
extension headers
original upper layer protocol
and then the next header that points to
the
next header
the real header
uh here we have example two examples uh
extension header or what h1 and hn
so the next header field
will
will allow you to traverse all those
extension headers
so now
currently the next header value is
actually taken from the ip protocol
numbers registry
so but to in order for
us not to use too many uh uh
values for npos purposes then
we say that uh one of the next header
value will allow us to say that
we'll have subtype uh
so that we can uh we can further
distinguish which are the mpos or
uh specific ones so that's the basic
idea
um
one thing i want to point out is that
you can see that if you exclude the
the header headers part
it's very similar to ipv6 with yx uh
one difference that the header lens
the mqs case is in the
four optic units but ipv6 header is
header lens is in the eight active units
that's one difference
next slide please
so now
we wanted to apply this to the same to
to beer so then the beer header would
have a
proto value to indicate that there is a
beer extension header follows
just like the nps label stack have an
indication
we talked about the
h value taken from the registry
so now
going back to the generic linear
function
the idea is that
some functions
that can be applied at many different
layers
we want to be able to to reuse the same
encoding and therefore we can do the
same hardware processing
so if you consider that
for real generic function
it will be applicable to ipv6 as well
so ideally
we would want to be able to just reuse
the
ipv6 extension
for particular
function if there is ipv6 extension
header defined
we would want to be able to use it as is
for mpos or for beer
but
the header lens uh in our four arctic
units prevents us from doing that
next time please
so um
for beer
here are the questions i want to uh
to discuss in the in in a working group
we don't have to have any conclusions
here
uh i just want to point this out we can
follow up on the muni list
so first of all does this make sense to
beard we want to align the extension
header formats including
between beer and mpos
and even with ipv6
and
in the iom case
do we want to use this format for br iom
if
the br iom goes ahead um
do you want to align with mpos or they
want to align with ipv6 as well
they're actually um so one simple way uh
well aligned with ipv6 is that
simply change that's uh header lens
uh from the four active units to uh to
eight
arctic units that would work out easily
easily
i guess the concern why they wanted to
do a four active units in npr's case is
because
it's more granular
so
for us
which why do we want to go um and also
actually just before this meeting i was
thinking of another way
to to allow that
for after units
normally but still we have another
container to
uh to to put all the ipv6 extension
headers in
um so i just want to throw out these
questions and then
we can
discuss
here and discussing in the mailing list
i want to point out that um
it seems that uh in the brlm draft uh
it also just seems to be uh putting the
ipv6 header
directly after beer header
so we may be already aligned
somewhat it's just that
if we want to do beer extension header
let's
look at it in a holistic way and make
sure that we consider all the use cases
and make sure that we
we are doing it
in a
good way and ideally generically and
lined up with other extension headers as
well
so
that's it
so jeffrey i mean frankly to be lost are
we talking about
gdf in beer or are we talking to extend
beer to have an
extension header
um
it's really uh to ex
to have beer extension headers uh well
gdf uh to do gdf we will need extension
headers right okay go to okay uh so
do you have you know some packet format
suggestion what we would need to do
um yes uh can you go back to
that sorry i was on the chat
yeah
okay yeah
sorry yeah so
um ideally
we would want to align beer mpos and
even ipv6 uh
uh extension headers uh same format that
way
uh any function that is
generic that can be
applied at ipv6 or npos or beer level
we just use the same
same encoding that way
the hardware
implementation can be
reusable
i pass i have to read the job you're
drafting in excruciating details i'm a
little bit lost what is coming afterward
here okay
questions
i follow precisely the original gdf but
that looks like another serious ref
thanks oh uh this is one way to do the g
uh to do the gdf yes this is the one way
to do the gdf proposed way to do the gdf
from me
so i don't see any
comments nor hands
wish we would have to take it to the
list
sure i mean you want to
stir up this discussion yeah
yeah so i think would be great if you
would send an email to the
list with the pointer to the
presentation and start the discussion
albert you were going to say something
ah okay
then i think we are done for a tf-113
hope to see all of you in philadelphia
great yep thanks everyone until next
time
bye everyone
what are you talking about
oh right
uh
oh
okay
sure
i really like that rbs
idea