hello
hi kevin
the room is all yours yes
pick your own seat
all right i think we are pretty much on
time here
it's good to see folks in the room
but uh thanks everyone for coming uh
this is iatf 113 the cdni session um
uh we'll go ahead and get started
uh sanji next slide please
all right
this is the notewell everyone should be
familiar with it your participation is
governed by the
the uh documents listed here um
so you agree by participating to uh
follow all of these guidelines i'm sure
everyone's seen it and read it
next slide please
um
this is a hybrid meeting so just to some
reminders for folks um there's some
folks in the room some uh
joining remotely um
some tips on keeping
connecting and making sure that you are
in the blue sheets and when you're not
presenting please turn off your video
and audio just to
help us save on the bandwidth
um next slide please
we will be using meat echo for
all of the um queuing even if you're in
the room so
make sure that you are on the tool
and you're logged in
uh next slide please
uh for remote participants you are here
with us on echo so um
hopefully you know how to use the tool
use the queue
use your video and audio blue sheets are
being tracked automatically through meet
echo so no need to sign in if you're on
site
but you do need to sign in to meet echo
next slide please
uh sanjay go for it this is the most
important slide you see
the only reason if you're in in austria
you've got to visit the state opera
and i was lucky to do that on sunday
evening so
i thought i'll just share that with you
nice very nice sanjay
okay
back to business um this is cd and i uh
do we have a volunteer to be a jabra
scribe i'm going to take minutes um
and everyone please log in to me that go
to make sure that we have a accurate
account for blue sheets
anyone in the room to volunteer for
jabber scribe
i think francesca is saying
she'll she'll do it
thank you i don't think there was much
there was much action so
okay
thank you
next slide please
um this is just a reminder of our
milestones
last time we did re-adopt the triggers
and we adopted the footprints so there's
a new milestone there for the for the
footprint draft we'll be talking about
that i'm still on our list is finishing
up uri signing and phil's going to give
us an update on that
i don't see phil online yet
but hopefully he will
he'll be here um acme star that's the
https delegation uh fred is not feeling
well so sanjay's going to take that
update for us
and then uh nier is here to talk about
the the triggers and the footprints
and then we have unpacked agenda beyond
that next slide please
um
chris lemmons can talk to us about the
cta wave stuff um we also have uh the
other half of the https delegation that
we split out last time
um so
kristoff is going to talk about that and
then we'll have updates on the metadata
and capacity advertisements from alfonso
and andrew and hopefully we'll get all
that in in the next two hours and
do a quick wrap-up
and i
30 seconds under my five minutes so
let's go ahead and get started is phil
here i don't see him
online
all right phil
will be here
um
let's uh
do we want to just go straight to chris
or do we want to let near go
i'd like to keep the cta wave and uri
signing pieces together
so
um
near do you want to go ahead and go
two why not
awesome thank you
hold on hold on a second let's see if i
can bring the next slides
so nearly going with your slides first
the cdna footprint extensions
yes
it's not showing up
okay would you like me to show me the
screen that
i can also share screen if
it's possible
yeah you can uh but i should be able to
bring this up here
okay it does but it doesn't bring in the
okay let's see
stop share slide
okay
this should work
yeah
okay
so let's start
uh
hi everybody
i'm neil sofer from quilt
in the previous meeting and the meeting
with we discussed
uh
an internet of additional footwind types
and we like to would like to get to the
let's call the volume group let's call
for this
internet draft
um
do you move the slides or
yeah i'm i should have
hmm
why don't you go ahead and um looks like
i
not letting me okay
here
sharing
an idiot
[Music]
approval
i need some one of you to approve my
request
it looks like phil just joined do we
want to go ahead and let phil give his
update
um
is your screen working
yes okay
do you see my screen
no
so i might have permission issues
yeah i gave the permission
no it seems like
mech i need to approve it somewhat so
um i'll try loading this slide let's let
phil go ahead since he's here now um and
we'll go back to our regularly scheduled
agenda
cool
phil you're up
we cannot hear you phil immediately
lots of technical difficulties today
i don't see you here muted phil see if
on your end if you can
reconnect
right i
it
just shows
i don't see any video i mean
yeah i don't see the option for audio
there
okay
phil you have to do the unmute your
audio if
i'm i guess that's probably the obvious
thing you may have already done that
can't hear you
yeah did you do that allow your browser
and all that when you first started
you shaking head you did yeah
still no voice phil
okay maybe he's
reconnecting
yes near do you want to go ahead i have
your slides up
go
okay
so a quick recap
and
rfc806 define the footprint types and
the object protein types uh
ipv4 or ipv6 idioms asn country code the
footing object is actually a
an object that allows to define uh
a bit of phototyping the values that the
client can match to
thank you uh
and rfc8008
allows to use this footment on a
footmate object uh to specify the k on
which a footprint each capability
uh is supported
so
in the
previous meetings in the previous
meeting we suggested two new footman
types expressed
the first is the
a
is a 31131662
a code which is a
the subdivision code
for example states in the us and which
this footing type publicly gives us a
better granularity compared to country
code
next
and the second and second fifty type was
the footprint union
that allows the
that introduced a did additive semantics
between different footprint types
and that's it the
internet draft with several comments and
thank you kevin for
start the shepherd review on the
on the draft
and
there's
no more action items i'm aware of so
and and nothing new to
to bring up here
if you this slides actually point to the
to the left
draft why would they be happy if we can
proceed to the less goal of this uh
thank you
yeah i think this one's pretty
straightforward uh it's just registering
two new um footprint types in the iona
registry we've talked about it for a
little while now it's i don't think
there's been any contention about it
i went ahead and did my shepard
pre-review as is our custom
um i think once assuming that all those
were addressed we're probably in pretty
good shape i don't know if anyone has
any objections to us moving this forward
to a working group last call
if so please speak now we will of course
take it to the list after the meeting
but we want to have a quick discussion
here to make sure everyone i think
there's pretty much agreement that we
should just move this thing forward
uh andrew supports it good
um all right so if there's nothing else
on this one um phil are you back to
having audio
looks like
i see the icon for audio and video
no no i can't hear you
gonna try one more thing
maybe change your browser
all right then we'll go ahead and load
up near's other presentation how's that
sound
since he's already here
okay
and the second draft we discussed and
the previous time was uh
the second edition for the controller
interface
and
a quick reminder
the
controller interface allows an absolute
uh
to manage and content and met is content
or metadata within the dance incident
operations like proposition or
invalidation
uh
we
suggested a new uh version for this rfc
uh early sanjay and myself uh next
in this new version and we already
discussed this added functionality which
is
additional information in the air
propagation
a
triggers extensibility
uh for example time policy that allows
us
uh allows the absence of the end to
indicate that he wants the a
preposition be done at a specific time
and also define two additional content
selection methods which are the
content regresses and content playlists
next
and
following the discussion which we
reached the point with we redefine
the trigger object so this is the
original version of the trigger object
it has
the trigger type for example preposition
it has the cdn path the list of cdns
that actually instruct
the operation and it allows us to
do some circuit breaking
and a
set of properties that are publicly
used for target selection
okay
the trigger should be applied on method
on des metadata urls or
those content patterns
etc etc
next
so the trigger v2 object first of all
edit was added with the
trigger extension list which is a list
of generic items that we can register
more and more item as we go
items
as we go
and in next
and
was also added with two properties for
project selection for content selection
which is the contact
context
excels and playlists
uh next please
thanks er so
the point we got to is okay we ask what
what could happen if we want another
method for content selection
uh
and then is it a separate property we
will need to define the trigger of which
we
and so we said okay
why not do the same trick use the
list of generic objects
for the
metadata and content selection as well
so
next slide
so what we practically want to do in
this change is to take all the green
properties that are used for target
selection to say on what on which
elements the trigger should be it should
operate
and put it in a list
of a generic trigger specs
okay
any questions so far
two three that's good
next okay
so we suggest a generic spec of the
object which is specified targets to
execute the trigger on
okay it's the generic object we may have
several types for example we already
defined the types matching they're all
the
types from arc 807 which are url spec or
uri patterns
as well as content playlists
okay and in the future we may add more
and more
types and the spec is a
sp
is specified for a specific trigger
subject we define a new term which is
called the trigger subject which is
either metadata or content
and maybe in the future where we'll have
something else i
have nothing in mind but
it can be done
next
so if we look at the spec object
structure it is the spec subject
the type of the spec
and their values
so this
specific example
it says a match metadata with the
following url okay we have metadata
that
that is chosen you are using url spec
with
this specific url do i have a pointer
here somehow
okay never mind
uh
okay
a
specific
that match the specific url
questions
we'll see an example in a minute
okay one last change before
uh
i'm showing the example next please
the in the original rfc uh
there was a temp trigger type which
which is preposition or invalidation or
purge it's actually
specified the operation the trigger
stands for
and
i find it more appropriate to call it
action
okay so i would like to have a win to
rename this field
and
to call to call it a action instead of a
type
okay so let's look
at the example yes
so this is the trigger v2 object
first of all it says okay the action is
preposition
and we would like to preposition
uh this following list we would like to
preposition metadata
with this single url
as well as content
with
that matches those two urls
okay and so
previously this would have been two
separate
trigger requests right you know there's
it was a single request there is a
metadata urls and metadata
and content url
so
uh
it was it was still in a single request
uh it was just
you you had to define the properties
over and over again so if we have uh
you need to define metadata url property
and content url property and
and change the trigger
version is every time you define it
so i see a queue here i see a question
from rajiv
rajiv you're going to go ahead hi guys
uh hope you can hear me
uh yes yes
i have a question here you're talking
about uh
metadata and content pre-positioning uh
typically when we do a content
pre-position we are also pre-positioning
the metadata with it but in this
particular case you know
you have a case where you're
pre-positioning metadata for a parent
part and content for
file console
that's the url
type
have any ability to do recursive or
wildcard
or is that only going to be on the
specific url
i'm sorry i i actually didn't
the line was a bit disrupted so i
wasn't able to hear properly
so so i'm i'm just wondering uh when we
are doing a content pre-position we are
typically doing both the content and the
metadata right
the metadata when we do a metadata
pre-position we are only doing the
metadata and not the content itself
but in this particular example you have
used a parent part for the metadata and
uh child paths for the content so i just
wanted to know how that interaction
works and whether when we are doing
metadata you know does the url spec
trigger type have the ability to do
something recursive or
is it implicit
or is it explicit in that it will only
do the specific listed urls and
you know nothing below that
um
actually i i would actually need to get
back to you with it with this uh
[Music]
for i think that
if
for metadata if you ask for abc
you'll get the metadata for abc but that
will also have pointers to everything
that's below it and it may be
implementation dependent on whether you
choose to pull all the rest
at that particular time
okay so so you're saying that it's quite
dependent on the exact metadata
definition of that particular object
right because
yeah so if there are pointers in the
metadata would
this uh the downstream cdn be expected
to recurse through that and
you know get all the
metadata for the objects that it's
pointing to
that's a good question
again
i don't know that we specify that i
don't know that we we prescribe
yeah so i i i suspect probably
specifying that either explicitly
make it a requirement or
you know if you want to keep the
behavior identical between the metadata
subject and the content subject we
clearly say that any any recursion has
to be explicitly requested by adding the
tile urls the downstream cdn wouldn't
implicitly recurse
the reason i'm bringing up this question
is because of this specific example
where we have metadata and uh content
preposition happening on you know
different levels within the hierarchy
yeah i would think it would be odd for
the downstream to
pull content for which it did not have
metadata
now whether there should be an implicit
pull of metadata based off the content
preposition is an interesting question
all right again
it it's probably something for
discussion uh on the list maybe
yeah i i admit i i failed to follow the
the details of this
this remark
um
but
as i understand it's not related to the
structure of the the trigger or it's
related to the specific example
uh yeah example and it's it's kind of
related to the expected behavior of the
downstream cdn when dealing with uh you
know a pre-position request yeah but
it's a a similar issue would have
could have existed with the previous
version of the rfc with the 807 where
you
already can define c8 metadata urls and
quantity urls together
it's not a new
it's
it's probably a use case that becomes
more visible because of the new
structure you're using right yes because
of the way it's kind of separated now it
may it forces us to think this way and
it's it's more visible now
it probably wasn't explicitly visible in
the earlier structure
yes and you should somehow relate to
that
rajiv can you also post your question in
the mailing list i think just so that we
can make sure that i will i will do that
we're separating the structure part of
it from the actual implementation piece
of it
okay
okay thanks
any other
question comment
okay so let's
proceed
i wait let's do the example sorry well
so i want you to okay
if you keep this example in mind okay we
will relate to it later on we have here
a trigger of people for preposition
of
a metadata
with a single url and content with two
different urls okay
let's move on let's move on
okay so similarly to the trigger v2 and
we needed a object we needed to redefine
the error object actually practically
defined a lv2 object without all
properties related to content selection
to
metadata like metadata urls et cetera
and we added a generic twig spec list
and we took
when we defined the status v2 object
which holds the arrow v2 object as well
so if we go to the next example
this is an example for an aov2 object
which in this case says that
the
air of type project
that we encountered an error of type
project
and it's important to note
that the error is
a
relevant is related to the lead
sorry
yeah the error the error is related is
relating
the
spec listed here
okay so it there the only the spec
relevant to the error are listed in the
spec list
okay so if you remember the example we
showed before
of the trigger we had
a a
metadata aspect and a content spec here
we have only the content spec
so the metadata we had no no error for
the metadata
and
if you remember the url list in the
twitter add two urls and here we have
only a single url because the error only
relates
to this url the other with the other url
everything went fine
okay
so this is the semantic of the error
it's similar it is similar to the
semantics
of the l the original error with
the previous structure
and
one point however i find
a bit of an issue here is
it seems like a bit of a of a a bit of a
hassle
to pass this arrow by the absence of the
end okay to understand which object
exactly
uh
was no
they relates to it's
it's maybe some swing comparison or
something like that and i would like to
suggest next
a
a bit of an adjustment to the structure
okay
so if we add some placeholders in the
list
it may allow us to uh
to to keep the a position
or to to take the trigger and the spec
list from the trigger
and uh add
placeholders for
saying okay for this object everything
went ahead is not relating to everything
went well so in this example
they uh
there is a spec list and the first video
is an empty spec which we respectfully
means okay they met the data spec we had
back then
everything was okay with it there is
nothing it does not relate to this
aspect
as well as if you if you are
going into the
uh
spec itself that the failing specs
there is a
again an empty object
in the url list meaning
okay this url was okay
the o does not apply to it
and
this may
help the
and better understand
the
error
so this is just a suggestion the uh
does not contain this change already and
i would be happy to your opinion about
it
so we have uh q here uh rajiv you want
to go first and then kevin
uh comments on this
one obviously
is the fact that you're
using your first example in the previous
delay uh you know there is the
two levels of ambiguity which makes men
one obviously that you've already
identified the fact that uh you know you
are only
listing those specific effects where you
have an error and uh
so in this case you're nesting at the
level of spec for
showing the specs that have an error but
what you're actually doing is you're
actually
populating it with a partial spike when
compared to the preposition request
because the request spec had two urls
and here you have a single url
so that is one question the second one
is you know how do you expect uh you
know this error to be dealt with in
cases where the error has happened at a
url that may not be part of the original
stick so like uh so this obviously would
not work with the spec type of urls but
say there's a
spec type of playlist which you have
added okay so part of that would need
would mean that downstream cdn passes
that playlist and brings all the uh
dependent resources of that playlist
into uh you know the pre-position queue
and populates them and say for example
on a playlist there's a subtitle file
which is giving me a 404. the rest of
the cop the playlist is fine i'm getting
a 200 on the playlist i'm getting at 200
on the av segments i got a 404 on the
subtitle segment now that subtitle url
is
something that i where would i put that
in
in this structure because that is
something which is not explicitly
mentioned in my incoming request
right
so so we'd have to be a little more uh
you know
intelligent in how we write this
structure in order to allow for these
kinds of errors to also be surfaced
and if we come to the next slide there
my uh
you know point would basically be
that uh you already have a status object
right is there any reason why we are
using an explicit error object rather
than just rolling the errors into a
generic status object and that generic
status object is designed to exactly
mirror the
pre-position requests
[Laughter]
mapping between everything
what succeeded what failed without us
having to you know put in hacks like you
know trying to maintain position or
without necessarily having the upstream
have to maintain a lot of state about
what it sent so that it can match up
when the response comes in
i've just a couple of two thoughts over
there
and
so i
again wasn't able to hear you well i
heard what i heard was the first
element at the
first part of the
uh what you were saying i'm sorry near
your voice is breaking up badly is it
just me or
yeah
i think maybe uh
rajiv if you can turn your video off and
see if that helps
if you can turn your video off
okay
because i was able to hear your uh
the first issue you presented
and i think it's something we need to
think of
the ability to say okay this playlist
not only this the the entire playlist
fail but only part of it
uh
and
it's
adds a significant complexity in the for
the definition of this api i believe
uh and need i think it we need to think
about it
um
and the second i i was not able to you
were breaking out from
at my place at least
what rajiv is saying is that
instead of using
why don't we create a generic object
instead of an error object but i think
that's
that really is part of these the rfc
already the the error
and it's not a generic object in that
sense so i'm not quite sure if
if i got his full question right i was
basically
trying to say that instead of having a
separate error object which only tries
to communicate the uh specific errors
why don't we roll the functionality of
reporting the error into a generic
status object so the status object is
designed to as closely as possible
mirror the structure of the incoming
preposition object the request so that
everything every spec that's in the
preposition object is available in the
status object and each spec in each
component of that spec has either a
status okay or
or a status error and if there's a
status error we have you know sub fields
and sub objects inside that more
you know
granularly describe what error was
encountered
the point the advantage of doing it that
way is that the upstream cdn doesn't
really need to maintain a lot of state
and
especially because some of these
transactions may be quite long-lived
transactions so if if a upstream cdn is
saying hey here's a set of ten
episodes playlist that i want you to pre
pre-warm or pre-position okay it it may
take
20 30 minutes for the downstream cdn to
complete that operation before it can
send the status back saying that hey
this particular trigger has now been
completed right so
do you really want the upstream cd and
trying to hold on to state
for that long so that it can match up
with an error message or if the complete
status message comes back it basically
mirrors everything that was in the
original pre-position request so the
upstream cdn doesn't have to have a
record of what it said the status
message is fully uh self-contained
yeah
first of all the status object itself
also
holds the trigger uh
the trigger v2 object
okay also yeah exactly
it's already it's the the trigger object
only the part of the status object it's
it resides in the object and the two
appears
both of them appears in the start in the
status object
uh so this is covered what is not
covered you you suggested also that
you would we would have an arrow at the
in a different object per spec so for
this that we have the status of this
block is like that and the arrow for
this package
and like
this is the error of this path and this
is the arrows of this deck and i believe
that
in we can achieve that particularly with
if if the opposition wants to achieve
that it can actually break the request
to several
twitters so it may have a trigger for
the fair spec and a separate trigger for
the second spec
and that's it so
yeah so so
my point here is
even with a single spec
you know that happens if it's a single
playlist um it may be it may be a
playlist say for example a movie which
has a quality ladder with six different
qualities so which means that's still
going to take some amount of time for
the downstream cdm to process before it
can respond so that's still
a certain amount of state that the
upstream cdn needs to maintain to be
able to correlate the errors so by
joining the error object as a part of
the status uh in the state testing as a
part of the trigger object itself you
know uh basically the response from the
downstream cdn is the trigger object
with it is embedded inside it so the
upstream does not have to
depend on any state the status response
has everything in it
yes
how does this advert i think we should
take it offline yeah
i'm going to inject myself as chair and
say that um
rajiv i think it's a good discussion if
you have actually uh a proposal for for
an object you know that might also help
move the thing forward but if we can
take this to the list and have that
discussion that would be great um we're
running a little behind schedule
so um near we could we could try and
push through the rest of this
thank you everyone
okay
let's uh proceed and skip
let's keep this one
next
yeah thanks and the last important thing
i want to discuss here
is the the photon capability objects
relates to this
control interface
and so the downstream sedan may support
some of the action it may support
pre-position and
invalidation but not support period
and
but it may support
those
actions but for different
subjects for example pre-position in in
validation and purge are supported for
metadata but only for content only
preposition is supported so for example
and we would like to be able to state
that
and
we would also like to say
for each such action
which
extensions are supported
for example a
a pre-position of content support time
policy but purge does not support time
policy
and
also
what is the target selection methods
that are allowed
okay so for metadata for people's
version of metadata you can you may use
playlist but for purge you cannot use
playlist
why i don't know
okay but
next
okay so what we try to do is define a
structure that says that for a specific
action
on a specific subject
the list of support supported specs are
this list and the list of supported
supporters extensions
is another list
and of course everything is subject to
the footprint that
the capability is
specified to so let's
look at the object and an example
okay so
the the capability is built from a list
of objects each object states the action
the subject
the supported specs and the supported
extensions
so in in this example
uh we support only preposition of
content and invalidation of content
okay no operation of metadata is
available
no purge is available
okay
and the specific preposition of content
can be done using your specs or ccid
specs
and it supports time policy
however invalidation does not support
a time policy it doesn't support any
extension because
the extensions list is empty or
not appear it doesn't appear
um
and then that's it
and do you have any questions for this
i think there's been good discussion
here i think everyone please go and read
the draft and we'll have
we'll continue the discussion on the
list i think this is good there have
been a lot of um good updates to
triggers and i think we're
making a lot of progress on making it
better so i'm excited
by the discussion
if there's no other questions
thank you
and we'll give phil another shot at this
and
did you have anything else
thanks
kevin you want me to see if i can bring
the slides up in the meantime while we
get um
phil still get back on
uh phil still there
new browser and
i don't see the mic icon
what i see is that your mic is muted
oh
maybe we we come back at the end of the
of the representations so you want to go
ahead and do frederick's
um
yeah
so you probably have to drive that
yep
i'll just stand up here
https
delegation
where is
it we go
okay so i'm just voicing um
fred here he's he could not make the um
the meeting today as he was not feeling
well
um so
the the revision of the draft that uh
that is put out uh in the mailing list
and also in a in the
really the the main change in this
version eight really is that it has been
pretty much cleaned up and has been very
simple very much simplified so what we
really see is that this document is now
aligned with rfc 9115
and
so basically what 9115 prescribes is
a pre
cdn
conversation that can happen between a
downstream cdn and upstream cdn where
the downstream will create an account
into
this entity
and it will exchange the certificate
information etc and all of that so once
all of that is done really the
the only um only part that is required
in this rfc is to be able to identify
that um
what is the location from where
um the downstream cdn will go and fetch
the certificate information and all of
the conversation has already happened
before it so
so there's no uh exchange of information
other than
um that
the the https um draft this draft will
basically essentially
uh only go out and make the request to
pull
the certificate from the upstream cdn
and that's what the the change is really
for this particular
draft
so as you see here the example acme
delegations and and then the
the url that has been already identified
on which it will go and retrieve
the request from so that really is the
change
um
you want to go to the next slide
and then
we still have to talk through about
uh security and privacy
the the sense is that since this draft
is not adding any other exposing any
other metadata
so there's really not any additional
security questions that come into play
here
and
the rfc 9115
and rfc 8006 already have addressed
independently of this draft
their security concerns that uh ensure
that the metadata is preserved or within
the rfc 9115
that there's no other security leak so i
think this document may by itself may
not have anything that
exposes
the security and privacy concerns but i
think we still want to just talk through
that
preferably in the mailing list if you
can review the draft and see if there
are any questions or concerns
that this draft should address with
respect to security and with respect to
privacy
so i think what
from the author's standpoint
the request is that if folks can review
this draft
this version 8
and respond in the mailing list
for any questions you have or you may
have
and
based on that based on the progress then
maybe we can ask for the working group
last call for version eight
i think that um you know it's it's much
simplified now which is good
um
uh i will go ahead and do the shepard
pre-review on on the new version
and hopefully everyone else can also go
out and review it
it's
it should be
pretty straightforward now um to move
forward with it i think we took out a
lot of the the
other stuff about metadata and
the harder stuff so right
yeah
okay all right uh any anyone have any
thoughts or questions otherwise please
review the draft i will review the draft
uh officially and
we'll try and move this forward by next
ietf
all right sounds good thank you
um
is kristoff around
can you hear me
yes
okay so i'm christopher wordpeak um
yes i'm going to present an update on
this draft here
uh on
delegated credentials subsets
so the start of this draft is actually
the result result of a split of the
previous draft that just has been
presented so the previous draft is about
delegated certificates and this one here
is about delegated credential which is
ongoing work in the tls working group
and
so this split has already been discussed
in the in this group here in cdni and um
yeah and uh yeah i would like to ask for
adoption of this uh draft within the cdi
cdna working group
uh the next line
so currently what is in the draft it's
uh that two
objects which are defined two mi objects
one is a
conf delegated credential
it only contains a url and
the idea is that the downstream cdn when
fetch or when accessing this url
can download another object and this
other object is this delegated
credential objects which contains the
delegated credential as defined in the
subset
internet draft and also
key material
so that's
yeah so it's quite simple those two
objects uh one which allows to
just provide an url in the other which
transports all the
uh cryptographic material let's say
so next line
so there are a couple of things to do in
the for this draft uh
so the first one is
so is about aligning those two drafts so
the one on dedicated certificates and
one on dedicated credential
just about the advertisement so that we
have an fci object which is a bit common
in which would allow to announce the
what is supported by the downstream cdni
and it could also allow to
advertise
additional parameters
there are sections about privacy and
security that needs to be added
and then but the main thing is about the
there's
still an issue about this delegated
credential object which is not really an
mi object as as uh
[Music]
as in the spirit of cdni so i have a
slide on this in the next slide
and
and then there are also things like um
currently in the current proposal the
public private key is generated by the
upstream cdn and maybe this is not
something that we always want to do
we should also support uh the case where
the downstream cdn is generating this
key and then asks for the delegated
credential for
to the upstream cdn
okay next slide
so yeah the open issue is that uh well
this delegated credential objects is not
really an mi object in the spirit of
the rfc 8006
because it's uh it's not um
well it's not fetched as a normal mi
object this is fetched via this url
which is defined in the configuration
delegated credential objects
but if we uh remove delegated credential
from this draft well there's no
point of uh
of just keeping the dedicated credential
of the conf delegated credential objects
and
so they're different object uh
options on
how to solve this issue
i mean the issue is really about uh how
can we fetch the delegated credential
how the downstream cdn can fetch the
delegated credentials
so there are one could be to rely on an
fci object which allows for the
downstream cdn to announce the number of
uh delegated credential it needs and
then the upstream cdn pushes the
delegated credential vsmi object
but the problem here is that
it's not really dynamic that we have to
keep in mind that dedicated credentials
have a very short
validity times so we have to renew
them regularly and
it's kind of the downstream cd and each
time it sees that
a delegated credential is expiring it
has to fetch a new one so we need a
really dynamic mechanism
and the other option would be to well
specify a dedicated interface which
allowed to fetch delegated credentials
so that
either it's an interface somewhere in
cdni or sva that needs to be defined
maybe the trigger interface i don't know
or something something else some
dedicated to that or
by proposing an extension so option b
in the acme working group um
which
details how to fetch the delegated
credentials
so this is something which is mentioned
in the subserts
draft
but
i don't know if the acme walking group
would exact accept that knowing that
the idea the interest of this delegated
credential is that you don't need any ca
anymore so it's not really in the scope
of the acme protocol
so
and yeah i mean i wanted to really
present all the
options and the this open issue and have
feedback maybe on the mailing list maybe
today on the discussion
and to see how to move forward
thank you kristoff i i know i owe you a
response on the mailing list as well i
haven't responded that email yet um i
apologize for that but uh sanjay is in
the queue sanjay
yeah um one quick question christoph um
i think the
i'm not sure that this draft will really
go into the acme working group
um because it really refers to the
subserts which is the work done in the
tls working group so i think it would be
better to to sort of if you're making
use of the uh subserts then keep the
focus clear that it really
um any reliance it has is focused solely
on that um
that rfc
um
the second point is that i i noticed
that the
the final version of uh that draft in
tls group has been submitted for rfc
though there's a slight change and i
don't know if materially that matters
but they're talking about that subsearch
document will apply to
dtls
instead of the tls
um it may materially not matter but i
just wanted to call that out also enough
not sure if you paid that attention to
that part
no i haven't i will have a look to to
understand the
the difference
okay uh i'm gonna put myself in the list
or in the queue i think um you know i i
brought up the this it's not really
um a metadata thing um i still need to
think about it more i don't know
that it makes sense to create an
interface just for this maybe we can
make an exception but it is something
separate i am concerned about the
security parameters of we're now going
to be
retrieving key material and we need to
be much more conscious of how we're
doing that and that
feels like a
security area not in you know not an art
problem but and we may get a lot of
pushback on that
if we try and specify something like
that in here um we can specify the
format excuse me right all you're really
doing is specifying the format and not
who's going to set up this server to to
provide it but it's a it's a
it's a fine line right now we're gonna
have to say what what version of tls are
you gonna use to pull this and is that
good enough and
um
i don't know that we want to go down
that road but i think everyone should
take a look at the draft and if you have
thoughts or comments on where we should
take it please please respond to the
list send your comments there and we can
try and take this forward
now as chair we wanted to have a
discussion quickly on whether or not we
can go ahead and adopt this draft this
was a split out from an existing working
group draft um
i i don't see a problem with us taking
on this work since we already had the
work and and we probably should move
this work forward but as a matter of
protocol we wanted to
um you know bring it up and say hey
does is the working group still
interested in going down this road i
assume we are but if anyone has any um
objections please feel free to voice
them now we will of course go to the
list and send out an actual adoption
email
and uh solicit
feedback but
if there are no objections here we will
go ahead and start that process
all right i think we're
i think we're good kristoff anything
else you wanted to add
well that's all on my side thank you so
much
thank you um
we're gonna give phil another shot
nope no idea
okay
so
[Music]
do we want to hear the access token or
we want to wait until after if
um
well okay let's let yeah let's let chris
go let's go ahead and let chris go
and give phil some another shot it
all right my audio working
yes well yes
fantastic and video too all right and
you got my slides up excellent yes
i'm going to try to move a little bit
quickly through this that we have time
for at least a couple of questions uh
this is gonna be the common access token
uh next slide
yep
and uh we're gonna start out i wanna
talk about who's doing this uh
what all we're doing and how that
relates to
the uri signing that is uh
uh being worked on in this group
and uh why this group might care next
slide
so this work is coming out of the cta
wave project
and the primary use case is for
streaming media
although
the token itself is a little bit more
general
and the goal is to find a single token
that covers all of the existing usages
in the industry
from all of the
uh
uh all of the cdn specific tokens that
are in use today next slide
so uh talk a little bit about how this
is different from the uri signing that
this group is doing uh
this uh the common access token is cwt
based
um
so it's it's going to be um
smaller terser and is a little bit
faster to parse
for cdns
there are more musts for the
intermediaries that receive these tokens
and so
the idea is to kind of draw a
very very firm fence around
what needs to be supported in order to
claim
common access token support
and
provide
provide strong guarantees so that
issuers can issue tokens knowing that
any intermediary can process it
obviously there's going to be no
built-in support for delegation it's not
part of a larger
cdni or other interconnect effort it is
just a token
uh but it does generally have more
claims with greater complex complexity
next slide
all right
we have uh
uh just like the just like the uri
setting token uh it has encrypted claims
in order to protect the privacy
of the uh end user
um but unlike it instead of putting it
as a base64 string it uses the cozy
object directly this saves processing
time and is
uh
and saves a lot of space
avoids repeated base64y
unfortunately this means you can't use
the subclaim
because that's a string
and this needs to be a cozy object we'll
get onto more of that
in a minute next slide
so it also has some additional claims
the first few are
really trying to draw a box around
any request
information
that
intermediaries or
providers are likely to use
in order to determine what content is uh
returned
so
the http method
is uh has a claim on it so that you can
specify that if your token is valid for
get but not put
and not post for example
and the
uh
alpn is actually an extension of
the fact that you can adjust based on
scheme
and so
there are tokens that claim https but
not http
using the regular expression on the uri
we wanted to extend that to
the alpn more generally
and then there are a number of headers
including an arbitrary number of
unspecified headers
that uh servers can use to return
uh
different differing information uh they
are of course well advised to use the
very header appropriately here
but um yes
having a regular expression on arbitrary
headers
um
we have some geography claims
um that we're still working out the
details on
uh we have a claim for the tls public
key
this allows you to use uh
for the tokens something similar to what
oauth does with mtls self-signed certs
uh wherein you use if you use a
certificate even a self-signed
certificate to acquire an authorization
token by whatever means you provide
credentials to get authorization tokens
um
the issuer can bind your public key to
the token it gives you
and the intermediary can
guarantee
that the
certificate you presented matches the
token so that if your token is stolen
then it can't be used without your
private key as well
we have nestable compositions for and or
and nor
and that drastically increases the
flexibility of the token and increases
the language that issuers can use
and lastly we have actions that modify
the rejections
so there are situations where when a
token is rejected
uh you
the issuer wants a very specific status
code uh and some headers to be returned
and uh
we're still workshopping exactly what
this is going to look like but the idea
is that
this will allow issuers to uh define
these rejections directly
next slide
okay
another difference is that uh we have
some strong types on these claims so for
example the critical claim here is an
array of claim numbers uh
claim numbers and uh strings
uh encrypted claims are of a cozy
encrypt type directly
network claims are going to be uh it's
going to be a seabor array of rfc 9164
tags uh other types uh other claims are
going to have appropriate types this
will reduce the amount of parsing
of strings and error handling that has
to happen uh post uh
well-formed validation next slide
so let's talk about why we in this group
might care about it
or we might not
um so like the alpn method and headers
those are just general um
uh uri
uh signing claims
they're applicable to any sort of a
uh any sort of a token like this um
compositions encrypted subject critical
claim those aren't even specific to
um
uri signing they are literally just
generic uh
claims
um
these are potentially generally useful
maybe it's useful to try to define them
generally
in a broader sense
next slide
uh
there's overlapping utility all uri
signing tokens can be represented as
cats here
and any successor token is likely to use
uh at least some of these
i don't see a whole lot of energy for
any sort of successor token
um to the
wonderful and delightful token that this
group has that satisfies the needs
but if there ever were
it's likely that such a token
would overlap heavily with at least some
of these claims next slide
so there's no real takeaway here uh this
is no action items this is uh noodles
for your noodle machine
and some public domain cats
um and i wanted to leave at least a few
minutes of time for
questions um about
uh what this token is and what it's
doing
kevin so
um i guess how far along are is the
development of this and do you see
um adoption of it and
do you think that it will
it will go anywhere or whether or not
you know uri signing token just
it will it also go somewhere or will it
fall by the wayside because this thing
is more i guess does this add a whole
bunch of stuff that people want or does
it just add a whole bunch of stuff
it definitely adds it it definitely adds
a bunch of stuff that people want
and it adds
some stuff
and which category which thing
uh is in
uh depends
based on the use cases
um so like there are some there are some
folks with zero interest in any of the
tls stuff
um
and there are folks that are like no no
that that enables my very specific use
case
and so
um there is there's a lot of drive
towards adoption on this
and that's why this work is happening in
the cta
um
that there's a group of people there
that represent a variety of
intermediaries and
providers
that
uh
yeah um
uh uh
that have a lot of energy towards this
and they're really pushing for something
that will be genuinely implemented
across
a wide variety of
intermediaries and so yeah the the goal
is to codify
the feature set that people are already
doing so that they don't so that nobody
has to give up features by switching
tokens right
and do you think that this is something
um
we should liaise with or is it just
be aware if we choose to take forward
uri signing if we don't ever do anything
else with urs signing then
they can go and do what they want
yeah i i think that some sort of a
liaison probably makes sense there's a
lot of overlap in uh participation
already
which is which is a valuable thing
i think there is um
if this uh if the cat takes off and uri
signing token does not for whatever
reason it may at some point be valuable
to define an interface layer between
the uri signing token and the cat
that allows people to use the cat for
uh cdna delegation right
we may want a metadata at least or
something to support it right
right um and now if we if if we ever
want to take on that work there are
other questions we have to ask um and
a lot of the the musts
around this were intentionally left out
of the uri signing draft because there
was not a desire to force all of the
intermediaries to implement all of these
features in order to
do cdni
um right
and and the goal here is to create uh
you know genuine interoperability and
may is the may is the bane of an
interoperable system right
so
uh
if we ever do that
there is a there is definitely going to
be some um some questions an issuer can
express anything that they need to
express in a cat but there are more
requirements on an intermediary uh
supporting a cat than there would be on
supporting a uri signing token
got it sanjay
yeah um so chris i
before
you were put on the agenda i did see
that there was some support in the
mailing list about you know you talking
about it so i'm glad you did that
um and you clarified some of the
questions that kevin was asking
um
moving forward you also mentioned about
implementation so that's an important
thing
um
so i'm i'm wondering
um if you want to keep us
sort of apprised
maybe you know in july when we meet
to see you know where you are you know
other companies are if there's any
implementation and
and you know maybe
if there's anything that you made use of
out of the uri signing
so you know we'd like to hear more about
it and see you know where you are at
yeah um
i can certainly i can certainly keep the
group updated um and yeah there's
there's no surprises um
the
the the structure is very similar
they're
coots versus jutes it's you know it's
the same roots at the core
there are only a few obvious ways to
express these sorts of things
okay
thanks for the chance i just wanted to
say that uh to the earlier question
there is definitely very very heavy
interest from content providers and the
cdn in the ecosystem of content delivery
to support a common scheme right now the
ecosystem is extremely fragmented and
cad has the benefits of flexibility with
these
logical claims that can be
put together with ants and ours but also
the conciseness of that which helps the
performance which is extremely critical
for
the cdn vendors
thank you
anyone else have any comments on this
phil
are you back
thank you thank you thanks chris
say get phil
can you hear me
yes oh yes yes i can hear you
finally
it took you what hour and for 45 hour
and 15 minutes
meet echo thinks it has something to do
with the udp session initiation but oh
this is amazing i can i can see all
kinds of little
uh
wave things going on over there all
right sorry
um
so
my my thoughts on this um i love
standards
things that are generic that can be used
by more people
i think that's why we change uri signing
to be jwt instead of all the query
params stuff that it was in the
beginning um if something like this
comes along that that fills that gap
better than uri signing i'm all for it i
don't i think you are a signing with
something that came along because there
was nothing else that did it but if
there's a more generic solution for it
i like it and i think the um the puns
are going to work out the memes are
going to work out a lot better for cat
than they will for uri signing
excellent
[Music]
oh funny andrew i got it
all right phil do you want to talk about
your signing real quickly
sure um so
uh the the issues that ben had with it
there was one
minor clarification he wanted to see
which i added and he was happy with the
other thing the other point was having
to do with delegated shared keys going
from
from going from csp to ucdn he was fine
with it was from ucdn to dcdn that he
did not like
and i
wrote to the mailing list and nobody
really replied and we decided to just go
ahead
and and correct it
so what i did was remove the the
explanation of how to do it and like
there were a couple places where it was
like oh and you can do this here and i
just removed that part
but i did not remove the concept
entirely
because i did not want somebody to
rediscover this and say oh this is a
great and clever idea i've come up with
and let me implement this and instead i
put um that they should not do this um
ben is still concerned that that's in
there at all um
and that it's should not versus must not
i guess i i'm i was torn on this i
thought about this for a while before i
went with should not
um and mostly because i felt like we had
we had no recourse like if we say you
must not do this
um or else what like they can do it in
the background it's it's already out of
band there's nothing that it's breaking
there's no way to detect it or stop it
so i just said you should not do it
i think he wants it to be must not i'm
super open
to
to that being a better route i just
didn't know if i had a solid argument to
make so it
please
give me the the grounds to stand on and
i will gladly make that change
i see francesco on the mic here so
francesca
hi phil
um
about the should not uh something that
should be noted is that it's not enough
to say should not and
um
and let the reader decide that what what
level this is like how
um
you know required or recommended it is
to not do this or
it there needs to be text around um and
i haven't reviewed the text so like
yeah i'm not sure at the moment if there
is enough text about that but
it needs to be clear what the
consequences are of implementing this
and
in in um
like ideally should not means that um
there are
like the the writer foresee cases where
this is allowed
and this could be like corner cases or
you know situations in which you cannot
do differently than
actually using this mechanism and
that's what the should and should not is
for it's for allowing these corner cases
and describing the content context and
like maybe examples in which
this is acceptable um
and yeah this is uh we see this a lot in
in isu evaluation where
we considered
is it must or should really and i think
it
applies here as well um
so maybe that's
that could clarify a bit uh ben's point
about
why um this should maybe is not enough
to him
um
i don't know if it helps at all but like
i see the point of you know not wanting
it to remove it completely and then
someone reinventing it um
it really depends on on the actual text
that is around this should not in my
opinion
how strong it is and how
well-described it is
okay yeah i i don't i don't see any
like valid use cases other than
people
who implement are saying no i really
want to use shared key and i really want
to use this and and i think we've said a
ton of stuff about not doing it and why
not to do it there's things in the
security consideration i can always add
more i'm always open to that i really
was on the fence somebody jokingly sent
me i forget what what rc it is now but
it was an april 1st rfc that had really
should not
and
yeah
and and i really i i kind of like you
know
really should not is what i wanted to
put there but i was like oh no this is
you know obviously a joke but it i was
really on the fence and i just i guess
maybe i'm maybe i'm just misinterpreting
the should versus must more as
uh
plain english versus what the rfc state
and so maybe maybe you must not as is
the right thing and i can i can make
that change i just
i i discussed it with some people um
some experienced ietfers and they they
didn't even have a definitive answer one
of them said start with must and see
where you go and the other one said
start with should and see where it goes
so
i can just i can just change it to must
or must not rather just to be clear
yes and and
if the working group has an opinion
that's that's very valid like
um to have this conversation and decide
and have a consensus call by the chairs
that is going to you know um motivate
putting in their must or not master
should there that would help so if i'm
also like i will have to look at the
text again too
to have a more definitive opinion but
yeah
i think our
original i mean the whole time it's been
there are people who do this right we
know that they shouldn't do this but
there are people who do this and we
don't want we didn't want to you know
completely lock them out but
and maybe it's okay to say must not and
they can still go and do it there's
nothing preventing them from going and
doing it right
um
but it
i guess the stance of the ietf should be
to do something secure and not allow
them to do something that's
unsafe right
like that could be um
described in the document without
normative language
and say like
we are aware that exists be like there
is exist and this is not uh this is not
recommender or like
yeah
yeah there's a lot of this is not
recommended language in it already i
think it's i think ben really wants me
to put
must not like just do not do this it is
not it is outside of the specification
if you do
which i think is fair i think it's fair
any other comments
francesca has one more comment i think
yeah sorry so so from a process point of
view um i just wanted to say that
uh ben will be stepping down the isg
tomorrow so his
blocking discuss will disappear
but i hope that
we can still
you know get his input and
um even though it's not going to be like
actually blocking the document
i hope that we can still get his
yeah like informal approval of some sort
um
but
yeah we should get to a consensus in the
working group and then
move forward
from my perspective i i definitely
respect his opinion and would like to
have him on board with it so i can i i
can totally agree with that
and he's been very helpful in finding
issues with the document in general that
that we fixed up so
i'm okay with going must not um
phil um you know
i'll i'll leave it to you to decide
um
i'll go and review the text again
everyone else please also if you have
some cycles review the text again
and if you have thoughts or feelings on
it
and we can really really try and get
this one finished up
and out the door
once and for all
thank you phil
thank you for the perseverance in
getting us your audio we appreciate it
yeah sorry for wasting so much time but
glad it finally got through
thank you phil all right
all right we've got we've got 30 minutes
and we've got two more topics to cover
here yeah
but i think we have enough time so um i
think next alfonso goes
alphonse are you good
yeah
i'll bring up your slides just give me a
second here okay thank you you can try
and fit it in 15 minutes to give andrew
time that would be great yeah i know
yeah i would try
sorry we lost the order here
so um
there is capacity
there it is
okay thanks
yeah i will try to go
quick on the first part of the slide
deck
because it's a recap of something that
we have explained oh glenn that was
let's understand what the the person
that was presenting this in the last
meeting so please next slide
yeah next please
yeah so just why we present in this um
this draft to the to to this group
um
[Music]
as
all of you probably know um in the
streaming video alliance there is a the
open catching working group
where
is gathering
different perspective of the streaming
video
business
where you have the content providers you
have commercials at the end so you have
sales providers
and that they all they have the common
interest of uh
bringing the best quality of experience
for video delivering this video services
to end users um
so we working
on trying
this effort of having the best quality
of experience um this is why we work
together um to create this inter try to
get integrations more efficient and try
to get some standardization of how
the different processes of the video
delivery goes from the content provider
to the end users
all
through all these different roles or
techniques technologies um et cetera so
please next
so
at the first let's see the sva open
catching working group was
paying attention to the cni
interfaces and metadata uh definitions
of the different rfcs like a80607
and 8008 um
but there was a finding that it was
probably needed um
to cover some gaps that uh trying to put
all this together for the
this video service deliveries um
the interfaces where metadata interfaces
were not enough uh to cover all those
needs from content providers from the
cdns or for the service providers
this is why
we were working on this
extending the metadata that come from
this group to try to to cover all the
needs from the different
members of different roles in the video
delivery
trying to define um
useful methods to
make the configurations try to automate
the configurations to putting this in
place with our current
implementations and deployments in in
real life
and extending with more advanced
configuration publishing
capabilities um that are required by
content providers trying things like
publishing versioning of configurations
and things like that
please next
yeah well this is very very quick this
is a representation of the of the
metadata mobile model of the 806 um and
yes i will be very quick uh we haven't
touched any of these
many structure of the metadata model but
we live for uh our proposed extensions
in the genetic met as generic metadata
objects so
with taking leverage of this infinite
extensibility that the interface permits
on the metadata is next
yeah so at the end
all what you have in in the orange
background are the different categories
that we are adding
or we are trying to add with this
extension
to the metadata model from the cdni we
will come in in a minute for that this
next
so as a summary uh
i think
yeah we can go later on this
past peace
sanjay
yeah one of the things that includes
this draft
is what we call it processing stages
this is a way to permit um to intervene
in the different processes that happens
when the
user agent is requesting a content
to um a cdn or a damson cdm sorry
how that process will go to an
abstinence cdn origin to get the
response back from the upstream and that
response goes to the user ryan by the
damson cdn these processes that we he
identified for the steps from the client
requests ordinance requests or any
response on client response we
defining a way to intervene on those
processes so
downstream cdn is able to make
transformations on different parts of
the of the request
for instance modifying the the headers
that goes to the origin when try to get
the
the the object that is requested or we
are able
we could be able to modify
a header in the response to the client
and and
any other transformation that could be
required for the different use cases
that are required for this traffic
delegation yes next
yeah well um
this is a i'm going to pay
time here now it's just a representation
of the
processing stages model all these leave
in a generic metadata object
that is defined defined in the in the
draft
so please next
and this was an example of the host
index
representing the generic metadata mi
processing stages and in this example
you can see that we use
an expression match as is defined in the
in the draft as a metadata expression
language
where for a condition in this case that
is the response from the origin is 200
then we will modify the cache policy for
that specific object
so this is an example of what we we
intend to do with this
next
yeah and and again well there is a
definition of the expression language
with the different operators variables
or even
built-in functions that could be used um
for for all these
modifications this next
in terms of the capacity capabilities
interface um we have in the these drafts
have been defined uh a few
new objects that are required to
the thompson cdn be able to announce to
the upstream the different capabilities
regarding these new extensions for the
metadata model that could be required
for the abstinence to know so for
instance uh it's important and it could
be important for the absent to know that
the processing stages is available or
not or even it could be important uh to
ha to the amsterdam to know that a
subset of the
processing stages is
the dams incident is capable for for
instance uh it should be important to
know the amps incident to know if the
spectral language is supported in the
dumps incident or not maybe it's not but
maybe is able to do some processing
stages
replacement without expression language
so um there are some
conditions here that the fci
interface could not only
announce the capability of a complete
object but of a part of an object
applicant
yeah
[Music]
yeah i will not stop here
this is something that will come
probably next so it's not changing in
this draft version regarding this but we
just for you to know the sva and the
opencasting working group is working on
try to extend
the metadata model with new features
regarding an advanced publishing method
that will meet the content provider a
better management of the configurations
um so probably this is something that
will come in in the following meetings
please next
i'm going to insert myself in the queue
here yeah
um so i i see that you have uploaded the
um
the new revision of the draft right yep
so
based on and i think you have addressed
some of the comments that were posted
from the from the last meeting in the
draft i see that yeah
okay
next please
yeah so well that we are version two
what's changed from version one to
version two one of the comments
that came from the last meeting is that
uh they could be good to have a
categorization of the different generic
metadata objects that we are
including with this extension uh that
was a very fair point um so we we have
made this categorization uh we have
separated different metadata objects
with
what these sections like cash control or
metadata related could catch properties
management here's the list of the
different objects in this category the
origin access
metadata related to the acquisition of
the content
client access control in this version of
the draft there is no generic metadata
object uh
yet but we did because this is something
that we in the open catching working
group are working
on different options
different objects for this client access
control uh but they're not
finished yet so we haven't included in
the draft uh but i think it would we
think we were good to having in the in
the as a category here even and is empty
now but we we will have different
objects in the next version of the draft
edge control genetic metadata to inform
processing of responses downstream
so it's a way to
to the abstinence to condition
uh the way the thompson cdn could
respond to a reversal agent request in
the edge uh so this could include
something like the i will see we will
see that in a moment for the crossover
in policy for instance there were some
doubts in the last meeting uh so
the upstream is able to somehow set the
damp since the end to
independently of information that are
that came from the absence indian origin
to enforce
some
functionality
to the end user request
okay
processing stages as a complete category
for itself and in general metadata is
where we include other objects that are
not
we haven't found
a category of the others categories to
where to put in there okay
yeah we have other
examples to every genetic metadata
object because it was something that in
the version one i think they weren't
examples
we have include some minor changes in
the metadata expression language um that
there is no change in the
in the
built-in operators or variables uh parts
but it's just about the in the syntax in
the in the object in the json object
um there is more detailed description
for processing stages
uh we have removed from the draft the mi
requested capacity limits there is
something that goes in the other draft
that andrew will be presenting in a
moment uh so we decided to put this out
of this draft as the capacity um inside
a draft have their own definition of mi
object that will be extending
the
and we added corrections from the
previous version that was detected in
the revision from the members
please next
so i will just go directly if you for
the sake of the time
to to one of some of the main doubts
that were in the in the previous
meetings uh so
i i'm open to to discuss any other
questions if you want um here i i have
asked in the presentation um in the
first column the section of the version
one and the section four the section two
so version two sorry uh because we go up
we have categorized all the objects then
section numbering has completely changed
uh so yeah for the sake that you can
find the reference of the of the
previous questions on the last meeting
um
so i i will i will go to the section 232
the third line there
um
about aloe compress and this there was a
concern about this object from kevin um
and
yeah there was a very fair point of the
doubt here the thing is that uh we have
found that this object allo compress
that we still have it in the in the
version 200 with that name
that name does not reflect correctly the
function that
is expected for a dumb abstinence cdn to
use this object
the idea of this object of the
functionality is that the upstream cdn
enforces the dumpster cdn to compress a
response to the end user if the user has
sent the access encoding header
correctly
but independently if the origin has sent
the response to the downstream
uncompressed
so it's like delegating the compression
of the an object in the damson cdn in
the response to the to the end user
independently of what the origin is
doing okay uh probably this will um ha
made the abstinent to not dedicate
resources to the compression and
delegate that to the dumpster in cdn
okay
so uh for sure the name allo compress is
confusing um uh we are working on
changing the name so we still don't have
a
a final name with this but something
like edge compress or first compress
will be more suitable for the use case
that is especially for this object uh so
probably will be changing the next
version of the draft um
for other the next section 211 the cash
policy and there is another one in the
next slide that this is the negative
catch policy
this is
something similar related to um
to what the origin is doing uh of the in
the upstream and what the
upstream cdn wants the dumpster incident
to do
all these cash
cash policies are related to cash
control headers in the responses
typically the origin could send a cash
control that
is the same that should be sent to the
end user right
but the thing is that there are use
cases where the upstream
wants the dumbstream to have a different
behavior regarding the cache
in this case this is regarding the time
to leave of the objects in the dumps in
cdn cuts so independently of what is
sent to the end user in the response to
the request the upstream needs to say
the downstream to change the way that
it's behave the cuts so there are some
examples um that that we have found in
in real life in in our
production services deployed is like um
for instance an upstream wants to have a
catch control zero or no cash no store
for the
local catching the end user but they
don't want to receive a huge amount of
requests from the dumpster
so they prefer to
maintain in a double stream a ttl of
let's say one minute
while the end user received
a no catch no store
why why damstring could do that because
at the same time the hamstring
using the cni or any other method
available is able to make content
management of the downstream
so
they don't need that the damsen
continues to revalidate the object
because if they need to change the
object they can use the content
management to do that
and that way the downstream block or
stop the huge amount of requests from
the end users and is not disturbing the
origin server so this catch control
policies or the negative patch
controllers policies is intended for
that so a way to change the behavior of
the dams in terms of the ttl of the
objects
without changing what is intended for
the industrial request
so please next uh sanjay
yeah
this section um this is two three one
one is regarding the gross origin policy
um the doubt from here from kevin was
in the description was not very clear we
have tried to change the description to
have a more clear understanding of the
reason of this
the course the cross-origin policies
that this came from
from the http fetch standard
the the definition of what comes in the
origin header in a request
when there is a fetch in the browser or
in a player in a client that is making
the request
the origin header include is included in
that request and there is not the
service um
url it's not what is defined in the host
in the course only in a host match
because the upstream one is delegating a
host match is delegating the service of
the request for a video content for
instance or for another object
but the origin header is related to the
url of the
you know how the client access that
content in the in a video platform or in
a web page so in an example you could
the client could access the video
platform.example.com
but the host match is
videodelivery.example.com
so the request goes to
videodelivery.sample.com
that would be the host match that is
delegated but the origin header included
by the browser or the player could be
videoplatform.example.com so in that
case
we cannot relate the course with the
host match because it's not going to be
that it's going to be where the content
is published
publishing on internet so
why it's the schema and the domain name
and port is because that is how it's
related in the http fetcher standard
well we have tried to explain this
better so hopefully the multi are now so
whatever you can find later we can we
can discuss can we wrap up quickly um
yeah i will try to finish yeah
yes next um
i'm trying to find something more
important uh catch policies is
explaining before
yeah some correction yes please next
yeah there are some questions about
including something in the registry for
different options one was for the
private fetchers um is my point here is
that
private features is something that is
more a point to point so from one
specific abstinence to one specific
downstream cdn
because our private features probably
from the dumpster so i don't think it's
needed to have a private a public
registry for for those private features
because of that because i think they are
not generic and by definition
there was another comment regarding and
the traffic type
this is a generic um
this is a video specific configuration
and we're talking about
generic probably generic
we can discuss later if you want by the
mailing list i think that's a good point
there isn't here an explanation but we
can discuss so this is next
yeah and that's it very quick i'm sorry
uh for the sake of the time but please
i'm i'm more than welcome to to use the
mailing list to for whatever requirement
that you want um
and in the last slide please sanjay that
is where
we find that in this draft person is
good enough to to plant uh to have this
adopted as a working group draft
uh all the realistic concerns
maybe we can use the middle east to to
discuss around this
um thank you
what i would suggest is that if you can
put those uh questions that kevin had
and the answers you have in the mailing
list i think that would you know at
least create a record there and yeah
you know that have similar questions
maybe answered it in in that manner and
then we can um
you know um
take up your question of uh adopting
this into the mailing list
kevin what do you think
i think um
thank you for thank you for the updates
i haven't had a chance to go over the
full draft the
the the groupings are great i think that
the other thing then is do we want to
break it up into multiple drafts right
now it's a 90-page draft and there's a
lot of stuff in there and
there are things we could probably
accelerate some of the metadata are
probably easier to push through um if we
do them as separate pieces um
some of the stuff that's more fleshed
out
we should consider that i think um
versus the
the mono draft
which is which is very hard and
especially with the um
the stages which i think are interesting
i think that's good stuff but that is
going to take a lot longer i think than
just pushing through some of the
metadata that's helpful for you guys
okay okay
okay we we will discuss it then and
with the other co-authors so what what
what would come plan to do with breaking
out in different drafts
okay
thank you alfonso thank you
great job
all right last but not least andrew you
have the remainder of the time
saving the worst
um i guess for the last
yeah yeah i'm gonna do this actually a
lot of the
back story and just kind of go right
into the changes
so this is the
version of the draft we're considering
it's the
capacity insights extension version 2.
next slide please
as part of this the this the draft has
actually been simplified a bit we've cut
out
one of the main concepts which was
allowing an upstream
to ask the downstream to reconsider
capacity limits uh we weren't
necessarily confident in
the approach we were taking so we
decided to strike it out
just to make it a little more clear and
concise uh next slide please
so the component that was related to
that which was struck out is the mi
requested capacity limits object once
again we just didn't feel we had a a
good enough grasp on how it would be
used effectively to um communicate
or allow the upstream to ask the
downstream to
reconsider adjustments
uh next slide please
this it represents one of the two
extensions we're looking to make to the
fcvi uh capacity limits payloads uh the
this is the capacity limits it is the
main driver for allowing a downstream to
communicate to an upstream
of
utilization goals they should be
targeting
next slide please
this is the uh the delta of
the json structure from the last draft
on the left you'll see that there were
some hard-coded
sections of total limits and host limits
we've decided to try and generize that
slightly by moving those over into
generic limits objects and then identify
or
adopting a new subscope to those limits
so you can see here on the right hand
side there is a scope object which
is of type published host with several
values this allows um
a more granular
scoping of
a capacity within a cdni footprint
sometimes that we found that that wasn't
necessarily um
granular enough to meet certain needs so
we decided to
allow within that footprint a subscoping
and this is the vehicle that we've
identified for that
next slide please
uh this object hasn't changed since the
last version of the draft this is a an
object which is meant to
advertise
telemetry source capabilities and this
is relevant in that
the capacity limits were advertising
we've we felt that there was a strong
correlation with correlating that to a
uh a telemetry source so there was no
ambiguity between what capacity
advertisement were specifying and how to
measure the utilization against that
limit um so this
this is really a foundation for further
work which we have yet to um
put forward but we we felt it was very
relevant in this case and wanted to lay
the foundation for it here next slide
please
uh once again this is a diagram from the
last presentation just kind of goes
through the over
overview of
what we how we anticipate this to work
really the the upstream would be polling
the downstream to ask for
the
capabilities of
and within those capabilities we would
include capacity limits
the upstream would then also be looking
to consume telemetry data that related
to the specific capacity limits combine
those two data points together to make
sure that there is sufficient um
sufficient capacity in order to delegate
requests to the downstream
next slide please
um
once again this is the the
diagram which allow or shows how the
downstream would reflect changes to
capabilities to the upstream
relies upon a callback mechanism and a
subscription service
handled by the upstream in the
downstream
uh next slide please
uh once again this is just a call out to
the fact that we had removed the mi
requested capacity limits object from
this uh version of the draft
and next slide please
and that is it all right i made it in
five minutes all right
good job andrew
thank you
um
any any comments um
so i encourage everyone i haven't had a
chance to look at the updated draft
myself uh everyone please go out and
read the updated metadata and capacity
drafts and send comments to the list
please um
i think
we should
we we should we should see um you know
if we can get some more comments out
there and have more people discuss the
draft and then we can talk about whether
um there's
you know appetite in the working group
to to adopt this work and take it on
um any other final comments andrew
no that was it
okay thanks so much
um we have three minutes left to wrap up
uh sanjay anything you want to say uh my
comment is i hope to see everybody in
person at
ipf114
um it's good to see people back in the
rooms
and i am happy thank you for everyone
who came and presented thank you for you
know carrying with us through some
technical difficulty um we got through
it all and i appreciate all the hard
work from all of our
authors sanjay
yeah yeah i i i echo your comments and i
think there's there's good progress
and i would like to see you know andrew
you know sharpen up this draft so that
you know we can bring it back here and
and take a pull on it and likewise um
glenn and team um
everybody has done a lot of work on the
metadata so
uh alfonso you know you you have the
action item here to try and move that
draft
um
maybe you know as um suggested that
maybe break it up into smaller pieces so
i think that might be able to we might
be able to kind of look at it easily
uh and move forward um with those
with those drafts
um so yeah i hope to see everybody in
person uh the next one is in july
almost end of july third week of july in
philadelphia so maybe
easier for some
not so easy for others but um
i know francesca would not be able to
join us there she is she's going to be
on
on maternity leave then
um
wish her all the best
but uh keep up the work here because
there's a lot of stuff going on so
a lot more to come i guess in the next
itf
um but before we end we've got about a
minute left francesca anything you want
to add
she says no she's
so she's all good i think thumbs up okay
all right thanks everyone see you in
philadelphia
take care all right thank you everybody
is that crystal at the back
hello hey chris how are you all right
good to see you nice people through
masks
i figured he must be here somewhere
how are you all right
good
oh finally we get this meat indeed
i know
so you're right yeah yeah
i don't know it's just tuesday and it
feels like already a long week yeah or
something
was that when did you arrive i got here
on saturday
yeah
i i did but i'm just like feeling
against something today you know but i
you know
i'm good you know just you know
having this
myself not stay up late in the night
you