chair slides share
with zero seconds to spare how's that
just in time terran
all right
just in time sharing yeah exactly
isn't that a supply chain problem
we'll give another minute or two for
people to wander in since it's
very early morning for some of us
i'm sorry two a two two five o'clock is
early in the morning
two is you know late the night before
two is two is a little rough
i'm i'm glad that this is my last 2 a.m
meeting so
yeah
yeah the next one is going to be
and
yeah
no problem will be much nicer for us
west coast folk regardless of what the
world status is i should make it to that
all right joey where where are you
located
right now in spain
ah so good time zone for you
yeah i'm a happy cookie this time
all right well numbers are getting
fairly stable
it looks like you have
there
like
actual humans hello people
hello people in real life
[Music]
so i do have to show off my my super
spiffy dane mug
that won't help unless i have my camera
yes
see that's nice nice and shiny
yeah we see the mirror image version but
uh
i didn't i didn't realize
that that meat echo didn't flip the
image
well
so my uh my camera is weird because it's
actually upside down and then i video
process it to turn it right side up in
order to keep the boom for the camera
out of the way of my vision i'm i'm very
strange like that
you know only geeks could do crazy stuff
like that so
how many meetings have you joined this
week with the upside down image though
just one just just the one so
i don't even remember what that one was
but
um
let's go ahead and get started it looks
like numbers are getting fairly stable
there's nobody standing at the back of
the room this probably won't be a
two-hour meeting so we have plenty of
time but
so welcome to the dane authentication
for network clients everywhere dance
we need music uh a meeting um so your
chairs today are west hartiger paul has
taken over as the
are you the a.d paul for the for the
group
now uh yes i am
okay so paul's taking over as the aed
newly indoctrinated into the aesg and
i'm really happy that joey is uh offered
to help us as my co-chair for dance
thank you joey
uh the goal of this group is to shut
down before i can no longer find icons
to put on the titles page of all of our
meetings so this is the latest one
the good news is the internet needs
keeps creating new stuff so that
probably isn't a problem
uh the note will i'm sure all of you
have read and processed the note well um
the essential
notes are be aware of what you're saying
at a microphone or else you know lawyers
get involved and nobody wants that
there's a bunch of bcps that talk about
it
the iutf has a code of conduct that we
all live by which includes treating
people with respect speaking slowly and
limiting the use of slang and
terms that people don't understand
dispute ideas by reasoned argument not
by
violent disagreement
and use best engineering judgment
finding the best solution for the whole
of the internet is the goal of the ietf
and then contributing to ongoing work
within the etf
this is the working group information
for dance we have a data tracker of
course we have a purpose
the mailing list is dance.etf.org i
assume everybody is probably on it but
if you're not there is the url to join
we now have
three active drafts to consider
two of which are adopted and the other
one is not as we'll talk about in a
minute
[Music]
this session is being recorded we will
do the queue management using the meat
echo online site tool so
if you are in the room please do use the
the mini client or
um i think that there's supposed to be a
scannable url in the room i actually
don't know i hope you guys do if you're
in the room
[Music]
uh the agenda today as i said you know
this and this probably will not take two
hours unless we dive into a whole lot of
discussion uh we'll take 10 minutes for
sharing related stuff
we already have this is meeting number
two
we had two buffs and then this is
meeting number two and we already have
an implementation so i'm super happy to
hear that that the hackathon actually
had
an implementation of dance-related stuff
so we'll get a presentation from them
look what it did to the font that's fun
the architecture document we'll talk
about a little bit and the solutions to
solutions documents of course we will
talk about uh and then we'll have a
little bit of time at the end for open
mic if people want to talk to things
remember one of the things we agreed to
er in the in framing the charter was
these were sort of the target documents
to start with there are some other
potential uses of of dance technology
that we were deliberately putting off
until these sort of got out the door
so we're happy to talk about those but
they're not within scope until we get
essentially these documents dunish
so we did have a call for adoptions i
started it on february 28th uh issued it
for three weeks which ended the last
week
the authors have recently published
updates to those documents so they are
now draft ietf instead of draft
hue and
the good news is that there seem to be
very good support for all of them
so those are now official working group
documents thank you for everybody that
helped
respond with your willingness to
participate and help with those
documents
i will say that the mailing list has
been generally quiet if you look at the
activity level on the mailing list there
is generally been very low volume of of
notes
so you know that brings me a little bit
of concern you know we do want things to
continue and i realize we're early on
and the documents are made not at a
point where we're ready to discuss the
minutiae of them
i hope we're getting to that point but
if you look at the message chart on the
right-hand side you'll see that there's
not been a whole lot of messages most of
the ones in february were responding to
me saying yes i agree to help with the
documents
so you know our thoughts on well how can
we increase discussion on the mailing
list and get more work done would be you
know please have more discussion on the
mailing list about the documents
remember that providing early review and
feedback is a good thing for the
documents so that we don't wait for all
the discussion to happen during last
call
and then of course discussing you know
use cases and things like that is always
a good thing to do too so
i am if anybody wants to speak to why
there's not been a huge amount of
discussion i'm i'm certainly willing to
listen to arguments and and uh things
but in the meantime
we'd like to see that pipe up so
and then back to the agenda so
i think we're up to hackathon
implementation results
um
i'm not quite sure of the couple of
people who was going to present who is
that this morning
someone walk into the mic or taking
notes
okay
oh yes and tim is taking notes thank you
tim for being willing to take notes
uh and let me get your slides
up are you doing it
all right thank you
um
so hello everyone uh gay bartomina from
ethnic i will present you briefly
the
uh implementation results that we've
uh done during the academ and also uh
the use case that we have using laura
one in iot
uh next type please
so uh
as you already know probably
we've worked on the uh two documents
that are here so the first one being
the
then
oh well the intent authentication and
the second one being the tls extension
to send the client id
to user server next type please
so
for the first draft we based on our
implementation on an existing uh dane
library
by schumann so
we didn't re-implement the whole day in
validation
what we did though
was
creating a
testing environment
to
emulate the
our use case with a basic client and
server doing mutual tls authentication
and we implemented the extension the tls
extension for both that's 1.2 and 1.3
i'll get back to that later
um also
in case of the
claim id being not sent in the extension
uh we fall back on using the
subject alternative name from the
certificate
but we still require uh the uh
tds extension to be present uh just like
there is no no extension uh data
also uh we have support for uh
authorization rules so that we can
process the client id and
according to whatever rules or you want
well accept the connection or reject it
the
one we did like the most basic one we
and the one that
was sufficient for us was just
accepting all client id uh on a
well on a given domain so our authenti
being like sub domain of a given domain
list we accept them and we reject
everything else
next type please
thank you
so for the tls
extension implementation we base our
work on the golang tls library and we
extended that so
i just want to to
mention here
that i was a bit confused uh on the
implementation because
on tds 1.2 well i don't know if it is a
misunderstanding on my side or or not
but on cs1 2 it seems that the client id
where the client is actually sending the
extension first and then the server is
responding because it's using like
client hello and server low
but uh
ts1213 is using message uh certificate
request message and certificate message
so it is the server starting the
well send
sending the extension first and then the
client and this causes issues uh because
uh at the clientele part we still don't
have like this uh
version like a negotiation so we we
don't know whether or not to to to use
ts12013
uh on the for the server side so if
someone like want to clarify that uh now
right it's honest um normally you should
be using uh this extension in the in the
same way in 1.2 and 1.3 when it comes to
the use of client and server hello so
there should be no difference uh
whatsoever
so you're you're saying that we should
uh always use clientele in serverless
and not the certificate uh request and
certificate message
unless you have a very good reason to do
so
according to the draft it's just that
incorrect in cs103 we're using like uh
certificate uh request and certificate
message and that this has the advantage
to like
not uh
send the client id and clear text
that's a that's a
good question to look into it yeah let
me have a look at that
uh schumann you want to speak
uh sure can you hear me okay
yep yes we can hear you fine
yeah so uh that is a good point so
the reason is uh yeah normally they
should be the same uh the reason they're
slightly different is because
of the need to
encrypt the client extension because
there are privacy concerns
and there's no way to do that in tls 1.2
because it has to be sent in
the client hello in in tls 1.3
you can send the
extension as part of the certificate
request message but you're right that
comes after
the certificate has been uh
prompted by the server side
in the certificate request
so yeah the order is a little bit
different but i don't think there's a
way
to do that with tls 1.2 right now the
draft says
there's no way to implement
privacy of the extension with tls 1.2 so
i think there were some folks
recommending that you know this may be a
new uh application or a greenfield
application and maybe we should only
support tls 1.3
but in the end i think we decided that
there may be
a
kind of a deployed field of clients that
use tls 1.2 and we would have to
support 1.2
as well
that is honest again um
but it could still be useful then to
send uh use the fluxes then flex
extension in in the client hello of
tls1.3 to indicate uh the support
um of this specific extension so that
when the server sends this later on in
exchange the client is not suddenly
surprised and see stuff that it's not
supposed to
sure yeah that's fair it could send an
empty uh extension in in the client
hello uh just to signal that it plans to
use it uh
sure i mean if the support for doing
that uh we could enhance the draft
okay thank you
um
so yeah that's uh all i needed to do
here to decide in this slide so yeah
thank you we can move on to the next one
um so
a bit of uh context i know the this is
what this was kind of what i had to say
about the implementation i would just
now speak about the
uh
use case that we have
so uh
next slide please and i think you can go
to the next one
right now okay
so
in the context of
lower one
we have like devices that are provided
by manufacturer and
to to have like the security between the
device and the application server
uh we're using pressured key so the
manufacturer
inject a key in the device and then
uh
share it with whatever well
actor that is involved uh next slide
please
so this sharing key sharing can be done
in different ways uh
either by using nfc the device is
compatible or just printing back on the
back of the device or send by may
whatever
next slide please
um so
during the device onboarding um
the
device uh so first sorry uh the network
is divided into parts like the radio
frequency space and the iep space
uh and when the device uh want to join a
network uh so it will send a join
request and that will be uh intercepted
by the network servers so the
little cloud uh
on the
uh on the picture
uh
so the network server will then resolve
the address of the join server so we're
using like
uh service discovery to to
know the join server uh associated with
a a device and the joint server will
uh
well say if yes or no the device is
allowed to to join the network and then
using the pre-shared key
uh we uh
we will establish uh encrypted uh
session between the device and the
application server
so
on our use case uh we will not be
focusing on the radio frequency space
and we'll see that in a moment but just
on the ib space next slide please
so yeah
uh the
if you if you want if we wanted like to
achieve uh
end-to-end security so
including the radio frequency space uh
using like uh asymmetric key or
certificate architecture we would not be
able to do that due to the very uh
constrained network uh
that we are having on the radio
frequency space
uh
as of right now uh a compressed
certificate will be like
146 bytes and
the size of the packets the maximum size
of packet is like
52 bytes um
yes
um
there's a common misconception but when
people refer to some radio technology is
that they
look at the mdu at the specific layer uh
and then say it's x bytes and then if
you the perception is if you want to
send something larger it's not possible
of course it's possible uh because it
just used fragmentation
um
sure this is a fair point uh
in number one we have a very very uh
slow emission rate so it's like one
message in a few seconds or minutes so
if we were to use fragmentation here it
will just take a very long time so
that's why we rather not want to do
fragmentation here
next slide please
so uh because of the constraint uh
or on the radio frequency space we'll
just like be focusing on the ip space
right now and
uh maybe if we have in the future or a
better way to encode certificate or not
or just public keys or on very
constrained
well packet size will uh do end-to-end
encryption from the device to the
application server using public key
right now we'll stick to uh pre-shot key
and only focus on the uh
ip space for mutual authentication here
so uh the ib space is a
we have like different uh kind of
servers so i speak about the networks
that are joined server application
server those are servers that uh can be
managed
by different stakeholders so
at some point we want to add some trust
in that and we're doing that using
mutual authentication and a
private pki
uh next slide
so the issue that we have like with a
common like uh
pka i like the web pair is that
we don't have like us to see a bundle
available in all uh
for the server to to use directly and
even if we had that available well
using uh as a
certificate that is like signed by a
common ca have some cost and even the
the free solution like let's encrypt
have some uh issue because we have like
constraint on the name that uh is not
allowed by let's entry basically we want
to do names with like i don't know
16 or 20 labels then let's encrypt
doesn't allow that
so we resulted in the pki
so but this means that we have like to
distribute the root certificate to every
entities and that is friction next slide
please
so this is like our
architecture or
right now like we have like a root ca
that is distributed intermediate c that
are assigning
a
certificate for each entity then and on
the bottom of the slide you have like
the
[Music]
dns configuration because as i said
we're using uh service discovery based
on the device so on the uh joining us uh
zone you have like
one record per uh device uh that is
either pointing to directly at the
address of the joint server or
a cname to the address of the joint
server
and the net ids is a similar zone for
network server so
this was just
mentioned uh because i wanted to
highlight the fact that we already have
the need
for a dns uh
well zone having
one and try per device and
network server
uh next time please
so uh because we have already
uh one
entrepreneur uh device and network
server we
it doesn't really have a lot of friction
to add a second one for the tlsa record
so
this is uh
i think it's important because it
doesn't have any more friction like if
we didn't have this zone it would mean
that we had to manage the zone
but we're already managing it so that
doesn't really matter
so now with
uh dane
we're just like uh
[Music]
doing the ultimate mutual authentication
so the network server will
send the
client id or the
dane client id
using the tls extension
and we have like the tlsa record on the
net
network server zone and on the same
the other side we have like the joint
server having a telescope recall on the
joint service area
and we are basing on trust that every uh
record all right this was my last night
anyway so
every uh
record is into the same zone so uh if we
trust every record in this zone we will
uh keep like the trust that we needed at
the first um
so yeah
that that's it
questions or comments
whatever
the dls protocol does it run between the
network server and the join server or
between whom or between the network
server and the application server
uh it is between the network server and
the join server okay um
well right now the implementation that
we use is using a single uh
server for both the join server and the
application server but ultimately it is
really between the join server and the
network server
we didn't
expand it now to other
well communication
so for example like network server to
network server uh and so on
and but
so the the net um
in
if i recall uh laravan's sort of
architecture correctly was it not that
the network server and the churn server
actually belong to the same domain uh
like the admin same administrative
domain or
um
yes they could um
but we we still have like uh if we are
doing warming or so we still have like
different uh stakeholders
and even if they are in the same domain
uh well yes especially if we're doing
running if everything is in the same
domain we don't have any much but i
think the roaming part is something i i
read through the specifications last
year but my understanding was that they
made an update to the specifications to
support roaming but then there were some
other entities involved that you didn't
show and i don't know where that
specification actually went to whether
that's actually common these days or
whether that's um they abandoned uh that
effort
maybe where's why just from from a
for the sake of uh sort of having the
the scenario and the entities properly
lined up
um
yeah
i couldn't really say a lot a lot of
things are on the roaming part i know
how well we implemented it and
i'm not sure uh
how is the state of the implement of the
specification right now okay sorry i
think it would be interesting to have
the dane client
on on a iot device because in some sense
um
there's very little about iod in this
scenario uh because you're not running
it like it's essentially running in the
on the network side between two servers
uh and it would be nice to have it uh
the link client on an iot device because
that's where the constraints would
uh show up that's where you would see
some of the
maybe interactions with some low power
networks or whatever uh that could be
interesting yeah ultimately that's what
we want to do uh okay yeah not uh we
don't have that and maybe the go client
wouldn't be of much use there either
unfortunately
else with questions
yeah i can go can you hear me
yeah
uh yeah so uh
thank you for doing the implementation
of the drafts um
i was already planning to extend my
library to support looking up a
generalized tlsa record name to support
this so thanks for beating me to it
um
and
one more question i had um does the go
tls library still support no hooks or
api to implement extensions i see you
had to fork the entire go tls library
which seems a little heavyweight but i
assume that's probably the reason is
that right
yes the gold library that doesn't really
allow for
much
like extension or also so i i i just had
to to fork it
it is not like ideal and i i know it but
uh i didn't really really have another
way to do that
okay got it yeah so i i guess it might
be worth
chatting with the go folks to see if
they are planning to implement a
generalized api to
for for people to be able to write new
extensions rather than having to fork
the whole thing so um
that might be something worth looking
into
because i know openssl and other
libraries
do have apis to create extensions
but thank you
eventually it'll all be in the base and
nobody will have to extend it at all
right uh that's true
we might get there too
hi stannis um
like from my experience it's unavoidable
to incorporate uh the functionality of
the extensions into the core
because um the extensions
often require
changes internal to the dls stack so i
don't so if
i guess you will have no other route
than
sort of contributing your extension back
into the the core and you would have to
do the same for empathy ls for wolf ssl
and for
open ssl for that matter
but they are
all these uh folks are
welcoming extensions in general they're
very open for contributions
okay yeah that's a good point so i think
with openssl in the past i've been able
to implement the functionality of an
extension just using their api to create
a new extension and they have callbacks
for the tls verification side on the
server where you can add functionality
so
but you're right in the general case you
may have to
uh modify the cuts in the library
yeah for all the verification i am also
using like callbacks for um
in the go uh
implementation it's just that the
extension itself
couldn't be implemented like otherwise
gotcha thanks
with that i don't see any more questions
uh thank you very much for both the
implementation and the discussion based
on it um fascinating work awesome to see
it uh implemented so so quickly
uh it's thank you
for good progress so thanks very much
all right next up in the agenda is only
with a
discussion about the architecture
document um or any of the authors that
want to talk about it
i believe you are
[Music]
there you are yep fire away
i don't think we have slides for this so
we will
i'll put the agenda back up
do not hear you yet
your microphone was on but no actual
audio
trying again still don't hear you
[Music]
no luck so far
uh he's he's enjoying the audio a couple
of times but
it's not actually transmitting audio
somehow
i don't know if it's a device selection
problem or
joey joey's right you could leave me
echo and come back and try again but it
could be a device configuration in the
upper right hand corner
permissions
yes always could be permissions
we'll give a minute i think we have time
but um otherwise we can switch and go on
to schumann with the solutions documents
all right why don't we do that um so
will you continue playing um
why don't we switch to schumann and you
can talk about the solutions documents
in the meantime
uh schumann go ahead
you need to raise your hand
do you want to share the slides and
control them or do you want me to uh
actually
would you mind doing that
of course not last time i tried i messed
up and was
well a minute ago i actually left the
room by accident so you know
all right you should be good to go
okay all right so um this
is just an update on the status of the
protocol documents
uh as you know i've presented these
drafts in detail at a number of earlier
meetings so i'm not planning to go
through
the entire protocol uh this time so this
will be quite brief
even though i see i've been given 40
minutes for this
um and you might recall also that these
documents have existed for quite a
number of years
long before
the dance working group was even engaged
so next slide
and as you may have seen on the mailing
list and
what wes mentioned these two documents
were formally adopted
and just yesterday i renamed them with
the working group
document titles and pushed out the dash
zero zero versions of each of them
and they are the uh dane tls client
authentication
document and the pls extension for
conveying
a client stain identity
uh next slide please
and uh there was really only one change
that was made since the last revision
and that was to the tls dane client
identity draft
so
previously the draft said that the tls
server may
optionally send an empty extension to
signal the support of this mechanism
but
it turns out after some
reading of the spec that doesn't
actually work with tls 1.3 the client is
only allowed to send the extension in
its certificate message if it has seen
the corresponding extension in the
certificate request message from the tls
server side so it can't really be
optional
on the server side so
the text in the draft
has been modified to
[Music]
fix to address this
so
folks if you could please
give a careful read and make sure we got
all the
language right in in the draft on this
point that would be appreciated
next slide
okay and here's the
specific citation from rfc 8446 tls 1.3
about that which says extensions and the
significant message
from the client must correspond to
extensions in the certificate request
message from this order
next slide
here's a quick updated protocol
annotation diagram with the relevant
information highlighted in red it's just
the thing on the right hand side the
dane find any extension in the
certificate
message that's no longer optional until
that's one thing
next slide
uh okay so there was one uh other
comment on the list during the adoption
call uh about the content of the draft
specifically and that was from michael
richardson who says
that
uh the introduction is weak in the
client authentication draft
so uh that was kind of intentionally
intentional this is mainly a protocol
specification document and didn't go
into
a great deal
amount of detail about application use
cases specifically
but i think i do agree with michael's
later comment that integration
of this draft with the treatment of that
latter subject about
use cases in the architecture document
will likely address that
uh
but you know if there's additional text
that anyone feels should go into the
protocol specifications document uh you
know please bring it up and we can we
can discuss and decide what to do about
that
and uh yeah i'd be happy to fix the
capitalization of iot to conform to the
existing and ones in that space
uh
and the next slide
to sum things up we think the protocol
documents are largely done
and we're looking for feedback about
anything that's missing from them or
needs to be clarified or expanded
uh
as you just saw one issue already come
up came up earlier today from the
conversation with uh hannes and kyle
about
whether even in tls 1.3 we should send
an mp extension in the client hello
message so
i guess we should have a
chat about that and decide uh if that
should go into the document that
actually was
one of the uh
i'm reminded one of the original
rationales for
existence of the client id draft
and that came from a discussion actually
with um many years ago with with victor
duchovny
to deal with the use case in the smtp
transport security community where
you couldn't actually
um
uh prompt on the server side you
couldn't prompt the client for a
certificate message
a client certificate unilaterally
because there were lots of broken
uh tls stacks in use by uh in the smtp
client arena where they would get
confused by that so the server would
need an explicit indication from the
client that it wanted to do dain
authentication and only then
would the server actually uh prompt the
client for a certificate right i mean
that's dealing with
uh broken behavior so i wasn't a big fan
of that but that was one of the
one of the reasons well one of the
original rationales for the client id
extension so
you know down the road other reasons
came up such as you know surgically
picking out
a client identity from a certificate or
supporting
tlsa uh
with raw public key authentication
uh
anyway um
and uh so i do think the plan work on
the architecture document may inform
other things that need to be added to
the draft but i don't know what those
might be at the moment and the same goes
for implementation experience and i
think we've already had a little bit of
discussion about that today
and
with that uh i think i'll stop so i have
some filler slide at the end for people
who aren't familiar with the entire
uh uh protocol uh they can go through
that but i'm not planning to talk about
that today unless
discussion points arise so i'll stop
here
yeah i would say that the the audience
in the room probably already has seen
them so
most of them but
anybody have questions or comments for
the the documents i appreciate everybody
having read them again and being willing
to work on them i appreciate that
greatly
anybody have
things they want to discuss or bring up
certainly the must versus shoulds are a
good thing for everybody to make sure
are
right that's always often a contentious
point
than that schumann it looks like you're
good
all right and supposedly ollie has fixed
his microphone issues so
uh you want to come back
i hope so can you hear me yes there we
go all right awesome
fantastic
uh so you don't have slides so you just
uh want to chat about where we are with
respect to the document it's uh
from a chair's point of view it's grown
uh greatly and you know it's it's neat
to see so many use cases spelled out in
it but go ahead
[Music]
uh yeah i apologize for my lack of
powerpoint skills this week but uh i had
to jump in uh
unexpectedly
uh the architecture document as it is is
a collection of thoughts ideas and
a lot of empty
pointers
as a working group we should properly
take that and sort it out
i forwarded to the mailing list this
morning i understand if people haven't
followed up on
everything on mail today
but we had an earlier discussion
in november about the structure of
documents
and based on that i think we need to
include the dancing rules in the
architecture document that means
helping people that write implementation
documents
like i
potentially could do for sip or webrtc
and others
another topic is iot
on considerations and requirements for
those documents
and that means that the iot usage that
is pretty detailed in today's
architecture document should probably
move out to an implementation document
but because of changes in the
employment i believe
the current editor
has limited capability to do that so i
should properly
try to find other people to work with or
take a first
stab at it myself to reorganize the
architecture document but
as schumann pointed out we need a
architecture document to go
in line with the rest of our documents
that's pretty much all i have to say to
say
yeah thank you for bringing that up i
want one
point is um ashes unfortunately has had
to move away from his role in
editing these documents and there is
sort of a replacement author kind of
stepping in as well but
um
if you know it would be beneficial if
the author teams wish it would be
beneficial to find additional editors to
help push these forward especially the
architecture document is fairly large
please do reach out to the chairs and we
can
negotiate whether whether more help is
needed i suspect that
the architecture document is you know
fairly large in particular
harness is running to the mic
um
yeah
i had participated in earlier
discussions but then sort of like got
lost in other activities and so um
just help me to provide a little bit of
get a little bit of context so the
architecture document is that still an
individual document is that's the one
you're referring to or is are we talking
about something else here
yeah it's not currently a working group
document it's an individual document
with a couple of authors yes
okay and like
so i hear you've got i'm saying
essentially you want to
sort of cut that architecture into
pieces and and have a sort of like
classical architecture document but then
implement there's guidance document for
uh individual areas uh
like iot sip and you mentioned other
things is that is that yeah
that that was what we discussed in
november
saying that the architecture document
which was really the document we had at
the both
uh should be slimmed down to more
classical as you say architecture
document but also include
rules and requirements for implementers
that want to write documents for
the various other areas like iot
like sip or other things yes
point of order from
what we agreed to during the charting to
chartering discussion was
uh we would start with the two existing
solution documents and we would add an
architecture document to help lay out
the framework
and
that additional protocols and things
like that would be you know subject to
rechartering at some point in the future
after we got stuff done so
you're absolutely right there's a
contention between how much you know
individual protocols can be put into the
architecture document i think defining
the use case examples is a safe way to
do that right you could you could
include pieces in the architecture
document for this is how we expect it to
be used but we're not defining it now
not normal text so
i'm curious what it makes you like when
whether you want to adopt an
architecture document as a working group
item to actually then
make some progress on this rather than
having it linguish around in a working
group as an individual document uh for a
while
um
you had all this i remember we had these
discussions um during the chartering
process and there was an iot use case
which was pretty fancy and and uh
um i'm hoping to see some of that sort
of being
sort of picked up somewhere and
showcased and so on
or like hackathon wise and then
described also in some architecture
document i think that would be pretty
cool
but i understand like obviously like the
eap use case and other use case which
are more
like
nuances of uh the architecture
and uh
yeah i don't i don't know so so the
reason
uh one of the other things that came out
of the chartering discussion was to push
especially the solutions forward without
letting them languish behind so that's
actually the reason i did the call for
adoption for them first they were really
ready to go if the architecture document
if people feel that it is ready to be
adopted uh we will certainly call a call
for adoption and i would let um only in
the the authors actually you know uh
discuss or dictate when that might be
when a good time to to do that might be
i know jim is um
asking in chat as well why hasn't it
been adopted uh last i checked there
were still sections that weren't um uh
fully fleshed out
yeah
so uh we probably need to take a stab at
cleaning up a bit um
before for that but uh i i can come up
with a proposal on that
for discussion
uh there is also some technical issues
but i'm i'm sure we can solve that
quickly that i think
ash is the one with the commit rights on
the github ripple but
that's
things that are easy to solve
yeah that's that's a management issue
all right uh barry you have a comment no
this is barry liba i always question why
we often seem to think that documents
have to be substantially ready before
they're adopted
um the working group is going to be
working on the document if we're going
to do an architecture document and we
have a framework for it even an outline
we should just adopt it and call it a
working group product and start working
on it
right right so let me ask a different
question is there any objection to doing
a i will call for a call for adoption
anybody actually think it would be a bad
idea to adopt it as is or ollie are you
okay with it if we issue it now
absolutely
i'm okay all right there's a lot of
agreements and plus ones and in chat so
um joey and i will
probably start but
we probably need to bring up what
we agreed on on on the mailing list
there as well
but
you know barry's 100 right
it does not need to be finished it just
needs to be the point where the working
group thinks that the the rough layout
outline is very put is is in good shape
and
uh last i looked at it i think it is so
excellent i think we will
issue that next week then
great
okay
anything else from you
nope nope okay
um that actually brings us to the end of
the agenda as i said um you know i was
debating when i was selecting a room
we've always filled two hours before
with discussion
uh and we did not this time so i think
you know next time unless we think that
there's a lot more content we'll
probably shoot for a one hour slot to
leave these uh larger slots open uh for
for more discussion
um so do keep that in mind and i think
uh next time i will default to one hour
unless uh people you know feel like we
have a lot more uh based on discussions
on the mailing list and stuff as well so
um anybody have
anything for open mic or um other
solutions that you want to discuss with
respect to
dance related technologies
okay i don't see anybody dancing to the
microphone so i think with that we will
close very very early and call it good
thank you everybody for coming and good
progress today and
we will issue a call for adoption
uh shortly and send a note to the
mailing list
thank you paul for helping out in the
room
thank you tim very much for taking notes
i've been following them along
thank you everybody
upstairs
you