okay uh with that i believe we are at
our start time
i know uh
yeah i believe we are at our start time
so
we're gonna get started
welcome to
debt net working group at ietf 113 we
are hybrid we have a few people in the
room and at least a couple of speakers
who are there and then most of us are
actually remote
that includes myself my co-chair janos
farkas and our secretary ethan grossman
ethan we appreciate you staying up late
or getting up early as you're in
california uh luis is our in-room
coordinator he's volunteered to help us
out luis thank you so much
for the help
as we are at the ietf we are governed by
certain um
processes and policies that are covered
um through our note uh
through various bcps rfcs
and if you're unfamiliar with them we
suggest you go
look them up
but it governs all contributions made in
the ietf whether it's in this meeting
on the list in a document or even
hallway conversations
similarly we have
um a code of conduct that uh
there are guidelines
that basically say we should always
treat each other professionally and
treat each other with courtesy and
respect
um
so we are hybrid there is a
on-site tool
it allows you to advance the slides as
well as enter the queue
if you
use that that would be most helpful
if you don't luis will ask you to help
manage the uh
the balance between the online and the
in in-room queue
and
i think people are pretty good about
working on online nowadays since we've
been doing it so long
we're using
meat echo for the cupid we've talked
about that but we're also using it for
blue sheets
we think it's important to sign in it's
automatic if you're remote please do so
if you're in the room
and
for uh note taking we're using
our usual
shared
note-taking facility in this case it's
now hedgedock we've been through the
third iteration please join us on that
on that link and
help contribute it would be very
we really appreciate it and it's also uh
very beneficial to make sure your
comments are accurately uh captured
we have two sessions um
we have the first session the one we're
in is just for our working group we have
a joint session with pals and mpls
and that is on thursday
oh well we have a pretty packed agenda
so we're going to try to keep to the
schedule
there's been a couple of updates
including who is presenting
um you know what's really interesting uh
janos i just uploaded a version but this
is the old version so somehow uh meat
echo uh
didn't pick up the latest version so the
um if you go to the uh um our
uh
the
either any of the online agendas you'll
see that's uh scott mansfield is going
to be presenting on the second slot and
also we corrected the name there's one
other correction that's not shown on the
slides that is going to be come up in a
minute and i'll talk to that
um
this slide is complete uh i don't know
what happened to this it's um
complete garbage
let's see if
all
that's so strange
so i believe this was um
status and talking about documents that
are moving through
i'll have to pull that up separately and
remember what else is here
the
this is just a reminder about
our disclosure process that we stop and
start before each
step in our process and do polls and
those polls gate moving forward
and
we're all familiar with working online
now but we want this is just a reminder
that we can host virtual interims if uh
participants would like all that takes
is a message to the chairs and we can
set something up
okay charter update this is a really uh
important conversation
we've been talking for a number of
meetings about
bringing in
potentially new traffic treatments
including and notably queuing on list
we've also um someone raised the point
about uh
we want to allow for scheduling we agree
that there are different types of of
traffic treatments
our suggestion to address the the list
comment which is not reflected here but
is on the online version
is um to add a
uh the clause for example
um between the word including and
forwarding and
so that this list is not prescriptive
and
so to allow for um
any other um
changes in treatment
um
uh
the
do we have our a.d
in the room
john are you here
billy
hi john
um
oh for some reason i thought you were
going to be in person maybe i just was
confused or you changed your plans i
changed my plan yeah sorry i thought i
had told you
i'm sure you did and i just missed it um
uh
and by the way i was right there with
you because i was originally planning to
go also
um so um
what we want to do is add the words for
example here between including and
forwarding and we just want to make sure
you don't have any objection to that
uh no objection at all
great i think it's it's it anyway but it
makes it clear i think that's just fine
yeah and the comment on the list and
you'll see that this is already on the
list that the someone was saying that
they want to talk about scheduling
versus queuing and and and there's a
fairly fine
dif difference there that i think most
people would miss and rather than
getting into that exhaustive list we
thought that making it exactly an
example would uh uh would be the best
way to address it so glad to hear you do
not have any objections we do have
someone in queue
robin
hello
can you hear me
yeah you're a little low but i i can
hear you okay
okay i'll try okay in fact i have a
doubt because i know that the tsn and
the dead knight may share in this the
someday secure mechanism
i'm not sure this
if we do this work in the that night so
i'm not sure if this work will
synchronize with the ieee and the tsa or
not
yeah um
so
i i the way i view it is that it would
be a alternate queuing mechanism we
always can use different subnet layer
technologies that bring in their own
queuing
um i i think
in there's the sort of in theory and in
practice
um
in
uh
in theory
we want to coordinate with other sdos
and the technologies that they're
defining and make sure that we're
compatible with them in practice we need
to look at the specifics of a proposal
in order to
address the specific question
in terms of working with tsn we see
nothing changing in terms of how we work
with dsm
okay okay
sure
uh any other questions comments
all right well thank you on on this
point and uh john i believe is going to
bring us to the iesg immediately
following this meeting and then we'll
run that process
and uh for the last slide
a and a good thing we're running ahead
is we've updated our milestones based on
where we stand in the working group we
haven't updated them in quite some time
so we thought it was good to do that
some of the
changes are pretty obvious
related to
oam
and our existing control plane work the
uh some are related to what we've just
been talking about in terms of expanding
the scope
and we've talked about rather than uh
call it out as queuing or scheduling we
just talk about data plate enhancements
and we've put in some straw man dates
here
for when we start um
adopting documents and um submitting to
the isg keeping in mind that we are
always contribution driven
so that uh you know in order to make
these dates we really need contributions
from the working group
um
the
requirements date we chose because we
think we have a a a reasonable document
um or
i shouldn't say reasonable a more
consolidated document based on the
discussions that we've had
and so we think we suspect we're pretty
close there we're going to be talking
about that today
we left a little more time on
the
um it solutions because we feel that in
changing the charter today we want to
give some time for different solution
documents to be um submitted and
to come into the working group and then
be discussed
so we wanted to give a little more time
on the solutions than on
the requirements document
um
and i think that's those are all the
points we wanted to um
we wanted to cover
uh ben
hi uh thank you thank you
uh i i
uh on this page i have two questions the
first one is i see the the for the ipo
document is actually it's updated and is
based on the mps oam document so um i'm
not sure that why and this this document
is first submitted between a bit before
the other oem documents or is there any
uh solution is not
not quite
decided to be the one
should be
submitted and the second one uh is the
clarification question um because we are
not quite yet sure about the enhanced
uh what what it has to mean in the
in the force to
to yeah from the four to two from the
fourth to the last um
um lines about these uh about the the
enhanced uh that uh then that data
playing requirements
so uh i'd like to first
have the discussion on these two um
understood
points and then
uh if it is possible and then submit it
to iesgb4
before we have the consensus on this
list
thank you
okay on the first point it's pretty easy
i believe that should have just said
first the oam document so that's a good
catch we were not trying to be specific
as to which which it was
uh so i think that's a simple mistake
um
certainly a necessary correction um
i did not quite follow
your
question or comment on the last four i
don't yanosh did you catch it do you
want to respond or do should we ask
the statement
maybe i can repeat my question the
question is i don't quite uh
follow the mailing of the enhanced
yeah that
specification of this uh this word
so we've been having discussions about
large scale requirements and then some
proposed queuing mechanisms those have
been going on for a little while in the
working group and we kept coming back to
a question of whether or not
uh changing um
defining queuing
uh belonged in this working group or a
different working group and um
and we've um in discussions with our id
aad with the transport area there was
agreement that this was something we
could do inside the routing area and
inside our working group
and so the require we have a
requirements uh need to define what
we're going to do that's the
requirements and then we
have room for defining one or more
solutions and that's the solution
document so that's what's meant here by
enhanced data plane now if there's other
enhancements that are needed
that's also uh within our um
within our charter um some of those have
been clearly youth in the charter others
have been sort of implicitly
and
rather than be specific at our
milestones we are
using we're using the class that the
term enhanced
net data plane
does that help
yeah thank you uh much clearer thank you
okay great
and as i mentioned we're going to be
talking about the requirements document
on the event it's on the agenda and
there's one solution document also on
the agenda
uh kwon
do you want to say something you're
muted
uh maybe we'll move to torlas
um thank you
so
that that looks to me as if there would
be only
one document for each of these areas is
that kind of because i don't think we
necessarily did the same thing right
with different
ip and mpls data plane documents so
can can you try to clarify that for me
um we certainly expect one requirements
document
for a solution this says first
solution it doesn't say last solution it
doesn't say only solution
right well because yeah i mean we can
see if
if if one requirement document
makes sense or if that
would also be multiple by mean of you
know
different type of
type of networks or use case
requirements right so i mean one one is
always good but i'm not sure if if
that's the the only way to do it okay
uh if we
um get you know as i said earlier we're
contribution driven
so if we have documents that look like
they don't make sense to be merged then
certainly
we can do more than one
at this time we're not seeing that
so
we do have a requirements document on
the
agenda if you think that there are other
use cases that are needed um or not
covered perhaps bring it up then
um and because then we can have it in
the context of that specific document
and you know talking specifics is always
better than talking abstract no no i
mean the the requirement document that
i'm on i understand what it's good for
and that we need it i wouldn't claim
that it necessarily covers all the
possible areas where that net might be
of interest so
that's uh why why i think for the
requirements there might be multiple
ones and i think also as a general note
right this is a mature working group
it's incremental work and so then the
question whether we do this type of
shall i say
three gpp style system level documents
as opposed to individual technical
contributions is then a process question
okay thank you
all right do we have uh
any other comments questions on this
if not we're going to move on
and maybe
maybe if you don't mind just there was
that broken slide
just
in one sentence we have two documents
for which publication requested
you can check it
and there is a newly adopted document
the defeat of by mpls over udpip
and the oem framework document is not on
agenda but you will hear the details
and sorry about this library
all right thank you for that um scott i
have loaded you up
if you want to present your screen you
need to select request
um
yeah there you go
right thank you
so
is
it i'm clicking grant screen and it's
not giving to you maybe i have to
are you sharing or am i
uh well i was
i have a screen request
you have to you have to stop sharing the
screen first i think
if you are
i'm not
someone is
somebody is i don't have control
oh because that's not what i'm sharing
so let's just
no i see the controls down at the bottom
i will cancel my request and just
use this and what i will do
well what i will do is i am pasting into
the chat window all of the links that i
were going to talk about anyway so first
off
thanks everyone this is scott mansfield
i'm representing
um erickson normally in this capacity i
am the ietf's itu-t liaison coordinator
so i said it in the middle between
communications that go between the ietf
and the itu-t and in this case one thing
if you check the chat window
i wanted to point out that there has
been some liaison activity going on it's
also what's seen in the agenda
we received a liaison from the itu-t
question 6 in study group 13 back in
july of last year
we considered it and replied to it in
i don't know november or something you
can check the check the liaison
and then
the uh so i've been having some
conversations with the rapper tours of
q6
and there was just a q6
meeting
last week or two
and so the uh chair the rapid tour is if
you i go flip to the next slot oh i can
flip to the next slide i don't need to
tell you that
um the rapid tours uh graciously created
a
short slide deck that provides the
status of what it is that that q613 has
been working on
and a pointer to how to participate and
when their next meetings are so i know i
have like eight minutes left so i'm not
going to get into the details of these
slides i
wanted to provide a
just a snapshot of where the q6 work now
has landed
post the liaison responses that we've
had if there's more that the ietf wants
to say you know let me know and i can
say it back if there's more that q6 13
wants to say to the ietf
i also attend those meetings and we can
discuss it from that angle as well so
the uh
the two uh rapid tours uh tasting from
uh etri is the one that put these slides
together i really appreciate the uh the
effort that he's put into this to
provide a nice communication mechanism
for those that don't know the work i'm
not reading this whole slide the thing
that you need to understand is what is
uh
study group 13 the itu-t is arranged in
study group study group 13 is the one on
next generation
work
and q6 in particular is
about uh qos
so quality of service and quality of
experience related to
networks resource control
large-scale networks even how qos and
qoe are going to be applied to uh
quantum key distribution networks so
this is kind of the space that they're
in i put in the chat i put a pointer to
the full
terms of reference and a summary of what
q6 is doing for those that are
interested
the
the one of the fundamental documents
that's driving the work moving forward
in question six the itu-t just had a
major reorganization or a major meeting
that sets the plan for the next two
years
so without going into too much detail
there i wanted to provide some
information about what
what we see the itu-t
and in this regard question uh six of
study group 13 is going to be working on
and they created a
supplement to the
itu recommendation series and a
supplement is an informational document
so this is work that was completed as
part of a study basically in in terms
that
most would understand it was a study and
a report has been created and this is a
supplement providing the information
particular to compact capabilities and
performance related to applications that
the study group 13 thinks will be
important in the year 2030 so
this provides some
details on how they're looking at terms
like uh later and later
latency and uh jitter i had too much
caffeine my jitter is too high right now
so the
uh so that's the basic so and i put a
pointer to that document as well in the
chat window if you wanted to see that
and then so
some of the buzzwords here that need
that you need to understand so that we
understand where the dividing line
between itu-t and ietf work lies
is
the itu-t it likes to use the term
large-scale networks entered into domain
networks and so looking at
use cases frameworks and architectures
that support
uh latency time synchronization with or
without time synchronization in
large-scale networks so they're looking
at it from the top down
where you know the ietf well i don't
have to tell you what the ietf looks at
everybody in this room knows what the
ietf looks at it and how it looks at it
from the bottom up
so this is a document that i did not
provide a pointer to but it's easy to
find the the numbers there and it's a
published document that provides some
more of the terminology that's the basis
of what's going on so
they talk about um
without time so yeah just just more like
i say i'm not going into the technical
detail i only have a couple minutes i
wanted to provide this so that if you
have questions about the the terminology
used how the documents are progressed
what documents are that are the most uh
relevant
and um the most current then you can
contact me or tasing and we can uh open
a conversation
so uh
documents that you see in this uh format
so if it's like a y dot a number that's
kind of like an rfc
if it's y dot something like this
this is work in progress and so there is
now documents related to functional
architecture breakdown related to the
terminology uh talked about in
y.3113
and so this document and this is one of
the documents i believe we received and
have sent comments back
and then there is uh lsn large-scale
networks
and this is a jitter guarantee
so this is a document about
well i mean i need to
re-say what it says so it talks about
the the math and the uh gives the
information and definitions on on how
they're talking about buffering
in um in this document
related to how you deal with it across a
large scale network
and then there's qos so you'll notice
requirements and frameworks so a lot of
requirements frameworks use cases
architectures those are the things that
are being discussed in in this
in this group
and then so um here's another document
that's qos um uh requirements on
large-scale telecommunication networks
uh this is a key word well you can't
highlight so uh imt 2020 networks and
beyond is the terminology that the itu-t
is using until the itu-r comes up with
what they're going to call
5g
or you know beyond 5g so this is that's
what that means
and then
uh so uh so yet another picture that
shows the uh general view of the
deterministic network so the large-scale
deterministic network framework and
provides some pointers to the
terminology that's being used user side
network site and multi-domain
so one of the things that i've found
being a liaison officer for as long as i
have is that it's it's important for
both organizations to understand the
terminology that they're using to make
sure that they're talking about the same
things and then so this is an example of
a use case document that's talking about
particular industrial ethernet use cases
and and how
and how the
work will move forward so
and this is yet another detail but
another dive deeper into the document
that describes the figures a little more
and provides pointers to the
information about how the
problem has been decomposed
and then so uh this is a slide that will
obviously take a lot this there's a lot
packed into this slide and this is
something that i encourage the
people on both the the ietf people and
also the the itu-t people that are
working on these documents to look at
the entire
space the entire
standards area that's working on
problems related to deterministic
network uh networking
quality of service
and this is a local area so local area
network so this one is directly related
to things that would happen that that
net would care about and also the ieee
802.1 tsn group so looking for where are
their gaps are there gaps in protocol is
it just a way of looking at it is it a
use case problem is it a framework
architecture problem
and so i encourage people to to look at
these to make sure that the right
questions are being asked
and then the last slide and i'm looking
at the elapsed time and i'm i'm still on
time so good so there are meetings these
are meetings that if you want to come
you don't have to be a member of the
itu-t to come to these if you're an
invited expert
so
you can contact me contact the chairs
contact the itu-t
what's called the tsb that's their
steering group if you're interested in
participating in in these we can find a
way to get you an account so that you
can log into these meetings and
and provide your opinion another way is
contact me for a liaison so
i will leave it there open for i see no
one in the queue but i will stop talking
now and let
the chairs do their job here thank you
very much for your time and i appreciate
the
time thanks
scott
magically i now have ability to share
again so whatever you did give you back
control thank you
okay
we are moving on uh shusang
can't hear me well well
yes and hopefully you have the buttons
across the bottom
uh
yes uh but could you help me to
present the slide if it
is
uh sure hold on one moment
i'll
maybe take control back
i can see the slide
you want me to advance for you is that
correct
uh yes
please thank you
sure
thank you
uh hi this is jose and i will give a
brief introduction about the status of
the nether controller plan framework
presenting other others next slide
please uh
i see slide 2
yes
that's it
this slide provides the background and
purpose of this document
uh this document then add controller
plan is first uh
the
is uh the the concept of data controller
plan is first firstly define the erc
8655 which is the combination of control
plan management plan and in a data plan
framework document
there are also some introductions about
the requirements and specifications for
the net controller plan and also in
different data data plan documents
there are some
controller plan requirements for example
for the mps data plan documents it
mentions that there are some
requirements for label distribution and
label management in controller plan and
this document is intended to give a
clear framework for the whole picture of
then at the controller plan which could
compile all the net controller plan
requirements in one place and also give
an overview of control architecture
which hopefully could give guidance for
the following work about the control
plan and management plan
next slide please
here is the overview of what have been
defined in this document
in section one we we have an
introduction and in section two
uh we listed the primary requirements
for dynamic controller plan
which align with the the definition of
rfc
uh section three and section four are
both about then and the control plan uh
in the nf3 there are three types of data
control plan architecture
the first one is a fully distributed
control plan
using dynamic signaling protocols
and the second is fully centralized sdn
like
control plan and we also define a habit
control plan which contains both
distributed protocols and centralized
controlling
in section four
then at control plan considerations are
specified in detail
respectively for different decnet
mechanisms that have already been
defined in den and architecture
including
explicit paths
resource reservation and
pruf support
also different data plan solutions are
considered for example
nps ip and also segment routing
in section 5 it is still
very brave
it gives a management plan overview
which mainly includes some brief
introduction
about
static provisioning for example yamado
and also some brief introduction about
data that net oem
next slide please
ah pascal is in cube do you want to ask
now or after the presentation pascal
i'm okay
can you hear me okay
yes yes i can hear you
yes it's it's about the controller plane
and control plane or
for that mechanisms
at fro we are
defining
uh
functions in the architecture which
which require some control of plane
activity and there was this discussion
whether
um this should be part of the raw
architecture or not and and a strong
uh tendency to think just like the
bat-net architecture that this belongs
to the controller plane and not to the
row or the deadman architecture and so
my question is like
would you like to include some raw
consideration as part of the death net
architecture control plate architecture
or should we also have a role control of
plane architecture
actually in my mind i mean if you could
put some raw configuration there we
would be understand
i think in the architecture document the
the
specifications for these functions are
not so detailed especially
in the aspect of controller plan and
this document may provide some
explanations and a more detailed
understanding about what could be done
in controller plan for these functions
so it i think it can be um
a detailed version of the explanation if
i understand this right but if um
working group have some other
yes please
yeah i think pascal if you have
something specific you'd like to propose
uh
do so um and then we can
[Music]
judge if it belongs in this document or
a raw specific document oh okay so i
i'll i'll post something on the mailing
list then
and and you lou you you know exactly
what i'm talking about right it's it's
all this actually i don't know i mean i
know what's in the raw document i'm not
sure exactly what you're thinking here
so you know having having that
proposed words would be really helpful
uh thank you okay carlos thank you
yeah this is kind of generous you see
three i just wanted to echo what pascal
said i think that is
very relevant to have that kind of
consideration i don't really care where
but i i think it will be important to
agree
where this work may be
or who it's gonna take that work either
that net or i mean with a specific
document but i think that that is a very
useful piece of information that we need
to add
thanks
oh yes just
oh sorry
now it was too early please respond
carlos can you go ahead we can't hear
you if you're speaking no sorry i i
think there was a collision i was a i
was getting too fast to the mic i think
she wanted to
to respond first
oh it's okay just uh
just as lou has mentioned it will be
very helpful if you could put the
contribution or detailed
suggestion in the mailing list and
i think this document if it is possible
we could include these
different
mechanisms considerations
right um tallest eckerd future way um
i think in bangkok there was a a quick
overview also about some of the tsn
protocols for their controller plane
which i forgot the name of because
they're always crazy names um but that
that that is a i think a very nice
hybrid uh one that allows you to put the
central controller in or not
um and it makes it much more flexible so
i think would be great to add a
reference to that i think some of the
co-authors should be aware of that i
didn't see that in in in the list of
reference technologies thanks
uh you mean qcc
the ieee our document
yeah the the actual ieee document i was
browsing through the references and i i
couldn't find that
okay
i will
okay good suggestion i can end it in the
in the reference part
uh yes this is the
go ahead please yeah i think the
important part is really to uh to
recognize that in the past we always had
you know
a solution where the operator couldn't
freely choose how much to centralize and
how how much not to right he either had
to buy into the full distributed rsvp or
the whole sdn controller and that's not
the case in the teas architecture
exactly exactly
um but the g's architecture allows the
the hybrid yeah we really should move on
because we're about out of time and she
has a few more slides to go yeah
yeah thanks
uh i will go really fast
uh here is the update in this version in
the first section we modified the
management plan specification
based on the discussion in the mailing
list basically these descriptions is
coming from rfc
and also in section three we remove some
detailed descript descriptions of
protocol extensions requirements for
example igp and rsvpe and the detailed
example is removed which may depend on
the implementation
and in section 4 we we remove some
description about the streak and lose
path which is also depends on the the
further implementation
option
the next slide please
ah here is some issues may need further
discussion in working group
the first one which has already been
discussed in the main list and
also in some
previous meetings how to deal with the
relationship between this document and
other rfc and working group documents
for example the architecture document
has been mentioned by pascal and also
the data plan framework document and
also some
other working group documents for
example then at oem framework so
suggestions from working group will be
very
helpful in the existing status we will
treat we we would like to treat this
document as an
uh calibrations or explanations of the
existing specifications and if there are
some
solutions has already been defined in
other
work for example young model and om
framework it is virtual and it could be
referred to in this document and
another question is what is the scope of
the net management plan
the orders cannot find a very uh
specific definition yet so
but there are some
descriptions in rc 865 and rc8938
so in our existing uh
understand
the management plan could include the
young as configuration
management and also oem as fault and
monitoring management
if people have different understanding
please also let us know
a next slide please
so what is the next step
um this document uh is
haven't include flow aggregation yet so
we will end the flu aggregation which is
very important a function in that in
section 4
and also we ask more input from working
group is glad to see
there are some comments
in the in our discussion so please
contribute if you think anything could
be ended in this document
okay thank you very much uh for the
update really appreciate the work and
look forward to the contribution from
others on the topic
and we're going to move now to oam uh
greg
europe
we are
um okay
uh hello everyone
and uh
so we'll have presentation on our work
on
oem for
deterministic networks using
with mpos data plane and they will
follow with their ip data plane uh next
slide please
have the controls
ah i have control yes it's uh yeah okay
it's a
fading colors thank you
okay so this is update uh we welcome our
uh co-authors janice and
and
by this meeting we updated
that net ach definition and provided
specifics of
flags filled and related
filled in related uh i am a registry
so
um
that
ach
is now different from
uh where we started with their more like
based on uh pseudo-wire ach
uh it
has a new version number so it will be
uh differentiated easy to differentiate
from the sudower
ach
it includes its own
sequence number channel type
and
also their second long four byte long
word uh carries the node id level flags
and session identifier
any questions
okay now
uh the flags
uh how much uh
have you been coordinating with the
joint work that's going on with um
pals and mpls
um yeah it's a good question so um we
are closely monitoring following and
participating in the discussions
uh of um open design team
the fact that
we are following on the pseudo-wire
architecture where
their control work
or ach are expected to immediately
follow
the bottom of the stack
label
so we are in a different position
so we are in this
sort of a protected space
that uh
enhanced mpls architecture that open
design team is working should not affect
all right thank you i was uh that was
sort of a planted question to see if we
would get any comments from others who
are participating looks like they're
happy so we can move on
yes thank you and
i appreciate this um
opportunity to clarify uh how we
um
how mpl uh that met with mpls uh is
related uh to um work out enhancing mpls
architecture
okay so um
now uh for now their uh
flex field is composed of five bits
filled each
flag filled is one bit long
and uh
for now in this document uh each of them
is unused
and that is reflected in the proposed
ayana registry
that is
requested to create a new deadnet mpls
oem flags registry
and do assignment as
in this
copy of the table
so that's what now in the draft
any specific questions about flags
or the registry
okay thank you
so um
for
next steps uh we always appreciate the
comments welcome suggestions
and uh we are planning to work
on this document and
would probably ask the working group to
consider uh working with last call
before the next meeting
okay comments questions
okay will okay yes thanks
uh hi hello work and thank you for the
presentation i have a question for the
uh for the for the encoding or
encapsulation of this uh
uh
that net oem um format um i i see there
are uh there is a node id and session
session
uh session i id i think i remembered
um
but before we before we set the before
we define this uh encoding of oem
packets and do that we should have a i
have a general uh consensus on the other
on the mac on the oem mechanisms um
because i see there are there is a new
encoding so that's
it it's different from what we have
um
in previous om mechanisms so
i don't know if we should uh first
define
first to discuss the the mechanism how
we use it and then we decide how to
encode it
i think that that is
yes very good question so uh as for
encoding
uh we are not envisioned that
okay we
propose to reuse
uh all the encodings
that are
we are familiar with uh in uh sudower
encapsulation
so
that
there are ipv4 ipv6
channel types for ach and that means
that
that net ach
can be followed immediately by ip
encapsulated oem
uh for example it could be
lspping it could be icmp it could be a
bfd control
message uh in case of lspping and bfd
control message with ap encapsulation
so that they can use um
loopback address
uh whether it's uh 127s slash 8 range
uh or
as prescribed in
5884 for example uh their
range for ipv6 or it can use
non-ip encapsulation of bfd
so then a bfd control message will
follow
for example dach immediately
and then it can use a tld for
identifying their uh
source
uh
does that answer a question
yeah i understand it um
i agree with what you have said but uh
for the for the new uh defined um
like the the session id how we use it uh
actually we don't know this
so oh yeah yes
yeah
actually
that's a very good point and uh we
welcome um suggestions and proposals
uh
we were thinking that
um in this document
we do not go into their
how these fields are used so we just
define them and
their use will be uh defined in a
further documents because for example as
you noticed flags uh yes
we can
define
some flags or all flags
but that might take time so uh
we found that it might be more practical
to define these flags now
and then uh let
um
further documents to define
um and allocate particular flags because
for now that's like uh unused
and uh i can point that it's the
approach that been um
used for example in
uh srh extension header in ipv6 where uh
the srh defined flags
uh in this
base rfc and then now for example uh
their proposal on
oem in
in srv6 defines one of the flag fields
as oem field
okay thank you thank you for the uh for
the reply and uh i think we i i won't i
uh use too much um uh too much too much
time here um to uh to waste for the um
to waste the at the time for the other
presentations but uh let's continue with
the let's continue the discussion on the
mailing list uh i just want to say it's
not quite ready for the
working group last call yeah thank you
of course let's continue the discussion
on melanie west and thank you for your
question
okay so now i'll try to
return some time because this will be
another um short presentation i hope
shorter than a lot of time
okay so um
let's uh recap
what we have proposed for active
ip or deadnet ip oem using that net in
udp
and then i will be
looking at how active oem uh can realize
a deadnet service sub layer
in a deadnet ip environment
so
with their deathnet in udp encapsulation
we
have to map
the active oem flow
with their uh
monitor that net flow
so that to ensure
um their fate sharing and that's it
because in ip
we have to work with their uh several
active oem protocols for example
um it's icmp or it's a bfd or it's a
performance measurement
whether it's a t-ramp or stamp
and they usually use a
udp destination port or transport
encapsulation diff uh that is uh
distinct from the death net flow
any questions
okay now to find
fun part
uh realizing a deadnet service sub layer
for
the detonate flow it uses mpls over udp
and that's well-known and established uh
technique
uh for
that net oem
in this case
it also must use mpls over udp
and then it's naturally is
sharing fate
uh with the detmit flow because
it can use uh the same ip
the same udp and the same mpls
encapsulation and then identify their
active oem just using the ach
and the next slide illustrates that very
nicely
so as you can see
all the transport encapsulation
for deadlift flow
and
active oem
are identical
and
the differentiation only in using
um
that net control word
for the deadline flow or detonate ach
for
active oem
and um your comments suggestions
yes little
so
you know we've talked about this in the
past having a solution that leverages
mpls over ip
is really very straightforward and and
makes a lot of sense
um but we also need a solution that
works when we're not running an mpls
data plane and we have no mpls at all
uh so really needs a solution that works
for
native ip
and um
you know i think that's uh
i i think there's room in this document
or maybe another document to cover that
but it's really important
yes i agree
okay let me bring it a little bit back
here so
we are following uh the data plane
encapsulation
so uh that net in udp
uh
does not realize doesn't um that net uh
service sub layer
so
there's there's um
going back to a hallway conversation you
and i had walking on the streets of
singapore actually
uh the
a net flow or whether it's a a fully
distinguished or an aggregate flow can
operate just at the ip header levels uh
currently we have it you know the six
tuple
and uh we it's important to have a
solution that also works with that
and as i read this
it this doesn't work with any six tuple
flow it only works with udv and that's
yes uh
with six top of four okay it then it
could be udp and udp
no no uh
why not why
why do you have to do encapsulation you
can just do fake sharing with having an
aggregate flow
um
i i suggest uh we talk more about this
offline uh okay
uh you know it'll be on me to give you
that those comments um but i i the point
is i think we have to cover the the full
six tuple uh native ip flow as well in
this document uh and i'm saying that as
contributor
okay thank you
okay uh pascal please
reference but greg if you want to work
together we can effectively uh
see how we can
transport oem information natively in
ipv6 using
basically what we are trying with the
option the that net options in my
presentation a bit later in this meeting
so the idea is uh pretty much like your
other slide can you go back on slides
it's gonna be important can you go back
the other slide when yes exactly
so in this slide we see that the oim is
wrapped up
in this case mpls right it's wrapped up
on the same envelope um as
uh the the
the data and this envelope is actually
a network construct which um
indicates the treatment of of the
packets so npls is really pointing on
the path
and on the treatment
and inside that signaling we signal oem
so basically the goal would be to do the
exact same thing for ip is is have a
network layer construct which signals
the path the treatment and then inside
that thing place one or multiple
application flows and oam so yes
basically realizing this but over ip
without the udp just the two internals
that's very interesting so i'm looking
forward to your presentation thank you
for
the comment
okay um so i think that uh
well we have uh several discussions on
the mailing list from these
presentations and i appreciate your
comments and interest and
yes let's continue work thank you
okay so this presentation is about the
packet ordering function
together with my uh co-post obvious here
stefan ryan farkas and myself
um
do i have control all your message to
the next slide
oh yeah i have you should have control
excellent
sorry okay
uh so
the actual status is version two of this
draft this is describing
uh algorithms which can be used for
packet ordering function in the deafness
service sub-layer so the pocket ordering
function is needed because replication
and elimination
by the characteristics they may result
in out of order packet delivery and that
can be confusing for some time sensitive
applications
uh
version 2 was presented in the last ietf
there were also discussion during the
meeting after that in qatartan and also
on the on the mailing list
and those discussions were about
the
possible delay variation which is caused
by the packet ordering function
uh the conclusion of the discussion was
that in that net we are building
functions uh in order to achieve a given
target a given end-to-end uh
deterministic characteristics
and
they are intending to use uh and define
building blocks in order to achieve this
end-to-end characteristics
uh and uh in version 2 it is already
stated that it is out of scope
how to eliminate the delay variation
caused by the packet ordering the text
already
contains some hints
how to do that you can use for example
digital buffer or a flow regulator like
a shaping function after the
functionality uh but the draft is
focusing
uh exclusively only on the
algorithms which are ensuring the packet
ordering functions so this is why there
was no
update in the draft and this uh
discussion resulted in that if you
intend to
change the delay variation or or
fine-tune the delay variation then you
will need additional functions after the
off
functionality
so the content of the of the drastic
draft is pretty stable uh we have
received many good comments for version
one and they were already included in
version two which is not stable version
from the puff algorithms perspective
uh so therefore we think that uh the
the document is stable enough and we are
looking for having a verb adoption for
for this document
thank you any questions comments
yes thoughtless please
well at least you don't have to stand in
line here the whole time but you need to
click before you go to the microphone
no thanks for the for the work um i
think the
the difficult part that that hasn't been
approached now is that uh
all this what what i would love to see
ultimately is i guess a
normative standard yang document
that exposes the parameters of whatever
puff is being done
so that when we go into deployments the
the yang model gives us the
knowledge that that we can actually
build a controller plane that has the
necessary information and obviously
um such such a young model would have to
be built from
what we're describing here more
informationally and i'm not sure what
the processes we're doing and if we even
agree on that goal to to getting a
normative yang model to to expose all
the relevant parameters
i think it would be interesting to have
such a young model not only for the puff
but for all the other service sub layer
and forwarding sub layer functions as
well
so i think that that is definitely
something that is that is needed i i
agree with that from from this document
perspective we have defined the
configuration parameters
which
are
uh configured for the both algorithms
described in this document so the
parameters are defined
and for the young model i think we are
missing not only for both but for other
functions as well uh extension to the to
the young model that we already have for
for that
yeah and and and hopefully you know a
young model as difficult as yang is to
just
i mean it still seems to be the
the best way for us to standardize the
data model is you know i mean that i
guess uh
yeah um
yeah there there's some some yeah
thank you i think we're running out of
time
yeah i'll just remind you both we're
contribution driven so a uh a draft that
augments our existing yang model model
or even a completely independent one if
appropriate is always welcome
pascal
and me the
presentation for the slides
oh i think i have them okay okay very
neat many thanks look um so yeah the
this is basically a continuation of the
discussion we just had uh on greg's
slide about being able to transport
multiple types of flow using a network
construct that is independent of the
application construct so the application
constructs read the circuit is is
expressed by the five six tuples it
retells you what the application flow is
and that's what the architecture says
on the other hand if we want to be able
to transport multiple objects including
oam and aggregated flows
it might be ideal just like we did for
mpls to have a network construct that
expresses what the network should be
doing for this collection of packets
regardless of the flows or of the oem
data being transported
and effectively ipv6 uh provide that
sort of constructs uh it's done through
extension headers like the hub by hub
uh the destination uh information object
and and the source routing editor so
depending on what you really want to do
i mean one or the other of those
extension letters is ideal
for instance in in the art of
ripple and now for vtn
ids that was discussed at six months
this morning
the hub by hub header is being used
to
express a uh a logical topology
i see that craig is speaking already
greg do you want me to finish this slide
and then you you speak or do you want to
speak now
i want to be first in the queue
okay
okay okay so just let me do this slide
and and then uh i'll point to you so
basically i was saying that um the
concept of expressing a a logical
topology uh using a hub by hop header as
already some history at the atf and
there is effectively uh for virtual
transport network for instance a draft
which is work document at xman which
encodes the vtl id
into uh hobby hop header in the same
fashion repo as the ripple option which
is also encoded in hub by hub header to
express what we call an instance which
is also a virtual topology so if we
consider that a path
which is a complex beast between a an
ingress and negras
is
is a topology is a logical topology it
just makes sense to do what the others
do um and and express it as a hobby
repeater in particular because we want
that every node on the path is as the
forwarding stab layer operation so it
makes for sense to encode it in half by
operator the cool thing about
operator is that it's completely
uh near the it's the first thing after
the ipv6 header so if you if you need a
other implementation
um and that cannot go you know beyond
say 64 or 128 bytes then having the robe
up header immediately after the ipv6
header allows you to process it in
hardware
so that's pretty important for
forwarding now for for the service sub
layer
not every hub necessarily processes it
it's only the relays
so
another way of encoding that that could
be substitutable
is uh using srh which uh
source rotator basically which indicates
what the relays are
and the destination option
that
provides the service supplier
information just before the srh and that
actually uh how it's going to be
processed by the intermediate hubs which
are signaling the srh so basically all
we're saying is
instead of of looking at the application
signaling which is the five double one
which can be far far in the packet it
might make a lot more sense to to wrap
the things we want to process the same
way which share a common fade
in a layer 3 signaling
and and the extension editor are fine
for that
and greg there we go
greg
yeah now it's off okay unmuted uh thank
you for this um
presentation for the uh
putting it uh so clearly together uh
i've been following discussion in six
men on a uh hub by hop uh
extension header
so my understanding is that yes there is
a requirement or i would say probably
expectation
that
each node will decide on its own whether
it can uh capable of processing
a
received hub by hub extension header
at line rate
and if it's not then it will just
forward it so as a result or as i
understand it
the processing of
how by hub extension header is not
guaranteed
unless we
tighten our
unless we tighten our requirements for
the domain for the nodes that are in the
main in encapsulations
so that we can ensure
that in that net ip uh domain with ipv6
data plane
uh the processing of uh
that net top by hub extension or
hubba hub headers that used
uh by that net is guaranteed
yeah i mean that's the
most of the prime you're talking about
is because
the ipv6 by hop document
is for the global internet
um as soon as you you're in a local
domain uh which is by charter.net
uh this prime goes away i mean if you
want to deploy that net you will
have to have that net support on every
router and you will deploy routers which
support whatever signaling you place in
for that net so the point is not the
capability of the routers because for
limited domain you will effectively have
the right routers whether it's over udp
or if it's uh
right after the ipv6 header
but you might have trouble
uh implementing it on other
much and silicon
if the the
that net signaling is beyond the first
64 bytes
and that will be a prime because
if if you are above udp basically
for some harder platforms whereas
placing it in the hub by half gives you
much better guarantee that you can find
more routers which are capable of
processing it
so yes the biop is not guaranteed but
that's in the internet at large in your
limited domain yes you will deploy the
routers which support whatever you want
to do
and hop by up is actually easier than
above your dp
yes uh what
i think that and that
uh probably will discuss it on the
mainland list and uh
in following discussions is uh the
impact or interworking with there are
this mechanism and other extension
headers for example uh srh
okay so uh i will skip the next slide it
pretty much shows that you know the uh
extension the hub by heart is right
after the ipv6 header whereas the
transport can be far far away depending
on how many other idles you have which
which can be a prime in some ip networks
where the hardware cannot go too deep
inside the packet
um so the requirements are twofold uh
we've got all the redundancy in the
service tab layer and we've got what i
was talking about the envelope of your
multiple uh application flows plus oam
and so that's that's why we have two
different types of options proposed in
the document
three tests of time i'm moving on
so
um
yeah that
we insist in the draft and i guess the
raw architectural system that as well
not to to to confuse what we call the
water and what we call the pipe
the water is the application flows and
and there is signaling for that which is
really under the control of the
application in the network we don't
control uh the tagging of uh
uh
of the ports and and the upper layer
protocol that signal the application
flow so using them inside the network is
actually um
sometimes complicated whereas having
like mpls our own
tag in the packets which we can use to
to to find our state and our operation
is a lot easier so so that's really a
reason why we we want to place it in a
hub by a hub as opposed to leveraging
the five double the other problem with
the five tuple is you would need a five
to four inside the five topol if you
want to merge oam and other and the
application flows here we are a lot more
economical because we just place
a tag which which basically indicates
the virtual topology that you want to
follow
and yes um current version is seven so
we we added effectively to to greg's
point
uh some text
uh regarding the various encapsulation
and the placement of the headers so greg
if you look at the new text and the
submission by fan and fun joined as
co-author
um and then we we in section in
seven we
uh enrich the application section
so we position better versus the debt
and architecture which shows it's a good
fit and it's time to stop but basically
many thanks to alice and brian for the
comments and uh we'll publish very soon
the new version which incorporates that
and i'm pretty much done if we have any
question
oh and thanks for cheering us we don't
really have time unfortunately for
questions
uh i think this is really interesting
work um we do have room in our charter
for
uh more
enhanced or uh actually not even more
enhanced this was just a more
sophisticated uh
data plane ip data plane support we
always called the original five tuple
the simplified approach so
this this certainly fits in
whether or not you use hop by hop or
maybe even flow id i know that's not uh
uh that's being frowned upon but uh it
it would be good to talk over with
influence
when you say it flower you mean
yeah the problem with flow labor and
and five topo it's it's the end point
decision so it's for one flow for the
next flow that wants to fair shade to to
surface well i don't know
share the same fate you have a pride of
signaling uh we should leave the
endpoint application level stuff to the
end points and and do our own construct
for the network just like mpls does it
makes a lot more sense
sure but it would be good to socialize
the uh the idea also in sixth man um oh
yes oh yeah oh yeah and the vtn id is
being socialized and this morning i
asked a question effectively on that
because we are doing the same thing in
role in in
well you know what he is right that's
great
we should move on pascal we should move
on
uh thank you very much appreciate it
and for the next presenter i think
you're squeezed down to eight minutes
and
uh okay
i'm handing you slide control now
okay okay
this is panel from china mobile and it
is a requirement of lightsaber
vietnamese network exercise please
okay another size uh you have control on
the bottom you should be able to select
just underneath the slide okay okay yeah
i'll say it that's it yeah
um
okay uh first is the recap but i can't
see it clearly
yeah i can't either um
uh
yeah i guess i'm trying to is there any
problem
yes but but like i could actually say
um the cap and motivation it was
presented first in the interim without a
draft but absorbed some good points from
the earlier draft
and since there was a positive feedback
we submit and presented a new draft
based on the slides last meeting and
before this meeting we merged another
requirement draft according to chess
suggestion and addressed the comments in
the
last meeting and offline so the
motivation of the document is to point
out different aspects in large skills
and mystical network such as
magnesium and also has
a little others
okay
oh good
and
some facts are that the domestic network
prototypes and the trials have been
performed
based on the the pro pro predatory
mechanisms in logistical network and the
experience from them will use that as
the input to this document
next time
i control it by myself so forget it
and uh from the last meeting got some
comments and those uh
uh other updates uh we merged another
requirement draft had two technical
requirements show the internet two
slides and the ad an
example of
in electric mix and
telecommunic
communications research into and move to
the example of the trial to appendix for
reference based on the contribution
added
tolerance chain and jingdom
has cursors and also removes these two
based on the
comments
so this is the first to added
requirements support configuration of
multiple queuing mechanisms um there
will be the level uh
servers fight
determines the traffic flow for what is
based on different mechanism in some
network device of flight square network
and for instance the network aggregation
device may need to support both
ts and ats so the network device shows
the ports multiple
parameters and the coding is unified or
simplified configuration and management
i expected to be support
so for the distributed and centralized
scenarios
some
simple requirements
for the advertising or some resource
topological when needed
and
this is the
second added requirement uh is to
support current mechanisms which over
cross multi-domains um
it may cross multi-domains and
adopt a
variety of different mechanisms within
instrument so it is required to support
the interdependent mechanisms at inter
domain boundary nodes such as
a priority but redefinition and
rescheduling of cues
moreover changing from the one queuing
mechanism to another may generate
additional end-to-end latency or data so
a collaboration mechanisms of course
multidimensions must be considered
such as
the increasing
buffer or interdependent device to
provide
enough adjustment
space for the flow to across different
magnets
and
this is the appendix about the trials um
here's a new
remote industrial internet of
things
service
of
eti and data through three different
operators network and demonstrates the
real-time
with a smart factory
and the low latency and from the jitter
showed here
so some thicker way is that strong
motivations and demand on the
enhancements about life skill than that
and
the pro
battery uh mechanisms coexist with uh
thunder technology in trials
so there might be some enhancement to
support it
and then
here is the overall technique
requirements
and first a thoroughly time
uh synchronization
um
considering the in the large-scale
network there might be some device comes
about the
synchronization and the second one is
supports the large-scale
single-hook propagation latency
brings
long-distance latency to support it and
the third one is accommodates a higher
inner speed and
force is key over to numerous network
devices and massive traffic flows
and the fifth tolerant figures of links
or notes and topology changes because
those will bring
maybe second levels
latency
additionally yes and six and seven was
introduced before so
next is that um
considering the recharger
of the wg we extract some potential data
plan
uh implications from the requirements
the first is a uh ipv6 extend header
based enhancement to supports the native
app basic network
and currently there is no change of the
extension headers
and the second is the array don't say
related files for the
free off then ps data plan uh suppose
while the native ipv6 data plan doesn't
have the files okay third one is for the
aggregation
um
flow identification
the ipv6 aggregate flow identification
is supposed by five or six
turbo ib uh prefix or wheel cards
it is a local window that works more but
in english skills the number of
individual flow charts that may randomly
join and leave the
uh aggregated flow
um so in some cases
the flow can't be identified by the
predictor with the cards
finally is some conclusion about the
queue related information to be
considered such as cycle specification
or the time
step or time information
like fields so
next is since they dropped up absorbed
the earlier draft merge another
requirement dropped and got enough
discussion the notification and online
offline would like to request for an
adoption call as a start point
for the enhanced requirements document
thanks and any comments
unfortunately we don't have time for
more discussion um so others it would be
good to
uh
if you have comments take it to the list
i'm particularly interested in if we're
missing requirements
uh
you know we showed on the milestones
that we would like to
get a document to
on enhanced data plane uh this seems to
be the one that is the likely candidate
uh so we'd like to see some more
discussion and probably poll
uh
for adoption as soon as next month
um so thank you very much for this uh
contribution
okay thank you
next up i believe
is
uh twirlis
oops i hit the wrong one
uh twereless you're in the room do you
want someone else to advance for you
where do you have the
the app i'll give it to
maybe
luis if you don't mind advancing right
this the sound is so echoey it's really
hard to understand uh next slide
or first light sorry i
need to manage this probably
yes
all right so uh
wanted to
re-summarize um
the high level what we're trying to
achieve here next slide
um
so we think we need according to the you
know previous presentation a uh
standardized bounded latency solution
for large-scale high-speed networks um
and if we look at what we you know are
kind of under the hood thinking of being
available today that has been proven i
think we have um the guaranteed services
from rsc 2212 and tsn ats as the two
mechanisms that i think people who have
worked in tsn
no we don't have the yang models um
there is a proposal for rspdp for that
but if we look at both of these queuing
mechanisms they really have three
core
issues right so one is the insufficiency
for applications because of the fact
that they have the maximum
jitter
because it's load dependent
and that may lead to a lot more
complicated applications with clock
synchronization on small iot end
endpoints as opposed to only in the
network
the second one is the um
an expensive scalability because of the
per hop state required in service
provider networks
and
then of course kind of like as a
follow-up the non-applicability
to um
current and future uh forwarding planes
that can operate stateless like sr mpls
srv6 and for multicast beer or other
similar upcoming ones so those are the
three big limitations of these uh
well-known um queuing mechanism next
slide
so and then there is tsn cyclic queuing
and forwarding which is another um tsn
proven standardized solution and that
solves problem one and two
but it doesn't really work for high
speed or wide area networks because the
cycles
on adjacent nodes need to be matched by
the synchronized clock so that means
that they don't support arbitrary length
with the latency and jitter and require
an extremely high clock accuracy linear
to the speed of the network so so far to
the best of my knowledge that has been
proven to only
work up to 10 gigabit per second so that
brings us to the uh wrong indented tech
cycling and queuing forwarding that
we're proposing which is really an
enhanced version of the cyclic and
queuing from tsn um and it solves that
high speed when link issues by carrying
the cycle identity type identifier not
just internally in the node and updated
by the clock but it's in the packet and
that basically makes it easy to support
arbitrary latency links even with jitter
and there are high-speed implementations
as proof-of-concept pre-standard um
obviously uh with uh equal to or larger
than 100 gigabit interfaces and deployed
for testing in a 2 000 mile long network
in china
next slide
so
we we talked about this
on the last
session it's also in the draft it kind
of explains how the more cycles you
configure into the solution the more
leniency you have against
latency variation or time interval areas
in your clock synchronization protocol
so basically uh it's it's also flexible
in so far is that it can
um you know by mean of configuration of
more than three cycles uh accommodate
for more uh variances next slide
so right so
the draft that we have um was the
attempt to try to
get two things out of it right so one is
to propose a standard tcqf mechanism
with the per-hop state machinery that
could support any type of tagging
even you know different hubs along the
network could use different tagging like
one uses ip the other mpls not that
that's realistic in current networks
and then really only standardize here
the one
tagging that we know we can do without
expanding any forwarding plane but just
using the one forwarding plane we
already have
almost everything else which is the mpls
forwarding plane with the traffic
class field which just relies on rfc
and that's the easiest to operationalize
uh thing and this is what we this is the
draft we want to
ask.net to adopt as a working group
draft um next slide
and so then obviously there is the
question of what's the adjacent work
right so obviously we want the yang
model to specify the configurability
there is the open question of
the ingress policing into the network
which i think is a general purpose issue
in the case of this queuing it's not
only the policing but there is a tagging
with the appropriate cycle
added to it as an edit requirement but i
think it could go either into this
document as a as a section that hasn't
been written yet or it could be a
separate document and then of course we
could equally then once we agree in that
net that this is
a scheduling queuing mechanism that we
do want to support i think much more
easily code to other working groups
accordingly um right the tagging for
others one like dscp probably with tsvwg
and then of course the whole question of
how do we do it with srv6 where we may
want to have a source routing header
that per hop
indicates the the tag something i think
where even an old and draft existed
right but to me that's adjacent work
just bring it up to the point here that
it is relevant to you know the adoption
call for for for this draft which we
would like to have
and i think that's it next slide i think
that yep thank you very much
uh thank you trois for this work as we
mentioned we're going to give some time
for
other solutions to
be proposed before considering adoption
probably around the next ietf is when
we'll
look to do
adoption of
solutions for
treatment enhancements
but of course any anything that you know
people would like to see improved on the
document right as as early as possible
do you do you hear me
uh yes torellis was just making a
comment if you could let him just finish
his comment and then and then go tour
list do you want to make her finish your
comment i know that that was is right so
thanks
okay thanks uh go ahead
okay uh thank you
my question is not
only for dollars but all but also for
chairs and do do we plan to adopt one
data plane solution for a qm mechanism
or
uh it or it may be better to define uh
try to define a generic data plane
solution to cover all kinds of uh cream
mechanisms
um because the this this draft has
mentioned
ipv6 nps and srv6 for the tcqf
and we maybe we have other
queueing mechanisms then we will have
many uh display solutions
so if
my answer to that would be that i would
hope that the debt networking group has
space for
multiple you know bounded latency
queuing or scheduling mechanism as we
want to call them i was just thinking
that this one would be the
one that would be most easy to justify
as a standardizing first because we've
got the deployment experience it's
derived from something that has even
more deployment experience with psn so i
mean we have nice research work for
something that we you know think might
long term be even better but where you
know high-speed hardware implementation
experience is missing so and it may be
the same would be a problem probably
true for for other cool ideas that are
being brought to that net so maybe we
should look at you know
the realistic uh timeline of adoption in
actual uh high-speed networks as as a
factor to guide us but not uh prohibit
something to happen
yeah and quan
i think you're actually getting at the
point that there's a difference between
queuing and marking
and
um
the
uh
the data the mark marking tends to be
data plane specific and we would expect
that to be in individual documents the
base queueing mechanism could be in a
shared document or even show up in the
in one document one data plane document
first and then be referenced
um by subsequent ones we do see that
there's um
definitely different data planes were
managing uh and there we uh talked about
this being there being a first document
for a solution and that we may entertain
multiple but as usual as i said multiple
times we're contribution driven so if
you have an alternative um
it'd be really interesting to see
see the uh
contribution on that and there is time
before we talk about adoption on this
one specifically to to
allow for more documents to be published
and with that we really any subsequent
discussion has to go to the list and we
need to move on to the next
presentations where they won't have any
time so let's be fair to them no no
let's be fair to the others please and
uh move on
so i think uh
uh i'm not sure who's presenting next
uh but i'm sorry not that somebody
opened the doors again in the room and i
don't hear you because there is all this
noise coming in from the outside so it's
really ah okay i'm sorry i can't uh
sorry about that
uh so
you should be able to present
we don't hear you
so we're going to skip this presentation
and come back to the person at the end
hopefully they can fix their mic
problems between now and then
my apologies
but we can't hear you
so we're going to
[Music]
the one-way delay measurement
uh high chair can you hear me
uh yes you sound something and you
should have yeah thank you
uh yeah yeah thank you um okay uh next
page please
and from channel
yeah you have controls at the bottom of
your screen
okay thank you very much sorry
so
um today i'm gonna
give a presentation about the
uh my draft on the uh reference
delay-based mechanism
about the along with the delay
measurement so one delay marine is very
important and uh
is a great performance indicator for sla
guarantee and especially for some
scenarios in 5g network so owd the one
with that delay environment is not novel
research many
studies have been down in years before
and especially some
offices also been published in ip
performance environment group
but our proposal is quite different and
so it's based on a prerequisite about
the net so
that's why we want to
you know predict this in needs in that
net group
so uh you can see that
the current deployment of the
uh one-way delay measurement
uh
deployment is
always is all usually based on some uh
clock synchronization you can then such
as pdp or gps
but the deployment cost is quite high or
uh if what if you want to do some
approximate measurement you usually use
rdt half of the idt but it's not
accurate
for the uh some
scenarios
so
our proposal
introduces a new method to accurately
mirror end-to-end one-way delay
so without using the clock
synchronization and
it only uses a reference delay based on
the deterministic path inside the
network and
the network latency is quite uh
it's guaranteed and has very low jitter
so
as as you can see in the typical network
topology we
uh deploy uh
uh
between the sender and the receiver we
have a clock offset
we need to first send a reference packet
from the sender to the receiver and then
follow following we we want to measure
the target packet and between the center
and the receiver so there is a clock
offset between the
sender and the receiver
and
you know
for the reference packet uh it is uh
then through uh deterministic path so
that it means that the uh the delay is
uh known before
it's based on the uh that and uh
and the target package is what we want
to marry so we just need to
uh record uh the the
send the send time the reference packet
and target packet and then the
similar and the arrival time and the
timestamp of the uh both the packets
so
uh our calculation method as shown here
is only has
two equations
we can uh we know that
uh the the reference delay uh can be
calculated inside the uh
at the very beginning by uh
at the very beginning and it won't be
changed during the measurement and the
offset
the offset one and offset 2 can be seen
as equal
when we
send the the reference packet and target
passes
uh the the interval is quite short so we
can assume that both off test is the
same so we can use equation one and
equation two to
uh derive to the the third quad equation
where the target uh delay between the
center and the receiver is determined by
the full timestamps i recorded i at the
both end and the delay reference delay
so all of the five values are known
so here that the target delay can be
calculated so
our method uh
here are some measurement procedures i
want to explain it in detail you can see
in my uh draft and the the time stamp
can can be also
encapsulated in normal uh
in normal format
and uh and you can insert it inside that
tcp header and
between the dot and the payload and tcp
header and also
so um
yeah so our uh so i want to sum up with
my proposal so our
mechanism don't has no need to deploy uh
time discrimination so that's the
biggest you know the um
i mean the vented point of our proposal
yeah
so you can largely reduce the deployment
cost of accurate one-way delay
measurement compared to the current or
state-of-the-art environment in canada
so it also has no impact on intermediate
network devices it's only
you you don't need to care about the the
uh intermediate
network path uh just that you need to
know that it you have a deterministic
path uh between the two end and
the target package might not
send through the the deterministic path
it can can be sent through some uh
different path i mean between the sender
and the receiver so you can you
you can use the delay uh i mean
reference delay to uh to calculate the
the measurement path uh and the the
target path so uh
so yeah that's my uh major concern to
propose it in that net
thank you so if you are interested in my
uh i mean my proposal you can
uh
talk to me um yeah yeah one also uh you
are welcome drawing to our work so any
questions i see that some um
some friends are raising their hands in
the queue
so let's try to get very brief
on the questions and the responses and
then continue on the list uh greg thanks
i just want to note that um
clock synchronization uh helps uh with
their uh or mitigate uh their uh
instability of the timers so uh without
clock synchronization
the network of the timers might
fluctuate differently and skew so
it not be a constant
difference between clocks and different
nodes
but it will be floating so that much
more challenging and difficult thank you
thanks
i think in fairness to the others we
have to take the questions on the list
and give them an opportunity to to talk
in the remaining uh 10 minutes if that's
okay
uh
uh to dean and uh dan and uh bing
yang
yeah sure we can talk via chat
chat box or you can
send me emails uh yeah thank you
okay we're going to try again uh if uh
uh shampoo if you could say something
uh he said that his local test passed
but we are still not hearing you
um
hello
yes we hear you excellent
uh
you have five minutes
oh uh so i will have to uh
this representation quickly
we
introduced a specific solution that uh
about
uh basis forwarding next
you have controls at the bottom of your
screen
so the motivations
internet architecture defines
whose goals
we know that our boundary delegate
abundant private law simulation bonded
out of ordinary and use
to resource
resolution explicit diluting and
service protection to achieve these
goals uh resource resolution is the
basis of
insuring bonding delegita and ultimately
depends on the crew mechanism
of the floating plane uh the wide and
use the priority basically scheme making
whether or not it's about with worst
case related thus
enhancement
scheme of before pq is proposed
um
okay
uh this page is about the deadline clues
the total anchors are violent of people
and also
based on our already skilled in it uh
there are several attributes of the
terminal cursor all right now gives how
tdl attributes
staggered from each other decreasing
with the passage of time
and the third night with ddr0 has the
highest priority
heighten the existence jiggled for all
his priorities sub secondly zero will be
reversed to the maximum initial
uh the third with tdlo non-zero has a
normal priority for end time policy and
the proliferation and already for anthem
policy the former can be involved in
skilled in while the later canada and
the figure the following figures a
simple example
of
that code that it contains four delanaku
each we see satellite attributes
zero one two three uh after
the
time of
the passage of time or for example one
microseconds the tdu actually will be
changed
so next
um
okay
so this page is about how to put pages
to the
description is mainly included booster
but the first uh good at the denial
information over the package including
the planned terminal now the planetarium
can be computed uh by under under delay
minus the
accumulated delay violation by one
caused by one absolutely uh this
information came together from a package
itself
second the product package
uh the allowable skills
plus the accumulated denomination minus
the avoiding delay internode then the
property we are putting to
the
cru with ddl attribute
consistent with
one of q
the following
uh figure shows a simple example
so i will go next
so that is
about the traffic location and the
shipping
traffic regulation and ui board to
ensure that the reserve abundance
underwater of service is not exceeded
control and world ingress
traffic shipping
is an
eye port to distribute the package into
the deadline
the following figure shows a
six part from the same deterministic
service are received on the ui problem
assuming that they arrive at the
outgoing port one by one
after internet of delay uh
forwarding delay f each part we under
the queue with ddl one consistent with
a low possible delay of the target at
least current time
so next
uh this page is about the benefits of
this specific solution
please
please please try to wrap up
okay
uh
for the coast time synchronization is
not required because network nodes
operate based on
relative time deployment
a pragmatic collection base is an
enhancement of bigger scheduling
algorithm from the network upgrade each
node can independently set the
authorization time of the deadline crews
based on several port bandwidths support
partial upgrade scalability a single set
of dynamic users support multiple levels
of
residence time performance could data
control just a single authorization okay
so for next hope we welcome any
questions and comments thank you
yeah very interesting work thank you for
bringing it to the working group it'd be
good to see if there's comments on the
list
and we're on the last
presentation
the remainder of the time is yours
okay
uh thank you lou this is specification
for that let's bend in an entity
uh in general it is required to consider
the vantage latency for a past selection
to achieve the net cues
first as per the death net controller
play framework explicit paths should be
calculated and established in control
play to guarantee their deterministic
the deterministic transmission so first
the end to end bend independency
concentrates should be taken into
consideration in past consider
computation and second as per the
atlantic bended lantern sea the end to
end
uh delay bands can be presented as the
sum of a long queueing delay and the
queuing delay
along the path
so the queueing mechanisms and the
parameters should be determined during
past computation so this drug disrupt
described the extensions to precept to
carry bundle latency constraints and
distribute deterministic passes for
end-to-end pass computation
in deadline surface
so we proposed some precept extensions
first uh is the metric object we
proposed two liu
types over metric object first is the
end to end abandonment latency
in the p uh the pc pcc uh indicate uh
carry the end-to-end validity metric uh
to indicate um the end-to-end band in
latency constraint in past computation
their end to end bending jitter is the
same
with their uh
bending their latency and second we also
propose the iosp and extended flag tle
we propose b bit to indicate under a
deterministic pass capability
finally we uh proposed to extend the uh
ero and the srero to distribute the past
computation uh we
proposed the new information structure
uh for example we uh proposed the death
knight sub trv and the cycles of qre for
different uh
viewing mechanisms
so last step uh we
we hope
that later
to uh determine this work could be done
in data or pcwg
comments and suggestions are very
welcome thank you
thank you for this i would suggest
bringing it to pce as well and it's
likely that they're going to ask for
this working group to agree that it's
good work and then
once there's general agreement that by
the working group here that there's
interest in it
we can
coordinate with the pce chairs as to
which working group does the actual work
uh but thank you you know this is uh new
work and it clearly needs to be
discussed by the working group to decide
if it's uh something that the the group
is interested in
uh
so
thank you
um we're we're just now at time so
apologize to those at the end who got
squeezed on time and appreciate you
shortening things up
um
and this takes us uh uh to the end of
the session and uh really look forward
to seeing everyone hopefully in person
uh in philadelphia at the next ietf
uh janos anything else
nothing nothing else
you said all
thank you everybody for the
contributions
absolutely and also thank you luis
for helping us out in the room
you