well these are all the slides the stuff
that's on the data tracker and that's
the ones that we've uploaded for meat
echo
so
bob's thing is on a github repository
it's not in the data tracker right so we
can't pick it up yet
and i think bob was intending not to use
any slice because you only got a couple
of minutes
video test one
that was speaking i heard you
thank you bob that was jim
what have i done wrong
just give us a moment here we're having
trouble with
i've got
i thought i had this right
is coming
do you want to run things
yes
apparently i want to run things
um
good afternoon everyone uh this is the
itf's
drip session
so anyone who is not interested in trip
please
leave the room or stay whatever
jim and me are here as delegates for the
real chairs who
uh attend remotely
um if you get me the next slide
we are trying to learn how to get to the
next slide
can you help me
what's up
daniella med would you mind sharing the
slides
if you know how to do it
um okay so so i think those are james
no
daniel you need to request sharing a
slide
with the document icon
yeah that's what i
[Music]
i said shared preload slides
oh yeah now something's coming up
and the audio level like this is good
enough
daniel you are good but at the desk that
we can't hear
our
um on-site delegate here
do you see my slides
not yet
i'm still seeing this section being
recorded
still says it's jim slides
i think jim has to stop sharing
to let yeah i i i i have to
unshare yours
okay
just heard some key clacking somebody's
coming too good
that's me
hmm
i said something
now back to the sessions recording
slides
daniel you are in charge you should have
another window with the left and right
buttons
so i i clicked on something shared
he asked me i had a window asking me
whether i want to share or not and i
said yes yes
and now somewhere in another window you
have the right and the left arrow
okay jim do it then
nope
i can try
doesn't look good for the away team
all right i have slide control now guys
i believe
yes i think you're under control
hopefully
there we go there we go oh no
okay i'm moving
okay
so
um this is a not well unless you have
never seen it
um so take the time to read it
if you have any questions please come to
to see us or um contact um our ad
next slide
so um
these are the rules for um how we
handle this meeting that's hybrid
meetings so we have in person
participant
and uh
remote participant
um
i
i think that um
we're not that um
numerous um and uh if you have a
question i would say um
you can jump into
into the conversation
um
we are more in a conversation like a
type of meeting next slide
so you have the agenda
mythical and other information
next slide
so where we are
um
so we have
um our first rfc being published
and now we're heavily focused on the
derip architecture
the the last call is just being started
today
or um
i hope it's it's it might be yesterday
for some people
and
we we have um
um
i would say one of the main document the
chord document which is the
err id
that is in working group last school
so next slide
so milestones
um
where
we have a few other documents that we
need to
to focus on um it's not the end of the
road but we're pretty good in that
um i see the registries
we we target to be done by the end of
the year
for the next itf we think uh oauth
oath might be
a good target
um pretty confident about that one
um the error id was for december
2021 but
i mean we're only in march so
it's an itf schedule
next slide
so um
this is the agenda
and i suppose that schway is gonna start
um
has anyone wants to say something uh
before we start the presentation
no so um i suggest that
schwei is presenting the
drip arc
android
i lost control here for a second sorry
uh what slide deck was it for
um
actually there is no there is no slide
for the um
the first two ones this is just
for the i would say for the editors to
report any last minute major issues you
have on the um
and for the read there's only one flight
from from school so if there's nothing
to report from the uh from the ark we
can move to the next one so for bob to
report in here i would say last major
issue on his side
thanks i don't see
any slides for bob in the decks to share
um
and that's that's what that's what i was
saying is that for the first two ones
for the architecture and the red there
is no slides okay just only for first
two it's the last i would say
item so
there is no major issue for the arc a
segment that
can jump in and commend the red draft
and then we can move to uh to see what
for the
for the astm uh update
got it okay
thank you
so i think
yeah did you want me to proceed with
this one
i believe so
okay
so
uh we all know our first rfc has been
published
and then um
at right about the same time as our uh
requirements and terminology were
published
the astm f-38 committee which is the
unmanned aircraft system
operations committee
entered ballot on two uas red documents
one of them is the revision of f 3411-19
which has been the basis of most of our
work
there
was extensive
uh
okay it went away um there was extensive
work um
done on um f-3411
in order to
keep up with the regulatory changes in
both the u.s and in europe uh we didn't
have a lot of
inputs from the rest of the world um
the ballot has since closed
a few days ago and there was only one
negative ballot the way astm works that
one negative ballot must be resolved in
other words either the chair needs to
convince the one who filed that ballot
to
rescind it
or
the
working group needs to find the ballot
non-persuasive
and then a higher level within the astm
needs to agree with that decision that
it was non-persuasive this may take a
while because it's an allegation of
international of intellectual property
conflict of interest fortunately the
means of compliance which is a document
saying how to
satisfy an faa regulation
based upon the technical standard passed
unanimously um the picture in the middle
is just an illustration of the
um flow if you will of requirements uh
from external
down to our
proposed standard drafts
as you know the architecture draft is
just entered iatf last call this mormon
morning
there are some nits there now we wonder
and this is not a question for ietf but
i just want you all to be aware of the
question whether we're also going to
need to come up with a means of
compliance draft to show how our
drip rfc is once published can be used
to address the
things that the astm f-3411 standard
does not address which is primarily how
to dynamically assign session ids ensure
that they are trackable by authorized
parties only back to
the operator and the
serial number of the aircraft
and we had a successful field test last
summer which we're going to do another
one this summer and we're hoping at that
point to check the interoperability of
our prototypes with those of others and
that is all i have thank you
any comments or questions
okay then thanks thank you
any questions
any questions or comments
nobody
okay then thanks we'll move on to the
next item on the agenda
which is implementation
hello everybody can you hear me well
hi andre
perfect okay so this is an update that
we were developing in in shopping
university with students regarding the
implementation of drip
protocols next slide
so this is our reference architecture so
there is like five components
observer with android application up uh
the drone with
raspberry pi and other add-ons like gps
and battery and
when the registry based on eroja
blockchain which keeps track of um
drone data and then there are different
types of users that can request this uh
data from from blockchain so next i will
describe like the progress of different
components
so code is using open heap
implementation of host identity protocol
with different additions
and it's a
part which is open source so
some changes which are coming
because of change both with in
hierarchical hits format we'll need to
address that
and second part is that mostly python
trips to handle this
registration and
look up messages so it's not currently
published but we work to do it
towards end of year
next slide
so the
the drone broadcasts things using stm
format with drip additions based on
extension of drone id and
we experiment with wi-fi uh different
modes as well as bluetooth 4 and
bluetooth 5. we also have like
registry implementation using eroja as i
mentioned
as well as extension of android app to
to do the lookups based for web server
next one
so why
irocan it's a
blockchain that it's permission-based
and it has some nice features so we
actually
did also some simulations to
understand what kind of uh
number of drones it can handle and it's
quite promising so it's like let's say
hundred of drones within uh certain
limited geographical areas is supported
in terms of
transaction times and
processing times and hence
and
next it's also
next slide please it's also supporting
uh some of
all the requirements that specified in
with drip registry draft
so i hope it will be also included as
one option in the future of um revision
of
registries uh rafat adam is
promoting
next
so i'm now going to talk briefly about
our experiments with bluetooth five
quite many devices claim now they
support bluetooth five but it seems like
not all features are actually supported
so for example raspberry pi 4 is not
really supporting it
well enough so we are trying to
experience with
a dongle and development kit rf52
f40 to sort of test the range and other
features
next slide
i have a question
yes
um when you say it does not support um
what is not support exactly um
well as you know there are different
profiles for example long range
bluetooth 5 or low low battery bluetooth
5 so it means like it maybe supports
some limited version of this
okay
um if you don't mind andre i'll expand
on that a little bit basically
a lot of hardware chips will support
bluetooth 5 the spec
is an extension of bluetooth 4 but all
of the extensions for bluetooth 5 are
optional the only one being back port to
bluetooth 4. so you could have a chip
that supports all the new features of
bluetooth 5 but then the firmware
running the chip doesn't and then the
software above that at the os level
doesn't and then the software above that
doesn't so you get this layering problem
of the chip will support all the stuff
but the stuff above it won't
and so you have to find the right match
to do it so for example the only phone
i've found that supports everything we
need for bluetooth 5 is samsung galaxy
s10 or s20 smartphones
right so we were trying to address this
for example by plugging this dongle into
into raspberry pi
4 and but as you said there are some
complications on firmware and driver
level so
we only had limited success with that so
far
next slide
but
yeah we have a script which using
python extensions and when it's
depending on which
communication interface is active and
available it will try to
send wifi bacon mode upload to five or
four and so on
next slide
so for wi-fi um
it works but it's a short range maybe
some
less than 100 meters so we're also
looking at the neighborhood awareness
mode which is getting support in the
recent phones
however
people like bob pointed out that now
wi-fi beacons is a way to go but i'm not
sure what's the level of support
of that and the recent hardware we have
to investigate
next slide and this is the observer
application it's based on uh
open drone id extension as in as you can
see it successfully receives
h
hits from the drones and displays
location as well allows to query
the database where registry based on
user credentials
next slide
and regarding the bluetooth 5 we did
some measurements it's not so easy to
find like
one kilometer open space in sweden so we
actually had to go to the two lake
and uh with this development kit we were
able to reach about one nordic mile
distance which is already much better
than
let's say 100 meters with wi-fi so once
we uh kind of
resolve this compatibility issue we will
new to five in different devices
hopefully it will be good means
next slide
so as you see these are components we
have to combine and put it like add-on
to to let's say a phantom drone so there
is a raspberry pi uh for when there is
battery hat and then where is gps so
all of that should be like mounted on a
drone to actually transmit this
id data
um
well now actually there is model b of uh
raspberry pi 4 so i hope it will have
better
uh bluetooth 5 support so maybe you can
do without a dongle extension
so
simplifies things
next slide
and regarding
openhip it's currently hosted on bit
bucket so you can download the code here
next
so one of the things we were trying to
do is to add the support for open ssl 30
because it's like
latest crypto library which has all the
latest
ciphers and hashes and so on
and the
open hip is
it's historically based on open sl one
zero and then it was extended a little
bit to one one zero but still
like not the latest one
next
so it was kind of challenging because
open
heap uses a lot of
sort of deprecated calls which are now
not supported in ssl three zero anymore
and when when you start changing one
part it sort of
leads to dependencies in the other parts
so it was like basically almost rewrite
of the code because it was like
thousands of warnings and other stuff
next slide
but we kind of finished the
update so the code is compiled
but it's not
well tested yet so we are maybe in
autumn we will work on more um
automatic tests to sort of uh
and packet format tests to make sure
it's
like interoperable and compatible to the
latest air fesis
next
also we were working about
not traversal implementation so you see
this rfc 9028 is relatively fresh from
from
july uh so again we finished basic
implementation but more testing is
needed
um but i'm curious to see your opinion
uh like is it really
helpful for for drip do we need uh to go
like over utp or and use ice or we
assume that we can have like always
direct
hip and ipsec you know in all cases
maybe at least for the
kind of
remote registry access maybe it's useful
next so we still
there is something to do so there is
like data relay server implementation to
do
and
update the core simulator that we used
for these use cases
next please
so what we are also doing is we are
trying to do formal verification um
like i know for example bob likes this
idea that the security protocol should
be formally verified and the
last attempt to do it for hip i think it
was uh
like
10-15 years ago so we are now using more
modern tool and also implement drip
features
and also we are involved in several eu
projects which are
targeting to do big scale demonstrations
like
almost a drone flying taxi or ambulance
so for example there are some
testbeds planned in
norway scavander and in helsinki
so try to put some
prototype and hardware to these drones
to broadcast remote id
and xoro squam is another example that
is also like large-scale demonstration
so we plan to fly a big drone between
two cities in sweden beyond light of
sight so maybe one of first operations
like that and it also would be nice to
to have a drip as part of this thing
and
the final slide please yeah so
this air more is focusing on emergency
medical services
because based on surveys it seems like
it's a kind of
application area that most people will
support adoption of drones even if it's
noise and some other features and
you see there are some chinese models
like
which is already purchased and
being tested and in norway and
they of course
waiting for some authorities permissions
to actually start
flying people in that so it's
ongoing
research and active area in new space in
europe
so that's it on my side if there are any
comments
questions you andre if anyone's got any
questions or comments could you please
put their hand up in the techo chat
and then identify themselves when they
speak also someone's speaking at all
please see who they are for the benefit
of everybody in the room
stuart is taking notes and i'm sure he
recognizes everybody's voice but there
may be other people taking part in the
meeting sorry
stuart
is um
taking notes of this meeting and it
probably recognizes everybody's voice
but other people are in the room here or
on the internet somewhere else might not
recognize who's speaking something by
yourself when you come to the mic thank
you very much
and help first question from daniel
yeah so
i have uh
one question to andrew uh it's a
um
i mean i i don't see the the migration
to open ssr three as a huge
challenge
but i just want to check if i am correct
well in terms of
i mean
yeah i mean it's uh if you have like
legacy code it's like a lot of update
it's uh
almost like rewriting from scratch so
i'm not
sure about other people using hip are
very going to do the operator
okay because that's okay that's not the
rip that's the on the hip
side of it
yes but you need heat right for for
registering yeah yeah sure yeah i forgot
this
okay thanks bob
pointing out as i said in the in the
chat
that
um the value one of the big values of
hip
for the ua
is going to be for network remote id and
command and control um and not being
locked into a single
connection methodology
he has demonstrated this already
in his test over at the
uas site there in fact in his
neighborhood here in griffith
international air force booth
you can do that in previous sessions
so uh uh you may think that this is
orthogonal the the open hip discussion
um but it is going to be important as we
move forward to the next steps than
being able just to well support the
activities
for um
where we go beyond
the basic broadcast messages when we
start moving on to the network remote id
and and support for better support for
command and control
that's it
to clarify
while
command and control itself
uh does not lie strictly within the
scope of the drip working group
recreating
applications
based upon identity does and so that
would include so-called detect and avoid
command and control
vehicle to infrastructure vehicle to
vehicle etc
daniel
andreas presented one implementation
um i guess two in adam as another
implementation
um
did you do some uh interrupt
interoperability test or um
um are we aware of
any other
implementation at that point and uh
um
maybe if if that's possible um adam was
too um
can you just uh let us know
um
uh what you are implementing i mean uh
are you doing the equivalent of uh
androids or is that um
more restrained or more specific
i mean if it's possible i'd like to have
some more detail i would be interested
okay
so this is a free time check here
we are about 10 minutes late right now
so keep it brief please
adam do you want to take this or you
want me to
please go ahead
okay so i'll make it very quick um adam
and others
at the new york uas test site are doing
a tremendous amount of work in
prototyping unfortunately the nature of
our funding is such
that it is a struggle to get any of it
openly released we will continue the
struggle
next up all right
yep thanks i hope everyone can hear me
uh so i'm gonna go over two topics today
i'm gonna go over
authentication formats
and also the registries so i'll start
with authentication formats because
that'll be pretty pretty quick on us
um so changing since 03 the fec section
is now fully filled in it will need
somewhat of an extensive review
uh there were a couple small things that
were changed on uh two of the formats
appendix a was fully filled in with some
diagrams and some text an appendix d was
added
for to do med's comment
um so sir some still some pending issues
as i said fec needs to get reviewed um
i've noticed that with reed solomon
especially in my implementation that you
need a specific polynomial on both sides
for the forward error correction to even
properly work
and i have run into an issue where i've
had colliding polynomials so we might
have to actually specify one in the
draft i'm not sure how to approach this
so i'd like some guidance on that
or we can just work on it as a working
group together
the appendix d was to directly address a
comment from med
hopefully it satisfies his comment along
with a conjunction with appendix a
and then i need to loosen some language
there's some weird language during some
transition where manifest became the
required and thing but it used to be
wrapper
but it seems like both can be used so i
have to just fix some of the wording
around in that to get it
right
uh for next steps on this draft i'm
going to be sending it internally in ax
enterprise to laura welch for an english
language review she's
very good at english
and maybe not so much on the technical
side but she'll be able to read through
the draft
make it readable
to humans that are not technically as
savvy
and help find any major issues um i
actually just got the sector review uh
right before this meeting so i'm gonna
be responding to rich
after this he's given some great
comments
and i believe we're ready for working
group last call although the chairs can
put their own opinion out on it so
anything discussion wise on auth from
anybody otherwise i'll continue straight
into registries
i'm going to take that as nothing so
i'll go right into registries so
this is the registries draft we're on
version one now
from zero zero
so changes from zero zero uh this was a
massive rewrite on my part the first
push was an absolute mess i
hated the document as it was so i took
some time
about a week and a half and really
cleaned it up reorganized it there's
some new sections in the introduction to
get a high level of view of like a story
of a typical life cycle using the
registries in drip
uh there was a whole section of
attestations and certificates that was
moved down into the appendix because
inline it was getting really clunky to
read the document
there was some text added for key
rollover and federation of registries
which i'll touch on a little bit later
and there was an attempt at merging high
level points from the deep section 5
into the section 4 of this document i'm
going to be working more with bob to
make sure that i got all the pieces
needed for that and
massage any text
there
um the big change from this was sections
seven and sections eight of zero zero
were merged into one section section six
so that would got a lot cleaner in
formatting it was more fleshed out
section seven uh in the original
document was extremely technical
and just
very hard to read where section eight
was more of
prose and like a story and how
registration works with the inner
components
they've been melded together in a lot
hopefully an easier way to understand
also epp and rdep sections were added
and
any examples that were shown in the epp
section have been come
have
came out of the ax implementation
so the title of the document is
currently going to change when we go to
o2
and the title will be drip entity tags
registration and lookup and this is
mainly the primary focus of the draft
it's look up in the registration of
deets and other information associated
around the deed
drip is not bound to dns epp or rdap um
i think there might have been a little
bit of a misconception that this was
going to be the only way for it to work
no that wasn't the intention it is
we're going to use dns epp and rdap as a
baseline to get something out the door
standardized and working for deploying
and then also drip is not exactly bound
to the d it's just come up in previous
meetings
there was no there has been no other
solution being put forward but if one
does come later in the registries
um
the registration architecture that we
currently have is strongly tied to the
drip entity tags hid structure the raa
hda split so if someone wants to write
another registry draft either one they
need to mimic the hid in their
identifier or two produce a whole new
registration architecture
using their new um
identifier format and hierarchy
um
and that's a bridge we will go across if
we need to but i tried to make it so
that the document was clear that this
ties with the deet
and if something else comes along
it would be a different draft
so
pending issues um there was a error on
my part when i pushed
i was asked to do a contributor section
i accidentally copied and pasted the
full
acknowledgement section into the
contributors section so scott allenbeck
was pulled into the contributors section
and i didn't realize i had done this so
he has been pulled back out in a uh
running version that's on my side and
he's back as an acknowledgement uh andre
was pulled as a contributor uh speaking
of andre uh i actually
oversighted and lost his text email
um
a couple months ago i found it again so
i have the text again um and i will be
adding it in
uh per andre's uh
presentation a little bit earlier um i
don't know if this is an appendix or if
it's going in line i believe it's an
appendix and that's where i'm going to
put it for now
and then we'll go from there
scott hollenbeck on the mailing list
gave a really great suggestion in
breaking the epp and rdap sections out
into separate documents
i like the suggestion
but i
want to feel the working group out to
see if we want to do such a thing and
add more documents to the listing
um i need to work with bob and i've
already discussed it with him about
pulling text for the ra and hda into
this draft so
hopefully that will happen in the next
couple of weeks and then i'll push o2
out
um so the rest of this time well
actually
bob let's take your question because i
have plenty of time
just uh quickly uh the top moving text
up from rid to registries um just
text from red to auth um we start with
the text and read to get it kind of laid
out and once the uh um where it belongs
started um evolving um we moved the text
so uh um dad and i will
do it
we'll be pulling checks out of red and
moving it where it belongs in registries
um
so everything i think will be cool for
everybody and then then i'll show up in
the my next strap the red 18 draft and
uh and and adam's next draft on
registries
thanks bob
okay so i want to spend the rest of the
15 minutes of this to go over some
registration process stuff
um this is the first time i think this
has been presented to the working group
this has been internal uh to
well basically myself and stu for the
past year um and i'm finally getting the
chance to kind of go a little bit more
in detail to it
just as a recap this is our registry
tree diagram this is how the registries
are laid out in hierarchy we have a
single root registry which takes the
values of 0 and 0 for the rea and the
hda and then there's two branches of the
tree there's a branch on the left that
consists of the irm and the mra
which
is mostly dealing with serial numbers
and then the branch on the right which
deals with other raas mostly under civil
aviation authorities
and they have uh values of
ras greater than two and hda is greater
than one
and then of course an unmanned aircraft
would register with two different
registries in the system one for its
serial number and one for its session id
and then with broadcast rate going to
the observer and then dns and rdap
lookups happening over the internet
we have three major typical registration
operations the serial number
registration of the manufacturer
into the mra and that's usually a d
encoded as an ansi cta 2063-8
serial number and this is documented in
the deep draft that bob has
there's an operator registration at
what is nominally would be considered a
uss but it's actually specifically the
remote id registry
uh portion of drip
and this key indeed would be used by the
operator during session id registration
and then finally session id registration
also at that uss or that remote id
registry and that is a deet proposed to
be used by the ua
during flight for that given flight
so this is a
z diagram it's not perfect there are
some issues with this that i'd like to
fix but to get us started um so this is
serial number registration into the mre
or the manufacturer's registry of
aircraft
basically at the start of time the
manufacturer would build an unmanned
aircraft
they most likely will generate the key
pair and the drip entity tag associated
with that unmanned aircraft
if the unmanned aircraft can't create
the key pair itself
uh and they would propose it to the
manufacturer's registry
using a self-attack station
there's some internal stuff that goes on
extracting the drip entity tag checking
for collisions in both the database and
the dns
um so to make a comment that i've gotten
from stu recently on these slides
there's a reason that dns and database
are different or split apart on this the
database mostly holds a personally
identifiable information or pii
or just other additional information
in this particular scenario
um we would be holding ua information
the ua's weight how many rotors it has
what color is it
um make and model obviously
what type of battery
chemistry it has
and this is so that people can easily
look that stuff up and not have to
scrape web pages
once everything is completed though
during a registration resource records
are added into
dns
private information is added to the
database
the serial number the public key the
the
drip entity tag and any attestations
that are produced are pushed into the
unmanned aircraft
in a secure element hopefully
so this is two examples these are pulled
from the
drip registry draft as it is stands
right now uh on the left is an epp
uh command
uh for
registering a serial number and as you
can see all of the fields here are you
know make model color material those
kinds of things that would end up in
the database and then on the right
is our inputs and our outputs
and also our dns entries what fields of
dns exist or what resource records in
dns exist for a given serial number
now while the serial number is useful
and we can
create a serial number using a deet and
that helps for modules the real
important one for drip is the session id
which is what the deed is acting as it's
acting as a uas
uh session id
so a very similar process happens with a
session id um hopefully the aircraft can
create their own key pair
um in this scenario so basically the
operator would poke the aircraft it
would generate its key pair
send it along with a serial number and
additional information around
back to the operator who x is basically
a middleman between the aircraft and the
registry software
passing it back and forth
we have the same
kinds of checks for collision checking
with the deets and all the varying parts
and once it's done
importantly for this the broadcast
attestation is generated and this is
vital as in drip we require that the
broadcast attestation be sent over the
air uh in the authentication message
this is what the auth draft is all about
and this is where that broadcast
attestation comes from
and this is all handed back to the
unmanned aircraft through the operator
there are other ways to cut this cake um
you know we could have the unmanned
aircraft reach through an lte connection
right to the remote id registry that is
a valid way of doing it this is just one
of
a different many different ways to
do this process
again this is some examples so on the
left
which is not the same as the last slide
these are the dns entries that would be
in
uh the remote id registry along with
what inputs and outputs
were needed
for the registration to occur
and then on the right is the epp is an
example of the epp that is sent
um there is a couple things in the uh
epp that we have not discussed in this
working group and one of the major
things is the operational intent the
operational intent is
basically the utm link back into utm to
get the 4d volume box
if
uh the particip if they are
participating in utm
so some next steps on the registry draft
i want some feedback on the epp examples
that would be absolutely lovely um i
need to produce some rdap examples we
haven't gotten into that yet
uh there as i said before there's i
talked about some federations and key
rollover
it's an interesting topic because we're
going to have to probably federate
registries and with the h hit or the d
acting as its identifier and the last 64
bits being
the hash
it'll be interesting to see how this
works because the hid would be the same
you could have a registry like the root
registry 0 0 but you could produce
2 to the 64 keys and they'll all have
different hashes but it's all
technically the same registry so
i'm curious how this would affect
deployment and use of the system
um i don't have any free cycles to
explore that
topic even on a crypto security level so
if there's any takers for that that be
really interesting and we can add that
text into the draft
and i hope to have an interim uh not
directly after this but maybe a couple
weeks a month from now
as to focus on the z diagrams there the
two z diagrams i showed you are two out
of
uh z diagrams that i have
um
and there i would like to do a deep dive
with the working group and anyone that's
interested
to understand the process and the flow
that we've had in our heads for the past
year and a half on how registries would
work
to get it into the draft a little bit
better
and with that i think i'm ready just to
take some discussion if anyone has
anything to discuss for the first time i
think i am not rushed for time and i
have eight minutes
thank you very much adam and that's a
great job thank
thank you
any questions or comments
going
gone
if i maybe
yep um i've only got one um and this at
the moment this is mostly focused on um
adam's uh registries draft where there's
a question of how much detail to include
on epp and rdap as specific techniques
for implementing the registries
and also to some extent on the
architecture draft i feel like we kind
of have a failure to commit here
to achieve interoperability we need
specifics and abstraction is a fine
thing but getting abstractions right
takes a long time
and the bus is leaving the station
with regard to regulations and
manufacturers building
application specific integrated circuits
and so on so we're really going to have
to come to some decisions rapidly on how
much specific protocol
detail to include in these documents
versus how much to attempt to continue
to remain abstract and then produce
still more documents that will have the
details uh slash ram
welp
the concern about the multiple um hits
per
rari or or hda is being issued that's
actually how how key rollover will be
achieved um
and and how they'll be linked in
registries so that was part of my
original thoughts when i came up with
this idea um it's just that now adam and
i are gonna have to sit down and get
done over the over the next two months
um so that that's uh in there it and
it's as uh students that in an
implementable way
so i'll uh
say this to a little bit to bob but just
as in general so i knew that key role
that that was used for key rollover but
what struck me is interesting was that
we have a root server hda ra0 hda0
and there's only one of them in the
registry tree and obviously having that
sync having it as a single server is a
point of failure
so you would probably want to have
multiple
root servers kind of like how dns works
now
um the problem with that in i think in
our thing is is like if you want to have
an asymmetric key pair
to generate the hit and
dust the deed etc
you would need to have a different key
on every box
so if you had
say seven root servers they're all going
to have different key pairs
how is this managed right because
who
you don't want a
malicious party joining the club just
because they created a key pair you
would want to there needs to be some
sort of control on that and this happens
at every level of the registry tree
and that was where my thought of
federation and interest in the key role
over in the keys came in
but it is a discussion we need to have
overall
okay
no more comments questions
um bob i think you wanted to have a
quick word about the status of the rid
draft but i think that may have been
overtaken by events judging by the
comments um
barely here i got my sound crank cranked
all the way up but um just again on the
slides for the rid that i
have permitted our proposed are out
there i put url again in the chat
um it was also on the list
basically um there's some med has a
couple things he wants me to address um
they are
easy to do work on them next week uh
ayanna says they are going to do a
review of the new ayanna considerations
um i added a lot of text in there so
they may have a lot of comments um but
uh ian and i will work that through
uh but uh x i'm parked for the end of
next week to have dash 18 out
of any comments on what i haven't had 17
please get them to me in the beginning
of the week so i can get them included
thank you
okay
um so i have one more thing to add to
the meeting this is what i get for not
putting it on the slide
um
so this is to answer daniel a little bit
earlier when uh andre had finished his
presentation
uh my intent
if all the stars align and the universe
is nice to me is that in philadelphia at
ietf 114
i would like to do a demonstration of
the ax implementation of uas remote id
and i want to do a full um a full uh
demonstration i'll have an aircraft i'll
have a puck
i will create well i'll have the
software loaded on the puck but i will
perform
serial number registration and session
id registration and fly the aircraft and
pick it up with
the ax uh
android application
so i do intend to have
a implementation
share
also to answer daniel
from earlier uh
ax has worked with another uh partner in
utm that was developing a remote id uh
application
uh and it was not drip specific it was
astm only but our implementation did
work with theirs so we were able they
were able to see our identifier we were
able to see their identifier their
side just kind of made it garbled
garbage on their ui but that was because
they didn't know how to decode it they
just took the raw bytes and just
displayed them
and they were seeing all the pieces
um they just didn't know what to do with
all the pieces
uh as for for with andre uh i would like
to do an
interrupt test with him uh we'll
coordinate that somehow it's kind of
hard to do an interop coordination when
you're on the other side of the world at
times but uh
we
i do intend to work with andre and get
in uh interop
with drip to drip uh maybe 114 is the
answer maybe it isn't i'm not quite sure
but as 114 draws closer we'll have a
better picture on that
okay
okay thanks for the response
has anyone got anything else to say i
guess not
okay this meeting of the dis working
group has closed i would like to thank
the speakers
um and also for doing a fantastic job of
keeping to the time even though i
screwed it up at the start by being
unable to make me tackle work properly
and i'd also like to felt my fellow
delegates to evan for his efforts today
and also to eric for applying me take a
clue whether it was badly needed so
thank you to everybody and hope to see
you all in philly cheers
thank you
yeah
thanks everyone
yeah i'd really just like to say thank
you very much uh jim and stefan
cheers much appreciated sure hope we can
have a beer together in philly
awesome
uh
okay
yes