oh
yes
my apologies
[Music]
connected
all right
good morning good afternoon good evening
yes
it is 12 30 um
i'm slowly going to get started
we have our responsible ide we have
major participants we have my co-chair
excellent uh
right
welcome
to email core at itf 113
from the list of people i can see you
are probably in the right room
this is just a reminder that
you should be familiar with not well
one point specifically is
a reminder to be professional
and just be nice
be respectful even if you're disagreeing
with technical arguments
this is for the list of documents you
should be familiar with
again itf code of conduct
this session is being recorded uh we're
using metacore
uh
we have a note taking
pad
we will need a note taker
which is
i thought that would be great if you can
take the notes um
so yes please um
maybe can i can just covalently you to
fill in blanks unless you are speaking
if that's okay
yes my apologies uh is this better
microphone wise
okay
yes much
sorry i was just mumbling to myself it's
friday it's the last session in the week
uh
i was getting ready for the session the
whole week i'm so over excited and so
over exhausted now so um
um right we have no takers
let's
that's
roughly our agenda
most of the
tickets are on
smtp couple tickets on
applicability statement at the end
and at some point i'll just do a quick
update on
email format
when pete is back in the room
so
i don't think we will be you uh we will
have to use the whole two hours but if
the discussion is productive and we're
making progress
that's fine um
is john
oh
okay
i don't see actually john clanson in in
the room at the moment he said he had
technical issues
yes maria i appreciate that it's 4 30 in
the morning so
um
right uh
so
while we're waiting
for john
i can quickly
i suppose i don't need pete for this
either so um basically email core
has
one ticket outstanding which is about
printable versus visible characters
um i will do a follow up on this i think
there is a valuable proposal that will
work basically suggestion is just to say
instead of
using possibly ambiguous terminology in
various contexts we're just going to say
which are character which is
um effectively the intent of the text
um
pete also has
one outstanding
change related to trace header to which
he agreed a couple of months ago he just
didn't get around to doing this
once he pushes
a new revision
we will be starting working group
colonet
so yeah which hopefully will be exciting
that's the first working group last call
in this working group
alright
with that i would like to start on this
on the main body of the discussion but
it's kind of going to be a bit hard if
john clenson is not here
so let's just give him a few minutes
i hope he is not right uh you know
running windows and it didn't decide to
update to windows 11 or something which
will take a few
hours um
hmm
so i'm actually so uh john levine is
volunteering to discuss his issues i'm
tempted to do the other way maybe we
should start from the end of the
slide deck and talk about
enhanced status codes
okay
right
ken
sorry i
i'm trying to um
yes reorganize agenda a little bit while
we're waiting for john so let's let's
start with your topic
so um
i read the uh the thread in the mailing
list uh two or three times
and uh the summary there is what
i boiled
boiled the issues down to at least my
understanding of it
and came up with this the following
suggested text
i don't think it's worth my while to
read it you can also i'll read it and if
there's any objections to that i am more
than willing to
accept some
uh some text
okay do you want to just give a very
quick sorry i'm just a
quick background so the originally your
document was saying
must support enhanced status codes and
then
um
some sort of implementation said what
does it mean
uh
for us and yeah so yeah there was a bit
of pushback from some implementations
yeah in the original text actually said
you must implement the the spec that was
actually the original registry for the
code so that was that was confusing so
uh this actually says you uh it's
recommended to
implement the
enhanced status code extension
to smtp and then also refers to the list
of codes in the registry
uh
any comments
i mean obviously we still need to double
check this on the mailing list but i
think that's kind of uh
would be nice to see if people think
we're going in the right direction
okay
sounds good to me
so john john clanson you're back
hope uh all right so let's get back to
our regional
right
okay
starting from the beginning of
list of issues uh we have an old ticket
11.
talking about possible clarification
about mail transactions and
transaction state
so john's original note was that section
33 should be
would be improved if it be more specific
about when mail transaction begins and
ends
um and what's part of the transaction um
there was some updates to the document
since the original issue was raised i
had a look at the text in this section
and i quoted the first paragraph of it
which
i think talks exactly about what john
was asking about
so it says me on transaction starts with
mail command
um
followed by one or more rcpt2 uh etc and
finished by data um there is a follow-up
uh paragraph also talking about quit and
our set
so
my suggestion is
it looks like this ticket is closed
john
uh i hope you can hear me
yes
uh i i as as i've looked at this more uh
i i agree with you no no change is
needed
i think a small editorial twitch
uh would probably improve things
slightly
and uh and propose the insertion of uh
uh of the word normal in that first
sentence
uh before smtpm mail transactions
as a slight improvement but uh
this is uh
um
not worth a lot of time
okay sounds good to me uh if you can
propose
[Music]
can you write the proper proposal where
to insert the word on the mailing list
uh i from my standpoint i could i
consider that a small editorial tweak
for which we do not need to have a
discussion but it's up to you
that's fine i'm okay with that
all right so uh tentatively
i will post a message tentatively this
is closed
subject to my editorial tweak which
we'll see in next revision
okay
um now another um
ticket that uh
rose out of our discussion at itf 112
was
iron registration policy for smtp
extensions
basically
the current document says as
rfc 5321 that it's a standard strike an
experimental rfc approved by sg
we have removed
um
x-extensions so they are not prohibited
from being registered now and i think it
will be a good idea to register some of
them which raise the question whether
our iron registration policy is correct
so um
roughly uh on the following slide there
are
two proposals one is specification
required
which is as a quick reminder this is
expert review
plus specification which can be rfc it
doesn't have to be ietf stream rfc
um alternative proposal is first come
first serve
with registration templates requiring
specification
so
i'll show the next flight
slide with the
proposal and we had some discussion on
the mailing list i think
we'll have more discussion now about
alternatives
so
yes let's have a discussion
okay
john do you want to say the first word
yeah
i don't know how many of you have
managed to see the notes i sent to the
list uh not too many hours ago
um but uh i'm a little
a little concerned about clutter here
and uh and vanity activities
and yeah we've got some dead ones but
the dead ones seem to be reasonable at
the time
um i'm uh so what i'm i'm sort of
feeling for and and i'm also concerned
about
the possibility of getting a an
extension proposal in conjunction with
some special application that the uh
that the expert reviewers don't
necessarily understand
um so
i've been feeling around and the
comments on the list summarize some of
it and i've had some separate
conversations with murray
uh about the uh
the possibility of uh
of creating a sort of in between here
where we uh where we don't quite require
the level of
of approval the current text does
uh but we still do it a community last
call
in which uh
uh which which gives people who may have
expertise that the
experts don't and this mailing and this
mailing list doesn't
uh to uh to chime in on the thing if
they see something that others don't
um
uh it's a much lower bar than requiring
standards track
but it's a little bit more than uh
um
than
allowing the my pet rock uh extension
so i think it's sort of like
specification required with extra uh
itf list last call
uh that's one way of looking at it
okay
um
murray
um yeah i i we did talk about that and i
i think
that or what you have described here as
new one are both palatable um we
recently
had a document come through that looked
more like new to where it's first come
first serve but there's some provisions
around that and vcp 26 doesn't really
support the i like it says that ayanna
will basically accept anything that's
well formed if you say first come first
serve
asking them to make a judgment about
whether the reference
describes a particular thing or looks a
particular way is outside of ayanna's
remit so i think new too might be a
harder sell
yeah i tend to agree um
very
can i
volunteer you to try to defend
sorry i i sort of got very not
yeah so i i wrote this this thing here
the i'm okay with either of these
options specification required or
first come first served with a reference
the reason that i proposed maybe we
should do the second one
is that i wanted to really stress that
that we would rather have these
registered than make the bar high to get
the registration specification required
ought to be a very easy level
but changing to that requires that we
appoint an expert for this and go
through that process
when really we'd just rather have people
register everything that they're using
but we do want some sort of reference to
say what what it means
so i'm okay with either one we pick we
just need to have the discussion about
which way we want to go okay murray do
you mind if i insert myself before you
no go ahead
um
my counter argument as a participant you
know i i kind of i will be okay either
way um is um
as murray pointed out earlier that ayan
is not going to check names so if i
start if i request an extension called
my shiny balloon it would be very hard
to refuse and say no pick a better name
or something um
so um
but i i guess my point is that if
somebody wants to use one called my
shiny balloon why should we tell them
not to who cares
um i i i
i think the way to resolve that is the
the clause you have here that says that
describes the extension's purpose format
and usage if you drop that i think we're
good
all right because because you're not
asking diana to confirm what's in this
what's in the reference well no
okay
the
this text is for the person who's going
to do the registration all we're going
to ask guyana to do is make sure that
there's a reference and that it doesn't
say chicken chicken chicken chicken and
beyond that ayanna's not going to do any
checking but i want the
person making the registration request
to know what we expect to have in the
reference as kind of a guideline okay
yeah that's i think that'll fly yeah
and and if we decide to go with
specification required i'm happy to
volunteer as the designated expert who
will basically approve everything
so
john
i i'm
i'm pushing back a little bit on
and i don't overburden overburden diana
i think we're agreed about that and i
think we're agreed about the principle
that it's better to have registrations
than to
have things floating around which aren't
unregistered
uh
i'm
i'm concerned that over the years we've
seen
attempts to extend things here done in
various ways
that are loony
and i'd like to be able to get enough
community input into the process to help
the authors understand where things are
loony or where things won't work
i don't want to create a bar to
registration in the sense the standards
track thing does
but i want to create the opportunity for
input and discussion and entire at a
more extensive level than the authors
talking themselves
or the reviewers
um
uh having to review something that they
may not understand even for whether or
not there's a specification that makes
sense
fair enough
you know
okay uh
john levine do you want to comment on
this you commented on the mailing list i
just trying to
get a bit more discussion
yeah um
i think i'm aligned with barry here i
mean i understand
sort of that in principle there is a
writ you know there's a risk that people
might want to
sneak horrible stuff through here but
given that we're not the network police
if they want to do horrible stuff
they'll do it anyway so i would presume
i would presume to be documented
yeah again if if we could figure out a
way to write first come first serve
after an ietf last call
uh
i i i'd be happy about that
uh it's something we've certainly never
done before
uh but uh but i do want to
give people who are proposing these
things the opportunity for uh
uh for community input
um
so my sense of
uh john clenson
my sense of what you want you want is
you you you don't want to block them
from registering you don't want to say
uh you need to prove to us that this is
useful you just want to have them have
the opportunity to have an exchange and
get helped if they need it
more
more or less barry and uh
and the only qualification is that uh
that i'm inclined to try to require that
because as we both know from other
contexts the people who most need that
help usually don't understand they need
it
right yeah exactly
yeah i have sympathy for that and i i
need to respond to the note that you
sent to a few of us
about that kind of how we could come up
with a new
kind of registration process that would
help with that so we can talk about that
another time but uh yeah i have sympathy
for that
pete
do you have an opinion you
sorry i'm i'm i'm trying to
track everybody he's got his shoulders
hunched over
pete resnick i'll repeat what i just
said in the chat room um i have a
leaning toward make this as close to
first come first served as we can
do it and i like the idea of
some sort of documentation that gives
people the ability to
you know
get some advice from the community if
they want it but
really that you know this is not a
closed name space at all and
you know if people like shiny balloon as
their
you know as
what they want to register that's not
going to do any damage to the protocol
so
i have a friendly proposal to my first
friendly proposal
um maybe what we want to say here then
is first come first served with the
reference must also be provided
describes this and say it is highly
recommended
that
registrants post to this mailing list
and get feedback before they proceed
with their registration something there
that will encourage them to ask for
feedback
but still allow them to just do a fast
track registration if that's really what
they want to do what do you think john
clenson
i could probably live with that
i do
i do think the implication i i'm still
hearing marshall's voice which is in the
text
[Laughter]
and uh
and the uh
the implication of needing to fast-track
one of these
because somebody has come up with a
brilliant idea they want to get in the
ayanna registry right away
uh is
uh is an invitation to having to revise
it later for which we have no procedure
at all right uh and uh uh and generally
creating a mess if anybody pays any
attention to registration
again i don't want to do anything which
will
discourage people from registering
but i do want to try to find some way to
encourage people to think about what
they're doing
and uh and and we have all seen over the
years in ietf people come up with
brilliant ideas at least in their minds
which are so important that they should
be deployed immediately many of which
are described as ipv10
but
there's a trade-off there yeah or or you
are in uris that don't have colons in
them or whatever so yeah precisely yes
and and and we have proved that this has
happened multiple times
all right
get ready pete uh yeah the speed again
um
i i think i just want to address the um
fast track i don't think that's the
reason that i lean toward first come
first serve it's pain in the ass
right
it's
we want people who
have something to register to not think
oh my what a pain in the ass let's just
skip the registration and start using it
which i think is what happens now
i don't think people really want you
know it needs to be registered today i
don't i think that's a very rare
instance i think the real problem is
that people view it as a hurdle
and so we want to say there's no hurdle
you just register them but please
announce them here
and you know get some feedback
okay um again as a
participant uh i'm sort of in between
varying pete and john
i think i would prefer
for registration requests to be posted
mandatorily
to the mailing list
but feedback yeah to
but then have first come first serve
after the you know two weeks period this
uh
kind of quite similar to what we're
doing with some media types
um
so you know in other words so you're
okay with the idea that somebody posts
to this mailing list
gets feedback saying your idea is really
really bad
rethink it please and they say
and register it anyway without paying
attention to feedback
that's that's my preference
because i'd rather see it read if
they're going to use it i'd rather see
it registered than not
but that covers john's concern that they
need a way to get feedback
i think
i can live with this
basically
i would prefer that people engage in the
discussion but if they say well that's
just a thing that
i just need to send one email and
never have to read any responses well
as you guys said we're not police
the the the
the
my my other concern here it goes
directly to the question dave asked in
the chat is that we end up with a
um
with a registration of something which
seems to have something which looks like
a specification
and then they discover it doesn't work
and the specification changes they don't
bother
it or
adopt a registration document because
that too is a pain in the ass
and i don't know that can be prevented
but again if the community gets a chance
to discuss the thing it may be possible
to uh
um
to get the thing
uh
uh improved a little bit if uh if
possible before the registration goes in
and anybody tries to use it
and i'm not trying to set a bar here i'm
trying to provide an opportunity for for
discussion
uh if we take that much out
uh the other question for the working
group is whether i should simply remove
the text which argues for minimizing
extensions because they
cause it because they inherently cause
interoperability problems
okay ken
hi ken richardson um
i think the the
bigger issue that we want to try to
solve here is
not having two different vendors
start using a keyword
at the same time without either one of
them registering and then there's
eventually name clash i think that's
more important than somebody registering
a an extension that ends up being
technical garbage
because as pete said before
no one's going to use it there's no
interoperability problem
but if vendor a starts using fubar and
vendor b starts using fubar and they did
two different things then we've got a
problem
dave
good morning um it's 4 30 here even
though i'm some distance from murray
um
the last comment goes to what i think is
the only operational problem
that has a serious effect
um the
the
general problems of posting stuff that's
crap
um is their problem it it
the name space will get a little noisier
but it doesn't actually matter
and
the
some of the discussion has sounded like
it's trying to create additional iana
policies
and my guess is that's not actually
what's being intended but rather
the intention is to use an existing iana
policy but add various uh items of
advice
to this document
and uh
well that wasn't actually clear from the
discussion and
um
putting in various commentary
uh
might seem like a good idea
uh but the more
detailed that commentary is the more
opportunity since this will be new text
the more opportunity there is for it to
be confusing
uh and and as an example of that i'll
point out that i was confused listening
to this if i was confused listening to
this what are the odds of somebody
reading this in a document is going to
think that this is a requirement rather
than advice
so i might suggest my suggestion is
minimize the changes address only the
the problem that is on the table which
is getting people to register and don't
try to quality control the registration
process
uh or or
because if they want it to be used they
will come and get advice
if they are convinced in their arrogance
that they know truth
they're just going to work around this
don't add more text that is basically
parental
even if it's good parenting
all right so uh
my feeling of the room is that we're
leaning somewhere toward first come
first serve
with
some kind
of suggestion about mailing lists
posting to the mailing list
yeah
and
i hear dave's comment i i i unders i
have sympathy for that too so
maybe what we want to do is introduce
apart from this text somewhere else from
this text
that there is a mailing list to discuss
extensions and it's useful and put that
somewhere else that's not right here
so people don't think it's a requirement
but it's a place they can get feedback
i i don't know
i'm designing on the
on the microphone right now
uh
you added yourself and you took
john
yeah i'll i'll i'll repeat what i said
in the uh in the chat
which is that if what we really need
if the issue is making certain that
people can register these things
absolutely painlessly
uh one
one additional possibility is to
allow immediate registration on request
which is very much like first come first
serve
um
and uh
and then give and then post something to
the lit to a list
and give the authors uh
um
60 days to listen to whatever comments
transpire and at the end of those 60
days registration becomes permanent
that's actually not a bad idea i think
yeah i could certainly live with that
dave does that
address your concern or does it um fall
into parenting
that sounds like it's trying to create
revised iana procedures
it it it doesn't date because after a
careful look at the ayanna procedures
and barry can comment more on this that
i can because he wrote them uh but uh
but the iana procedures require
do not require that any of those
standard categories be used it requires
only that the procedure be clear to
ayanna
right that's correct and there are in
fact some pretty bizarre
twistings of these that people have used
in various areas
and they work really
sorry right and they're a mess sorry
so so
as you try to create conditions you
create opportunity for confusions this
is the problem with new specification
i thought the goal of the working group
was to make minimal changes not merely
make whatever changes seem like a good
idea
but dave this
making any change here is is a change
and uh
and a change which
preserves some of the current properties
of what the document says
uh while loosening the requirements
is a minimal change and it's no less a
minimal change
than uh then
or no more or less than a of a minimal
change than saying well check it all and
go to first first serve
going to first come first serve invokes
an established process that is
reasonably well understood the downsides
of doing that are also fairly well
understood as soon as we start adding
more conditions
we're creating a new specification with
more opportunity for misunderstanding
and miss action
but but but if we do what i suggested
more or less
the only
complication
is whether ayanna can make a mark on
their calendar and count to 60
or some other period which somebody
picks
and
per the diana specification document
again barry can say more about this than
i can if iana doesn't think they can
count to 60 reliably then they say no
that doesn't work
so no i i think what john is saying
there is in fact a cue and i understand
we're doing a little colloquy here but i
would like at least the chance to step
in my ears
i'm sorry
the the mask
right pete then barry
this is pete i i want to um
actually
disagree with john on this um
the
the simplest way to deal with this
is do first come first serve
and if we want some sort of iana
instructions in the iana considerations
that they announce it somewhere that's
fine putting a 60-day delay is exactly
the kind of fence that is going to cause
people to not register these things and
i think the amount of damage they can
possibly do is so minimal
that it should not be done
we should just simply do it first come
first serve if we want to give ayanna
instruction that they should announce
this such that we can interact with the
person because they're going to provide
an email address anyway and we can cc
them on this
that's fine that's certainly
not changing
the
registration policy it changes an iana
procedure but it's basically an
announcement
um so i i i think we're asking for
trouble
if we're going to go away from
specification required and not require
expert review if that's the decision
we're making then let's just go to first
come first served and make an
announcement
okay there's actually something new in
what pete said that i'll follow up in a
second but what i wanted to say first
was i think john what i
john is
is looking for something
yes john is john is trying to propose
something that is very different
and what pete said that um that keyed
there is
if we instead of trying to put this on
the registrant we put it on iana we ask
them
to post to the
discussion list
i think that helps i think that makes
that takes the
load away from the registrant
i have to agree with dave on this that
um
there is no need to change this text at
all
we can leave this as standards track or
experimental rfc specifically approved
by the isg for this purpose
and we did say we're going to make
minimal changes so that is the minimal
change is not to change it at all
the next minimal change is to say well
but this is really is ietf review is
really what this means so let's change
it to that
even making its specification required
is more than a minimal change
and making it first come first serve
with this and that tweak
is a bigger change so it depends how we
want to go with changes
i i am fairly ambivalent on it at this
point
okay
i'm going to lock the door in this room
and nobody leaves until i make a
decision
remote people have a slight advantage
here they just just run
um
i think the path of least resistance is
to to go with specification required and
have the
have somebody review it
but it doesn't have to be the ietf
reviewing it
works for me personally
this is pete
my only concern about specification
required is i don't think it
significantly changes
the barrier that the current text has
such that we're gonna solve the problem
no it does actually i understand the
difference between the two
but
i i suspect that anybody who is
unwilling to even do an experimental rfc
just submit the draft is not going to do
specification required
yeah but specification required can be
you post something to your blog
right
this is a go doing an rfc even if it's
through the independent stream is
more of a burden
dave
so in response to barry my question is
so what
so what on which
you you were you were laying out a
possibility
of uh some um
let's call it casual
uh uh behavior
which might have some uh uh challenges
in utility so posting to a blog might or
might not actually uh be useful
um and so they register a name and they
only post to a blog
um
and gee that's that doesn't work very
well let's let's just take that case
which is just what i assume
uh why you mentioned that as an example
and to which my response is so what
their
their option
perhaps isn't useful
so what yeah that basically what i was
saying i'm agreeing with you there yeah
no what i was saying is that as opposed
to having to do an rfc which is what
they have to do now
which which is
oh okay i thought you were raising it as
a worst case an example of a worst case
scenario
so specification required
is an entirely reasonable barrier but
it's a very high barrier if we're trying
to lower the barrier
then get rid of the damn barrier
and that's why i proposed first come
first serve yeah right
sorry i i
yeah okay
and i'm just pointing out though that
first come first served is a significant
change and if we're really looking to
make minimal changes to the document we
have to consider that so i i
hansjorg
who was patiently listening to our
bickering all this time
uh yeah hi this isn't
indeed i might probably have a little
bit of an unpopular opinion here so um i
was wondering for myself uh
for quite some time actually with any
ayanna registry that's
i'm not really sure if this is a core
part people use a lot actually and
you know i'm they do yeah they do i'm
wondering actually i mean i i i totally
understand why this discussion sort of
is necessary however i'm wondering a
little bit like we are discussing here
something for quite some time now
um which actually is probably not even
as such a big deal because just not so
many people will actually ever register
something here i mean one could argue
because currently these policies are too
strict but i'm actually sure that's not
the point
the discussion in my opinion rather
should be on a much more meter level
maybe like you know
how in general could could ayanna
registries made more useful for
users of the services and doesn't that
kind of stuff need redesign overall i
know that it's probably too big of a
topic yeah right now it's probably out
of scope that's why i said it's an
unpopular opinion maybe well so so i
guess the point here is um and i have no
data and so i'm just
sort of groping but
it may be that that people who have
cockamamie ideas that are
not really useful
are deterred from putting them into
their stuff by
having to do an rfc
and they can't do an rfc because we're
never going to do it we're never going
to approve an rfc that has this bad idea
and so they don't bother at all and they
just don't come with it and if we made
it easy
they would come with it and put in a lot
of stupid ideas
i i doubt that that's going to happen
i'm not really expecting that if we just
said first come first serve with no
restriction i'm sure we're not going to
suddenly get 300 requests for bad ideas
as smtp extensions
but maybe john has some data to refute
that or dave's next in the queue
actually
dave
sorry i was distracted being too clever
responding to me ago so i didn't
actually hear what you said
you do you mean to be in the queue or
oh sorry your hand is up no i i i i was
i i thought that barry was asking me a
question so i was trying to respond oh i
just saw that i couldn't answer
sorry
right um
i can think probably of four documents
that will
this will affect right away
three of them or rx extensions in some
common use
published by sendmail and others uh
one probably fall into the care of their
bad idea category
um
i don't know if it helps us but
so i i can see that uh both there are
things that are not registered because
of current registration procedure
and i can also see some cases which
might might not be registered depending
on which bar you know which level we
pick basically and i'm perfectly okay
with seeing a few bad ideas come in and
get registered but i wouldn't want
hundreds john
i'm uh
i think we're spending far too much time
on this discussion than it is worth
relative the rest of the agenda and uh
and we either take this the mailing list
or drop it and uh and adopt the
principle of minimal change which i of
absolutely minimal change which i would
oppose as well but um
but i think we're going around the
circles right now
and the fact that i'm having trouble
hearing
speakers who are speaking almost next to
micron into the mic uh doesn't help much
but it's
just
an added aggravation we're spending too
much time on this
okay so yeah uh
just doing a mic check is this mic any
better for you to hear from john
uh no
okay that's the same and i i'm right now
i'm right up against the mic so
no no though as as i said it's uh it's
about the same i uh i can hear you barry
when you're speaking close to mikey
clearly i've had trouble hearing other
people who are a little more trouble
hearing other people but it's still very
faint
okay
right um
buddy i will delegate you to follow up
on the mailing list on this
i will do that
gosh you can just never predict which
topic is going to be easy i thought this
one will be easy one so
you better help me out on the next one
please
oh by the way uh so john had technical
problems so he was late so i talked
about this already
so yes
thank you though um all right uh moving
to the next one is one of the issues
that john lewin raised was about verify
being required command and observing
that
a lot of implementations either don't
implement it or just have a stub
implementation
um
so one thing that we sort of discovered
while researching this um
issue is that uh
verify actually can be a capability and
emitted by some mtas
it is however not registered with ayana
which probably should be fixed
so basically the question is should
should the document either say that
verify
may be implemented but doesn't does is
not required
or uh alternative we can just keep
verifying the document and say if it's
implemented then
you have to emit verify verify
capability
thoughts comments
john divine
yep
and the interest is minimal change
i would you know i always say
leave it in and say it's requested i
mean just leave it in and require it
since like i said
if you don't actually if you don't want
to actually provide a useful answer
you're allowed you're allowed to do it
to do a stub
you know in my
poking around it appears that in fact
everybody does everybody does just do a
252 so that would also match existing
existing practice
okay so uh
right
maybe there's a sentence saying about
the stub implementation then or or is it
right well i think
you know it already allows this stuff um
yeah i don't remember where the sentence
allowing is the stub implementation is
it may be okay already
yeah i don't think the text quite allows
the sub implementation
there is uh certainly text saying that
verify should should spend more energy
trying to verify addresses than rcpt2
does
which kind of the opposite of
what we are proposing
i can't
jon
uh yeah just remember too that we've got
enough loopholes in uh
in five three two one even
uh for uh for not doing things if they
don't seem sensible or don't seem
operationally reasonable or seem
insecure
that an
implementation or configuration which
doesn't feel like
supporting verify simply leaves it on
the hello list and moves
on so one can not implement this while
implementing it or something like that
that's an argument for no change
um yeah so maybe i think what we are
it seems like it would be nice to add
some text to as but maybe the base pack
doesn't need to change
is it roughly what i'm hearing
or maybe not at all
john would you like uh
do you think we should have some text
about verifying in is
if we don't do a change to the base pack
i
i think if people want to we can clarify
the existing rules a little bit
because it's convoluted and
different sections
i believe after trying to review them
say
things but uh but it's very very easy to
read them in ways which the uh in which
what said it's not consistent or is he
is even contradictory so that may be a
little
maybe a little straightening out but i
don't think there's a strong case for
making
any substantive change here like trying
to deprecate the thing
okay
pete was in the queue and he said what
john
said um todd
yeah just to clarify the earlier bit
about
stop appearing in the spec or not
the word stub doesn't but um in section
seven three it speaks of
if a site disables these commands for
security reasons and one of the commands
is verified the smtp server must return
a 252 response so that kind of speaking
toward the sub
to the stub topic without actually using
all right all right
fine uh
okay so i think what i'm hearing is or
what i would like to propose is
no change in the base pack uh
if people want some extra explanation in
as we can discuss this on the mailing
list
the separate minor issue about verified
capability we can just take this
directly to ion i think
john
do you want me to go through and see if
i can see just
clarification and editorial cleanups to
this
collection of statements about verifiers
so we just let that go
um i think it would be useful there
might be like three sentences in
different parts of the document that
might look contradictory but maybe you
just need to cross-reference saying
this is what you know typically is done
but look at x
yeah
okay
i think that would be useful
my guess is it'll be a few words here
and there and maybe some cross
references
but but let me make a proposal on the
mailing list
okay sounds good
[Music]
right moving on
uh john levine raised another um
question about what is restricted
capability client
section three three
restricted capability client must not
assume that any smgp server on internet
can be used as their mail processing
relaying site
um
so uh i think it's it's a valid question
what what is meant by the student
capability client
um
also
depending on what it means uh
if this is talking about open relays
not
not being a good thing uh then maybe the
text is misplaced and should be moved
um
john levine would you like to
talk more about this one
i think i would
i didn't understand what restricted
capability client meant
and
i just
you know it like if it if it means it
like the example i gave is my printer
which sent which sends notifications to
one address i mean if that's what we
mean by a restricted capability client
then the advice is fine and maybe we
should define restricted capability
client better i thought it might i
thought it meant an mua that knows how
to send mail to anybody but doesn't know
how to it doesn't know how to find an mx
in which case
then it's
the advice is kind of wrong
so i guess
yeah so yeah
yeah my preference is just to be a
little clearer about what we mean by a
research capability client
pete
yeah um
now that i read the sentence
do we just mean clients
i mean no client should assume that any
smtp server on the internet can be used
as their mail processing relaying site
well i mean
it's about open relays that then it's in
the wrong section i i think that's what
that
is referring to
i mean it it it's you know there you
might not be able to get to an open
relay you might not be able to
have something that acts like a
submission server
um it you know
not every smtp server on the internet
can be used as a mail processing uh
relay
site uh unless someone thinks we meant
something different there and and
i mean maybe it should be moved but
basically you're saying drop restricted
capabilities yeah we're not saying
anything magical there as far as i can
tell i i'll go re-read the context but
i think it's just clients
john
the the first observation
is that uh
uh as as the several exchanges between
john levine and i
um
uh indicated
prop probably indicate this this text is
confusing and horrible and in my defense
i didn't write it i was told to put it
in
um
[Music]
and we certainly need to clarify it
one of the clarifications is that it was
this
sentence and a few others
that caused me to raise the question as
to whether we wanted to switch back to
smtp sender rather than and smtp
receiver rather than smtp client and
smtp server
because
i think this texas intended to talk
about smtp clients not muas
and that immensely changes the meaning
what's going on here although it still
doesn't make it clear
uh and uh and again the uh the note i
sent to the we are the morning about
this
may at least clarify what the problem is
if not what the solution is
and i have no opinions today beyond that
okay
dave
so as i posted there's sort of two
different uh lines of thinking that can
go with this text the first is
do we know of existing operational
problems being caused by this text i
think the answer is no
i think that the concern being concerns
being raised are by the static reading
of the text and thinking about it rather
than having reports
that argues against making any changes
given the nature of the current working
group effort
that said
there are problems with this text first
of all the idea that software makes
assumptions doesn't make any sense which
invites confusion about this the second
of all
this actually is not text that is
operational
it isn't specifying it it isn't
specifying a meaningful action
or prohibiting
it isn't meaningfully prohibiting
an action that makes any sense
and that argues for just dropping this
text completely because we don't know we
don't seem to know of what problem this
is trying to
the text is trying to solve we've just
had several people make some guesses
about it but we're not sure
and so if the text is confusing which it
clearly is
dropping it in the absence of knowing
what problems it's picking uh would
would actually be the simplest thing to
do
leaving it given that we don't know of
field problems it's causing is the other
choice so dropping it or keeping it make
the most sense changing it does not
okay uh speaking as a participant i
would be in favor of dropping it
john
i feel really strongly about this and i
will drop it if people tell me to drop
it
but uh but i am reluctant to remove text
that uh
the drums
the drums are yam i don't know which one
at this point uh put in uh
without
without understanding what that was
intended to say
uh so i would argue for
clarification in preference to dropping
if we can figure out what that
clarification means and i think
clarifications are clearly in scope
okay
and i offered a hypothesis about what it
means
the um
the text from 5321 we we've omitted one
word from
this sentence here that the sentence
actually starts with the word
consequently and it is
contextually it is sort of talking about
um
open relays
so
that may
inform any future direction we take on
this text
it doesn't just say restrict capability
clients must not assume
it says
you know
that the prior sentences these
restrictions may make the server useless
as a relay for clients that do not
support full smtp functionality
consequently restricted capabilities
must not assume in any server on the
internet whatever so i just want to
throw that out there
yeah todd i i think it's still a a lousy
construction
um but uh
by the indeed when this is taking
context with the uh
with the associated text it it makes
some sense and actually gives a clue as
well speaking about what he was intended
so a very small amount of this problem
is that the text is recorded out of
quoted repeatedly out of context
john said that uh it looks like this
text was quoted repeatedly out of
context because we the previous sentence
is not quoted
john can you suggest a clarification to
the sentence
john clenson
in real time though
no no uh uh yeah i'm i'm like in the
next week or so
um
let me uh let me try to do that next
week or so and uh
uh and if john
if the other john wants to have an
office conversation about how that fits
should be written i would appreciate it
uh i would also appreciate for your
reputation in mind if you would clarify
how his last name was
pronounced before we get completely
confused
okay
pete
yeah um i asked in the chat room
uh
john you you indicated that if we can
figure out what this means you'd prefer
to clarify it
what if we can't figure out the history
of this sentence would you be more
inclined to drop it or more inclined to
just leave it there and ignore
it and anyone else can answer as well
but i i'm curious what your particular
take on this was um
my my my prediction especially when it
looks at the context of this half
sentence
uh is that we will be able to figure out
what it means so i hope you're i put
your case is entirely hypothetical uh
having said that if we can't figure out
what it if we cannot make it clear that
i prefer dropping it then leaving it
there okay
all right so yeah i i think that's
probably the best way forward is john
will propose a clarification
if we can agree on it great
if not uh if it generates lots of other
discussion and confusion then we'll just
drop it
i i i i do think however the condition
for that is that it is that everybody
make a good faith effort to
to to read whatever it is i write and
then see if we can either fix it or
agree
rather than not agreeing in order to
take it out in order to take this text
out and that was the reason i was a
little bit reluctant to answer each
question yes
absolutely
everybody should always act in good
faith
are you joining the queue pete no no
all right okay
okay
moving on
uh
to the next issue that
i would like john and john to discuss
um
this is around
nullimax and some terminology
up here here i am nope here here i'm not
um
did you put in the other the other slide
that i suggested about this
yeah there is no slides yeah here we go
yeah so the question is yeah we have a
host that handles mail for yeah so
here's the setup
mail.example.com
handlesmailforexample.com but not for
itself
so if someone sends
so if someone addresses a message to
mail.example.com what should it say
and as the next slide suggests we have
we have two competing answers one is 550
which is what it normally says
and the other is 556 which says it's a
null mx
and while i don't think 556 is wrong i
don't think it's i also don't think it's
realistic i think in my experience mail
mail servers know what domains they
handle and they know what domains they
don't handle but they don't know any
they don't know why they don't handle
other domains so this basically would
require every time a receipt two fails
you know it's got to do an all mx lookup
and say oh i know i know what's going on
there and it's actually you know it's
it's it could be surprisingly
complicated because
um it is not rare for mail servers to
have 100 different names i mean like at
microsoftoutlook.com
every
the mail server has a name has the mail
server has has a name for every domain
that it handles you know so
there's a lot of possible looking up
there so my inclination is just is i
think not not to change anything and 550
550 is the normal response for not our
mailbox
john clancy
actually i just both stay in the queue
and just
you're the people who who seem to
understand the issue you know i i to be
honest i was a bit confused
um
i want to agree with john on two things
one of which is that this this gets
rapidly
and
and the other is that
probably we're better off just leaving
it alone
not going to disagree with that
sorry did you just suggest no change
basically
no change to the document
okay
moving on
uh
right this and the following issue is
actually um
slides are now out of date because uh
discussion on the mailing list moved on
a little bit but we don't have a
proposal text so this is uh
basically clarifying about
when
[Music]
like how blind copies and rcpt to work
and also
when the foreclose in the received
header fields can be inserted
um
john clanson um you had a proposal you
would like to pursue
um
[Music]
i think this this needs some cleaning up
and uh
um
and i don't know whether it's best
cleaned up here or in the as i think the
minimum change argument are used for the
as but uh but that would still require
some changes here
uh and uh
uh and i outlined
um
several cases partly the
complexity here
is that the statement discussion of
blind copies
which i of course wrote as my fault
uh is is itself
problematic
because the uh
the an smtp server which is following
the rules
uh has no idea what's a blind copy of
what isn't
and uh and this gets inexorably tied up
with four
and uh
and i think what i've said on the
mailing list is probably more articulate
to what i can say this morning
right so um
you propose to have a look at this i
suggest so
firstly uh
i talked to pete and he was happy to
help you out with this
if you like his help
i i i always appreciate constructive
help and peace health is always
constructive okay so petraeus thumb up
uh so um you will have a look at this
text
uh suggest clarification uh
or you know things to delete things to
add i think
probably the best way is just you
suggest set of changes
we'll review it on the mailing list and
then we decide which one goes into
base pack which one goes to as if any
works for me
okay
um
again uh if we can get this done within
a couple of weeks that would be great
i think we need to to do some kind of
aerobic exercise in the room everybody
is sort of like
come on come on
exercise exercise jump up and down
uh
well they already had so much coffee
there you know
um
right trying to get through the rest uh
as energetically as possible
this is a follow-up on the discussion we
had at the january interim
about the text which seems to prohibit
list exploders to
add any header fields
uh
i think where we'll end it with this on
the mailing list there are four options
no change
remove the set uh
in option one uh the sentence
and the discussion is actually listed
second choice remove the sentence
um third replace it with
this change to mail from doesn't affect
the header section of the message
for this change uh replace it with the
this change to mail from doesn't affect
the header field that is already present
in the message
um
i don't want to have the whole
discussion all over again so i pro i
think
john and i are happy with choice three
and four
if people have any strong object
objections
if people have preferences for either
three or four maybe we can have a quick
discussion here
battery set three
ken says
whatever
pete is shaking his head as well
okay and the winner is number three
um i mean uh realistically number three
and number four is kind of so close that
i don't think it matters
in absence of
any objections
i think john
please implement change number three
and i can close this issue
sorry i was distracted by an emergency
telephone call
the only advantage of four over three
is that if there was some weird case
which so far nobody's been able to
identify
that uh
that would uh would cause somebody to
want to put a
um
trace or other sort of receipts other
sort of fields
into the message
that indicated what was done here
uh three prohibits that
probably and four does not accept that
three is uh
except that there's already text there
and says you can't cannot change any
header fields that's already in the
message so they're
uh right right click i i guess you write
me down is indifferent and if the
consensus is three i'm happy with it
okay mary
gal this is barry lieber um
the way i read this is the the the text
that isn't quoted that comes before this
just says you have to do this stuff to
the mail from yes you change the mail
from the only thing that we need to say
is and we're just talking about the mail
from here it does not affect the message
headers
and that's the straightforward thing
that
and that's why i prefer three
i don't mind four but i think three is
all we need to say and it's less
confusing than anything else
wow
okay all right all right
okay
so what's that they've had a question in
the in the chat room um in the the jab
room whatever so
okay
yeah this is pete to answer dave yes i i
think the reason we need to say
something here is because people have
had trouble with this people think that
changing the mail from means that they
have to change the from field in the
message which is a bad thing
and
this
clarifies
that we only mean
changing the mail from doesn't affect
the message header in any way as far as
instruction goes there's an instruction
here
um that we're going to be leaving in
which talks about changing the mail from
but that doesn't affect the header
section so i think this clarifies and
doesn't change what's currently in the
text it just clarifies the meaning of
what's in the text that people have
screwed up in the past
yeah and adding to that the reason we
want to make some change to this is that
some people have interpreted the message
header section must be left unchanged is
that you're not allowed to make any
other unrelated changes to the message
header if you're a male exploder and we
want to dissuade them that we want to
make it clear that we're not talking
about that at all
yeah
dave
so i'll repeat the point
mailing list exploders
are acting long after mail delivery
they're creating a new message and
they're posting it
so the problem here is much deeper than
this bit of text fixes
the idea that we have a separate ticket
for that
we have a separate ticket about male
explorers which i i postpone because ned
is not here
you're right we need to do some other
changes
if that's where you're going with it
so my
to to apply the point here that says
option two
remove the sentence
the sentence is
that i mean this is sort of beyond layer
violation
since it's
53 21 talking about 53 22 topics but it
it's sort of beyond that in that it's
trying to fix a problem with something
that's completely out of scope for this
spec the fact that historically it was
in the spec
at the time was
there weren't really meaningful choices
were 30 years later
yeah let's
for what it's worth i i i could live
with two i think three
adds the clarity that we were trying to
get to but i could live with two as well
right let's just go ahead with three and
done with this one
right
right so peter's saying if we're going
to discuss alice's and mailing list
clarification so there is a separate
ticket for this
we were supposed to discuss it and ned
was supposed to propose some text or
possible document but
he got delayed so um
we are going to do this later
so how much time do we actually have
left
half an hour
i'm going to mix up things a little bit
because i am
in the front and i can
um
todd
do you want to do a quick recap of
your slide
sure
um
i
posted
i've posted several revs of proposed
text to the list
since january the most recent was
earlier this week
um incorporating whatever comments have
been made after the interim
alexi made a few minor comments
i have incorporated them in my working
document but haven't posted them to the
list or in the ticket or anywhere
i would encourage people to
look at the list and
give it another
pass when they get a chance uh
let me get you the proper
or the the actual subject name here as
soon as i can find it in my threads
uh
the subject is ticket number 54
authentication and encryption for a
asrev4
so if anyone uh wants to take a look at
the list and make some more
suggestions uh
i appreciate it
but that's really i'm not going to sit
here and read the text to everybody
today
pete
sorry i missed that
pete seems to be in the queue but i
don't see him okay
right so um
let me make a proposal maybe we have a
couple of maybe you can post the latest
version
we'll have a couple of weeks of comments
and then if there are no further
comments then ken just can incorporate
the text
okay it's like one big section with
sub-sections you know so but i mean yeah
yeah that's fine with me
ken loves text already written for him
sounds perfect
okay are you
ready are you ready for the last ticket
of the day
are you ready to
can i get your commitment to be
productive
okay
right
you can see why i did i didn't want to
do it earlier
right
john mentioned some of it
earlier on in relationship to other
tickets
basically question is whether existing
use of
mta is sufficiently defined whether
we want to use senders mtp and receive
smtp instead of smtp client smtp server
okay
and the next slide is definition of mta
i wrote this slide long time ago my
proposal is to do no change but you know
if
if we can get some useful discussion out
of this topic
john
uh there's uh
a small interesting complication here
and i think some of it is changes the
working group told me to make
this time around and some of it may have
crept in in five three two one
but at this stage the document contains
both sets of terminology in different
places
and the principle of minimal change
would say that uh that we just leave it
alone the principle of maximum clarity
says we've got to make a decision and i
should clean it up and i'm agnostic
between those two principles
actually i prefer the minimal change one
because it's less work but that's not a
very good excuse
pete
miss pete reznick i
i actually would argue in favor of
minimal change on
um what i now take to be the crocker
principle of
this really hasn't screwed up anybody as
far as i can tell
no one has
come to us and said what the heck does
this mean or that mean i think people
get it now sufficiently that
we could leave this exactly as it is and
it really wouldn't affect implementation
at all
yes
speaking as a participant i i have kind
of similar feeling that
even though the observation that there
might be two set of terminology used is
correct
it doesn't seem to affect readability of
the document
shall i quickly close close this ticket
and everybody can go home
going once
ken wants the last word
i have no strong opinion on
what we do but i just noticed that the
proposed text that i have for the
as document with regards to
enhance status codes uses sender and
receiver so
in the interest of
being consistent i assume you want to
change that
to be client server
and pete has a response
yeah this is pete since
john said that there are still instances
of both of these floating around in 5321
i think the as could do well
to
clarify the meanings of these terms and
and
you know
be explicit that
5321 uses both sets of these terms and
and
they both mean the same you know they
both mean the same thing but
um i don't think there's
any particular reason to go one way or
the other in the as
we'll pick one when we get to that you
know uh discussion but
you're going to
that as is there for clarification
purposes anyway we might as well clarify
in there if we're going to do it
okay hold on
thank you
hans yeah is this antioch um i would
like to say i probably prefer send a
receiver because there's an smt client
for me could also be a mail user agent
you know sending the email this is
actually a client for me
um and also like the sender smtp still
techn in a technical sense might be an
smtp server component and in fact in
many situations it is just the same
piece of fulfilling the role of a sender
smtp and a receiver smtp
yeah
but i agree that probably it won't have
much of an influence
on interpreting the rfc but as i hear
this is also used in other
contexts might be still worth thinking
about that
okay i think you're volunteering to
review the whole document and point out
every case where it might be better
are you scared yet
yes you cannot leave the room i will
lock the door as i said
um
john
yeah in indeed uh following up on the
last comment
um most of the cases where one senator
where the
sender and receiver terminology was
introduced or reintroduced
are cases where what is talking about a
uh
a single piece of software acting in
both capacities and the and that
distinction is is more helpful than
talking about it is the server or the
client it may not be entirely consistent
that way and the question i'd like to
ask is whether people would object to
um
simply inserting the sentence that a
sentence equivalent to what murray
suggested
uh into uh
in the thing which says that in general
these two things are just uh
interchangeable these two sets of things
just interchange and would move on that
that's a clarification which really
ought to be made
for people reading
5321 bis and not merely in the as
okay
i think that makes sense
i just wanted to be sure that before i
put it in that there were
were no strong objections on the claim
that it was on the basis that it was a
claim we that it was a change we didn't
absolutely need
okay
right
with this
i think we at the end of the
session um
nobody complained
okay
yeah
um i uh i was
uh
i want to talk about
whether we do interims or not
so um
as you might or might not know i spent
probably five hours this week working on
slides and communicating with everybody
this is taking quite a bit of time
um
i think it would be nice to be done
so we have email format document in
walking group plus call very soon
uh
i would like to maybe have one or two
interims to just nail the remaining
issues we have some of the stuff we are
going to discuss on the mailing list
like the whole exciting and registration
procedure
then again if this is the most exciting
topic no let's have an interim to
discuss that
interim to decide the next set of
tickets to discuss on the next interim
you might as well get my job then you
know just just just just just take it
so do people think about interim
in a month or two
i'd like to make a case for people
actually
trying to deal with these things on the
mailing list the extent possible
uh it is at least for me much more much
easier to
uh get texts into documents based on
mail english discussions
than to remember what happened in an
oral discussion and
and transcribe for minutes
uh and uh and in theory we shouldn't be
making any of these decisions
without confirmation on the mailing list
so if between now and the next ietf for
the next interim or the next lawn party
uh we can all pay more attention to
mailing list and uh
and and respond to things there make
suggestions there
um
i think it'd be
well be much more efficient for me and i
and i think for everybody else
uh john i i agree
but you know from our recent experience
obviously interims and
video meetings
uh serve as a focus point so we do get
progress on things we get stuck and
unfortunately we sometimes get on the
stuck on little things
absolutely and it's been very clear that
the interims have caused a uh a focusing
of attention and a burst of activity
which is worthwhile
uh i was just making a plea for and and
and based on experience that's the right
thing to do i was just making a plea for
a change in behavior if you want to
schedule an interim and then
we can accomplish a lot of the mailing
lists and then cancel the interim i
think that'd be great
that would be
fine with me
uh
yeah uh this is pete just
to agree with that
i would prefer you get the interim
scheduled because
getting
getting time on the calendar for a good
block is sometimes tricky
and
uh you know getting it on the calendar
and if we have to cancel it is way
better than waiting to see if we need it
and then trying to squeeze it in
fine so uh todd and i will try to
pick a date
maybe early next week
early next week pick a date you know in
a month months month or or two you know
now we'll we'll just have interims
monday tuesday wednesday thursday and
friday next week and until we get
everything done
um
murray
yeah there it goes um
i'll be away most of next month so if
you need anything please let me know
before then otherwise i'll pick up
whatever you have for me when i get back
okay thank you
so with this the meeting is closed any
other business
yeah come
on
is it is it uh
okay it's a question for the draft
actually okay yeah fine sorry for but i
mean
maybe for it anyway uh so when i was
looking through my notes i was thinking
about what's going on here so i
understand you basically went through
those two rfcs mentioned in the charter
sentence by sentence and try to figure
out where there are inconsistencies or
clarities right
um
not quite sentence by sentence but yeah
well okay some of us yes paid more
attention to some sections so when
singing about smtp one thing that comes
to my mind which for me at least seems
to be unclear in terms of overall rfc
coverage is sub-addressing
so as far as i know sub-addressing like
these plus addresses you should use for
uh um or you could use in siri for you
know
um
doing nice things uh with your email
it's actually only mentioned in an rc by
this guy in front of you it's only
insane yeah because it's um
so if we are talking about clarification
of um rfcs in particular smt prcs it
might be worth why i'm mentioning it i
don't know okay
um
it's a local convention even though
commonly implemented one so it's kind of
out of scope for this mtp itself it was
just an observation okay
and i jumped in the queue to say if if
we want to put something like that in
the applicability statement we can
discuss that in the context of the
applicability statement but it's
definitely out of scope for smtp
okay
fine
on that note
i think we're done
thank you for thank you for attending
thank you for getting up early
in
dave and murray and maybe others
so first come first serve wins as the
most ridiculous discussion of the entire
meeting
i'm happy
okay
can you send me mao
because it's not there it's it's not
part of smtp
okay it's something that some people
have rolled in
but it's not
okay
the purpose of this is
is
okay
yes