um
[Music]
with any mine anyone minds closing the
door please
thank you natalie
[Music]
welcome everyone
warren please be quiet
hello
a warm welcome to all of you it is very
nice to be here
face to face in part
and a warm welcome to our remote
attendees from all over the world
luckily for us we are anchored in the
european time zone native to my home
but i very much appreciate all the
people that are going bad
back to bed
or got up really early to attend this
session
um let's go through the
administrative
administrative that's a difficult word
administrative side of things
first of all this session is covered by
the ietf notewell
this means that we adhere to a certain
code of conduct specifically
in relation to civility
different than other meetings there are
no blue sheets to go around i dearly
miss the tradition but if you scan the
qr code that was here at the beginning
of the session
or go to the agenda on your phone
there's the meet echo lite
application and that's how you check in
and also how you cue yourself up for the
microphone
since this is the third day of itf i
assume that all the people in the room
are somewhat familiar with that
procedure
and meet echo thank you very much for
your assistance and help
specific to the grow working group there
are a number of resources
most importantly
our agenda can be viewed online and we
have a mailing list
i would now like to ask for a minutes
taker
jared would you like to be volunteered
for this job
good enough for me thank you for your
services jared
if anybody can also keep an eye on the
meat echo chat which is what previously
was known as the jabber thing
to ensure that we catch any and all
comments and questions
that
arrive from that communication channel
we have a volunteer for
jabber scribing
thank you warren your services are much
appreciated but in order to
fulfill this task you will need to open
your laptop
all right
agenda
today we have
a few topics
specifically bmp nrtm
mbmp you can see that we mix them up a
little bit to create an interesting
variance in our cadence today
our presenters are remote
[Music]
and i think unless you have anything to
add chris we we can move
to to the first presentation
yes
please all right
we're not there yet
follow
you
hello
hello paulo good to see you
yes great great and thank you for
awarding you know 12 minutes uh of the
agenda not 10 not 15. that was a greatly
appreciated it's precisely what i was
looking for
um
so
um i have uh updates on two uh drafts so
the tlv and the ebit tlp ebit draft so
next slide if some somebody is running
the slides
yes if you give me the signal i will
make it go to the next slide
next slide please
and next one again
perfect so i skipped the context because
every time i present the this draft i
give the top context so it's in the
previous slide for who has lost the
context for this one
um so just a brief update on what
happened since uh the last dra the last
version of the document so which is last
itf um
essentially we formalized a little bit
the boolean story coming from you know
programming background i was thinking
that just saying boolean was clear
enough but i received that the feedback
that
uh we should specify it's a one byte
field with
you know zero and one that can be
encoded in there so thanks very much to
jeff and bang for their feedback about
that
uh following uh the the rest of the
recommendation here uh they they were
all coming from jeff haas
and um so we should ask uh ayanna for
two new registries one for the root
monitoring a message and the other for
the peer down and then we added also an
error handling section um so in which
essentially what we say that um the tlvs
are trailing you know are following the
bgp video and of course you can decode
the tlds only if the bgp pdu is well
formed if you cannot pass that then of
course you cannot go beyond that and so
you cannot parse the tlds
uh so uh side remark is that uh you know
if you want to do an exercise which is
different from uh you know
conveying the messages but uh
you want to check the sanity of the pdu
and things like that maybe you are
looking for the root
mirroring instead of the root monitoring
um
and the second thing the secondary
market that was also coming from jeff
was that
as we know you know the message size is
limited and then uh
this is already you know a problem with
the bgp pdu itself and with bmp by
itself because there is a decoration
around the bgp pdu uh should it hit you
know itself the maximum length and then
of course this is aggravated with the
the use of tlts so it was good to make a
note over there
next slide please
and so
this is the status
for the version 7 of the draft and
essentially all the feedback that was
received has been processed and there is
really no more outstanding work
so this is a message for the chairs uh
and also i don't know if there is any
questions or any
any anything from anybody at this point
i have a question
if there's no more outstanding work
is there running code that you can
report on implementation reports
yes
yes this is all coded on the collector
siding pmsct it is coded it is working
it was test
um there is at least one vendor that i
am aware that has you know such
implementation so
yeah
so i guess you're asking for working
group last call and the sausage
machinery to
start running yeah
i think we are already in last call
i think i want to go beyond the last
call
all right
all right fantastic so next slide please
uh so this is about the uh tlv ebit uh
so this is the last present the last
time i presented this was at uh in
singapore in 2019 the last time that we
were i i was in person
um
and i think this is a very useful draft
but uh uh you know uh
we received even in the room some uh you
know
interesting comments about it so i've i
thought to refresh a little bit give
context again and share updates
so next slide please
um so what is the
problem statement here is that of course
uh you know uh we have uh tlds that we
explained in the other draft and till
these are public our ayanna governed and
you know we asked ayanna for registries
and then you know um every you know id
in that registry will mean something um
that is something for those registries
governed by ayana are of course for um
you know
elements that should be supported by you
know everybody or generally supported of
course next to that there could be some
elements that are not that are
proprietary that are you know not public
uh why is that there is a wealth of
reasons for that so the one of the most
common is that it's a you know a
pre-standard product right um another
one is that there is a
something that is commercially sensitive
but yet another point and this is
something on which i will update uh the
introduction of the of the draft is also
that there could be elements that are
very low level so they cannot really be
standardized right they could be low
level or really touching the internal of
the implementation that maybe it doesn't
generally exist or make sense to make
something you know ayanna go there so
this is this specific point which is
very relevant it's not yet mentioned in
the draft and i will do in the next you
know
release let's say
and next slide please
so um
as an introduction just in case uh not
everybody's familiar with the uh pang
pang is a private enterprise number and
it's a number that is assigned by ayana
so
whoever can go to a young and say i am
an enterprise and a young hands off
you know um an id i i don't know if it's
whoever but for example even
pmcct as a pen number okay
so the pen is the key in order to
make the enterprise specific part to
work and this is all you know nothing
new under the sun uh you know who knows
me i know i come from a lot of
experience with ipfix working with ipfix
and things like that and i just borrowed
something that i think it's very useful
and it totally works for ipfix but you
know porting that to bmp
next slide please
so
this is how ayanna gover and the tlv uh
is looking like you know um so
essentially we strip the first bit of
the type for that e and that becomes the
e b to the enterprise bit which could be
zero or one so in a young gober in the
tlv the e bit is zero and then
everything just stays as the other draft
the tlv draft that i just presented then
next slide please
in case
instead it is an enterprise specific one
the ebit goes to one and you see that
after the length you have the enterprise
number the enterprise number will be the
pan that i was describing before so you
have type land the enterprise number and
then the value
next slide please
so
what is you know the status right so um
there was uh you know some feedback that
was processed uh or actually all the
outstanding feedback was uh processed um
so an operational considerations action
was added again on on under suggestion
of jeff jeff has
um and essentially he was recommending
that you know uh whoever is endorsing
this uh scheme essentially should um you
know make publicly available their
privately defined registries
and uh and there were a number of
editorial comments and things like that
there are open questions like what could
be the scope of ebit right so for so far
the scope is just the tlds but uh of
course the you know you can make private
messages you can make private stats
types and things like that i mean we can
be you know more ambitious than this but
i would say that first of all and that's
the next question whether this is a work
that is relevant for the working group
and whether um
you know uh it would be accepted and the
last time just for an extra context and
with that i'm done uh let's say when i
asked this question there were
a little bit of mixed feeling and then i
wanted to see whether uh
also with that remark that i was making
before about that ebit is also about you
know things that cannot really be
standardized because maybe they are not
really their internal
internal bits are very low level and
maybe do not apply to the wider you know
public the well doesn't make sense to
make a young a good point for that uh
whether that changes anything right
are there any questions from
participants or the room
i see ben
virtually wants to get in the queue and
is now physically moving towards a
microphone
uh
ben madison work online hi paulo
um
so i think this is a generally good idea
and i think that given the overlap from
an implementation perspective that's
likely to exist between bmp and ipfix i
think kind of stealing the the mechanism
is also a good idea
um
question on
uh could you go back to the uh
the packet format slide
um
uh the the one for the enterprise
variant the next one
is it coming
i see
so the
the the private enterprise number field
is that is the idea that that contains
only the private enterprise number or
would that be the private that would
that be some locally significant value
qualified by the private enterprise
number
because not that
no that's that would be just the
enterprise number so depend the public
you know the private private enterprise
number but the type would be the you
know
locally
okay okay i see so the the the the
enterprise number acts as a namespace
scope for the type of field exactly
exactly okay that makes that make sense
that makes sense yes um
so my only my only concern here um
is that this ends up being a way for
vendors to all implement essentially the
same thing
but with their own special name and
syntax and you know various different
ways in which you have to write the same
code 100 times in order to operate a
multi-vendor network
i think that
i think maybe a slightly stronger
recommendation about making a registry
available
possibly in some sort of minimally
machine readable format
might go some way to help alleviate that
but i think you know a a fairly strong
recommendation that this should not be
used other than for you know temporarily
for things that
are likely
even in the distant future to be
standardized would be helpful because we
don't want
you know
a situation where
every vendor in the whole world has got
a separate type for
asparth for example do you know
yeah yeah absolutely absolutely and you
see this is very along
the lines of the feedback that was
provided also
um
in singapore in 2019 and that time who
was uh saying that was actually it was
job it was job right our very and true
job
um and the the my answer back then and
that's uh you know the only thing that i
can answer today is that so first of all
is that yeah we should put in there all
the text possible right
uh we should make this happen because
it's useful and put in there all the
text possible in terms of recommendation
and things like that the second thing is
that we can look at the story of iphix
because fortunately since we are not
inventing anything we can
look at the past and see how that worked
well or not with ipfix and in latifix we
don't see
that happening that they all have the
very same thing
but um
not standardized you see uh there are
things that are certainly remaining
permanent right so uh for example then
not the whole career grid not uh logging
for example it's something it that is
staying into private elements and things
like that but uh
that is probably because there is one
vendor only implementing that or two
vendors only you see so i from the story
of ipfix i feel to be positive that this
mechanism is not abused of course i
don't have the oracle so i don't know
what's going to happen
um and i'm totally willing to do our
part as itf and put in there the whole
world that we should be putting in order
to discourage to
abuse this mechanism
yeah that makes sense
thanks
jeff
uh so
backing up ed's comments uh i pasted a
presentation that i had given the prior
ietf and codepoint management
the the challenge that you usually end
up seeing for this stuff is that uh
it's usually back pressure that you get
from the registry availability so like
the majority of uh
you know bmp's spaces were originally
done under very tight uh requirements uh
the current one is under a specification
required which is
not quite as loose as first come first
serve
and
what we're looking for for
stuff that you'd want to put into
non-enterprise space is
if this is generally useful
make it as easy as possible for people
to be able to publish a specification
and get a code point and just ship their
feature
and you know that said
part of the back pressure that you get
is you know what if you're not sure that
it knows something that's generally
useful
giving the vendors a playground to be
able to do stuff
is a useful thing
uh one of the sort of dangers that's
discussed in the slides is that when you
do these sorts of things
there's always the concern that you know
how stable is the vendor going to make
something if it's their magic number
maybe they're less concerned about
stability than ietf might be and we see
this for incremental deployment of pgp
features is the example that we give in
the slides
so
the enterprise number isn't bad
uh there is a motivation in the bmp
community that if it's generally useful
feature we should be pushing people to
push put the stuff into public spaces
and we're very likely end up seeing that
uh they're could be transitional
scenarios where stuff may show up in an
enterprise field and they stay there
while also manifesting in the more
public versions because long term the
goals people's collectors will want to
gather the information from a common set
of code points and not have to worry
about well where do i get did you say as
path you know for this particular thing
thank you
benoit briefly was in the queue but
somehow disappeared so uh
read his comment out loud he indicates
[Music]
we did not see
concerns in the ipfix ie history
hopefully
so i guess that is a positive sign
towards using pen numbers in context of
vmp
so let me redo it right i want to make
it short but okay let me go to the mic
now so uh benoit class so yes in the
history of ipfix we had the same concern
initially and we have not seen that most
of the people were actually eager to
come
and propose them to ayana
as uh as in high peak information
elements the only one that were not done
in ayanna there were particular reasons
like it was
we would know we could not get consensus
across the industry but these are these
are really corner cases
so it was a concern for us initially and
in the end it was not
thank you
jeff you're still in the queue is
the queue cleared up
um
so the two items paulo
the ebitd thing you said it's in working
group classical and the chairs need to
do work
and for the
the tld not the e-beat
in this presentation you mentioned two
drafts right yes the first one yeah
the first one needs to
complete the working group last call
exactly the second one you propose to
request working group adoption
exactly
all right we will do those action items
thank you very much thank you very much
for your time
thank you paulo
um
next up
is sasha romain
i think i should actually ask you how to
pronounce it in english
i i don't even know how to pronounce it
in english
in that romaine
uh sasha please indicate when you want
me to move to the next slide
and the floor is yours welcome
thank you
my first itf meeting actually
so yeah my name is sasha romain i'm
presenting the draft on the near real
real-time
mirroring protocol version 4
co-authored with job schneiders at
strain and staffers constantires
next slide please
so a little bit of context first uh
energy mp4 is a protocol for ir
mirroring uh as many of you may be aware
but maybe not all the internet routing
registry actually consists of about a
dozen sort of
authoritative registries they have
different
operators different purposes different
scopes
and mirroring exists for these different
uh
registries to be able to mirror data
from each other it's a one-way process
so
for example if someone queries entity
comes
ir server they also see data that has
been mirrored from right and
things like that and also a number of uh
operators run their own local mirrors uh
they don't have authority but they run
their own mirrors for performance
analysis things like that
there are
a few common implementations for for ir
servers there's a few versions of the
right database software out there which
runs uh the registries from rypn c and
ethernet and apnic
there is a legacy version of iard
version 2 and 3 that's currently run by
rdb level 3 ltb few other smaller ones
and there is the
latest ird version 4 which is actively
developed still by me and runs
most of the other larger registries
next slide please
so currently this mirroring is done with
nrtm version 3 and mostly ftp downloads
this is a very poorly specified protocol
uh there's pdf somewhere it's plain text
overall tcp so that's there's no way to
check any kind of integrity or
authenticity
it skills very poorly essentially
there's
it's very difficult to skill at all
there is no status signaling so if you
query a server for
new
changes there is no automated way to for
it to tell you
you don't have access or i don't know
what you're asking or
everything is fine i just don't have any
new data so
there's no way to detect when it breaks
there's also the streaming of new
changes and the ftp downloads that you
initialize with are completely unlinked
basically and you sort of have to hope
that you got the right tool matched up
because there are
many fascinating ways in which nrtm
version 3
can break quietly weirdly
it's actually a major source of support
i give to users of ird version 4.
next slide please
so the new
draft
is
publishing nrtm data publishing the ir
mirroring data on a https endpoint
which
uh creates all the benefits that we have
with with publishing things on hbs which
is a thing we know very well to do
uh
it is inspired by irdb so there are some
similar concepts and names in here
there is a small update notification
file which functions as a
often retrieved index and points to a
snapshot
some deltas usually with changes in them
and the snapshots are periodic they
contain all the records at that time in
the ir database
they are large
and small deltas only contain
changes they are bashed into one minutes
time frames if there were any changes
and all these files are json-based
they'll support utf-8 currently in
energy mp3 and ftp there's no standard
on encoding so all the mirroring is full
of encoding glitches everywhere
the snapshots and deltas themselves are
immutable and they are cacheable
so
that helps with scaling them
and the update notification file itself
is signed the end contains hashes of all
the referred files so this allows
integrity checking
a bit more on that later because there's
still some open ends but the idea is to
offer integrity checking which we are
currently missing
and finally
there's a random session id which has to
match otherwise clients re-initialize
and this basically allows
mirror servers to
force clients to re-initialize which
there's currently no way for so somehow
there are gaps in history clients
silently and
without possibility of detection or
recovery run out of sync and
yeah it's uh
it's bad
next slide please
so for br servers the process is
basically going to be they generate new
session ids i'm obviously skipping over
a lot of uh details here but this is the
broad overview they generate a new
session id generator for snapshot which
sometimes may be empty not typically
a new update notification file publish
that on an endpoint
and then you're running nrtm version 4.
i should note that this is everything in
the protocol is per ir database so ripen
c who publishes ripe and write non-auth
these are totally separate in for nrtm
version 4.
next slide please
for updates uh every minute
where each mirror server will generate
a delta file if there are any changes if
they were a little late if they had
downtime they can catch up but generally
every minute if there were changes and
they are all sequentially numbered so
you can always know that you have a
consistent complete set of delta files
without
gaps
they then generate and sign a new update
notification file
also periodically there's new snapshot
files so that new clients who show up
they need to start with a snapshot file
so that shouldn't be too old
it's not necessarily every change so we
don't generate snapshots every minute
they're too large for that
but the idea is that clients don't start
off too far behind
there's also a regeneration of the
update notification file
even if it hasn't changed which allows
detection of still repositories some iar
databases are
incredibly quiet they have one chains
every few weeks maybe
so this allows to attack like is an ir
server still publishing to this endpoint
or or not
and an important distinction to note
with compared to energy and version 3 is
that we don't
none of the data that is transferred
between servers and clients is different
for clients the mirror server publishes
one set of changes that contains
everything any client needs
next slide please
mirror clients they retrieve the updates
notification file and signature they
verify it if there's data there and the
session id matches uh it's the same
version you're up to date you know and
you don't have to do anything
otherwise the client tries to pull in
the deltas to get to the latest version
if those are
not all present
because probably the client is has run
too far behind
or if the session id has become
different the client will always
reinactivize from the snapshot
automatically retrieve that verify
process it then continue following along
with the deltas again so if clients run
out of sync if there's a new publication
points clients always automatically
recover
next slide please
[Music]
um i won't go through all the fields of
the file in detail that's all in the
draft but this the update notification
file
which
as you can see essentially lists the
current snapshot and the version of that
along with all deltas the the
ir database that this is for and a
timestamp of publication to detect
stillness
next slide please
the snapshot file itself is a
fairly simple contains also session id
version source name so that we know
those are consistent and essentially a
list of objects uh nrtm version 4
intentionally does not go into the
actual syntax of
ir objects
basically because we don't have a
singular syntax of ir objects
so uh yeah that's why they are they're
presented as encoded strings
next slide please
and so finally the delta files are
are similar they list changes so one
delta file can have at least one
possibly many different changes of
deletions
additions modifications to
objects
next slide
of course any point of the draft is open
to discussion but i wanted to highlight
two particular ones
the first is the database configuration
file
as i mentioned the update notification
file is signed and it then contains
hashes of snapshots and the idea here is
that
we provide end-to-end integrity checking
so the ir server that published it all
the way to the ir server that is
processing this there's also hps which
offers transport security for part of
this
but not all of it
the problem of course then becomes how
does a client know which public key to
trust and how do we deal with key
rotation for example
because people will want to rotate their
keys
clients mirror clients don't really sign
up there's not really a single way to
effectively reach them
and so this is uh
we have
a plan for this now in the draft but
this is definitely the most open to
discussion next slide please
so the current approach we've chosen is
to have an additional file the database
configuration file
which contains ir database name like
write private non-public signing key of
the
updates notification file and the url
where those files should be expected and
this file is different from all the
others in that it must be published on a
well-known uri
on what i've called the generally known
authoritative domain
so other files can be published wherever
the operator wants to this one has to be
published on
this particular domain it's also low
traffic
and the idea here is that
if i would say
radb then everyone who is familiar with
the ir system
would agree on the same domain name that
we would all trust to say
where do we
retrieve the update notification file
where do we retrieve nrtm version 3 uh
where is the ftp server
and so to use that as a basis of trust
and allow configuration from there
this is
yeah so this is our approach so far
uh next slide please i only have two
more slides so question maybe at the end
uh another problem is delta expiration
uh because many of our clients will very
closely follow all the deltas that are
being published they retrieved snapshots
the update notification file frequently
download any new deltas they're going to
download a handful at a time
and these are also the ones that we want
to have low latency
so that's why we make them every minute
some clients though are going to lag
behind they're going to be down for a
while connectivity issues anything can
happen
and sometimes they are days weeks
potentially even months behind and
they're going to start up
um
and
with one minute
one delta every minute potentially there
are up to 1440 deltas okay
but for many databases i run some
numbers it's much less more in the order
of hundreds but still significant
next slide please
uh and so the initial idea was uh trim
the delta so that's their size
cumulative is less than a snapshot so
the idea is downloading a gigabyte of
deltas is better than downloading two
gigabytes of snapshot because it's still
less data however ir data based on some
rough
calculation is uh changing too slowly
and so a client that is running three
years behind on ripe would die would
still prefer deltas and would try to
download 250 000 of them which
obviously doesn't scale
so optimizing for size does not work
here next slide please
so the current new plan is uh we expire
fast after 24 hours so anyone who is
more than 24 hours behind has to
reinitialize from the snapshot
upside is this is simple you might still
have
1400 downloads if you're a day behind
although for many databases it would be
less
we feel that it would be a good balance
between allowing catcher preventing
excessive downloads and simplicity also
good to remember is this is all
automatic in nrtm version 3 this is all
manual like an operator has to actively
start the the fresh redownloading
process
another idea we had is delta irrigation
where we aggregate older ones into
larger blocks that are a single download
and can be processed in bulk
it's more optimal it's more complex
personally i don't like it so much
but of course we're also open to other
ideas
next slide please
so
the state is uh
the author of the draft uh ed works on
the database team at ripe ncc and i am
the author and maintainer of ird version
four so the authors we are also the
people who needs to work on
implementation so there's support from
there
uh the right database working group uh
i've also presented
a broad strokes of this in a off session
and that was generally supported so
there's support in other places also for
at least the general concept and ideas
it was posted on the mating list there
hasn't been any feedback yet
and i would like to propose this draft
for working group adoption
and that's it thank you
thank you so much sasha
the reason i invited sasha specifically
to the grow
working group
is that from all the ietf working groups
grow has a history of mingling with irr
related topics
so for instance in end of 2015 we
published rfc 76a2 considerations for
internet routing registries
there has not been
done in the ietf any prior work on nrtm
so nrtm version 3 is a two-page
specification hosted on the the ripe
website
so from that perspective it felt
appropriate to to bring it to this
working group
uh and the chairs will
bring the request to the mailing list to
guard interest
let's go through some questions i see
ben and jeff cued up
hi sasha ben madison from work online um
thank you for working on this it's
really really long overdue um
there are some really confusing topics
that i have to take new recruits through
um and what to do when an rtm version
three breaks is i think probably the
worst of it
um
so it's really nice to see someone who's
actively working on this it looks i
haven't i i i read
a really really early
markdown version of this that i came
across
somewhere
but i haven't read the most recent draft
but i think from what you've described
it sounds like a sane solution to the to
the problem
one thing that i found slightly
confusing is the the term session id
because that seems like it's
used not so much to identify a session
between a server and a particular client
as to identify the base from which a
delta is taken
so it's kind of identifying the current
the current snapshot that's most recent
so i think maybe a change of terminology
there would make that less confusing
um
the
i had one
suggestion about how to deal with the
trust anchor discovery problem um
that's a little bit less hand wavy than
kind of hoping that everybody knows that
rad b is radbeed.net
which is probably true it's probably not
a terrible assumption but it's it's
maybe not very robust
one of the problems
as an operator that mirrors
irr data
is there's not really
a good list of things that one ought to
be mirroring and there's not really a
good list as a consumer of transit
services for example of where am i
which databases can i register my things
in and expect them to be generally
available to anyone who i care about and
that's maybe a that may be a problem we
can solve at the same time as this by
having
um
by having an eye on a registry which is
fairly permissive in terms of its you
know its policies but where people can
actually go and register source names
um and that can then be mapped into the
dns somehow or you know there's a whole
bunch of one once you've got a registry
of unique names like that and there's a
mapping between source and somewhere to
go then a whole bunch of possible
solutions to that problem start
presenting themselves
yeah i i do like the ayana rs3 idea i
think we had it briefly
but then i was thinking like what if i
email ayanna and i say hey i'm i'm ripe
and here's the new key that should be
used for update notification file and
we're hosting it on this domain now
which would also then need some kind of
verification process but i think there
are there are definitely ways to
approach that this is sort of the the
shortened version but
i agree with you also like just in terms
of
what
registries are out there and and like i
sometimes have struggle finding like
what red streaks are out there
so i think the inner registry is uh
interesting
yeah i think that if the if the content
the initial contents of that registry is
bootstrapped in the draft with kind of
you know the databases that are out
there and are a thing
then the you know the the the competing
for the same source name problem
probably doesn't really arise because it
would only be new entrants or much much
smaller databases that come after the
fact
asking for new names
there are not a lot of new irr databases
being stood up in 2022
i'm going to cut the cue after rudiger
folk
ben you have an action item writes an
internet draft defining an ayanna
registry and some procedures around it
that's called featurescope
uh
jeff house
hi this is jeff
sasha i have a question um
last time i worked on this type of
technology was back in 1999 for radb so
things have obviously evolved
significantly past that point and i'm
not aware of them
at that time one of the
problems around the snapshot versus the
incremental
diffs that you get
was a dual tension between
the diffs basically encoding the
transactions that have passed through
the server people were interested in
this for historical and other auditing
reasons
and the intention of being able to
quickly resynchronize when things you
know broke and fell out of sync
this happened especially in those days
quite a bit because the software is
the reliability of the indices let's
just say we're not very good at the time
for the work that you're doing right now
is the intention to try to reduce the
amount of the delta files
based on just strictly
transaction load or is it a desire to
simply
limit the amount of traffic that you're
expecting to see on the servers
um
well traffic on the servers is is
probably not the main concern the the
the
issue here is that if we allow a client
to catch up with delta files after three
years
it'll take forever like the client will
do this automatically it'll find that
all the deltas are still there
but
i don't immediately know of stuff my
head how long it would take but
downloading 250 000 separate files over
http is going to take a while so we are
not serving the client their goal is get
the client up to speeds as fast as
reasonable without excessive
data transfer basically so that's why we
want to place limits
on how
far back a client is allowed to go on
this
okay this is not actually going to help
just downloading a snapshot is going to
be faster at some point
i completely agreed uh one of the other
pieces of the tension was
finding out what version effectively a
given server is running for a given
database was a
non-standardized item has that changed
in the interim
sorry can you repeat the question
so as an example uh the
delta file gives you basically
individual versions so if you're up to
delta 100
you know that this is as far as you
happen to be in sync for this database
um at the time i remember that ird for
redb
did have the ability to tell you what
version it thought it was at for
itself
i don't recall if this actually got
standardized
the motivation is that if i'm running a
local cache
i could actually use that to compare
versus maybe the remote cache
um it it's kind of it's a little bit
standardized like many things in ireland
but
in rtm v4 that would be the snapshot
file so the snapshots
sorry
update notification file so whatever the
update notification file says the latest
version is that's latest version that
was published
there is to catch i suppose that what
the server is running at right this
second could be newer because it might
take up to a minute for a change to be
pushed out
um
okay or is that the kind of gap you're
asking about
i i think that is in the lines of what
i'm asking about if it was the case that
the
manifest file
that's reported
uh is
provided a conventional consistency
because within a minute you'll get the
newest data
that's probably a reasonable thing
if
a fully standardized mechanism to query
the database version number is not
present that might be a thing to spend a
little bit additional standardization
time at because it allows a local cache
mechanism to decide
does it have data that is not fresh
enough for some strange reason
yeah yeah
ird will also offer this because we have
some non-standard queries right now
they become sort of standard partially
once they get implemented in ird version
4 because
there's there's uh right tb is the only
other actively developed implementation
uh but yeah there will be also direct
queries but
yeah the idea is this update
notification file if you compare this to
what your local version has then you'll
know whether or not your mirroring is
running up to date
also we'll be able to actually detect
errors so that will be a big improvement
that if your local mirror cannot update
that it can actually tell you that it
can update rather than producing errors
all the time that may not be actual
errors as you have with version three
the detection of local errors would be
great i remember that at the time a
significant problem during the mirroring
process uh using one of your other
example slides
if you received an object that could not
successfully be parsed locally because
the implementations were different this
led to potential situations where
objects were out of sync
yeah
thank you for your time
i think jeff
in ird version 3 and nrcm version 3 you
refer to the serials to
corrupt the distance between local
locally cached data and what the remote
server has
and in the nrtm version for notification
file
that is called the version
so
i pulled that slide up
you see
version three in nrtm version three
lingo would be serial free okay now
everybody is confused
and again this is because i'm asking
about technology that i've not done the
appropriate homework for commenting on
this presentation in an informed fashion
and uh thank you for educating
next up jarrett's
um i'm looking at the clock a little bit
so please keep the comments brief
yeah so i guess i'm a little bit
concerned about the one minute uh
snapshot requirement is the reason why
it isn't kind of done on demand based on
when there's actually a change
uh
you know or for the uh you know for the
deltas and such because that that seems
like having that always
misunderstanding then snapshots are more
rare because they're very large deltas
are one minute but only if there were
changes if your ir database never
changes the only thing you have to do is
update this update notification file
which is very small just to
sort of clients you know like there's
someone still publishing to this to this
endpoint
yeah no changes means you don't you
don't generate anything
okay and then the second concern i have
is about uh whether or not ayanna is the
right place for there to be a registry
for services that may not exist in the
future because i think many of us have
seen
irr databases come online and go away
over time
and going and sticking it in a registry
seems a lot more permanent than what
actually exists in the operational space
please talk to ben he
will
figure out all those concerns
rudiger
retired backbone engineer
uh
i wanted to jump on europe's remark that
nrtm never had an official standardized
standardized definition
[Music]
at least not ietf
as far as i remember
there has been for quarter of a century
irr
schema definition
done in itf as far as i can tell
no
excess protocol no on the wire protocol
so far as i can tell has ever been
standardized in ietf
and
the existing
de facto registry
does not even include the information
what software is run
by the various registries which is
necessary
for
tuning or selecting your client code for
successfully accessing the stuff
it's not only this
i know it by heart from the time when i
still was working
not not quite sure not quite sure
uh whether this will actually be fixed
uh before the thing is forgotten and uh
replaced by something else and better
yeah i did mention that nrtm never has
been standardized by the ietf
but given the history of ietf
in irr
i felt that nrcm version 4 might be an
uh find an appropriate home here but
we'll discuss this on the mailing list
in the working group call for adoption
the reason the offers
are here is is to make something better
than a two-page pdf hidden on a website
but make a proper document that is easy
to read and understand
sasha thank you so much uh for your
presentation and information
uh i think we are gonna move on to the
last presentation of the grow session
hey hello good to see you
where on this planet are you
i'm in colombia very early okay it's not
too early
so we are
we're in a hurry right or or we are not
tell me uh we're
we started like three minutes late so
we'll end like six minutes late right
perfect so can you go into the next
slide please um
so what we are proposing in this draft
is basically a young module for com for
managing bmp on routers
why not uh
well the idea is to have a standard way
of doing that bmp sounds like a simple
protocol but is it well simple protocol
to configure and manage but is it
let's figure out ourselves while having
these discussions
the next one please
um so what the
model has basically i mean are the items
to configure and monitor vmp on devices
that is
uh well configure your stations the
connectivity for your stations the bmp
session
parameters
um i like to highlight two things that
probably are not so common between the
models of the vendors that at least we
have read
um first is an action to clear the
to clear the session with the bmp
station uh
well that's basically it
and the second part is that we are we
try to be very explicit in
how we configure what we call the
bmp sources um
and that is
we right now have already uh uh five
remotes on bmb the the latest three were
standardized
um just a few months ago
so you have to be explicit on whether to
say you this remote is enabled for the
station then for others families the
same so for every address families you
don't take there's no default you have
to enable every others family
and for the rib modes that are actually
not a single rib but multiple ribs per
pier
then we also would like to be explicit
that is you can def so you you enable
the peers
that you want to send information from
or to
uh explicitly you can select that
individually
so by using the
by reusing the remote address from the
bgp module
uh also by the type also you can define
which peers you want to
to select based on the type of beer uh
here we are also reusing the um the bgp
peer type from the bgpa module
so
you can say
please send me the information from all
the external peers for the internals
and so on
um because we also needed a way of um
of of especially saying we want all
peers that's why we also added uh an
enum with a with a single value called
appears in the vgp mode and the bmp
module in this module
uh that you can use to say okay you'll
send me everything for every year
we probably will discuss this a bit more
in the next iterations of the module
but let's see
next one please
so we already had a good feedback on
this thank you very much for to team
jeffrey and tom for this
um we already addressed some of them
some of the issues uh
mostly the ones from tom that were very
low thinking fruits and some of them
very clear mistakes
in this version that we already uploaded
versions 0.2 i'm not going to go into
the details
uh next one please
yeah
so we do have some some pending points
um that we promised to tackle in the
next version
uh tim mentioned the vmp session options
initialization delay backup times
uh
we will actually re
take a look again to all the modules
from the vendors that for
for configuring bmp
and see what else we might be missing
to try to add them
um
jeffrey mentioned the tcp module that is
um that is um i mean we can really
leverage that module to try to
another invent the wheel uh how to use
it we're really not sure that for
instance we could actually copy the four
the four um the four tuple
uh connection from there
uh it's not in a grouping so maybe we
can just copy it or i don't know or
we'll see how we can integrate it and
maybe
and then we can discuss it all together
units for stats where to place the
module in the routing tree uh this can
be important so we so if we for instance
uh we put in under network instance then
we can you know we can use the we can
directly
um
we can directly monitor those the
network instance from there or we can
put the network instance in a bmp source
so where to place the model the module
the model is um
it's a good question to have and of
course adding examples to
i mean to enlighten
these trade-offs
uh next one please john
so this is it uh
well grove works on the vmp and we have
been working in the last few years about
this so i think it makes sense to have
this draft in the group
but i also let you guys discuss that
besides that if you guys have any other
questions or comments guys and girls
[Music]
thank you um
jeff has you're up first
uh so yes i absolutely think we should
adopt this i agree that there's gonna be
a little bit of churn as we figure out
how do we actually monitor the various
address families
within networking it's going to be i
think when we're modeling challenges
we're actually going through a similar
effort through that in my employer right
now jennifer
the second item is about the tcp
integration
partially what being discussed here is
do you want to actually do something
model the connection is something that
is a little copy and paste
in a lot of cases that can make sense
many other cases
part of the reason to point you towards
the
tcp module
and potentially longer term discussion
towards the itf key chain module
is you'll want to figure out how
authentication actually rolls into this
so if you're running like tcp ao or tls
or something else similar for the
sessions
you'll want to model that not only for
configuration purposes but you know what
your operational state is for that
that's it thank you
and i agree with jeffrey
next up
yeah i think this is a useful work uh
really
helpful for the
configuration of the bmp
uh my uh brief comment is that uh it is
better to consider
the alignment with the the pgp model
like the
uh maybe it is first based on the
instance and then peers and ribs
follow the
because that
user of the bmp young will be
also the users for the bgp models so
that the alignment between these two
models will be very helpful
second one is also
based on the young model
design in the bjp model it may
reduce the amount of configurations in
some circum circumstances but for each
uh
rape you may
need to with this current model you may
need to configure the different peers
for different ribs but with
if you follow the b2pm model style you
can
configure the peer then the rib and
rebound can
just
follow it under the peer model
that is uh yeah
for some more detailed comments we can
maybe have some further discussion of
flying
thank you
thank you and and our purpose here is to
to reuse the
bgp module as much as possible i mean we
try maybe we are missing some we're
having some gaps but there is yeah so
indeed address families and peers
and even peer types are right now
reference than the vgp module when when
we find a location into the into the
routing tree we might be even be able to
make it more direct
yeah
but that's that's the day okay
thanks
thank you
um
all right so the to-do item for the
chairs appears to be to issue a call for
working group adoption uh this would be
i think the first time the grow working
group has any involvement with
yang
so there there might be a bit of a
learning curve for some of us at least
for for me myself
but together we are strong
um
john thank you so much for this
presentation
and
this concludes the grow
session at iatf 113 i hope to see all of
you at iatf 114 in philadelphia
and a
big thank you to the meat echo team i
have to say this has been the smoothest
running hybrid
session i have been part of so
folks behind the camera thank you very
much
um
well go enjoy your break and see you
next time
thank you
i'll do that