okay
okay folks uh
sorry for the delay
thank you very much for coming to the
host tech talk this is shipping seo from
huawei
um
there are a million ipv6 talks right so
i first want to answer the question why
you should also listen to this one
and the reason is that
that
i think that most ipv6 talks are given
by ipv6 supporters
and usually the ipv6 supporters only
tell you the good thing about ipv6
and i think that what's unique in
today's presentation
is that we are going to talk about a lot
of the challenges
facing ipv6
and the reason why i feel that this is
important and useful
is that
just like you know nobody is perfect no
technology is perfect you know every
technology have certain problems
and in order to get all the people on
board
to deploy ipv6 we really need to
acknowledge the challenges certain
challenges facing ipv6 document the
challenges um
possibly provide a guideline and i think
that eric linker kind of like set a good
example for us in rfc 1999
because i've seen 1999 basically
document all the ipv6 security excels
and provide guidelines this way you know
people
feel more confident like oh you know
ietf no other issues and you know they
are solving this is actually you know
provide more confidence not less
confidence
so with that um
[Music]
i really want to say that we spent a lot
of time presenting uh preparing for
these
uh presentations and a lot of people
providing a lot of uh
you know either statistics or provide a
local review and the list is long and
here i really again want to thank eric
binker because he provided a lot of you
know very detailed feedbacks
so
the first part is the momentum um
while this is both for the ipv6
supporters and the ipv6 deniers and by
ipv69 i really have no pixel respect you
know just an easier name to to refer to
the camp
i know that the ipv6
for example in the nano
in the nano mailing leaks there was a
big debate this month
about ipv6 and
some people are complaining that our
ipv6 is not easy to deploy there's no
user demand etc
one will acknowledge that later here we
want to say that you know for many of
these
are you aware of the ipv6 progress
in recent years because 10 years ago if
you are consuming ipv6 you are more or
less justified because at that time
there's almost zero ipv6 users
but now
according to these google stats we
already have 36 percent ipv6 user
um some people argue that actually
due to the way google called the users
many ipv6 users in china are actually
mixed
so if you count e also the users in
china it could be as high as 45 percent
based on etsi started
but
while ipv6 go very fast
the
it's very uneven and this will have a
major implication later that we will
talk about so what's driving these ipv6
momentums
according to jeff houston this is you
know the gdp per capita you know which
country usually are more enthusiastic in
doing ipv6 the user grows like a
reliance on the ipb for authorities
and also the competition
but it's not just this it's not just
this and here we would like to offer our
perspective
other you know strong momentum on ipv6
the first one is that we believe that
the
loyaltineness
of
ipv6 value chain is something very
important because
the ue's the network and the application
trend
is finally ready
because 10 years ago if you know some of
these the content are not already then
even if operators deploy ipv6 you are
not going to get much benefit but now
it's very different
and here we list some of the major
milestones but the slide is busy so you
don't need to read that all i want you
to know is that
it's summarized in these two blue bars
by 2011 ietf lastly you get the
solution ready
um by 2017
the ues the ues and the big application
like you know google netflix are already
and this year we believe that there is
another important milestone that many
people may not realize yet is the public
cloud support of ipv6 like as
aws these are important we will talk
about why you know this is this may be
quite significant
and then on the value trend
we are seeing that the network
is still slightly behind the ue um
the
content
and if you are interested i will not go
into detail if you are interested even
later we can discuss why another network
is 42 percent how we're computing that
is that
um another point is that
i don't know whether the ipv6 the denier
realized that the price of ipv4 is going
up so quickly and specifically the price
doubled last year
and if you call it long 2014
it already increased seven times
so if you the world on ipv4 you may have
to spend a lot more money if you have to
buy ip
default address or for some operator
they are even considering you know going
to ipv6 quickly and while ipv4 you know
price is very high they can sell their
ipv4 address this is important one
and then the public ipv6 wait this is
the kind of the other momentum that we
saw
um
one is this
just now we mentioned that aws ages
support
of ipv6 why we believe that this is uh
maybe very important
we when we look at the operators you
know the big operating six terms the
small and medium enterprise
we find that small and medium enterprise
have the least motivation
to move to ipv6
because they they have a very you know
they don't need mainly address
and also they may not have the technical
expertise to make the move
so usually you know we if we look at the
sme you know there's a huge number of
sme they're simply in ipv4 but we
believe that when these you know aws as
when they support ipv6 and as the you
know
sme go to the cloud you know uh aws may
enable them to move to ipv6 very quickly
in the past they may have to do a lot of
work themselves but now they simply
select ipv4 or ipv6 and if they select
ipv6 they go ipv6 so we may
know today in the v6
working group that discussion will
you know how to move the sme and we
believe that this may be
a very big momentum and then on the iot
you probably see the number already
there's a lot of iot device
then 5g
bring new beo a new opportunity and then
obviously there's these innovations on
top of ip
v6 srb6 and other things provide better
traffic engineering network programming
etc
so
for the people who don't believe in ipv6
i think
we really want to
these are some of the recent progress
not to mention the for example the big
government proves even though u.s
government is pushing towards ipv6
chinese government is fixing but i guess
maybe ietf people don't want government
regulation so i avoid them here
and the second part i think the first
part is more to the ipv69
and the second part is more to the ipv6
supporters
and here what we want to say is that for
the ipv6 supporters
there
there really are more challenges than
you think because you know we as the the
supporters sometimes we feel that oh you
know
our work ietf work is done you know
these people are not doing ipv6 just
because of the lack of the
motivation or because they are they are
saying all kinds of skills you know i am
completely ready and what i want to say
here is that yeah we are we are quite
ready but not completely and let's see
so first this is a
survey from every nic it's done in 2017.
you can say that oh 2017 maybe too old
but actually you know based on what i
hear from other industry forum if i
compare it to some of the ipv6
challenges in
in december last year
it didn't change that much and really uh
here i think it may be difficult for you
to to see
uh other things but i just want to
kind of like quickly classify them
into four categories one is motivation i
think that for ipv6 this motivation is
always one of the biggest uh xu
okay you know my end user don't care
about ipv6 it's a lot of work so you
know why supply so things like this and
then knowledge is also a big part you
know okay you know i don't understand
ipv6 there's so many new protocols
it's difficult so i think the big car
ecosystem is the value train that we
talked about the ues you know is my
that's my cp support ipv6 and the
network the routers etc
and then technology is what's closely
related to ietf that we will focus on
today
so regarding this motivation knowledge i
think that you know these uh slides look
a little
deeper
i think that maybe
we focus on the the more technical part
is the technology is the technology so
that the legacy device
is the ipv6 the network management
system i think generally this is a field
that you know ipv6 network management
compared to ipv4
i think that you know there's still
some work to do and the oam also may be
not as mature these are some of the you
know common complaints from the field
but we want to say that yes
these are issues but you know
the industry largely you know taking uh
action to
to deal with them so regarding the
motivation and knowledge you know
leading operators are selling that
experience and then you know there's
many ipv6 forums councils
i think as far as i know the uk ipv6
council is is
especially you know active and they're
doing a lot of book work
and then for the
ecosystem i think they will so clearly
thank you know
google amazon i think microsoft
they really did a lot of work at all
they really did a lot of work to move
the industry towards
ipv6 and for the last part for the last
part we are going to talk about the
technical challenge i think that it's
the focus of our
presentation today
so uh before we talk about the bad
things uh first let's uh
let's say that you know ietf has done a
lot so you know this is not to to
complain this is not to to complain but
even though that we have done a lot i
think that there are remaining
challenges remaining challenges
um
so the first one i think that you know
to compare the ipv6 performance versus
ipv4
uh may be uh very relevant and more
telling because between ipv6 and ipv4
there are so many things that you can
compare there's so many things that you
can compare for example neighbor
discovery is very different from app but
we believe that you know performance is
really the
very important or maybe the most
important you know
kpi so
the first one is regarding the raw chip
time
the latency
so as you can see okay you can see here
over the years the
the
ipv6 road trip time
is you know constantly improving it's
constantly improving
but today it's the old you know 2.5
millisecond higher than ipv4
than ipv4 but this is what average this
is whatever right you know later i will
provide you know kind of like the
the the grain of salt on my own you know
uh this data and again this is based on
jeff houston's status in ap nics
there are you know in the industry there
are some other statistics
like linker that all have some statics
right ncc have statics etc
but we or at least i personally believe
that maybe ap nix data is more
systematic so we are
so i think that the first is that you
know ipv6 and ipv4 is very very close
but it's slightly higher on a worldwide
average scale
so uh i think a very good question to us
here is that what are the top three
factors leading to this improvement why
you know over the years why this is
improving and if we understand what are
contributing to this improvement then i
think that you know we can provide a
guideline for other operators that oh
you know do this from day one
then you know you can you can you know
avoid
certain things
so this is the
logic time the second one is the packet
loss
rate
and we find that the data here is really
inconclusive
we provide you know two data points here
the first one is from this uh hindavi um
it reported ipv6 plr actually uh lower
than uh ipv4
and this is they they did the management
based on one way of management from
from china
and it says that you know for them they
find out that ipv6
packet loss rate is 0.25 percent
um for ipv4 is 0.33
so ipv6 performs slightly better they
also have some you know distribution
so in the asia is is much better it's
all clearly better
ipv6 and ipv4 and for other regions they
are more or less seeming more or less
similar
and then we also
that's one data point on one angle and
then on the right hand side
we are seeing kind of like a different
result so here we are citing you know
rfc 7872
by i think by fernando by zhang lincoln
here and now i think recently uh
eric winker also have the so-called jerk
james
talking about some new management on
on these like uh extension headers
but
uh the the long story short the result
is that you know in 2017
the packing loss rate for for the
plastic waste fragmentation extremely
high 21 percent and even last year it's
still eight percent it improves a lot
but it's still very high
um because we heard from many operators
we heard from many operators like their
ipv for
packet loss rate or their packet loss
rate is about 0.1 percent and we take it
as ipv4 because mainly most traffic is
still ipv4
um but you know there's really i think
that we find in the industry but there
is no data on ipv6 packet glossary or at
least ap nic didn't provide
so if anybody have this data we would
love to hear from you
so if we take it from the the first
study at
02.5 percent then ipv6 is uh higher than
ipd4 but again this is inconclusive
um we
we we don't know uh
how much of this overall
packet loss rate is coming from those
fragmentation extinction headers etc we
believe that this would be uh you know
something good to to find out
um
we we
we really feel that you know if we can
dig into this and find out why you know
ipv6 is losing package etc again this
would help
will help
to to improve the performance and make
the the life of those deployer a little
easier
and the third one is the tcp failure rig
again we can see that the the blue one
the green one is ipv6 and then the other
is v4 we can see that over time
the
ipv6 tcp failure rate is like again
constantly improving
but i think that based on the data uh
today
ap nick it's still you know 0.96 percent
and ipv4 you know depending on how you
look like it may be like
0.25 percent or
some people jeff houston said oh it's
almost like zero percent so you know
ipv4 is almost
successful but anyhow i think that the
conclusion is the same
tcp failure
ipv6 is higher
so
the question is that is it because of
the higher packet loss really
of ipv6 i think that this certainly you
know if you have a higher ipv6
plr it's quite likely that the tcp
failure rate will also be higher
and then because quick is using more and
more
in addition to bill to measuring tcp
failure
we also be measuring quick as well
so i think that these are some of the
good questions
um
okay you know me as a supporter
ipv6 supporter talking about ipv6
challenges here and some people say that
oh they they may be concerned that okay
you know i come to the conclusion that
we shouldn't do ipv6 and i want to tell
you that this is not the case because
again
that just now what we're presenting is
the worldwide average
whatever it can
you know the average can hide a lot of
things can hide a lot of things and if
we look at the data you know more
carefully we will see that you know the
world average can be jerked out by a
region badly and again this is the same
steps from ap nick
you'll see that you know
the whole world
uh the rtt of uh ipv6 is slightly higher
but it's largely you know because of you
know swing me
and if you look at the world you know
american and europe actually you know
ipv6 perform better than ipv4
so i i really feel that these data are
useful for
for communicating with the ipv6 deniers
you know when they say that oh it's bad
you can you you you have the stats to to
tell them what uh if you look deeper
what's the case
and also there are reports that
ipv6 can perform better in
enterprises for example we provide two
references here you know
apple at one place is claiming that you
know ipv6 can be you know 40 percent
better
in the in the data center again you know
we provided the reference here you can
check out and facebook is also very
enthusiastic in in
promoting ipv6 so i think the point here
our real point our real point here is
that
ipv6 can perform better than ipv4
if
if you you have a lot of talent if you
can do it you know correctly but it's
not always easy this is this is a
complicated machine and if you install
it you know
correctly you operate it correctly then
you perform better than uh
ipv4 but because it's due to its
complexity
you may make mistakes and if you make
mistakes then it don't work uh take work
so i think that this is the concern that
we want to want to provide
um
as a consequence i think that this is
also another thing that i find
as a big surprise to me last year and it
may actually be a big surprise to many
ipv6 bathrooms
is that
many operators
uh ipv6 deployment are actually in
overlay and in the underlay in the
router et cetera they're actually
tunneling ipv6 in nprs etc
so you know when the operator tells you
that oh i do deal stack
you think that you know their routers
are transporting ipv6 traffic natively
you think that their underlay is also
dual stack but that may not be the case
that may not be the case this is a big
surprise for me
last year so first of all let's uh let
me clarify what's overlay and what
underlay i think this is this is a
notion it's applicable to operators and
to some extent also applicable to
data center but it's not applicable to
for enterprise if you are not providing
a cervix to other people you really
don't have this like distinction between
overlay and underlay but any household
operator
overlay is the service layer and it
involved the the user device
and also the mobile gateway or bng or
etc this is your your kind of like your
service layer and then underlays your
routers etc is the the the to send the
send the package
um
because ipv6 is i think the the number
one uh
reason is to address this
address sorted you know to provide
enough address and if to do that then
ipv6 the overlay is sufficient
it's sufficient and why operators don't
want to you know many operators
don't do
native ipv b6 packaging talk is because
if your router is still stacked
really deals that then you need a
a control plane management claim data
playing for ipv4 you have need a
separate play
for ipv6
however if you just tunnel ipv6 packet
inside ipv4 then you only need a single
you know data and controller management
click so many operators feel that okay
you know
actually it will be easier for me to
maintain just one per plane then two
separate play and there are many of them
are using 6pe set
so
uh some of the ipv6 veterans thought
that
operators ipv6 is largely down but this
is really not the case first there are
many big operators still doing ipv4 and
even for those already deployed ipv6
that ipv6 may still just in the overlay
not much in the underlay so this is
again you know back to the question that
we need to make ipv6 perform better we
need to identify the challenges and make
ipv6 perform better than ipv4 otherwise
otherwise you know there are still a big
part of operator network playing
remaining
you know there are there are many
consequences
so here uh
how to
make ipv6 perform better than ipv4
there are these answers the first two
came from jeff houston
the first two point that came from jeff
houston he actually have three points
but i had to delete one point because
you know that could receive a lot of
protest the deleted point is that he
said that you should avoid stateful
ipv4 to ipv6 transition
and then
kind of like you know is clued for
example four four six four x lab
etcetera i'll receive a lot of you know
protests from that point so you know in
the end i delete it
um
there are other points the the next five
points you know below the below the the
white space the the other six points are
the five points are you know based on
our analysis first is move content
closer to end user this will improve
both ipv4 performance and ipv6
performance but there are data showing
that you know the improvement for ipv6
is actually
uh bigger than for ipv4 so if it
close the gap or even you know
change the change the wind
there are some explanations and but we
don't have the time to go into detail
why this is the case
increase link mpu if you can and change
the choose the tcp mss these are all to
avoid trying to avoid fragmentation
because of fragmentation if it happened
the ego ego caused very high packet loss
rate and then there's this like
announcing ipv6 routes and a lot
filtering and jeff houston provided some
example that you know if you don't do it
you basically provide for example that
between australia and singapore ipv4 is
australia to singapore directly back to
to australia but for ipv6 pakistan
australia to singapore to germany to us
and then back to australia then
obviously you're going to have a lot
higher uh
roadship delay and possibly a packet
loss and then there's this package
filtering
i would say that here we provide some
some references some references
but
more work probably need to be done or at
least even should you know discuss and
document these challenges and then
provide guidelines provide a guideline
on all of these you know what can make
ipv6
better
so this is the second part and the third
part is looking forward as we said
if you look at the world average it
seems like ipv6 seems to be a little
worse but if you look at you know deeper
actually
as we say if you do ipv6 correctly ipv6
can perform better than ipv4 just like
in america and in europe
so
if we look at the the world today i know
that this is a busy slide and you will
not be able to tell the company or read
the small numbers i think that there are
only two impressions that i want to get
want you to get from this slide first is
that there are many companies with very
high ipv6
user percentage already
starting from the you know the top one
is 100 ipv6 and even the bottom one is
still like 57
it's still 57
um as we said
these are companies that do ipv6
correctly and benefit from it
[Music]
they can already move to ipv6 only they
can already to move to ipv6 only and
brian carpenter told me that you know
every time you talk about ipv6 only you
should immediately say that ipv4 as a
service over ipv6 because otherwise
people will say that oh this guy is a
lyrical how how how can you be you know
ipv4 will stay for many many years they
thought that ipv6 only means that no
ipv4 but it's not the case it just means
that you know ipv4 will be long as a
cervix over ipv6 but it will disappear
from the infrastructure
layer so it's the the time to to do so
and here you know will be a little bit
more specific
so at least from operator perspective
you know facebook already done it i
think that the hyper scale
the hyper skill have a lot of talent
they probably have you know the best
talent in the industry and they have no
problem you know they can they they
they they can do uh whatever
but for some operators it may not be so
clear so we're kind of like you know
draw some picture
um i think like the mobile one we kind
of like use four six four excellent as
an example and the first one is a little
bit like a
you know
quite dislike or you know one of those
solutions but the the real difference is
i think ipv6 only at the moment in the
industry
for some people it doesn't mean the ipv4
as a cervix again you know it's just in
the overlay and here we want to make
sure that you know by ipv6 only we not
only mean overlay we really mean you
know underlay and the ipv4
the packet will be tunneling inside ipv6
will be finally inside ipv6 we believe
that this will further improve
the performance of ipv6 and make it
better than ipv4
so this is
largely the the the kind of like
the last slide before sung murray is
that
way
the difference between these one and the
ipv6 overlaid is that we believe that
you know the if you do do the today's
way ipv6 overlay plus ipv4 underlay you
are basically you you have no exit
strategy
because you your underlay is stuck even
though that your ipv6 traffic is
increasing but you know you you don't
change your underlay and
you always have you know two protocols
but even though if you tunnel your ipv6
traffic ipv4 over ipv6 because ipv4 is
is
becoming a smaller and smaller
percentage then you know one day you can
finally just purely ipe
purely ipv6 and really this requires
solving some of the challenges that we
talked about in this
uh presentation
um
[Music]
really we need the help of ietf and the
leading operators we really need first
we need to document all the challenges
and provide a guideline
so this brings me to the summary again
we want to emphasize with our feelings
it's like a sophisticated machine only
if you can install and operate it well
it will be better than ipv4 otherwise it
can be worse then it can be worse than
ipv4 and in this aspect we really need
you know ietf to kind of like provide
kind of like better user guideline to
make sure that you know uh people
will have a higher chance of you know
install and operate it
correctly
um
these if we do this then we can we can
you know accelerate uh move to ipv6 and
ipv6 only and here we will specifically
list some topics
that we hope to get your contribution
i i will pause here let you
a few seconds to read it
i also provide my contact information
so we love to to hear from you
thank you very much
[Applause]
i think you don't usually get
a approach in ietf so i feel really
honored
any any questions comments
in the queue
whoever is the first so
rajiv do you want to speak
uh i hope you guys can hear me
so i have a question
um
you talked about uh there having been
some work done to measure the
performance improvements
um and that performance improvement for
ipv6 being larger than the performance
improvement for ipv4 when you
talk about uh dealing with keep edge or
deep in the network deployed content key
so i was just wondering if you have any
study or
reference material that i can look at
uh you know because that is an area of
great interest for me and the
organization that i work for
and uh we'd love to we're already kind
of
semi-dual stack but we deploy in a lot
of networks which are
till to this day
large uh you know consumer facing isps
that are ipv4 only so we'd love to be
able to show some statistics and you
know try to help move the needle with
these um you know medium mid-sized isps
who you know i have just not got onto
the ipv6 bandwagon yet
uh okay i i think the way should
probably you know take this discussion
offline because
uh it will it one is it will take a lot
of time and the second you know i cannot
remember you know all the
other you know the the the reference so
i can send you the reference afterwards
i i will definitely email you and we'll
we'll take this up
offline but then um you know it it this
is a very interesting data point to have
because we as service providers who are
going into these deep network locations
we would love to have some uh you know
ammunition so that when we go to these
providers who are reluctant to
you know
embrace ipv6 we have something that we
can show them and say it's in your
interest to do this even though uh you
know you don't mean you may not see a
pressing commercial need to do it right
now but hey here's a case for a
performance improvement for your
customers that should
you know help you make the decision to
go ahead and do this
okay thank you rajiv
uh
journaling over google as an enterprise
operator who spent some time operating
dual stack and v6 only network
i have an impression that in my
experience every single case when you
see v6 performance worse than before
is because of happy eyeballs
because v6 network is broken nobody
monitoring kid because of happy eyeballs
users are not complaining and it stays
like that until you turn off ipv4
so i'm quite sure it's not something in
the protocol not something in the
connectivity it's just bad operational
practices
okay yes i think that's that's kind of
what we are saying that you know the
machine itself is fine but you know if
you don't operate it correctly
then it has problems
hi this is barry lieber
can you go back to the slide where you
show the performance differences in
different regions
and i'm curious on that yeah the just
you just passed it now go back the other
way
next one
that one um
do you have any sense of why oceania is
so bad compared with the other regions
um
i
i don't okay because
i think that you know this is a slide
that i newly add and i today i went to
the the ap unique data and copy this i
think that this but i think that it's a
good question that we can probably
discuss together with jeff houston okay
thanks
hi mike ackerman first off i want to say
that you covered a lot of information
this is really good stuff i hope you'll
come back and do it again it's almost
inspirational thank you um
the
first question i want to ask maybe
somebody already did can we get copies
of your slides yes fantastic
uh and then i just wanted to ask one
specific question i got your email i got
a whole bunch more so beware um
you had a slide that said and it's right
up there it's uh
that ipv6 performs better in enterprises
i'm one of those can you is there a
short answer as to why or how
uh
we
see it in this uh
for example let me let me take facebook
as an example you know facebook
we provide here you know this
link to a youtube video
in this youtube video i believe that the
person's name is taught
well it's a
facebook person talking about
ipv6 his ipv6 performance is better than
it before i i remember using a nano
meeting or in some kind of meeting and
then there are people
from the audience
ask the same question that you just
asked yeah we want to know that those
people
i think that you know uh they provide
some kind of i i will not say that it's
it's a very direct answer they say well
for example if you do ipv6 then you have
no net
but really
nat
will introduce only a very small
difference
so ipv6 is better is it really because
of net or because of some other reasons
we didn't get a a very clear answer from
that uh youtube video i think we have
the reference okay yeah yeah
you can you can take a look
hoping there was some great generic
answer but it could be application or
situational specific and that that's
certainly understandable but yes we
actually we really i think like these
are the questions that we should dig
into and this is why we are doing this
and actually maybe maybe jane also you
know have some comments do you
google network do you feel that ipv6
performed better or you know if it
performs better why i definitely wrote
down what she just said that when you
get to ipv6 only and that makes a lot of
sense you can see where the economies of
scale will start to add up and give you
better performance maybe even
holistically so
i'm just looking for any answers
anywhere i can get it and this was great
thank you again
thank you
so we are already
5 30
and if there are no more questions i
really want to
what did you have another question
very quick question
if it's not too late
yeah so this is again relating to the
difference um so while
in this table you're kind of showing the
average uh difference in the rtts uh and
and yes based on these numbers uh looks
like it's a massive outlier with a much
larger average but uh i probably am not
as surprised by that because it's quite
likely
that the
overall total rtt average for
connections in oceania are probably
going to be a whole lot higher because
of the fact that it has very limited uh
capabilities of serving traffic locally
and most traffic originating from there
is reaching out to some other region of
the world
in order to get served which is not the
case with maybe uh america's uh or
europe or for that matter even asia
because a lot of that traffic will be
within the region
okay so a lot of asia is going to be
served out of china or india or
singapore and you know doesn't really
have to go outside the region so when
the total
uh
connection rtts are
in the range of 40 or 50 milliseconds
their 10 percent difference turns out to
be 4 milliseconds perfect with oceania
if they're if the average of their
connections are mostly going
to be in the 300 and 400 millisecond rtt
rate because they're all going outside
of the oceania region to get served a 10
differential in performance would still
look like a very big difference over
here so i'm my question is have you
looked at that as a data point
while doing this analysis
uh
the the answer is no as i said you know
this slide i added today you know upon
the request of a colleague but i i can
offer uh
uh observation is that you know if you
know jeff houston how he how he collects
his statistics he's basically partnering
with google and you know
uh
putting a kind of like an ad on the you
know chrome browser and then this chrome
browser will contact his you know he's
he's a prober let's say and then um
because this is sinkholding this is
stinkling so i
do the the observation that you know
at different time these can you know for
example tomorrow if you go to you know
jeff houston's side and then take
another snapshot the number can be quite
different
so i think that this is this is point
number one this you cannot definitely
not uh you know draw a conclusion that
you know oceania is always is always bad
so again you know all of these you know
uh
every statistics you must also look at
you know kind of like take it with a
grain of salt with a grain of salt you
know
really tomorrow we when we look at the
the one and just now when you talk about
the
the maybe you know osuni is far away
from content but again we are here we
are talking about the difference between
ipv4 and ipv6 and the long distance you
know is a burden for both ipv4 and ipv6
so arguably you know it shouldn't create
a lot of difference but other than that
really i'm sorry you know
i
i i really feel that that for ipv6
performance
uh
there are
a lot of analysis is worth doing because
we really you know know i would say that
we know very little um if we we just
support ipv6 and we don't face these
challenges
they will not just go away so i think
this is why you know i i like to do this
talk and kind of like expose these
challenges and so that you know we can
you know do something together
thank you that was very informative
well
let me thank all of you very much for
spending the afternoon with us i really
appreciate it and you got my contact
information
we really love to to hear from you
so
again bye now
thank you so much
you