who's live
so
yes
uh
foreign
oh
thank you
so
ah hopes to unmute
how about now you're good
it's very low in the room
the audio
try to speak a bit see if it's sure okay
i will talk louder and like the rest of
the house that's fine between
how about now is this better
yes it's very good
okay anyway
all right shall we get started do you
want to wait a couple more minutes
i'm ready whenever you are
francesca all right
i'll be doing the slides daryl will be
doing the content franchesca
is our local rep
okay
uh welcome to
the http api
um by now
you should be
many people will be familiar with
um
the eye chart here
no well
it is a set of references to
intellectual property
harassment online conduct and so on
if you haven't read it
when you signed up you should have
gotten a pointer to it so we'll assume
everybody has read it please be nice
respectful and
professional and kind to each other
in case you haven't learned this meeting
is being recorded
the tips by now or we only have a day
and a half left
everybody should be
signed in via meet echo apparently there
is a
qr code you can sign in if you're one of
the dozen or so people in the room
links some other resources
and
late in the week this should not be new
information
although i guess our group is a little
different in that we have people who are
not
full
regular ietf attendees
so
it might be useful
this is all in the
chair slides file
in the
github repository it's also on the data
tracker
agenda
okay so first part administration
uh we need one or two people to
volunteer to take minutes
that can be done in the
uh
code emd hedge dock
do we have any volunteers
i will also be online doing it
oh
you have to sign in
which i'm about to do anybody else
we got martin and mark in the chat
volunteering
great thank you people yeah when you're
showing slides you can't
see stuff
great thank you gentlemen
all right
uh we have some
presentation
of any other changes to the rest of the
agenda people want to talk about
we have presentations on
current documents
uh some status updates
and then there's a couple of proposals
to bring new documents into the working
group
uh
darryl mark francesca and i talked about
increasing the bandwidth of the group
since we seem to have
our feet
under us we know what we're doing
uh even if it is
at times frustrating for some of the
authors we'll talk to that
and then finally any other business uh
twitter bot if there's time daryl could
show the github project board
which is very impressive
anybody have anything else they'd like
to put on the agenda
okay
that's it on the chair slides
which freezo you want me to bring up
next
well probably a good idea just to go in
the order uh so if we start with the
right limit headers
okay
roberto are you
ready
hi everybody
yes oh
we will start with the http api red
limit
can i show the screen
your slide deck
i have the slides if you want to share
the screen
whichever you prefer
uh happy to let you do it we'll
request to share the screen i will stop
so
so red limit headers we
made um we're already done uh we're
almost done with this uh
specification
there have been some changes
well the goal of the
of this specification is to communicate
service limits so clients cannot stop
before being throttled out
can stop before being traveled out
align
all the already existing red limit
headers so we are not inventing
anything new
we are just trying to
standardize something that is already
existing our or an already existing
practice and
we want to express
multiple rate limiting policies
so
we want to stop header proliferation
we are
the current setup is that
we have three
fields
the red limit limit that is a structured
field list now
uh as red limit remaining and red limit
reset data structure
structure fields uh integrals
one providing the number of units
remaining to be consumed and the last
one are delta seconds just light
recreate
so this is the current setup with
structure fields before
the
that are were implemented in this
version
so we have three integrals varied items
and then
in the case of red limit limit
we have
optional values
conveying
the quarter
so the technical choices are to support
only delta seconds just like we try
after
this avoids issues with with ntp skew
and adjustment issues and now we support
structure fields
there is a flexible semantic and we
don't mention infrastructure concepts
like connection
changes from the version were the
now we are using structure fields
this may need some editorial work uh to
align with the
latest
way of expressing
structure fields the latest pros
that is going to be used in
http
extensions documents
we
resolve the field dependencies
so after a long discussion we state that
rate limit limit and reset are required
while red limited remaining is
recommended
and we fix another issue saying that
protein scope is eventually delegated to
uh parameters
that can be further registered in a yana
table i am a table
martin
the fact that those fields are required
means that if you want to be
interoperable
with respect to this specification
you
always need to
reply with those fields
so we are not saying that
all http server must implement this
specification but if you implement this
specification
since the goal is interoperability
between servers and client clients will
expect
those fields to be present
to
enable actions
so
of an issue needing input
the first is we had some uh
requests
from users to separate quota policies
from experiment limits
and
me and alex the other editor
are supportive of
of these changes
this because some implementers say
that they prefer to
separate those information
because it's much simpler to implement
the the behavior
the arrow is pretty er should be
credited
to
lucas
perdue
that
invented this
is arrow
uh
the upper uh the second of an issue is
do we want to define an upper bound for
it limit reset
or not since it's a delta second
maybe we could suggest to implementer
that if they receive a
incredibly huge number
on this red limit reset
probably
[Music]
they shouldn't wait
all that time
and
maybe the
those red limit research should be
either ignored or interpreted in another
way
and there was a
last of an issue about field names
uh
[Music]
we me and alex discussed this a lot
alex
is one of the editors and
is one of the
leading engineer from the redox
api gateway
that implements with kong and then by
proxy
this specification
and
the
our um
opinion is that
we shouldn't
modify the field names because we
adopted field names that were very
similar to the one
api gateways are using now
and we think
that
we should stick with those names
because those names are
something that is already used
well to split quarter policies means
that instead of having a
i'm moving on but um
so the quota policies now is that the
rate limit limit is a
a structure field list
while we've been asked to have two
fields
one
with red limit limit that is
only that only contains the first
field of the list the expiring limit and
the second one contain containing all
the other uh
um
quota policy
uh
information
we have been suggested that this is
easier to parse about confusion between
the expiring limit and the quota
policies
and moreover in this case all the list
items
have the same structure
so
i think this
this is a
reasonable idea
the
what we'll have then is that red limit
limit remaining a result are just three
bare
integers
and the optional part is in another
field the rate limit policies
containing uh
the
old
quad apologies and this is the only
feeds that support parameters
so probably um
[Music]
this is the
principle
uh
question
and we want to ask the
the opinion of
work group on this
splittings part
we think this is reasonable
because it's
it's apple with apple and oranges with
oranges
while in the previously we had
different meaning for the first
list item and the other ones
and the rest if we want to discuss the
other policies
um we have uh mark in the queue do you
want to
uh take questions now or do you want to
wait till the end
afternoon
i'm finished actually
because this was a the core issue the
other can be discussed footer after the
work group plus call but if we close
this
we will make the
requests and then we we hope to make our
group let's go
so i'll hand it over to you mark
working
can you hear me
yes wow
technology is wonderful hello um
so i did to me this seems like
we're seeing this proliferation of
fields
and it seems like it's quite verbose
you know sometimes it's a good idea to
split out data into multiple fields
especially when it changes at different
rates
um but it seems like
you know like the remaining and the
reset are pretty dynamic as far as i'm
aware whereas the policy and the limit
are not
um
so i i just i can't help but wonder you
know this is maybe related to issue 65
as well i can't help but wonder have we
tried to
combine all this
information into one field like a
dictionary
and use clear dictionary labels to to
clarify the relationship because it's
all fairly tightly coupled it seems to
me
i was just wondering if if the editors
considered that
we did but
the point is that
this is
what is already used
by everyone
on the internet this is what everybody
does
and
that paving cow paths is is a good
strategy sometimes
but i don't think we should be bound by
it i think that
developers if it with a clear
specification and a clear direction
forward can change we're already
changing the names of the fields that
they're using
i found the reasoning for issue 65 quite
thin on that basis that if we don't have
it starting with the words right limit
they won't understand it seems to be the
reasoning there um
so i i think that if if we come up with
a well-reasoned design we don't have to
be too
bound by by precedent there um and i'd
encourage you to to at least explore
those directions
thanks mark we actually did
talking with implementers
there does not see
we after our investigation it seems that
implementers
not only
are um
not willing to change the this layout
but when we try to conflate policy and
limit
they expressly provide feedback in
splitting them
so
maybe uh
i i wouldn't
it wouldn't be useful to create a cool
specification that implementers are not
willing
to use
that's it
at least this is the thing that we have
okay i i i would love to probe that a
bit more because it sounds
somewhat thin to me
um that
that
the implementers want to see it spelled
in a particular way in particular
headers in the wire otherwise they're
never going to use it
that seems a bit odd to me
martin's joined the queue martin
um
so i tend to agree with rocky i think
the uh efficiency advantages that you
get from having a single field
sort of far outweigh the
advantages of having simple unique
um
fields that you can pull out with simple
images
uh it's
the assumption here we're using
structured fields
for pathing these things out and my
guess is that those implementers who
would
rather we didn't put all the things
together
are
not using structured fields to do their
path in which
it's probably
okay maybe if you're just using a simple
integer field but these things can be
parameterized and there's no guarantee
that they won't be
and so i i tend to think that pushing
them towards a dictionary would be
pretty straightforward
the um the dynamism aspect of that can
be pretty well addressed with header
compression
and
i
think it's much more compact and concise
to have a simple a single break limit
thing that sort of says well here's one
parameter one one pair of values here's
the limit here's the reset here's the
remaining
and um i don't know how to express a
policy but i'm sure
thanks marty
does anybody have questions on other
parts of this
presentation
okay this is rich so i'll mention
that um
in the oblivious http
group
um
the idea came up
um and i don't know if the people there
had reached out to you
uh or your author's co-author robert um
the idea that so in ohi
there's an intermediate proxy between
the end user and the client and the
origin server and that obfuscates enough
information and it gets obfuscated
information so we can't tell what the
request is and it sends it on to the
origin
and there seems to be a need
for
having
that intermediate and the origin
collaborate to do rate limiting
uh one way or another and so
they might be coming here or they might
be looking at your draft as a way to
reuse some of it and probably adding
some kind of indicators saying
this is related to the origin or this is
related to the proxy or this should go
back to the user whoever they are
saying you're doing too many requests of
this kind
the proxy has no idea what the requests
are
but
it can be you can tell the the
the client
you know stop asking for every single
picture in the phone book
so i think it's mainly just a heads up
that uh
ojai
needs a similar kind of thing it's
different in that there's multi multiple
parties
and they'll need to
be able to address
where the limits are intended it might
just be as simple as adding a new field
indicating which party the limits are
encoders are for
that's all just a heads up
frank this is
this is interesting and
probably we should file an issue to
understand better
the use case and possible exchanges
in
in general i am well i understand uh
the
suggestion of
reducing the number of fields
but please consider that the actual
feedback of many implementers
is that they say
in direct limit policy that they don't
even want to conflate all those
information in the same field and they
prefer to say for example red limit
minions that limit our different things
i don't know if this is because they
implement this at different layers so
they have different proxies
or different intermediator
that provides
each different
time frame
no i'm i'm i'm not using i'm not
the i'm not trying to avoid using
structure-filled parser but i need
i i'm building this specification for
implementers
and my goal is not forcing them to do
something they don't want to do
but is avoiding they
to provide different
the same information in different things
i i i'm not uh i mean uh
trying to
interpret
what they
um
that their goals i'm trying to
i'm trying to make them use the same
field name for sending the same
information
mark is back in the queue all right go
ahead
working is it working yes it seems to be
working okay
um so roberto i think it's great that
you're going out and engaging with folks
who are using you know similar things
out there and
i mean
implementers potential implementers i
think there's maybe a mix there i'm not
sure
but uh generally when we do that um it
it's great but it's important to make
sure that we're doing that to bring back
uh their feedback in the form of
arguments not just preferences you know
it's it's much more convincing if you
came back and said implementers want to
do this and there there's this technical
or this this reason why that we can
understand and take into account in our
discussions but it's it's less useful
when when they come back and say
they want to or they prefer this or they
prefer that um i'm much less willing to
be convinced that that that's a good
reason to choose any particular design
in the discussions for a standard
the problem is
to find something that
matches
the
that can
be accepted by
bad implementers
i mean
part of the challenge of writing
standards yes i think we're maybe we
have different calibrations on what
uh will work there
brian hello is this working yep this is
brian gondwana um i i wanted to add
something in favor of the idea that
something that people want to use
has value in itself not just because of
the technical arguments but because they
enjoy using it and hence they're more
likely to use it we're competing against
someone can throw whatever they like in
the header if we're offering them a
standard that's a pain to use and looks
ugly and they don't like then they just
won't use it so i think
the
operators prefer this is a significant
users prefer this is sufficient argument
in itself it doesn't have to be it's
technically the best and and they have
made a compelling argument for why it's
right just they would prefer it is a
pretty strong argument
eric
yeah um
hello everybody this is eric um
so i i just wanted to point out that
maybe sometimes we also have a different
view on
the people we're designing for i think
and i really don't mean this in a
negative way but i think mark has a
perspective that is a lot on people who
are very professionally working with
http and http header fields and so forth
because that is the core
of what they're working with and for
those i would assume they should and
probably will be much more willing to
adapt to technologies like structured
fields and make sure they understand
what it means and how they can use it
and use the library and so forth but i
think in the api space really in the end
what you end up with is you end up with
a lot of developers who are not core
http developers who are using http as
part of the work they need to get done
and if you tell them
that they have to use an additional
parser and that there are rather complex
header fields to work with and all of
this i think it's just a different kind
of
client base we're working with here so i
i just think we should take into account
that from an http api perspective for
most people they are not
http experts
so for them http is just something that
they need of as part of the work they're
trying to get done
so we sh we should try to make it as
easy for them as we can
to get the information that they can get
in http and to work with http header
fields without
requiring them to
adapt technologies that may may be
designed for a different user population
thank you eric martin
oh wow okay
um
i think probably the thing
that tips me towards saying that using
structured fields properly here is
is acceptable is that
report guns
that those casual developers
have in front of them
is is much more than they think they
have and
[Music]
usability is not necessarily um
very different when you look at uh
restructuring this
as a single structured header uh you you
take the hyphen and you turn it into a
colon and you take the colon and you
turn it into an equal sign and you have
essentially what um
what we were talking about using using
structured fields for it's not that
complicated to parse
um
it's certainly
no no more difficult to use than what
what roberto has described
and
you really don't want to have a
situation where people think
they can
just
i would just throw
cars in or something in here
because that's led to a number of
problems that we've had in the past
and as much as i think the professional
uh casual thing is important here
um we want to make the casual people use
the structure for your powers as well
we want everyone to be using the
structure of your partners because those
are the ones that are safe
mark
oh the graph is moving you can probably
hear me now
um
eric i really don't buy it sorry um
people who who have to parse hp headers
by hand are exactly what we want to
avoid with this
and and having those parameters there
like the w on the screen that just went
away for some reason is is the huge kind
of foot gun that martin's talking about
um
if
you know and and and frankly making them
just straight integers like this but
still structured fields is
encouraging people to write their own
parsers and then they'll break when
people put it on a parameter on it later
so i i don't buy it um structured fields
is designed exactly so that people can
just go off and use a library off the
shelf and not worry about any of this
and api developers love using libraries
that's that's their heart and soul so
yeah
um
and and i actually got a key to respond
to braun absolutely if we get feedback
that that implementers and users prefer
one thing that's great i'm just i'm a
little concerned about one person going
off and coming back and making decisions
based only on that person's interaction
with the community i would expect
broader input
that's all
and speaking as an individual eric i
will both agree with you and disagree
with you um i i do agree that in your
characterization of a lot of api
developers
but most api developers are also not
implementing
the throttling infrastructure they're
going to use some kind of library i
think people we need to convince people
writing
throttling libraries and at that point
it's the people serving the headers that
are making decisions the consumers will
use whatever they're given
um and hopefully they'll use library to
go do that parsing um so i i i
i think
i i am concerned that it's the yeah we
just don't want to change our thing
that's using x dash and if you make
things very very different it'll be
obvious that we're not using the
standard thing anymore
um
so i i definitely would like to hear us
dig in more
into the pushback on making any changes
and having backward compatibility
hands
yep uh hi this is hunter speaking um so
first of all i very much a preacher
appreciates it works so i think this is
something very useful uh once it is
finished and in broad use
um i like eric's uh distinction before
uh regarding like there is two distinct
user groups like you know the casual
user consuming api and maybe not wanting
to spend so much effort
and more advanced users but i slightly
disagree with which
which of these users we should focus on
here because i think for the casual user
actually this doesn't matter at all in a
way because these users will just be
heart throttled by the apis if they have
no clue anyway so this is complex stuff
actually
and people that want to implement this
kind of stuff they really need to
understand not just the header fields
but also maybe the documentation behind
that so it's not just only the header
fields to
understand here and i also very much
agree what daryl said this is also
something that needs to go into
libraries in the end
um so i think it's it's very much
important here to have this very
conceptually clear and convey as much as
information that is necessary for
libraries to deal with that and yeah to
make stuff work smooth
brown
since i put my name into this for the
first thing a lot of developers are
going to probably just be doing a regex
that matches digits off the front of
rate limit remaining and not care about
anything else uh would be my guess
glancing at this
realistically and that's that's the use
case that is going to
be for a lot of people if they care at
all if they just throw things at it
until they get a rate limit error back
um which is probably what i would do
so
that's that's the kind of thing that
that we're really going to see with this
if you look at what's been done in the
field already i think that's a good
place to look at because that's what has
organically grown
and what's organically grown has been
separate headers rather than a
structured header uh it's what the
people who already just do stuff in this
space are going to be familiar with
and so i mark i totally see your point
who is going to do that research because
just saying that research needs to be
done with no one volunteering to do it
is the same as the work never happens
mark
there it is you can hear me
okay the lag is amazing uh
it sounds like that you know
there are two extreme solutions here
and i i i don't want to paint it as we
have to choose a or b but it sounds like
we might be migrating towards that at
one extreme we have an unlimited
number of fields depending on how many
pieces of data
that uh we need to send and each field
just has an atomic piece of data and
it's not structured field it's just
you know ten six and three literally and
you don't have any parameters because
that's too hard
or
you have a fully structured field and it
is you know fairly complex but we throw
structured fields parsers at it and the
data just appears
and uh
we it's we have to make it complex
enough to be effectively self greasing
which i think there's probably enough
data to do here if we combine it into
one or two fields
um if if it's not self grazing then i i
think that braun
you know has a point that that people
will just try and parse it
and then it'll break when somebody adds
some data to it like a parameter to it
later on
um so so maybe what we need to do is to
write up those two extremes and see what
they look like
uh there seems to be some noise there uh
so right up those two extremes see what
they look like and and figure out what
the best path forward is from there
so i i and i think we've chewed through
the meat of the issue i don't think
we're going to solve developer
motivation um i think it would be good
for us to uh take this further
conversation to the list and maybe we
can move on to uh the next presentation
from roberto
on
and his mind goes blank media types yes
there's gonna be a lot of conversation
on this one i fear
thanks so much
hi hi everybody i'm roberto
nice to meet you
so
in this specification
we are trying to register some media
types that are widely used
on the internet
and
but are not yet registered
the goal is increased interoperability
when processing api specification is to
leverage content negotiation when
exchange api resources and simplify
comparative development and cataloging
of api and schemes
so open api specification relies on
yammer and json schema that are not
being registered this makes impossible
uh content negotiation uh done
in a
standard way
and yaml users do not have
interoperability and security
considerations
so
we want to register yamalan the placing
ammo media type providing
interoperability and security
consideration foundation for open abi
plus yaml
registering up an api plus jason and
yaml json's camera plus json and yaml uh
jason led placiamo
does ingredient a
quick win
we already have onboarded
json schema and open avi folks
on plus yamo there is some
work needed we imported yamo fox but
there is uh
work to do
on ld plus yaml
journal defaults
agrees
but there is more quark needed and on
schema plus yaml there is some
disagreement
so
this is the
outlook we engaged with almost everybody
at different degrees
of
interaction
we have
these other issues
one
engage with mega types mailing lists one
in what group plus calls suggested by
francesca thanks
the third fragment identifier
considerations
number 22 can we use normative language
in media
meditab registration it seems that it is
possible but
i don't know so i asked for feedback
here today
to the to the work group
there are some issues in json ld plus
yaml for a set of reasons because
json led seems that
use the infraspecification not only the
json
specification
and
the more divisive one is
do we need the json schema
media type
so the changes from the first
revision is that
it now supports json
schema we added the yama structure
syntax suffix
and after the yaml interrupter will get
security consideration with some support
from the yaml
folks
um
yes we need this the question with uh
the question from martin
the point of jesus schema plus
is related to
the open api world because of an api
specification are actually developed
in yaml
and
if i have to create a catalog
with open api specification if you want
to
refer reference
json schema
then
developers expect to
develop json schema
in
in yaml
having json schema only in jason means
that folks developing yaml
and then
add them to catalogs in json
so that
api specification written in yaml can
reference json schema within json
and this is what
is probably happening now
this is not very comfortable
uh reusable
because why if i develop something in a
language i need to
convert it
in
another syntax
to be used
moreover
for developers
jason is very
less easy to use
respect to
to yamo
but well this is was just to present
this specification i think there is a
lot of work to do
especially on
all the impacts that yaml has
on
various parts
of the specification
and what
have your thing
so
i read that there are some
ideas
i don't know if you all read this
specification
but
the there was one comment brought up uh
by martin with regards to shouldn't that
application slash schema plus json b
application slash json schema plus json
because it feels a little like squatting
to be to call it application schema
uh well i just told them from jason
schema
community and i
didn't want to
push the toes
[Music]
on jason schema community i'm discussing
with them
they will probably write the media type
registration they already did
so we are hosting
the
opinion of the json schema community for
what regards the general schema
mark has joined the cue mark
there it goes all right i have no idea
why there's so much life
um so i'm not familiar with this work
the only thing that i'd caution is we've
had situations like this in the past
where there's a draft to do some work in
the itf that's
related to a larger piece of work
that lives somewhere else
and and it's it's super super easy to
get your our wires crossed when doing so
so i would i would very strongly suggest
that if if you're not already
going through the most
official liaison channel you can to do
these things
in other words just relying on
people you know in those communities or
chat on a list or something is probably
not adequate you need to get
the most formal possible
consensus or decision or whatever the
mechanism the community has that they
are okay with this and they want to do
it this way and they want the ietf to do
this otherwise we can end up in a very
very awkward situation so i'm not saying
that anything wrong has been done
anything i'm just from past experience
uh this can bite us really hard so we we
need to make sure we do that right
that's all
but but thank you for doing this work
because
this is the unglamorous stuff that often
doesn't get done
i just
sorry go ahead
no i was just thinking
so i i can i can speak to the open api
community um
and the opiate api community
is very much behind this effort
um
and
this
we've had conversations numerous
conversations in the technical steering
committee meetings uh about this so that
there's definitely support there
uh
the jason schema community who are also
actively involved with the open api it
is a fairly small group of people and i
know that roberto is talking to
the right people um i
i think we should go back to them um
and suggest that applications like
schema is is a little broad
um
and i i do think they will be receptive
to that kind of feedback
and it
seems like um
the other communities to engage in would
be the link data community which i know
has registered media types before
and uh the yaml community of course as
well
martin
it's only the audio
i don't quite know um anyway i i was
going to say
my first look at this also um i was
aware of its existence
but um the
thing that
i would suggest here is that you've got
a lot of media types
uh in the one document and and one of
them is
this plus yaml structural syntax um
suffix
it might be a good idea
to
just slice some of these pieces off
and do them as separate documents
simply because
i think the slide three back where you
have the different color codes for the
things
um being at risk and and those ones that
are simple and easy uh there's good risk
that those things are difficult
um
holding back the thing the other ones
and it might be nice to just get some of
the easy things out of the way
and and published
and
from a user perspective being able to
cite just the plus yaml spec when you're
registering your media type
would be a lot easier than than trying
to fish around in a big pocket of
different media type registrations when
you have to do something like this
and just one of the call out in the
media man
meeting this week
there was a discussion of multiple
suffixes
and
because they're talking about wanting to
be able to say plus
ld plus
json
um
on top of the application slash did so
i'm
not sure where that's going to land but
there was some pushback
in that conversation specifically around
using
suffixes at all so um
i in in reading through the issues
uh
like
early on when this was just focused on
open api and
um
json scheme it seemed fairly
straightforward but some of the issues
seem to be opening up a bunch of stuff
and sticky stuff
so
maybe
martin's feedback is good that
stopping at one point and separating out
some things would be a good idea
so
but this is an excellent conversation
and
uh yeah i think it
these
media types have been long desired by
the community
so i love the fact that you're doing
this work roberto
yeah the goal was providing
a specification where
all actors
all media that's related to the api
can be addressed because i think that
we need to
at least to me it has been beneficial to
get in touch with all those community
together
to have a better overview
of the relations
that there are
even when people use them
between all those media types
martin days are not
we don't
we don't even have the yaml media
so application yaml is not registered
now
so we are registering both application
enamel and the structured syntax suffix
plus yammer
so if you are
interested in martin in this yaml stuff
probably
we can
fork this document
work on the yaml stuff together
in the same proposal
okay so i think
okay
we have a volunteer erica
the silence was long enough that
somebody felt they should step up that's
excellent
so
we will try to separate those documents
and
hopefully having the
yaml
registration
uh
moving on
but
before doing this i think
i asked the church if we can get some
feedback from the medium
sure and it's
manu uh who you have been working with
uh on this uh document who's involved in
the
multiple suffixes effort
yeah
so again you're talking to the right
people
there okay
thank you roberto
thank you for your patience
thank you for yours
so um we have
uh we have another presentation from uh
martin before we go there
um
i just want to quickly go through
the set of open issues on and some
status across all of the documentation
and i'm
i'm going to
be brave rich and actually try and share
my screen here
do you really want to share your screen
yes
do i want to share this screen yes
and um
as
this working group is
from what i understand a little unusual
in that we have so many documents going
through
um
in order to
try and
uh keep track of all of the different
things that are going on because most of
them are going on github i attempted to
take advantage of
the new beta
project boards in um github
and so
the
if you go to the organization
of um
the get repo
uh you should see there's a projects tab
at the top
and
uh then there is at the moment just one
project you can set up as many of these
as you like
um
when you are working with an issue so
i'm just going to click on this to open
it
there is this project's
uh category here and so you can simply
say this particular issue we're working
on i want to show it on the project
board and you can specify a status and
as soon as you connect it here
it will magically appear on the project
board and we've set it up so that it
groups by repo
so we can see
the open items for
the deprecation header
the item potency key media type straight
limits and http problem
um
yes
so
since we have a repo for document
the document authors can click on the
add to the project will automatically
show from this math program
i i am still
getting all of the wrinkles out of the
permissioning
my understanding is if you are if you
own
uh if you are
have right permissions on a repo
you can assign it um
to the project
okay so we we might need to tweak some
things but
great
this doesn't require one person to do a
master list and what you know the
individual people can do it that's
awesome correct
what the the the interesting thing is
this status here in this column
is independent of the issue you can we
can actually add new fields to the
project so that there is additional
metadata that can be controlled at the
project level
so these statuses are independent of the
status of the
uh the individual issue and then so in
reviewing some of these
um
i created these statuses to distinguish
between the ones were still having
debates about and the ones that we seem
to have resolved
um
[Music]
the discussion and it's just a case of
the uh authors needing to go and do a
document update um i think one
mechanism we could use here in processes
is where we have things that say you
know there's a document update required
it would probably be good if we had
somebody assigned to
actually do that document update
and you can see here
in the case of this one there is
actually a pr that has been linked to
this one so it's fairly easy to dig down
into
these items and so um
i
you once if
you have been given permission to this
project there's another view that i set
up which is more kind of like a kanban
board
and you can just drag and drop
between here but because this is
changing the status that is owned by the
project you need right permissions
on the organizational project
so this
we
will be a thing that hopefully evolves
uh
to be more effective over time mark
is it working
yes we can see okay
that's it asked for permissions yet
again
um that just
made a question occur to me um
is the expectation from the chairs that
document editors
will respect the categorizations that
you've given them there so for example i
went through and did a couple of prs for
issues in
the 1707 bist today
that appear to have consensus um should
we wait for you to change the
status to document update required
before you merge them are you are you
overseeing it to that level or is this
just entirely kind of best effort
informational what's the stance there
um i mean
that's the conversation to be had like
the least work we have to do
the better but um
i'm i'm more than happy to go and kind
of reconcile i think if uh
if we want to use this as a way for
document editors to communicate with
chairs that this is the status of where
we are up to
then i'm more than happy that that
document editors have right access on
this project and can change these things
themselves
okay so i just wanted to understand
whether the status was you know
exclusively controlled by the chairs or
shared with the editors or just kind of
a best efforty sort of thing that sounds
like it's more the latter than the
former
yeah i mean
as you saw from roberto's deck like he
had a slide that had a bunch of issues
that were open and to the base to talk
about it and then we did that in the
last ietf meeting and this is just kind
of like hey here's an easy way of
keeping that kind of list of here are
the active things that we're talking
about uh up to date okay um it was
unfortunate i don't seem to be able to
find a way of actually getting the issue
number to appear as a column but if you
hover over you see in the bottom
left-hand corner uh the issue number and
i will note roberto that you called out
in uh your rate limit headers and issue
number 41
and i can't find issue number 41 in the
uh repo
or at least fish 41 had a very different
title than the one that you call them so
we should reconcile there
yes
yes agreed eric this is additional
this is a status view
with hopefully an absolute minimum
amount of additional work
and
we could if we if we decide
we could just completely
throw away the status column and just
use labels
and we could use labels as a way for
document authors to just put a label on
an issue in and be able to surface that
up at
the central place
and because you can see over here
whether an issue has actually been
closed or is still open
how easy is it to share labels uh no you
have to
reinvent the labels
you're a little quiet rich yeah sorry
about that so the script i used to
create the repos when we have a new
document just copies
standard set of labels that came from
you know marx and martin's first thing
uh using the quick group
so
yeah there's no way to say these are
labels for
across a whole
organization
but
it's automated it's not terribly
difficult
okay
so that was the main thing
go ahead
as i say mark points out it's possible
to create default set of labels for new
new repositories which would be
presumably very partly very useful for
this group is our goal is to get you
know many documents through so i'll take
a look at that
cool
just in an attempt to use this for a
moment um
there uh there is still active work
going on in deprecation header uh
there's some items here
there
is a couple of items still in discussion
so please i encourage you to
go check out these issues on the github
repo
uh and provide feedback
um
i debated whether or not to create this
block this is this is related to using
date time and there was a reference to
other ongoing work with regards to what
is
the appropriate
use of
a date time versus just a delta seconds
um
as i say we can evolve these statuses uh
the item potency header is has expired
uh we should uh follow up with sanjay
uh as to
whether this is going to come back to
life
or we should encourage sanjay to bring
this back to life
and
uh
we've discussed those two and 7807 again
some open items for discussion
and with that
oh i see somebody in the queue
eric
yep um
hello thanks there this is eric yeah
just with regard to the item policy i
think that that was not kind of um
intentional so to speak that it expired
the idea was not to say we're not doing
that anymore it's just that um there are
a couple of open issues that should be
addressed i don't think i don't think we
have a good plan
on
which of these issues should be
addressed before we create a new version
but
at least the intention definitely is to
keep this alive um even though it is
only expired so i think i think we
should definitely keep it in there and
hopefully um this one will have a new
version in the not too distant future
thank
it would be good to get confirmation
because i i read through some of these
issues and it looked very much like
there was a suggestion and the response
was yes yes we should update that in the
document um so those
yeah like some of the things
that you put there you know it's like
okay somebody should be assigned to it
so that we know who to go back to and
yeah good but i think like your table
there really is also it's just great for
housekeeping right like making sure that
well
we're discussing many things but
nobody's responsible maybe that's not a
good sign
mark
yeah okay i should really unmute in
anticipation
i guess
um
do do i may have misunderstood the
agenda do we have time to actually
briefly run through the 7807 issues
because i think that would actually help
us move the document forward
i believe we can the primary uh
item left on the agenda is martin's
date request
but i we have 50 i don't think it's
going to take very long
okay so let's
okay um so
i'll use the numbers on the left even
though we know that they're not the real
numbers um the number 21 mapping problem
details into a header um
i suggested that just as kind of a
thought experiment because it has come
up in the past uh before
uh of of conveying this information in a
header when you don't have access to
writing to the response body for
whatever reason
um and or or if you want to expose this
information to an immediate area that
doesn't want to crack the body open um i
should say content i shouldn't say body
but you know old school um
and it seems to me like the response to
this was was somewhat lukewarm
so um on the one hand you know a
lukewarm response like this
i think if i could characterize the
responses i've seen is that oh yeah that
might be useful but i don't really have
an immediate use for it now
so uh the most obvious thing to do would
be to drop it and just move on um
i think i if you look at the very last
comment i said if if people think that
they have a clear use for this or or
that it might be useful very soon we
should do it while we have the document
open because it's just easy to do that
otherwise we can wait on it knowing that
you know if there is pressure to use it
out there then that'll build up for a
while until we actually publish the
document which we've experienced for a
lot of other api facilities as well
so i don't have strong feelings about
this i'm happy to drive uh to drop it if
no one wants to fight for it um i just
was curious to see what other people
thought about it
i guess last call for including this
into this pack
i i i thought it was a a really
interesting possibility to address the
topic that has come up multiple times
before which is this ability to include
warnings
um
it depends on how fatal you perceive the
word
problem
um
because we have smart problems
you know that's right that's a small
problem you might consider rewarding
uh so i i think that's
that would be a
a really nice thing to be able to just
say yes i want to add a header
uh
to indicate there is some kind of
problem with this response even though i
returned it to you with the 200 okay
i i mean i'm happy to do a pr just to
see what it looks like i mean my
inclination would be if it's a huge wall
of text it's not worth it
um but if we can get a couple of
paragraphs and get some value out of it
i'm happy to put it out there and then
see if that spurs anyone to say yes i'd
really like to have that
does that make sense
just to me i'm also equally happy to
close it with no action
i think it can have some value
so i'm not sure about the queue but i
think i
it's my turn right
so yeah
this isn't circuit again um yeah i would
actually second i think it might be
useful for one kind of style so i would
i would argue for keeping it in
okay that that's that's actually really
helpful i'll i'm happy to do a pr and
just see what it looks like and it may
very well be that that that reveals that
it's a horrible idea or horribly complex
and not worth the effort or whatever but
i'm willing to try so i'll give it a go
um next issue thank you hans that was
helpful and and roberto
um down thank you
requiring a specification document i
think that is just a mechanical thing
about the registration policy i copied
for the registry of problem types and i
copied some text from elsewhere that
wasn't appropriate and this is a
correction of that
so there's a pr there if anybody wants
to look at it i intend to merge that
very soon
excuse me
uh the next one number quote unquote 23
multiple problems um this has been a
long discussion and i i think we have a
fairly
strong agreement at least in the issue
and in the discussions we've had
previously in working group sessions
on a path forward in terms of deleting
some text about status code 207 that is
not terribly good practice and uh
putting in another kind of warning about
the limitations of of this structure
uh sanjay was uh i know a bit sad about
removing the examples that he'd put the
work into or at least one of the
examples that he put the work into
adding to the spec
but i think that there's a fairly strong
agreement there so if folks want to look
at that pr
um
and give any feedback i again intend to
merge that pretty soon as well
and if folks have comments about that
right now i'm happy to chat about it
i i hadn't posed a question
as to
you know this
question about putting
uh examples into the spec but actually
not putting is a best practices document
like the natural next logical conclusion
there
or is that overkill
a best practice document for 7807
yeah to include all of these examples of
well this is how you do multiple problem
types and this is how you use it for
warnings and this is how you
i i would hope that that kind of
documentation in the first instance
you'd you'd put it into some of the um
you know whether a blog or some sort of
industry communication or something or
something i think there are a number of
outlets out there like that and if there
aren't there should be you know you kind
of smashing mag but for api developers
or whatever you know
if anybody goes and does that i expect
to cut just saying
um
yeah and and you know if we can uh
there's a line to be walked there but i
think
that would be my response for now yeah
um
hans do you have your hand up for this
or or is that just uh
no okay
um
extension to so so
the show source of problem and request
forex class of errors
that is actually um blocked by another
issue which isn't on this listing for
some reason
um
let's
see if we can fix that
currently when i show share my screen
things go a lot slower
uh is it is the issue that's blocking it
discussed here i mentioned
uh at the bottom it should be yes 36
that one right there which was just
opened recently maybe that's why
there we go
so we we've had this latent problem in a
lot of discussions about 7807
and it's good i'm actually glad that
this was opened as a separate issue so
we can just discuss it separately
um and and it's that um the 7807 does
not allow new standard
um
uh
d done what's what i'm looking for
properties
members whatever to be added to the
structure
that all the all the ones that aren't in
are effectively any possible name is
under control of the problem type so
you know we can't come up and say well
here's a new
uh member for
i don't know uh for a pointer to where
the problem is in the response body for
example which is
what the previous issue was about
um and so if you scroll all the way down
um
yeah i think that that we have a couple
of ways out of this
um we we can either you know zero which
i didn't put into this message is the
status quo which is don't
allow don't say anything about this
uh or we could find a name convention
for new standard properties that doesn't
conflict with any existing usage so for
example add a prefix to new standard
properties um and and the issue with
that is that we by nature can't know all
of the usage of of 7807 around the world
and that we won't conflict with them in
every single instance you know
we can make that less likely
by choosing a weird prefix and then of
course we have weird ugly prefixes on
new standard properties but whatever
um but but that's kind of like a just a
you know there's a risk strategy we had
around if we take that path
uh the other path we have is to mint a
new media type for problem details for
this next revision
uh and the concern there you know that
gives us a clean slate to work with but
of course that also
risks creating fragmentation that now
api developers have to choose which one
they use and there's momentum behind the
old one and oh would i have to use this
new thing but i don't know if everybody
supports it blah blah blah blah
and so that that creates more confusion
potentially
there is a third option and that's kind
of the unspoken option in 1707 which is
we can't define new standard this is
recognized in every problem instance
across the world
but what we can do is create new
conventions that new problem types or
any problem types can opt into and say
oh yes i use that convention so for
example we could create a convention
that there's a problem pointer and it
means something when the type says it
means something
um
not quite as automatic and nice as you'd
like but you know maybe a path forward
without breaking too much
i i don't have any strong feelings here
personally if you want to call that
option zero one two and three
but um i kind of feel like
i i i'm most against option two i think
minting a new media type there should be
a fairly high bar against it
and i think option one actually
probably could work my only concern
there is
um there's a lot of experiments that
people want to have i think about oh
that that's a good idea this is a good
idea and we should have a chat about
what the bar is for new problem for new
standard attributes i don't think we
should just put them out there
willy-nilly
um but but that's all i have to say
about this i'm really curious to hear
what other folks have to say about it
eric
um
yes thanks this is eric
um thanks mark for coming up with these
suggestions
um for number one i think you know we
have a typical problem like this good
old x-dash considered harmful right it's
like once people start using stuff then
it's kind of that's how it is and and
renaming it to whatever convention we
come up with is always a little bit hard
but um
i think my my preference probably would
be number one only that we
maybe we could consider using uris which
why not it's kind of like a prefix but
one that
maybe is a little less just random but
anyway um
the the second one also to me is not so
attractive
the third one actually i have
my problem with that is that this means
that that kind of each type would need
to kind of opt in individually and i
think in many cases
you might rather have a situation where
you say my api
always uses these fields and then it
would become kind of complicated to say
well and i have these 28 types and then
all these 28 types so to speak would
need to opt in into that additional
field that you're trying to use so so i
think that one is like
it doesn't scale so well i think so my i
think my preference would be to go with
number one and to go with um
uri some kind of uri
as a prefix and then i think the risk of
conflicts is relatively low
and that's
well given what rfc 7807 already does i
think that's maybe the best thing that
we can think of
[Music]
i i i think i agree with on most things
there i think the for me the problem
with the third option is that tools
um
want to be able to automatically you
know invoke the semantics without
recognizing a particular problem type
and then you can offer richer you know
handling of a problem without having to
know its particular semantics um and and
if it's opt-in like that then we that
implies that we'd need some sort of
problem type description format to
enable tools to to process that which is
kind of nasty and frankly we know it's
not going to happen what they'll do is
just say oh look it's using problem
pointer i reckon it probably means that
even though i don't know for sure
um so yeah i think you're right i think
that number one is probably the right
way to go i i do have kind of this
visceral reaction to using
uh uh
uris as json property names i think that
some developers are absolutely fine with
that especially if they are of the link
data world and other developers are
going to look at that and say well i'm
not going to use that then
um and i'd like to avoid that reaction
personally i'd rather find i don't know
some people use a dollar sign i don't
know double colon we can have that bike
shooting exercise later on
this is daryl just one comment on the
third option
um as
the 7807 biz introduces a json schema
i think what the third option is
describing is what json schema now
allows with vocabularies and dialects
and because this is almost exactly what
we did in open api
uh in order to extend the keywords that
are supported
uh we introduced a vocabulary and then
you declare
that um
we are using this dialect which is a set
of vocabularies so there may be some
mechanics
it it's a little
interesting to get your head around but
there may be some mechanics that we
could reuse but it is somewhat dependent
on how well adoption of dialects and
vocabs
comes because it's fairly new in json
schema
so if if i can
respond oh is it working now fantastic
it's telling me that it's success big
green box that's great
um i i have again a kind of a visceral
reaction that it's very similar to link
data world where
they're like you know the to me the the
whole idea there is well we've got this
data model that we overlay on top of
json
but
it looks like normal json and that's
kind of an attractive nuisance you know
because a developer who doesn't use
linked data will come along and say oh
look it's json but if they don't use
that data model they might actually
really mess things up
and and so when you overlay these data
models on top of really attractive
native data models
um and processing models and so forth it
it becomes tricky for for everyday
developers to use it and so i'm a little
wary of those sorts of things i think it
should behave like it looks you know
okay
plenty of meaty issues
do you have anything it sounds
good oh sorry so it sounds like there's
there's maybe some convergence on the
number one with a tremendous bike
to build
if if i can characterize that one
yeah okay um so that one you're not 2x
oh don't don't start me on that
um
so that that that actually the number 24
is dependent upon that number 26. if we
get the number 26 sorted out then
there's just a question of whether or
not we actually do that and we'll get
there then ld jason ld context
personally i
won't use it but i know that other
people want to
i don't know that it's harmful to add to
the specs so i've just asked for people
to make a proposal
and we're waiting for that for someone
to make a pr of what text actually needs
to appear in this in the spec so if
somebody wants to go off and do that
work that's great um if it if nobody
does it by the time that uh uh
we get a last call i think we'll
probably just drop this issue but i'm
hoping ashborne or somebody will step up
and i think that's everything for this
so thank you thanks for the time
excellent thank you
okay so if i
remember the agenda well enough i
believe
next up is
martin you're gonna have to do the thing
with the thing with the
slides
yeah sorry
to fix my uh
i don't know you don't have to do it
you're fine to do that
i was uh requesting it
that's cool
now i'm gonna have to say things like
next slide please
oh
you know what
yeah sure say next slide
i i did say that i think the title
starts
all right so um
uh this is this is something that's come
up in the ohio working group as well no
it seems that we're uh running into a
bunch of issues uh with the use of http
that are kind of interesting and
sort of break into new ground
one of the things there that
we've discovered is that there's
some use for having the ability to to
mark the time of a request
particularly in that case for dealing
with
anti-replay as i'll get into later but
there's a general class of things where
you put the current time into a request
or something like that so that you limit
the the time over which something oh
oh that's a nice feature
someone spent a lot of time on that i
can move the slides down
um
so the purpose of this craft is to
basically explore the use of putting the
current time in a request
and all of the hazards that that
necessarily come with that moral and
otherwise
uh with the publicly trying to make date
time stamps and requests
so the specific that we have in ohio is
that
requests are replayable in that context
which is not particularly good
and so
having a replay strategy is particularly
useful
um
and in order to
manage the state commitments on servers
that are doing anti-replay
you
probably want to have something like a
date or sequence number or some sort of
monotonically increasing thing a date is
kind of okay
having a date means that if you receive
a request that's been replayed you can
rapidly identify it as such and then
just out of hand reject it
and then for those requests that are
within a certain window of the current
time you can simply say well i'll accept
those and remember some other details of
the request so that if another one with
the same
details comes in again you can quickly
reject it
as a duplicate
without the date
there's basically an infinite state
problem that the server has to deal with
so primarily looking at date but uh
there are other other timestamps in
requests
so um probably the biggest part of the
document talks about the ad clock
problem
so
shockingly common that our clients and
servers have a disagreement about what
time it is it's quite often the case
that uh
the clients are very very badly wrong
we've seen
times that are in the wrong millennium
and
um
it's not that unusual to see things that
are months or years out of out of date
so um
having you having a means to break that
is interesting there's a scheme that's
suggested in the document that uh
simply says take the date from the
response
and try again
of course um using an untrusted time
from an arbitrary server random servers
on the internet is probably unwise uh
talk about that a little bit as well
uh talk about the caching
interaction and uh some of the things
that might happen if you have an
intermediary in the path
it's quite common
for things like cdns to overwrite the
date
on the expectation that the cbn knows
what time it is they often take extra
clearing
ensuring that they have good clocks
the servers that back them don't often
get the get the time right so city ends
often fix it up for you
the implication there is
generally that this is no problem
uh but if the server time is very very
badly wrong and it's rejecting requests
and the cdn is fixing the date up on the
way out
it could mean that you never get a
request through ever
so um i know we had some discussion with
this one already um
the
questions i have is do people find this
material useful um and is this something
that the group would be interested in
working on
he says expectantly
oh mark tells me i'm wrong about why
this idiom is right we write today
i bet they rewrite it for all sorts of
scary caching reasons
uh jonathan asked the chat
is there
an error description for i need a date
but it didn't include one
yes so part of what this document has is
a problem report type that says your
date was wrong
which includes your date was absent
uh
so
how straightforward and short is this
document do you think martin
it's about five pages from memory
uh
i don't do da i don't do pages anymore
so i couldn't i couldn't tell you maybe
it's eight
um
it's not a particularly long one
yeah i don't i don't do pages anymore
it's probably five
i you know screen screenfuls would have
been enough that's fine
yeah
oh mark's in the queue
dang i'm just talking to okay good good
um
so i think maybe uh the the focus of the
discussion here should be on you know if
this document just needs a home i'm sure
that ohio could do it i'm sure that http
would probably be happy to do it as well
i think maybe the focus the way to make
this discussion useful is is do api
folks think that having this document
and these clarifications in this problem
type would be useful for api consumers
and api designers um and and if so then
this is a natural home for it and if
it's a little more scratching your head
i'm not so sure we can probably just do
an http or in ohio or wherever and if it
gets used elsewhere that's great but
it's not you know necessary to have it
here
that's how i'd think about it personally
i don't know the answer that's just how
i would find the question
yeah um i think when i when i first
floated this one i don't know if it was
you mark who pointed out the item
potency key work and there's a bit of a
relationship with that one
um the sort of complementary pieces of
work
right i remember that now that's right
yeah
just go ahead robert just speak up
well uh
thanks martin i i think
it's okay the documents to be related to
timestamps in general
but
i i really don't want to mess with dave
because
uh and i i'm not even sure that this is
the right place where
in information
that should be
in in some way
guaranteed should be used but this is
a personal opinion this this is my
opinion for
uh seeing the networks and for uh
and in general for
whatever is related to
either confidential integrity or
that is not just
an operative information
that's it
so um
i think that's that's that's a fair
comment i i didn't quite catch your
piece about um
third date
i i would just say the the document
should be named time stamp information
instead of date because we are speaking
in general about timestamp right
yeah and it's possibly not even http
specific apart from the problem type
work right
yeah i'll make that change
i think this is daryl's speaking from an
api perspective i haven't seen this
particular issue come up a whole lot um
although i can imagine
uh four apis that require to do signed
requests this does get a lot more
interesting
um
and i think just the fact that we're
using and it does include a problem type
as a way of describing it does
kind of correlate it back to apis fairly
strongly so
um i i think
this it does seem like a reasonable home
for adding this capability even though
maybe at the moment in the api world
it's fairly niche
all right
is it working okay
um that makes me wonder whether uh have
you talked to justin about this because
if it's
you know
has the strong link to the signatures
draft maybe uh um it could go in there
or be a companion document or just just
stop thinking out loud
yeah i i haven't spoken to justin about
this one uh in the discussion i have
with roberto on the list i think we we
kind of concluded that the signatures
thing was was less directly applicable
to this one it's it's often the case
that when something signs something they
put the time at which they signed it
but the purpose of that is is usage
limitation rather than to indicate the
the current time
and so the the connection to signatures
is a little weaker than
than that so
i don't think i don't want to over
emphasize the the application to
signatures
okay well i've gotten some good feedback
here perhaps um i've got to take this to
the list and
i've got a revision to make there's um
there's a few things that have come up
already in the discussions thus far
i might revise it and then ask again on
the list and we can have that discussion
that's the chairs object
just from the perspective of this
working group i have a small worry that
it might
interfere with or or have a
distracting kind of element with the
item potentially key work um i'm i'm not
sure it would be a you know
i i guess i'm wondering out loud whether
they would
resonate with with each other or whether
they would pull pull apart from each
other i'm not sure
my read of the item potency stuff is
that this is complementary and entirely
complementary you can use both or
neither or one
and and that's going to work out pretty
well
depending on what it is that you're
looking to do
so i think this is probably okay for
that and one of the nice things about
the item potency work is that it could
be a way to to signal
what what aspects of the request can uh
determine that it is either put or not
uh which
is sort of very complimentary if you
you're talking about anti-replay
strategies and whatnot
because if you if you've got an item
patent request then
you don't have to worry as much about
the item uh the the replay properties or
something
i thought i thought they were very much
complimentary
all right so you'll make some changes
and bring it to the list and maybe we'll
discuss adoption or
you can continue to venue shop
i would
i would never say that
i'm not no
finding the most appropriate with useful
work i'm sorry i said it two times oh
very good very good
yeah
all right uh
are we in the aob section now daryl um
we we are in the um
proposal for new working group documents
which we are now more enthusiastically
open to
um i believe
uh we had
last time a conversation about link
template
uh as uh a
document to do a call for adoption
unlist
which i believe we failed to do
uh and so we are recommitted this time
we really will do call for adoption and
we have more renewed enthusiasm about
adopting more docs
so
look out for that on the mailing list
and the other
[Music]
document that has been brought up in the
discussions area
uh on the github repo is the
health check
um
document which is um
as i understand it is currently an
individual contribution
but it
doesn't have a working group home
and i'm gonna defer to rich with regards
to what the processes and procedures of
adopting something like that would be
um
we can adopt it you know
the author would
presumably want to want to have that
adopted
eric you can speak in a sec the pers the
process is not it's not a big deal
it's the same as any other adoption
yeah thanks rich this is eric
um i just wanted to so because last time
i said i would get in touch with iraqi
and see you know how he feels about it
and so forth and in my defense i did
multiple times um but not much progress
was being made so
i still have i don't know last thing i
heard from him was that he tried to join
mailing list and i'm not quite sure of
how the status is there i don't think
i've seen him on the mating list but at
least i'm still pinging him
on a regular basis i'll keep doing that
and hopefully um there will be some path
forward i'm not quite sure whether iraqi
has the
the cycles to actually um
go forward with the draft
but one way or the other at least
he knows that that the group is
interested in the general topic and i'll
keep the group updated if i make any
progress
great okay thank you um if it helps to
you know loop daryl or i into the
conversation we can help ensure the
process will be relatively painless
until it gets to
as folks know after
that that's not the limiting factor
right now yeah
okay good
okay so i think that leaves us with aov
great
hey francesca
hello um
i wanted to ask the chairs and the
working group to possibly consider
updating the milestones
um
we don't need to have
i think it's useful to have some sort of
record of you know what's the
current status of the documents even
though we have an awesome github project
view now but
this is a more
high-level general view
and
we can use the uh next and later and
last instead of
dates if you know the working group
prefers but also
having an idea of what our goals times
are could be useful we don't have to
like be super precise but
yeah it would help me so
i want to bring this up right now we
have no milestones
got it
okay
martin go ahead
and then i'll say something
man that's so slow um
have i've done the research on
milestones and concluded that having
dates on them
is uh probably foolish uh we'd probably
decide whether whether we wouldn't put a
date on any more ones in this group as
well i'd sort of advocate the thing no
yeah i i think
yes having some kind of priority or a
rough you know
t-shirt size estimate is it will be
worthwhile um
daryl mark and i can discuss offline
with francesca and
post them and then see if the working
group says we got it wrong
so we'll do that between now and the
next ietf how's that
thank you
um
okay
you want to mention the twitter thing
daryl
yes rich and i
discussed that there was the possibility
of setting up a twitter bot in order to
provide more feedback to the community
and some more visibility
i suggested that i think
twitter is actually quite a
common gathering spot for api community
folk
and so
if we want to get the attention of more
people i think that probably would be a
good idea so i guess it's just a case of
understanding exactly what events
we would want
so that we understand what kind of
frequency that that might
spam a
audience with notifications
see
okay
um eric you say you like the hd working
group one um
does
folk do folks have uh pointers as to how
to get that set up
there we go
yeah
there's a straight line mark
sorry we may run out of time before my
wife becomes active again
um
yeah yeah you you talk to me um i have a
bot that does that um if you have new
features
um i take pull requests or cash
so
i like cash with a date stamp on it or
cash
sorry
all right
okay i will talk to you mark
cool great yeah i think adoption is is
definitely one we want to put in the
list too because we want to know
right we want to tell not just
end of the process but the beginning of
the process
yeah the hard one right now is um
when when i when you put out a call for
adoption because there's no way to
recognize that easily with the event
stream the data tracker puts out
but we'll
we'll talk
yeah okay yeah we can uh
maybe we can get the tools to change
mate okay
um
all right
unless
anybody has something
else to bring up i think we'll give
everybody
link setting
right thanks you suggested
we do an update on
uh
save the best for last
thanks the authors for their patience
and good nature
um
yes there was one change made in the
last good point one change made after
the set of isg and
itf reviews which turned two shoulds
into a may
two shirts into a must sorry for
interrupt
um
i'll post the diff to the list and if
anybody disagrees
by the end of you know next week
speak up but
it's just tightening your requirement it
says you have to do this particular
thing because it's really required for
interoperability so therefore it should
be a must
so i don't know if eric wants to share
more in detail but
since i'm shepherding this through the
ist process i can say that
uh yeah just
for summary if someone like if people
haven't followed this but we had to do
another ipf last call because of process
because some down ref were missed that
were in the um ice so
we started that and it's ending the 28th
of march and
um i also requested an
internationalization
directorate review
so i hope that will arrive by then and
um
and after that we're only missing a
couple of ballots and i
don't think that it will be
a huge re-review from the whole isg and
i wanted to thank you the authors for
answering all the comments and they
already post posted a
next version version zero nine
so
it should be
um
quite painless in my opinion um i'm only
waiting for the internationalization
review to make sure that we get that
right i am not an expert in the topic so
waiting for their opinion um
since there is an internationalization
section um
so yeah that that's basically
from my side
okay so i'll post the note to the list
and and also make it
if you object respond by the 28th so
that the same deadline applies
everywhere
and we will get this one in the queue
yeah and it's in it's up for telechat on
the 7th of april to get the last
ballasts that are missing
all right
um
thanks everyone
i i want to say that
you know this was sort of a
different group for the ietf we have
i'm very impressed by
all the authors when they go out and
they say oh i spoke to the opening api
people i spoke to the ammo people
these are whole communities that are
certainly new to me as an ietf geek
but i think we're doing a very good job
i think we're bridging
appropriate communities and getting good
stuff done
sometimes when
east meets west there's little friction
and frustration so i appreciate
everybody's patience
um
eric and herbert particularly most
recently
um
but
we seem to be doing well and that's
partly why you know that's mainly why
daryl and i think we can sort of open up
the pipe and take on more bandwidth
so
stay safe safe healthy
pray for peace
whatever
thank you everybody for joining me
all right
and hopefully in the future we'll all be
able to be in the room there on the
upper left corner
thank you very much everyone
thank you thank you for your time
thank you
thank you francisco
thank you roberto you're doing a great
job appreciate everybody
thank you take care bye
uh
so
well yeah