now we can see you yo can you hear us we
still cannot hear you
hi linda this is roman i'm also
confirming that i hear i see you but i
can't hear him and i just saw riff
rifaat uh
put his stuff down so i think he's
coming back to be our in-person helper
okay good good
well it's uh
similar talk
and uh time to start
okay so this is uh
interface to network security functions
and
the sessions recorded
here's a note well i think this
fourth day of the meeting fifth day of
the meeting so everybody should have
read it if you're not not please do so
uh here are some general tips for ietf
113. i think for this session most
people are remote
so we're all calling in to the mid-air
club
it's not oh
we don't have anybody here
much for sitting in the room for us to
make sure we're appropriately bridging
the kind of both locations both remote
and in person
thank you um so i encourage everybody to
look at the notes
and um
uh make sure your name and your
questions your answers are captured
correctly
um many many thanks to sue harris for
volunteer taking the notes for us
thank you sir
so here's the agenda
um
of the meeting
any questions for the agenda
no question let's just go further
so um
for we haven't met for quite a few ietfs
because of a data model has been under
review there's lots of like minor
changes so couldn't warrant a
face-to-face meeting time
so now
we have three drafts under iesg review
right capability data model an sf
phasing interface and asset monitoring
data models
lately there are still
many uh
dialogue on them i think the
rome can you correct me if i'm
correct that
capability data model
um we still miss uh need one more yes
for this to move forward
that that that seems exactly right with
my recollection let me just confirm that
with the switch over the numbers may be
off by one or two so give me a second
yeah it'll be either if we're short it's
either kind of a yes or no objection uh
data tracker waiting to respond
yeah
yes hold on all right so yes so for the
capability model we're actually in
better shape than that we have enough
ballots we just need to
we just need to clear the discusses
is it okay if i talk about the other
documents too
yes
yeah okay so the capability document we
need to convert the
we have there's enough ballots uh the
discusses need to be clear for the
nsf facing interfaces
same situation enough ballots discusses
need to clear for the monitoring data
model though that has both discusses but
also needs more balance
oh that needs more balance okay so i see
lots of discussions um on the mailing
list
paul can you update us with that status
have you cleared
cleared all the discuss comments
so okay
um actually uh three um data young model
capability and spacing and
monitoring interface uh actually the
discussion uh discuss okay bullet will
be uh lifted because i addressed the
oral
discuss comment so also i send an email
address
so
leave those
maybe one or two uh discuss but i
believe i uh
addressed all of them okay so i believe
i think uh
so we can get
approval from ict
great great thank you thank you so much
okay thank you so much paul for the very
hard work okay thank you very much if i
could if i could jump in here as well is
that okay
go ahead
thanks so first of all it's uh i've done
some meetings kind of with lyndon the
pandemic i haven't done with one with
you live paul so it's nice to see your
face
uh okay all right yeah online
uh
so i i i know we're clearing talking
about clearing discusses the other thing
i would say is about being off by one in
certain cases is
uh i believe that
ben's discusses are going to be picked
up uh by
by paul paul has not had a chance to
really be paul reuters uh has hasn't the
other sec ad now the incoming one hasn't
had a chance to i think do all the data
tracker magic so all the things that you
previously saw assigned to ben in i
would expect in the next day or two i
don't want to put constraints on his
schedule he's to kind of pick up and
he's going to be able to adjudicate and
respond back to those things
oh good so looks like in good shape
thank you thank you roman
thank you paul
okay you're welcome
and
we have two working group drafts waiting
to be sent to like for um last call
one is a consumer-facing interface data
model another one is registration
interface data model those two are to be
discussed today because there were
comments about those two
and also nsf facing
interface data model are not consistent
so paul is going to give us
an update on the changes and whether we
should make them consistent or not
with that
we go to the first presentation
um
so
palin can you do the presentation from
your end or do you want me to show the
slides
i can show here
okay
so i need your approve of that request
uh
okay
i approve that
oh i just need to end my
yes yes you need all y'all
yeah
oh i mean the whole
screen
i'm sorry
okay
whoa
so kai okay here my my screen
yes yes
yes
hello hello everyone this is a draft of
it
remote attestation interface young data
model
and
in fact this is the second edition of
the original draft which name is the
trust enhanced isf
so
this uh compared to the first edition
we revised the drafts traffic name to i2
answer remote attestation interface
young data model and the the first
reason is that
it's more easy to align with the uh
right with the recharger of items or the
potential each other of i2 and sf
which we will discuss later and the
second reason is that the term of trust
enhanced is not a specific term which
may bring some potential controversial
misunderstanding
so the second item is that
we added a new paragraph about the
definition of granularity of remote
station in iphone 7.
and uh right now in my opinion i think
there are three components in
united
self-deserving remote stations and
there are nsfs and maybe the basic
platform to carry the asf and then
without trust which can be show the
device identity
the third volumeter is that the remote
adaptation interface is also reversed
based on the granularity of granularity
design and the two kinds of functions we
may remain in the interface
the remote procedure call and
notification
the last one is that
the reference value of remote station uh
can you hear me now
we can't hear you we can hear you
clearly
okay because i changed the screen
so i can hear i can't see the mid tackle
i can only see my pdf if there are
someone want to comment please let me
know
yes we'll let you know okay
okay
the last item is the reference value of
remote station and
this hasn't been defined by rights group
yet there have
some personal draft but hasn't been
adopted as working group
dropped so i just wrote a temporary
interface and add it to the draft next
slide is yeah this is a main topic it's
a
relationship between rights and i2s
remote addition
so
i think that the rights has defined the
basic architecture of remote station and
they find different types of remote
station evidence
like based on tpm and te and
maybe uccs
and other graphs like testing results
and
in the itunes remote edition i think
that we just focus on the remote station
of nsf uh especially in the iphone 7
architecture and the remote station
target is nsf and its platform and the
root of trust in irsf is unlimited so
it's a it may be a tpm maybe a te or
even uh like a quan uh qpc i'm not sure
and the verifier and the relevant party
in itunes i2sf
a
maybe a security controller which is to
be determined because
because we will discuss in the next page
so
with all these drafts right we need to
define one
interface in itunes self remotely
station and to focus on the answer
itself
next slide is about the necessity of
itunes for remote station i think there
are
three main reasons and the first one is
the security reasons and
in a remote environment the deployment
of sf may be inappropriate
and
then there may have potential attack but
the remote has remote platform that who
carries an isf and the third one is that
we may want to know the security status
of trustworthiness of the nsf
so the second mentor a main
reason is that the practicability
reasons and because that
the target and the granularity
in this remote session it should be the
asf
and the rest architecture is not very
convenient to use in
iphone directly because that a different
device may have different route of trust
and one unified remote station interface
would be more convenient for to nsf to
implementation and there are some
future extension reasons and this topic
may not include in ietf but i think
there are worse awards to mention about
and first maybe it's a zero trust
concept may use advanced remote
heitation to assess and sf trust status
and
maybe uh the sassy sase they may want to
use the itunes remote station to enhance
edge security function and then the
security automation i may use iphone sf
remote station to manage the asf
and the last
bullet is that a decentralized security
intelligence sharing may use remote
attestation to judge the trustworthiness
of such intelligence for example if a
device is untrusted so
its
security intelligence may not useful
next slide is about the current
interface overview of the
of this draft
right now this draft only focus on the
sf remote station interface and the
reference value interface this two
interface is the basic interface of this
architecture and the um
the endoscope uh the connection between
the security controller and the industry
may not have to be an interface because
it may be
offline method like x5.9
[Music]
next slide is about the interface detail
and right now these drafts have three
basic groupings the first one is the
grouping uh sf remote attestation the
second is a grouping platform remote
attestation and the third third one is
root of trust remote attention
these three grouping will map to six
different
interfaces like a notification of nsf
notification to the
root of trust and then
there are three
remote procedure called
interfaces and the main reference
document
about the rats are mostly uh chara
its name is a young data model for
challenge response based remote
attestation procedure using ppms and it
is the entity
attestation token
so
this is the issue that needs to be
discussed and first one is the chart
model of itunes to nsf
and i think uh
people may we need to define which
component we need to trust which we
don't have to trust and
in the potential recharger which uh paul
sent to the minimalist and he mentioned
that both the nsf user uh the security
controller itself need to be
a remote attestation i think this is a
a question
which we need to discuss later uh i
don't have a an obvious answer right now
so the next issue is about the
granularity of remote station and in
this chapter i think uh i define the
three layers the first one is the root
of trust then it's a platform then we'll
have different servers that deserve a
remote station
like the platform the platform could be
a traditional os operation system or a
virtualization platform like a
hypervisor
and if the platform does not support
virtualization uh then the asset will be
application or process in the os if the
platform is a hypervisor and think that
the granularity of isf deserve a remote
headstation will be a virtual machine
because i think that in
in some
technology like tpm the vtpm may be not
convincible because it's the
virtualization it's not physical so
we need to
do not use that concept about like a
lack of vtpm
so
yeah this is a basic information about
draft so is there any comments
i will share share stop sharing a screen
is that okay
or
what should i do because
well
this this is
i'm confused are you gonna walk through
the
the decision
questions you had for the working group
at this time or later
i mean you mean the
decision of this draft
so
paul do you want to comment uh yes
i think yeah uh
very nice representation
uh thank you uh your own
okay sure okay
maybe
so
my comment is i think uh
i checked the uh let's
working group basically they are focused
on
the architectural procedure rather than
some interface young data model so
in order to provide
remote attestation to protect some
inside over
sprite chain attack i think
this work is i think very important also
currently the draft
has a right direction so we take
advantage of the previous our
itunes up to the young data model
and we can
synchronize with
the okay penguins um remote
attestation so
so i think it is a feasible to make also
um improvement
proof using of the future hackathon
project with the
paneling and our group together
okay that's my command thank you
thank you
okay uh roman you joined the queue
i think uh we plan is on the queue first
we pan ahead of me
okay go ahead we pen
uh i i have a um
aging question
and and i think you me
in this draft you mean to do the um
remote attestation for
um the virtualization platform and
as i know um in etsi isd nfv
they are also doing the remote um
develop their standards about the remote
station over
for the nfv so
i i don't know whether um there will be
overlaps
and so i i don't know how how deep um
this uh draft will go
for
about the virtualization
yeah as a virtualization is just one
scenario of our draft i think
and right now i haven't think too deep
about how to implement the remote
station in the virtualization
environment
and
i'm not sure how i uh actually work
about the
virtualization draft so i we
i think i can just
research it later and i can't give you a
direct answer right now sorry
okay okay
uh another another question or a comment
is about uh
you mentioned the sassy security access
age and
yeah i i think uh this may be um i don't
have maybe a helpful to be used in
this scenario so yeah but
but i don't know how they can be
implemented or
enhanced because but
if the ideal asset can be used in this
scenario it will
increase the applicable
um
or deployment in the industrial of i2
and theft so
i think maybe
we could consider this uh in the
recharge yeah
okay
yes i i
i agree to your comment because
i think assassin is a more advanced
technology of beyond the iphone sf but i
think isf is based on the is a flow
based uh network of security function
and the sashi is about the flow-based
and non-flow beta security function so
i'm not sure we can cover these two
different types but i agree with you we
can consider more about the sassy in the
returning thank you
okay roman and then diego
thanks uh thanks for the presentation it
was really helpful to also have the side
by side with uh with the rats and what
you're talking about and the way you
overlaid the architecture made it really
kind of clear what you're talking about
uh i have no ad hat on here i have two
clarifying questions asked so uh just
i'll ask them back to back so the first
one was
given that we're talking about the
network uh you know virtualized kind of
network functions i didn't understand
how exactly like you're shimming down to
a tpm without intermediaries and kind of
how the trust model would work given
given those intermediaries was my first
question and then my second question was
uh
there there is some work with the yang
model in chara that appears to be doing
attestation about kind of properties
from the tpm which seems like the same
root of trust that you're talking about
i i didn't understand
you know why that was insufficient
because i mean it's a young model i
guess i figured like you could pull that
out even if you know the the existing
rights architecture is a little
inconvenient as you were kind of
explaining why you just couldn't reuse
the modeling
thanks yeah the for the first question
is about in the virtualization scenario
and since the tpm is a hardware so the
vtpm may be not trusted so we think that
uh the hypervisor is the operation
system is the platform so we the the the
uh the the vm the virtual machine rides
on that we consider it as as a
maybe a process maybe a match which will
load to the hypervisor and the way when
at the start of the running of the
virtual machine we will uh measurement
the image of that vm so we will
uh
to see if it's trusted and that's my
opinion because i think that the tpm is
not very mature technology so we need to
do not use that yeah and the second
question you mentioned is that china and
i think china is about the how to uh
measurement uh how to measure a device
and it will send like the
uh email and measurement list to the
verifier but i think that uh
that is not convenient to the nsf
because that
uh in a scenario we may think that there
are three uh assets like there are three
uh uh
accepted in a platform and the first two
attractor and the third is not correct
so we want to uh to challenge the third
one and
when we use the character it's not
convenient because child will send you
all the message of the device it's not
focused on the sf that's what i think
maybe we i'll have to look into the
details
my understanding at least kind of with
on the chair is
yeah and i'm making a modeling
observation rather than an observation
on exactly how rats is using the word i
thought the way that
the ima was shimmed into kind of char
they were actually really flexible on
all the different properties and so all
of ime was in scope which gave you
properties beyond the initial uh
boot level kind of things which they are
saying is that they're trying to get but
i figured that some of that
the network virtualized kind of function
stuff could be shimmed into ima as a
generic modeling thing but i haven't
looked at the specifics enough to say it
sounds like it looks like you asked
yeah i agree with you
and
because because of what you said i
referred a lot information about the
character
well i i assume joao was saying now
diego so
i was trying to to read your lips
hello thank you
now
if you comment uh
originally set up a step up because of
the comment on on nfv but
there are
a few others
well regarding nav the what is proposed
here is not incompatible at all with
what that is doing right or what
we said she did some time ago among
other things
because what the t did was precisely to
identify a set of uh of level of
assurance for the procedures for
attesting
infrastructure or functions so probably
we could we could reuse some of the of
the
recommendations there on the levels of
assurance reference them but it's not
going to be incompatible and it would be
a natural revolution
i believe that precisely is the only
other way around whatever we start here
would be uh useful for for lc to refuel
the uh their work in the future but here
i think that the atf for this in
particular is
better suited because the i2nsf
architecture
has this this architecture with the uh
with the controller with the mechanisms
for for verifying etc that goes beyond
what that c
is concentrated that is about the life
cycle of the virtualized environment so
i i think that this there is i mean for
sure there will be can be or can be some
of small overlaps that isn't something
that would be
uh
easy to solve and for sure there is not
i don't foresee any any uh clear clash
in the future this is one thing the
second thing is regarding this
discussion on chara and the uh
and the applicability i think that chara
as a mechanism for for request and
response would be totally applicable in
this case
something else is about the claims and
how you restructure the claims and how
we structure the verification of the
claims and who is going to be the
verifier
how policies are going to be expressed
etc in general on monday if i remember
well it was at the tip session
and tip is doing precisely right now
something very similar to what we are
proposing here that is
taking rats architecture taking rats
concept taking the format for claims the
protocol etc and saying well look
for verifying from making the
attestation of a trusted execution
environment we will need this we need
that this claim was sufficient this
claim is not going to be sufficient
this kind of analysis is something that
we i mean i believe we have to do here
in the context of what we are that what
we have in place with the security
controller the different capabilities
etc that's
and i think that in that sense
what berlin says is proposing is
precisely goes in that in that direction
and well that and the proposal is
chapter in that is another source
thank you thank you
so
any more questions on this
so this is
good thank you very much
so now we go to the
next one
which is the
um
paul it's your turn to
can you share the slide from your side
paul can you share the screen
no we can now hear paul right
i cannot hear you
no we can't hear him no
not yet
okay
i'm not waiting here yeah okay okay can
you see my screen
no
wait okay
you okay great
so let me uh okay explain quickly uh we
have a limited time so i focus on uh the
analysis between consumer page interface
and nsp uh face interface
so this is our framework okay so this is
a consumer phasing interface and this is
an nsf face interface
okay so as you know the control phase
interface is full
okay front end the web
application is used usually uh deliver
high level security policy okay and then
typically um
highly policy can be translated into
rollable security policy by security
controller especially a security
policy translator
and nsf facing interface nfpi is focused
on providing security on detailed
configuration as a low level policy
okay
so
as you can see top level young tree
comparison
the most of the
element in young module similar okay
except
some description
right so
uh description on case
has omitted but also
the
both
uh cfi and fi
they provide the language tag and the
resolution are strategic okay
however you can see the difference is
some
default action play out of key uh usage
okay
so before the action and priority usage
omitted the um from
um tfi because uh our philosophy of gfi
to make cfr as simple as possible to let
a security operator specify high level
policy okay so
those
deposit action and the priority usage
can be
set
by security of policy translator okay
and also shared by end point group and
the threat prevention are used to
register information for a translation
purpose okay
next the low-level young tree are
carried okay so lure our
i2
case event condition action model or eca
right so
you can see even the condition action
okay so here also
event condition action okay so
but the long connection case here this
one is uh
typically used
to allow connection is maintained after
the connection even though there is no
traffic activity okay
so this kind of time
for um duration allow
the connection is alive even though
there is no actual traffic
so our
phosphate of the gfi
also applies to make
as simple as possible for gfi
okay
next
so and then uh event the case you can
see the sim chip the same this is saved
by this nfl right so description is for
the
operator some human uh letter of
sentences okay so
except that uh the same
and then this is um
condition so event condition action
right so condition case also
uh you can see
uh
usually uh we specify user group over
divisible can be translated into
error three ip addresses okay used by
the user or device icaderes okay so
those endpoint groups
are used to register
user group device group ip address okay
button 4 or version 6
eventually uh this information stored
in security controller and translated by
spirit controller
and then okay cfy
the msf easy security policy
configuration okay so i
saw right the ip address user device
group
ip addresses are stored into the
database in security control okay and
then some elements in nfi can be handled
by
uh security of policy translator okay
so so i can skip it and then condition
okay so condition case you can see
um
cfi condition and the nfi condition is
you can see the similar
with each other okay even though some
name is a little different but most of
the structure is the same
okay so
but
here note
the restoration of a variable name
here name and actual value
for condition here if i needed to read
a okay
done three controller
for an actual translation uh later okay
so
police translator can handle all those
things
and then um
so you can see uh cfr nfl young data
model similar for some
security attacks okay
ddos etc okay the difference is cfi
some information name and value
confirmation save the database for
easy configuration translation of
purpose okay and also
the name and the value compilation
can be stored so using this kind of xml
expat okay using this so we have this
example for a resolution of name value
for translation properties okay such as
the employee case they are using ip
addresses linkedin
device group web server case they are
using this kind of
the ip addresses
also
the sls website is this this one is for
the
database in the
security and controller for
transformation purpose okay and the next
one is the condition
so you can see condition
is almost the
same you can see the name
is the same description i mentioned the
there is no description
elements in the cfi
okay context contains extra information
especially the filtering of purposes
okay
and then other cases do the same
and then
you can see we have other information
geographic location so geographical
location
name and actual the corresponding ips or
if you address it
either ipv4 or ipv6 okay this also
literation is a
proponent okay
okay can you hear me
yes we can
okay great
so
you can see um
the young data model in cfi eventually
the context condition can be a
one-to-one mapped
to context condition in nfi which means
that we can translate okay except some
certain high-level value user group or
device group or geographic
some information can be translated the
specific ip addresses okay that can be
handled by a controller site okay so
time condition geographic
location can be handled okay
so in the action case okay let's move on
so we i explained the event condition
right now action so action case uh
we have a two action in cfi primary
action and secondary action okay usually
primary accident is um you can see
those things okay ingress
eagle action pass drop eject something
like that
and then secondary uh action case um
usually typical example is some logging
okay
so
we can
using
those kinds of packet level action and
the pro level action over advanced
action for dpi or some ddos attack
mitigation case we can
divide it into more detail in
nephi
so
remember also
some cases however cfi
policy tried to for example employee
cannot access some assessor website
during work time so in that case we need
two security services one is a fiver
based on ip addresses the other is web
filtering so those kind of
services can be
combined using uh service function
training in
nfi interface okay
so conclusion there is no translation of
problem from cfi policy
to nfi fallacy
so which means the security controller
can handle those missing
elements such as a deport some action or
priority can be handled by security
control law
and also shfi young data models provide
high level policy for easy configuration
so some detailed information um
register relation over federal name and
value can be done in advance into
database in security control law
and nfl young data model focus on
providing security policy
configuration for nfis
as a low level policy
okay so that's all so my message is
so cfi and nfi uh
young lady motor are synchronized also
uh can be easily uh translated we are
demonstrated using
um
the hackathon project so
i believe
now our cfi has a
okay the pre uh material
stage so
we can finish our working group let's
call and then we can
sum it to ies that is my opinion thank
you
so
okay let's move on uh legislation
linda
okay let's move on
okay
let's move on maturation quickly i can
just i finish
okay this one is very short okay uh
restoration interface is based on a
capability young data model because most
of
element young
imported from capability so
the resolution you can see
developer management
system registers
the capability of nsf okay into a
security controller okay
so
also so uh certain cases um
i don't have to use your
um to deliver however young um skills
policy right xml and then there is no
such kind of capability
um
nsf and then it can query
okay so and then a developer management
system are
so searching that kind of public and the
leicester again okay so we're providing
um two things one is a
quality the other one is uh
the
register okay of security
okay security nsf
capabilities okay
so objective over like simulation
interface
okay i mentioned right
uh two um
the futures okay
so
let me move on
so we have a two things i mentioned the
nsf capability resolution and the nsf
capability
so this is two features okay
and then we have this um information of
the model okay
so
the regulations have this hierarchy okay
so nsf capabilities
is imported by our capability data
models okay so other cases we also
providing access information
such as ip address and the portal number
for
nsf okay to provide the
specific security of
services okay
and then and this is the uh young tree
so
we import the security capability we
import okay
our itunes capability data model okay
other
uh performance capability cases
uh to explain that
okay capability in terms of some
processing
or vendor resistance and inbound or bond
okay and also access implement i
mentioned the ip address and photo
number for
nsf okay
so
other cases okay quality case also input
uh given some certain
quality such as some
for example web filtering the kind of
query is the input and then researching
on this okay
using this capability data model based
and then we make some external and then
we send to
vms okay and the dms return
corresponding capability to a security
controller and the secure controller can
translate appropriate to
another facing interface xml okay
so this is a corey okay
so this is xml example so
so we updated the uh restoration
interface xml example uh based on the
latest capability
um our track okay
so conclusion leisure interface has a
short
young data model
based on capability uh young data model
okay
so this one is almost okay done
except okay one uh discuss i believe
that also lifted uh
up soon okay and then most of the
changes
maturation interface just
um the
xml
syntax
based on capability young data model
and then additional information um
capability
performance information access
information can be provided by the
expansion interface okay that's all so
my conclusion is also literature
interface also ready to
submit to ict okay thank you
thank you very much
so
um the registration you're going to
import some of the capability data model
right you're going to raise them
okay yeah exactly yeah
okay thank you thank you any other
question from the
group
i guess thomas now here he was the one
complaining about inconsistency so we
can have to follow up with him on the
mailing list
um right
next we only have 10 minutes left um
right so
um for the chartered
china discussion
um can you
you have slides right
okay i have a slide so
maybe i share the uh the okay so maybe
we
uh okay to me let me give a couple
minutes so address
uh what extension is needed and then uh
so we can discuss okay
okay so
so
contrary uh we imp uh
okay
the application interface is required
because
uh monitoring interface okay
pull uh monitoring data from nsf and
then alternative analyzer
uh this is a new uh component okay in
our itunes framework using machine
learning and then they detect some
security attack over some
hardware or software problem uh from nsf
and then it gives some feedback
information so we need the application
interface okay that is a one one thing
also um
slides aren't being presented i don't
think i see it screen sharing is started
am i the only one
no oh oh no
okay so i'm sorry roma so i didn't push
the okay confirmation button okay yeah
no no you were clearly talking about
something but i wasn't seeing it and i
thought that would be helpful
okay great thank you so
okay
so this is uh the chartering the main
okay the you all okay
item is
to provide
some security or manage automation such
as monitoring data okay
from
monitoring interface
to
alternative analyzer so analyzer this is
a data collector also performing machine
learning
to detect some security attack
uh from nsf or
some hardware security or software
problem and then it gives feedback
information to
security controller they can augment
current
security policy or they make new
security policy so in order to that we
need
new okay interface or new
element that is um one
item
okay
so
eventually we need one interface okay
i explained okay
so the goal is that we um okay providing
security management automation case how
to extend our framework that is the
question okay
and i explained that okay and also
uh remember the roman uh explain the
right there is some insider and
spry chain of tag in our applicability
uh document right so in order to prevent
this kind of thing
we need to somehow remote
a destination or
we
need some auditing so maybe we can using
dlt technology
okay okay so
today apparently explained well remote
attachment okay so other latest system
technologies
2kd and the pqc
dlt so we can uh consider this one uh so
we can make uh one applicability and use
cases for those you know
current uh demands okay
and then uh we also consider
nowadays
there is some migration from
virtual machine to a container such as a
cloud native architecture so we need to
consider how to
support those kinds of okay container
deployment okay for itunes so we can
consider architecture also young data
model can be
extended for them
i have a question on this one so um for
the container based
architecture are you talking about
interface with kubernetes because
container is normally managed
controlled by kubernetes right exactly
yeah
so container cases
yes
okay okay go on so
okay so container case um
it is different from um vm virtual
machine approach so
uh
our case young data model this is for
the virtual maze machine based
model so we needed to augment somehow
okay
that is a
one input from okay some my collaborator
and the
next one is a sport
listen to the developed protocol such as
quick and http 3 so during last
capability um data model and
the another phasing case
so
in order to support this one we need
some
extra work so
that is our another yeah score
so in order to okay certify those
demands and we can extend our framework
okay for spirit to manage automation
so we can make application interface
and also
translation is actually important you
can see we can provide some
um some architecture also some
uh procedure also mapping
uh structure between high library young
data model and low level young model so
loma mentioned that the algorithm itself
not standard right but we can provide
some framework for our speed
transformation case i believe
uh is useful so we can decide the policy
the rfs or not we can decide later on
and the remote or destination we can
work on
and also
sport
dlt based on distributed system auditing
to prevent the supply chain and the
inside attack
and then
i transfer for container deployment we
can
also we can work on it
also applicability and use cases for
security managed automation including
the latest
the quantum computing
something like that also some actually
okay network
the inside computing technology we can
consider
and then
our next uh three case we can extend our
current nsf phasing
capability consumer pacing
to accommodate
the
new
protocols okay so we can uh maybe uh
revise later on
so there is a milestone okay so i just
make some estimation here okay that's
all
thank you so
there's a lot of lots of things to do um
any comments from the questions from the
group
okay
um
so um for the i just have one comment oh
roman you have comments
please do
no i mean diego i'm going to drop out of
diego has things to say i want to hear
from the community uh so let me drop out
and have the community talk here
okay sorry sorry for the for the delay
but i had to unblock the uh the phone
etc to raise my hand and
things are complicated in these days
basically it was uh i wanted just to uh
to to
make a remark on what linda was saying
about the containers and all the like
especially
that in general when you start to start
talking about containers basically what
you
is i have here several times oh well but
this kubernetes take care of these and
that
precisely we are assuming here and we
are implying in the in all the process a
particular trust model in which you have
the controller you have the capabilities
you have how you expose the capabilities
you make decision on that
i am under the belief that the the use
of uh
of course of containers and the uh the
fact that you can even
decompose functionalities in in uh in
smaller pieces both imply or would
require some changes and some of the
assumptions
that we have i mean it's not that have
the the the
solution or it's clear to me in which
aspects but i think that we have to
rethink some of the
of the aspects in the architecture to
really match
what is what implies the kubernetes
services uh lambdas and all the like
and and think about how we can reason
about uh security functions and under
deployment so i believe that this is uh
that makes the whole thing
uh
more challenging and let me insist when
it comes to at the station et cetera
we're talking precisely about adapting
the the architecture that rats is
proposing to this particular case and to
something that is equally important that
is precisely the automation part the uh
the uh box i go
right now the analyzer
how the analyzer perform the analysis
and how you can trust as well the
analyzer and what the analyzer decides
thank you
any other questions i think we are
reaching the end
three more minutes
roman
hi uh
so very interested to hear kind of what
the community thinks about that of this
list of work
my initial so first also thank you paul
like you doing the voiceover with the
slides was actually very helpful in
learning what you put in the text so
that's actually i think that's very
helpful to kind of facilitate the
conversation my initial reaction to this
is
there are definitely hard problems here
being enumerated this seems like a very
very large
and it almost seems like in each i mean
this is my initial kind of first boss
reaction of hearing the talk it seems
like some every one of those programs of
work is almost a working group uh you
know we talked most about one exact one
specific one about orchestration of
containers that that particular thing
seems
there's a lot of details of that there's
a lot of choices that brings together a
lot of things to the itf doing a
distributed ledger uh i mean we have a
whole other working group where we're
talking about doing that for supply
chain risk management as well so these
seem like very big topics
and
to tie this into what i said before
we're six and a half years into trying
to deliver our first tranche of things i
know we're getting close but we're still
six and a half years we didn't do it so
i would urge the working group to
continue talking about these and try to
really think through what scope will
want to tackle first and what what
bandwidth is there to tackle out of
those dopes
thank you
very very very fast
uh it's uh i i i i agree with roman that
from time to time i mean the temptation
of this famous uh term avoiding the
ocean and whatever that we whatever the
endeavor that we start is there
the point is that uh
you you say with roman it's a
is the fact that the idea is not to
invent a new way of using dlts so it is
not a new way of inventing how to use uh
uh at the station et cetera especially
leverage of what many other groups are
doing and trying to profile it for the
case i mean we are going to i mean
if you ask me for sure i will try to
climb on the on the shoulder of giants
as uh as uh sir isaac did some time i
ago precisely with the idea of free
reusing all the work that is there and
using it for enhancing the the
architecture that's basically yeah
we can for sure we can we should
elaborate a little bit more in terms of
priorities
for sure
okay very good thank you thank you so
much
thank you
so i think we have reached our limit for
this meeting well thank you everybody
it's very interesting informative
session
and we will continue on the mailing list
especially on the
priority of the next seven works to be
done by the working group as roman said
we shouldn't make it too big and make it
manageable thank you
so much thank you
i think with this you'll have to okay
there are actually
people willing to do the work there's
22 people in the room i'm not talking
about the physical room
the whole meeting there's 22 people and
the conversation here has pretty much
mostly been
three people
if we don't count chairs and babies
it's three people
and well there's a suit who
didn't speak up but she is acting on the
mailing list other than that were
pretty much don't have people
but okay i guess we need to discuss this
on the mailing list and with the abs
okay great okay okay
okay thank you bye
trying to save the
document and publish it i'm going to
download it and
um
send it as well
okay
i'll download it and mark down and then
yeah that that's a
very good suicide and and good to hear
your voice
okay so
it's good to hear yours like
we are asking you what's more important
paul you did an awesome job
thank you very much yeah i appreciate
your support and help okay diego you too
okay
so we should meet uh in