hi sue can you hear me
we can hear you loud and clear
super i'm having trouble loading up the
slides for some reason
so how long have you been back in the
u.s
um yesterday
well it hasn't been today for too long
in in california
okay
uh
oh
this
okay
so are you there
yes
yes i'm here
good thanks
i'm here i just think my medical is
crashed um i can't get into the
participants list
so
we'll see what happens yes
yeah jeff are you there
jeff i can't hear you
i am here
super i'm having trouble uh jeff uh
sharing slides
for some reason
okay we have it
here just click your slides that's all
i've done
so let me end the chair i'm just
clicking the share icon directly to the
right of the join q hand
yeah it's not loading the right chair
slides
all right what browser are you using
uh firefox
same
seems to be the old slide decks
even if i refresh them it's not
uploading the right slides
they auto loaded them if and they pulled
the list beforehand if you change the
slides at the last minute they could
easily have autoloaded the wrong slide
you need to then go in
delete the slide deck
pull add slide deck and the
tool button and the tool icon manage
slides
yeah the meeting materials
is showing the right set of slide text
reloading reloading them let's see
okay you do you want to try sharing your
screen
if you have the slide deck in front of
you
yeah i could do that
can you see them
yeah
so
all right we should get started
so jeff
about seven minutes late apologies
welcome folks uh to idr session 2 on the
last day of itf 13.
um
can you folks hear me well this is kev
can you hear me well
all right super uh let's get started
we're about seven minutes late apologies
for that uh
here is the note well um
it says uh that
if you're participating in itf you agree
to follow the rules um those of you who
haven't seen this um should pay special
attention to the notewell itself
uh meeting tips
wanting to make sure
um how to sign into the session here is
our point is for that
point is to the random resources which
may be very useful to you um again for
the agenda as well as the preparations
and
we have a full agenda today uh with uh
lots of drafts so we would like to make
sure most of the questions that you may
have
please take it
on to the chat
or on the mailing list yeah
here is the agenda
any questions uh before we get started
all right
um shoe bang
i am just
going to
now switch to the pre-loaded slide
screen
can you hear me
yes
good
okay go for it
thank you chair
and this is shooking i'm going to
present this uh ap flows back next
please
since we have presented a few times in
this meeting and we have official wiki
and without the epm active drafts so you
could refer to so here escape the
introduction of the apn
and for the flowspack we define a new
flowspace component apid and here is we
use the lens to indicate the
mask and ap id lens and we use the mask
to indicate the base of the apn id that
needs to be matched
and here we give an example for example
the apn id there are two parts and the
group id app group id and user group id
and in the mask we have the base
which uh here you could see that it's
actually
indicates the parts of the app group id
and when it is matched
the app group id in the float space
we lost you
so
are you there
yes can you hear me now
yes much better please continue okay yes
so and when it's matched that that means
a successful match
and next at least
yes here we define four traffic
filtering actions
and here i used figures the diagrams to
show the first one the marking actually
we this one can be used to mark the
entire ap id which can be encapsulated
in the uh the
packets and here the second one is used
to
to uh match the
the mark to mark the partial parts of
the apn id which is carried in the float
spec and the the third one is used for
inherit the pin id which was carried in
the original package and that means when
you want to copy and
encapsulate the ap id in the outer
tunnel header and then for the
third one the fourth one is we use that
for the stitching
and that means you will get part of
typing id from the original package and
then stitch with the one the part of the
ap id in the flows back
next please
and here
there are some it is about the ordering
and organizations of the flow spec for
apn because we found two things one is
that there is not only the flows back
rules for apn and there are also other
rules so they will be co-existing
and the second is that uh
the ap id has different parts and for
each part that can be determined by
different
flow spec rules so considering that
these two
consider
conditions and here
we we defined is um
[Music]
two
two categories one is sub group id
and
the other one is a group id and for all
the ap and float back rules we put it
into one group and use the group id to
indicate that
and for others we put we could put the
rules into another groups
and for the subgroup
for each subgroup we use it to contain
the rules for a specific part of the
apid so here we also give the uses
principles
so within a subgroup
that is uh
the same as what we have already defined
so this
i i want to
repeat and for between between
some groups that because each subgroup
is ordered with id
and if the evaluation in one sub group
stops or finished
it will
start the evaluation in the following
subgroup
if there is any left
and between the group set
so the group is ordered with the group
id
and if at least the one condition in
this group is matched
and when the
evaluation reached to the end
it won't
continue the evaluation will stop
okay so
i think that is all
next
yeah
so do you have any questions or comments
thank you
jeff you have the mic
thanks for the presentation too common
first one is that this feature will
require spec v2 we currently have no way
to extend flowspec v1
second comment is the ordering for your
group and subgroup may need further
discussion
uh there's gonna be discussion about how
rules are ordered in flow spec v2 and
you'll want to make sure that
you pay attention to that discussion
thank you
yeah sure and uh
i think this can be smoothly removed to
the v2 but of course we can discuss
about that
thank you so much
thank you shubang
thank you
the next one
is
uh
shown one
hi everyone i am
the topic like letter i am presentation
is a traffickers italian used in bgp
follows vector with srv6
six policy this is a work done by
several wonders is under the
organization of china mobile
next please
okay
this worker
has a vm presentation
presented at ietf
once vlog 105 meetings and we got a few
good feedback from the ieti
community thanks to everyone
for their use for comments and
suggestions
at this point
all the comments have have been
addressed
since what john and jeff's comment
data has been changed to
informational
overload is informational the
specification this library in this
document is very useful it can have a
unified
implementation across
multi-wonders
the most important update is that we
have added a second to report multi
implementations
next please
we have oriented this detailed solution
twice
in the past the presentations
under here
are some summary information
our basic
idea is to you
re reuse the components of components
from maltese then dark
documents based on
past comments
we add some more clear this
collaboration here
they are also described in the jobs
number one
and the current stage
this work
discusses how to use the flash vector to
match the global routine table prefix
number two
we only support the usage of one
redirect ip community under one color
community
how to support a multi-extended
community attribute will be discussed
in the
in the other jobs
next please oh no no no number three uh
both the uh intro s and the inter s use
case are supported
number four uh regarding the usage of
prefix attribute component we have two
options
if the last srv6 sid in the segment list
is usd flavored
then we can use option two
both two options
have already been supported by multi
wonders
next please
okay
this work
has been implemented by marty wonders
and the multiple mutations had a good
inter operatibility test
which is hosted by china mobile
following table shows the participating
wonders under the device let's pass the
test
uh sends to channel mobile
for putting multi wonders into a perfect
team
thanks to all the wonders who
contributed to this work
next please
okay
next next data we will update the
information implementation report to the
idr wiki
and
all the no
known
comments has been addressed the
way request wg adorable
this worker
the any questions or comments are where
kinda
that's all thank you for your attention
to this work
yes yes song you have the mic please
me
yes okay perfect okay thank you okay
i mean sun liu from the china mobile
and i want to say that currently there
is a lot of public network traffic in
china mobile network
and as a operator i think it is very
useful to optimize the traffic for
by the using the btp flow spec with the
sri 6 policy
and we have completed the lab into our
test with multiple vendors as schwein
mentioned
and so
i think it is also available for the
working group thank you
thank you
thank you so much
oh thank you
whim
you have a mic
you have any killer
post a draft but uh is a draft already
in idr that does something similar so i
will i will post it in in the
as an email but i think we should look
to see whether we can have synergies
between that proposal already because
that's already has progressed quite a
bit already
okay
thank you
[Music]
oh thank you
next on the agenda is uh bgp flow
specifications for
that net flow mapping
can you hear me
yes i can hear you well please
completely
okay okay thank you
and uh um tren show from city this is a
bgp flow specification for the net flow
mapping next slide please
so first uh we look at the update from
last version
we have presented at itf one one two and
got flip feedback from uh that led and
the idea working group they are very
appreciated first we got performance
from the lecture it is required to
clarify that this document is focused on
tsm mapping not generic does not
and second that the net charts are okay
to
work on this target in either the net or
idr
and we also got comments from every uh
it leads to be implemented to uh
in flossback version two so based on the
comments we changed the draft name to
clarify the ts tsm mapping
it is now uh is the
bgp flow specification for the flat and
the tsn flow mapping
we also changed the extensions from a
bhp fs version to one to uh bgp fs
version two as per the uh s divide in
draft health idr flows back version two
um
and we added either tsn subtree in bhp
fs version 2 l2 header gre we also add a
sequence action sub-tier vhp fs version
to wide community
we enter a netlist sub-qre in bgpfs
version 2 in
ipad or tlv
value we add tsm action sub-theory in
bhp fs version 2 white community
unless my please
so this is the overview with csm and
that
mapping
uh dividing rfc 8655.net
might uh provide that it means the
deterministic
service for the tsm end system and the
night ip and the mps flows may be
carried over tsm sub networks so the
pro
primary requirements of the controller
play for the tsn and then that flow
mapping is as flows the mapping between
tsm streams and deadline flows is
required for the
service proxy function at the led engine
modes and the
mapping table can be configured and
maintained in the control plane so this
document proposed the extensions to hpfs
version 2 for tsm and the net mapping by
using their traffic filtering rules to
identify the packet and using the
associated action to map the package to
the related service
so let's let this
so we first proposed the btpfs
extensions for tsnt3 mapping to data
flow
for the filtering rules for tsn streams
there are
a string id is a 64-bit field that
identifies the string in tsn and the
spring identification functions are
defined in actually
under other parameters has been uh
defined in
idr flows back lt2 vpn and and so this
document
proposed a new tsn sub-theory in
l2 heteroe to
uh
identify the guessing
string id
we just propose the
mask and match screen and a vacation
uh in uh for tencent uh traffic
filtering and for
traffic action uh yes for the streams
the action is to accept the tsn streams
and that matches the law and matter
streams to the net flows so
their action for l3 traffic
with extended communities has defined
manning parameters
uh in uh the bgp flows back label draft
so this document proposed the sequence
action subtree uh in uh bgpfs version
two white community
next slide please
so for the netflow mapping to tsm string
in bgpfs extension
for uh
filtering uh rules uh for tesla flows uh
the
l3
rings have defined and can be used for
net ip flow uh for example as label
intellect mps flow can use the filtering
rule defined in after itf ideal for spec
mps patch so this document uh proposed a
data sub tree in bhp fs version 2
in ip header tle
we just
defined the dcw in for the download and
ps4
for the traffic action for
that net flows
the extension extended action for and
and that traffic filtering is to
accept the tesla flows that manchester
the ruler and the matter flows through
their tests and strings so this document
proposes under psn action software
in php fs version 2 white community
this
tss provide can be
defined to
convert it to the screen related
parameters for example the tsn string id
screen handle sequence number and the
traffic scheduling function
next map is
this is what the extension for bgp fs
version two uh next slide step we would
like to discuss and collaborate with bgp
fs version two and the draft uh help idr
flows back version 2. so comments and
their discussions are very welcome thank
you
any questions
zoozong please go ahead
thank you
hi hi don't hear me well
yes
oh thank you this is joseon from huawei
one question for the six number because
indiana six number is used for the
emerge the redundancy flows
so i'm i'm
i am not quite understand why we use six
number as the filter of a tsn flow maybe
more
explanation or descriptions could be
ended here
yeah thank you for your comments uh we
will add the
description
in last version thank you
thank you so much
so the next um topic on the
um
on the
for the discussion is the bgp auto
config
discussions jeff
and sue
do you want to take a lead on that
jeff
yes i'm here
i don't
recall that being as part of our core
agenda but
certainly there should have been sure
slides to go with it if so
okay perfect and we'll continue
next on the list is then in that case
ls extensions
for our
sr policy extensions for the matrix
g
well i think the next one is uh
as a policy it flows back it goes back
up
for the
load balancing group on the agenda
or do you want to
shift them
it's not appearing on the
list
so
yeah this one
perfect
care me
yes i can hear you please go ahead
thank you
uh hello everyone
and this is
maui
today i'm going to talk about
people's back redirect load currency
group community
network is
first let me explain the motivation
because
traffic
in some scenario due to
as traffic
to
a lottery one from lotus zero we may
want to steer traffic to lottery to
lotus rate and load flow
in a ratio of one two two to two
and then if the controller suppose
detecting the network the ratio could be
changing according to network running
status
and the loaders may be deployed in ip
and prs or srv6
networks
so i expected to support all types
also in some improvements in
ecmp of redirect to ip action can be
achieved by encoding multiple redirect
extended
communities
the current
sites of
mechanisms can hardly support each
example of sry6 tunnels nor usamp of
other types
let's slide please
and to achieve this will propose
redirect load balancing global community
it is an exciting to prep community
container attribute
defined in the what vlp
communities draft
it allows traffic direction to a load
balancing group and suppose
both ccmp and the usmp scenarios
as the picture shows the general format
comply with bjp community container
attribute
for example the face of the type
flash reserved links
community value source es number and
contact as number
combined with the corresponding
definition
in bdp community container attribute
we define a new community value
representing the related load balancing
global community type
the value is to be defined
and subtype is three representing bdp
while committee parameter tra defunded
in what vlp community's draft
and the
uh answer
parameter must
present and show the appearance on ones
in a redirect load balancing global
community
parameter theory contains audit a list
of atoms
each liberations was massive for
radiation action
next slide please
atoms are encoded as theories which
comply with the community atom format
and we define some atom difference of
atoms for mass the figure is one over
four mass
its ipoh6 preface with color and weight
indicating the derivation path is
weighted and to a srv6 tunnel
it contains the phase of the type
lens flag accuracy
color and weight
the type is used exclusively with the
redirect load balancing global community
and the type of value is 8
the length is phase for each atom
the flag is the two actors reserved for
filter use must be set to zero
the ip video is ip video address
or asa 610 and pawn for redirection the
car is srv6 channel color for
redirection
the weight is the load balancing weight
on next slide please
and currently we have introduced eight
types actions
for both ipv4 and ipv6 nest
coverall profits only price with weight
price phase and color profits and color
with weight
in pre-simple sub-theories may be
combined in any mode
the supported combinations depend on the
specific implementations
the redirect global community contains
more than one atoms
if not
all atoms are of a weighted type these
atoms will form a ecmp group if all
atoms are of a weighted type
these atoms will form a usmp group
in this case the
weight field value of these atoms should
be ignored
and the values are used
as
the ratio of the usmp group
and let's try please
welcome more comments and discard
thank you
jeff you have the mic
thank you for your presentation
uh a couple of things
first thing
we will ask the authors for white
communities to review your extensions
for the atoms and
offer some advice
as an example it's unclear whether we
need a new atom for color
uh an integer could work in that spot as
an example
but that's a small detail
the second item i would ask you to
consider in your draft is as flow spec
v2 begins its work and is starting to
look at how to do load balancing and
potentially
interactions of different actions
we need to figure out
how this feature is intended to behave
if you have more than one type of
redirect community present
it may just simply be an error case
it would be good if you discussed that
in your document
thank you
super thanks sue you have the mic
can you hear me
okay yes yes let's go ahead okay well
would you go back one slider here would
you go back one slide
two slides i think
one thing i didn't understand in your
discussion
um
is
what please go one more slide down here
i'll see if i can help
this one okay
um no but i'll just uh
number five please
that'll help you
the question is
you had a discussion for waiting on
these it would be good to discuss
not only if you can handle one as jeff
said or one other there are other ones
and then i didn't quite i'd like you to
improve the text on reading and i think
i'll just leave it at that
uh
karen you can go on well we can i'm glad
to chat with you offline on this one
uh jeff is correct on the white
communities
i have questions specifically on how
you're waiting this compared to other
things
in the v2 spec so we'll go from there
later
super thank you so much wolf okay thank
you thank you
hi
thank you
all right g you're next
okay can you help me
yes i can
okay hello everyone this is jaden from
huawei
i'm going to give an update about this
draft called bgprs extensions for the
scalable sr based enhanced vpn
okay next page please
first some background about this work
we have the vp framework in the test
working group which is
described the framework for the enhanced
vaping services and one of the typical
use case
is to deliver the itf network slide
service
and item narrative slice framework is
also describing this
and that document introduced a concept
called
natural resource partition for the
natural slice realization
and in the context of of network slicing
narpy is considered as an instant
instantiation of the vp vtn defined in
the vpn plus framework
and
considering the scalability of the nrp
is important we have another draft in
the test working group which is working
on the
analysis and the optimization
considerations of the scalability of nrp
in both the control plane and the data
plane
it also provides some guidelines for the
protocol extensions
and for the igp extensions to provide a
scalable sr-based vaping plus service
there's a draft in the rsr working group
so here uh in the idr we would like to
introduce the bgp rs extensions to for
the scalable sr based vpn plus
this document introduced mechanisms to
distribute the intro domain and the
inter domain nrp topology and resource
attributes to the network
controller okay next page
yeah here we would like to give an
overview of the related documents in
several working groups as i just
mentioned
the framework documents are in this
working group which includes the itm
network slides
document it is working on the concept
and the general framework and the
vpnplus framework
provides a
mechanism which can be used for the
slice realization the nrp scalability
considerations is also in the test
working group
and for the data plane there are several
data plane capsulations mechanisms
to carry the
rpo
specific information the first approach
is described in the spring working group
based on the resource aware segments
and in the ipv6 based encapsulation
there's another draft based using the
ipv6 hardware hub extension headers to
carry the vtn id or we can call it uh an
rpid maybe
there's also another drafting mpls
working group to provide a similar
functionality
for the control plane we have several
set of drafts and for the control plane
and to distribute the vtn rp information
both in the network domains and to the
network controllers
uh
and this document is just one of this
set and it provides a scalable between
nrp information distribution
we also have the drafts
working on the nrp of 18 specific pass
computation and instantiation based on
sr bgpsr policy or psat protocol
then in the management plane there's uh
young data models and to provide another
slide service
model to the network size customers and
also an rpm model for the installation
of the nrp in the network
okay next page
so
some information about the optimization
introduced in this document the first is
uh to improve the scalability
uh
the
the practical mechanism is to map
multiple overlay connectivity services
to one shared vision of nrp
so that nrp provides the underlying
network topology and the resources
required by a group of the services
and the second approach is that we can
decouple the resource attribute of the
narpy so that multiple vietnamese can
share the same topology and also they
can share the topologies but specific
route computation
uh we can also allow multiple nrps to
share the same set of resources on some
of the network segments to allow
flexible resource isolation or sharing
based on the requirements
the last point is
to introduce a network-wide
data plane identifier in the packet so
that we can avoid to introduce
additional
uh per nrp
src's or srv6 locators in the network
so we will talk about the pgprs
extension will achieve these
optimizations in the following slides
okay next page please
so here is the first extension we
introduced the nrp definition sub dre
in the
pg uh maybe recorded trv in the bgp rs
attribute which is associated with the
node nri
it is used to advertise the relationship
between the nrp and the associated
topology and algorithms and other
attributes
here this
trva contains a 32-bit network
identifier of the nrp
and there's a mtid field to carry the
topology id associated with an rp
and another 8-bit algorithm id field
which can be either a normal algorithm
or the flexible algorithm
it also introduces a sub-sub-trvs for
the future extension for optional
attributes associated with nrp
okay
next slide
the second extension is to introduce an
rpid subtle
which is used to describe the list of an
rps that link belongs to and this can be
carried in the bgprs attribute which is
associated with a link nri
it can be used for both the intro domain
links and also the internal links
so the format of the tre is shown here
it basically contains a list of the nrp
ids and the flag field and the result
field
it also can be used as a subtree for the
layer to bundle member attribute tlv we
will talk about this
in the following slides
okay next page
the third the third extension introduced
is to
have a link attribute flags tlv
it is used to specify the attributes of
a link
and it can be carried in the bgprs
attribute associated with the link nri
or as a sub to v in the l to bundle
member attributes dlv
and the flat and the field
the format of this uh
htlv is consistent with the flag fields
defined in the isis link attribute sub
to
and here we introduce a new flag called
e flat
so it is used to indicate whether the
link is can be used for load balancing
across a bundle or the
group of links or it is can only be used
exclusively for the traffic associated
with a specific set of nrps
okay next page
so uh for the topology information
action distribution
um
here
for the intra domain topology
advertisement
we would reuse the existing
multitopology and flash algo based
mechanisms
and multiple uh nrps can associate with
the same topology algorithm tuple to
avoid the
duplicated topology information
distribution in the network
here the multi topology is used to
define the logical topology and the
topology link node attributes
and flash algo can be used to specify
magic type and the topological
constraints which apply to topology
and with the extension
for s-segment routing
we can also distribute the pro topology
algorithm srcs and srv6 locators using
bgp rs
okay next page
g are you still around i can hear you
can you hear me
yes i can hear you now okay uh so we are
on this page into domain topology
okay
so for the introduced methodology
information advertisement we will reuse
the bgpr scpe to distribute the inner
domain link connectivity and also the
bjp pairing segments
including the pure adjacency seed pure
node seed and the pss
and here
we will also
need to use the nrpids tlv
in the bgprs attribute of the interdom
link nri so that we can describe the
list of analyze in our piece the
interdomain link is associated with
okay next slide please
okay for the
resource attribute advertisement
for each nrp we have
considered two options
the first option is to use a auto bundle
based approach so that we consider
each partition of the link resource as a
physical or virtual l2 bundle member
link of the layers reading so that we
can use the bgprs extensions for the
auto bundle member links to advertise
the bandwidth and other tea attributes
of this
partitioning resource partition
and to associate this r2 member link
with the nrps we also use the nrp id
subtlv
with this pgprs auto bundle member
attribute tlv
here we also use the to
link ashby flags
uh as an e-flag defined in this document
in to indicate whether this bundle
member link can be used for load
balancing or it is exclusively
for the nrp's usage
and for the t attributes uh
information like the bandwidth and other
t attributes of the autobundle member
link this can be
advertised by reusing the existing t
attributes of the bgprs
okay next page thanks
and the second option is we can
use the nrp link t attributes to
advertise the different partition of the
resources are allocated to the different
rps on the link
so that this upper energy specific t
attribute rv is defined
which contains a list of the nrp ids and
the list of the t attributes which are
shared by the
set of the narratives on this specific
link
okay next slide please
okay this uh
in in addition to the advertisement of
the topology and the resource attribute
we also need to advertise
the nrp specific uh data plan ids so
that we can generate the forwarding
entries for different nrps
here are also two options the first one
is we can use per nrp src's or srv6
locators and it's
falling this way we need to add a set of
new tlv or sub trvs for the
advertisement of the
nrp specific
amperage seed or nabi specific services
locators and seeds
the second option is we use the
mechanism optimization mechanism
mentioned in the beginning we use
dedicated nrp ids in the data plane so
that we can use the same id
in the data plane as the one in the
control plane
this this way we don't need to advertise
additional nrp specific
ids for the data plane
and this can
save the
problem and resources for the additional
id distribution
and in this mechanism need to introduce
the new encapsulations in the packet and
the encapsulations for ipv6 and mpls uh
described in the separate drafts in the
t as ib
six-man and the ampere smoking group
okay next slide
okay so
for this document we would like to hear
comments and feedbacks about this
approaches and the options described
so that we can refine the document in
next
revision
and by the way we would like to mention
that we are working on the terminology
alignment with the test documents and
other
igp extension drafts
like the fbt and rp we will align them
in the next version
thank you
comments
thank you g
okay thank you thank you
next uh we have is uh giuseppe uh for
who's going to talk about sr policy
extensions for ife giuseppe can you hear
me hello everybody can you hear me
yep
please go ahead
yeah this is an update about the
bgpsr police extension for ifit so next
slide
yeah just a quick background so
i fit denoted all the on path
uh telemetry technique so in particular
in c2im and alternate marking
we all know that and then can be
informed about the candidate part
for nsr policy by using bgp and there is
a well advanced document on that so
this
draft simply extend
this document and extend bgp to
distribute as a policy carrying also the
ifit information in this way
uh iom and alternate marking can be
enabled that automatically when the sf
policy is activated
next slide
yeah this is basically
the
extension so
how the i feed attributes are
included in the bgp
[Music]
as a bgp extension so at
candidate part level dfi attributes are
attached as some tlvs
since the sr policy candidate part is
encoded in the tunnel encapsulation
attribute it is
simply it simply extends
the
the attributes defined in the itf idr
segment routing t policy graph
so as i said there are five sub tlvs
currently defined four four in c2im and
one for alternate market
uh next slide
next slide i guess there are the details
of the sub tlds
uh of course they are aligned with the
relevant document for in c2im and
alternate marking
next slide
yeah in this slide we just
explain how this document complements
the sr policy operation described in the
segment routing t policy draft
so the only addition uh is that
after the event can be informed about
multiple candidate parts via bgp or psf
or preset additional information uh like
ifeet are included at candidate part
level and then the selection of the best
candidate part can be done and
selected and installed in the forwarding
plane
it may be possible for an implementation
to choose the candidate path also
considering the supported by hit
attributes based on the local
configuration
and then the effect methods in c2im and
or alternate marking can be enabled
automatically
next slide
okay yeah we consider this document
quite relevant to enable um in c2im and
alternate marking for
control mechanism
as as also mentioned before this is a
simple extension of
of the current draft on segment routing
t policy
of course we welcome questions and
comments on this
thank you
thank you so much any questions
cool thank you
okay thank you
next on the presentation we have uh
sid algorithm information in pgp
uh by yao
hi everyone
this is a yao leo from zte
and the presentation is about
advertising set algorithm information
bgp
next slide please
as introduced in the
draft segment routine t policy eleven
segment types
uh segment sub trees uh from type a to
type k are defined between code sisps or
srv6 segments
and sr algorithm can be optional that it
can be optionally specified in
segmented sub-trees for simplest prefix
srv6 prefix and srv6 adjacency and this
document defines some new segment sub
tvs with algorithm
to meet more requirements when
delivering as a policy via pgp
next slide
one kind of new second sub tv is simples
adjacency with optional algorithm
and the draft idf lsr algorithm related
adjacency complements that besides
prefix it the algorithm can also be
included as a part of an sim prs
adjacency
advertisement
in scenarios where multiple algorithms
share the same link resource
so in this case
an simples policy advertised to the
haddad may also contain
algorithm specific
adjacency
following are the four new segment sub
theories
the formats are similar
as the existing type e f g and h
except that there is an optional
algorithm field with the
next slide
um so i'm gonna escape the detailed
structure of the new segment subject
next piece
and another new kind of
segment sub theory is
set only with optional algorithm
carrying the algorithm information along
with the seats can be used for
verification purpose the header can
check if the set value and the related
algorithm
received can
whether
whether it can be found in its srdb if
request to do so
and the header may also need
to know about the city-related algorithm
for troubleshooting and network
management
so type l and type n are defined
separately in this draft for as i am plc
set and as i said said
the familiar uh the format of
similar to type a and type b segment
sub-tree
except that there's an optional
algorithm algorithm field
next slide
yeah that's all and we welcome feedbacks
and comments thank you
thank you so much
caitanya you have a mic
thanks for the present
thanks for the presentation
uh
i think a couple of those uh
seems valid or new uh
where adjacency said was
for adjacency said we introduced
algorithms
i'm not sure about other ones
but in any case it would be good to get
some review or feedback from spring
working
thank you
oh sure thank you
any other questions
for y'all
thank you so much yo
okay
next presentation we have is on bgps or
policy extensions for metric uh
this is kazan car you have a mic
hello can you hear me
yes
okay thank you
my topic is bgp as a policy extension
for metric i'm cut down from huawei
next slide please
uh as a bdp can be used to propagate the
extra policy candidate paths to the
heart and nodes in the network and
using bdp the as a policy as a f i can
be
encoded like this and
with the
with the k distinguished policy color
and endpoint and each candidate path can
have several segments list
next slide please
by using bgp as a policy
controllers may deliver different asset
policies which satisfy the constraints
of vpns or bdp routers
but sometimes the bp router of a pin
router needs to choose the next hub
according to the igp metric of each sr
policy for example in this scenario
on p1 the router prefix c2 has two
different next half
one next top is p3 the other next top is
p4 and each next hop has
one as a policy as a policy one as a
policy tool
both as a policies satisfy the delay and
the bandwidth constraints
and the magic
the idp metric of active parts of as a
policy wire which is the p1 to p p1 to
p3
the igp matrix is 20 and the
whereas the igp matrix of the active
path of sr policy 2
which is p1 to p2 to p2 and 2
p4 the igp matrix is 120
in this case if p1 wants to choose the
laptop according to the igp metric of i
as a policies
that's neither uh the i need to know the
actual
adp metric of the
as a policy thus the controller should
deliver the idp metric of sr policies
using bdp as the policy protocol
next slide please
uh to solve this problem we propose to
add the matric subtype of it to bgp as a
policy protocol the matrix sub two way
is added as a subject of segmentalist
next slide please
and the four the format of magic subtly
is defined as as follows
uh here the the type of magic is to be
defined the length is sex
and the magic type specifies
the
magic type
now we can define the uh
several several values for example igp
magic t magic hop counts delay
or loss losslytometric
and the
magical value is encoded in three
inserted 32 bits ieee for a from
floating point format
next slide please
and by using the uh the idp magic of as
a policies
the controller can deliver the
the is metric of different uh as a
policies and then on p1 because
we can get two different types of
policies and the idp magic is different
thus p1 can choose the next hub
according to idp metric and then
the results the routing choosing result
is
next hope is p3
next slide please
when as a policy head and get as a
policy second list with with magical how
to process the metric is local policy
for example the active candidate parts
of essa policy may have several segment
lists
each sectionalists have different
metrics
it is recommended that the secondaries
in one candidate pass have the same
magic type
and if the magic values of segmentalists
in one candidate pass are different the
candidate path magic can use the minimum
value as the magic of the candid path
and the asset policy use the magic value
of the active candidate paths
the as a policymatic value then can be
used in routine preference
next started please
and
that's all welcome questions and
comments thank you
any questions for carl
luke please go ahead yeah mike
what's the consideration about
the internal injury
while your extra policy
is across multiple igp demands because
your expansion is about
igp magic
what's the entertainment menu
okay
different
because
the different as a policy path may may
also satisfy the the my the delay or
bandwidth
of the application and
so
the application may want to idp magic to
choose a different hub
thus we need to know the the idp metric
of the
parts of sr policies
so
if the sr policy is across
multiple igp domains
is this scenario out of scope or have
other considerations
okay
then then uh
the controller may
may control different areas of igp then
the controller can know the
idp matrix of all the whole paths so the
controller can download the idp magical
to the
device
okay let's take it to the list thank you
thank you
actually i got a question for you um
you have defined
different matrix
do you also have to define another
matrix type for aigp or aigp is not
applicable here
okay
maybe
we can add
add it to the metric tab the magnet have
can be extended
okay super super you may want to
consider that
yeah yeah okay
thank you
thank you very much
the next presentation we have is bgp for
beer de path um this is going to be
presented by
haimo yes
please go ahead
hello everyone today i'm going to talk
about the pgpe or bate pass
next page
so i would like to thank uh jeffrey john
susan
and tony p for their valuable comments
and suggestions
so according to their suggestions we
made some updates these updates to the
previous version include
selecting partner type for blt pass on
the tunnel in cap attribute
and make
making some editorial changes next page
on the terminal
in-cap attribute type 23
we define
terminal encapsulation plv
for vit pass
this tlv
contains
some subtle v's
this sub tv includes
bat pass sub v
b a t pass lame subtle v
and
pass
identifier snapper tail v
b t
pass subtle v
encodes
the explicit plt path
vit
name
past name subtle v
consists of
the name
of the bat
path
pass id
subtle v
contains
sub domain id
bfr id
of the inquiries of the
bate path
and the tunnel id
and the pass number
next page
so i think that after
the updates the draft is uh
clear and simple and uh uh we but we
will still
welcome comments and i would like to
request for adoption
are we taking questions comments
can they still hear us
why don't you go ahead
okay jeffrey drum from juniper
um we probably don't need to call it as
beer tea just call it beer then whether
it's a beer tea or not it does not
really matter probably just call it beer
yeah that's okay that's okay yeah
there's no problem for me
thank you
all right
so you're next
just so you know
your draft is in
the queue for adoption i have a favor to
ask do you think you could
um ask the
bigger chairs to summarize
uh their work in this area and send it
to us or shall i do that
it's it's good i think it's part of the
pre-adoption cycle we need to
have an understanding of
uh is this conflict
uh is this something that the beer
working group is
thought of worked on is it something i
think we should pick up
that would be helpful did you do that a
couple
sessions ago and i'm forgetting it
oh you mean uh request request a child
of a beer to have a summary of this one
how this
how this fits in the rest of the bear
group we can send it to the chairs and i
can re
focus if he doesn't want to send it
directly to the idr group but one of the
questions
is how does this fit in the rest of the
architecture
the architecture document i thought it'd
fit in
i'd like
to make sure that we
check with the beer
chairs and the beer working group to
make sure
we're aligned on this does that request
make sense if not i can take that
offline with you we will
maybe take offline to we can discuss in
details and uh about the water
and then what the details and then to
what the extent of the detail
i can summarize yes yep
the whole idea is to have the idea folks
before we do the adoption cult because
it's coming up
um
probably after the
the bgp um
autocomp from the car dt one it'll
probably be one of the ones that comes
immediately after so we have a little
bit of time i'd like to make sure the
working group has the context
with a message
that goes along with the call so i just
need to have your help there
thank you very much
no problem okay thank you
thank you can you hear me now
yes
super
i'd lost the connectivity
uh
next on the list to present
is
link bandwidth extended community by
weiyen
can you see the presentation
yes we can yes we can super thanks
when you're dead
uh yes
hello we can't hear you
you're probably talking to a mute mike
we can actually actually hit his
um um
well his face his face or his icon
that means he's sending audio
the audio is coming out very choppy at
my end
let's give him a minute
if it doesn't recover we can go to the
next presentation
oh can you hear me
yes much better
please go oh
my topic is the intentional income and
wise you could send the community
this is the update for previous version
another page please
a review reviews of the
one and two issues
the too many uni units
defendations
we are away in this version we remove
with the more unique definitions using
the original units
bytes per second
second
a suggestion for a sacramento floating
point typo we learned you about the
diacomo of lotium point typo and
font is that user was very complicated
briefly
hello
is
here
yes we can hear you please continue
okay okay okay
i'll continue briefly the uh diagonal
diagonal floating type of previous two
accordion uh
schemes
a tacoma coding a scheme and a binary
coding scheme those two coding scheme
can be
said to be a complete difference besides
the coding of the
complement part is also difficult to
understand
certainly
may use
cst for
these unsend integers in ginger we think
this is a feasible direction
and that's the picture please
at the same time we also consider
consider many extension methods based on
the extended community attributes
first
new accordions came the same unit as the
same unit
uses the unsending changes in batch
force seconds the bandwidth value origin
is the limits
this is
the problem and the second
the new coordinates came on new units a
year
megabits per second
this this also has a problem that is the
bandwidth value or the funnel with value
above can be
fixed but the prices was lost
next page please
so we extend the
link up another based on the
64 bits a new type of
ipv new
ipv6
addresses pacifico you attended the
community's attributes that is
considered to
represent
in 64-bit selling abundance
as shown in the future
uh the typos
the type of
three or
of uh fourth three are the the commanded
refers to
rfc
four three six zero sub type is tvd
that's the pitch
thank you more coming
companies and discussion is welcome and
another ideas is also in is in
will come
thank you
thank you so much any questions for
albanian
cool thank you
um
the next presentation we have
is about
pgp metric credit from
shuffle
hi
hello yes we can hear you please go
ahead
okay thank you
uh thank you
now i will introduce
pgp measure collected past attributes
so
next uh
excuse me uh
how to
turn the next page
oh thanks so uh the motivations here is
that the dystopia is related with
pgp and tenderlode
uh as i know uh
now the calendar pgp
intended scheme are discussed in idea wg
pgp intended loads includes not only the
load with minimum delay
but also
with specific cumulative delay for
example 100 milliseconds
so a single nintendo template configured
under intermediate bgb speaker
may be used for multiple paths
designated to different endpoints
that means that
we can not
rely
on the configuration and ucb speaker to
use
different
low solution
data requirements so
uh this information
is better to color
in the
what has the
nose
next please
so these are typical signals for
example
we can see the figure eight
volume of the head and the total and the
point
the
intended load with delay 100
milliseconds
there may be multiples
but for each pass
the segments
may have different requirements for
example in figure eight
the segment form can end
from age to b1 is 16 milliseconds but
the from h2 b2
maybe
40 milliseconds
that may be caused by
the set of domain is
different
now we can see
the fake b
there is a similar for example the
first part
is averaged about 50
milliseconds for each segment but for
the past 4 it's
33 milliseconds per easy second
place
next
okay
that is another two
scenarios we can look at the figure c
uh there are two intended laws uh
just lead to different endpoints e1 and
e2 but the intent identifies the
same
the the first thing conclude
with the delay 100
100 milliseconds but the second is 200
milliseconds
so how does node b determine the
different delay requirements for segment
volume b to
e1 and volume b to e2 respectively
and how does the av determine the
differential requirements for the common
segment from the age to be
for these two
intended loads
so
for the figure d
for this example uh there's also two ten
dollars
uh
that designated two
different endpoints with the same
identify
but both with the
100 milliseconds
so the question
is similar
next please
so at the current phase we just provide
the
symbol schemes for
for symbol case
but this schema has
problem is that is the intended routine
is established between the no and the
determined endpoints with a digital
propagation path controlled by policy
that is the past all the arbitrary
from
multiple propagation pathways were
different obcoms
we suggested
using different intents all using the
explicit
propagation object
list
so
the following metric correlated
attribute information
is just defined in the
draft now
the magical information is a targeted
current
for each
the total
and the endometrial quality information
and the estimated of counts
and with the optional quality the piece
information
this information can be
applied
for the simple scenarios such as
single pass
for some communicated cases
then maybe need uh the explicit
uh propagation object
that uh uh to be defined in the next
lesson
so
next please
uh so
based on the muscular quality
information contained in the
the
attribute
uh there's a cellular method to get the
innovation for
the solution
uh assembler is you use an average
inventory created that can be
uh get
to
that total under under measurability
divided by the estimated heat of
accounts
and 10
uh good average
metabolism with the
[Music]
relative
magic together minimum warning
and the second method is to use the
exponential piece
uh
we can't get the from the collided piece
along with
index
the intensity is just
set by the calendar hope
then we can get the
minimum from the exponential
piece and the
positive one for resolution
uh
this the third method is using the
epo and is the data user to be defined
in the next version
next please
okay
that is the percentage of this
document any questions and comments i
will come thank you
any questions for
shuffle
but thank you shuffle and folks that was
our last presentation we started seven
minutes late
and my apologies but i believe we made
it through the time
um jeff sue
any closing comments before we close the
working group session
my question is
to any of the presenters since we've
ended up
thanks to cares good management
um
with a few bits of extra time does
anyone want to
raise any questions about any of the
drafts get the last call
and while you're thinking i'll let jeff
talk
i'll just throw in closing remarks thank
you everyone for
coming to idr and also
dealing with our usual friday session
it's been a very long week and we're all
quite tired
you'll note that there's a number of
threads that have been started on idr
covering a wide variety of topics that
have been raised during the sessions and
you know the chairs like to urge you
to go look for
threads that are of interest to you and
also if you see something that was a
question you had that has not been
started as a thread
please initiate one so that we can have
good technical discussion
thank you
all right with that thank you all
we hope to see you in philadelphia
and more importantly in person um see
you all in philadelphia
and safe travels back home
okay
the ones that are out we'll close
uh but i think the chairs would like to
talk a little bit about what we learned
uh this week on the bgp auto comp and
the uh
our
ct talk thank you
so
you