uh
all right everybody welcome to the jmap
and extra session at iatf in vienna and
remotely uh thanks for joining us
there's a few people here in the room
probably a few more remotely i'm having
to pop up here to this microphone to
speak because the table microphone is
dead so i'm just going to drag this back
down to the desk while i read through
these initial slides and then we'll get
straight down to business
so this is this is the slides we've been
given here uh we're doing both chairman
and extra the plan is to the gym at
first there's about 75 minutes of that
and then about 45 minutes of extra
according to
what we put into the agenda but of
course that is things will change as we
go
the noteworld
i think everyone in this room has been
in additional sessions this morning so
you've probably already seen this for
everyone remote everything you do here
is covered under the note well so you
you have to follow the iotf's processes
and policies
little tips for people in the room uh
there are qr codes all over the place
that you can scan from your mobile
device or you can use the little mobile
device on-site tool thing
otherwise you can log in with the full
meet echo client if you would prefer
either way logging into medieco is the
way that you indicate you're present for
blue sheets everyone remote obviously
has already done that
cool um links to resources you can find
all of this directly from data tracker
so i won't spend long on this page
here's the agenda for the jmap session
so planning to start with jmf s mime
because that's with the editors already
then work our way through the active
drafts with each person speaking to
what's happening with that and finally
review our milestones and then we will
do the same
for extra starting with with things that
are further along and going back to
things that are less far along so with
that said any agenda bashing before we
get started
all right my co-chair is remote here
jim if you want to
take notes or or
put snarky comments whatever you want to
do
that's all good
give us a wave nice to see you
awesome all right so the first on our
list here is
the s mime
do i have any slides for that i have s
mime signing but not for jffs anything
to say on that
alexi if you want to pop up
um yeah alexey melankov uh not much
really i think all the
uh feedback is addressed i think um
i copied the old niels convention for
underscores and stars around various
elements and
rfc editor is asking what is this
so i i did my best to replace it with
the xml v3
emphasis and
[Music]
strong elements
hopefully i did it correctly and so
there is just a few minor formatting
things and it should be done
maybe even uh announced this week cool
fantastic
thank you
next is actually me with gmat blob
so i'm just going to stay seated in this
chair since there's a camera pointed
straight at me anyway
i put in quite a few changes based
mainly on jim's feedback and discussion
with neil about
the fact that blob set was not really
quite the right thing for it because
there's no state for blobs and there's
no update or destroy this only create so
blob upload is is basically a set that
can only do creates
it still
creates creation ids because you need to
have them
to be able to back reference which is
the large point of doing inline blob
creates
i also removed the catinate
both because what even does that mean
nobody knows and
because it makes it much simpler if it's
always just a list of of bite sources
octet sources in order that you
append together to create a final result
which could be zero if you're uploading
the nothing file or it could be one or
more
sources
also made the capabilities simpler you
used to be able to
specify a maximum applied upload size
for blob and if you didn't specify it
there then it should get it from the
upload endpoint if you didn't specify
that like not either you specify it or
the client can just assume it can send
what it likes and the server will reject
if it wants to anyway
what is that
this is the example as you can see it
looks beautiful
um
it works on my computer
interoperability is a thing
ah
no
libreoffice
breakfast of champions
um all right so what you can see here is
that instead of it saying create and
then an id
and then just text the data as text
it's got a data and then an array and
then the data is text item in it s1
hash within an array
it does um
are we done it's this was in working
group last call it's a fairly
significant change
um
but it's been posted for two weeks now
and i told everyone on the list so
if you have feedback please send
feedback if not i'll ask jim to push the
button and send it off to the editors
does anyone here have feedback
yes
yep um feel free to
push the button pop up whatever you want
um just just go talk to the microphone
it's fine
just tell people who you are
you don't need to do this
oh
there you go you beat alexi by a
millisecond so you're first hence
okay
um so yeah basically um
sorry okay
the basic things i
looked at was a little bit also from a
migration perspective so i wondered um
there is this um the way i understood
the blob gap thing is that i could
specify which properties to get from the
server right you can specify uh the
range that you want from a blob
exactly so my question would be because
it was not explicitly written down if i
i think in theory i could only include
size and would just get the size of the
block right yes you can get the size
of the blob and you can get a range from
within the blob
okay because um it might be worthwhile
in my opinion to point that explicitly
out because this is the only single
operation which will only give you
metadata from the server without having
the server to touch the actual files on
disk okay this is an operation typically
we do for instance during some scanning
kind of operation
exactly
and this is a reason why i would say
also for implementers to have that in
mind
cool
second related thing is actually so the
question is would there be a case
actually for a list or blob thing
um in case you know you want to have a
full migration from one mailbox to the
other one
obviously you could get that from the
actual items where you get the
references from but sometimes it's more
handy also for some reasons for
polarization also
if you
oh
let's
check that
while we're stopped who was uh who was
speaking i didn't catch your name
still didn't hear that
all right uh let me bring you the
microphone here you go
okay so
so so this is hubble hello should i
repeat everything or yeah
okay i give it short so i have basically
two remarks so first remark is um on
blob get
as far as i interpret
rc it's possible to explicitly mention
the properties to retrieve from the
server so it should be possible for
instance also to only retrieve the size
which is basically a metadata and
sometimes it comes handy to only get set
data before deciding maybe
you know for forgetting uh knowledge
about the size calculating some duration
and so on
without having the server read the file
physically or something like that so it
would be
helpful i think to point out this
possibility also for implementers to
make that distinction in the
implementation to make it more efficient
to read size only
that was my first remark
and the second question was if it would
make sense to have
something like list all blobs
in order to have the possibility to read
all blobs from the server in order to
transfer them somewhere else for
instance
i need to come and grab this i think
this is the one that works
was listed by meet echo as being remote
so
yes because he's on the full client
um
medicare doesn't know if you actually
remote just knows which client you're
using
i understand so uh to respond to that
second one yes it would be possible to
add
a blob query i imagine um service might
reject it but they can reject anything
um certainly the ability to look through
everything
um it could be quite a lot of data
but
yep um okay i think alexia is next let
me give you back the microphone
um i'm sorry can i be the naughty child
in the room that i haven't read the
latest draft
i'm not always
okay so um
i think taking out catenate for
simplicity is probably fine can you just
remind me what the use case for it was
was it like i'm a catenate kind of case
right
to answer that uh what i did by taking
out cat mate was made everything a cat
note so instead of having a type that
was either a single item or a type that
was a list of items it's always a list
and so
you list may have only one item in it
but instead of having a key called
catinate that meant concatenating
multiple of these together everything's
just a list we good now
hello
i don't know
can you hear me
yes yes oh good okay um
fine i i think that that's the right way
to do it then
perfect cool
next on the list was neil
what
um
yeah i just wanted to say i'm not sure
about having a blog slash query and i
don't know that's a good idea
um
like the point of
this draft was
to be able to do kind of in band um you
know upload and download of blobs so
it's kind of the same functionality you
already have but
um just without having to have a
separate connection for those if
for some reason that's what you needed
uh but
knob slash query is quite a different
functionality
uh and also
is a bit weird with you know blobs not a
base type in the same way a normal
managed object is you you don't have
state strings to be able to do um change
tracking and
stuff i don't it just seems
a lot of extra stuff to add
without really thinking about it
yeah i guess to respond to that a little
bit
it's it's not
going to be that they can change blobs
are immutable uh so it's more just a
list of all the blocks on the server
including ones that maybe aren't
referenced by anything
um
if you if you're using this as a
replication mechanism between a system
and a hot standby type of thing then
doing a an rsync type situation where
you fetch the full list and then grab
blobs that aren't copied across would
allow you to do a failover safely so i
imagine that's the kind of case that's
being looked at here
um
the the main issue with it is it's a lot
of data so you'd have to page it or
something and because there's no state
string
pagination becomes quite difficult there
yeah you wouldn't know they actually can
always find the references from the
objects themselves
yeah i think that should be really the
encouraged way
all right thank you any other comments
on blob or shall we move on
all right thank you i will i guess
post responses to what's happened here
to the mailing list um possibly do an
updated draft with the the advice around
fetching size from blobs
and then asked him to do a working group
last call again
uh yep
hi i'm eures baum i just have a
question about the
is it still
planned to to make a new document
based on jmr blob management extension
for files or jmf for files or something
still in scope of the that's
separate from blob but self blob is just
for creating creating the blobs which
you would then add to files so yes that
files is still something that that's
that's interesting
okay but yeah it would it would use this
as an upload mechanism rather than
extending this document well it could
maybe that could also be the place to
have like a query functionality i don't
know if it probably will have more
metadata associated with all
yeah the thing is you might not have
your calendar events and your emails
appear as files
via the
files or storage node api yeah
so you still need to be able to get the
look at all the things that you're
interested in to find out which blobs
they reference okay
cool
oh that's not what i meant
chair slides so um
back on the chair slides for a second
next on our agenda is jmap quotas
uh
yes hello can you hear me hello yes
yeah yeah hello i'm renee so yeah uh i'm
gonna uh
present quickly i mean what's new in
gemma quota not so much to be honest
um
[Music]
do i control the slides or not
uh you can if you share them would you
like me to do that
uh
i mean you can just push it's just one
slide after this one
if you
thank you
uh so i mean there's not much changes
lately
but i mean thanks to neil that did a few
more feedback
so
[Music]
i think it's pretty stable now also in
kota capability i mean yeah it was
useless to have kota ids
we can just fetch them with a quota
slash get method
for the scope and resource type as well
i mean we don't need
to specify the
some custom extension i mean we can just
keep it simple with the standard and if
people
want to
[Music]
make extensions of it i mean they can
they can do it themselves
and then the resource type just uh
renaming size to octet so it's uh it's
more clear about what we want here
and uh
and limit as well a bit more generic
definition
and uh
that's
that's pretty much it
so if people have questions or maybe
feedbacks on kuta's uh i mean yeah
you're free to ask questions here or to
to answer the mailing list as well
okay
i guess i can uh give you the handbag uh
bronn
yeah cool
go ahead alexis
yeah just uh my apologies i haven't read
the latest document but now that the
quarter i'm up quarter rfc is about to
be published i i can
you i can give full attention to your
document to make sure it's you know
consistent uh
with mine or at least
if there are differences then we discuss
and you know agree why they are good
thing
okay yes basically uh i thought i
haven't read the recent version but i'll
have a look
okay thank you alexa
all right anybody else
all right right
thank you guys
all right
uh probably after your review yes
yeah i think okay i will do i'll do a
working group last call on this document
and that will that will lead us to
reviews uh next up is jmap sharing
so
um i guess i can share it and then oh no
sorry being shared fantastic i do not
need to do that
or is that me sharing it's hard to tell
i think it's you sharing it's me sharing
so i hit share and it says a new slide
deck has been shared which is not true
it's me trying to look in here to see if
i have any slides for james sharing and
i do not appear to have anything
yes sorry about that i don't have any
sharing i just had some calendars
sharing though
actually um
it's pretty complete i was just somebody
look at that again um before this
meeting and i think uh it needs some a
bit of wordsmithing just to make sure
everything's as clear as possible but it
it you know it's reasonably short it's
only kind of 10 pages i think in rc
format um and
reasonably straightforward so
that one could possibly progress pretty
soon um
i don't know whether we want to wait to
do it at the same time as
calendars and stuff but it's not exactly
tied to it it's kind of
it's related but
i think just yeah go ahead in that case
so one more update and then working
group last call
yeah i think that should be fine
cool
i don't have any open issues or no any
concerns particularly about that one
yeah anybody
have anything
for sharing
guys let's move on to calendars where
i've got a few things to
discuss
all right i will
find the calendar slides
and i think i can pass control over to
you neil
oh yes excellent okay
cool
okay so um
[Music]
since the last meeting been quite a few
updates uh we've got quite a bit of
implementation experience with this now
which has been great uh mainly for
servicing just little edge cases which
needed to be properly documented um
uh
so that's obviously why we do that
before we try and publish this
uh
there are still a few questions also
that uh came up while
from the implantation experience so i
just want to talk through a few of those
and see what people in the room um have
to say about things any thoughts
so i'll just step through that now
uh now the first one of these is
actually one of those ones where when i
was writing it up i realized that the
answer was kind of obvious but i'll just
talk to it briefly anyway because it's
kind of interesting
um
there's a concept that i've called uh
whether
the server is the source of an event um
and i wonder whether that's actually the
best way of naming this but essentially
this comes down to whether
it was created on that server or whether
it was created say on completely
different
server run by different company but you
received knight message that added it
uh and the the
that affects
a few things in terms of how it behaves
um
for example whether when you update the
event sending an rsvp or whether it's
sending out the invitations to all the
other people
uh
and you can't just look at the apples uh
here um
uh because you have full permission to
edit it it's just that actually you
shouldn't edit most of it because you're
not really the one that controls it and
another update may completely blatant
your changes
so generally
clients already have this concept i
don't know what other clients call it
necessarily uh but they look at the
organizer to know and see is that
someone they know is you to determine
whether they think this is the source or
not but that won't necessarily work in
all circumstances because you might have
a per event or per account reply to
address which lets you do some nice
other things um
but it means it's not necessarily easy
to work out whether
this event is uh the source of this
event is this server that you're on or
somewhere else
so
basically the episode of this is i think
we probably do need to add a new
property to the event that the server
will set when you create it for the
server to say does it think it's the
source that's spent or not uh so the
client can
change his behavior based on this
uh so i guess first of all just
any objections to that and also does
anyone know of a standard naming for
this concept or other names or who
should i stick with sauce that's kind of
the name for that
you go ahead barry
this is barry lieber uh how about his
controller i mean does that
ring better than source
certainly reasonable um
it's what i was going to say and it's
the word you were using to describe the
concept as you were talking about it
right one thing i did want to add to
this is that
um
let's turn myself off
all right the one thing i wanted to add
to it is that
for import export you will need a way to
set controller on the server tell the
server you're importing this data and by
the way you're taking over control of it
well
i don't know about that because so so
it's defined at the moment in the spec
of um
that the server is the source if
it will receive messages sent to the
reply to sent to the organizer
essentially and so it will know that
even when you import them you won't need
to set it explicitly uh it's just the
client can't necessarily know that it
doesn't know all of the addresses that
the server might receive stuff on but
the server does so i don't know you do
need that to import
it's just a matter of saying that
there has to be some way to set it on
the server but not necessarily via jmap
i guess yeah the server has to know
what it can receive on but yeah i don't
i don't think it needs anything to dream
up particularly for that
that's more about identity management
really
cool that's read-only but mutable
it's it's read-only but yeah i guess
potentially mutable by the survey if it
changes yeah who what which stresses it
receives from my suddenly inside
actually i am now the source of this
event i guess
cool
joris
so i just wanted to
um state that i also added a
source property for jmf for tasks
currently so
this this is supposed to signal if a
task comes from a
was automatically created from a mail or
originated from a web application or a
mobile application
so just to put that out there that it
might be confusing to have is source and
source at the same time
with two semantic different semantic
meanings i
i've certainly thought i wonder if like
his remote event or something is you
know switched around the thing rather
than use controller i don't know
maybe people can think about it in email
list if they have other thoughts but
yeah it looks like source is not the
best term to describe here so we should
come up with
something better because it turns out to
be a reasonably important concept that's
referenced a few times in respect for
different behaviors
here
yep that seems fair okay let's move on
call the property aquamarine and
everyone more
okay um
so the next question is back about about
default calendars uh and
you know first of all
does there have to be one for each
account um
or
can there be none set which basically
means at that point you can pick
whichever
calendar you want if you need one um
like to add an incoming invitation to
for example
um
we
the expected company says no which is
based on our previous discussion uh
because as i recall
just because
it's like
you're picking one at random anyway so
you know why why bother just say
explicitly i didn't pick what i don't
know which one is default but it but cal
dev mandates one it uh i think ken
reminded me so
perhaps we should match uh so anyone got
thoughts on that and then also it is
mandated like what happens if
in various education i'm not sure
whether it's for this or the previous
thing but jim go ahead
the end of the source discussion
um i haven't had a chance to think about
this
very much but is there a
by the way i've got a long echo that i'm
hearing so that's why i'm
uh talking a little bit in here i'll try
to ignore it
but is there
any sort of a security aspect to who has
the right to send
um
uh an update to an event
and
uh is there is there a question of
whether the gmap server can be trusted
to not uh change that that property
inappropriately
so this is talking about the source
stuff again i presume um
i think
yeah you you
we presume that you trust your own
calendar server um to not do something
deliberately malicious um because it has
all of your data already anyway uh
um and in terms of uh processing the
updates and the security bits around
that whether you should accept like a
change of stuff that's kind of out of
scope of jmap that's part of it really
okay thanks
barry
that's barry lieber this this back to
the default calendar thing this seems to
be analogous to the imap inbox where
imap specifies things that um you have
you have to have an inbox
if you delete it it gets recreated uh
with inbox if you rename it
then a new one is created with the name
inbox you probably don't want that for
this but
maybe you want to do the same kind of
thing with this as imap does with inbox
so basically alexa just said so
basically you're just say you're saying
yes to default and i'm saying yeah
probably especially if caldev
requires it it would be useful to have
that
specified as some uh standard behavior
in in jmap calendar
okay
uh ken richardson yeah um i'm
clearly in favor of default calendar as
it's made by caldev and if you've got a
server that's automatically processing
itip whether it's
implicit scheduling or or via imep
you need to put new invites someplace so
if the user expects to receive invites
they need a calendar and they need to
tell us which one it's going to go to
and if you've only got one calendar well
then that's the default if you've got
more then you tell us which one it's
going to be but i think we need to have
at least one calendar if they expect to
have scheduling work
so does that mean there must always be
at least one calendar in the account i
presume which is fine i guess and also
yes i'd say yes so cause yes because if
you don't have any calendars what's the
point of
so then what happens if you try and
delete the default i think is the next
question i'd say you'd have to create a
new default before you delete the
existing one you just can't if it's
currently the default if it's the only
calendar you have i'd say we we prohibit
you from deleting it
and barry gives me a thumbs up so he's
in agreement with that
and i guess well i if you look at the
slide then you also get questions of are
there other conditions like what if this
is a read-only calendar so i can't
actually add stuff to it so i have a
calendar but it's not
sufficient to be my default calendar if
that makes sense do we have restrictions
on what can be said
that's why i said it's analogous to imap
in imap the inbox can't be read only and
um
like i said
you can't fail to have an inbox
yeah
yes
so this is kind of again based on what
pete and barry just discussed
perhaps the what we do is you do not
have to have a default calendar
but in that case you aren't able to
schedule
yeah if all you want are read-only
calendars because your subscriptions
fine but don't expect invites to go
anywhere because you've got no place to
put them
as pete said it's like the inbox right
if you don't have an inbox you're not
receiving email but you can certainly
read mail on other mailboxes there are
certainly servers where you cannot have
an inbox and then when mail arrives it
gets auto created and then the mail put
in it
this is robert speaking so um
i have to say i don't care so much if a
default calendar must be specified so i
find it perfectly reasonable that the
default calendar id and the preferences
might be null but it of course must
still be then we could still state that
servers might then pick whatever
calendar they want to
put an
invite into
and if there is no calendar as we said
has been said before while then
there is no no invent can't be delivered
at all anyway
um but separate from the fact if you can
set or cannot set the default calendar
id to null
um what we are doing in our current
implementation currently we allow to
delete the default calendar but we
immediately pick a new one so um this
might also be stated in this back then
that the server might pick a new
default calendar immediately after they
destroy or implied not that depends on
the implementation
um
yeah actually that sounds quite
reasonable to me because that that's
yeah let's deserve it to decide it
doesn't actually have
that's interoperable you know regardless
or whatever does because it tells the
client what it did
yeah then i think it might make sense if
we decide on that to put it also in the
spec
where it's currently saying that
um it's possible to destroy default and
then it's set to null
still make clear that the server might
choose what what it seems appropriate in
that situation
and that being said for participant
identities um the
which we which we mapped to the caldf uh
calendar user user address set property
i think these should these two
properties in cal def and jmap should be
aligned
um but the califs back in 6638
definitely says that if the if the
property is destroyed in caldev
then this disabled scheduling
for that um account so
uh in that regard it's in that regard it
speaks to me that the participant
identities in gmap
must be non-empty
as well
i think it shouldn't implement the magic
that if there are no participant
identities then scheduling is off
if
i would have thought
probably the server well the server
obviously is allowed to reject anytime
do you try and destroy stuff and like i
would imagine it won't let you destroy
whatever your you know your username
identity for example you might let you
destroy extra ones you've added but not
yes um what i'm trying to say is also
that
it shouldn't be a magic by having or
having not participant identities to
allow scheduling for an account or not
if if that's
if we want to disable scheduling for an
account there should be some
appropriate flag yeah yeah whatever yeah
yeah all right
okay uh alexi uh very quick note maybe
it was sort of overtaken by events but
then the question i would ask is
what are the benefits of not having a
default calendar
maybe answer to this question will help
you
decide i don't know
yeah it's more kind of a
data consistency thing it's hard to
you know if if you say you have to you
can't delete the default one so you have
to you have to end up doing this dance
where you create a new one assign a
different default then
it's it's easier i think if you can
allow it to delete delete the default
but then there's the question of what
happens at that point basically and
that's where i specify that and actually
from
my map experience there are certain
operations that allows
allow multiple outcomes and it's
actually having multiple outcomes is
more difficult to code for clients so
if you can decide on one then
you either don't allow deletion or
if it's deleted it can always be
recreated unless there are reasons not
to um
but if you can't you know the two
choices might be okay
okay yeah the cases like undo are
particularly messy if the server starts
doing magic
under the hood and you have to
work out
that magic if you accidentally deleted
your last calendar and then you've got a
whole mess to clean up and the offline
case where you've you've scheduled a
bunch of operations
you don't necessarily want all the
default calendars changed meanwhile and
so one of my operations failed
anyway
all right um this is santiago again um
one more point so i think i'm also in
favor of having definitely a default
calendar because i'm not aware of a
single other system
that doesn't have that so some systems
even only have the default calendar
groupware systems and so on um i also
wonder um you know from a ui perspective
if there wouldn't be anyone what would
the ui display would it you know need
the user to create a calendar first i
think that would be also very weird
um and another point it was mentioned
before if i delete the default calendar
some other calendar might be promoted to
be the default calendar i just want to
raise a point that um typically the
default calendar in most systems since
it pre-exist doesn't have a particular
name
so some systems give it a
you know
some weird name like default or the
identity of the user or something like
that
and so some systems might get confused
if the default calendar after such and
delete operation and another calendar is
promoted to be default has now a proper
name
so there might also be internet internet
generalization issues we set because uis
will have the default calendar displayed
typically with a predefined string in
the system and not with a user given
name
and that might be broken if you promote
another calendar this would be the
default calendar so the case i'm making
here is probably not being able to
delete the default calendar and make
another calendar as a default calendar
i
yeah i don't entirely agree with that
yeah
yeah yeah i i i think i understood that
um
like
you can choose
a different calendar to be your default
like in caldave and it can have a
arbitrary name we don't you know i don't
think any client just shows the word
default
server can always um if it has yeah
exactly i mean it's not a strong point
but certainly it's something from my
experience with clients that might
lead to weird results even if it's
specified
yeah
camera just said again um i can't speak
to the interrupt
potential problems that hans york just
brought up but to try to clarify my
previous thoughts on this and wrap
things up so
my opinion is if the user expects to
have scheduling they need at least one
read write calendar
the default calendar essentially is a
user
option that if they have multiple read
write calendars
they tell you which one they would like
new invites to go into
it's not a mandatory thing on the server
it's a user preferences this is where i
want to see all my new invites
that's really all it is in cal dev
um and i don't think we should make it
more than what that is
in gmat
so it's it's a user preference if they
want scheduling you have to have at
least one read write i don't care if you
call it default or not because it's only
one so it's the default by default
yeah you know it's it's really in the
concept if you have more than one read
write calendar
all right
should we move on
yep let's move on thanks for that
everyone
um
so this is
about um default alerts on calendars so
uh
we've discussed this bit before that you
can have specified default loads on
cameras and then you can specify on an
event to use default alerts and just get
whatever the ones are on the calendar
that's in
um
so the first question is about if i
create a new calendar
should i should the server
copy over
uh the default alerts
from your default calendar if you have a
default calendar i think from the
previous discussion
um
because at the moment the the spec just
says the default is null so if you
create a new calendar it doesn't have
any default alerts until you explicitly
add them um
i think again while i was writing up
this slide i came to the conclusion um
and so i'll just see if other people
disagree with it which was that this can
actually made vendor specific because
the way jmap works
the server will return if it created
if it said anything like copied over the
ones from your default calendar um
and
uh
if you if and the client can always
explicitly set null or whatever he wants
on create if he doesn't want the server
to pick something
so
does anyone disagree with that in the
queue
so let's just again so given what i had
just said about the default calendar
being a preference as opposed to an
actual entity
i would like to
see default alerts maybe be attached to
the principal or whatever whatever we're
calling that in jmap
since that's yeah
the trouble is thing on the server
regarding the user
well yeah
i was trying to avoid having yet another
level of hierarchy because does that
mean that they might inherit
from
so if you have to say you use default
alerts so they inherit from the calendar
but then the calendar might inherit from
the principle
up here to argue with whether we should
have should or should not have
inheritance i'm just saying
because of default
calendar being a preference and not an
entity
you really can't attach anything to it
right
yeah but i mean in this case it's not
attaching anything to it
in the spec as such it's just saying
that the
uh when you create a new calendar if you
don't explicitly accept if you have one
okay
all right that's yeah
what i'm saying really here is if you
create a new calendar and the client
doesn't explicitly say
use these default alerts including the
category of i don't want any then the
server is allowed to set
whatever default alerts it wants which
might be copying over from your default
calendar or might be something entirely
different whatever it's going to tell
the client so
it's up to the server
if it if the the server does inherit it
then they should probably be returned
as part of the create response so the
user knows what happened and can change
it exactly there would have to be
yeah because and that's already part of
the core spec of jmap if the server sets
it and it's not explicitly set by the
client so if i have to tell the client
what he did
um i'm comfortable with that
um
possibly the more interesting question
is the one on the bottom this slide here
which is
are you allowed to set default alerts on
a calendar if you don't have the
may update private apple which is the
app we need to be able to update alerts
on individual events in that calendar
anyone want to
pop in for that
does that require more
that does seem reasonable like yeah if i
can't set alerts on individual events
why should i be able to set default
alerts
robert
yeah so okay so probably i misunderstood
the question then um
yeah but
since i have the mic i agree
if you don't have to make update private
it it doesn't really make any sense to
set the default alerts you you can't
even then toggle if you want to use
default alerts on the event or not so
no but suppose that it was set to true
because you know
by whatever source set that
what does that mean that wouldn't be set
to true for you um it would be
it would be set well
that brings up the question that we
currently have around shared calendars
but
um by the default value of the js
calendar object it would default to
false so yeah
yeah in that case you would you wouldn't
need to be able to set them for this
calendar
um but
yeah
at the moment where sherry of a shared
calendar defaults to true with usd for
the alerts
then
i think it definitely
needs to be
possible for them to set the defaults on
the calendar otherwise they don't get
any alerts at all for the event
okay
but it yeah
there's a there's a few interactions
that i guess like whether it's a team
mode calendar or
kind of secondary mode and stuff yeah
it's okay but what i'm trying to say is
like if the default value for use
default alerts ever changes to true
under
which circumstances any then under these
circumstances might also be allowed to
set default alerts because otherwise
it's really
it isn't useful to default to true in
that
situation
because there will never ever be any
alerts there
yeah yeah i'll i'll go check the
cases and yeah try and come up with some
insane
cool all right um let's have something
on that i'll just move on
uh
this one's simply we've got this
calendar preferences object we've um
talked about last time and we've got to
store now what the default calendar is
and what your default participant is
your default identity is um do we want
to put anything else in there for now i
mean i'm sure at some point this will
get extended but there's anything else
you want in the initial version of it
the one thing that came to mind is the
user's first day of week preference
which is just a cultural thing if you
want monday or sunday as the first day
of your week or in a few cases saturday
and some other stuff but mostly one of
those two um
is that worth putting in here or do we
just keep it simple for now it's just
the default identity and calendar
or is there anything else people think
should
it's worth storing here as a kind of
at the data model layer so every every
client has access to it
default time zone
time zone is attached to the principles
this is ken again so if we expect
multiple
different clients to be speaking jmf for
calendars would the user might want to
have their preferred
date time format stored in this
preferences
certainly yeah if you were storing first
of a week that would make sense as well
like yeah or like day month year or
whatever but
yeah
that's good good point
cool thanks ken uh daniel
um
apologies for asking a question maybe
everybody else here already knows um
i'm not sure i understand why default
timezone would be a principal
uh level thing
as opposed to a per calendar thing if
i'm scheduling for a group that
regularly meets on east coast time i
want that calendar to default to east
coast time and if i'm scheduling for a
group that meets in utc i want that
group to meet in utc
so this seems calendars also
calendars also have a time zone um but
if if it's null then it inherits from
the particle from the principle there
into the calendar
i see so why not use that same mechanism
for first day of week
because it doesn't actually affect me
the scheduling um this is purely a kind
of display preference if you like
okay
should it be on the should it just go on
the principle as well
is
more stuff that's required for
scheduling and like if you were
looking up someone else in your company
to you know schedule something with um
whereas
this to me is just purely a yeah user
preference which is why it's in separate
place
but that sounds like
it belongs the same place that the um
uh
that the
i mean the the date format
belongs as well right like everybody
wants to see it in their own in their
own perspective exactly yeah that's
exactly what it changed
ken just said yeah um
i agree i think that's something worth
storing here as well if we do first ever
week
okay
um
final slide of question stuff i have is
just nyana one
so
the spec lists a set of properties which
are
treated as per user properties so this
means if you're in team mode then each
user that's accessing the calendar
they can write to the properties but
they would just get their own copy of
them it doesn't affect the other users
like your alerts for example so that if
you know we both have a shared calendar
with with the you know team meeting next
week i could have an alert two hours
before and bron could have an alert the
day before so at the moment the list of
properties that are considered per user
is hard coded inspect
do we want to have this in a registry
somewhere
probably like it seems possible that
there might be others in the future that
you want to treat in the same way um
and if so do we modify the js calendar
spec which already lists all the
properties but to add like an extra
column to say whether it should be
treated per using germap calendars or is
this
something we should create just a
separate jmap calendars registry for
just popping myself in the queue for
this one
i think we should modify the existing
registry it's going to be easy to update
both things in one place rather than
creating a separate registry which has
the same keys in it just a subset of
them
is that reasonably easy too i've never
tried to kind of update registry in that
way before i can't
yeah
yeah that does sound the most reasonable
event because yeah one place
yeah
okay that sounds good to me
great so just um
wrapping up uh
[Music]
i think we're almost there with this now
um implementation experience has been
great i need to
make changes based on the discussions
we've had here
and add some examples which um
i saw and yeah but hopefully that none
of that's going to take too long and i
hope to get this to last school before
the next itf meeting fingers crossed
cool
thanks neil
anything else before we move on to the
next topic
excellent uh next is gemma tasks
sorry neil i just turned off your audio
because this this system is very good at
moving things under you when you're
about to click
uh i will put gen up tasks up unless you
want to share it from your phone
and hand you the microphone thank you
hi
i'm jos baum
so um
yeah i'm just gonna present you what the
last changes are of general for tasks
and um
yeah
present you some of the
like most of the changes resulted
from the
the survey that i did last time
um and i also prepared some discussion
points that resulted from this survey
so if you can continue to the next slide
yes so here again is the link to the
survey uh i published on github
uh the goal of the survey was to make uh
you know to make jammer for tasks a more
common standard that's not only specific
to groupware systems
but also specific to kanban boards or
issue trackers
so we extend the idea is to extend the
spec
here and there to make it a more common
thing
yeah so i started with uh
yeah some more obvious
or for me at least obvious properties
um that i added to the spec
um and here's a
here's a list of the changes basically
so the first thing i i added is a
source property that i saw in several
systems so
this describes where
a task oh
also this is only these are only changes
to the task object for now they are not
not for the task list object
so the source property describes from
which
from where the
the task comes from there are some
systems that
can automatically create or can create a
task from an email or
they they tag a certain task as it was
created from a mobile app
yeah um that's just basically a simple
string value then there's also an next
value is estimated work which is similar
to estimated duration which was already
ready there
but it's more of an uh more
abstract
estimation of
the amount of work required for a
certain task which is a
more or less popular thing in kanban
so you don't
have a time estimate you have more like
a more abstract measure
um
then there's an impact property which is
also a simple string
um which
is more popular in issue tracking
which has some values like major or
block
for example
and
then there's a the progress property
was
i extended the progress property with
some more values which you will see in
the next slide and then i slipped in a
small mistake
that nobody noticed
and i just noticed it like a few days
after i published the spec
um i
added related to which was already in
j's calendar it's
what i wanted to do is like to extend
the relation object
with more values
so
related to can also contain
blocked by for example um currently it
contains
values like child
next
things like that okay if you can go on
to the next slide
yeah so the progress property is a bit
is a bit of a bigger change
um
there already were certain values for it
the the progress property basically
displays
yeah the progress of a cert task and uh
yeah there already was uh needs action
in process completed failed and
cancelled
and they're just a bunch of other values
that exist in
various systems
so what i tried to do i tried to
come up with a mapping from those
various values that i that i saw
and
added some more
values that i
i thought were necessary in order to
have a more complete mapping
so for example there are some simple
systems that have only done or not done
[Music]
which was not so obvious for me how to
map the simple done or not done
uh progress indicator
and also uh
yes there were some issue tracking
specific
um
values like deferred
or waiting or
resolved or feedback
yeah so basically this is uh this is the
mapping
here i came up with
i also mentioned that in the spec
so that other people implementing it
know
how to which which value to choose
for their own system that they
they want to implement it for
yeah so
i don't know maybe there are already
some thoughts on
this
i think the next slide is gonna be
what are gonna be other properties for
discussion
yeah i think it looks good and i think
it would be just simple to add these to
the
uh registry as sellout values for the
enums in
um
i'm not sure if
is it also for is is it for
i calendar v to do's um
i think we already have the needs action
process completed
already or not was the chest just in the
task draft
but nevertheless for for gs calendar
yeah i think it's just it should be just
a thing of
extending the existing registry with
these values
okay
all right then if you can move to the
next
be nice
yes so
one big thing
from the
survey was grouping the property somehow
so
right now there are quite a lot of
properties and the plan is to add a
bunch of more properties to the
mainly to the js
calendar
[Music]
object
or the js the js event object
so the idea here is to to group it
somehow because there are some systems
that just
don't need certain properties and
for example
issue trackers
they typically
don't want to
have some scheduling mechanism
built in or
recurrent issues in an issue tracker are
just
not really a thing
so
yeah so that's but that's like a big a
big one that i wanted to discuss first
because
uh yeah i think it's i don't know it's
kind of a big change
so
yeah so it contains a lot of group very
specific properties right now um
um
yeah that's why i tried to split it into
groups and the idea here was to split it
into certain feature sets
um
but keep it in line with jmap
so use the capability mechanism to to
display
what the
server understands what the client
understands
but also not make it all too
fine-grained
um
at the same time so we don't want to
have 20 different
capabilities um
yeah so and one thing i wanted to notice
that it's
if we go that road then systems will
need to implement a bit more than they
absolutely need but i think that's just
that's just uh i don't know
one
that's just necessary
um
and what we can do is we can make sure
the overhead is just small enough for
kanban boards or issue trackers to
spot to have some interest in the
current spec
yeah okay
thank you for this work um can we go one
slide prior i just had a comment on on
the chat that i was asked to take to the
mic
um confirmed seems orthogonal to the
other states here
and it sounds to me like each task has
uh exactly one
uh progress property
and so i don't know how you're expecting
like how do i indicate something is say
confirmed and deferred or
confirmed and
uh in process
uh that seems a little bit confusing i'm
also not sure why we have both resolved
and completed
um
i wouldn't know which one to pick in
most contexts
okay so
you wanna have deferred and
which one
confirmed confirmed seems orthogonal to
the other states
there's a separate property in jazz
counter let's jump in
what can you repeat that
where does the sound come from
um
i don't i'm not exactly sure where um
so what i what i did my my methodology
was that i looked at the issue tracking
systems
and
they have
not only a progress
like a status property but they have
several other properties like impact
that i already mentioned but there's
also another one
so i'm not sure if there is an issue
tracker out there where you can confirm
something
and have it
i don't know assigned at the same time
well i'm not i'm not suggesting this
problem is uh specific to your document
here i've certainly seen issue trackers
where
there is a separate state that is
confirmed but it is not assigned
but i know that
i use issue trackers where
whether something is confirmed or not is
independent of whether it is assigned
it's useful to know okay you know here's
a here's something that someone's
actually been able to replicate for
example
um so it's just it doesn't seem related
to this
i really don't understand the difference
between resolved and completed though
that would be another thing worth
clarifying if you're going to drop you
in this bag
yeah
so um
[Music]
okay
um
[Music]
yeah i think
if i remember correctly
if it's resolved then the it has been it
has been fixed actually
but if it has been completed it's it's
done basically so the issue might
it's like a won't fix
it could be a won't fix
you know it's the same as closed
uh you just don't work on it
any longer
but if it's resolved then it's actually
yeah you actually fixed something
that's
maybe i need to i mean to need to
specify that a little bit more
that's a that's a very good feedback
because uh yeah i me too i think the
the whole terminology is
not very obvious i agree
yeah but maybe also
[Music]
it would need some splitting up
it's a it's a good feedback that i need
to look into it a bit
deeper so this is this is kind of
against i stood up for the next slide
but just to chime in on the resolve
completed i tend to agree that they
probably are the same thing and the
language that's used in the ui is just a
ui thing
uh unless we can clarify those in the
spec as to what the actual difference
between the two are and where they
expect to be used
so i apologize i haven't read the
current spec but
regarding the grouping thing so just to
wrap my head around the issue
are there mandatory
properties in js event that the task
folks don't want to see
or
i'm trying to figure out why we need to
either remove
not show properties in the event
that's the intent that i'm i think i'm
getting from what's going on here
for my way off base
not
not show okay
and what's the reason for not showing
them because they're not a proponent of
tasks or
i just uh just wanted to understand
sorry
you said you if they're not show
properties or no i didn't i might get
that i'm trying to understand my head
around why we need the grouping
so
what's the the end goal with grouping
these
yeah is my question
um
so the way i understood it um
a server still needs
to understand
or you if you have a server
that implements the whole js calendar
spec
and it it tells you with its capability
that it's able to understand it then you
expect it to
understand all the properties even
though they're optional or not
you can just leave out the not optional
properties um
but
yeah
it's a basically capability thing yeah
a little bit i think the
reason or what we found out
in the survey i think that was presented
at the last itf is a little bit we found
that task systems in general are much
heterogeneous and the calendar systems
so for instance each calendar system
typically will include recurrences
whereas this is rather exceptional even
in groupware systems so some like google
tasks for instance there is no such no
such thing as such a recurrence
and so we argued somehow if you want to
use this also for an interoperability
issue like systems might adopt jmap for
you know interoperability as a standard
api tasks in indifference to calendars
will require some sort of a
differentiation
because
there are certainly a lot of task
systems around not having recurrences at
all and so we need some sort of a
mechanism in order to
can i maybe
just finish i have two more slides about
all three more about grouping actually
okay
i think it was just that i i think the
grouping idea with like
a reasonably small set of capabilities
that can divide up um
kind of like you've said there seems
like a reasonable idea i will have to
see you know the
the the details and the specs but i i
think the virginia idea is kind of
changed
okay
yeah so the current idea here is i don't
know to to group
the the the way i tried to solve it is
that i i currently
um have a grouping of three different in
three different groups so the common
properties across all task systems um
and there's a time estimation features
that are
um
that are about
do
the do properties or the estimated work
for example
and there's also advanced scheduling
properties
like recurrences recurrent tasks or
[Music]
some automated scheduling features so if
you can go on to the next slide i have
them
i have them a bit uh
yes okay so there again the three the
three ones yes so and
here is a list of the
of the classes that would be inside the
common group uh i don't want to go
through all of them it's just to get you
like a glimpse what's
what
what's my first initial idea of having
in there
um yeah so for example i don't know
color
title
things that are just very
very common
or also a bit more outlandish but uh
yeah so
it makes sense to group them somehow if
you continue to the next one are the
time estimation properties
which basically would add
alerts and time zone classes
and um
yeah also add some some time estimation
properties as i said the estimated work
estimated duration
if you click to the next one there is
advanced scheduling
which would add recurrence rule class
and nd class
and
add a bunch of properties like free busy
status
recurrent specific properties as well
so yeah that's a the first idea of
grouping that and as you can see it's
quite a lot already and it
i just think to spark interest
uh for uh
issue tracking and and also kanban
boards
it makes sense to
yeah so
either we we say uh
it's not really required to implement
the whole thing in general or we say
it's uh
there are certain sets
that you can choose from
like yeah
yeah okay this is kind of again so i i
think i finally understand where we're
going here so okay um
i
i think what rather than specifying
which properties go in various groups i
think you should just
come up with
different
levels of capability so anything in
common which would you describe in the
text would essentially be mandatory to
to implement four tasks which we all we
need to be interoperable anyways and i'm
either very repeat probably said that
before i did
then
if you've got
other levels of feature sets
you describe in the text
what that feature set entails in terms
of properties and just make those
sub capabilities underneath the actual
js task capability so within the object
you say supports time estimation true
false advanced scheduling true false and
whatever else you might end up in there
i think that's probably the easiest way
to go about this
that makes sense
that's nice yeah okay
okay
good
um okay
so
so if that grouping comes then
i would suggest to also introduce a new
set error for a task set so that you
don't have necessarily
an invalid properties error might not be
appropriate because the system most
likely will know about the property but
decides not to implement it
so probably i don't know like a not
supported
set error that might even
give the
required capability uh might be a good
thing but um yeah i would just
as to use a set error that's that can be
discerned from a
from a regular invalid properties error
sorry about that yeah but on the other
hand it needs to know
that it um only advertises in its
capabilities a subset
of the js task properties so in a way
i would expect the implementation to be
able to at least know about properties
it doesn't support so but anyway
this is kind of again so agreeing with
robert that
um
for the the base draft yes an
implementation should know if it's
excluding certain features and
properties
but
if there's an extension to this draft
down the road you can't expect the
current implementation to know what
hasn't been implemented yet so i can see
there makes there's a case for
uh unsupported capability but then for
other things that it's totally unaware
of not supported still makes sense
okay i guess i'm in favor of both one's
more descriptive than the other one you
fall back to not supported if you have
no idea what's coming at you
okay
all right so if you could
the next how much time do i have left
roughly
is it fine okay
so here again i i
wrote down a mapping between
different task systems and the groups
that i currently am using uh just to
double check that the grouping kind of
makes sense so for grouper system
obviously we typically want to have
we typically want to have all of them so
common group time estimation scheduling
you just want that
then the simple is supposed to be a very
simple task application it's just do
done
i didn't write down a specific system
for that but
yeah you can imagine there is one out
there that doesn't need time estimation
or advanced scheduling for kanban
systems
um
yeah they would they would typically use
a time estimation thing but they could
do
without
recurrences and
and scheduling properties
for example microsoft planner and
extorted trello
and for issue tracking systems they
typically
make do with the common group
already
with
some slight exception for gyra and red
monday they have one
do
property
as i saw
um
yeah but
i think roughly the
it kind of looks like it makes sense
right now the groups that i chose
but yeah of course it's not the final
iteration so
okay
um if you could go to the next slide
yes blob created i already sent the mail
to the mailing list about that so
i saw that in several systems as well so
they they tag an attachment basically uh
with the time it was created it was
uploaded
um
the first question i i would have is do
we actually want to have this in this
back
it's not a very important thing i think
but it's it's a nice to have i would say
and
yeah
and um
if you want this yeah so
i think the the the mailing list
discussion ended with we could
use it as an extension add it as an
extension to the an object that
references a blob and not to the blob
itself
yeah so yeah maybe neil already has a
an opinion on that
yes i was just going to say it should
definitely be the
thing that references the blob that has
created that's the thing that has all
the metadata the blob itself is just
the bytes of data um like you can't
assume that you know it could reuse it
uh between users even if you know to
save space um and reference count it
like the metadata is all in the thing
that's referencing it so that's where
that should go if you have it
all right uh so and the the question
that i have is uh would that be the
for jay's calendar it would be the the
for this particular thing it would be
the links
um
uh the the link object
so
i'm not sure would we just extend
the link object with a single um
property or would that be sufficient i
don't know yeah you can you know
everything's in a registry so it's easy
to add
properties on it you can just say that
the creative property is allowed to be
there on the link object as well
when that's created
i think i'll be reading forward
okay
yeah
as i wrote on the mailing list already
um yeah we can add we could add the
created timestamp to the link object if
we do that i'd rather say we should add
it to any object because
why only for link then if you really
want to track the
timestamp when this object was added
and with that being said i promised two
itfs ago to come up with a spec um that
tracks property changes
in a
that that fits all jmap object types
basically
so
we could also take this as a as an
initiative now to
where this might be already useful
so
yeah i would even prefer the last but it
means more work for me um but i might
find time to come up with a draft and
and and that it comes quite in time for
gmat tasks too
yeah it makes sense
i was going to say i think that's
somewhat orthogonal to this the created
time on a file is is when the file was
created which is not necessarily when
you added it to
the jmap store you want to say
here i'm uploading a file and this is
the creation time from the file system
um i want i want to say this file was
created six months ago and that you're
not going to be able to a gem up event
history is not going to give you that so
it would be a separate property yeah
this is what i wrote on the mailing list
so it very much depends on the semantics
of the created timestamp if it's to
create a timestamp for the link
then um i would assume that's when the
link object was created when it's the
created timestamp for the underlying
data on disk then that's something
different so i don't know what what's
the purpose of of the created timestamp
in this context
i would say there's no
big consensus on this like i would need
to look a bit deeper but i think it's
fine if we
come up with a solution that fits
for us
i think that this is somewhat related
you mentioned before
sorry i think that's a gmx jmf specific
topic here because you have that blob
storage which allows you to reference
objects from many
um you know potential items which is
something you typically can't do in most
other systems so i think what we are
talking about here is really like when
the user linked it to the actual item
irrespective of when the actual file was
already created which i understand which
i understand um
in the jmap system might even be from
another user probably i don't know
yeah so i think what we're talking about
here is really in the context of the
item
the link the time of link
yes
all right so there's not much left
so keywords was already discussed in the
mailing list already and i think that
makes a lot of sense to have a
what was that keyword color
property for the task list
with
the colors
that we have for each keyword and then
you have a separate keyword
property
or change the keyword property to be not
the same simple string but
uh yeah something a bit more complex um
yeah as already discussed on the mailing
list
um
it probably makes sense to keep that
in sync with the category categories
property so to be able to do that with
that as well
and it might also make sense to do that
in gmo for calendars as well to not
be able to do that for tasks only but
also for calendar events so is there an
opinion on that
it's not something i've
seen implanted in calendars at the
moment
once you start adding these extra
properties like this it makes me want to
wonder whether it should be a separate
data type like is this
you know
you should have a
like a taskless object because it's a
um
this is another way of uh it's like a
label essentially um and then you just
reference that
i very much like the proposal that braun
has written on the mailing list for that
okay
yeah
okay so we basically as i understood we
want to keep that out from
discussing calendars right now
but yeah
it might make sense to sync that with
categories as well so
okay
um yes future work is basically we still
have to
get some more feedback or yeah from from
the from the task system vendors we
already prepared something for that
still needs to happen and also there are
still
two
more or less complex properties like
comment
which we don't want to exclude because a
lot of systems
is very important for a lot of systems
as well
and the history property was already
teased in previous meetings we still
have yet to tackle that one
okay i just have uh com short commands
for the properties that were mentioned
at the beginning so okay for estimated
work
i think this property is useful i'm not
sure if it's useful if it has uh
an arbitrary number in it because i
would assume that the meaning of these
numbers will differ
by teams uh or by products so yeah
i'm not sure how much value is in
allowing just any number without giving
hints
what number range indicates what
um
for the impact property uh i wonder if
if that
can be if that if that is necessary if
the priority
property
um is enough
um
and uh what was the last year for the
source property i wonder
how
how much value it provides if it's just
a free text
if
with different implementations put the
same thing in or could there be an
enumeration of
of
of typical cases where source property
is set
or should that be the product id of
whatever
product generated
was the source of that
task yeah so i'm i'm not sure how a free
text video alone will be inter-available
between systems okay
yes
i'm sorry
sorry
i'll just present from here thanks yeah
thanks alexey
make it quick because the document
hasn't been updated
next slide
um
so yeah as a reminder this is to uh
gmap extension to allow
signing and or encrypting on send so
there are two
uh boolean attributes added
by default they are absent and you know
may the signing or no encryption would
happen
if both are specified then its first
message is first signed and encrypted
next slide
three ish open issues
one is to what extent we need to control
uh
how the sign message is generated there
are two
common ways of doing this using multiple
sign or
application pks7 mime
um
if i don't get any feedback learning
tentatively i'll probably suggest that
there is a boolean to control this with
application cases seven mind being the
default
um
as far as header protection is concerned
uh lamps working group is working on
this and actually uh
this atf will announce that we made some
progress on this so there is some hope
that this document will complete um
so i would say
yes we probably need to have another
boolean to control this for backward
compatibility
uh
with the default being probably no uh
don't protect headers
[Music]
and then the last question is
whether this needs to be extended for
a spam decryption um and
well there is one way of doing this
through decrypted blobs cool daniel's
just popped up in a queue do you want to
say something
yeah um i mean lexi may feel differently
about where we're landing on the header
protection draft but uh i believe we're
in the position where
the default should be able to be true
um because i think the generated
messages won't actually have problems
um
so i think it'd be a shame if the
default if we baked a default of false
in here
uh for header protection
um the second question is about how do
you think um
the s mime signing
we're talking about delegating here
secret keys to the jmap server
yes
okay
um that definitely changes the idea of
end to end
at some level uh yes and uh depending on
how exhibited the slightly different
trust model right yeah the theory here
is that maybe the gem app server and the
jmf client are within devices under your
control so that is still your end um for
that purpose gmap's not really designed
so much to
to
only pass encrypted blobs if you did
then there's no point having this at all
um so if you are using this it's because
you believe that you control the server
as well and so it's part of your end
okay
um so
yeah i will uh
at least implement the first two
changes next time and then we talk we
can talk about decryption which is uh
it's kind of
complementary feature but it will
require different approach
um
yeah that's the last slide yeah the um
so what i think i understood from that
was that we could make it be default to
was it signing true
if you request the capability for this
obviously if you don't request the
capability then then this property
doesn't exist but we could default it to
true everything i think uh gkg was
talking about header protection actually
okay if you want to do
if you do a design encryption by default
header protection will be true unless
you okay you disable it
yes alexa has it right
cool thank you awesome uh
with that we're basically done with the
jmap portion of this other than having a
quick glance at the milestones but we
might leave that just to the end and
move on to extra if that works for
people just because we're running over
time
so looking at the agenda for extra
the first item we had on here was
uh extra quota which is with the editors
is there anything to say on extra quota
um
no um i've said it i basically noticed
that some text to an eye on a website
was out of date
uh
i sent a separate ticket to anna to
update it it's sort of a procedural i
think they uh
they don't want to publish rfc unless
this is sorted
but uh even like the page saying you
know who approved the rfc publication
already disappeared so i assume that
it's sort of like
it's near imminent basically
awesome thank you all right so the next
thing on our agenda is
uh steve action registry
yes uh very quickly about this um
basically the registry itself
the template is relatively
straightforward and then the main part
of the job was
to actually populate it with initial
registrations
which hopefully can can just did
uh so he is now coeditor
i think we have one little pending
things about reject
uh we want to add a comment saying that
it
with which actions it conflicts which
might be useful information
uh
but
basically i think people need to check
what we've done
uh
and you might as well send it to working
group last call
all right next on the list is not
actually what the slides are up there
for
because i don't appear to have slides
for civ snooze
this is ken regarding sif's news
no updates to the draft um it's been
implemented in cyrus imap it's been
deployed at fast mail
it works as intended as expected
firing any other feedback
i'd like to ask for working group last
call
all right anybody have any feedback on
that before we go to working group last
call
okay i checked the diff and it was like
minimal qualification so i think it's
it hasn't changed recently so it's just
done
all right um we now since what's up
there we might as well talk about
process imap
sure so um this is an idea i sent an
email to the mailing list a few months
back um
sketching out what we intended to
implement in cyrus imap
went back and forth between an action to
a test back to an action
i finally documented what we have
implemented in cyrus imap which is on
the next slide
so this is what it looks like
we've got
five different options there first one
is a list of addresses if they are
outside of what the server would
normally know this is
analogous to the addresses parameter in
vacation
so that the user would tell the server
these are the identities that i have
normally email addresses so any invite
or reply that i get for one of these
addresses
you can go ahead and process for me
next set is a it's a
mutually exclusive pair
you can give it a calendar id onto which
you expect new invites to go on to which
goes back to our previous default
calendar discussion
ultimately if you do not want to get
spammed with invites from untrusted
users
you can tell the server only
process updates which would mean replies
from other users
or or i'm sorry it would mean updates
only meaning changes from an existing
event on your calendar or cancel or that
kind of thing
third option we tell the server if i do
receive a cancel please remove this from
my calendar
and then the other two are optional if
um
you've got the variables extension
enabled
um two different variable names one to
give you a set of thick strings what the
outcome of the action was
this could be anything from no action to
updated to added
and i think there's one other one in the
spec i forget what it is off top my head
and the last option is another optional
variable which would give you a human
readable string explaining the actual
outcome most notably if it's a an error
or a failure
so that's what we have
i'm here to see if there's interest from
anybody else and moving this forward and
formalizing this
as a spec this has been implemented
again as i said in cyrus imap we
deployed it to some of our users last
week
and it appears to be doing what we've
had previously done
in middleware as opposed to directly in
civ
um alexi melnikov so yeah i i've
scanned this today quickly
seems to make sense um
a couple of comments is one
um
versus pro it's probably the first case
when you have extra
output parameters in action but i
suppose you know when there are two
extensions but you know
it's not
in any obvious way wrong is just unusual
but i think that's a fine solution um as
far as the outcome
values
uh concerned
i think it would be better if you split
update and cancel
into two different values
it just
i don't know it seems
cancelling and possibly removing the
event might mean something different
from just updating it so i might want to
do something different based on that
um
the other comment is
now that cf action is going to be in
last call we need to add it to this to
the document
yeah this is kind of guy i realized that
last week and didn't get a chance to
push another update figuring that i was
i got added
unknowingly to the civ action
spec i should probably follow that spec
there actually is a
a uh
example of what this looks like on the
next slide
but it still doesn't change the
question out there is if anybody else
feels this is work worth
adopting in the working group and moving
forward
hi this is jerk um i have just a tiny
question and maybe i actually i have to
admit i didn't read the draft yet but my
question is from what i see
i'm asking myself you know is there a
standard way imap is currently
implemented in systems because it's i
guess not really standardized how it's
done architecturally
and this somehow hooks in
you know somehow of kind of a dependency
which in some systems might
you know create architectural issues in
some way which is not necessarily an
overall issue but i'm just wondering um
this is something one should maybe state
for potential implementers of this
that there might be wider ranging
consequences of implementing that so to
answer your first question the only two
ways that i'm aware of currently that
this is done is a the email clients do
the processing
or b the provider
has some other out-of-band facility for
doing so which is what we did
previously
so this is just a different way to have
the user be in control of what's going
to happen in a standardized way
i'm sorry your second question
maybe
just thinking about it
um
before probably the it was primary
processing might have been unconditional
on hard-coded how it's handled now you
can say
only accept invitations from this set of
people for
example you know
and do a few fancy things
yeah
to that point this
currently does not
give you
the ability to say i want to accept from
this set of users but i believe
yes i believe there's other facilities
within civ to do exactly that especially
using the list extension
so you could have it reach into your
your card dev
you know
address book you know whatever
this does not tell you when to do the
processing it tells you how to do the
processing if you choose to have it done
does this go to the list to adopt this
or just yeah i'll do a call for adoption
on the list
um it sounds like this there's nobody
violently objecting to the idea so we
may as well
go ahead if adopted i might wrote lexian
as a co-author
we cannot just credit everything ah yeah
i mean not everybody will implement it
but i think it's a sensible idea to
to doing this working
that's all i have thank you excellent
thank you there were more slides but
they're just examples here
beautiful
all right fantastic then all we have
left
in all of this is imap partial
right i i actually uh updated the title
of the document because it actually has
sort of two related extensions now
um
yeah
so uh
shall i do people remember what partial
is all about
do you want to know
so uh
basically in imap if you do search
typically search will do the full
mailbox search
you can say only return
and messages
and first or second page whatever
this helps
the client to receive less data as well
as servs saves server work
once it reaches the number of messages
it can stop doing it
somewhat similar example is with uig
fetch
you can have a uid range where you don't
actually necessarily know how many
messages in the range so again you say
if if my client can only show 10 000
messages
there is no reason
to return hundred thousand you know
if it's so many in the range so you can
say just just return me first or you
know
um
yeah next slide
and uh
i mean for smaller mailbox on mailboxes
it doesn't
matter that much but this is concerned
with large mailboxes say 50k and more
so as i said uh search return option for
returning page or mul it's a range of
messages in the response
and also so it's a search modifier and
uid fetch modifier
next slide
so this is how it looks
this example says
return
100 messages from the end of the mailbox
the most recent ones
if you don't use miner syntax then it's
the first one from the beginning of the
mailbox but
[Music]
so this was
motivate partially motivated by yahoo
people they they want to
do better
handling of very large mailboxes and
their
most common case is going to be the most
recent one
i have a question about this one yeah um
that's not only allowing negative
numbers it's also reversing the order
it's got the higher numbered one first
is that
deliberate and supposed to be allowed or
is that a
what uh minus one minus hundred or minus
hundred minus one this should be the
same
what happens if you make a minus and a
positive then i i i i negative and
positive you either both use both
negatives or both positives
oh okay
so a a the a the
range at the you know the most recent
one or
in the kind of the least recent one
so the partial
positive number colon positive number
was original part of 5267 so it's
backward compatible but this ends the
negative syntax to say from the most
recent messages so you don't
necessarily need to know
your ids for them for example
one positive and one negative for voice
versus an error
okay next slide
cool and this is how the fetch example
works
uh
again you know
some cl if you know how many messages in
the range or in the uid fetch range
that is not
as useful but if you don't or if you
want to
page through results
then it gives you more control over this
next slide
yeah so uh
we do have wonderful problem in imap
where we have so many extensions we
sometimes forget how they interact with
each other
so actually partial existed before save
existed before save is
[Music]
do the search and save the result in a
variable
right and um the interaction between the
two weren't actually specified so um
timothy ryan and from duff code asked
about interactions and now this is
clarified
next slide
so um
there were actually a fair amount of
changes since version zero but most of
them were not related to the partial
uh the main
clarification about partial is that if
it's used with constore
uh it
exp it is explicit how they use together
so you can say
send me flag changes for all messages
change this timestamp
and only return so many of them
so
the other extension is message limit
where
server basically insists that
you cannot request any operation on more
than
so many messages
i mean obviously if the limit is 10
messages it's not going to be very
useful but this is supposed to be like
10 000 or 100 thousand messages or
whatever
this is of more interest to yahoo people
because they try to avoid
[Music]
storing full maps of message numbers to
your ids
so it's kind of easier for them to page
page through numbers and resolve indexes
this way
so
various revisions clarified interaction
with sort
i think they a message limit and sort
can be used together
but you either need to have a special
index
uh
or you say well this mailbox is too big
so i cannot do it
thread and message limit cannot be used
together if the mailbox has more than
message delivered messages it's just not
going to work
because threading doesn't work with
partial sub data basically well
sort of gives you corrupted threats
which are not very useful
um
don't remember do i have a next slide
yep two more
okay
uh one of the main open issues is copy
and uid copy
[Music]
one of the things that this is trying to
address is the client can say well
i want to copy all messages from the
mailbox to another mailbox
you have hundred thousand messages
message limit is ten thousand
so do you just fail to do the operation
altogether
or do you copy uh
ten thousand messages and say well
i only partially completed you need to
retry with other
with the remainder of them if you care
um
this is kind of tricky because
we never had copy failed partially
before
but this is trying to
do we want to uh
all the clients that don't support this
become unusable
because they don't understand this
response code or
so that's kind of a tricky question i
have i have an opinion i think we should
reject it outright rather than allow it
to succeed because otherwise the clients
will just try again and again and they
will wind up copying the same ten
thousand messages again and again to the
destination holder no it's not how it
works
i mean yes it might be a valid reason
but the way it works at the moment is it
says
he says copy hundred thousand messages
it will copy ten thousand and return
okay
with message limit
so the naive client will say oh all the
hundred thousand messages got copied but
on actually only ten thousand for a
pocket uh and then it will try and
delete all of them and it will only
delete the same ten thousand assuming it
hits the same limit
yes yeah uh
so
well
the alternative is you know the client
just cannot do it and then it's like
well does it try to repeat itself or
just give up i don't know yeah or the
client has to do batch copies well
that's the thing the client basically
needs to be updated to know about about
the limit and doing batches
uh
i don't know i i keep flipping back and
forth about this this is kind of tricky
but
we can discuss yeah
i don't necessarily have an opinion on
this issue but just something else to
bring up which is probably painful does
this if any way shape or form affect
renaming of the inbox that abomination
where you're copying
barry has an opinion
sorry i didn't push the button but this
is barry
not on what ken just said but the other
bit
we
previously don't have any
stuff in imap where the server puts
limits on things that the client
may not know about that affects the
client's behavior and this is the first
that i'm aware of
i don't like that i don't i don't like
the idea that a client that tries to
copy
a hundred messages and only gets ten of
them copied
doesn't if they haven't been updated to
understand this they have no way of
dealing with that situation and i i
think that's bad so i think
that if the server has a limit and the
client tries to do something above that
limit it just gets no
and nothing happens
and then the client that a client that
understands message limit knows what to
do with that or shouldn't have done it
in the first place but a client that
doesn't know just has to throw up its
hands because it has no way to
be recover
arguably not a lot of service will
implement this because this is kind of a
little bit of more niche as opposed to
partial partially generic facility
so uh
what we are saying
users will try their clients with the
server like this will be unable to do it
we'll have to complain to their client
client says well
i didn't i i didn't implement this why
do i want to then there is a discussion
with the server vendor whether you know
whether they want to implement it
okay uh i'm okay with that yeah this is
basically what i said as well that it
should it should be rejected and then
you the client either you either do a
smaller copy of just a range of messages
which the user can do
or you
you fix the client
okay
yeah this is why i struggled there is
now like it's unfortunate situation and
there is no elegant solution that will
just sort of
it's kind of a yeah
and still barry the
uh
to go to what ken said with uh what do
you do if you uh
rename inbox
um i think that has to be an exception
to message limit i think the server just
has to do it even if if the server has a
message limit of 100 and there are 10
000 messages in the inbox and you rename
the inbox
while the server can say no
or the server just has to do it and move
all 10 000
right you know whatever and if the
server is distributed and have a client
part and server part well then they'll
have to update the client part to
actually support this and then it should
work
i mean
can you actually send this in uh uh
send the email to the mailing list
because i think it's probably worth just
saying this explicitly
no send the reminder to the mailing list
saying about what about renaming box
with more than message limit messages
what will happen and we'll just say
server just has to do this we can add an
explicit statement as a reminder for
server implementations to do this
great thanks alexi is that everything
uh you got one more slide next step
seems ready for last call with partial
message limit may need a bit more work
who needs who wants to implement yeah
this is kent so
i as a server dev i think partial is
pretty straightforward to implement
uh question for alexi is a as a client
of have you actually implemented on your
site so we know it operates the way you
expect expected to operate
because i'd like to see some running
code before you go to last call
okay
yeah i'm happy to do that so i actually
did implement it in the client side but
i didn't test it with my server yet so
that's why i was hesitating i did it but
i just
i think it worked it's fine
it actually makes uh handing off big
mailboxes um
like webmail clients you know if you can
only display you know 10 pages
or 15 messages it makes it much easier
to implement because you don't need to
download you know the whole map for 100
yeah i was mostly concerned with does
the spec do what you needed to do as a
more so that i was worried about
interoperability at this point
awesome we have five minutes left let's
let's run through our milestones quick
hey
thanks everybody uh
here we go yes i do want to share my
screen
this one
i mean i i put the message limit and
partial in the same document do you want
me to split them up or is it okay just
we'll just keep it first i think we just
don't that should be fine to stay in the
same document and we'll just do one if
it's going to
well it's also if
if we decide that one of them is more
experimental than the other
but until we get there that's fine yeah
um
i'm happy to to
have a working group last call on this
as one or two documents and i have to do
a separate working group adoption call
sorry on on one or two
all right here's what we've got uh
submit document for blobs via gmap to
asg is going to have to move forwards to
next months
basically
uh submit civ
document to isg that's also for april i
guess
we decided that
the
uh gem up sieve
is ready for last call
i was hanging on to this because i
wanted to get some implementation
experience with the civ test method okay
um but if we want i could break that out
and we could make it a an extension down
the road no i think
it should be fine just to
we can we can test that within a month
we'll send it to working group last call
and test it during that time
fine
uh
sender extensions
we're ready to
last call that now alexi
no
fair enough
when
cool uh
god's implementation of imp servers and
proxies
kick it down the road
cool
gamer access to address books
this is
what do you reckon robert
yeah we're back on j-map now
calendar as we said is nearly ready to
to go isn't it
i don't know it's pretty late for him
no i think he might have might have
headed off to bed already
yep
i'll say july we'll get it by next time
here
uh
jason contact document and i need to
move that because it belongs in the
other work group now
i'll just hit delete on that
murray
go ahead
what what did you have to say
oh the first the first one that you
edited um
you said it for april 2021
did i
yeah ridiculous well down there right
there thank you
okay
that's i mean it should have been done
by april 2021 but we're where we are
thank you for that
um
i've deleted the js contacts that's
being moved uh gmap we said was
basically ready to go
and that
that says june all right
i'll say august
be nice if we get some stuff done
yep
done
review changes all
okay and milestones for extra
we had
steve actions registry adopt that got
done
so just resolve that
ea with sieve
that was just for adopt so
um adopt i think we've adopted it
already i'm just gonna resolve that
um
okay
i might say adopt by june
submit by
december
and that leaves update charter which is
for extra not done
but
we were going to update the charter
given that we've done
stuff but we didn't we charted email
core instead murray do you want to
comment on this
what am i commenting on
uh whether we want to update the charter
for extra
um
given that it's currently whatever it is
ah not that
i was just looking at it what what do we
want to cover that's not in there
already
yep um this was more whether we were
going to this was going to take on the
other email related stuff
oh
but the stuff that was brought up in
this match this morning this is before
email call
started i think we decided to question
whether it was going to happen here or
not oh
um
yeah the discussion that happened in
dispatch this morning i think probably
that whole question will either just
close the update charter here delete it
and work out what we want to do later
yeah i don't think we have to include an
updated charter as a milestone so let's
find it
yep
awesome
we will
put those changes through then and we
are done which is good because we're one
minute over
thanks everybody
good work see you tomorrow
what
all right
barry's gonna do a thing
all right there we go well you got you
got the infinite thing i need to turn
off my screen
i say grant
and you now have permission
there you go
you are now sharing slides
go ahead
oh everyone everyone's gathered around
barry
all right thank you to both of my chairs
for helping out
in this weird combined session
and particular gym taking notes very
much appreciate it
have a have a great evening everybody or
morning or wherever you are
and thanks for joining us
sure thing the hybrid session worked
pretty well actually yeah we did all
right
see y'all next time
uh it was a little bit wild not having a
microphone at the table i had to hold
this thing the whole time
um