yeah all right it's uh
time for the net count working group
session so let's get started
um
this is the first hybrid meeting for all
of us and i'm sure we're all trying to
get used to the system a little bit so
bear with us if not everything quite
works perfectly as you would expect
okay
um
this is the 113 meeting for netconf
here is the familiar notewell
i'll give you a moment to just quickly
glance through it
there
is also a link at the bottom
in case you
want to read it in more detail
okay
moving on
um
a couple of administrative things for
people
who are in the room first
do remember that you need to sign in to
meet echo
for it for you to not only speak to the
mic
but also to be registered as a
participant in blue sheets
so make sure you do that there are a
couple of qr codes around the room that
you can use to log in
also
even though you're in the room
you're supposed to join the queue in
meet echo
before you
speak into
the
microphone
so do remember to do that
for
remote participants
do turn off your audio and video unless
you're presenting
or asking a question
and using
a use of a headset is highly recommended
blue sheets we already talked about
we do have a chat window which you'll
see next to the attendee list on the
left
you can use that to communicate
um
there is also
a notes window
that you can
open into a separate tab from the menu
bar at the top right
and
while some of us here in the room will
be taking some notes i would highly
encourage
people sitting remotely
if they could add their
understanding of what's happening
to the notes section
it's been pre-populated with
the agenda for netcast
jabber if anybody is on jabber they're
whatever they type should
show up in the chat window of meet echo
all right
we have a two-hour slot for today
we'll try to help the presenters along
with the counter that will show at the
bottom of the
screen for them to know when their time
is up
we don't expect
to use
to have to cut off anyone either on
presentation or questions
but if we have to use it we'll use it
we talked about the queue
to remember to cue yourself in miteko
before speaking
to speak use the icon with the play
symbol
and remember to remove yourself from the
queue once you're done speaking
we talked a little bit about the note
taking
if you don't have the link i have put
that at the bottom the last bullet
but it's also available in the menu bar
on the top
of me takeo
all right so status of liaisons and at
this point let me hand it over to kent
to talk a little bit about the liaison
statement with ieee
yes uh thank you mahesh
um so ieee
802.1
reached out to netconf working group
about
half a year ago
with regards to the keystore draft
and in particular some language with
regards to
promoting or copying private keys
from
a
built-in or system
data store
to running data store
and
just
on a couple weeks ago
rob wilton and myself attended the
youngsters meeting
on march the 10th which is during the
ieee 802.1 plenary
and we had a good discussion i thought
it lasted for about 10 minutes or so
and which the action items that came
from that was one first for rob to send
a liaison response
with regards to
general conformance
when dealing with multiple standards or
standard spanning multiple sdos
there's three
items for myself
one to ensure the keystore keystore
draft adequately indicates what kind of
key is being referred to on a
case-by-case basis
second to amend the keysword draft to
indicate that built-in keys should not
be clear text
and lastly to ensure that the crypto
type strap adequately defines what is
meant as a hidden key
and then lastly
mick seaman from ieee would ensure that
those draft updates addressed his
concerns
so the actual impact would be of course
the updating of the keystore draft and
potentially also the crypto types draft
so that's all i wanted to say about this
uh but i know that scott mansfield
who's part of the ieee group is in the
room and maybe would like to say
something as well or yes go ahead scott
i don't want to
bust in line uh rob has something to say
first and then i can close off
sorry i didn't see the queue order
you're right go ahead rob
yeah go ahead and use that uh euro
robles from cisco so um yes i think kent
sums it up well i think was a good
discussion in terms of laser response i
raised this with um the isg and iab
suggesting that i'd write this response
they're quite happy with that so i think
that's fine i think it might end up
coming from the working group but i'm
happy to work on the text and then uh
work out what the exact process is and
probably we can run it by scott and mick
beforehand to check that they can be
happy with what we're writing there as
well
thanks
perfect
scott did you watch or add something
yes scott mansfield erickson
also works on liaison and such the
first off wanted to really thank rob and
ken for reaching out and trying to get
this
issue resolved
the
ietf
ieee liaison officer i believe is russ
housely so we should include him to make
sure that it goes through the right
proper channels
if you need any help from me since it is
an 802.1 specific thing i can also help
with the wording or help get it to the
right people but other than that it was
a great discussion the next youngsters
meeting for those that care will be on
the 29th of march
so if you if there's any follow-up or
questions please feel free to join that
meeting thank you
all right
um so continuing
the chair status um
so this
with the chartered work group items
the yang push notifications as an rfc
congratulations to the authors
rfc 9196
the
rest of the workgroup items
we have sztp csr draft
that is passed iesg review
i believe it's in the rfc editor queue
at this point
the https nordicdraft um is waiting for
a write-up
and i guess should is it fair to say
that the shepherd has been identified
i'm asking robby here
uh robert yes i've got a shepherd lined
up so that's good
and i needed the write-up so it's just
waiting on me so i will try and get to
that soon this week hopefully
thanks rob
um
the client service suite of drafts
have completed work group last call
there are a couple of uh last call
issues that are being resolved as we
speak
the european order draft is work in
progress
will be discussed in this meeting
and the distributed notif uh is that
version three
and there's been very little discussion
on the list
so
here is the agenda for today
um we have
of course kent with
the client server suite of drafts
and
udp notif they uh sorry udp based
transport
for configured is all the other work
group
chartered item
on the non-chartered item list we have a
few presentations
um so
it should be a fairly packed session
with enough time for questions at the
end
right i think that's pretty much it for
the chair presentations any questions
go ahead scott
hi it's uh
maybe it's just me because i am remote
but mahesh you sound it sounds like he's
underwater or something i don't know if
i just need to turn up my volume but i
have no trouble hearing kent or rob or
anyone else so just wanted to raise that
thanks
okay is this any better
yes it is better when you face them
all right i'll try to speak into the mic
okay
all right um mahesh i'm going to revoke
yours oh you did it yourself fine let me
start sharing the next
slides
okay so
my name is kent i'm presenting the
client service with the drafts
um this has been a long project for the
working group and we're almost to the to
the end of it
this is actually the first time that the
client service suited drafts has been
presented since itf 110
though they were touched on as chair
slides amendment or you know notes
during the chair slides in previous
ietf sessions
so uh on this time i'll just do a little
bit recap going back to 110 it's not
much actually because we've just been
doing uh fit and finish for the most
part
um but for the crypto types draft we did
accommodate some sector review comments
from valerie simslove and we added the
hidden keys feature uh i mean so the
hidden concept of hidden keys existed
before just the the feature statement
hidden keys didn't exist before
in the trust anchors draft we added
prefixes to the path statements on a per
trust anchor issue um
regarding that issue
and we renamed the trustpillar supported
uh feature to central trustor supported
that was from jurgen i believe
we removed two unnecessary slash
unwanted min element 1
statements and added a present statement
and we added an informative reference to
the mos netmod with systemdraft
so with regards to built-in keys at the
time that we wrote the text for built-in
keys and trust anchors
we only had operational data store but
now
there's this introduction of a system
data store so those things could show up
there as well and so an informative
reference made sense
for the keystore draft we also the same
note about adding prefixes to path
statements
and again we renamed the feature from
keystore supported to central keystore
supported
and we added feature statements for
asymmetric keys and symmetric keys
and lastly an informative reference to
the with system draft
you'll notice that on the right hand
side it does mention that the key store
is the liaison we just discussed
and
so next slide we had a tcp client server
draft
we removed the tcp connection grouping
grouping um and so now we just use the
tcp common grouping directly that was
actually done quite a while that was
back in the 110 time frame it was done a
while ago we added a security
consideration section for the local
binding supported feature
and then for ssh client server draft we
removed the supported authentication
methods
from the client authentication grouping
and we moved algorithms
away from
the ietf ssh common module to a more
general iana maintain modules and this
is kind of a big thing we also did it in
the tls client server graph but
essentially the same update where
we're going to the iana maintained
registries for algorithms
once for ssh and then separately again
for tls
and converting those registries
into gang modules
that can be henceforth maintained by
ayanna
so that's what that item there is
we also added a config false list for
the algorithm supported so
while they're in iana registry defines
hundreds of algorithms a particular
server may only
support a subset of them so this config
false list enables them to identify the
server identify which subset they
support
and we also added
to be discussed in this slide
presentation a generate public key
rpc and so we'll be discussing that in a
moment
for the tls client server craft we again
moved algorithms and we have now the
iana maintained modules
and again we
added a config false list for the
algorithm supported by the server
and then lastly we made a major update
to this draft and specifically to the
yang modules to support tos 1 3
mostly in reaction to comments made by
tom patch over of course the last year
with regards to how cls13 was quite
different
and shortly uh we'll be presenting that
as well
so
moving on uh there were really no
updates to the http client server draft
in these past a year just nits
in the netconf client server draft
we did augment in a mapping required
flag into the client identity mappings
only for the ssh transport
and so
just locking things down making the
the validation more correct
and then lastly we removed appendix a
which was having before fully expanded
tree diagrams but those tree diagrams
were enormous i mean literally the tree
diagram itself spanned uh five pages i
think and so we just removed those
foliage and once they fully expanded i
mean all the groups have been expanded
so the uses statements have been
expanded uh so now only uh both the
netcomf server netconf and rescon client
server drafts have just the unexpanded
uh where the grouping are displayed as
users
that's what so those are the updates of
sense 110.
i did mention a couple items that we're
going to circle back on the first is
this generate public key rpc which is an
open issue and i'm hoping to get some
discussion uh so about three years ago
folks may remember that the crypto types
draft attempted to define actions for
generating private keys
and after much discussion we abandoned
these action statements when it became
not possible to define a set of
algorithm identifiers that span protocol
stacks so for instance ssh and tls
each of these
protocols are their own
crypto silos if you will having their
own iana maintained registries and
trying to get the security
directorate or area to unify to come
with a unified set of algorithm
identifiers expand these protocols
proved difficult to say the least
so we did abandon that idea about three
years ago
but uh since then um as mentioned
earlier both the client the ssh client
server and tls client server drafts now
have their own
iana maintained algorithm identifiers
they're being pulled from iana
maintained registries
and so it becomes possible again to
maybe define
um an rpc but this time make it be
protocol specific rpcs in each draft
so i've already made this update to the
ssh draft which i'll on the next slide
i'll show and the slide after is
regarding the tls draft which is where
the discussion comes into play
so for the ssh draft you can see it's
just an rpc it's very straightforward
their input but notice that the
algorithm at the very top on the right
hand side
in yellow it's a it's an algorithm
identifier identity reference so that is
a reference to
and you can see it ssh of course the
protocol ssh pka stands for public key
algorithm
so in ssh there's four different kinds
of algorithm
identities based classes pka is one of
the four
and is the only one that really matters
when it comes to generating private keys
so it's a reference to that public key
identifier
as basically what is the kind of
algorithm or what kind of key do you
want to generate
there is a bit so how long of a key
and then and then there's a little bit
of how do you want it to be encoded do
you want the key to be returned as clear
text
or should it be encrypted by another key
or would you like in fact the system to
hide the key like it becomes a built-in
key
not
ever visible to the outside
outside the server
and the response
is uh effectively exactly the same as
what you'd find inside keystore but in
the form of output for rpc response so
the format of the key how's it been
encoded
and then of course if it's different
kinds of key if it's clear text you just
get the key if it's hidden then it's
just an empty you don't really get the
key it just says it's empty and if it's
encrypted you get back the encrypted
data but also a reference to the other
key that it was encrypted by
so that's all very straightforward and
it's easy i mean doing this rpc took me
no more than 45 minutes probably to put
together very straightforward then i
moved on to tls to try to do the same
there and discovered some complication
the issue is that with tls there's only
one registry and that registry defines
what's called cipher suites
so these cipher suites are you know
they're not standalone private key
algorithm like ssh it's it's more of a
combination of a private key algorithm
an encryption algorithm blocking padding
and so an example would be for instance
tls-rsa-with aes1256
cbc sha-256 so you can just see how many
different algorithms have been encoded
in there but the main thing is rsa so
this is in fact an rsa key and if you
were to ask the system to generate a key
for that cypher suite it would be
expected that the system could say oh
what you want me to do is inherit an rsa
key
anyway but it's a little bit it's not
perfect right it's not like with ssh so
the question and and again i'm hoping
for some discussion
is should we
move forward should we continue and and
and define this rpc passing in a cypher
suite algorithm uh assuming that the
server can identify which private key
and generate the appropriate key from
there
or should we just back out of i mean i'm
kind of adding in this generating a
private key at the last uh at the last
hour um again it was removed about three
years ago
at that time it was uh author's
preference and at the i decided i prefer
not to move forward with it it's kind of
what i was thinking at that time but now
it's been it's so easy because the iron
had defined registry so i'm willing to
give it another small go
if people um
can help me get past this one issue any
comments on this
okay i don't see anyone in the room
joe's on the cube go ahead joe
uh yeah
um joe clark cisco i don't really i
don't can you go back a couple of slides
i i didn't actually have a comment here
it was just reading okay one more up
so is it generating the public key or is
it generating the public private key i
just found the name of the rpc
yes it's
confusing
okay well it's generating the private
key but in doing so it also generates
the public key
and in the key store itself it stores
both
and since this was a mimic of what is
stored in the key store then also the
output the contains both the public key
and the private key
but that the main thing that's coming
back is the private key
brian and so i was thinking would
generate key pair or something along
those lines be clearer um i just think
of like analogous to ssh key gen
um
something that is unambiguous that
you're do you're actually generating
both okay um possibly i i the actual
name of this rpc generate public key i
think i stole from
open ssh
and uh it mimicked their language and
remember mean i mentioned the ssh has
four different kinds of key elements
sorry algorithm identifiers so this is
the public key algorithm it's actually
called quote public key
so um i was trying to leverage that but
you'd make a good point uh we don't have
to necessarily we would just say
generate
key pair a symmetric keypair that would
be an option yes okay sorry i didn't
have a response to the other one but
this one was i was scratching my head
because it it seemed like you were doing
both thanks
okay anyone else any other comments
are crypto experts in the room
well how about this is anyone feel like
we should not pursue this
again it's sort of being added should we
just
close down the idea of i mean it's best
practice for a server to generate
private key
okay we do have one person coming up to
the mic diego
lopez
i forgot to register on the uh
i was checking that uh i remember on the
in the
good old days there was sifer suites
that were allowed to have a new value
for some of the
i i know that they are not valid for tls
but you could either you could use a
cipher suite only to identify one
particular part of the
of the suite is here this is the
the relevant part that would be uh
doable i'm not sure this has been
deprecated by the people in the tls but
if the uh in the tls group but if the
purpose is to identify
a concrete
private key for example
i think it would be valid
valid for the intention not valid as a
tls acceptable cipher suite anyway
okay thank you
we can confirm with the tls chairs as
well
okay moving forward
thank you everyone for those comments
um i'm going to transition now to
slides for
the update to the tls and um i have a
co-presenter jeff hartley who's joining
me and uh jeff yeah perfect i see he's
joined the microphone queue and so jeff
i'm going to let actually if you'd like
i'm going to pass slide control to you
which you now have if you hit your right
left mouse button you should be able to
increment the slides
gotcha just checking the audio there i
see the graph showing up in the
interface just want to make sure it's
audible over these sessions
you sound perfect to me
okay
so just a quick summary try not to take
too much time here um
some feedback had arrived via previous
chatter parts by
joining the team
uh think of me as an informal liaison
from bbf we have a lot of client server
type applications that we're looking at
uh rolling out in the next year or two
and some of our own standards and uh
having a
standards-based framework for
integrating those would be perfect
things like grpc kafka https transport
things like that so some of the chatter
that had been active at the time that
i threw some time over the wall here was
that uh tls one two and tls one three's
usage of the term psk
uh are vastly different and that proved
to be the case
so
in the uh
original
specifications there of course was
already a psk in place
uh and it sort of had the assumptions of
tls 1.2 and going
before that
so
it was quickly deemed necessary to split
that out designate which one was one two
which one was one three in fact this
notion of an external psk is prevalent
throughout the tls 1.3 rfc
so in fact i would dare say it's not
really a tls v 1.3 psk it's a tlsb 1.3
epsk
one noteworthy change uh is this notion
of zero round trip time as they call it
and it's that
the
entire handshake
once the client has authenticated itself
and the server's accepted that
and they they effectively agree upon the
parameters embedded in the external psk
they can immediately start sending data
the server can immediately start
fulfilling requests and while that's a
gross oversimplification of the full
description which you can of course find
in one three
it it really did need some attention and
call out here
so the
the action items as described uh just
split 1.2 and 1.3 psks apart from each
other
a few additional identities and features
of course so we could use a feature
statements uh to just apply some
constraints to them
but uh nothing too earth shattering
beyond that
uh hopefully the font is legible but i i
kept only sort of the the main body you
can see the full text of these drafts uh
via kent's
github and that sort of thing
so all the all the descriptions and
references i assure you are there uh in
fact a couple of the uh the notes are
are pretty handy reading i would say
so in the case of the
tls one two psk that was the original
structure it really is unchanged it's
just renamed uh the the original psk
there and you'll notice that you're
going to see the the concept of identity
hints and things like that which don't
exist in one three when we get into the
one three e p s k
right and again the those of us who are
our sticklers for syntax will notice
that the e p s k is different than the
psk above it
i assure you that's consistent with the
rfcs and it helps really point out the
difference that there's no parity
between these things and how they're
used
um the
uh the actual cryptography underneath it
was was really not the
the big challenge here in order in other
words
we could still reuse this notion of
keystore as canton companies draft
cesari had already defined it so that
part wasn't so bad but you're going to
notice that there's some leaves in here
that are dissimilar to what had come
before
of course the
the actual
hash itself
you can see right there there's a new
type for that like what hash algorithm
you're going to use there's a limit of
exactly two that are currently defined
uh that being an identity could be
extended pretty easily in the future
should
tls13 add additional types of hashes
supported
and a lot of this is sort of context
specific there's the the actual leaf for
context
uh target protocol for example if you
had
say
an https client
right or if you had some other form of
client that is
effectively manipulating this then that
information can be populated uh and the
key derivation function is another
mandatory piece in here again the
descriptive text had to be trimmed to
fit on the slides but uh but this is the
structure of what was added and
differentiated from the tls12 and prior
psks
uh the server of course when we're
looking at the client the server is is
the inverse of the clients
and it simply specifies hey
which of these if features are you going
to support when you're talking to a
particular server
if you look at the server it's of course
the inverse of the client
the exact same structures right with uh
opposite positioning so
the tls server grouping
contains the case statements that we're
just speaking of
and the
container specifying what client
altercation authentication it will
support in terms of psk's
is there
and i believe kent did i have the i did
i did include the
additional uh
identities here there was a bit of a
nomenclature clean up there
we went for the most simplistic
uh structure of just tls one two tls one
three uh that got cleaned up throughout
the files
and we talked about the new uh the new
type def for epsk supported hashes
that's easily extensible i had said
identity earlier but uh type def
for that
and
that's about it the references it's
really the same three references in most
of the fields we talked about there
and you can see those listed here
i'll pause here and
see if folks want to line up with any
questions there might be a couple of
folks in on the chat or in the room
whose previous comments were directly
addressed by this or at least i hope
we're directly addressed by this
i do not see tom patch on meet echo
so
if we're waiting for him to respond i
don't think we're gonna get that
okay well then i'll end my section by
just stating that if folks do have time
to look at these later and they like to
make comments uh i do
participate in the netcoff mailer so
thanks
oh
oh i think i killed slides
sorry about that
um
oh hold on
no no
because we're not supposed to be we're
sharing these slides just yet
ah okay here we go sorry about that
zooming ahead to the end
thank you jeff and by the way um jeff
was just absolutely awesome
we worked together i think over the
course of maybe three months and
possibly meeting every other week
on all this so a really huge
contribution thank you jeff
last slide for me uh next steps uh
we mentioned uh so jeff just talked
about updates to the tls we you know we
need we should definitely be validating
the correctness of these updates
um significant uh security
you know related update
it would be good for sector to take a
look at it i do know that that sector
takes a look at
all drafts as they're being published so
perhaps we do it just as a part of the
normal
ietf publication process or if rob ad
would like to have a proactive
you know sector review beforehand before
doing that we could discuss that as well
as mentioned also there's the ieee
liaison some minor updates need to be
made there and lastly resolving the
generatekey rpc action issue that we
just discussed
and then we're done i i mean amazingly
uh working group chairs can publish the
entire set to a.d at this point in just
a few weeks
and i'll be noting here we started this
work in 2014 so eight years ago this has
been a large long effort
and uh happy to be near the end
and that's it for this presentation
thank you oh i do see rob in the queue
go ahead rob like you up the next thing
so just uh robleton cisco i was just
going to ask in terms of an early sec
dear review have you been working quite
closely with the security folks anyway i
understand so i think you're probably
pretty good to do that just as part of
the general reviews i'm not sure we need
an early review here unless you think
otherwise
i don't actually think otherwise
i think it'd be okay to push it you know
do as part of the normal process
so i think that's that's what i would
suggest
what i would do rob is uh in your
write-up just bring note to it so some
extra attention is brought to that
section just
i think it's reasonable to just have
people take an extra careful look at the
way the tls-13 is supported
uh yep happy to flag that
okay thank you
okay
and now we're
moving to the next presentation this is
udp
based uh transport for configured
subscriptions
yes thank you alex please go ahead oh
let me pass you control over the key of
the slides as well
if i can
i'm not able to so uh just tell me when
you want to see next slide oh i hear it
i can't do it sorry about that
okay you can increment your own slides
now hit right button left button
yes it's working yes thank you
um so this is alex wang from insalion
and i am presenting today the few
changes we did on the dash
o5
of udp native draft
on the agenda i will explain shortly
the div we made on this new draft and we
would like to start a discussion on
uh how to configure dtls from the young
module
which
we got a little feedback on the mailing
list
so the few changes
during the last ietf
we got feedback
from
rob i think
that we should
specify the rfcs of the encoding types
of json and cyborg because they they
they had multiple
uh rfcs
uh we at the end uh decided uh that
instead of just specifying the rfc we
could
just
referencing the media type instead
so the registry would reference directly
to the already standardized
of the jana media types
after that
we modified a little young model
the module
we added
a feature in code seaboard leaf in the
young module
and then also change all the encoding
type references to be aligned
with the whole draft
um
we also
uh have been talking with the chairs uh
for the dtls
encryption part of this draft
we got feedback that it should be
[Music]
it should make it good for the security
review having the gtls part in in this
draft
and then
lastly some days ago i would say
that we got some feedback
that if we
would
add
the dtls part in the young module to be
configured configurable
from the router directly
so we would like to start actually a
discussion on this meeting that
if it is
something that it is expected for for
from the community
i would guess yes
but and then if just
importing the
i we saw that in the draft net conf
tls client server there are some uh
young modules implemented
and if just importing them it's it would
be enough
or
but what starting the discussion on on
this meeting
and
[Music]
i would say that would be all uh
just a quick uh
quick uh presentation too
about the distributed native draft
we changed a lead so we we did some
minor changes on the young model and we
also
uh think that uh the draft is already
pretty stable
and
that we would like to last call
when when this udp notifies last called
so that would
that would be from from my part and we
we could start this discussion
so can't
thank you
sorry so yes it is a good idea to
modify the configuration model so that
the actual tls part of dtls can be
configured
i mean so we're asking the
server to
in some cases initiate the outbound tls
connection to a remote tls server
and you know how does it authenticate
that server certificate
does it need to authenticate itself to
the server
you know where is the configuration for
these things uh specified it is uh
necessary it's not it cannot i don't
believe be just a flag like dtls is on
and there's a configuration that has to
be specified and i think that's the
request so uh yes exactly what it would
come down to
is the yang module that is in this draft
would
import the tls
client
um
module and maybe also the tls server
module if it turns out that it needs to
actually listen to uh connections as
well
and then um that should be most of it
you would want to also add examples that
illustrate
those configurations being
set and
i think that's the ask
does it make sense
yeah i think so yes
okay
thank you all right so i had similar
comments uh
uh as kent for the udp native but
also for the distributed native
i would love to see some examples
of
the configuration aspect i know there
are some examples of
subscribe notifications but the actual
configuration part
examples i did
at least the last version i didn't think
i saw
anything in particular
so that would be nice to have
and then um
in summary would you say that the
distributed node of draft is really
about
having this id that identifies the node
from where the
notifications are coming from because
that's pretty much the summary
of that what i understood of the draft
um
sorry can you repeat the last question i
did not get
um
so
with the
um
what i s what i remember seeing the last
version of the draft
uh
essentially what you're trying to do is
put in i don't remember the name you you
gave to it but it's
a node id that identifies where the
notification is coming from
is that i guess this
yeah the subscription id
yeah maybe it's the subscription id so
is that the summary of really that whole
draft
that you're essentially providing a
subscription id
uh maybe thomas or pf who dots or that
yes
okay thomas you're kind of breaking up
on at least at our end
okay is it now better
yes
okay uh domain
id is basically identifier which
identifies export process on the route
if more than one
and this is needed for the segmentation
of okay
in a nutshell that's what distributed
notif is and sits its uh transport
agnostic uh we need to describe that in
a safe director
okay uh so the uh the comment on the uh
it being transport independent
would you
still say that you don't want to talk
about whether the underlying
whether the transport is
tcp based or udp based
or you
give particular examples for each one
each type of transport that you're going
to use
which is uh basically where we can
implement that it's not implemented in
https
but for future drafts
that's why
and this
concept is not something which is coming
from that country is actually also being
applied the same way in it
okay i'll i'll
um send you the comments on the mailing
list
sure because we are having some problems
at our end
should we move on to the next
presentation now
yeah
okay
and um
why don't you uh or just i mean let
people okay there's a small agenda
bashing
while we were uh between slides here
and we've moved the adaptive
subscription presentation to the end
everything else will be the same
so
next is per node capabilities
for optimal data collection
i think benoit is in the room we'll be
presenting
yes i am
perfect
so let me present this
so as you introduce this this is like
the per node capabilities for optimum
operational data collection
so that's a draft that started about two
years ago
and the goal today is to see if there is
still interest to continue on this draft
so disclaimer i have not updated it just
a refresh
so if you go to the next slide
there is just
you know if we're looking at automation
we know that in the end automation is as
good as your data models
so we created many models in the itf and
in different places in industry
so we're going to write track over there
so your automation is as good as your
tool chain
and we worked on the tool chain in
hackathon different places
is it perfect
no
but it's getting there
your automation is as good as your young
model's metadata
and we work on the young catalog where
we've got metadata about those young
models
the standard this implemented it is
service model orders
the last point is the per node
capabilities because if you want to
configure something in your network you
want to know if a specific node that you
want to configure let's say for
telemetry has some capabilities
now if you go to the next slide
this is what we did with this new rfc
that mahaj presented in the in the intro
what we have in there is two young
models
the first one is the placeholder
and the second one offers some
capabilities so if i look at the last
four entries on the slides
it tell us per nodes what is the minimum
update period that you could have on
telemetry right for a specific object
it tell us uh what are the support
update period whether on change is
supported right let's say you want to do
telemetry with unchanged
it's key to understand if that specific
note supports it or not
and the minimum dampening period
so
we've produced that rfc and that's also
a reason why we have not updated our
draft because it's linked
so if you go to the next slide now
so this draft is about updating this
list of yang objects
so per
node
and
we provide to our pc
just to be able to retrieve them easily
to see if those nodes that we're looking
for are capable of doing
what we want
okay
as i mentioned
the draft has not been updated but now
that we've got the previous rfc it's
time to decide what you want to do
so let's go over the
the couple of
examples
so next slide please
so the first one is like
the suggested
observation
observable period right
it's like yeah maybe the router supports
all these different
periods for observation observation
but maybe there is one which is the one
that the vendor suggests
right
and
it's different different at the minimum
one
because maybe the minimum one is like
one millisecond
but maybe it's not very practical or the
router will have some problem to sustain
it
the second one is that well
if let's say i want to stream the
flipped content
we could say the minimum one is one
millisecond one second but actually it
depends how big your fib is
right so just giving something like a
generic answer is not always practical
so telling
like the router
under these conditions
knowing the number of entries in the fip
as one example
we advise you to stream it every
five minutes or whatever
but the point is that it's these are
characters that are depending on a note
per node basis
next slide please
the next one is the optimize measurement
point
so typically
in a in a router
let's say you want to stream a specific
interface
counter number of packets
all right
now
internally in a router you might have a
structure with all the interface
counters
so going and taking a single entry in
the structure structure to stream it
might be more
might be less efficient than just
streaming the entire structure
from a router point of view not
bandwidth right
but then on the character side you could
just be filtering out what you don't
care about
so in this example of the interface
number of packet interface
maybe
this value will tell you well just
observe the entire
three which is interface
right
so this is the idea behind that one
on the next slide
this one is about
the corresponding
yang object and mip or id if we know it
right
so
we know snmp still works
right
we know it's not going to be replaced
so
sometimes just knowing that a specific
kang objects refer to no id
is interesting now you could say i'm
going to do it offline
and i tried
now here's the thing if we take
interface that we all know
it seems like very simple
but
interface in snmp we know this admin
administrator superstatus if we come to
yang it depends because we could have
like
the interface young module which is pre
and mda with two different containers no
one container
we could have the young module
nmda which is one container
but different data stores
we could have the open conflict which is
yet a different one
we could have like a proprietary one so
there is not a single mapping but from
the router point of view
if you know you support one or two
then you just give the mapping for those
right
on the next slide
it's something similar to the
admin status and upper status right
how do you know that it's an mp
one is the intended and one is the
applied
because you know it right in yang we try
to solve that one
by adding different data stores but in
case you have like
non-open config or non nmda
you don't know that so there are things
you could be telling
that this one relates to that one this
is the id between the written notes over
there
so these are and i believe this is the
last one i want to show you
these are examples of the things we were
thinking about
at the same time that the rfc 9196 was
done
and initially in there there was one
that was unchanged just or no it was
moving to the other draft
now the question is and if you go to the
next slide please
oh by the way there is also
two rpcs to directly get the information
from the router before you configure
them
okay
and on the next slides
i'll skip the open issues because they
are
not so important for now but i want to
go to the last slide which is okay what
do we do now
we have this brand new rfc 9196
it does its job
right but do we have a need
do we still have a need for the new
object i mentioned here
if the answer is no because it's or not
now that's fine
if there are some use cases
well we work again on those
this is the status where i'm right now
with the quarters
so the floor is yours for
feedback so we could um uh try to do a
show of hands if that's what you're
interested to find out if there's
interest
feedback of
show fans or you know interesting
whatever you
okay there's a couple on the queue yeah
and maybe tim you want to go first
hello
yep hear you
good uh so
i will say uh meanwhile that um we have
seen in the past
uh similar uh problems that you're that
you're um
talking about with like the mibo id
uh but actually for other protocols as
well like for uh ipfix for example the
the ie number there
that would be assigned to the node so um
you know we do see some usefulness
for for those features to be able to
have the source
correlate it back with other
identifiers for other protocols
um but when you do that if you could if
we could somehow make that kind of a
list
uh and allow for you know um you know
the the identities
uh to be done for uh or for you know one
or more types of things you can do you
know ipfix or snmp or both right you
know where you're giving annoyed or or
the i can fix number
for for whatever purposes that the
system needs
very good thank you tim
uh for the iphic is slightly more
complex because there is semantic behind
it depending on your key field
definitions
uh so there is not always a one-to-one
mapping
i could go into more details later uh
it's slightly more complex or flows
than yeah but it's for the same
the same problem right that you're
trying to do in it exactly so i think we
if we can address that i know that
there's needs in the market for that
very good thank you
so before rob comes on there is a poll
out there right now for you to vote on
the answer is if you raise hand you're
saying showing interest in the work
if you're not raising your hand you have
either no interest or have no comment
oh on the online tool uh
is there an ability on the phone
yes i believe there is
okay go ahead rob
um
thanks very much it's very interesting
so i had one comment on the
on the idea of sort of a recommended
polling interval rather than a minimum i
definitely think that makes sense in in
the context that as you say
a minimum polling until doesn't always
make sense depending on the capacity and
things one of the things that even with
the recommended one is it might depend
on what other subscriptions you are at
the same time so if you've only got a
subscription against the variable the
fib then that might give you one
interval whereas if you're pulling
polling pulling off a lot of other data
at the same time then that will change
and i think that's one aspect that's
also related to like the adaptive
telemetry drafts the same issues how do
you
how do you advertise not just what you
can do at the extreme but what you can
do in a sort of more generalized sense
um i think that's an interesting problem
i don't know whether
the recommended one because that would
change dynamically is is what you want
or or whether you need something to be
able to say these are all the
subscriptions i'm interested in
tell me what you can do here and it's
interesting that what gmy does here is
they have an option of saying
um just do the best so it's just
whatever the server can provide
but again if more subscriptions come
along does that then it will then change
over time and how does the client adjust
to that or not so i think there's some
interesting here
interesting stuff
your other question is are you
interested in this now i've not i've not
put my hand up by the way i i don't know
there's some interesting aspects here
whether we would implement this at this
time i'm not sure but down the line i
think so
thank you rob good feedback so somehow
your mansion your whenever you mentioned
do your best this is
this is what we want to do right because
the router is left to route packets from
time to time so do your best is what we
want now we want to slightly formalize
this because if at an example of flows
you know ipfix you do sampling great
you're able to get your sampling rate
back to your flow collector so that you
could do your own computation
now in this world of adaptive where you
do your best
if you don't know
what the best is and it keeps changing
if you don't advertise this
to your data collection system
then you cannot reconcile information
easily if you speak about some data
that's fine because you could kind of
average that if we speak about
multiplying counters because you are
doing some sort of sampling
then we have a problem but this is this
is the idea do your best
based on what you could do
now and send me the information by the
way because i need to get the context
that will follow the data
all right
yeah this is charles but i'm channeling
a question from jurgen because we
weren't able to confirm with him
about asking it
but uh he just asked us the nodes tag
work and netmod
provide the means to obtain the metadata
do we really need a new rpc
do you want to take the mic
jorgen short answer i don't know yet
i'll look into that
all right thank you charles
and joe's in the queue next
you have a question joe
uh not a
joe clark cisco not a question uh
comment um
so i think i raised my virtual hand i
think it's interesting i'm kind of
curious and i can leave more details on
email
like
some of that you think the the what rob
said about the polling yes
the snmp oid i mean you and i know
useful
but
there's a lot of challenges there like
just knowing the oid alone doesn't
really help me i need to have the index
mapping and that's on a per instance i
just wonder if if
there's
it sounds useful is it going to be
doable enough to actually make
to to spend the time to do the work i
guess that's what i'm getting this kind
of rosetta stone would be amazing um
tim brought up another i just don't know
how practical it would all be
the very good point uh joe actually
i tend to agree with you because it's
whenever i will go in the details of
getting an index in the map or actually
multiple indices and then we've got like
a yang which has different indices and
it's going to be complex so this one was
put in there because we want i do want
to store that when we arrive i'm not
sure so maybe if if we have to do things
in step might be the right answer
i was trying to raise my hands and go to
the queue at the same time and it's not
well
yeah it's uh simply that i mean this is
the kind of feature that we have been uh
demanding quite often i'm talking among
us precisely because it would be
really helpful in precisely warrantying
uh
well i would not say comfortable but
reasonable path for migration and for
integrating different elements that
instead of using what we are using right
now that is the best guess or whatever
we get fall from uh
from experience or from interaction with
the uh
with the with the manufacturers this is
quite useful in the sense that you can
integrate this in a in a whole
life cycle of the of what you're doing
so
you have my my hands were my hand was
raised for for a long time so i
just uh so they were like go ahead take
the mic
sorry so because i want to to clarify so
there is like map or id
there is like a
proposed observation uh collection etc
so it's a race and for everything or you
have things that you need now and we
could do some later
in principle if you're asking me well is
it the letter to santa claus for
everything come on
no no
seriously no if we had to to experiment
with something personally i found i mean
from my experience not the the purely
operational language people for me but i
or the oid will be probably more
interested the one about the related
note is something that interests me
personally more but i would say that the
that the migration pass
probably will be the most interesting
for the real uh the people that are
running the real networks
thank you
we do have one more question but just to
let everyone know we
i ended the poll and we had 29
participants with 24 saying they had
some interest
um
and we have balaz in the queue
go ahead bolas
actually just quickly before blood
starts speaking uh that was uh diego
lopez who was at the mic just last time
he didn't introduce himself
yeah
go ahead blush
let's make sure you unmute your
mic do you hear me
yes
okay so besides oh ids and ipfix
references
we also deal with three gpp management
systems using distinguished names so
that could be another reference that
would be very good to map to yank
sometimes
thank you
very good thank you
all right uh for those who did comment
uh
go ahead to the notes
page and do add your comments for binva
please
all right next presentation will be the
um transaction id jan lim blood
let me get the slides cued up
and
yawn i'm going to make you the
controller so left right mouse button
should do it for you go ahead thank you
so this is a
update what's going on with the
transaction id that some of you may have
followed earlier
so i wanted to go
do a quick problem and solution recap
and then talk about the simulated
results that we have since earlier
and then mentioned a few words about
what's in the works right now
so
this work is trying to address three
problems
one is the get config
it's a slow and costly operation
and if you want to use it for change
detection on the server if it's clients
wants to know if the server has changed
this is
an expensive way to do that
so you do get config and you get a
response and then you do get complete
clear and check get a response
and see if it looks the same
but it's consuming both the cpu on both
sides and a lot of network bandwidth
to find out that nothing happened
uh the second problem is with jan kush
so if a
client is subscribing
to updates on some parts of the server
configuration
and then getting
updates after that
when something happens in the server
that's of course great but what happens
is that if the client is configuring the
server
he will get updates about his own change
as well
and it kind of
unnecessary and it takes a lot of
computations to figure out oh actually
this i i already knew this because i
said it
so if there was a way to identify those
updates as being what you already know
that would be good
and the third thing uh
well
actually more more than cpu consumption
and the network bandwidth consumption a
problem is uh that's important for in
many cases is that we want to detect
when
multiple clients are making changes uh
at the same time and to the same server
so that if they are clobbering each
other they would want to know
and the the current method of using get
config is
both costly and
it has a hole right you can do a get
config but before you are able to send
the edit config that follows to make
your change there's a window of
vulnerability if somebody else is doing
an edit config
in that window you would still be
clobbering
uh you can of course take the lock but
since getconfig can take several minutes
you don't want to take locks that are so
so prolonged
so a lot of people have talked about
yeah let's introduce a sort of
simplistic top level transaction id
where
every server keeps track of for example
the timestamp when it was last changed
or some sort of global number at the top
that reflects the contents so that i
didn't get confident you can ask what's
your transaction id and when you get the
content forget config you'll also get
that number like 4 7 11.
many servers have implemented this
already but not in a standard way but in
each vendor in a proprietary way
and then that could reduce the amount of
traffic in cpu considerably
for some use cases
but
what we have found is that
many of the use cases that are
interesting are not like that
you would actually have more
applications more clients that are
interested in certain subparts of the
configuration of servers
let's say we have a vpn client a
security client and an underlay client
that that care mostly about different
parts of the config of the server
and if you all you get is this top level
e tag number 471 there and the changes
these clients they don't know
if something that affects them or they
care about has changed or not
and in many cases that e-tag number is
changing so frequently because of
changes that are going on on this device
that there's no point in trying to track
that at all so we have found that many
of our customers
are turning off that feature even for
the devices that support this top level
thing
so that's why we think a transaction id
or e-tag mechanism that goes deeper into
the tree is very valuable so that you
can synchronize
the part of the configuration or track
changes to the partial configuration
that your that you actually care about
and the draft is also talking about the
edit conflict mechanism is lock free and
uh detects clobbering without any sort
of
vulnerable window vulnerability windows
so this is something that you might have
already known because we talked about it
before is nothing new here but just to
remind you what we are talking about
here
in order to measure what we what this
draft would give you
we did a measurement on a real world
application that was running in one of
our labs for an hour
uh and this application was then doing a
lot of management of devices in the
network
and it was
doing 569 round trips
that means get configs and edit configs
and all sorts of
messages that they were sending
to the server
and
it was sending about one megabyte of net
conf
traffic
during that time
but if we implemented the sort of
mechanism that we talked about in this
draft
those 569 would go down to 378 round
trips so about one third would be
gone and that of course removes both
network load and delay in applications
because round trips take a lot of time
and uh reducing the amount of traffic
from one megabyte to just a little more
than a half megabyte
which again reduces network load and
processing time on both sides
and this is now then a mechanism that
doesn't require any sort of locking
and it removes this
window of vulnerability
so if you think this is interesting we
can continue working on this together to
look at how we implement things and
there are a few open questions in this
work
the thing that we are looking at right
now is to
add text for
how yang push should integrate into this
it's uh something that is not mentioned
in the current dash one version at all
and we are looking at
in-house
doing prototype implementations of this
just to verify this with a broader class
of use cases than this
simulation that we did
that's all i had to say any comments or
questions
uh yeah did you want a poll to see if
there was interest in the work
that could be a good idea yeah
if you can arrange that please
before the poll maybe some questions
at least i have a question
um yeah go ahead and set up the poll
okay great
um jan so um i i'm highly supportive of
this work but first can you just clarify
you didn't use the word rest conf in
your presentation but this by and large
in my mind
is uh enabling that conf to have feature
parody with rescue
at least in terms of uh the e-tag and
maybe also the modification time on a uh
you know within the tree uh deep in the
tree um is it is that a fair
characterization it's a as a effectively
enabling that contact feature parity to
rest conf in that regard
yes and then if you read the the draft
you will actually see rest confirmation
in there and exactly how it would work
and it is i would definitely say it's
feature parody but it also goes beyond
that
yeah and that's that's that's uh going
beyond is also applicable to rest conf
okay and then my second question is on
your first bullet point in this slide
you talk about integration to yang push
it doesn't even occur to me what can you
just say a few words more about what is
the nature of that integration that
might be needed
yeah i mean we have this
let's see i can actually go back here
in the slides
you know i have this pole in front of me
so i can't really see the slide very
well but okay so when you subscribe to
uh configuration updates using young
push for a part of the tree that you're
interested in
whatever you the client itself is
pushing to that part of the tree will be
echoed back to him
but it's uh difficult to understand if
this is another update from some other
transaction that happened on this server
or if it is my own thing
since there's there's no way of knowing
you have to actually parse this whole
thing and say yeah actually it matches
exactly what they already had so
yeah this may be an echo of your problem
number one i forget if it was or not but
you mentioned uh the server getting back
a notification for something that it had
already
it knows it did it so why would it need
to get a notification for it um and as
you were saying that i was thinking to
myself that maybe it's not so bad i mean
if
if if the
bandwidth and you know processing isn't
huge
it's still probably valuable to have a
record of the thing having occurred and
so in that regard i probably would say
it's not a big deal so if it's the same
issue then maybe it's not a big deal
i think that actually if you look
into how we could do this with the
transaction id you could do exactly that
but much more efficient than getting the
full data back and
having to process it and compare and all
that so getting the the update is great
but if you have the young push
mechanism integrated with transaction
ids
you could do that
okay thank you that was just
that was and again this is kent as a
contributor thank you
that's it for me
okay i think those numbers are quite
impressive
yes so
um
oh i see them now okay
so we had 23 who participated and 22
said they would see the work interesting
very good
so i think we can move into an adoption
call shortly
excellent thank you
any other comments or questions
we have none in the queue
thank you
changing the order just a little bit so
next is going to be
jamming
as i understand it this draft actually
pretend presents the use cases for the
adaptive subscription uh presentation
which is after this one is xiaomi here
who's presenting this
should be xiaomi
okay
i don't see so marky fog do you think
you could present on behalf of
germany
i think i can't represent him to present
this work
yes or no
no sorry i can't really represent them
okay fine
um all right well then
i guess we'll just skip this
presentation if he's no one's here to
present it
so
we will
kill these fines
i shouldn't use that word
but bring out the next slice adaptive
subscription
uh yeah i think i can drive this slide
okay i'll pass the control to you
as soon as they come up
okay there you go thank you
thanks
so uh
[Music]
okay
on behalf the authors and contributors i
would like to give a presentation about
the adaptive subscription to young
notification
so
for people who are not familiar with
this work um usually a high frequency
debt collection leads to more resource
consumption while low frequency debt
collection is insufficient for
for photo nuclear neglection and people
sometimes may find it hard to
balance the need between expensive data
management cost and better fidelity for
troubleshooting so
this is exactly what we want to do and
our main idea
is to install the adaptive subscription
policy which is built on top of young
push mechanism
and allow the servers to switch to
different update intervals based on the
network condition chains
so about the document status
this work was first proposed about two
years ago
and we have received a lot of comments
over the past two years
about two months ago
the working group adoption call was
initiated and we have received different
opinions i think
we got a lot of support and also
received concerns and objections from
andy and the poor and some of the
objections about the problem statement
while others is about the evaluation of
the x-path expression
like the usage of the watermark
evaluation of expat external evaluation
etc so
the authors investigate these concerns
very carefully and update the draft
accordingly which includes the the
following chance like we have defined
new rpc errors
in last itf meeting i think it's rob rob
has suggested us to define a new rpc
error to report when a server cannot
pass the expat syntax defined in the
x-pass evaluation expression which is
more complicated than it can handle
and andy asked us what if multiple
expats criteria conflict so we have
defined three rpc errors so far to show
adaptive subscription unsupported
and exposed syntax defined in the x-pass
external evaluation unsupported
and the multiple expat criteria conflict
respectively
and we admit that the watermark leaf
defined in the module is confusing
so we have removed this parameter and
there are also some other questions
asked by andy like how to evaluate the
x-path expression
how to compare a targeted data object in
a specific list entry
uh how often does the server checks if
the period should change
clarifications
in the updated draft has been met and i
will also
explain some of the later in my slide
and another progress we have met is that
we have proposed a hacksaw project in
this itf meeting to provide some
implementation results
we monitor the kpi chains at different
frequencies of data collection
and also evaluated the performance of
adaptive subscription
so i i will introduce the hacksaw
project
briefly and then clarify the open issues
so this is about the our exome text
environment setup we use the grpc-based
telemetry to collect data from
different access points the network
devices in our campus
and we have evaluated the following
different data collection methods
a high frequency periodic telemetry a
low from quickly periodic telemetry and
an adaptive frequency telemetry
and for each debt collection method two
cases are evaluated one is to report the
rssi values so as to detect the real
time
whether roaming events across different
aps and the other is to stream the bytes
sent from the ap uplink so as to detect
the
potential congestion
and we also use the elk to collect
analyze filter and visualize the data
so in in this case
uh we tried to
we have
collected and aggregated the rssi signal
data from
different aps and the usually the issi
is a measurement of how well the
terminal devices
can receive a signal from an ap or a
router
so
usually the default roaming rssi thread
hold is the negative 65 and if the
actual signal stress is length is less
than the threshold the then the terminal
devices will search another ap to
attempt roaming
so in this case we try to figure out
when a with a roaming event happens
during the movement of the terminal
devices
and also identify
try to identify continuous signal
degeneration
so we tried different methods to collect
the same metric and the results show
that
a very high frequency debt collection at
a two second interval is easy to
identify when a roaming event happens
and
signal degeneration but
also
but it also at the cost app
at the cost of a greater volume of data
and
unsurprisingly a low frequency
collection at the 13 second interval can
greatly reduce the data volume but it's
hard to detect the important events and
data
and we also tried adaptive subscription
which is on the
right side of the slide
if the rssi value is less than the
negative 65 we set the period to be
every 2 seconds otherwise switch to 13
seconds at the interval
so since the condition can also be
evaluated at the subscriber side the
subscriber evaluated the received rssi
value and manage the decision whether it
needs to modify the period so
while our proposal is to configure the
adaptive policy into the server and
allow the server to switch to different
intervals automatically so we have
compared these two different ways and
the results show that for the first way
for the condition evaluated by the
subscriber
uh the low frequency at a 30-second
interval that collection prevents the
subscriber from capturing roaming events
which lasts only two to four seconds
because the subscriber can only use the
data collected every 13 seconds as the
input of the condition evaluation and it
will realize to
increase the frequency only when it
happens to receive or as
as i value which is less than the
threshold but for the the second
adaptive way
the server will evaluate the condition
at the end of each high frequency
interval which is two seconds in this
case so it will check whether it needs
to switch to another frequency every two
seconds even it's during the low
frequency streaming now
so any there is no no important events
and the data will be missed in our
proposed way
another case we have tried is to stream
the bytes sent from the ap uplink so as
to detect the possible uplink congestion
and similarly adaptive frequency debt
collection is able to
capture as many traffic but as possible
while when the monitored operational
data is normal the frequency can also be
decreased
the
the light charge at the bottom right
side of the slide we can see that the
adaptive subscription can greatly reduce
the amount of transmitted data compared
with high frequency debt collection
so this is about the the hacksaw
projects
and regarding the issues clarification i
i think that the very first one is that
young push supports the adaptive
subscription already
yes i think it's true it's true that the
subscriber can monitor the targeted that
object change and modify the period for
an existing subscription
but we think that it takes time and
resources for the subscriber to to
analyze the network status and send the
modification request
and it also takes time and resources for
the server to receive the modification
and react to it
and sending modification requests to
switch to from the low frequency to half
increases streaming cannot capture all
important events and data due to
the low frequency debt collection
interval as i showed in the rssi signal
use case
use case with when it is low in low
frequency debt collection the subscriber
can only use the that collected every 13
seconds as the basis
input for the condition evaluation and
such a time interval is very likely to
cause the loss of important data
and also the third point is that when
tens of thousands network devices need
need to be managed the frequent frequent
modifications are prone to errors
then people may ask about
uh how about the proposed server driven
method how often does the server check
if the period should change
um
i think it sounds more like an
implementation decision because the more
from the condition evaluations are
performed the faster the server can
react to the network condition change
but it's recommended that
it's recommended to be at the end of
each high frequency streaming update
period
and which means that the data is
reported at a high frequency only when
the network suffers but the server
should periodically detect the condition
change at this high frequency even its
reporting data to the collector in a low
low frequency currently
and this to reduce the frequency of the
evaluation the server can also choose to
check the targeted object change at
every multiple update periods
so that's also fine i think
okay then
it's about the
and another issue is about the
expat instance information
um yes it's it
we think that the the question how to
select no more than when entry if there
are this instance to handle
we think that xpath itself can be used
to identify a particular instance
and it's true that there may be a desire
to select an object inside a list
and but the the expats itself
supposed to identify a particular
instance inside a list already which is
defined as a abbreviated syntax in xpath
1.0 w3c specification so we don't really
think this is a problem
and the last issue is still about the
expat capability
the problem statement seems to be
limited to
absolute values of specific leaf or leaf
list and usually at least a rate is
needed
well in maybe in itf 111 i can't really
really remember it but maybe there is
there used to be a concern about
arbitrary expat complexity so we think
in order to reduce the complexity we
have recommended
the implementers to use the comparison
of the specific that object value and
the threshold but for the server with
more powerful capabilities to handle a
complex express syntax we think that
it's okay to use the mathematic
operations in the expression
so it
so i think the x partition text supports
it to
use a red
we did not really limit that
capability but our current focus on the
smart field cases
which means like the monitor data object
exists a specific threshold it this is
the recommended way but we do not really
limit that capability
okay so
any comments and
questions about this
yeah go ahead adopt
uh robinson's cisco uh speak as a
contributor and i should have say that
when i was responding to benoit as well
speak as a contributor so i i still have
concerns about the sort of complexity
that we're pushing
onto the devices to do this sort of
continuous monitoring
and the xpath evaluation um it just
feels to me like it's a very
computationally expensive solution to
this problem so i think one of the
things that i'd be interested in and
maybe the other presentation on the sort
of use cases if that's related to this
might be interesting is is
how many cases do we actually have of
solving this generically are there a few
point cases that we're trying to solve
and would it be better to build
solutions and concrete data models to
solve those particular cases rather than
building a generic infrastructure here
so
i guess what i'm saying is i don't know
exactly what you were monitoring there
in terms of your your site but could you
build a data model that does that
sampling at a high rate and
build up either aggregated statistics or
something with a decay
and then you can monitor that a high
frequency and then and leave it at the
server to respond so i still have
questions as to what data you're trying
to capture do you actually need all this
data at a high rate or are you just
trying to pick out when
these particular events are occurring
more generally
and and hence if you had a summarized
value in the data model that might might
give you the same solution with far less
complexity
that's my comments
okay well for your your first question
um
i think i have the slide to
yeah for the adaptive subscription the
condition can evaluated at the
subscriber side and also at the server
side and
if we
want to leave the complexity with the
subscriber then we
it's maybe we have some issues to
collect the
enough data to
identify the important events and and
data and
and for the the second where the
adaptive subscription evaluated the
condition at the server side we can
collect enough data but
yes we did
add some complexity to the server we
don't really have a
uh
performance statistics about the network
devices load to implement this adaptive
subscription but the results show that
it seems okay because it the server only
adds some
some if then
logical programming codes on the
adaptive subscription and there don't
really have so much load than we
expected and also
about the
the stream data in this case with the
evaluation data is the issi signal data
which is defined as a leaf better node
in our
the module in the draft appendix section
so the rssi is the the stream data and
and it's also the evaluated data so this
is
the the filtered about the
these and i i think that for adaptive
subscription uh the rssi signal data
streaming to identify the terminal
devices roaming events maybe is the most
uh
solid use case for
for for for this draft and i also know
that there is another draft
of a dedicated discussion about the use
case and the problem statement about
adaptive subscription but i
uh we can we we can see that uh
uh um i i think that it seems more like
to focus on the
data collection
the traffic debt collection but our
focus is about the the young push
mechanism which is to stream data from a
particular young data store
so but we can see that whether the use
cases dropped can fit in
some use cases in this in this one we
can see that
so so just to
to concrete examples i could think of is
for like interface
statistics um often
i don't know the idf yangon has this
don't think it does but other ones um
other vendors have this is you have like
a rate calculation that's telling you
what the current load is on that
interface and that decays over time so
it's giving you sort of a point
load value and you could potentially
sample that a reasonable frequency and
an another case i can think of um is to
do with like interface flaps if you
monitor the the link layer flaps at the
very low
hardware layers you may be getting
thousands of interrupts per second
coming through but you don't want to
notify all of those
instead you could notify a counter of
how many flaps have occurred each point
of time so you can still you can still
spot
when these flaps are occurring and you
can still spot it occurring at high
frequency or not but you don't
necessarily have to notify every single
flap that occurs so you're reducing the
amount of data you're pushing off the
device
okay thank you i i i will look into that
and
and try to give some more implementation
results about their mission the use
cases
thank you
yeah
okay if there are no other comments um
suddenly there is interest in
the
use case draft i think we would have
really liked to hear that today but
um
considering the author is not here to
talk about it
one other way that uh
actually
i'm sorry
um i did receive a private chat message
from xinwu who says that
the presenter xiaomin will be
presenting or joining
shortly to present
imminently i'm hoping
so this may still happen
um
so
in the meantime you want to go ahead and
propose
a poll on
okay shin says he's online
no i want to hold off and doing the poll
until after we have this other
presentation if possible because it may
it may answer some questions
um but i don't see shin
yet
i'm probably saying the wrong
shout i'm saying
hello
yeah can you hear me
i hear you jim
yeah this is
actually i do see uh
online and i did talk with him and he
will present
is he in the neck of
okay i'm gonna cancel this presentation
and bring up the next presentation then
xiaomi can you queue up to be a speaker
you have to raise your hand
all right charming uh
if you see your name on the top okay
you see that
yes okay
hello yes hi we hear you
i'm gonna oh
i'm going to pass control slide control
to you you can increment uh the slides
between the red or left right mouse
buttons
okay
let me uh let me introduce
this
draft problem statement and the use
cases of adaptive traffic that con
collections
next one list
you should be able to hit your right
mouse button or right keyboard button
and increment it
okay please please turn to
the left kg
okay i'm going to take back slide
control and just tell me when you need
to have the slides incremented
sorry about that
okay next slide go ahead
oh okay okay
motivation and objective
motivation
idea career network can lead to
providing real-time traffic visibility
to have network upgrades
quickly and
accurately look at the network
congestion and packed loss
make timeline pass adjustment for
deterministic services to avoid
congestion
as this trendstyle assembly
i mean second intervals will generate
generate a constant variable amount of
data which might claim too much
transport by the way's resource
will be load the service for get
collection storage knowledge and lab
release
objective
explore the adaptive traffic
data collection mechanism so as to
capture real-time network state at
meaning minimal resource consumption
please
next page
okay
problem statement
if network use of
traffic-based calculators tickets after
a long time
operates have obtained obtained traffic
vicinity from ms
which cannot reflect this kind of base
calculations
first to observe it observing the
evolution network traffic
my excuse the calculator's tickets are
for traffic based game direct smt is
widely employed to collect
network traffic at five minutes
intervals
second in spite of low
links usage such as setting
to 14 percent final base utilization
mailing
billing time plans have still been
received about four k in delivery
application based the sense same
sensitivity
of the delay and the pipeline loss
large quality of laboratory data and
evolutionary object medicare diet and
microbes but belong below lab because
frequently he operates calorie little
workers such as ip brain
antimatter measuring quality little work
actually backbone little work and
in the
data centers
families of television television
indicates we can capture their company
that's packets of macrophage traffic
however
it is an impractical to gain
the real-time traffic visibility at cost
of persisting this time same thing at
milliseconds in the wales
please the next page
scenarios of effective traffic that
use case one
dimensional real-time portrait of
interface traffic characteristics
real-time traffic visibility can help
operate but understand
network performance so as to achieve sla
guarantees for latest and low and lost
in
sensitive sensitive applications
i'm telling the hardship and genuine
characteristics of interface traffic is
also a basic requirement for the
statistical multiplexing model of iit
network which is of great significance
for traffic prediction network planning
to work habit
capacity expansion and the network
optimization and so on
it is essential to expand the
adaptive traffic data collection
techniques to depict
not
multi
dimensional real-time portrait of
interface
traffic categoristic is at a
minimum resource consumption
next page please
this gets to
make the best traffic
detectors not the best traffic as a
intense
instantaneous congestion phenomena
occurring like united kingdom network
will cause political
detention and impact laws which will
stimulate the effect accurately of late
transcendent lost sentence applications
the ability of detecting market-based
traffic of inter interface where network
operates quickly and equally equitably
located network
tangency and the factory loss and make
timely has adjustment for for
deterministic delay services in order to
avoid the congested load and links
triggered by the events such as packet
loss
cure depends beyond the
threshold which is the detective
families assembly sector must be
timing turning to milliseconds to
capture a magnifier of interface
the next page please
use cases please congestion event
for deterministic and domestic services
the real-time check visibility is based
on the adaptive traffic that collection
techniques can accurately predict the
time congestion and quickly have shared
their
instantaneous congestion
of inter interface
and millions of delivery time traffic
visibility the automatic
of optimization tool brings up your ai
can make timely path adjustment for case
type flows
the next page please
this case four
parts can imagine based on adaptive
traffic assemblies
adaptive approach can be used based on
the network condition to analytically
adjust the sampling threat
in low mail network stated a low
sampling rate is enough to develop
reflect network performance in case of
network congestion family just practiced
something related at a very high level
so as soon as to
acquire real-time measurement data such
as latency data and packet loss
the next page please
next steps
solid state conveys and refine the draft
accordingly
population will overcome
possible implementation and verification
as well thank you thank you
does anybody have comments questions
sorry
no i was saying the same thing that's
perfect
yes benoit please
so vanuatu please so thank you for
coming to the itf to express your
problems now something
so when i read the slide it seems it's
mainly about data plane monitoring
right and about and sometimes i mean it
would be
easier for me to know if we speak about
data plane and then like in ban oem like
what you described in the last use case
or if you speak about flows if you speak
about something else as opposed to you
know
uh just telemetry
periodic updates this is where
the use case should be likely more
structured i believe
all right thank you um i don't believe
there are any other comments
so just uh so we did have to take these
last two presentations out of order
the idea was that this presentation was
going to provide the use cases
that would help
justify the potential adoption of the
adaptive subscription draft which was
the the previous presentation
um
but now that we have
had this presentation i know
uh so it required i know there were some
objections that were raised previously
on list
by andy and also per
with regards to
[Music]
concerns with the adapter's description
draft
and andy's not online i don't know
i think i see her if um
if the use case or other um oh jan is
joining the queue perfect
go ahead and john
yes jan please go ahead
make sure
uh yeah perry is not able to speak at
this moment but we are working together
so
i think it's perhaps better to discuss
the details on the list if it's possible
but
i think many of the
concerns we have are still still
relevant
okay
all right thank you uh so i do want to
put a show of hands
pull
to the working group
it's on screen now
okay i think we've gotten i don't see
any new oh there's one more participant
all right i'm gonna
end the poll now because it's
pretty pretty much good enough um
so we did we we just got 24
participants in that
poll um
it's about half half in terms of whether
or not the working group should
you know continue um looking at adopting
this as a proposed standard versus um
an experimental message
uh sorry experimental um draft
and uh so so again this is not an
adoption call on either on either front
but uh it looks like we'll hold the door
open uh longer for the possibility of it
being proposed standard i think as jan
just mentioned
more discussion on list needs to occur
to try to resolve the concerns of those
that have raised them
and
i think that's it for for that
presentation
so thank you very much everyone
and also i believe that's the end of the
meeting
we're at the end of our agenda now
yes with three minutes to spare
all right anyway
thanks everyone
yes thank you everyone for joining the
necron uh 113 session
wish i could be there in person
see you in philadelphia right
that is correct
okay
yes
um
i think