today
i think we can get started
sound good francesca
okay cool
well hi everyone welcome to the ohio
session at
ietf113
i'm siobhan and i'm joined by richard
bronze and francesca is our eyes and
ears on the ground thank you for that
um
and we are still looking for a note
taker
so if anyone
would be willing to volunteer that would
be fantastic
anyone anyone
face for the link
i think yeah i think richard also said
that you can keep an eye on the minutes
as well
so worst case we could do that but it
would be really nice if someone could
just volunteer
fantastic thank you
so we have a note taker um
yeah and if you have anything
that
um you would like to
say the mic just prepend that with mike
and you can
get that sorted out
this is the itf note well please go
through this
whether it's your first idf meeting or
your 113th it's always good to refresh
your memory
um iatf 113 is
hybrid so if you're in person please
please make sure to sign into the
session using
meet echo online tool
um and please please use
uh we are going to join the queue um
it is important for queueing and all
queueing is done through medico
um all right i think
we can get started we uh we do have
quite a bit of time um so i'm hoping we
can get some good discussion on
and
first up
we'll have martin and then
there will be
um
some discussion about issues and updates
since last meeting and then we have two
brand new drafts
being presented by tommy and hero
so if martin i think you have some sites
mine's coming up
perfect
i think i have to
let's see how this works
i'm going to do the uh hall of mirrors
thing for a moment
because i'm going to be jumping in to
uh yes i want to share my screen that's
the crazy
crazy thing
uh yeah
okay all the mirrors
and now slides
so
um this is
uh
just a brief update on what we're doing
and i'm going to go through some of the
issues here that we've got
um
since the last meeting there have been a
few issues raised in the last hour or so
obviously i won't
go into those ones but
i will hopefully get through all of the
important things that we identified
this is every open issue that existed as
of a week ago
so
option
one
changes in version one uh we've moved
the padding to the binary messages draft
that
is something that i think simplifies the
overall design uh and it makes the
binary messages stuff more useful
generally
we've also made uh changes to the the
labels that we're using for generating
to
extend the exports
those are now um based on the the
content type of the um
of the the content that's enclosed
and there's some text about repurposing
the design that we have here for other
purposes
not that this is a primary goal for us
but it's something that makes a little
bit easier for us to manage
there's some new text on resource
mappings
i think one of our new issues is about
that
and some draft texts on anti-replay that
i'll go through as part of the issues
here
so the first one
of the issues that we're talking about
is
what information the proxy is able to
provide to it to a server when it um
relays messages obviously we want the
proxy to hide a lot of information about
what the client is
who they are and where their requests
are coming from
but there are certain use cases where
um
it might be useful perhaps to have a
proxy
um
provides just a tiny amount of
information
at the moment we're considering one bit
that would allow
proxies to to do shadow banning for
instance that is
identify abusive clients
and allow the request to pass and appear
to be handled correctly but give the
server
a sort of side channel signal that says
hey this this guy's probably a bad actor
you might
want to
de-prioritize or or
respond in a different fashion
there's a pull request uh
we're discussing that i
don't know if we want to talk about that
one just
just now
it's kind of in flight right right now
there's a number of comments
so um
i will
probably
just stick to this uh
one here are there any comments about
this one i'm going to bring this off
full screen
where did you want to go
it's just waiting to be to be called on
um
yeah so i guess
i think my take on this is that actually
like this entire restriction is kind of
misguided um
and
that
there's a number of things that you
might want the proxy to say um um one
one of them is this bit as you indicate
um one of them um i've heard floated is
a um a token of some kind indicating um
you know um
uh you know that there's been some sort
of dial service reputation kind of stuff
on it um you know one thing i've heard
of is geo is rough geo um i certainly
heard suggestions of you know um
of short term uh short term linkages for
um for
ip address you know this is the same
person over or cover a couple of a
couple less messages
um yeah i'm not like a huge fan of these
but i guess my my thermal thesis is
these are all out of scope for this
protocol and that we should simply not
say anything about what you should say
and
um and and leave that to applications um
fundamentally that's i don't know
exactly what what messages are what what
crap is conveyed in that metadata is
really
like for
um
the uh the client and the um the client
in the proxy to like work out for
themselves um
so um and i understand like certainly
like you know that that allows you to
bypass any possible protections being
offered here but like but like you know
this is just like this is like this is
like a 6919
don't do it so i just think it's like
rather than trying to like put that in
the number of language we should like
talk about what um
um
well uh
nick asks we don't know it's being out
of them yeah the point the point is that
like the point is that there would be an
understood policy of what of what the
proxy was doing and not doing and the
user be aware of that at the point they
chose it just entered we're still aware
of anything issues anything here right
um
um i mean like you know the proxy and
the process can just be side channeling
all the information to the server for
once right and so the only question here
is like um um
so i think you know your fundamental
trust in the process
yeah so that speaks to to potentially
saying
um as long as the the
potential uh
range of things that a proxy could
communicate to a server is is known to
the client then the client can use that
as part of this decision to use a proxy
that's what i just said that's my name
and in general maybe we could just make
some have some waffley words about
you know don't include too much
uh chris
yeah yeah i think that's what the the
text in 96 tries to do right now in
particular tries to say that any of this
of this public metadata that the client
and proxy agree upon
uh
as being revealed during the course of
using this proxy
um
is known to the client uh whereas in
contrast what i call private metadata
like this this shadow banning bit where
the client does not necessarily agree to
the presence of that metadata
um that must be strictly bounded the
proxy just shouldn't
add things to the you know client
forward of requests without the client
being aware of it
so the sort of intent here uh in my
mental model has been that the
any sort of public metadata is agreed
upon between client proxy
and and factored into the decision to
use a particular proxy or not
um and private metadata must be uh
strictly bounded it is sort of like a
you know
a must but we know you won't in a way uh
um
but at the end of the day you kind of
have to trust the proxy to to not do
bad things like forward your ip address
or whatever so i i'm not i'm not too
concerned with the language there but
that's the tent that's my mental model
so i think that aligns with ecker as
well so so chris i want to pull on
something there a little bit there's
there's two things that we're sort of
conflating perhaps one is the
uh spectrum of possible things that the
proxy might say so the type of
information that it might pass to a
server and the other is the specific
values
that those types take
now are you suggesting that most things
fit in the you know the precise value
that's being communicated
or
um it is that
just all of them just you know the type
of the thing that's being communicated
about you
um
can you repeat it one more time i'm i'm
sorry i just spoke so so
understandable um so in the shadow
banning case the client might know that
the so that the proxy might pass a bit
along but it won't know the value of
that bit
yeah
in the geocache
do we expect that the client will know
the precise value of a geolocation
that's being provided along
or
it will just know that geolocation of a
certain type
yeah my uh thank you
my my um
my thing is that the client does not
necessarily know the precise value it
will just know that the value is being
communicated
um faithfully by the proxy um
like it would be the right geo mapping
or whatever it would compute the right
token it would send the right bit
um but the client is explicitly made
aware of it
yeah i
i do wonder whether some of these
examples can be made to work i mean
geolocation is pretty dangerous to do
these sorts of things with so yeah i
think there's a lot of sharp edges
within that any more metadata you're
adding that's why like with the 96 pr in
particular
um i tried to
punt any anything more than a single bit
to a separate you know discussion down
the road
um
uh
and
because to your point uh any any any
more information you're adding is uh
it's a slippery slope so to speak
okay thank you
hi tell me
all right hello
um so i agree with ecker that it's
difficult or impossible to try to make
this
normative
maybe one thing we could do is have a
normative statement about
future standardization of protocols
between a proxy and a target of saying
like
we really shouldn't approve things that
give away you know lots of information
but otherwise we can't really enforce
this
and to echo what people have been saying
i think this really comes down to how
much the client trusts the proxy
and the like the implicit thing whenever
we're using oblivious proxy is
that trust relationship and so anytime
we try to talk about
untrusted proxies or proxies doing
things that the client don't doesn't
want
we're kind of missing the entire
deployment model
um
and
i think even for the shadow banning case
like i could as a client
once i learned that a proxy
does shadow banning bits i could choose
not to use it and say i don't trust you
anymore because i don't want that in my
contract so i don't know if the shadow
banning is really
unique or if it's just one more thing
the client could
decide not to trust you about
yeah i i think the the the general shape
of the things that chris has described
is is what we're aiming for i'm not sure
that we're there yet on the pull request
but this is good input
shivan
yeah i think um i kind of mentioned
something similar on the pull request
but yeah i kind of agree i think that
um well i think that we should just keep
it to be assured and you can describe
the many ways in which this can go
really badly and like why a proxy
shouldn't just add you know
everything under the sun
and it communicates with the server but
i think applications will have
things that they want to do
um
so there's i don't know if there's much
point being like
this is the exact amount of amount of
information that
should be uh given out
david david kanasi privacy proxy
enthusiast um hey martin i want to
really echo what folks before i've been
saying like
this must is completely unenforceable
and we will probably have uses for this
later which all we'll have to do is by
the way that must just ignore it in that
previous document
so
having some text about well
duh don't put the name of the user in
there uh sounds i would have should
sounds good
and some like implementation guidance
says we have more implementations is
good but i wouldn't i would prefer no no
must
i'm suggesting that at this point
perhaps it's time to um
to to go back to the the the
separate work on the poor request and
maybe we can try to like
um go back
um and like rather than try to like i
think i'm generally like
obviously when i'm generally hearing of
course if people agree with me but
what i think they think agreement is
like that we should try to talk about
the positive
the space here and like give some
guidance but not actually tell people to
do anything and then we can work out
the exact importance of the thing around
that later offline
this is also my issue 100 so i think
this is like clearly this is clearly
like a hot issue in this document
yeah this is one of the more difficult
ones uh we will take this to the pull
request i have probably one final point
here
in and that is that um some of the
things that people are requesting here
are probably generic http features that
don't exist currently and
they might be something that uh we would
would benefit from
standardization with and so if we we
took those things to say the http
working group we could define new header
fields for say the shadow band bit or
no i'm not i'm not going to say that
we're going to do the geolocation thing
but um
other things
those lines
okay so i'm going to move to the next
one
this one's a little more technically
complicated so um
i think a number of people have pointed
out that
this isn't particularly good at carrying
all of the different http semantics
at the moment uh we sort of have a an
atomic request and an atomic response
and if we want to do things like have
large request bodies or large response
bodies that stream and are processed in
a streaming fashion
it's not very well set up for doing that
in fact it would be a very bad idea to
use the current thing for doing uh
very large requests that are processed
incrementally
and it also means that we can't do
things like encapsulate
uh 1xx responses
um
which is a little bit awkward so um i
have a slide uh ben if you have a
question
i might answer it as we're coming up so
jump in if i'm
so um this is just a sketch of a design
i'm part the way through writing this up
it turns out that writing this up is
awkward and time consuming so
the couple of hours i've had to spend on
this has not been enough
to do it cleanly but the basic idea is
that rather than having a single aad
invocation either via hpke or just
directly itself
we invoke it multiple times
and send the message in chunks
so this is easy for hpke because it
maintains its internal counter uh for
the aead we need to maintain a counter
in a nods
and which we can follow the pattern that
we have in tls for that sort of thing
for each chunk we can prefix each of
them with a length
which if we use say for instance the
quick variant encoding it
might cost one extra byte if you send a
single chunk
and then the only other consideration
here is that we need something to seal
off the end of the message so when you
have a series of chunks you need to know
that the chunk that you're processing is
the very last one otherwise you're
exposed to potential truncation attacks
so
use something to distinguish the last
chunk and if there's any number of
things that you can use the the simplest
thing
in in many respects is is just use a
zero length for the last one
because then you have a distinguishing
thing and you ensure that the um
ensure that it's uh
you rely on the the outer encapsulation
to to manage the length of the remaining
things
uh richard's going to complain about
that probably um
and that's all i have so comments folks
hi
ben schwartz
i
first wanted to ask
can you just confirm that i understand
correctly that
the proxy already can stream requests
and responses
yes the proxy can stream everything it
receives it's the it's the client and
the server on either end of the
hpk thing
okay
yeah so that doesn't seem as important
to me um i understand the
the interest here
but i would
uh i would ideally prefer for this to go
in a separate document possibly as an
extension to hpke or you know as
essentially an addendum to hpke because
this is a very general purpose
thing that you're describing here has
really very little to do with
uh http
it seems like it seems like an expansion
of hpke itself
i'd love to hear what richard has to say
about that
so hp
hpke has a notion of doing a single key
exchange that you then use for multiple
ads
now it's up to the application of hpk to
like provide sequence numbers to make
sure that you process them in the right
order
um etc but um
but that that's there we could use that
it'd be pretty straightforward what i
was wondering is whether
we need to invent something new to
signal end of stream here or whether
like we could lean on the http
chunked content encoding or something
like that to
you know
which if i recall correctly has end to
stream signal
um and so you would just basically just
have the the encrypted thing be
you know here's some some chunks and
[Music]
uh
and you can encrypt them and then the
interior thing would signal when you got
the last shot
i don't think we can rely on chunked
encoding for this i don't think coupling
the the chunk boundaries that you use
for the aead with either the chunk
encoding thing or http 2 data frames is
a good idea
i think there's
any number of reasons why you might want
to be doing things like rechunking
at intermediaries for instance so i
don't think that's going to work
particularly well
um this design that i have here is
going yeah so what i was going to say is
like if you're going to do the hpke
uh multiple aud thing you're going to
need a framing a little bit of framing
anyway so you might as well just put a
bit there
that's exactly what i'm suggesting might
happen here yep
tommy
um so one
question
because i was waiting to see kind of the
proposal i understand that that's not
ready yet
does supporting
this streaming chain
do the streaming does that change the
wire format for the encapsulated request
for requests that don't want chunked or
streaming
yeah the the way that i've got it at the
moment uh there's a single zero byte
at the
at the start of the message but
otherwise it's exactly the same so
exactly the same code that you have
today
you put a zero byte in
and if you're unwilling to support
chunking on receipt then you
just simply read a zero byte off and
then
run exact same code that you have today
right so
okay
and that makes sense i don't
love it so i guess the other question is
like you know what are the use cases for
oblivious http that
currently would use this like are
who is going to benefit
from this
uh
bite and the potential complexity of
implementing like
is anyone going to actually use this and
test it out and exercise this um as
we're developing the protocol because i
have a couple use cases that i'm
currently using this for and they're not
needing this
right so there's a there's
a lot of use cases that we have that are
very small requests very small responses
and that would be
kind of this would be a waste on those
um those things now the question is
whether there's anything that you might
use this for that has much larger
requests or responses
there are some of the things
that i've been looking at for um
the npc related submission of
you know advertising related things for
instance that
might use larger payloads
it's uncertain
and
sufficiently large that they couldn't
just create i mean couldn't just
essentially stream it to the proxy and
then
have that be one large request that's
forwarded
well it's it's more about being able to
stream it into the in the encryption or
description
okay
yeah
david sknozzy this time mask enthusiast
um
so similar to tommy i'm not entirely
sure we need this because like in my
view most of the use cases are for like
short things
and
like if you're starting to get into
things that are much longer
i mean
i know i'm the math guy but you know at
some point you can use mask like if
you're really want to stream that's we
have another protocol for that that
might be a better fit uh so at first i
was like oh yeah this makes sense but
now that i'm seeing um crypto foot guns
i'm kind of concerned that solving those
might delay the rest of
uh this effort and unless we have a real
use case that's not solved i'd like to
understand more why that one can be
solved by something like mask
right so i suspect that the right thing
to do here would be to uh put out a pull
request see what people think about the
concrete implementation of it i suspect
that
the feedback that i've gotten here will
remain unchanged
but
since i'm 90 of the way through work
i'll probably go ahead and
ship a
pr circulate on list and see see what
comes out of that
ben schwartz uh just one quick note you
you could consider separating this by
mime type
effectively
um
and that would
that would make an extension
so in effect that would mean using an
extension which isn't completely
unreasonable
a number of ways to cut this one okay so
um
this is one of the more interesting
technical problems that exists here i
think it might have been david benjamin
who
has sort of reminded us that um
anti-replay is kind of a thing when
you're doing this when you seal
something up in hpke
uh
there's nothing in it that ensures that
their connection is live and so a
malicious proxy that gets their hands on
a request can
replay that request any number of times
and the server
that has no defenses against those sorts
of things might just process the request
multiple multiple times
so uh what we have at the moment
and this is going to require a little
bit of coordination perhaps to address
is
we've got some text in the draft that
that looks at the general problem and
surveys the space
and
there's a call out to a new draft that
i've proposed to the http api
working group that talks about how you
put timestamps in requests and
how you deal with the problems in there
um
i will go on to the next slide to show
you
the sort of problem so um
if you're doing anti-replay
there's um
sort of two
broad ways that you can deal with it
first is you can just not care
this is often the case
for
things like dns even though perhaps
maybe they should care in certain
circumstances a lot of dns servers won't
care about replays
and the other one is
you take all the requests you receive
and you remem remember them and if you
see
a request that's played out twice
you reject the second one all subsequent
ones
for something
like
oh gdp you just look at the a slice
of the the request that the encapsulated
key
is a good thing to use in that case
you don't need to remember the entire
request in order to recognize that
something's coming again
you just need enough of that ink value
to to ensure that it's unique
probably 16 bytes would do
so the problem with this is that you
even with as little as 16 bytes per
request that you've processed
that's an infinite amount of state
if you're a long running server
so um
a practice that we've used in a number
of other settings is to include
uh some sort of timestamp in the request
and the http date header field
is not a bad
choice for this one even though the date
is not
used particularly often
and then you only need to remember
requests over a short span of time
anything outside of that
span is rejected because it's too old
it's probably a replay or too far into
the future someone's got a wacky clock
for those requests that you remember as
they get too old you just
stop remembering them
it sort of keeps the amount of
the state that you maintain finite
that leads to the next problem which is
that client clocks are bad and in some
cases really really bad
there's a paper that we cite that talks
about just how bad it is but um
it's not unusual to find clocks that are
years bad
some of them
like
centuries into the future
that sort of thing um completely weird
stuff
so um the solution there i think is to
just let the client retry so
you have a the service send a signal
saying that you'll collap your clock is
wacky and the server response will
include a date header field conveniently
and the client can just retry
using the date that the server has
provided you should turn the value
around in most cases
there's a number of ways in which this
can go really really badly wrong
you don't want to use the service date
for things other than an immediate retry
but
there's a you can use it for this one
retry so there's a there's a bunch of
stuff in the in the date request draft
that covers the security risks of taking
random clocks from random servers
um
but in general this this works
reasonably well it provides linkability
between the original attempt and the
retry but if the retry is essentially
the same request tried again then it's
not particularly bad
and here there's not there's acne
answers as well in the chat i don't
think that allows you to do the time
windowing thing
although it may be uh possible in that
case because the server is the one
that's generating the noises
it seems like the server generated date
here because the server comes indeed
yep so it's essentially a token so um
this is more or less in uh for your
information um i think this is probably
a reasonable thing here i think the
challenge here is that we're citing a
draft that's an individual draft in
another working group
so i just wanted to make people aware of
that that possibility we could probably
break that dependency
uh by folding some of the content in
but um
we haven't yet had the conversation in
http api about what to do with that
draft
so
um there's a little uncertainty there
thankfully we have some other problems
to solve so we
this doesn't become urgent
any input on this one
okay
so first let me just like state what i
think is the case um which is um that
this is about replay by the proxy
correct
so the proxy is pretty much the only one
that ever gets to see these messages so
yeah
right are you good just making sure i'm
the same page as you um
i think
i mean i i guess i wonder like i mean i
know i know
as you say clocks are like terrible um
um
but i wonder if the answer is just don't
do that um you know uh we're talking
we're talking a new protocol definition
and um i i wonder if like maybe the
answer is just like
it is say well
like like have an accurate clock or it's
not gonna work
um
and uh um i guess i just like like i
know we talked about i mean you alluded
to some of these things but it's just
like that the like just just just like
you know naively accepting whatever date
the server gives you has like all kinds
of other problems um and
um
um and and if if um
um you know i think well i guess i guess
there are the other two there are two
flavors of this right one is where you
don't know or you know you accept it but
only for the purpose of this message at
which point you mess measures or not
because it's basically nuts or the other
is where you persist it at which point
now you have a tracking problem i'm not
sure how to do what and so it seems like
and it seems like maybe like the answer
is just like
um it's just like fisher clocks so um i
don't know but um i think um i guess i
guess if i'm i i think i think my i
guess maybe my my my bottom line is like
either we should do
not try to correct the clock at all and
just do what you have this in this thing
or have send a correct clock or you're
gonna have to absorb around trip for
knots i think it's probably my take on
this i don't think i don't think trying
to crack the clock is going to like this
is a great idea
so you you're thinking of having having
the server respond with the nonce and
then you have to
make another request with that nonce
well
the mechanics and the mechanics
obviously or if your clock is wrong then
you're going to send a request and
either it's going to be dropped or
they're going to tell you to try again
with some other new information and and
and and the version and the version you
have here uh the version of the next
slide effectively is try again with a
correct clock but i'm just saying that
unless you're that if you're not going
to store that clock information for very
long then you might as well just try the
knots and you can skip the clock part
and then and then the way you think
about this is the clock is the clock is
a shortcut around the around the knots
right um is going to think about this
anyway i'm
i'm not sure if i i guess i i'm just
trying to avoid having this like having
to like define the privacy rules around
precision o'clock
yeah i mean
i i went through it in the other draft i
think it's probably
probably tractable but um yeah you you
essentially if you have a bad clock you
end up with with a round trip an extra
round trip for every request that you
you send which is unpleasant
then
uh so i i
looked just briefly at the i guess two
drafts involved here um
neither of them seems to mention the
problem of
distinctive skew linkability so if
you're the only client who's 11 seconds
behind
then all of your requests become
thinkable you lose the oblivious
property
so including a date header in the inner
request is a little scary
unless it's
i guess
fuzzed
rather than quantized
anyway something to think about
yeah i did talk about fuzzing but uh i
should probably have
brought that out a little bit more
maybe ecker's idea is much much better
tell me
all right
one high level comment on this is like i
would suggest that the normative
bits
should be a bit more generalized that
they should be around the fact that the
client and the target
should ensure that the protocol that is
encapsulated
isn't going to be vulnerable to replay
attacks
and then
drill down more specifically for the
binary htb case and say okay here's the
date field or we talk about the
technique
and then yeah i mean calling out to your
draft
makes sense but i think probably be a
pretty soft
reference because
other
protocols like if i'm doing just dns
message wrong here or something new in
the future like that will have their own
considerations
and those don't need to be
a fundamental dependency
from
the main ohtp draft
yeah that's um
this is
really only http at this point so i
don't think we need to make it
particularly generic but it does i think
i think we do a text on the generic
protections that are necessary
if we don't then
let me know fix we'll fix it up
eric
yeah similar to the
to tommy's comment a moment ago i think
this is
enough of a case that a lot of the uses
of oblivious won't care about this to
the point where i don't know if this
really belongs in the main oblivious
draft at all this i think this should
either be
either something generalized or maybe
just a
a quick informational draft of
if you care about replayability attacks
and your oblivious usage here's what you
do about it and then the main draft can
just be nothing other than a citation of
hey
replay is a concern for it here's the
draft to look at if you do care but
overall since i think the majority of
usage won't care i don't think this
should be polluting the main draft
um okay let's take this to the list
because i think this is a little bit
more challenging than i
had anticipated
let's see where we're up to
and the queue is trained great so we'll
take the take that to list there's some
ideas floating around here that we can
probably take up
uh i'm not convinced that we can
ship something like this without some
replay protection but
we'll see
so um final final issues a couple of
small things
uh
issue number 58 uh and and 19 are things
that i think we can dispense with
relatively quickly here i just wanted to
test
since the room on two of these things
the first one 58 asks whether this work
should be experimental
i'm going to suggest no does anyone
disagree with me
please come to the like if you have an
opinion on this whether this document
should be experimental or standards
track
i've implemented this i think we plan to
ship this
and there are others so
it doesn't seem to make much sense to
make it a grand experiment but uh
i'd like to hear reasons why there's
feedback on the in the chat that says
not experimental
wouldn't it be great if medieca would
scroll the chat
all right so uh issue 19
uh
is um
talking about discovery and there's a
number of things that we could talk
about in discovery
um i think i'd just like to reaffirm
that we're not going to do it in this
draft
we may do it in this working group i
think tommy has a
document that's talking about discovery
or at least some aspects of the
discovery related to this
there may be other things that we need
to discuss about discovery
i suspect this is a very long topic
and we should we should continue having
those discussions
does anyone think that we need to
address
more
of the discovery problem in this in this
document
now i've got a couple of notes
but those people are sensible
[Music]
because i don't know how to do discovery
in this document uh because
yeah
i can imagine the service b config stuff
um
is is going to be enough of a challenge
for the what is it ddr
so
i would note that the charter text on
this says that the working group may
work on other use cases or deployment
models including those involved
discovery so this is at best secondary
in the charter
so
with that feedback i think we're good to
close that issue off
and move on
that's me done
thanks martin
i think next through
hello
hello uh theory did you wanna
uh
[Music]
you want to share a screen or um i think
it might be easier to do sharing
of pre-loaded slides
yeah that would be great yeah
wait do i have to okay
can you try controlling that
yeah
hey um good afternoon everyone i'll be
i'm through from i will be presenting
the obvious proxy feedback draft we
published this rap a few weeks back and
we got some feedback on this stuff so we
worked on that so i'll share
the feedback as well as what this draft
is trying to propose
the problem is quite straightforward
that uh
uh because we have there's an obvious
proxy which is basically uh masking all
the clients behind it and sending the
traffic there's a good chance that uh
the
traffic that's coming from the proxy
could
exceed the
uh capabilities of the target server and
that would cause it to start rate
limiting the traffic from the process
this is something that we have seen in
various deployments today with regard to
various types of rate limiting that gets
applied uh but this is quite different
that because there's a proxy involved
typically the rate limiting is usually
applied for clients but in this case the
right lifting would get applied to the
proxy and if the rate clipping gets
applied to the proxy then it would start
harming all the clients that are behind
the proxy that's the problem that we are
trying to solve by this draft
the proposal is to signal the overload
from the server to the ws proxy and the
proxy uses this feedback to rate limit
uh any http request from uh like
offending clients or misbehaving clients
or botnets which are trying to overwhelm
the server
uh
one of the feedback that we got was uh
there's already a draft in http api
working group with regard to use of rate
limit headers which basically is
publishing the quotas or service limits
to clients uh we updated the proposal
that we have to align with this draft to
basically send those quotas or service
limits only to the proxy and not to
these offending clients
so what we did was uh we introduced a
new uh
proxy header earlier in the zero zero
version we had just a feedback editor
and the feedback was not to pick a very
generic header so we changed it to ohi
proxy feedback header which provides
feedback from either the
request resource or target resource to
the proxy and the whole idea is the
proxy would remove the header before
sending the http response to the client
a simple uh workflow would be like the
client gets sent in that's in
a crafted packet just to target the
server and
the target resource identifies that it's
an
uh malicious request and it sends in 400
response along with the ohio proxy
feedback back to the request resource
which which again forwards it to the
proxy proxy basically takes it out from
the foreign response puts it in uh
the request resource takes it out and
puts it in the 200 response only for the
consumption of the proxy and sends the
encapsulated 400 response without this
feedback header and then the proxy
applies this
rate limiting rules that if it believes
is the right remitting rules that the
target resource has given it and the 400
response would hit the client back
so what we did was uh all these
parameters that we have would be part of
this uh
proxy feedback header uh so we have
picked the various uh
fields that are there in the rate limit
headers to be part of this header which
would be sent back to the proxy for
enforcing this rate limits either for
the proxy to enforce late remits or for
if it's an offending client which is
trying to attack the server then the
target server can ask to the proxy to uh
rate limit this uh offending client and
uh
and the server obviously in this case
would not have any information about the
client
all right do could i ask you a
clarifying question please sorry to
interrupt yeah could you go
one slide to slide five please
sure
so
when you were first explaining this i
was assuming that the request resource
was getting too many requests from the
proxy resource
but now i'm kind of thinking that the
target resource is getting too many from
the request resource so can you clarify
in which which server is being
overwhelmed or
receiving malicious requests here so so
in this example we have just targeted
the target resource getting an offending
packet for example assuming it's getting
an abnormal header the attack could be
even on the request resource that it's
getting let's say and garbled
encapsulated request and it tries to
decrypt it and it just fails so the
attack could happen
the draft currently talks about attacks
uh encapsulated malformed uh request or
higher rate of
request coming and hitting the request
resource or it could be hitting the
target resource with crafted packets
okay thank you i'm gonna need to think
about this some more
thank you
hi um eric scroll um
i guess i'm a little unclear on how this
is supposed to work
so um you know the um you give the
example of um
of a uh undergraduate message but like
it's perfectly easy to make a decrepit
robust critical message right so i guess
like
so i guess like what i'm trying to
understand i mean it's like there's
there's like like so there's like one
very specific set of veg cases where
somehow there's a particular kind of
like message i send that like has abuse
like has abusively high single message
consumption of resources on the server
um like i do something that requires you
like making a normal secret powerful big
computation right and then no legitimate
client would ask for but the way that
dots and act like frequently work is i
send legitimate appearing requests and
um and they're indistinguishable from
illegitimate requests and their problems
the volume of those requests and so
given so i don't understand like which
give it if you're getting if you get you
know if you're if you're able to channel
a thousand requests a second and you're
getting five thousand requests a second
like to which ones do you send the
throttling messages
yeah there are two types of attacks when
i was referring to either it could be a
simple http flood or it could be a flash
cloud scenario and it's quite
undiscontinual in which case the target
resource is getting over and branded
want to handle those the other one is
basically an attack where it could be a
slow loris or it could be a malformed
request or a garbled request kind of an
attack
okay but we agree this does not work for
the ones where it's just a lot it was
just a lot of legitimate looking traffic
right
sorry i didn't get that we agree this
does not work for ones where the traffic
is legitimate working right
yeah yeah
the malicious request is not for the
legitimate tracking but for if the
target resource is getting really
overwhelmed with let's say
black millions of requests coming from
the proxy and it wants to rate limit
then it can basically signal that the
rate limit is not just specific for a
client it could be for the proxy as well
i guess i'm still not like
i hear you're saying but i don't i don't
see how this works because you're just
now you're just rate limiting everybody
like you got you got i mean for this to
work properly to discriminate between
the valid traffic and invalid traffic
and
um you know if you just don't like how
much bandwidth you're getting likes like
you know slow down your tcp stack or
something i mean like it just seems like
you know i mean i i guess
i mean
it seems like i mean i i guess if you're
just trying to like like narrow the
amount of bandwidth being assumed but
you're not like actually writing any any
better service right
yeah narrowing the bandwidth to to
basically give an equal share to all the
clients both the legitimate and uh
i don't understand how that works what
i'm saying is is that like
the the nature of the proxy
is to
transparently send the data coming into
the data coming out and so in order to
and so like and it will like naturally
attempt to share between those clients
right and so if you want to like do less
you've got to somehow tell it give these
clients less and these other clients
more i don't understand how you're
saying that well but ecker the the whole
concept here is that the resource server
can't or the request server can't
distinguish the clients
i think the idea here is to say dear
proxy server figure it out
because you can see the clients
by
uh okay but i guess like
sure okay i guess but like
um i mean i would hope the processor
would always do that i guess
one might think
so we have a bit of a cue here um tommy
hey
all right um
thank you teru um so
actually to this point that you have on
the slide right here about aligning
with the rate limiting
um it doesn't really seem to be quite
aligned i see that you're using some of
the same terms as like the values of
your http fields
but
in the right limit document those are
the actual
field names the header name so i would
really suggest like
just use the rate limit headers i i
don't see
really what we're getting from these
additional ones um
and overall the reason why we didn't
pick the fields as is as what is there
in the rate limit header was we didn't
want this uh signal to go back to the
client if it goes back to the client
then probably the client would know that
hey it's attack strategy is being
identified and that's being mitigated so
we wanted the signal only to reach the
proxy
so how do you distinguish other
fields that are
i guess i would say um overall for ohtp
if it's not already said
the proxy should not just be relaying
arbitrary headers between the target and
the client or the client and the target
um
i i
if that's not said it should be said by
i wouldn't expect that the proxy would
just say oh yeah the target just can
just include whatever random data it
wants and then we'll send it
kind of as clear text not inside
the actual encrypted payload
right and with the current rate limit
header i believe it will be in the
encapsulated response so the proxy
wouldn't even know what is there in that
right
yeah
um and then overall this seems like it's
like what we should have here is just
normal rate limiting between the target
and the proxy saying hey proxy you're
sending me too much
and then the proxy should just figure
out on its own
what it needs to do about that and it
can identify its own clients that are
overwhelming it
right
but
that's it we should just leave it very
very simple this is just two
layers of
normal rate limit headers and we don't
need another header field here i think
okay so sure yes we can restrict that
quick point of order um did you have
more uh presentation content you wanted
to get through because we have a queue
here we can put that off so you're done
sure uh just one more slide so basically
uh if
i wanted to have a discussion whether
this header needs to be only conveyed to
trusted proxies and
if an attacking proxy which is colluding
with attacking clients would leak this
feedback to change the attack strategy
so
is this something that
needs to be only conveyed to proxies
which authenticate back to the
target reso target and resource servers
or could this be used with any any any
proxy
that was
one of the questions i wanted to discuss
with the working
all right going back to the queue eric
mr escort law
all right reggie
from piconets uh just wanted to say you
know um
i have only personally reviewed the
draft but um at least based on heroes
description if we can go back a couple
of slides um i am still unconvinced
whether this uh rate limit based
approach is the right
uh approach to take to try and mitigate
these challenges so i i i see clearly
that there are two types of challenges
here that uh you know like eric
mentioned
one type which is where there is a
obviously
uh
individual request that is likely to be
malicious in nature either because of of
the scope of that individual request or
how it is structured uh it may contain
junk or it may contain the kind of
content which will
is designed to overload the server okay
so
there the challenge is the fact that
it's a malicious or uh
you know overloading style request
which you want to restrict the second
uh condition that we are looking at is
like eric mentioned a large amount of
legitimate looking requests but just at
a scale designed to disrupt the target
server okay now
in
scenario one where it's an individual
request that is malicious by nature of
its content okay
fill rate limiting
are you going to send back a rate limit
of zero because that's the only way you
can guarantee that the next request does
not come through
right because here it's not the volume
of the request that is a problem for the
server it's the nature of the request so
i have three clients each sending one
request
per minute but if those requests are
designed
to bring my server down and
and the only way for me to stop them
from coming is to send a rate limit of
zero because these kind of malicious
requests are not designed to be limited
by a rate limit
type of mechanism
so in the first in the first case rate
limit is obviously the wrong
approach to take to try and uh you know
mitigate or block that particular
traffic hey rajiv i'll answer the first
question i think uh if you look at the
rate limit headers graph right it allows
a rate limit uh uh option where you set
it to zero basically that means to say
that the server is not willing to accept
any any further client so the rate limit
is typically a block action
correct but then in this particular
scenario because of the fact that you
have two levels of intermediation with
anonymization happening in between what
you have effectively done by allowing
rate limit zero to be said is you have
dosed your entire proxy infrastructure
no uh so if you see the headers that we
have defined we have defined multiple
headers one is rate limit p limit which
is for the proxy and one is rate limit
uh uh rate limit hyphen limit which is
for the client basis
which then brings into the picture the
fact that now the now the dependence is
on the target server somehow knowing
that this is coming through a proxy
infrastructure and i need to have
separate headers for that or you are
talking of putting intelligence at the
request
resource level to identify that when i
get a rate limit zero okay i am now
supposed to be uh
setting the rate limit p limit and
sending that onwards to the proxy but
in in most cases the expectation from
the target resource will be hey i am
talking to the requester resource that's
that's all i know
okay i am the whole point of being
oblivious is that the target resource
should not have to know that it's coming
through a proxy infrastructure
anonymization intermediation is all
a black box to it all it knows is i've
received
a malicious request from request
resource so i'm sending a rate limit
zero to that request resource which
means anyone any other traffic coming
through that request resource has
effectively now been dosed
yeah it all depends on if the request
resource and target resource writer
requests because all this can share that
it's coming by a client or a proxy right
otherwise if it's let's say if it's a
direct communication
for example in case the target server
could be attacked by both the client
directly talking to the server or it
could be coming by an oblivious uh path
right yeah in both the cases the server
needs to have that context right if you
see what we have proposed is there has
to be some uh communication that's
happening between the request resource
and the target to identify whether this
was this request actually originated
because it was obvious or or a direct
communication so that way uh
obvious basically so that the target can
actually set the right kind of headers
there
yeah so this kind of goes against the
text at least in the first section of
the draft where it clearly says that the
whole purpose of oblivious one of the
use cases that should be supported is
the fact where the fact that traffic is
coming through an oblivious proxy
channel is masked and not visible to the
target resource the target resource
should not
not know nor care that this is traffic
coming in from an oblivious reason yeah
it doesn't it doesn't care about the
client identity right i mean that's the
purpose of ws is my understanding but
whether it knows that it's coming
because obvious protocol is being used
it's not going to invade the client
privacy in any way right
okay so so on on on the one hand then
you're saying that yes uh you know you
will have some sort of uh probably
header level communication between the
requester and the target saying that hey
oh oh by the way this isn't a request
directly from me it's from it's for a
downstream client of mine but it's
anonymized
so therefore i'm not sharing that with
you
so and and then you're talking of uh the
target server then having intelligence
in it to understand this communication
from the requester and know that if i
see a malicious request of type one i
need to send back headers specifically
allowing the requester resource to
continue to come to me but
also to communicate downstream to its
clients saying that you you specific
client are no longer allowed to come
right
okay now i think you should move on
congratulations
yeah let's check the discussion on the
list but the good questions thank you
thanks for all the questions here
okay can i very quickly address my
second point uh which is the volumetric
actual volumetric attack that date limit
was designed to counter against uh i
tried to keep it down to 30 seconds
so um again in a case of a rate limit
the same
you know
limitation applies the target resource
has to be aware that this is
a volumetric traffic coming through a
proxy infrastructure of some kind so
that right you do not land up in a
scenario where the rate limit basically
doses your proxy infrastructure itself
correct and secondly there's a even
bigger problem if you come back to the
previous site on the proxy resource side
when you're dealing with a volumetric
proxy
the minute you start having to maintain
state of saying okay these are the list
of clients who are blocked or these are
the list of clients for whom these rate
limits are set up especially in a
volumetric attack that effectively
becomes a
toss on your proxy resource because your
state table is going to grow to a point
where it
probably is going to land up becoming
unmanageable
right
so that's also it all depends on the way
that yeah it all depends on the way that
you enforce these rate limits if you're
if the proxy is authenticating the
client then it's a different way of
enforcement if it is not authenticating
then how do you put acls for example we
have we have been implementing rate
limits for
ddos attacks all the while and we could
even program millions of such ip
addresses to be blocked or rate limited
so uh i can share more details on how it
could be done
okay
but i'm i just point out that that
should be something that should be
addressed in the draft specifically
because it is a it is a non-trivial
problem i i'm pretty sure you are good
that you you have a lot of data you have
a lot of years of
engineering behind being able to do what
you're saying you're doing now right
thanks rajiv let's move on eric
yeah sort of quick mental exercise to
sort of decide if this is a worthy thing
to pursue or not if we ignore your
specific proposal and just focus on
what's the simplest thing to solve the
issue
i i limit the issue down to saying
this specific thing that
this request was doing something's bad
in it and the proxy needs to know that
to
either ban or limit or
act on that specific client if they have
more requests of that sort i think the
simplest thing we can do is proxies i
mean the the server sends a bit to the
proxy saying something was bad about
this request
and then that's one bit going from the
survey prox and this immediately
something hey this sounds very very very
very similar to that whole shadow
banning conversation we just had 45
minutes or so ago now so from that
perspective maybe we should essentially
shelve this until
the debate is settled on the proxy
banning thing and if it's decided yes
sending one bit or similar information
from the proxy to the server makes sense
okay then we should go back okay this
makes sense to send similar information
from the server to proxy because that's
in my opinion exactly what this is and
if it is then then we can discuss okay
what's the exact stuff that makes sense
to be able to send and
pick this back up again
okay
hi ben schwartz so i think this issue is
real i think it's it's worth solving i
think
that you're
i understand the concern that you raised
about using the unmodified rate limit
headers directly
and i think the solution is to
use the unmodified rate limit headers
and work with that draft and the http
draft to make sure that they actually
work in the way that you that you want
it to work here
so i don't think we can i already
reached out to the authors of
their draft to help us out so
yeah we'll work with them so yeah i
don't think we need a new header here
but i do think there's there's some work
to be done
yeah
the whole challenge was how do you make
sure that the proxy strips it also if
there is a way we can the the target
resource can put these headers but the
but
how does it
from from the http response and how does
it get percolated back in a way that uh
it's it's it's it's not being sent to
the client field we can discuss that
yeah that can be specified either as an
aspect of the header itself or as an
aspect of http proxies
so eric
had a
fairly good in it
that i think probably works in this case
um
it requires communication between the
request resource and the proxy
not the target result and i'll get i'll
get to that
but um just like in the in the issue 66
discussion
we were talking about sending a a single
bit that says this this client is
suspicious
um
in the direction of the proxy to the
request resource not the target or the
request resource
so that the request resource can act
accordingly
the same applies for in the direction
from the request resource back to the
proxy and and that single bit with the
same sort of standing
uh would work uh it does require there
is a private communication um
that the proxy resource understands this
message
or that the proxy resource is not it's
not generic and doesn't blindly pass
uh header fields alone
but
i think both of those things are quite
reasonable in this heading
for the target resource communicating
this state there's a lot of cases where
you'll have the request resource and the
target resource
collocated
in which case none of this coordination
problem really needs to
occur over the wire
in the other case i think
that the
the rate limit stuff
doesn't work in this case because of the
way that it depends on understanding who
the client is
but some there may be some ways in which
we can signal um those sorts of things
i think there are two different
solutions there though
and um
the more important is the is the signal
that is private between the request
resource and the proxy resource
okay
and it is just that one bit this request
was potentially suspicious and then you
potentially have to have the volumetric
things as well
sure
see since martin you're suggesting that
for malicious requests we just say that
it's a malicious one rather than uh
providing any rate limit uh parameters
but for proxy continue to have the right
limit uh parameters being pushed on to
the proxy
yeah i i think
in a lot of cases though as as ekka
pointed out the individual request won't
be problematic
it will
you will need
some other ch
or perhaps a separate type of signal
that says hey by the way uh
the number of requests or the rate of
request that i'm receiving is too high
proxies start looking for for individual
clients that are acting badly and and
try to eliminate or slow them down in
some way
that i think requires
probably a richer outer band
communication than what the individual
request headers
can provide us with
okay
uh why do you think that uh the inline
one is bad and we need an out of band a
new communication channel
sorry i'm going off
then you ask me a question um for
exactly the reason ecker stated which is
that individual request in a denial of
service state will generally be genuine
or appear to be genuine
so um
it will be from the perspective of the
server that's operating here it will be
unable to distinguish between
the the requests that are coming from
bad actors and good actors and all it
needs
is try to push
further out toward the edge the
responsibility for filtering those down
got it
one additional point that just came uh
you know into my way or achieve here uh
was the fact that in uh cases of most
target resource servers um while they
may implement things like sending out
rate limit headers and stuff like that
many times when there is detection of
any sort of malicious traffic
there may also be other security
measures that kick in um i like an
application level firewall that starts
uh blacklisting
stuff like that so um having some text
in the draft specifically saying that
hey uh you know
any traffic that's going towards a
target resource from a request resource
must contain some header or some
indication that it's coming from a proxy
which then allows the target resource to
say hey um
yes i'm seeing a malicious request that
would under normal conditions lead to an
immediate fan on that ip but because
it's coming from a proxy infrastructure
of some kind i
don't do that ban right now because i
may end up
impacting legitimate users
which again kind of to me it's a bit of
a
disconnect between the text of what the
draft is intending saying that you don't
want a mechanism where target resources
have to be necessarily aware of the
oblivious framework in order to be able
to support the traffic
so
i just thought this was also something
since we're discussing security
implications that should be part of the
draft and uh you know it's a problem
that needs to be addressed even if we
don't have a solution for it at least
say that this is a potential problem
that we need to look at
yeah that's a good point rajiv i think
we can add some text to address that
okay great i think we've drained the
queue
um
yeah so it seems like my sense is that
um the
is that there is a need for something
like this but
um maybe that should go in the http api
range limiting draft um
in a section over there or
sounds like
like more fundamental work is needed in
the contract yeah especially we'll work
on the feedback and i think we'll get a
new version and then we'll take the
discussion on the mailing list to see
which working group fits us
okay perfect thanks a lot
great um tommy
you up next
thank you let me show the slides
and i'm going to forgo sharing video for
the moment
apologies
all right so
um we recently posted a draft
about how to do some discovery of
oblivious target configurations via dns
using service plan service binding
records
and this is what martin was referring to
earlier as one of the directions for
discovery
this is certainly not
the only mechanism that could be used
for discovery it is
a particular model that works for
a particular deployment scenario there
are other aspects of discovery that we
would want to get into but
this may be a good starting point to the
conversation
so what does this document do
it's relatively simple
it
sends the oblivious configurations
as well as when needed the http pads
for targets
and is specifically for the oblivious
targets and it sends these through dns
records
and these are defined using
the service binding slash
https
rr types which allow definition of new
parameters
and i
explains how you can use these for
discovering the configuration for a
generic
oblivious http target
and essentially learning that a server
that you would normally access not
obliviously also does offer an oblivious
target
but then it also talks about how to use
this
specifically in the dns case for doing
oblivious dns over https
and this is the part where
at least for my end we have a lot of
experience
deploying it now and this is where this
becomes interesting
this allows us to integrate with
um
work that's going on in the add working
group to discover
uh encrypted resolvers either via
a dns query to a well-known
resolver.arpa name
or
as something that can come in dhcp or ra
messages
and this also um explains
the similar use for the previous version
of odo which is
the experimental version that pre was
the precursor to a lot of the oblivious
http work
what this document does not do
at least in its current form
is talk about anything for oblivious
proxy discovery
that's one thing that i think
martin brought up
an issue
and
the draft could probably be
more clear and emphasize this more
strongly that it does not cover this
the
proxy discovery case
could be added but i believe it's
something that's quite different
as we discussed earlier
the
relationship between a client and a
proxy and that trust about what it's
doing what it's potentially adding or
not adding really matters
and
i don't see as much of a use case for
that being arbitrarily
discoverable in a mechanism like dns
maybe there could be a registry of known
and trusted
proxies but
what we're talking about here is
discovering targets
now there will be a little bit more on
this later
so
as an example
um
the
we have two cases here we can have
oblivious dns
um being advertised for essentially the
discovery
of encrypted resolvers case
ddr
so we would have a record for
dns.resolver.arpa
amongst other things it could say that
it supports an odo
server
this would include within it the fact
that this is an http target it would
have the path
to use for do on this query along with
the list of o http configs
this is quite similar to how the
encrypted client hello tls configs can
be communicated in the same way
and you can imagine this then works also
for a generic
oblivious http case where i could learn
that
metricsupload.example.net supports
oblivious http as a target and i could
learn what its config is there
so to walk through a very specific
example and this is kind of the real
life case that we would have
i have a client that has an oblivious
proxy that it goes through that it
trusts that has a strong relationship
with
and it currently would be by default
talking to
one or more oblivious
dns targets that it knows about this is
how icloud private relay works today
and in this scenario
i can imagine that i join a network
and i connect to
the isp dns resolver
just for my normal maintenance traffic i
can query it for dns.resolv.arpa
and i learn that the isp has designated
a specific oblivious dns target
and the reason that this could be
interesting is
maybe there is some
in country or in isp policy about
the type of responses i get from a
server
there are you know various regulations
in places about
what content someone may be accessing
and so
the case of maybe my isp knows that this
is a child's device
and it wants to have some filtering for
particular content
i do not want to when i'm using this
privacy system disclose
my kind of full browsing history
to that isp dns infrastructure but i
would be happy to go through a proxy and
use oblivious dns if that is safe
and so if we learn that configuration we
can essentially bootstrap this
and the client is now able to access
that isp selected oblivious doe target
if that target is known and trusted by
the proxy so there is a transitive trust
relationship
here in which the client has to trust
the proxy in the proxy
or some other
mechanism that the client can check
against validates that this is not a
unique per-client target but is
something that is more widely known and
registered
so to be very clear about the deployment
model for which this works this is a
case where the client knows one or more
proxies that it already trusts it's not
trying to discover that
the client wants to be able to access
oblivious targets
that are published
by their local dns or public dns
the client
needs a way to know that this target is
supported by a proxy and what path to
use
because oblivious http does require that
there's a mapping between the request to
a proxy and what the target is
um this
i'll point out and there's actually an
issue on the main ohtp draft that ecker
raised about the flexibility of these
mappings
while ohttp does require that you have a
one-to-one mapping that one-to-one
mapping could be something that is also
expressed as a uri template
so it is possible to
have this be a bit more generic as long
as the proxy is doing the correct access
control checking
i think
that having an unknown or untrusted
proxy that i need to discover
that's not a very clear use case
from what i can see right now
if someone does have a use case for it
let's definitely talk about it i'd love
to hear it
but
at this point i'm not aware of that
so the question is you know do we want
to
adopt something in this direction
um
certainly you know there could be more
refinement and changes but you know do
we want to be able to communicate
these types of configs
in
service binding records if so it seems
like it should be in scope for the
charter as one of these secondary items
and as part of that we'd like to get
these um service binding parameters
allocated because we
are planning on using them for our
olivia's dns
deployments
and that's all i have
hi tommy um thanks for raising this
um i'm a little
um i i understand what you're saying and
i think this is like a reasonable thing
to think about um
i'm trying to think through some of the
privacy implications
and
it's not like entirely clear to me that
the price implications are
straightforward as one might imagine and
so let me give you a concrete example
supposing i have
um two and i have two endpoints um i i
have two you know dns endpoints a and b
right and they're otherwise identical
and
um i'm the isp right
and um
i've two there's end points a and b are
identical and so to everybody but you i
give a
and
to
you i give b
and yes um and that they're specified by
by path or whatever right and so yes now
and so now
as another proxy like faithfully does
this it hides everything but it doesn't
matter because i okay because i've i've
now i've not linked up the dns
publication in that and so i'm like i'm
like
i'm just really worried that like
actually this will be quite easy to
attack um and i can imagine like i can
imagine a bunch of other like variants
of this well i give like really short
dhcp lifetimes and then i like i
encourage your identity and like in
single bits or i have multiple things i
mean i can imagine a lot of ways to
attack this directly and so i i i guess
like i want to persuade myself if this
actually is going to work
um
right exactly and i think that's
so the approach
you know we are thinking of here is
again relying on this relationship
between the client and the proxy and
that there is trust there the proxy is
in a place where it can ensure that the
volume of traffic of essentially
different clients to a given
target path as well as like the the key
ids
of the configurations is sufficiently
large the proxy can definitely recognize
or clients could all report to some
other entity for transparency
you know what are the paths and stuff
they're seeing so you could detect oh
this is a unique client and they're the
only ones who get this
um
and that that's part of why i think
there is a
there is i think a case where this
discovery makes sense and is useful but
it's
it has a lot of constraints on it and it
doesn't make sense
oh sorry i
i don't know what to do about that
you're better now
okay
sorry
um
anyway yeah i
i think it depends a lot on how the
client can trust
the proxy or work with other clients to
detect
um unique configurations and i think we
have a call out to some of the work that
chris and mt we're doing for key
consistency
right
well i i i think i guess so i i think
well i guess i perhaps feel differently
about this in the sense that like i feel
like we kind of we kind of like hand
weight this away when we when we started
privacy pass and now we're like having
to fight it because we haven't waved it
away and we didn't have a solution so i
guess like i'm a little reluctant to
take that bet again um without having
like some a more clearly worked example
of how to make this one how to actually
make this work but um
um but i agree it's a problem worth
trying to solve
thank you
hey ben schwartz so uh
maybe some people didn't see the the
comments on the the ohio mailing list
about this but so i read through this
and i conclude this is this arrangement
is um
first of all not secure
like above all this arrangement
uh
essentially hands over root ca powers to
the proxy server who can now
arbitrarily
invisibly impersonate any
um any website on the internet
uh it doesn't even have to be a website
that actually supports oblivious http
um so i am
seriously concerned i do not support the
draft as as written
i do think that
there's i i do disagree
about that
model i think it'd be good to explore
that a bit more right
sure so
there is a trust relationship between
the client and the proxy already and i
don't think that it's going to be able
to just
grab
tell the client whatever keys it wants
that's not where the keys are coming
from
uh right the keys are coming for over an
insecure channel they're coming through
the dns which is assumed insecure unless
stated otherwise
so uh in our in all our threat modeling
for the web we always assume that a dns
attacker could be swapping in arbitrary
things we don't trust
you know we don't rely on the ip
addresses coming back from dns or
anything else
uh to be secure in order to
in order to authenticate the domains
that we're visiting uh this
this would change that this would say
that if the proxy can
poison a dns cache if the if the
entity that operates the proxy can also
execute a dns cache poisoning attack or
just operates the dns resolver which
seems entirely reasonable or happens to
be near the path between the user and an
insecure dns server which also seems
highly plausible for a lot of these
proxy deployments
then
the proxy can
swap out the or or even inject a
synthetic ohttp config
for whatever domain the the user is
attempting to resolve and then
act as the origin
so
to me that makes this really a serious
problem i also have some other concerns
with the design i think the use of a
path here is basically wrong
the dope the path the doe path parameter
in the dough service b mapping is not a
good thing it's there as a compatibility
hack to be able to
work with pre-existing dns over https
servers but the the
dns service beam mapping has a long long
multiple paragraphs of caveats trying to
explain the dangers that this creates
because that path again is
attacker-controlled
so
uh so you can't assume anything about it
there's some problem like pat multiple
paths on the same server can interfere
uh so i think that we shouldn't have a
path here right there should only be um
that should somehow be a fixed value
effectively you know through the dot
well known mechanism
i mean a path on the target
is required to be known
i understand but we don't need it to be
flexible um given that there is no
install base that we're trying to
maintain compatibility with we can set
that we can say in the case where you
are trying to upgrade a a standard http
connection in this in the case where
you're trying to bootstrap ohttp
off of a dns name where all you have is
the dns name then we can say there's a
fixed default path for that or there's a
fixed inbound mechanism for learning
that path by again querying to something
in dot well known
i do think that there's a version of
this that can be made secure and and
workable and it's actually much simpler
and that is to just set a flag here that
says i do
http or i require ohtttp and then let
the client actually contact that origin
directly and you know through an
authenticated channel learn the ohtttp
config
learn the preferred path and then use
them
alright ted
uh ted hardy speaking um can you go back
to slides seven and eight please start
on seven
uh so if i understand this correctly um
once the
client has gotten information that the
isp dns resolver is accessible through
the isp doh target it tells this
information
it starts to use this information
through its proxy and i want to make
sure i understand this correctly
because is it your presumption here
that
if
the isp dns resolver presents an isp odo
target
it must always be accessible
to
all parts of the network in order to
work with any proxy
because typically isp dns resolvers
aren't
globally
accessible and this makes them so and i
want to make sure i understand that
that's your presumption here
that that is correct it doesn't
necessarily need to be open
to anybody in the world it could
certainly have an allow list of known
proxy deployments that it is willing to
work with
but yes it does need to be reachable via
the proxies
and that means it's not
isolated within the isp network okay so
i i think this is worth unpacking a
little bit more as you think about how
this goes because there are a couple of
consequences to that one is you if you
say there's an allow list
um you you either can pay a penalty um
by checking
each one of the proxies that you have
access to to find out if any of them are
on the allow list and that that's
perhaps not a very serious latency
penalty but it definitely would occur if
the only way to discover whether it's on
the allow list
is by experimentation or
you can publish the allow list in some
way and i think if you publish the allow
list you actually have changed the scope
of what you were talking about from
changing
how do i find a a target
to also how do i find a proxy because
what you're in effect doing
is using the the information uh from the
the information carrying that the target
list to also carry
uh the the permitted uh proxy list so i
think if if you're gonna go down that
path and use that allow list as
something that's published you're you're
in effect
whether that's
generic or not
you are providing discovery for
for proxies
i don't necessarily think that's a bad
thing as was pointed out on the list
this is this is sort of a twinned
problem here a proxy is useless without
targets and the target is useless
without proxies they don't without
knowing both of them you you actually
can't get this oblivious service but i
think if you are going to do that
you have to kind of rethink
architecturally that that's the scope
now and is this the best way to do it
um and
maybe maybe that does need some more
thought thanks
all right thank you um and just to
respond quickly to that so yes you
certainly could have an approach where
along with
the target information and target
configuration you get a list of
associated or trusted proxies
the other way that this can work is
again
the client
has to know
with its proxy
what the mapping is of paths so
if the client does have multiple proxies
it essentially needs to be able to ask
its proxy
have you heard of this target do you
know how to access it and so it's not
like we will have to actually have to
create
and just try random requests it can have
its own communication with proxies to
say do you already have an established
relationship with this target
uh so i agree with that thank you and um
there are other ways you could do it as
well right the the dns resolver target
could tell you uh what uh its
reachability limits are and say
basically give you a reachability limit
that's only within the isp
um or only within some region etc and so
you could do it in a bunch of different
ways but i think
it it may be important that you work out
in a little bit more detail which one
you expect to be the standard
davidskenazi hey tommy um
so
overall i think there's
definitely value in
having a way to
um
for a target to be able to say hey if
you want to talk to me here's a way of
doing it that improves your privacy so i
i like that i think there's a problem
worth solving here
um
however uh and i think you know some of
the deployment concerns uh are somewhat
orthogonal uh some of them not all of
them
but the
the point that ben made where uh
because of the way we have odo
sorry oblivious http today
um
you don't have a step or you verify
ownership of the private key for the tls
certificate um
that breaks kind of the security model
of a lot of things
so
i would say totally agree with the
problem to be solved here um i think we
should refine the solution to make sure
that that gap is fixed because otherwise
this sounds like a giant foot gun
thanks
all right thank you
martin
you're in front of me i wasn't sure if
it was me
so i'm sort of wondering whether there
is something here
that's a little little different in
terms of the design that might be might
be able to work so
i i think the large open problem that
you have here is that there's
there's a target and you've described a
way of discovering the target which i
think generally works um
there but the discovery proxy and
finding the intersection
of the set of proxies that the client
will trust and the set of proxies that
the target will trust
is
challenging um
and because there's no discovery
mechanism for the proxy pieces
the information the client has is
insufficient
based on your your current design i
think we did a little bit more about
that to ted's point earlier
so um
i think we probably need something more
i found
that the draft to be quite confusing on
that front because thinking as a client
i
i saw a url
but that's not the url that i i can use
i need two of them in order to make a
request with the oblivious http and you
only gave me one of them
so um
i think there's probably
around before we would go there
yeah i mean to respond to that i think
the existing model without discovery
for either proxy or target is
essentially you need some proprietary
mechanism for
learning the configurations and learning
what your proxy is and what the paths
are that map to your target
so a lot of this is
managed to clarify it assuming that you
still have that
proprietary
mechanism to communicate
uh what the config of the proxy is to
the client
and that essentially the client and
proxy can learn
you can negotiate
what they support and what the paths are
etc
and learn whether or not this target is
supported
and a new mechanism
have that relationship between a client
and a proxy that is generic
um
i think is a larger
scope and is less clear to me
yeah so probably the
uh
other idea that i had here was
if you get a url for the target resource
there's a bunch of things you can do by
talking to that target resource
in terms of learning what proxies it
trusts and learning what it's uh
its config is that of course creates
some interesting issues when it comes to
consistency
but um
those are the issues that i think we
need to be we need to be thinking
through here
chris hi yeah chris box uh i work with
bt um i just wanted to
say i think this is a really interesting
idea
it
it allows an isp to offer
dns based services
in a way that
doesn't require exposing the client's
identity so for example
an isp could offer malware filtering you
know for that service
we don't get to know who make the
request
so
i don't yeah i take the point of of
others about yeah we need to explore all
the implications of it but uh
i think it's a it's a good idea and uh
i'd like to see it adopted
all right thank you yeah yeah definitely
let's work work on the problem is right
here and fix the solution
yes eric
yeah very very similar to the last
comment actually i i think this is a
very good problem i like the overall
i like the overall solution i like the
overall area solve i think this is
something we should be adopting i think
the only question is do we solve the
very big security issues that i agree
with almost everything ever said in
those areas already do we solve those
before we adopted or do we adopt and
write the solutions for them and i don't
think they're too hard of security
issues to solve we've had a lot of
talk in the chat about hey signings of
all this
the draft r discussed a little bit
linking the consistency draft for stuff
about the
the other one that echo was discussing
earlier so
i i think if we if we beef up the
handling for security implications this
is a very good draft to have so i mean
i'd say let's adopt it and
do that beefing up
great um and what i would say is
besides stuff on the list there is a
github
for this and so eric and ben and egger
if people have ideas
let's
work on them and try to revise this we
can turn out another version of the
draft quickly and if that's something
that people like the solution on more
then that would be a good adoption
target
all right i think that's the cue
oh
ben
ben did you have any last comment there
if there's time i'll say uh i do think
that
that to step back one more step i think
we need a little bit more of an
integrated architecture approach here
that figuring out what makes sense here
really does depend on
how we decide to handle key consistency
for example it depends
a little bit as
some some other folks are saying on
how
uh
how users are learning the initial url
that that got them to this query so i
think
i would like to
see us step back a little bit and see if
we can get put together you know a set
of puzzle pieces that really fit fit
together into a
into a clean overall solution
jigsaw puzzle one might say
yeah so i've been chatting with with my
co-chair in the background here it seems
like where we're
ending up here is that there's you know
some energy behind this being a problem
that is useful to solve
um but it sounds like this the draft is
not yet in a state where it's it's kind
of adoptable and there's enough energy
around the draft in particular
so i i think the investors there is to
kind of keep refining the um
problem statement and especially around
the security requirements and um
i think we can look at uh
you know whether a future draft would
align with that better
all right
i think that brings us to the end of our
agenda siobhan is that correct
yes um we do have
about 15 minutes left i think um you can
just let everyone go early unless anyone
has anything
they'd like to say or we do have like
buffer time
um i don't know if anyone has any
comments
uh i guess something that we didn't want
to ask uh which was that like
it seemed like there were at least a few
issues that were
pretty i guess like hotly discuss so
we were wondering if folks would be
interested in having virtual interims
well the shadow band case i think
was the specific one you were thinking
about but
maybe for some of the other ones as well
so if folks would be interested in that
um
i mean please let us know yeah go ahead
martin
i don't know
i
think given the feedback that we got on
the shannon banning case here i i have a
pretty good sense that we can come to a
conclusion on some text that will work
for it in the next
i would say weeks
uh
the
anti-replay stuff uh is maybe less
settled but i i suspect we can make some
good progress on that uh
on on the list
the discovery issue does seem to be
something that is is worth um
spending a bit of in person high
bandwidth time on
so if there's any topic that rises to
that level i think that's the one
that makes sense so
it sounds like we maybe don't need to
schedule a virtual inum right now but
um if we get to a point where we're
ready to have some deeper dives on those
latter two topics
we chairs would be happy to do it
yep
that sounds right
um
francesca anything you want to say
no sounds good
okay perfect
all right then thanks all for coming and
see you all on the list
thanks for watching
thanks again francesca for helping us
thank you and thank you the minutes take
care as well
the three big rooms are closed because
they were reshuffling them
to prepare for the final
well i mean just
you can't you can't say