it's quite possible that the hotel might
have more ups
and this is the iegf stuff is great it's
just the stuff that we had in the
box fort
i know a lot of hotels took the
opportunity to be like oh we're
innovating
right over the past couple of years
or we're shutting down you know that'll
be another thing you can do i mean
it's quite possible
mundane reasons
[Music]
i'm gonna sit at the back
so
these
greg wood
[Music]
no
are you
yes
hey
uh
[Music]
oh
all right
it
is the mic on its own
please please come in and take a seat
and the mic is really on
uh welcome everybody um
yeah my name is liz eckhart i chaired
the ihf since a year ago
it's very very nice to see all of you
here in person it really feels like an
itf meeting although
as you probably can realize we're not
quite at the usual bench strength but um
it does feel really good it really feels
like it's been a long time it's been way
too long and uh i also hope the remote
participants will have a chance to join
us again at some time in the future um
hopefully in philadelphia or in london
later in the year or at any other time
and
we're also hoping that the improvements
we made
to the tooling for remote participation
because of corona will have a sort of
lasting impact
that will
open up the organization to more
participants
in into the future
because i really think
we're not going to go back to the old
style meeting for a while
and it's also so it's exciting to be
here in person
it's also quite sad and i'm pretty
emotional about this so i'm struggling a
little bit here but you know it's been
sad because obviously because of covid
we haven't really been able to meet um
for a long time
and some people had some extremely
challenging years
um and it remains an ongoing concern for
many of us
but also walking around the city right
you can't miss the signs that a war is
going on
right now
and it's a tragedy
and the war in ukraine feels very
personal because
we know that some of our friends and
families and colleagues are directly
affected
and the personal safety and security is
at stake
and their lives are in peril
so we worry about the safety
of our ukrainian colleagues
and their families
and
being so directly impacted
makes it difficult to concentrate on the
work of the itf which is
making the internet work better
um
and uh
i personally sort of
believe the inner is fundamentally about
connecting people
and
i can take some little bit of comfort
because
i choose to believe that
doing so
will hopefully allow us in the future to
avoid
needless wars
thank you
that's it um
some things never change and you can
take a great comfort that the
note well slide remains
as unreadable
as it has been
for decades now so
if you're new to the organization this
is
what we require of you as participants
please try and read it it's not very
easy but um you should be familiar with
it by now
um
there are some tips on how to
participate here
um when you join me deco which is the
tool we're using for displenary
your audio will be muted your video will
be off
and would you like to speak
from the floor or
i guess up on stage um
please unmute yourself
when you are recognized in the queue
and we ask you to share your video if
you feel comfortable doing so because it
makes it a bit more
personal
and if you have a headset please use it
it makes a big difference
and there's a lot of other helpful tips
that you can follow if you choose to do
so
[Music]
um the agenda is very generic um
i'm struggling through my welcome
address so thank you for what very much
for bearing with me and we're gonna have
a brief update from our host huawei
um who graciously even though we moved
the meeting out of bangkok and to vienna
have upheld their commitment to
supporting us so thank you very much for
that
um we're gonna have brief updates from
me about the istf on the isg
i asked robert from the tools team to
talk a little bit about the recent move
to github for some of our made tools
which will allow people to
help with improving them much more
directly than was possible in the past
mir is going to give a brief update from
the iab colin is going to be going to
give a brief update from the irtf
uh jay and jason are going to talk about
the idf llc and glenn is going to talk
about the trust
we have have the usual recognition and
in memoriam session sadly and
we have open mic sessions for the llc
the isg and the iep in that order
with that again thank you to our meeting
host huawei without whom
meetings like this wouldn't be possible
i want to ask ryan from huawei to
say a few words and if you can turn on
your video
yeah
last you hear me
yes
sorry because i tried several times but
but i still cannot get the video
permission i don't know what happened
but anyway
i just want to spend only two minutes to
express welcome and thank you to
everybody here
so
good evening good morning and good
afternoon for
everybody here to join it0113
in person and also online
this is ryan chu from huawei
and i wanted to ask a itf-103
host to spend two minutes to express our
thanks and welcome here
really thanks to all the itf43
participants to for joining the itf
meeting 113 and as well to the aoc iest
the leader
the leadership team for the hard work
and perfect organization arrangement
um i still remember two years ago uh for
itf-107
the first virtual
itf meeting
also huawei was working with aoc and isc
together to
to make the virtual meeting based on the
challenge of the pandemic and now two
years later
uh how is the also uh honored to to host
uh the first uh hybrid meeting
um three
and uh
as i know because i'm not on i'm not in
person i'm still uh
just to join the meeting from beijing
but uh we appreciate that more than 300
percent to join the woman's three in
person it shows that whatever happens
uh the whole ietf community will just
stick together to support the itf
mission to make the internet working
better
and so
again
to want to thank all the itf committee
or the itf community
uh thank you again and please take care
and be safe healthy and enjoy the item
113. and while we still wanted to say
long term to commit and support all itf
community activities here
thank you
everyone thank you ryan thank you huawei
and your commitment
we really appreciate your long-term
commitment to organization and we have a
beautiful wooden plaque or it's actually
going to be a glass black this is the
dummy i'm not trusted with the real one
because apparently i might drop it
um
we're going to make this come to you
somehow and thank you very much
um right uh and again also thank you to
everybody else who made this meeting
happen um
i said it feels like an itf meeting and
it kind of is except for the mask and
some of these other you know corona
specified things but
secretariat has done an heroic job to uh
pull this together and the corona
restrictions in austria were
quite a bit more strict until very
recently and so all the planning went
towards that much more strict type of
meeting
which was um even more work than what we
have now so thank you very much the
secretary of meet echo the knock
all of which
handled the relocation which happened
really late in the cycle from bangkok to
vienna very well
the lrc did a good job the tools team as
always at the hackathon deport great job
thank you
[Applause]
which brings me to the boring part which
is the chair report um
participant statistics and a few other
of the usual suspects we're going to go
through very quickly so we have time for
open mic
we did see an uptick in registration
numbers we are
just under 1400
total
just over 300 onsite in 1100 remote
which is
about in line with the regular
quote-unquote european meeting so we did
see a significant uptick in the last two
weeks to normal numbers
we used almost 250 fee waivers which is
great
allows people that otherwise couldn't
afford to participate to participate
remotely
we're going to continue
the fee waiver program
into the future so there will always be
a
free
remote participation option at itf's
we have 231 hackathon registrations
which considering
you know
134 of those were online so a lot more
of the online people actually rented a
hackathon for 50
uh roughly it's great um and we had a
lot of people participating remotely
statistics by country i think this is
for the total
number of uh participants you can see
it's the usual split more or less and i
think i have an extra slide that i
haven't seen yet
on this breakdown between on-site and
remote so join me looking at this light
for the first time
we have uh as i said 300 people on site
and about 1100 remote
and the breakdown glancing from up here
looks pretty much identical so i don't
know what we learned from that but
apparently the
cove did not keep
some regions of the world further away
than others so that's i guess good um
but
okay i'm getting corrected from the
floor
the colors are different okay
well since i can't read the font
do do what you will with that
information so i guess we will
i will stop analyzing uh things i can't
read
but you can look at these uh in the
minutes
right future meetings um
we have a bunch of different ways so we
have a for a while now i had to support
at itf.org email address which is your
one stop shop for anything goes into the
ticket system and you get directed to
the right person for your request
um if you have something urgent about
the meeting or something else
it's typically a good idea to email that
rather than some random mailing list
where the secretariat is not hanging out
to handle your requests immediately
for tools specifically it's also a good
idea to email tools discuss
um jay is about to send out the post 113
survey which has a bunch of
new questions because it's our first
hybrid meeting
and we do want to know how that worked
for you especially those of you who are
here
but also those of you who are using the
remote tooling for the first time
and we have the shmu working group
that is still meeting as far as i
remember
which is our general generic group that
talks about
meeting related things
right um
we have a few things that are
experiments
or
planned actions
um we have an ongoing um
comment period on the proposal to
archive
discussions between document authors and
the rpc during world 48
um i think it runs until tomorrow so if
you have strong feelings we have a day
to send them
we are constantly
tweaking the way we review buffs
proposals for new work
because they're important
um
so we're scheduling
when you need to submit them by how
we're viewing them so we can give you
feedback we're also
looking at running
more
virtual slash interim buffs and these
are not necessarily new because we've
had them but very rarely in the past and
we recently decided there's specifically
because of the band that make really no
reason to try and have more of those it
seems silly
that proponents of an idea have to work
until the next meeting just to have a
session
and we
discussed that we're going to create
this
important news announcement list which
is going to be very low volume
but we'll also go to everybody with a
data tracker account because we need a
way to communicate with you guys
right um we had zero appeals since the
last itf so
thank you for that
um and we made did one statement on how
you should as an author
um understand when you get isg ballot
position emails um and i think to short
version is don't freak out
um it's not as bad as you think it is
there's a lot more written reports
including ours
at the url there that you can look at
there's also the idf blog
that sort of gets fresh content every
once in a while
that's also worth checking out
and now i'd like to hand over to robert
from the tools team
and i can
try to give you control
except i can't
testing testing
i can hear you i'm just trying to make
you
able to drive the slides
how's this
it looks like it's updating
all right should be able to drive
so hello everyone i'll see if my next
slide
yes as lars mentioned there has been a
lot of activity around
the repositories for the tools that we
use
at the ietf we are completing a project
to move
the largest ones to github
these are on the slide
these are three of nearly 50
repositories that are available in the
ietf tools organization at github
i encourage everyone to go explore all
of them
now that we're at github
we're asking that people use it for
bug reports and feature requests using
the issues and discussion
mechanisms that are at github
and you can also send email to
toolsdiscuss at ietf.org which is a
backstop for people that have any any
difficulties um using github for
whatever reason
please take a moment when you can to
read the contributing
document that i've got
on the slide you can find it
linked from the readme from each of the
repositories
that will give you a good overview of of
how you can engage if you want to to
work on the code beyond providing bug
reports and feature requests and
engaging in the discussions and join our
code sprints when you can
watch the tools discuss list for um
when these when these are going to occur
the
tools discuss list is also discuss list
is also a good place to um send code
contributions if for some reason you
have no no
ability to to push things directly to
github
um i'll always be willing to take
patches directly and manipulate things
into the repositories on your behalf
the tools team meets regularly you can
watch for their meetings in the upcoming
meetings calendar and we have a set of
workshops that are are that we're
working on scheduling you can look in
that repository to find out what they're
about
i also wanted to point to a new set of
resources that are available to us at
authors.ietf.org there are
tools up there that describe how to
author how to convert things from
provide tools for converting things from
the authoring formats into the various
rendering formats and doing guests
um we'll also have a bib xml service up
there very soon
um the last comment that i'd like to
make is
look at the discussion on tools discuss
about the work that we're doing on the
way the data tracker looks we're
currently moving very quickly towards a
major update to the look and feel of the
data tracker
you can find information on the tools
discussed list about how to see what
that's going to look like
and help us find any issues in it before
it becomes production if you if you have
the time to contribute
thank you
thanks robert and i think i remember
that the author tools idf drug wallet is
working for many people already it's
still considered better and so if you
find issues please report them it's much
better than the old tool that we had
already but i think there's still some
things that are still being improved so
thanks for that
and um i think next i'm going to hand
over to miriah who gives the iab report
and do i need to take back
control here
i have control
yes hello everybody
um i'm also very happy to be here see
you all in person um i don't know if you
recognize but i've been the ib chair for
two years and this is my first time i'm
standing here so very exciting
um hopefully next time we will see even
more faces in person again we're excited
about that
um and we're excited to be here to work
together with all of you
um given um this is quite quite early
for plenary for us but quite late for a
lot of people online again i will be
trying to be very quick i only have a
few slides
my first slide is as usually all the
other information that i don't tell you
here today are in the report so you can
pick them from the proceedings and read
them yourself
um and i'm only reporting a little bit
here on like the important admin stuff
but if you're actually interested what
the iab is doing otherwise interested in
engaging with some technical and
technical discussion with the iab we
have the iab open session tomorrow so
there will be a little bit more
reporting tomorrow about what we
actually do and there will be a
discussion about centralization or
actually how to encounter centralization
um tomorrow so it would be great to see
you all there
um maybe not all of you because it's a
smaller room but many of you
oh sorry now i skipped some slides
yeah i slip and skip this important
slide so one of the big announcements
today is that we have a new independent
submission editor um the iab recently
appointed elliot lear to
take over this position unfortunately he
is not here today um but i'm sure you
maybe had a chance to meet him online
there were office hours and hopefully we
will see him next time again and like
he's pretty well known to many of you i
think otherwise all i can give you at
this point is this photo here
um and i would also like to take the
opportunity to say thank you to adrian
again um i already announced last time
that he decided to step down after i'm
four years and so this transition had
just happened recently he already
stepped down he's unfortunately also not
here so like again no chance to have a
nice dinner with him and but we will
ship him some chocolate from here
so we got we got this extra large box
for you adrian
okay one more thing i would like to take
a few minutes for
is to announce the outcome of the iab
program that is designing a new rfc
editor model because this program has
basically concluded at work it's still
open if we need to and pick up anything
again but effectively we are done here
and the new model has quite changed
quite quite a bit
i've presented a few hints about this at
the last plenaries already um but if you
want to know all the details you
probably have to read the document so
we'll not go through this here i just
wanted to report back where we are
and the status is um that the the
program is basically ready with their
work and handed it to the iab we already
had like a four week community feedback
call
and we got a lot of feedback because we
were reached out to many community
members and asked for previews actively
to make sure
people are aware and we have considered
all different angles
and we got a lot of good feedback
fortunately we didn't get any like big
issues out of that i mean there were
definitely some concerns
but nothing that we didn't discuss that
lengthy in the program already and
nothing that we didn't consider so the
bunch of clarifications and make sure
we're going in the right direction here
so the iab has also reviewed
the last version um
which was like just published a few days
ago was like the last editorial changes
and effectively approved this document
what we're doing right now is we're
actually waiting for three additional
documents um that are small updates to
existing process documents that are
going through the ietf stream these have
effectively also
been proved by the ihg to a certain
extent already but one of the documents
we missed something as always so there
will be another working uh itf last call
and that's what we're waiting for
but um yeah to make the message short is
like we're done and we're heading
forwards and thank you everybody who was
involved because that was quite a big
effort at the end thanks to the chairs
to the editor of the document everybody
being involved in the discussion all the
reviewers
i think
it's good to see that we work
productively together and get this done
yeah and this is my last slide also as
usually
an opportunity to thank those people
that we appoint into different positions
we already have selected somebody for
the iso board of trustees but we will
wait for the announcement um to
coordinate with isaac respectively so
this is still a secret
um but i can thank um peter
who has been reappointed to the icann
technical esau group to taking over this
position again or keeping this position
and then this is also always a good
chance for us
to
tell you about our open calls do you
want to say something less
the mic is not even
on mike is not working
about that it's not on there
[Music]
it's on there
yeah but i see like this is very
important to last so i make sure i point
it out carefully
um
we have two open calls one is for the
icann root server systems government
working group and now jared wants to say
something but the mic is still not
working yeah
maybe it'll maybe it'll work but i'm i'm
guessing that in the future we may need
to use a larger font size for the future
ietf meetings
it's i think it's this green background
color which is irritating here
okay let me start again because that is
important for the iap
um so we have two open calls uh one is
for the i can root server government
working group um so this group is that
isn't supposed to be around forever
um but we're looking for somebody um
committing to kind of work until the end
of this kind of project which will be
you know who knows it's like the idea no
nobody has deadlines but it will be in
commitment for like one or two years
hopefully
um
ted was serving us in this position
but because the process got delayed um
he's not able to take this position up
anymore so we're really looking somebody
who can be engaged in this important
process and thanks for ted serving in
this position
and then now lars
we have another open call
together with the ihg we are looking for
two people to share the new rfc series
working group that was the outcome of
the program that i just talked about
um and this is also very important
because it's a very new process uh so
we're looking for people who can engage
there
and help the community to move forward
in this so if you're volunteering for
that as always
send us an email or propose people who i
think are qualified
um or talk to
people and convince them that they
should put their name in
okay that's it from my site
okay colin will be next up and i should
have switched to the next slide but you
can do it yourself now
uh yes
hi uh can i just check the sound that's
working
yes we can hear you
okay thank you maria uh this uh this is
the the irtf report um my name is uh
colin perkins i'm the irtf chair
um what i wanted to do is just very
briefly uh mention a couple of
activities the irtf is involved with
running which are unrelated to the the
research groups that we also run
the first of these is the applied
networking research prize which we've
run in conjunction with the internet
society
and with sponsorship from comcast and
nbc universal
the applied networking research prize is
here to recognize uh some of the best
recent results in
applied networking research uh it's here
to recognize some interesting new
research ideas which
may be of uh eventual uh
relevance to the standards community
and it's here to to recognize upcoming
people that are likely to have an impact
on the the internet standards and
technologies going forward
we
uh made two uh a rp applied networking
research prize awards uh during the irtf
open meeting yesterday um these went to
uh sangeeta abdul jyoti
who had a really nice paper on the the
resilience of the internet
infrastructure to uh solar super storms
uh and to bruce uh bruce spang uh who
also had some really good work showing
that uh network uh a b testing
algorithms can be biased uh in the the
presence of network congestion
as i say these were two really excellent
talks um if you're interested in these
topics i would encourage you to take a
look uh the talks are available on the
irtf website uh and the full version of
sangeeta's talk is there and a shorter
version of bruce's talk
uh and the the recordings of the full
talk should also be available on the the
ietf channel on youtube
in uh addition to the uh
the prizes uh we also run the applied
networking research workshop uh in
conjunction with acm sitcom
uh the
2022 version of this workshop uh will
co-locate with the uh july iatf meeting
uh i'm pleased to announce that uh tj
chung from virginia tech uh and marwan
fired from cloudflare
have
agreed to co-chair that workshop
the call for papers uh went out
yesterday and is on on the um the
website
um and please do uh consider submitting
your work if you're doing research
that may be relevant uh as i say it's a
it's a forum for for those to
present new work uh related to applied
networking research
uh and the the deadline for submissions
there is the end of april
okay and that's everything i have i will
now
pass over to i guess jay is coming next
thank you
thanks colin um hi i'm jay daley i'm the
ihf executive director
um you've probably seen me in all of the
plenaries but last time in person was
singapore in 2019 my first in-person
meeting
so to kick off for the llc part of
things
first of all thank you to huawei our
global host and meeting host
as lars said they've been
very very helpful to us over a long
period now
it's
it's difficult i think for many
organizations to understand what value
they get from sponsoring a meeting that
is has lower in-person attendance where
you don't know what who's going to be
here
you don't know what um exposure you get
but why i have taken the risk with us a
couple of times now and that's very much
appreciated thank you
um and a big thanks to cisco and juniper
and
cisco through webex meetings for their
equipment and services sponsorship
the
i don't if you know this but the value
of the equipment we get off these people
is extraordinary it really does help us
so
run the meetings and do all sorts of
things with that
and also a special shout out to
hurricane electric and some of the other
people that also provide us equipment
and services to help things in the
background
work for this meeting and for this year
we have akamai and cisco who are our
goal diversity inclusivity sponsors this
is
good to find that we have people who are
as well as sponsoring us for specific
meetings are also um helping sponsor us
uh on a values basis throughout the year
um very much helps us um work throughout
that year
and
uh huawei are also a silver sponsor for
diversity inclusivity so thank you for
that
and then we have the domain name
industry steaming in here with verisign
donuts and cn nick as bronze sponsors on
the diversity inclusivity and the
running code side of things so thank you
very much for that
and then finally a special
shout out to next layer who are the
local company who have provided the
network here who offered to do all the
letters of invitation and have been very
helpful
doing a lot of work for us thank you
very much next layer
so um
as lars said we have a lot of volunteers
who come and give their time on the um
code sprint on saturday we had a whole
bunch of people who participated there
thank you very much um it's a
very very serious room when you go into
the code sprint it's not
quite the same as the hackathon shall we
say you know um
people take it very seriously and get a
lot of stuff done i'm impressed at how
quickly people can adapt to that
and the knock um
so thank you very much the people are
not and also thank you to their
employers who um allow them to dedicate
their time to do things and to create
the um 650 different networks that itf
participants require that's absolutely
fantastic thank you
and there are as you probably know some
dashboards around that shows the stuff
from the knock
that you might find useful to look at
we um as we're now meeting again we've
been able to take the secretary out of
deep freeze and they're back here so
thank you very much secretariat um for
running an excellent meeting again
um
and uh thank you also for our covid
officer who's been ensuring that we'll
wear our masks at the right times
we um on the we have on the knock side
we have uh the contract and crew from
line speed thank you and of course we
have meet echo who are here in numbers
to help support us and to um get the
best from the product thank you
the
on our tools team we have uh a
a set of contractors who are um
dedicated to all the tall side of things
and then uh the llc staff and we have a
number of the llc staff here as well so
um please come up and say hello to meet
us
iatf114 will be in philadelphia
um i expect a minimum of 1 500 people to
attend please um
and um there will be plenty of
opportunities for doing rocky poses on
steps and things okay i shall ensure
we'll just have a photographer that if
necessary so please come along um i
think you know i'm very glad that you
all made the effort to come here that's
been very helpful and for all the people
online um you know try to come to
philadelphia if you can so that we can
make this into a um
you know a very much bigger meeting in
person that'd be great for us
so
the
the bulk of our um meeting funding comes
from our global hosts and global
supporters
these are companies that sign up to us
for um six or nine years
give us um money every year towards that
and then host these meetings and without
them really we could not run the
meetings they're extraordinarily
generous so thank you to cisco thank you
to comcast ericsson huawei juniper nbc
universal and nokia um
your commitment is tremendous
particularly over the long terms it's
very difficult for i think for people to
get budgets in corporates to last this
long and they do so i'm very impressed
by that thank you
so these are our upcoming meetings um we
have philadelphia then we have london
in uh later in the year in november
we
uh
[Music]
still working on um asia for 116. we
hope to have an announcement about that
soon it's it's a bit
complicated because of um covid to
come make contractual arrangements with
hotels the um
to put it bluntly they don't believe
that we're not going to cancel so it's
just taking a bit of time for us to
arrange these things but hopefully that
will be arranged soon we have san
francisco one of the rearranged meetings
um
prague and then asia which we're looking
at um
uh one of the moved meetings from and
vancouver which was a move meeting so we
we are filling up the pipeline of
meetings coming forward we are still
interested in new ideas and new places
to go to and things or old ideas and old
places to go to um for example i'm told
that london has been completely rebuilt
and we probably won't lose that many of
you there this time so um you know
please let us know your favorite
locations
right the registration numbers
i think those might be slightly out
actually so um
we'll look at those later lars figures
are the ones that believe on that
currently
right so this is um us the staff
that's me approximately 25 years ago on
the left but why would i change the
picture and then we have greg wood over
there our director of operations lee
berkeley shaw our director of
development casara one of our software
developers is somewhere in the room and
nick is another software developer who's
not joined us this time
right so a small thing about the itf
endowment so the intf endowment is um
created to support the iotf and its um
activities in the long term to create
long-term sustainability
we are basically trying to raise money
so that then
at some point in the future it would be
possible to live off the interest of all
the the investment income from the
endowment if that's the case
it gives us a diversity of income makes
us not reliant on any particular funder
or and not reliant on any particular
industry or
set of companies in that way it's
something we would like to get to and we
have a goal of trying to raise 50
million us dollars by 2027.
this is particularly useful particularly
helped at the moment by a commitment
from the internet society to match fund
any donations we get so um on the first
12 million
we get a two to one match funding and
then on the subsequent six million we
get a um one-to-one match funding so uh
internet society could end up giving us
30 million of us raising 80 million 18
million so that's a huge amount that
really is
very useful for us so if you um
uh can uh help persuade your companies
in any way to please help us then please
let us know certainly um but 2021 donors
are
we had ripe um thank you laknik and
google and over a dozen individual
donations including some very generous
ones from individuals
so thank you very much and in total we
raised you know 239 000 us dollars which
with the match gives us um seven hundred
and eighteen thousand
so um
and
uh lee berkeley shaw over there waving
is our director of government if you
have a spare million or two or your
company is looking for um some way of
showing that it properly is investing in
the internet which is the person to
speak to thank you very much
okay i'm going to hand over to jason
who
i do not see on the list of participants
oh i've got it here yeah i
have to hand over the slides i've got it
perfect
looks like it's passed over to me
successfully i think
um so thank you um jay appreciate your
presentation and thanks everyone for
attending whether
in person or virtually
this will be a brief
itflc update
so should be pretty easy
this has not
changed since the last meeting these are
the folks that serve on the board
thank you for all of their time as
volunteers
these are the upcoming meetings that we
have scheduled right now
you know april may june basically
monthly the meetings are completely open
so you're welcome to join we do have
open q a during the public part um so
certainly feel free to join if you're
not able to join at a particular time
you can also send questions in and so on
and we're also working on as i'll
mention
shortly planning a
strategic planning retreat and as with
prior years we'll have large sections of
time where
people can observe and ask questions and
so on
so in terms of the current work things
that we have
recently completed this year since the
last meeting or are currently working on
we've made changes to the investment
policy following recommendations from
our financial advisors goldman sachs
in essence um increasing our exposure to
equity investments
and also
considering the possibility of private
equity investments over time
uh similar to many other nonprofit funds
we've also been working obviously on
this meeting um working with the
executive director jay and all of the
other folks here in particular the noc
team
to make sure that the first hybrid
meeting got carried off all right and uh
be very much looking forward to feedback
because i think
as probably lars said at the beginning
you know this is a model that will
likely persist for some time
and
you know making it work great for both
in-person and on-site
uh and remote excuse me participants is
important
number three we've been assessing
potential policy needs and changes
related to antitrust
there's been some list discussion about
that of course
and we're inching closer and closer to
uh to sort of a final decision on some
of those things
so stay tuned
uh and of course as i think jay may have
noted he's relocated now
um to the united kingdom to london area
uh greater london from new zealand and
so we've had to do a bunch of
you know legal and benefits changes with
our employment management company
and lots of odd you know inter
sort of legal changes but you know
important stuff to get right to take
care of our employees like jay
we're all obviously also planning the
annual
strategic planning retreat we should
have some dates out fairly soon
and again as i noted welcome
participation and we've been increasing
focus on fundraising so that
fundraising topic is now on our monthly
agenda and it's something that we are
focusing on
all the time to see
that we're making maximum use of that
isoc program
in terms of prior fiscal year operating
budget
um
this will look a lot better as we enter
into 2022 because we had this sort of
outstanding accounting
issue with the way that isoc funding got
recognized last fiscal year or two
fiscal years ago excuse me
so last fiscal year ends up looking odd
we'll have audited results um you know
in the relatively near future
and you know everything is
uh generally uh on track i think we've
continued to weather the coveted 19
disruptions fairly well
um but again a lot of the the weird
variances that we see are just due to
this one-time isoc thing and that is
should not be an issue for this fiscal
year so it'll be easier to read our
financial statements
and of course these are all the ways
that you can get in contact with us
feel free to reach out at any time on
any subject
in any of these these different ways
that you'd like and of course lots of
different web page
links here in terms of meeting minutes
financial statements
and so on
so thank you with that i'm going to pass
it over to glenn
hello
everybody it looks like uh you have
control awesome hi i'm glenn dean uh
from comcast nbc universal i am the
chair of the icf trust
so these are the five trustees um they
are selected by the eye tip nom com one
of them is selected by the icy border
trustees and one is selected by
um the iesg and we've been the same sort
of group now for a few years which is
good because uh having trustees around
there sort of know the lay of the land
it's
always good to have people
that they're well engaged and well aware
of the background
um these are some boilerplate plate
slides because a lot of people you know
don't really know what the trust does
we're a pretty quiet bunch
and that's a good thing because we deal
with legal stuff and when legal things
are nice and quiet uh that's the ideal
situation uh but basically we hold ip
assets this is like copyrights and uh
trademarks and domains and software
licenses uh on behalf of the itf ayanna
icann
and and water internet related
activities uh and we make sure these
things are protected and and
uh freedom used as appropriate uh but
also that we don't accidentally lose
control of them uh through some slippage
around you know not complying with laws
and jurisdictional requirements uh we're
a currently a virginia common trust uh
we're a non-profit
uh and uh as i said we have five
trustees and we're a small group well
the budget is about a hundred thousand
dollars uh keep it light keep it tight
and most that goes towards legal fees
what i want to talk to you today about
though is that the trust is having a bit
of a problem
and it revolves around uh insurance uh
trusts when we were created back in 2005
have evolved a lot and
we historically carry
a lot of insurance on our professional
liability and directors and officers
insurance to protect the trustees when
you sign up to be a trustee uh because
of the nature of trust trustees
literally own the trust they are the
owners of all the assets of the trust
and they are
themselves uh
their personal liabilities are
intertwined
with the uh the trust and its assets and
the activity so if the trust gets sued
uh one of the consequences of trustees
themselves can be named as part of the
the suit so we hear a lot of good
insurance on that to protect the people
that volunteer to become trustees
all trustees are not compensated they're
all volunteers
and we've run into a problem the last
few years we've tried to increase the
amount of coverage uh through our
insurance broker uh to a level that is
appropriate for both inflation and the
legal risk that we see in the landscape
the trouble is that uh the market for
insurance providers for trusts uh really
is very limited uh there's a very few
companies that provide it
and those that do provide like the one
we currently use aren't interested in
increasing the limits uh part of this is
because the trusts are very often these
days used for other activities such as
real estate holdings uh generational
wealth management uh tax
efficiency uh and not so much use for
uh what we do protecting you know the
the ip materials for the itf and the
other parties that we work with so this
has created a problem for us we we've
been scratching our heads about how to
uh deal with this for the last few years
and uh so we're looking at the landscape
and maybe making some changes to the itf
trust structure
relating to this is as i mentioned the
individual trustee liability um
the current structure of the trust
because the trustees themselves own the
trust and all the assets they themselves
take on a lot of legal liability and in
fact when you become a trustee
we give you a document that says hey
read this over and by the way don't just
read this and sign it quickly read this
over it has a lot of stuff you are
taking on
and uh you know anecdotally we know
there are people within the itf
community that have seriously considered
being a trustee
looked at this and said oh no no no
that's uh i'm not going to take on that
personal liability um for myself the
risk is just too high
and so we've been sort of trying to
figure out the path forward given these
two key issues that are causing us
you know personal liability
making our pool of trustee candidates
smaller
and
proper insurance levels to make sure the
ones that do get selected and served are
well protected
and one of the things we've observed is
that while trusts have a lot of these
problems
uh corporations don't
and
it breaks down to the corporations have
within the legal frameworks uh that they
operate under more protection for
directors because directors aren't
owners they're just demoted to
uh from the owner down to a person
serving to help run the corporation
and uh they have more legal liabilities
that help
them along with there's a very large
insurance market that will provide
insurance coverage to such entities
so
we're exploring the possibility of
restructuring the ihf trust on a legal
basis
into a not-for-profit corporation from a
trust
now
in reality very little would change
awkwardly if we did this right all the
trust's current assets would just
transfer over to the new entity
all the current licenses we do and the
way we do them and the way we make them
available for people to use would all
transfer as well
we're going to demo the trustees though
they get demoted to just be directors no
longer would they be owners
uh and we would also move from virginia
uh probably to delaware where the united
states is very popular to doing
corporations um
the itf llc for instance is in fact uh
based in delaware
uh
what would not change
the role and service to the itf and all
the other communities that make use of
the trusts assets would not change in
any way
licenses would stay the same and we
would continue to be a 501c3 entity so
non-profit
as well the other thing we're not going
to change is how the trustees are
selected uh or in this case the new
directors would be selected uh there
would be still be five of them the
selection process would still follow the
process you know by 80 uh rfc 87
um but it was just the legal definition
of how we're registered as an entity
that would basically trust it changed
so that's pretty big delay in the
community
um
there's an obvious question why don't we
just fold this under the itf llc we went
all the work
in
uh you know to create it uh why don't we
just fold over and i won't go into this
slide in detail but there are
some dependencies upon the trust being
an independent entity uh that has been
established from the very beginning uh
and along with some requirements that
uh because the llc is associated with
isak as a
um
as an entity uh officially you know
disregarded uh entity by eyestock um
transferring the assets of the trust to
the llc would effectively be given an
arms
uh length relationship to isoc
and both the original founding agreement
from 2005
had a particular restriction that that
can't be done with the trust's assets
uh and then later on in 2016 when we did
the ia transition and the trust took on
some service diana and i can communities
uh that was done with the expectation
that the trust was an independent entity
so we've looked at this we don't think
this is an option
so we've
been looking at this we've been
consulting with attorneys and so we're
going to do is the following we are
going to open up a consultation with the
communities that make use of the trust
this includes the itf
i can uh the ir rars
we're going to use the tlp interest list
over the idf.org
for comments and questions and we're
going to hold a multi-hour webinar in
april uh for anybody's interested in
this topic to come and talk
we're going to explain why we're
thinking of what we're going to do how
it would look and then open for
discussion uh you know opinions concerns
ideas uh we want to hear from people
we're not just going to go off and do
this you know in a vacuum uh this is a
community conversation to have uh to
figure out what the right path forward
uh for the the trust and for the assets
that managers are
and with that
here's how you can contact us in general
and i will pass it on to
lars
thanks glenn this is again very hot uh
thank you and we're coming to the
recognition of the outgoing leadership
part of the
um
agenda and jared will be happy to hear
that the the rumors of my diminishing
eyesight are vastly over exaggerated but
my glasses do up when i wear a mask
so i actually did not see that thing on
the slide earlier
i'm very sorry but everybody's paying
attention that's great um right
first up is the outgoing iab members
[Music]
yeah and we have um two outgoing ib
members that i would like to to thank
for a service today both of them have
served for two years
on the iab so they have been fully
virtual iep members
um
i think that was challenging and i i at
least had still a good time working with
them
i would like to start with jared because
he is actually here in prison so at
least i had finally a chance to meet him
in person after two years of only online
meetings
um we had a couple of chats online as
well so i do have the feeling i actually
know you well but it's not the same
um and so i'm happy that we at least met
at this very last meeting
um i think um despite the challenges we
had the last two years with the wichita
virtual setup it was great to have you
on the iab
you have strong opinions very often but
but it's uh it's good to have different
angles and and we had some discussions
uh we we do agree on a couple of points
but sometimes also disagree and it's
very important for the iab to have all
these different views in the discussion
and make sure we represent in this way
also a little bit the community
so in order you will to remember your
time at the ibb we brought you a little
present um so this is it you can come up
if you want
um this is the water bottle which is
branded for you with the ieb dot on here
so you will never you use it
so that's for you excellent thank you
and
and we brought you a little bit of
chocolate as well smaller pocket than
adrian but that's also for you
[Applause]
yeah i took jared first um because ben
we also got you a bottle and we will
ship it to you and of course you will
also get some chocolate from vienna
so um ben as i just said was also on the
iab for two years
at least for me it was a little bit
easier because i was serving together
with ben on the ihd already so i know
him very well he has always been a very
very kind person and
contributed to discussion always in a
common kind way he was always there to
pick up any tasks if needed
and so we would definitely also miss you
on the iab ben
and i hope very much that next time we
will see at a meeting we will have a
nice dinner together and chat about past
times a little bit more thank you very
much ben
[Applause]
all right
i will hand
we'll do the isg recognition next but
first i want to say actually ben was
also the liaison and during the last
year at least to the iesg and so we've
worked with him as well and ben
has written some of the best uh short
reports from the isg from the iasg and
what the delaware from the i to the iab
on what the isg is doing
and they're so good that i actually
internally forward them to my boss and
say this is what i did this week and
there's always like three things that i
forgot about but ben didn't forget it he
put them in it's a nicely bulleted list
and it's been extremely useful in
whoever we get and we need we need that
level of reporting was excellent uh so
thank you ben also from the isg
um which brings us to a
slide i don't see here but i see it
there which are the outgoing isg members
uh benjamin kadek uh for the security
area and mata vigorous for the trans the
transporter is wrong he was routing
um so
testing me here huh i'm awake
so marta for the for the riding area
um some of you in the audience have done
this job and some of you uh remotely
have done this job and you know it's
often
thankless um and
both of them
are unfortunately not here so
when the open mic later on gets boring
maybe take a minute and send them a
message and thank them for their service
because while it can be you know not
often fun to argue with an ad who has
requests for you as an author i think
that the reviews actually do help make
the documents better and we need people
like that are willing to serve and
ask to hide questions and do the work so
thank you very much ben and my turn
[Applause]
and with that i want to pass over to
john
me the um you can actually just forward
it too either way
i think i'm giving you control
yeah there we go
so
susan
r harris
it was always susan
never sue and the r is really important
because she worked with both susan hares
and another susan harris
so susan r harris she passed away
on march 6 after a short and um and
she'd probably have said inconvenient
battle with cancer
susan was an outstanding writer and nerd
whisperer
and
in the days before
everyone knew that of course the
internet was going to be a big deal
she was instrumental in explaining it to
decision makers who
needed to know that this was important
stuff
she played a key part in getting nanog
off the ground
as it evolved from the earlier nsf net
regional text group
she authored a number of important rfcs
notably the dao of iatf the discussion
list charter
her license plate was rfc 3005
the guidelines for conduct
her keen skills as a writer
and editor were complemented
by her
dry self-deprecating wit
and her generosity of spirit
she was a good co-worker collaborator
colleague
and a friend
i'll miss her
i know many of you will too
thank you
thank you john that was great
and we will miss her
um next up is the open mic for the llc
so those of you who are in the room
would you please make your way to the
stage and those of you who might have
questions for the llc make your way to
the microphones and please use the
on-site tool or the full version of
mitecho to insert yourself into the
queue and you can probably see if you
are close to being up and
if you are make your way to a microphone
thank you and i can't see the queue
other than there but i see barry go
ahead
hi this is barry lieber
jay i want to thank you for
relocating to london
in preparation for our meeting there
making sure that you're local and
helping out and i expect you to continue
your nomadic life as we make up meetings
in in bangkok and and madrid so you know
but that's not why i got up i wanted to
talk about the um
a bit about the ietf endowment
for a moment the um
we are now
for several meetings had an option on
the registration to donate a little
money to the ietf and
i've been doing that for the last few
meetings and since it's been available
and it's an easy way to chuck a few
extra bucks there and i was talking with
lee berkeley during the hackathon and
she said now that money is going to the
endowment so it's getting the benefit of
the matched funds from isoc
so i just wanted to encourage everybody
to take advantage of that it's just easy
check check the box whatever put in a
put in however much you can throw at us
and continue supporting the ietf
financially as well as technically
thanks
thank you perry that was that was great
um i didn't hear a question but that's
okay
um do we have somebody else queuing up
i don't think so
okay this was very short thank you very
much
up next is the isg
and this is where you hand over the dots
so i think that might be the next slide
no but we'll do it anyway um i have a
role so so if you're misbehaving you
might also get stuck with one of these
later on in the bar but for now we have
a new incoming security area director
who gets his dot
which is paul waters and um
andrew alston is a writing id who is not
able to be here but andrew we're going
to hold your dot for the retreat and
we're going to stick it on you there
thank you both for joining us and
serving
[Music]
right and uh i think we go down from
paul and uh tell us who you are
are the online um sorry the secret
language of the itf has become german in
case you weren't aware yet um
so
fair fair point miriah
[Music]
i think in the interest of camera
fiddling we're going to unfortunately
skip the online people but i think for
those of you in the room it would be
nice to do the traditional let's go down
the table
so let's do that paul
paul vargas incoming security
uh robleton and i'm the ops management
id
routing
warren kumari opsedy
martin duke transport
irrigating
and i do see andrew up there on the
screen so since he's the other incoming
area director andrew why don't you
introduce yourself
you muted
so uh can you can you
finish this table though
transported
this is not my day um
andrew please
you're still muted
while andrew is trying to unmute you i
will tell you that he sent me a message
on the slack saying is there a way for
my wife to watch this without being
registered and i said yes there's a
youtube link and then he went downstairs
to give her the link and she said she
invited a whole bunch of friends over
and they're having a party to see me
become an air director
which is great
so i hope you enjoy your party and and
do you have audio now
uh i'm hoping we've got audio
yes you do
ah
ending austin incoming routing id
thank you and uh remote we have uh
murray from art we have um
john from uh routing
we have uh
roman from
transport what are you doing with
transport why is it
roman
who is not in transport but in security
uh we have eric klein who is in ind we
have van gater who's outgoing for
security
uh rob wilton's here warren kumar is
here okay that's it i think
questions
oh yeah
martial's outgoing
questions for the iesg please
do we have people in the queue
i think you guys forgot how this works
i mean
don't remind them
i'll take it but i'm confused
okay
no questions for the isd at all
so be it
thank you thank you
and up next is the iab please
okay i hope that doesn't mean we get all
the questions now
yeah please come up um
yeah we will try to do the same so
we start on this side yari
just for some change
david schnazzy internet architecture
enthusiast
okay and then i will try to read you um
the online people but you also have them
on the stream so we have van is outgoing
we have deborah there wes is with us
colin
um senben
we david you're here
we have tommy russ giancan
colin as the irtf chair
john should be with us um as the inter
temporary rfc series editor mallory new
incoming iab member and chin also new
incoming ib member
and now
we would take questions
ah we have one
person in the room even perfect
same problem every single time uh lars
c1 lee man from that note this is not
actually a question but of
uh offering my my um
as a volunteer uh
you mentioned before that you're looking
for a volunteer
to sit on the
roof service system governance working
group i think thank you very much i
think you have to write us an email for
that
i'm already on it that's
that's the point if anyone on here wants
to know anything about what's going on
in that working group i think i'm the
only member actual member from that
working group
there you are sir i forgot so there at
least two of us here then so
if you want have any questions about
that come and see me um i won't offer
you without your
consent but i'm here if you want to talk
about it
okay thank you thank you for showing
showing your face so people can thank
you um yeah this is definitely
thank you yes
yes this is definitely a position where
we were really looking for a qualified
um volunteer who can um bring in some
knowledge and and help guiding the
process there
so i just like to comment one of the
things that's always a
unique challenge is there's a lot of
positions the iab does end up appointing
for
and so
definitely
talk to your local iad member
including you know i'm willing to answer
questions well about stuff
so we're always looking you know we've
always been looking for good candidates
for many of the positions so if you have
extra time
please let us know
yeah that's also a good point so it's
like
some of these positions we need very
specified expertise so it's not like a
huge set where you should drawing from
and it's always hard to find a diverse
set of candidates and also selecting
people who might bring into
some more diversity and so some of these
sports so the more volunteers we have
for any of these positions the better
you really really want to go out and
enjoy life there right yeah and me too
it's fine
okay three
two
one
thank you everybody
[Applause]
yes
you all look very confused
oh
so yeah
um
[Music]
uh
i
okay
thank you
is
lovely
[Music]
you