now i have the control yes
and what happens when we're done with
this
how do we pass do you pass control back
or does it always stay with us
as well
say again pascal
as a chair you can
the control that you gave you just take
it back
so there's i'm at the chair right now so
i can't see the button
i mean you can say back
i've seen the time
let's let's uh let's
start so um
let's find the chair slides
excellent
um so good morning everybody um it is
morning local time
this is raw reliable and available
wireless uh so we are
doing a full hybrid experiment here by
having the chairs both remote and uh
karina and carlos standing in being our
in-room delegates so thank you very much
to both of them for trying it
um
i think we have more chairs and
delegates that we have attendees in
person but um
celebi uh hopefully this will change
over time so can i eve can i have the
next slide please or can i just take
control
i think you can just take control
but let me
pause this like
there you go
thank you very much so uh ietf note well
i do hope you are familiar with the
noteworld at the moment um having
attended uh a few of these
meetings before if you are unfamiliar
this is uh your
rights uh so important things
contributions covered by patents and
patent applications uh participation you
are agreeing to be recorded
um
there's also the personal information
handling by the ietf and
your agreement to behave respectively
respectfully uh in
association with others
so please
read this information uh in depth at
your leisure if you are unfamiliar with
it otherwise please be aware that this
meeting like any other working group
meeting um
operates under the ietf note well
and here are the exact um
bcps which cover the the fine details so
there's a record here
so ietf113 this is a hybrid meeting
which is exciting uh i can see a lot of
people are participating remotely but if
you are on site and i do have a view of
who's in the room uh there is an on-site
tool so that we can integrate the
meeting queue with uh the remote queue
um
and we'll see how well that goes i mean
meet echo i think has turned into a
really elegant tool over the last couple
of years so i'm confident that this will
work well
um key things is in-session participants
please keep your audio and video
off if not using the on-site version
not 100 sure what that means but that i
assume is to reduce echo from the room
as you can tell we're in quite a large
echoey room in vienna
but it's not destroying the audio too
much for me
i apologize if anyone else is having
terrible feedback
uh right administrative yeah so uh yep
this is obviously on meat echo i'm
assuming everyone is on meat echo
although i suppose you could be
connecting via jabba um but there is the
url for the meat echo uh automatic blue
sheets so the days of pen and paper have
passed um
or are there blue sheets in the room
carlos and karina
no
um so
we seem to have lost kodi md but we now
have hedge dock built into um
the meet echo ui
so we would like to do collaborative
notes if there is someone who is willing
to act as an interactive
note taker that would be great but
please
everybody join in to
make sure
a any um
spellings of names are correct because
there are a combination of different
languages and different names so please
make sure that that whoever is taking
notes has got your name right that's
very handy and also double check that
the point you were trying to make was
captured correctly so
anything you can do
in that way would be great
um
so the mating list as usual is raw at
iatf.org you should please subscribe to
that if you're interested in the
proceedings of raw and the meeting
materials for this session so that it's
the slides and the agenda and so on are
all at the url at the bottom
uh right i'll hand over to eve at this
point because i seem to have spoken for
five minutes
off the cuff
oh well i was going to say that due to
the hour
where i live it is about 2 a.m um i'm
likely to be quite silent during the
meeting and i will be taking notes so
please join me i see that there are a
few others on here so thank you very
much
our agenda is quite full today we
are going to hear from
um
nils on the status of the ldx
draft which is wending its way through
review
and we also just
had the use cases draft submitted and
carlos will give us an update
after it reached
working goose group last column was also
submitted to
uh for for formal review
pascal will give us um
an update on the architecture draft
which
after the last itf was separated from
the framework draft
and we will hear about both of their
status
and then
we have some
an update on the oam support draft which
of course has its
mirror drafts in the debt networking
group as well we will hear from forbids
on the status of that and carlos will
come back to us to speak about a new
draft that he has submitted for
consideration on multi-domain extensions
we do have a bit of
additional time so we're we don't have
to stay entirely within our limits
because of course discussion is
the
main point of having these meetings so
we welcome your questions comments
and inputs
all right
thanks steve uh if he is available uh
should we go straight on fell back or
does anyone wish to pass the agenda just
very quickly checking the
queue
no pretty
if you're available or
excellent
uh
i believe we're going to be the magic of
if you do request to share slides oh
we're trying to make this slide thing
work
so pass slide control
so i'm talking to myself now while i try
and click buttons which is a little
unprofessional
um
so niels you should have control of
slides
all right
which means you should be able to share
pre-loaded slides
or i cannot
hold on i can't there we go
all right then i cancel my request and
you can share the slides that watched as
well
and if i pass slide control you should
be able to change forwards and back
does that make sense
it's getting there this meets echo it's
pretty good these days so anyway thank
you me checker um
all right good morning everyone i'll be
relatively brief today uh but i want to
talk a little bit about the changes that
we did from the last version 09 to the
version 10 now
uh thanks to john scott we really
received some great feedback that we
incorporated in the draft and i think
the draft is just um
and the pros have been uploaded the
version 10.
so let me just walk you over the changes
um it's a note well
and here are the changes so from the
version 09 to the version 10 uh the
outline basically remained the same we
did some changes in chapter three with
the motivation use cases
then
we adapted some
lines in the requirements section
and i think the the biggest change
happened in the reference section since
we removed a lot from the normative or
basically everything from the normative
to informative references
um since with a little back and forth
with john
we received the feedback that the draft
in itself is completely understandable
without relying on any external
references and the rest is just
additional information for the reader to
really grasp the depth of the work here
additionally in the appendix we had some
changes made to enable the reader to
understand
the requirements imposed by aeronautical
referential documents
and i think with that i walked over all
the changes and now we go in the depth
of each of them
so
in the motivation use cases
um
we weren't clear enough about the
current security concept that is in
place so
um if we look at aeronautical
communications today
and we're talking about terrestrial
based long-range communications
um there's just one system in place
really that's currently rolled out it's
called the video number two that's the
vhf data link mode too
and uh
it was rolled out in the 90s about that
and there are really no cyber security
measures on the link in itself and so
the entire security concept relies on
phraseology
well-trained personnel
pilot and air traffic controller really
knowing each other
but there's no security measures as we
would define it here and essentially had
to clarify that and that is one of the
big differences between the current uh
version of aeronautical communications
and the one we're proposing here with
ldx
um the second one is about the
separation of uh safety
based communications and entertainment
or in-flight entertainment based
communications
and this can so so there's a scenario
that can happen for instance the flight
crew or the pilots they have a
limited data link available meaning they
have around
10 kilobits in in up and down stream
while a passenger can watch netflix in
plain basically but those are different
domains right so one domain is for
communicating safety critical stuff so
basically high reliability and
availability are key so the links are
designed with more robustness in mind
and on the other hand it's just about um
throughput and this is why
uh we have those two concepts and both
of them obviously must be strictly uh
separated and this
also happens with aldex as well
let me
all right so uh that covers chapter
three
in chapter six with the requirements
um we made clear again that there's a
huge change currently happening with
aeronautical communications so until now
most of the stuff was communicated by a
voice
and there's a protocol from the 70s
called a cars
then in the 90s there was the 80 in osi
and since the 2010 um the entire idea is
to
run traffic so aeronautical
telecommunications network traffic via
an id based network and it's also why
we're here with the ietf
and
the envisioned network so it's not
installed in place except for some
experimental
airports
uh is that you have an ipv6 based
network for aeronautical communications
but um
you want to have again separation of
consensus so if you want to have the
aeronautical ip internet so basically
for routing the atm traffic and
obviously you want to have the the
customer internet as separated as much
as possible so that you don't um you're
not able to switch from one to the other
and cause shenanigans
um the second part was about the rollout
so um i think everyone is aware that
with the
uh pandemic everything has um scheduled
a little later than uh was anticipated
so the entire ruler was initially
planned for 2024 and now we're on
2025-26
um
yeah last thing that we
changed again with the references
um
with with a little bit of back and forth
and discussions uh
we
basically adapted the document um to
such a state that if you read the entire
document that you'll be able to
understand what aldex is what it does
and you don't really need additional
information to grasp the concept if you
want to go deeper such as what kind of
modulation schemes are
done how does the file protocol look
like then obviously we point to other
references but it's not necessary to
read them to fully understand the
concept of it
and i think that covers basically all
the changes obviously we changed knits
and bits here and there um some some
rewritten some sentences to make them
better understandable
and yeah um at this stage i just want to
thank uh john um for the really really
the feedback
and um yeah from there
it's just a road down to what comes next
thank you
um i jumped in the queue first there but
actually i wanted to ask a question
really of john and and niels is have we
addressed everything john wants to say
and
uh
addressed all john's comments and are we
ready to move forward so uh i'll shut up
and let john speak
uh yeah so i i went and looked at the
preprint um and it looked like
everything was well covered um
thank you very much
and
um and thanks for writing an easy to
read document by the way
i know that's not easy um
anyway yeah i think we're ready uh so
you know so sometime this week i will
hit the button to start the ietf last
call
and we'll be on our way
excellent thanks john so that's that's
good it looks like we might have our
first raw rfc and it might be ldx but uh
yeah fingers crossed
thank you very much niels so uh thank
you since then i have closed the agenda
so i can't tell you what's happening
next so next up we've got uh if the
oh karina you're in the queue go for it
um
just two questions
references in should we just delete the
section or put
nothing to apply here
oh that's a good question i'm not sure
if there's a convention
for that uh i'm
comfortable with you either removing the
normative references heading or leaving
it empty
either one is okay um the the rfc editor
will fix it to match whatever the
their preferred style is once it gets
into edit
um i guess my my instinct would be to
actually there's an argument either way
so um
my first instinct would be to go ahead
and leave it in sort of as a you know
this space intentionally left blank but
really do as you prefer
karina my my advice would be
the rfc editors are very good at what
they do in terms of editing so
leave the heading there say this section
intentionally left blank and they will
fix it and they will fix it with you
they're very good at it so don't worry
too much about that sort of thing as
long as the content is good they'll
they'll really help you with the rest
it was just a question because i still
need to upload the version 10 because it
was blocked yesterday there too
yeah it's that that strange thing with
our atf where you can't upload until the
meeting starts for one week very bizarre
but um when you can just
no big deal so john i will upload it
within the days it should be online
latest tomorrow
fantastic great thank you thank you
thanks guys
so
uh next up we have carlos with uh the
use cases draft and as carlos is in the
chair i'm just gonna get out of the way
and let him
to do the thing
i was trying to use the
tool to share but anyway i will go to
the old way
sorry about that
i was trying
to use the new feature
but maybe it's easier if i do
okay
one second and i'll be there
yeah that's great we can see that
okay so this is going to be
let me
a very quick update on the raw use cases
so this is the
outline just for for those that may not
be
familiar with the draft there are
several use cases described aeronautical
communications amusement parks wireless
for industrial applications probably on
video wireless gaming uav and b2b
platoonian control edge robotics control
and emergencies
and for each of the drafts we have
different
sections analyzing the motivation for
why we need the use case the need for
wireless for that particular use case
and kind of the requirements for for raw
this is basically the structure per use
case description specific challenges
need for wireless and requirements and
in the last itf iteration we also added
a
subsection for the non-latency critical
considerations because
raw is not only about latency maybe
about latency of course but it may be
also about resiliency
in some scenarios where the latency is
not that critical so we believed based
on some comments from pascal
that was a
important thing to cover in the draft
and we basically
adapted the structure to to highlight
that point as well
then since last atf cycle we got some
very nice and good reviews from pascal
and from korina we think authors that we
address all the comments
from the reviews in the current
iteration so again big thanks for for
the reviewers to to take the time to
provide the comments and to check
everything from
things to clarify
reference to ad and also needs and and
typos that we had to fix
so by doing that we also did some
editorial fixes and improvements along
the way
and in terms of next steps well now it's
um it was publication requested so it's
at the asc
and we're basically waiting for comments
at that at that stage and then we will
try our best to
to address the comments so not really
much to what at this point
any questions comments
i was just going to add a thank you for
getting the document to the state it's
in at the moment and thank you to the
reviewers
um i think obviously charney's is in the
depth of previewing ldx at the moment
and so this is next in his queue when he
has the cycles so
thank you very much
anyone else with comment
excellent um so next up we have uh
pascal who uh is speaking about the
architecture and the framework documents
and the split between the two and so
he's got quite a big time uh slot for
this basically it's pascal knows what
you're doing so um take the time to
split it up as you like
um
go ahead
okay i hope you can hear me i'm sharing
the uh architecture slides and if it
doesn't consume more space i can't send
the video out i guess
there we go
guys um yes so this is about the the raw
architecture document which was uh split
uh between architecture and framework
as we said
um so
i won't go back to this slide which is
basically uh summarizing what we expect
to do uh in very short it's it's a
matter of
uh balancing the use of energy and
spectrum uh the more energetic spectrum
you use the more reliability you get on
your transmissions but um on the other
hand uh you have constrained energy and
constrained bandwidth in the wireless
spectrum so you cannot push
too far on either energy bandwidth so we
have to find
uh engineered methods to to optimize
effectively the balance between how much
reliability and variability we get and
how much energy and bandwidth spectrum
basically we stand we spend getting that
reliability so that's that's a generic
concept for common context forum
now um the initial document had
two main pieces
uh which we kind of split into
architecture and framework one is is
forward-looking it's basically giving
the the broad building blocks and that
includes terminology because if you
don't have a crisp terminology you
cannot go anywhere because we don't even
understand each other so so we need we
need to have a very crisp energy in
which we can build and we we also need
to say hey here is there are the objects
we are manipulating
and and here is what we are trying to
achieve
but without giving
here is why you take that draft and we
are using that protocol because we don't
even know yet
so clearly we position ourselves as
spin-off or maybe hopefully one day you
spin in
of that net
uh
focusing on
wireless and reliability
but exactly which which drafts rfcs will
will be proposed and uh
to achieve role it's it's not the scope
of architecture architecturally says
there is a broad picture of what we
intend to achieve but so it's really
something that we want to publish early
in the
work of this group so so we can have a
terminology and can have goals that we
all understand the agreement
the framework on the other hand
is to be
our
journal if you like i mean following our
progress the more we focus on there is
the technology that we're going to use
uh this draft this rfcs
those will be
how we effectively build our solution
and so the other idea is that the
framework
is
to be read by people who bought the work
in between so they can see where we are
and it will be published at the very end
so as i say testimony of how we do that
i mean this that's basically how it
works it's using this rfc to you know
hopefully everything will be rfc by that
and there are all those rfc interact to
effectively achieve
uh what the architecture was talking
about
so
yeah we have we hope we are close to
workgroup let's call it the architecture
and effectively for the framework we
want to keep it alive until the very end
of the of the work
now
the um
the first thing we need to really agree
about as i said is the terminology and
and we realize uh trying to dig into
what we want to achieve
that there might be a gap and i just
reviewed an excellent review thank you
so much lou uh an email by lou that was
posted this morning on the mailing list
i mean at least alpha these commands are
really related to you know goal to
terminology and then the rest is
obviously the goal and the context but
the basically the terminology will be
very very critical to us on the one hand
we want to
to use you know as much common
terminology as the rest of the ietf so
we don't want to involve a different
term for something that exists which is
kind of a quantum and valuable track
um
on the other hand
when things don't match we want to be
able to differentiate and say hey
um really our understanding of this is
that
and in particular we we have this
problem with path i've been digging
uh the idf a lot of the term path and
that that really troubles me
most of the
path has been used by many many working
groups with ietf and iota
and
the term usually references
not
a a graph really but more like an
experience
like here is the path that this packet
has been following
and that
kind of
yields the notion that the packet has
kept is its integrity from a to b
and that does follow a serial sequence
of nodes and links
a to b to c to d whatever to destination
and we are not doing that
we we are computing a graph
which is a potential
and the path that the packet will follow
it's actually many of them because the
packet may be duplicated
and a packet we may not keep its
integrity if we took some network coding
and we flood
a small graph from a to b
with different network credit fragments
then
yeah the the packet will not even
experience one path it's pieces of the
packet or by-products of the packet
fragmentation and coding will follow
different paths
so so basically
we we we kind of want to keep the the
concept of path to express an experience
there is no everything that was used in
the process of getting that information
from a to
and we call that a complex path because
now it's not as simple as a cereal thing
it's not even the experience of a
packet
because it might have been broken in
pieces
so we we call that that experience a
complex path by you know an energy to a
path
but then then we still need a term
to express
the potential of a packet because what
we are doing really is we are building
this graph from a to b
and then we are using a subset of it
so so the big graph that that exists and
may or may not be
fully or partially
is is not an experience it's a potential
it's it's what you may use it's the
subset of the overall network that is
available to you at the ingress to to
effectively propagate that information
all the way to the destination so we
want to make a difference between that
potential and an actual experience
and that's why
we have this concept of track now uh
i just saw this morning the the
the feedback from lou
how is that different from from a uh
basically a tea
path a protection path for traffic
engineering uh
we need more discussion with lou and see
you know how the terms overlap and if if
track is completely uh within the
concept of of t-pass and protection path
and honestly i don't know
um i've not dug into that and uh
contribution on that term and etc i mean
that would be great uh but for now we
have the definition uh that i have
copied here it's basically
defined as an ios3 abstraction basically
a graph
and that goes from a point a to point b
uh
with uh that net edges uh that net nodes
at the edges
and uh
serial path between the edges uh
operating as segments that join the
edges so the vertices are serial path
uh
uh operating at as i said that the dead
next player
could be actually at the four okay i i
need to check that term because uh for
me the vertices are stereo and they
could effectively operate at the
detonate forming subliminal so that
might be a typo
but the the
when you do any replication elimination
uh at the edges those those will be uh
relayed out so they will they will go
all the way to service okay
oh uh effectively that's that's what i'm
okay that i want confused with it's an
edge but yes so so actually the text is
correct so the notice vertices the
places where you can effectively fork
they are uh directly a detected surface
and then the the edges the hops it can
be a multi-hop that net transit path
in that case it's really serial
between the edges it's going to be a
serial uh set of nodes
so i'm sorry it's just like english
confusion between vertices and h i can't
choose to do those terms
um okay now
once we we've introduced what we uh mean
by the the concept of track which is
really that that potential graph and
that
based on layer three abstraction doesn't
really care about the layer
um
we need to differentiate another thing
which is
um
what is the piping you know what the
what the network
layer operates on
uh how to get from a to b etc from what
is being transported within this this
pipe
um initially for instance in that
network when we looked at ipv6 we did
not want to introduce too many headers
and stuff so we basically said
um we identified the flow which is an
application layer construct
with the five or six double depending on
v4 v6
uh that's basically source designation
address uh uh sort edition port uh
application and
upper layer and
protocol and if your v6
you can have those bits as well
anyway
using that basically means that we do
the network operation so we process the
water based on the color of the water or
whatever
but at the network layer it's
we can have a lot more power if we
effectively use our own network layer
uh
objects
that i call the pipes and android pipe
stuff and then we put the water on the
pipe at the ingress and it goes out of
the grass and this way you can put
multiple floors for instance inside
inside a single pipe then you can merge
multiple pipes um to a bigger pipe and
separate those flows uh when you reach
this nation etc so basically there is
this desire to separate the piping uh
which would be the track
from from the applications and the
network layer construct from from the
upper layer signaling which is reflected
by the factor
so how we do it exactly is is not really
said and that's going to be the
framework and that could be something
which really happens at that net but but
it's a goal for us to to be able to
transport multiple flows in the same
track and signal the front treatment at
the network layer as the track as
opposed to the flows themselves and keep
the flow
the application object separate from the
network object
so separating signaling we would work on
the float
oh alright i see uh you have your hands
wrapped
sorry i didn't mean to interrupt too
much pascal but
this is where crossover into debt net
applies now
so far i don't see that you've defined
anything that's particularly different
from the definitions in debt net
which does raise and i'm sort of hoping
lou is going to jump in and correct me
sorry i'm going to cough
sorry um i i i'm a little wary about
defining new
terms
that should be very similar to the terms
that already exist in internet i
understand we're going to build into
perio functions etc but
how how or why is this different it's
maybe my lack of understanding
that that would be the discussion on the
mailing list uh on on loose email
right
how much try can i see that who is
joining but uh this was just
this morning so we could not have a
thread on it but basically we we will
have this this uh track versus uh t
uh uh protection path discussion
and see if we can convert uh track into
t protection or if if if uh we want to
be more specific into exactly what works
about and then we'll give the voice to
please look
no
sorry
i guess i need more coffee um
rick i think you're
you're right on um the i agree with the
comment is uh that there's a lot here
that's similar and there's just some new
terminology that if we can align um
we'll be in good shape so largely what
pascal said i think another question is
um are we really limited just to ipv6
uh yeah yeah so yeah yeah for later but
yes
oh
rick brought it up so he asked for me to
comment so i commented uh i'll wait to
the end thanks
yeah i i i put up your email actually
luke and i wish at the end of this
presentation to go through it
have four items and i would like to to
make sure that they are all discussed uh
but yes and and the answer is certainly
not i mean i have personally i have no
idea that it's it's it's i understand
it's a mistake i i can wait
it's only because rick asked
okay okay so so let's move on
um yeah so the
basically the architecture focuses on on
one item
that joins to another point of look what
is raw basically uh
right now this architecture focuses on
just this udalu
is that all that relative on the
variable could mean certainly not
so
if we want to make the term raw generic
enough to really mean reliable and
available wireless probably we need to
to say that this architecture focuses on
one aspect of making a wireless relay
board available and that aspect this
particular architecture is really
focusing on the huda loop and then
probably to answer uh that other part of
of luke's review
what we are doing right now is probably
not you know the overarching
architecture of anything that could be
you know
that could make wireless uh really more
available but really uh
this this uda loop and the psc that we
are building to to uh complete the loop
so maybe we need to
to
or something uh when you say the raw
architecture we should basically say
this architecture or something
because it's not everything that you
could do for a labor wireless it's it's
very specifically handling this this
loop
so the determiner i mean i've put a link
here it's it's 40 or 50 years old it
probably started in the military if i
like the history of it
um
it's really this loop of you know
observing a fact and that's really where
the oem comes in
orienting is more like applying
intelligence
and you know the what you learned from
the past for instance
uh to to say oh based on that
observation there is
there is the sort of thing it should be
doing
and and in our case probably if we have
a pc and that's another question
if we have a pc computing uh the the
track
um then the pc could also come with some
recommendations on how to use it
that would that would be what
orientation would mean for us i think
some some intelligence
of uh how to to use the subset of the
truck for a particular
packet because of the particular
condition of this time
and the decision is is our plc engine uh
basically
making a decision based on the
observation and the orientation you
compile those two you match them and you
say oh here is what they should be doing
and and then the
uh the action is the actual signaling uh
how you copy the packets and multiple
paths and how you signal that
so that's that's pretty much the the
focus of this document
uh which is called raw architecture like
you said but we need to to figure out
uh
inside the document how would you say
the raw architecture what we need to do
exactly and that's that smooth point
so more under the loop i mean you've
seen that number of times it's in the
architecture
but basically obviously with oem oreos
based on you know pc metal information
about the graph
uh decide and that would be the psc
decision and act and that's how we use
the terpario which which extend the pre
of data that net
features
um
so
robert says that not
we have interesting use cases where
actually some pieces of the path
are not necessarily deterministic in
terms of uh fully bounded latency for
instance when you
look at the access network and we focus
on the first half which can be wireless
5g wi-fi
some things and multiple technologies
we don't have control on the rest of the
way and it might be very very different
but at some point we need to to make a
decision on depending on cards by not
reliability and so far to provide
for the service level objective uh
associated to this back-end
and that's still a raw decision
so
there is a little bit of uh non-overlap
as long as that naturally requires that
every every uh node underway is
deterministic and that requirement comes
from it comes with the body latency
so reliable and variable does not
necessarily mean bonding latencies many
times it will but
it's reliable means you have an
objective and you need it if that
objective uh that objective has
bodybuilders you need to beat that if
that objective has
you know
so much of nine so many notes in the row
etc but you have enough buffer for the
latency
um that really you don't need to go into
the gory uh aspects of of uh that net
and tsn
for instance you know the back end of
wireless access
can be considered relatable enough and
low latency enough then then you're done
okay so you know right basically uh
splitting some functions of the pce
because
in our cases that would be translated
pushing the reaction to the network and
basically you can see the pc as the
brain
and then there will be loose discussion
on whether there's always a pc and yes
it's an architecture we need to to
decide that is there always a pc or not
probably not but we need to rely on that
uh on this email and then the psc which
really exports the the data plane
short-term solutions uh
selection from the pc
and there is how the
takes place so the architecture
shows those confidence and
places them and shows their relationship
normally as i said it should not discuss
effective protocols it should not say
it's this protocol that protocol and for
instance for iam it's a very
vague term that's perfectly fit with
what we want at this level the only
exception and then a bit on this slide
is the lip
i don't know
if
it's fair because now we say oh it's
still if it's now but
there's no no real family but the leap
itself is a family also
so it seems to me that using dilip as
the term
is broad enough just like using oam is
broad enough and we i mean if that if
i'm wrong on that then please
give me a term but then compasses ddp
and its family but
that's probably the only case where i
effectively list
in a
specific
protocol kind of
so the status of the document
so within the split uh right after itf
on 12 since then we have two iterations
uh one for
fabric review so many many signs fabrics
um
so there were a number of
um points which were transmitted
reformulation clarification
and then there was uh they've got a
country uh review
and uh
yes there's more
pretty special route of loose
issues as well how do you position
things versus statement
my personal view is is we are kind of a
spinning spin off of that net with an
extension focused on one specific aspect
and with the hope that
at some point the work goes uh back into
into that next but but we can have done
this study
uh and i hope it still fits um as we do
it we we effectively need to to realize
where we have some tension and that
includes a path where uh
you don't effectively have the net nodes
all the way through
that can be attention uh the definition
of track
uh we'll see if that
we can fold that back in
um
but even if it if it stays as a terror
maybe that can adapt it i don't know
then then
the the concept of truck is is already
present in two other working groups i
mean that six station and raw by the way
to mean pretty much what we mean here
um
and
then yes the scope and that's that's
again a question uh so first by dave and
then
as well uh for instance lou asks about
ipv6 and maybe that's when we can
discuss that uh right now there is a
sentence somewhere which which points at
ipv6 extensions
do we leave it to ipv6 or do we want to
encompass more stuff
and i have absolutely no idea that we we
should limit to ipv6 it's just that i
have no idea either
and how we could do that outside of ipv6
so so um
i'm not happy to read the term ipv6 from
from the sentence that lewis pointed out
now i would be also happy to to find
some to have some contribution
explaining how we can do something else
yes carlos
so pascal one question um
where do you see potential control
playing
extensions for for i mean for the pc the
the pse
doing all this learning and taking
decisions do you foresee any control
plane extensions
need to be done in the future either
indented or raw or how do you see that
that part
just to provide some
background on why i'm making that
question i'm working on some potential
research projects that are looking into
how to enable
ai based decisions in a raw network
in a multi-technology raw network
and now we are trying to see
where the control plane
hooks to enable that application of ai
based on monitoring an iem will will fit
in the network
okay so i see that trick and join with
you i will give you my entire video
request to add stuff so the way it's
described right now
the
intelligence
the learning the time series and
everything
would reside in the central controller
and then we have to lose question is it
always a central controller
but the way it's written right now and
happy to modify that but it says there
is a central controller that does
learning
uh based on statistical information like
long-term information etc so you can
learn your time series you can so it's
all statistics and ar is really
statistics so that's why it's that it
fits now this experience
can be translated in new control plain
element as you say as you're saying
whereby the pce will feed the psc
so the psc what sees a real-time event
like this link is flapping can make
instantly a decision based on all the
experience that was digested by the pc
so the pc would basically say in that
case you do that that tells you the data
you know
transform the experience in something
which is immediately actually
by
immediately actuated by the psc that's
that's why what we mean by orient
so the whole
goal
in role
in the raw architecture is
effectively uh doing this learning that
you talk about
beyond feeding that learning
into the uh d which is the decision by
the plc
so yes you will need signaling there
between pc and pse in the control plane
now
do you the second question is do you
have the psc
at the ingress only or do you distribute
it
in the different uh
oh i just know that which is
the
and if you distribute it
then you need some signaling
in
it would be a data principle for control
whereby the intent of the ingress will
be propagated to
uh the that net relay so they can make
appropriate action based on what the
ingress intends to do
with this we have rick on the line
unless you want to
doesn't seem to fit exactly your
question
keep going carlos
i think i sort of agree with carlos on
this and yes i know i have been
promising you a review on this
architecture document
and i need to to get it done
um
it's the
logical architecture i think is good in
terms of the the
explicit separation between the pce
element and the pse element and lou and
i have are having a small discussion
about whether an exact pce
implementation is required or not
and my argument would be as a logical
separation of responsibility it's a very
good model but i think that needs to be
extended down so there is an
understanding of
the psc communicates with some oam or
linked date
awareness protocol you know dlapp is an
example of that and understanding that
there is that southbound communication
with the underlying layer two
and
there is a well there's northbound out
of the layer two into the pse
and there may well be some southbound
communication from the pse back into the
layer 2 to say
i have understood
how
that and this is where the track um
concept needs to be properly defined i
understand the observed flows the the
tracks of the data i understand the
communication that the policy that is
being set by the pce and therefore i
need you layer two i'm i'm operating as
the pse at the moment
that diagram here to make this change in
order to achieve the policy that is
being determined and i think the content
is all there i think it just needs a
little bit of clarification in the
document and i think we have to use the
new um svg content because these
diagrams are getting so complicated
so
my comment is is clarity i think we have
all the information there but if and i
think that might answer some of us
questions as if we can say
in the architecture this is covered in
section three talking about that
north-south interface
between uh the p this pse stack section
yeah so so basically we we probably can
improve the
uh pc to psc relationship with the
orient and the capture of data and maybe
the oaf flow flies directly from the the
nodes to the pc or it's aggregated by
the by the increase i don't know i mean
we need to keep it yeah i would i i
would i would recommend and i don't want
to get too far into this because i
should just do this as a proper review
but i think we can separate the
um
the logical concepts of a pse talks to
the layer below
and commun you know there's a
bi-directional communication there
separate that from
and here is some of the actual mechanics
for doing that eg d-lep oam passive
active blah blah blah and and sort of
separating the detail from the the big
concept because the i think in an
architecture having that big concept is
really good nothing to stop us drilling
into more detail but if we separate that
then i think it would be more obvious to
people like carlos to say oh okay so if
i'm doing ai guided prediction then i
can influence my my outputs from my
model is to influence this part of the
architecture and it gives a bit of
clarity
yeah okay okay i i i need a proper
no more questions sorry
yeah so the psc seems to combine two
separate functions
one is the um
sort of determination of which tracks
are available
and then the other is the selection on a
per packet basis of which track is used
or and that may be one or more
and
those are concepts that exist already in
um sort of more general traffic
engineering where uh instead of track if
we call it a protection segment uh or
protection path depending on
the extent of it um
that that happens at one time scale and
then the
uh the selection of which protection
function is being used whether you're
doing one for one one for n or one plus
one or one plus n even um that is uh
that's a different time scale and and
happens at a different place
really in the architecture and i think
if we start shifting over to those sort
of older terms we can leverage those
concepts and that separation and that'll
really help clarify
the distinction of what you're thinking
of belongs in a pce what belongs in the
track identification part and what which
belongs in the track uh selection part
um and again you know those those sort
of would be uh a loose path the the the
protection segments and then the the
actual protection uh switch function
um so i i think there's some uh some
terminology we can leverage that'll
really help clean up uh the uh the
concepts here and make it uh so we can
delineate the different concepts and and
clearly articulate the different
functions that are um that are possible
and and can be filled in in the raw
future
yes and you you have to be
very very useful there because
as you know i mean you have you have all
the tea expertise that
making sure but basically what we have
now is the expression of what we want
and now if it's if it fits within
something then we can work that out
and so just jumping in my with my chair
hat on when this working group was
formed we had a pretty solid steer from
the iab that we shouldn't
invent lots of new terminology
unnecessarily so um i i think we've got
to a good place actually where we have
an an architecture which is it's a good
draft
but we can now look as lou said for
alignment with
net or tease or existing definitions of
paths and tracks and i
totally agree with you that there is a
difference between the historical
path that the package traversed and the
future path you which pack you wish
packets to follow they are two very
different concepts and we need to make
sure that terminology is accurate but if
we can reuse
something existing then we're going to
be um much more
on charter than if we uh totally
reinvent new concepts so i'm all in
favor of just doing that kind of gap
analysis and making sure particularly
with people like lou to advise to say
actually this is the same concept to
make sure we're aligned
yeah and that was for me now be aware
that the concept of trunk is already
present in the other dtf we are not
reforming that term no no no i'm not i'm
not saying i i just making sure that
we've got consistency we're not
inventing a new track which is different
from somebody else's track no no it is
the exact same as 60-ish and
raw actually
so so we would have to look at that
okay
so i'm watching the clock tick down and
uh i think i'm going to call that your
time pascal if that's okay oh i just
turned my video on there to politeness
yeah so
do we the the
framework we will do it next time right
yeah it does not change any weight split
mostly split of the architecture
so so
just just to cover the framework um we
are
we held an interim meeting just to
discuss these two documents it was uh it
wasn't hugely well attended it was
attended by carlos pascal even myself
i think we we published some minutes of
it we will continue to have these
meetings um
if particularly well where there is
still discussion around the architecture
document it would be great for those who
have a strong opinion about it
to get involved just to make progress
because
the intention of the working group
really is
as covered in the last ietf meeting
the architecture document should be an
early document that we push through the
working group which contains
informational
uh information um describing how raw
will
the problem that raw will tackle and how
it will tackle it whereas the framework
is very much a living document which
we don't intend to publish until pretty
much the end of this charter cycle of
the working group so we can almost use
it as a peer-reviewed
notepad of
um
how these
how the architectural concepts are being
implemented and how we're tying all
these things together without forcing us
to
get it absolutely firm until this
charter cycle of the working group is is
complete which should be reasonably
prompt because the iab
do not like working groups running and
running and running without a regular
recharge
uh lou you're in the queue go ahead
yeah you mentioned that there was an
interim on this document i didn't see an
interim announced um
uh it wasn't it wasn't an interim on
this document it was a uh well no it
wasn't it was an interim meeting it was
held over ietf webex uh we announced it
um i tried to look but it wasn't
announced there's an ietf vendor meeting
a formal no it was not announced as an
interim meeting per se it was it was
announced as the beginning of a series
of
regular meetings to discuss architecture
and framework and i think the error was
probably mine that i didn't give the
subject line quite a crisp enough
name to identify it as such and in the
future we'll do that
yeah that's actually where is going more
than the past as the going forward is is
uh an intro might a formal intro might
be a really good idea since there are
some big questions here um and maybe you
use that to kick off these other
meetings i i i did miss that meeting
unintentionally um sorry about that uh
and but i think an interim will will
force more people's attention
um and maybe get some wider attendance
and then then maybe move on to uh
uh
less formal meetings so rick while you
may have spoken there i think it's a
great idea
yeah i'm sorry again the miss speaking
was was trying to work out the correct
terminology between a a formal virtual
interim meeting and a
get open get together published on the
mailing list about a document so yeah i
i take your point about a formal interim
i think that's
probably a really good idea go on pascal
um
what would be very useful new uh short
term is if you could point on where
we could find the actual definitions of
of the terms
that overlap so we can read them
carefully and analyze that
that would that would be very good
the terminology that you would suggest
we reuse
right um i am i am conscious that we are
now actually we've got a little bit of
time but uh if that's everything on
these two documents
yes great i mean the framework was more
like through the other piece but we we
introduced it and that's good enough for
today i mean if you have a tight agenda
uh we don't actually have a tight agenda
so uh do you want to take five minutes
on the framework document they're quite
happy
uh okay
let me share that
i need to
oh i have to approve
[Music]
so
yeah
as we said we we split between the
architecture which are the building
blocks of
here's what we want to achieve and the
framework
which is
the future post-mortem
and as of now it's the journal the live
journal of
what we think we are doing and how we
think we're doing it
and um the sort of thing that we want
and we need
is
um
explaining
which use case we're serving and that's
that's when for instance uh that was one
of the questions by uh
dave is doing do you serve the use case
of the one-hot access
network and just the first stop is
wireless and then the rest of the way it
could be your 5g core or could be
through your enterprise network
and android back somewhere where the
photos are
the applications are eliminated or
something like that
so
um
how do we signal
the
the the tracks
for now their tracks
are you using
a source rod
by the ingress which will basically tag
the packets for that behavior or
would we
support a distributed plc and i guess
the same will apply to the pc it wants
to the pcb to answer those questions i
mean how do we
implement the pce is it really a
centralized box is it a distributed
function in the network
uh how do we signal the orientation
that's
the question by carlos so how does the
orient piece
operate
so all the protocols and and the
protocol elements which which will be
added to support opens we need to
basically point at them
very as we elaborate and if we change
our minds as we work on then we need to
update this document as well so it's
really the expectation is it's the live
pointer on the things we use and we
think we're going to use
and when we're done and we think we have
a workable solution then we basically
close the shop
and this document publishes us here is
how it works
next slide please
oh it's me
please yes so that's why it's again it's
it's it's the dave
so i obeyed myself as you can see uh
that that's the um
assignment
this is the just one use case we have
many multi multiple use cases we have
mesh we have but but here yes this is
especially there to illustrate the fact
that we cover uh the wireless access
where only
uh the only monitored network is the
first half the radio access network it
can be wi-fi 5g whatever and the
internet is is best effort hopefully
good enough uh if it's your your
copyright or factory network uh
hopefully it's good enough and low
latency but
not there can be that that other can be
no that's not into it
so
that that's
basically the same drawing as before but
now we'll be talking about how this gets
implemented so basically which protocols
go into all of those little triangles
part of what we will have to to document
is how effectively we signal
the flows and that's basically the
architecture so we don't have to do
anything about that so the flows we know
that that framework is very clear
but how we signal the path on which we
place that flow
how we extract
how we split that
um the track into the actual experience
of the packet or the package fragments
which is what we call the subtract so
it's tracks within tracks
that go end-to-end between a ingress and
egress so how we signal all that in the
packets
we will have to point on the documents
which do that
um so
that is the road map that we decided
long long ago so we have to select
appropriate radios and and effective use
cases and with the progress we've done
the index document and the others are
coming
uh and the use case that uh carlos just
presented which is uh already pushed for
uh ietf score uh we're in very good
shape so i can i can say we we
checked uh this thing
now
next is is to
to uh basically decide how we signal
the the the tracks and how we do the
adaptation
and
then we have to talk about the iom
there now depending on what the group
wants to work on we probably want to
have and that was called canon's
question again we probably want to have
a new item here which is about the
orient for me the orient was autoscope
mostly i mean it's the pc to pse
uh control play
skeleton and how really
um that piece of the loop happens
uh
is not part of the framework well it has
not been documented it doesn't have its
peace in the framework but if the group
wants to to include that in the
discussion then yes we need to have a
framework section on on the orient piece
so basically which data how it fixed to
the controller and how the controller
fits its its orientation back into the
psc
so it's not sufficiently
expressed in the framework as it stands
and then again uh since we we are we
expect to use a lot of work which which
is being done elsewhere
um we had this list forever i see that
peace is not probably enough mentioned
uh though it was at the
their very initial
meetings so probably we need to add
these in that list
any question
i didn't speak about authorship but
pretty much um it was the first slide
with for now it's it's slow and i
uh
and then it was just me when i did the
split i
was expected to work on the architecture
so the authorship of this and of the
architecture are subject to change
obviously
go ahead yeah and not me as co-author is
aspirational not reflective of reality
but maybe future realities what is it
the
future yes it was the intention right i
mean so so to give you access to the
documents that allow you to basically
publish or what uh your mistake
and yeah i appreciate it i i i think
let's
get the architecture straightened and
then we'll come back to the framework
thank you
yeah yeah this one is you know to be
published two years from now three or
four i don't know
okay and that's pretty much it for me
do we have questions
thanks pascal uh i don't think we have
any questions i have one point i didn't
bother to jump to the queue because uh
we kind of jumped to the end i think
talking about the pse oh my god my dog
is molting everywhere the the psep
ce communication control plane um to me
that smacks of netconf
i mean that seems such a a a standard
network management uh control plane
given the the speed of speed of
communication et cetera it's
i i quite happy
could be that
now
at some point we need to point on the
solution
so either we say it does not exist yet
to do it proprietary which is pretty
much what we have right now you do your
own proprietary young models and what or
representing the communication in both
directions
or we kind of decide that we want to
provide some hints and then i mean
that's just not done right now
i i see that as stretching the scope of
the working group to worry about that
communication i think we can describe in
the architecture the nature of that
information so that's the the policy
that is arriving and we can talk in
terms of of track etc but how that
information is carried i don't think
it's in scope for the working group at
the moment to start developing
proprietary protein well not
customized protocols to carry that
information
yes if somebody is excited in writing a
yang model that sketches out how that
information is carried then that
obviously says you know you can use
netconf to discuss that that young model
it that could be if we feel that we have
to define that that would be an obvious
next step but i don't think we should
burn too many cycles on that at the
moment
yeah that's pretty much where we are so
we haven't seen it
okay so moving on um
next we have fabrice talking about uh om
support i have
i will click the magic
grant preloaded slides oh
sure to be able to have that and i will
give you permission to control your
slides
uh no i've given that to eve i've given
that to the wrong person because your
name moved around there we go february
so you should be able to steer those
using the overlay at the bottom perfect
right thank you very much uh you've got
15 minutes which i hope is sufficient
yeah largely sufficient i will just
present the
update so
here just to have a remainder about the
chronology of draft initially we had
everything together in the oim draft and
it was split in something which is
related to date net in general so all
the generic aspects of weim has been
moved
and we focus in this novel argument only
on the om specs which are very specific
to all
so thanks to chevy for his proofreading
last year
we have made a few modifications
i will present now
so first of all we introduced another
section about the recommendation we are
listing in this section
uh so typically we are listing the num
the
specific metrics that needs to be uh
supported by the om nodes so typically
we focus up to no on the packet there
was show adventuring latency and the
maximum consecutive failures that must
be exposed by all the nodes
we also say the fact that we have poor
functions that must be currently order
sorry
and
we need to also have some methods to
aggregate the statistics to compress
everything in the um later
and we must also which will support word
tracing with hybrid way
in this novel uh draft
uh we we are specifically the the
piggybacking uh problem specifically so
piggybacking that's inserting some
additional information in existing
packets so we we typically had some
industrial control readers uh in
wireless it may be also interesting to
put the packets back to back
in the same test slot because in
wireless networks and particularly for
schedule networks we have a cost for a
medium access and the time slot is fixed
so we will waste the bond wave so the
interest of this kind of schedule
networks is to put the uh impacts of the
om information
in the space of the temple time slot
which is not used so
that's the image of having control
information for free so for free which
means only that we have some bandwidth
which is wasted however we we are
keeping on having some large
energy consumption because the
transmitter and the receiver are
obviously awake for a longer time so
yeah we just reduced the cost of any
medium access with this piggybacking
technique
and just to
be clear about that we clearly classify
the different way so active passive and
hybrid active we are sending some probes
with test packets
with passive we just use database
information and with hybrid om we have a
mix so typically we may use some counter
values or you may piggyback some
information
and we would just like to insist on the
fact that
piggybacking and ym techniques are
probably orthogonal in the sense fans
that's a negative or impacted that's a
probe
maybe trustee transmitted heroin so we
should have in that case
we must have in that case dedicated
resources or we may encueve the prop so
that it can be piggybacked with another
data point when we have enough space in
at a given time slots so so we are
we are kind of stealing the the
resources uh that are used for the data
the data flows so basically that's just
to be clear about this classification
between oem and piggybacking
so the draft is now stable
your comments obviously and suggestions
are worried welcome so please go ahead
and have critics comments and
suggestions
and thank you and if someone has a
question
please wise you want
any comments any questions
pretend to step away for a moment
thank you very much for the
update and also for the ongoing work on
the draft
um it's great to hear uh
the specifics
okay good thank you
to be continued on the mailing list
um
okay i think we are going to move now to
um the last presentation which is the
multi-domain extensions presentation
carlos back to you
would you like me to
grab the slides or do you want to bring
them up
please serve the slice and pass me the
control and then i will okay
okay perfect
thanks so
this is a a new draft
that is on multi-domain extensions and
the purpose of this document is at this
stage is mainly to
present a problem that is not currently
under
the scope of the working group as far as
we understand
but to see whether this potential
problem may be of interest and then to
identify gaps
and things that we may need to consider
for this problem to be to be addressed
so
as i mentioned the current scope of the
working group is although i don't think
explicitly mentioned but my underlying
assumption is focus on on single domain
single administrative domain although
that
may translate also to technological
domains if we make a like a one-to-one
mapping technology
to administrative domain or even if we
don't there may be a scenario where
multiple technological domains may
involve this kind of
multi-domain gaps
so there are scenarios that we believe
and we try to identify some in the draft
where we may need to have multi-domain
raw for example we may have hosts
connected to different broad domains
that they need to communicate to each
other one host to another host
traversing two different domains
and one example is maybe large factories
where may have uh
the different networks organizing
domains because of scalability and this
kind of things and there may be
particular situations in which we still
need to connect
one node in one domain to another node
in another domain
and we want that connection to
be provided with some reliability
availability
warranties
so the goal of the document is to
explore
this what are the potential gaps in the
architecture
in specific technologies that may be oem
traversing multiple domains and try to
start proposing some initial
solution but just to to foster the
discussion
so this is one example
using the ascii art that is in the draft
that is not very simple to to show but
we have two domains one at the top and
one at the bottom
we assume that each domain has an
associated pce
for the path computation
and then we have different row notes we
are assuming the distributed pse model
where
each node may be potentially a plc an
english node
then we have another domain at the
bottom with another pce and different
nodes
and we
have these two domains interconnected
somehow
in the document we don't go into how
these domains are interconnected and how
the different entities that as we will
see in a assembly flow chart are aware
of those interconnections there may be
solutions different solutions for doing
that so we start from the assumption we
know or some nodes in the network know
how these two domains are interconnected
but they are still operating
separately and we are trying to provide
some
solutions to enable host one for example
in raw domain one
to interconnect or to have a flow
with host two in the second domain with
some
raw warranties
so we have some discussion in the
document again this is just to foster
the discussion in the working group and
to see whether this there is an interest
but the the first idea that we thought
it could be a way of enabling this
is that we have the english node in the
first domain where we get the request we
want to have a communication between
host one and host two
and the ingress the pse in that domain
will request to the pc in that domain i
want to have
this
communication between this node and
the nodes
that are in the in the second that are
connecting to the
the english notes in the second domain
okay
and that
the pce will pc1 will know
that there is a connection with the
second domain and will request to the
second pc
the paths from those nodes to the
destination node in the second domain
the pc2
will provide somehow we don't go into
the details
the tracks for that interconnection in
the second domain and also the link some
metrics about the link quality in those
in those parts
and with that the pce one will provide
to the the ingress pc pse in the first
domain about the tracks on each domain
the different pscs involved in the other
domain in the second domain and
some kind of a split of sla that needs
to be one and t on each of the domains
because then
we foresee but this again one initial
discussion that its domain will keep
track of
monitoring and ensuring that the slash
on each of the different tracks a domain
sorry will be maintained somehow with
lim mechanisms that may need to be
cooperating somehow
so in step number five
the english pc pse in the first domain
will communicate with the psc's in the
english pss in the other domain
to basically communicate
the tracks that are involved and to
enable those psis to have some uh
to start doing these
domain specific oein mechanisms at each
of the domains
and at this point each of the involved
pscs will be able to compute the the
paths
or the at the the pse runtime
and the oem mechanisms will be in place
so as you can see this is a kind of high
level
initial discussion point
but just to trigger some some or some to
foster some potential discussion on
whether this is something that is of
interest for the for the working group
or not
so the point is not that much into the
solution but more into the problem
and the potential gaps that we may need
to
to address so just as the final slides
is there any interest in this in this
problem in the working group now it's
not in the charter but maybe in the
future
there may be many gaps that we need to
identify and address
for example related to the aim
there may be new protocol work needed in
case raw recharges to do new protocol at
some point in time of course if not
that would not be the the case
and of course there are some potential
relations with deadnet
because at the end of the day that they
may be also interested in looking into
multi-domain issues
and that's it from my side just
wanted to collect some feedback either
now or
maybe even better on the mainly list
where we can have a sustained
discussion
so questions comments
hi carlos uh it's rick
um
i'll turn my video on
i thank you very much for this work this
is this is i think is it really
important uh so i i really have have a
question and a statement so lou has put
a a link in the chat
to a
generic multi-domain problem statement
which is coming from
the tease working group yes it is so i i
recommend people to have a look at that
for reference
the other question is
the architecture as presented by pascal
just earlier um as as it is written has
a single pce communicating with uh
one or more pses
does the working group think we ought to
include the multi-domain use case within
the architecture or leave the
architecture as single domain and
take on this work as as a sort of
addendum to that architecture
this is a very open question
may i comment just briefly
um i
whenever we have talked about um raw and
whenever we have made reference to the
debt net agenda
um and charter there is the specific
wording in the charter uh about
coordinated domains
and although it hasn't been a
topic of discussion it is
uh described that way
in the debt net charter so
and maybe that's a good segue over to
lou
i was just going to say that the
architecture i think already allows for
it
where in particular the text that talks
about going over
uh non-raw aware which i would translate
to non-debt net aware
uh domains
it basically turns you into a
multi-domain problem
so i think we're all in agreement
that it is uh although it hasn't been i
wasn't stating an opinion on whether
it's a good thing or a bad thing i was
just saying that it's already in there
it's being alluded to okay yes
yes if not focused on it it
the problem description um
uh already references
it both directions
so i expressed my question with chair
hat on is is carlos are you uh are you
requesting working group adoption for
this or do you want to
get some review comments and burn a few
cycles on it first and then
what's your feeling
at this point i wanted to have some
feedback uh not really thinking of
adoption or anything that that may come
later if there is interest so that was
my own my own purpose was to foster
discussion on this point
and of course if there is interest yes
at this point in time and we of course
are open to get more people joining the
draft
the more the better i mean the more
people interested the better so yeah no
no no question at this point i think
this is the first time we discussed this
so i think it's best to have more
discussion before
okay thank you
eve you still have your oh no you don't
you're just in the in the chair section
so uh are there any more questions on
this topic
no
okay
so uh we actually have half an hour of
the session left
um so really this is this is an open mic
opportunity um if anyone wishes to
raise anything that they think might be
of interest to the group in general
stand up and tell us that we are going
in completely the wrong direction and we
ought to be looking at whatever some
other working group is currently working
on in classic ietf style or if there's
something we have missed in
what we've presented or documented so
far
or stand up and promote something
exciting that's happening in another
working group that we ought to be aware
of
this would be a really good moment
well people consider that one thing i
will add so
i think this came out
in one of the earlier presentations i
think from pascal talking about
um
radio specific properties to be
discussed
as part of the
link awareness or the oam feedback
between
the link layer and the pse component
i know there are uh at least one
extension to delap being proposed in the
man a working group which i believe is
meeting in the next session this morning
uh to do with specific things such as
channel assignment uh frequency
bandwidth uh some really very uh
radio link layer specific properties
that could be um
announced via a dlap protocol session
if anyone is interested in further
direction that the d-lab is going in
that's in many
otherwise anyone else
if there is nothing else
may i suggest that those of you who have
booked out the two hours today for raw
take this opportunity to go away and uh
do the some of these reviews that you
have promised i know i shall be
um because
the ietf
revolves around good quality review
and i know the authors of the various
drafts in this working group deserve
good quality review because they they
have put
a lot of effort into these documents
eve do you want to add anything
no i don't thank you for leaving the
charge particularly given the hour
well i'm in europe so it's easy for me
and i also want to um thank both karina
and carlos for
um their very much appreciated help
that's great and for those of you in the
room
hello are we outnumbered
i am very jealous of those of you sat in
the room um i wish i had been able to
meet you in person this time around uh
as a rough intention from the chairs we
intend to be in person uh in at the
atf-114 which would be very nice to meet
you all again and speak to you again
after two and a half years of of
isolation
but we've never met in person by the way
no even i have never met in person we
have we have chaired this working group
for two and a half years without meeting
in person so that's an all credit to to
the internet but it would actually be
quite nice to meet um
on that note
if there is nothing else i think we
should probably close this meeting early
any objection
there we go
and
we are giving everybody half an hour to
go away and quietly read some raw
documents and add comment to the mailing
list
uh no objection from our a.d which is
always good so um in which case thank
you all very much uh extra thank you
from me as well to carina and carlos for
for being our chair delegates in the
room luckily we didn't have a mad rush
to the mic and everyone behaved and meet
echo did us proud so
thank you very much i'm going to call
this a stop and um speak to you all
on the list and in person and we will
probably if we arrange a virtual interim
we will publicize it in advance and
properly on the mailing list so
please keep an eye open for that for a
bit more of a deep dive into
architecture and possibly a little bit
of multi-domain maybe i don't know right
and even if we don't uh schedule an
interim we may
we'll do a better job this next time of
creating a subject line that announces
um a regular
regularly held series of meetings to
discuss those documents
yeah indeed
okay uh thanks all uh in which case i
think we should probably
close the meeting
i'm gonna work out how to do this i
don't know how to do it it's the very
right most icon in meat echo at the top
it looks like a gas station an old gas
station
you
you press the button you do it
okay
oh no
thank you all
thanks pascal
that just leaves the room thanks to all
the presenters
yeah thank you very much everybody um
and authors
we may just have to leave this room open
with nobody in it
uh me techo we have no idea how to close
the uh how to close the meeting
um it's automatically closed when the
session determines
but there we go also in the beginning
starting 15 minutes early
okay perfect thank you corinna uh in
which case i'm going to leave you to it
and make myself a cup of coffee thank
you very much everybody
thank you very
much so it worked out fine
[Music]
what i'm gonna
and i will check out
some people wanted to meet me and i have
a student taco in half an hour
let's see okay
so you just contacted me because of sba
research
yeah
so i i have an
agreement with sba research since
two and a half years to be one of the
key researchers here
because i'm involved in the big security
project concordia where they are
partners
and then they just asked me with my
expertise of iit security