do not
so hello to people in the room
actually there's nobody in the room oh
there are
the corners
oh there we go oh there we go
[Laughter]
somebody jumped up to him
i'm thinking i know ulrich's around
because he was in uh yeah he was in dns
op so yeah
there were a bunch of people in dns op
it was it was kind of cool
yeah and and for us here is so bright
and early
um
okay uh anyway i'm letting myself get
distracted here i got to get to um yeah
do the uh
i know that there are more people coming
ulrich has said that he's going to join
and uh
but they might be stuck with lunch
because lunch is only an hour now so
yeah well
it's one o'clock
so jim shall i shall i open the meeting
then
and sure yeah
you do the um
the upload of the presentation
yes i'm getting it i'm typing in the
title right now oh sorry there in a
moment alex
um um the mobile app doesn't show the
session for whatever reason
anyway or maybe it's just me
on the agenda it's there yeah but on the
mobile app it's not there so maybe the
schedule and uh
oh well
don't know if meat echo is listening is
that something they can help with
okay um you should check the meeting
materials uh uh
antoine and make sure that you now see
the data dictionary slides or do we have
to ask meat echo to reload again of
course we have to you have to reload
them from there there now and now see
so they are there now and now we only
have to wait when we do the next
presentation to see if they're there
but okay since we're already
two minutes over time let's open the
meeting this is the
registration protocol extensions working
group
my name is anton vaswen and on the
screen you have your co-chair jim galvin
it's the 22nd of march today which is a
special day for me
i won't go further
i turn 55 today
um i'm sorry antoine i have to jump in
i knew there was i you know i wasn't
catching on i'm sorry
you would do the introduction right
that's right i have to do the
introduction we have four minutes here
we're not we're not over time yet not
over time yet but it is antoine's
birthday today this is a very special
day for him
so uh you know it's a shame that you
can't be in vienna and go out and
celebrate in style
yeah
yeah too bad i'll be at the next one
right
yes
yes we'll definitely uh do our part then
oh look we got some more people coming
in the room isn't that lovely yes okay
so it's yeah well they probably want to
skip the note well but they're still uh
[Music]
they should read it and they should
adhere to it
i think everybody has read the note well
everything you say
here in the meeting room on the mailing
list or in the corridors
um is subject to the idf notewell so
read it well
and of course we
one of the things
as well is the idf code of conduct
guidelines which i present on the screen
now
which basically means you know treat
college with respect um be aware that um
we're all here uh
mostly for the single goal
of
contributing ongoing work to the group
in the itf for
the best solution for the whole internet
and not you in particular
um and be aware of that and
treat your your your colleagues
with the same respect as you wanted to
treat you
then
that is the welcome introduction usually
we say another word and that is the way
that we do document management
which means that we expect people to
read and
react to documents on the mailing list
um everybody that has once written a
document will be happy to
to to see contributions there we also
have
the process within this working group
that once a document is adopted
that
we request to have a
document shepard right from the start of
document adoption and not at the end
when when we're going into the
working group last call um so if you
submit a document for
adopting by this working group we kindly
request you to search for a document
shepard for your document which is not
the document author
or any of the chairs of ads
and for the people that want to
volunteer being a document shepard it's
a very good opportunity to learn
everything about the processes of the
itf
and uh and get to know
the especially the process of how a
document
is going along in the in the
publication
process
so that was the welcome and introduction
the notewell document management i just
told you about
um
we have a few documents that are
published since the last idf
one of them these is the um secure
authorization of information for
transfer
rfc 9154 as you can see on the screen
and the other one is original registry
maintenance notification
also for epp
rfc 9167 congratulations everyone with
everybody with again publishing new
documents
so that's off our plate
and then we still have some working
projects work in progress documents
first is finding the authority the
registration
data for the rdap service this is
as you all know
an elevation to uh standards um for one
of the the other documents um it's very
close to being published it's still in
the rc at the queue i didn't see any
messages today but expect this one to be
published within i think the next the
next days or week
then another one is the use of
internationalized email addresses in the
ebb protocol so internationalized email
addresses
this document has passed working group
last call
but we are during working group last
call this document changed a few times
and we assume that this is for
uh
that that it didn't
uh change anything substantial
which is why we uh we want the uh
document shepard to state that on the
mailing list and then do his write-up
before we can submit this to the
isg
and i see james gould in the queue there
james go ahead
do you want to say something can you
unmute
[Music]
or should i
so james is in the queue but he's having
some audio issues
i think i can hear him in the background
it's very very faint though
well if you can type your comment in the
chat room jim we'll uh we'll read it out
for you
he's gonna add a comment in the chat
room i see it over here
okay
um i don't see jody in the
participants
um
list i actually wanted to ask him a
question you know how far he is with um
yeah
um so um
james said in the indie chat you know
nothing material was changed to the
draft we know this i mean jim and i have
read the draft too we think
that there is not no that there are no
material changes
made during last call but since we jim
and i need to be impartial here the
process is that the document shepard
is supposed to state that as an
independent reviewer
and basically we're waiting for that and
then when
jody has done that he should also do the
write-up as the document shepherd
but since jody is not in the room
jim and i will continue to harass him on
that and to make sure that that he's
doing that but so if anybody is aware
that
if anybody's asking why this is taking
so long uh at the moment it's it's on
the document shepard if it takes much
longer we
might want to
look for another document shepard
but
let's let's first
give jody a fair chance to
do this
then
we change use uh
jim and you'll do it from uh from here
on for the existing work because i think
the first
one
that's on the list
is the simple registration reporting and
you are the one to
state something about the progress of
this document
uh yes thanks um
let me um first just put a chair on for
a moment and and remind us um we we uh
in the beginning we were talking about
notes
um we we should have asked for people
for for um
the uh the agendas pre-loaded in in the
notes uh the note-taking uh thing over
here we really would just like for uh
folks to add a bullet whenever you hear
uh an interesting point um and just put
that in the in in the notes so uh we're
just gonna depend on the recording in
the chat room here to keep us honest and
the note-taking facility uh is is just
for capturing actions and decision
points
so if anyone could feel free to add that
about their documents or any question
that would be great and the note docs
looks empty he says
um
note-taking tool
i'm looking in it now
and um
now why is it the agenda's not there it
was there the last time i looked
honest
no i'm at the hedge talk too rick and
i'm not seeing it in there well we'll
get back to that let me just deal with
my document oh okay
or did you just stick that there
maybe somebody else stuck it there
took a moment okay i'm sorry
yeah simple registration reporting very
quickly uh we believe this document is
ready for working group last call and
we're going to be asking for that on the
mailing list after the ietf year it's
going to get added to a list of uh
several documents here are on the cusp
of working group last call so we're
ready to move that along as soon as uh
other folks are ready there really
hasn't been much discussion um uh with
the document and i see tim with your
hand up do you wanna try again jim
and still not hearing you jim if you're
talking
okay well you know back to you uh uh
antoine about registration reporting um
we'll let jim keep trying um
or if you put a comment in the chat
we'll deal with it there sorry jim
not sure what's going on
yeah james audio seems to be very low i
don't know why there is
could be a local a local issue
you said back to me jim
but you're unmute
um okay next one is the reverse search
capabilities and that is mario mario
alfredo i think i saw you in there
i saw you earlier this week
do you hear me
yeah we can hear you mario okay
yeah yes
yes since uh
last meeting i added the dota t add-up
web client to the implementation status
section and following the up the
feedback from jazdick and tom i extended
the query model to represent
a
reverse
reverse search based on any relationship
between
the rdap object classes
and i changed the the role
path segment into a query parameter
now i think that
the document is
is in good shape and
is substantially ready for
to go into the working group last call
it includes two
dependencies from two
draft
drafts but they are informative
references
okay very well so
conclusion for this talking you think
it's ready for working good glass call
we saw your um
request for that and um we will follow
up on that on the mailing list after
this
yeah itf meeting uh tom i volunteered to
to share the document so
uh
i think that
you agree
yeah
thomas
is the document shepard we we already
discussed this with him that this
document has a
quite long reputation especially for the
uh
privacy considerations section um he's
all aware of that so
we'll be
expected to
have this in working group last call in
the next weeks
then the third document uh federated
authentication using open id
is scots in the room or in the
meeting
scott do you want to make comments for
this one
uh sure antoine um i'm not in the room
i'm remote
yep yeah so so this document changed
extensively since we last met it shifted
from a token management approach that
put that burden on the client
to a token management approach that puts
the burden on the server
and in doing that i think it made the
document much more acceptable you know
to people who are familiar with open id
oauth and how it's commonly implemented
in web services
i've got a few more minor changes to
make based on feedback received from the
last update but once i make those
changes i think we've got a document
that's in really really really good
shape
the only other thing i'd like to ask
people to look at is the list of query
purposes that are currently there
uh those are part of a proposal for an
iana registry of query purposes but if
we agree that those purposes
you know cover the use cases we're
familiar with i think this document will
too will be ready for working group last
call with one more update
that's a really good news scott because
this this has been on our plate for
quite some time as well of course
does anybody have any questions to scott
about the changes or about the status of
the document
if not
then we will move on
to the next one and that is
js contact
and that's again mario do you want to
say anything about this one as well
yes
uh i just made only editorial changes
since last meeting so i correct um
i update the references due to the
transfer
of the js contact document from jmf to
collect
but nothing else so
i don't know if now it is the
right moment right time to
ask for the
working group last call because the
guest contact documents are expected to
a schedule to
to go into working group law school
next july
so
i don't think that
there will be a
important
changes
in the in the next
until july in the in this document so
i would suggest to
go into working group last call
and uh i know that there is obviously a
a deep er sun to depend in two
dependencies from
the js contact documents it seems to me
normal
so
i don't know what is the
the the right procedure in this case i
never
i never
experienced before so
i
i trust in your experience to to to do
what is the
the the right
track to follow
yeah yeah
thank you mario yeah for for folks that
didn't didn't get this yet there are two
normative references in this document
two internet drafts which of course are
not allowed
and so we are actually waiting for the
uh the two other drafts which are not in
this working group but they're another
working group on js contact
to be published together with this
document in one go uh and therefore we
have normative references to rfcs and
not to
to to internet droughts we already
discussed this with with murray um our
area director um
he says it won't be a problem they will
just queue up and so we can do the
working group last call but be expected
not to
to have them published until the other
two documents are to be published as
well
and i see murray in room murray i don't
know if you want to add anything to that
no no uh it's okay for me now for murray
i said murray not married i'm sorry
i have nothing
that sounds right
okay so yes that's the status of the pro
of the uh of of this document uh it
means that we can go into working group
last call with this one but it is in no
hurry at all since we have to do this
before july when the other two documents
uh will also uh be uh be published in
the other working group uh so i propose
that since we have already
three requests for working group last
calls
we can do this one after the other three
um if you're okay with that mario and
because it will it will be linking
lingering around anyway
no problem at all
yeah
okay thank you mario
then the next document direct fields in
the rdap response and i don't see
[Music]
jodie
nor
roger
in the meeting
if i'm correct
i have to scroll down the whole no
they're both not here
um so let's deal with this one uh
further on the mailing list um
i don't th this one is not in working
group last school yet if i'm correct uh
there's still work in progress here to
be done
so that's that let's uh let's let's just
keep that there
then the next one is the registration
data dictionary i don't know jim did you
find the slides already
so if you can upgrade upload the slides
for this one and i will give the floor i
think to heather or steve
steve i see you in the queue yeah there
they are
yes heather will speak first and then me
okay
if jim can put the slides
or yeah i think i can request to share
them as well
if i hit the right button yeah they're
in the meeting materials
did you want to do it heather you can go
ahead
yeah but then we have to stop sharing
slides first right
let's see yes
yeah
okay so i stopped sharing slides
okay
and
let's see if i hit
this button
and this button
did that share slides not yet
let's try again
but um
heather you and i are gonna
switch off maybe if jim could run the
slides we'd both be in better shape
um true it's not it's not sharing it's
opening them up for me but it's not
sharing them so
yeah and they're not in the preloaded
slides yet normally before the meeting
we have pre-loaded slides
but since
these were not in the data tracker yet
at the beginning of the meeting
they're not in the pre-loaded slides as
well
let's see if i can do something here
yeah can we ask um meet echo to uh to to
reload the pre-loaded slides and i want
to give rick a chance to go back to the
previous document and say a word while
we're waiting for that
uh he wrote a comment in uh in the chat
room which is kind of important i'd like
to give him a chance to uh to speak that
permissions can you hear me okay
yeah
okay very good thanks uh so yeah uh rick
wilhelm pr just for the
uh wearing my rdap working group chair
hat just letting everybody know what i
said in the in the uh in the chat there
that um the icann rdap working group is
working on modifying the i can rdap
profile
so that rdap responses
are allowed to use js contact and are
not required to use j card uh this will
probably make a lot of folks
in the room that are not big fans of jay
card pretty happy so we're allowing
flexibility there in the response
mechanism
and so we're kind of hoping that that
would it's not required that they use
js contact but it certainly allows that
optionality and so we'll we're hoping
that we're going to start to see some
variety and implementations and an
evolution in the uh in js content
implementation i'm probably going to
learn some things in that
and um
so
uh happy to take any questions about
that but and and also a lot of uh shout
out to mario on that thanks
okay okay thank you rick
and i now have uh thank you meat echo i
now have the the data dictionary slides
so
over to you guys
outstanding um so we're we're going to
assume that folks have had a chance to
read the data dictionary um jim could
you go to the next slide please
so when last we left our humble
explorers um uh since ietf 112 the draft
was accepted as a working group item
thank you all very much for that
uh for my own purposes of keeping track
of feedback i did go ahead and create a
github repository not suggesting
changing working group process on how
you normally handle drafts this was as
much for me personally as anybody else
but it's there
if anyone would like to
follow along if they would find that
easier
um what changes we've made
as as a result of the feedback that came
for the call to make this a working
group item we updated the abstract
one of the big points was we really
don't want to set policy with this draft
so we tried to make that clear
we updated several of the definitions to
remove the normative reference to the
epp
spec
the
general data element specification we
made a note that local interpretation is
expected for any any legal
issues and this this in no small part
touched on questions of you know legal
natural person what not what is what is
the local definition because the data
dictionary isn't trying to set that
there were several areas that could
inform policy just by how they were
defined
and for all of those we put the
definition to to be determined
we also did to be determined for um
any elements that that had questions
about what format are you choosing so
for like date or name or address
that's those are always sticky to to
define well so those are also tbd
and given the previous changes we moved
several items from
um
normative references to just informative
references
because they're they're no longer
fundamentally required
next slide please
there are a couple things that we were
able to just close in terms of uh
requests that people made
for
as part of the call for adoption one was
to change the title from the dns
registration uh dns data dictionary to
the registration data dictionary so
that's been done and the removal of the
references to epp so those two things at
least i created issues for them solely
so i could close them which felt really
good
i love checking things off the list
i
the github shouldn't be private i will
double check that as soon as i hand off
to steve
who gets the next slides
thank you very much heather
um
let me
just emphasize a pointer to
this work arose
out of
work that heather and i and others have
been involved in
where we realized that we were making
references or making lists of data
elements and that there are other places
in the ecosystem where there are
references to the equivalent data
elements and that there was no common
place to refer to those so this is sort
of a
an emergent uh aspect of the work and
the intent which i want to emphasize
very strongly is that this is not
intended to influence um any of the
substantive developments going on in
these areas it's simply an attempt to
gather the
terminology that's used and provided as
an available source of commonality
across the system
i know that's a question that keeps
coming up as to whether or not we're
trying to
change things that have been developed
or influence existing things so we're
just trying to put something on the
table that would be a useful building
block for either existing or future
systems and
of course we'll see how that goes so um
uh here's some of the comments that came
back
um
and and the first one i think i've just
spoken to that this documents various
terms but not expected necessarily to be
in complete agreement um that was a
suggestion so we'll see how this goes
but we've been trying to strip out any
of the things that are biased in one
direction or another
another concern is that definitional
nuances might be lost many words very
policy loaded can be difficult to
capture a standard definition for them
that's
true and will as i said we're trying
hard to
be as as neutral and as sort of vanilla
as possible in these definitions
um
a concern about whether there are
implied policy decisions um
the comment was it says it's merely a
dictionary but then it goes on to make
very clear policy decisions e.g and
section 2.30
and by defining elements
the existence of these fields as defined
by this data may create foundational
bedrock to build an argument
to support bi parties as to why in the
presence of the definition of fields the
information is not being captured
well um
i'm not sure what more i can say with
respect to the first of those things but
with respect to the second that's an
interesting
and
in some ways
a quite um
insightful
uh comment that just by putting those
definitions in there it provides
ammunition for parties who want to argue
well it's defined therefore it must be
used
um
no doubt there will be
instances of that kind of dialogue but
i hope we're making it clear in here
that
um
that is a separate and an explicit
decision that has to be made by each and
every group as to whether they want to
use those data elements and one of the
things that i think will
um
uh sort of make that case is that there
will be plenty of data elements
uh that are defined that simply will not
be used
it would be strong agreement not to use
it in a particular application
so i think that would be uh
it'll be easy to push back
in those situations where
um
somebody is trying to say well it's
there therefore you have to use it and
the answer is no it's got to be much
stronger than that
next slide please
jim
there we go
uh a question about the use of a label
formats uh international version uh u
label seems to be more inclusive
i
actually am going to punt
um
i remember listening to some discussion
about that but i realize i don't have
the
full picture of that there are some
others in the room here who might be
able to speak to that
feel free to speak or chat or whatever
and with respect to the second bullet is
the goal to describe the semantics of
daniel also specified syntax in the last
case we need to specify unicode
normalization so i would expect that
this will be come out in the back and
forth that we're going to have as we
move forward on all of this
nobody's speaking to the a label format
issue
next slide
i think i saw
in the queue
yeah jim gold had his hand up briefly um
but uh i i will also comment
that um the issue in in my mind about a
label versus you label is is just that
you probably have to have both
because
even in the gtld space where you get
policies from icann
they only apply at the tld level
and some limited application at the
second level but you can't control
anything else down the tree
so
you know those are just issues so you
probably have to have both
that's all
thank you and um
yeah it's james gould but we're trying
to see if his audio works can you try
again james
can you hear me this time yes we can
hear something we can hear some
something
yeah yeah i think kind of yell okay so
yeah no i actually want to speak to the
second bullet uh not the first one
um because i'm a little bit confused of
the purpose of this draft
because it has a mix of syntax some of
the data elements do some of them don't
and then if they do have data element
syntax definition
how do
what do we use that for
so if we're using these data elements
and the protocols they're not they may
not match
so is the intent to try to normalize the
syntax as well
in this draft
so my recommendation is to remove the
syntax and just make them data element
definitions
as opposed to trying to to mix it in so
just want to speak to that one
good comment
noted
i don't think we're going to resolve it
on the spot here but uh
we'll make a point of having uh some
dialogue on the um
on the mailing list
all right next slide
um
suggestion clarifying iana
considerations clarify that new data
elements will be created for use across
the entire domain system as opposed to
describing how specific data element is
populated for a given domain and i have
to add quickly that
we're although this arose out of work
that we're doing in the domain name
system it applies also to data elements
for uh address registrations and and
potentially for other situations so we
need to
um uh make that a bit clearer
word domain there might uh might seem
like it means domain names and i think
we'll we'll pull that out
a little bit
thank you
next slide
all right uh several next steps i need
text
oops what happened here
yeah sorry jim gold had his hand up and
i wonder if he took it down because we
changed slides
just wanted to be fair quickly
sorry about that
that's okay did you want to speak to
this
different issue i want to bring up um so
just trying to find the right time to do
it
thank you
oh wrong brother
yeah wrong button
just a moment
been there done that
yeah
and
there you go
excellent recovery
all right so a handful of next steps
obviously we want to uh
fill in the tbds
um
and identify any terms that are missing
although
my strong expectation is that this is a
live process that once we put this to
bed and and get the
registry up and running there will then
be
additional data items that will get
added
at some rate won't be it won't be a
torrent but uh might be a little trickle
but there will there will be ones queued
up and there have to be a process
assigned to that
and most important we need to document
shepard we need a volunteer
i don't see a whole bunch of hands going
up please please please
[Music]
we need we need somebody who serves the
proper role of a document shepard has
the right
time commitment neutrality
and insight
well if you don't volunteer we're going
to come around and
find you
and that's it
okay thank you steve and yeah what what
the documentary's concerns please
volunteer indeed and also on the mailing
list or or write directly to the
document authors or the chairs and uh we
can we can
make that happen
okay any questions i see james in the eq
go ahead james
uh yeah i have uh two uh items of
feedback one is
associated with the choice of the data
elements um since
i'm seeing new elements that i'm
unfamiliar with that are tbd
and i really don't see a large set of
data elements that exist in other rcs
related to registration data like the
data escrow
rfc so
it may be worthwhile to review those
rfcs and try to pull in data elements
that are applicable um a second item and
i i believe this also applies this is
what i was trying to say for the report
uh draft is
making sure that the data elements
follow a consistent naming convention
i'm seeing a mix of abbreviations versus
bars
uppercase versus lowercase um
i believe it would be good to formally
define
uh the the convention and to follow it
uh consistently in the draft
that's it thank you
those are two very very very very effort
um
it's certainly
data elements that are defined in
various rfcs
we ought to include
um
there will be
other data elements that are coming up
in some of the work we're doing and
other people's works that will not be
familiar to everybody
which is at least in part part of the
motivation for this but
with respect to covering those things
that have been used in other documents
that's an extremely good suggestion
and on your other suggestion of uh
using consistent
naming
and
naming convention is is also quite
appropriate so thank you for that
okay
thank you thank you chief
gustavo
you're next go ahead
yeah can you hear me yeah
wonderful things so i have two general
opponents one is i mean as
most of the participants in this group
at some point in our careers we have to
implement
a registry or registration
and over time i learned that
i mean there are going to be conflicts
because the risk is going to be dynamic
obviously and then the contracts local
law all of these things are also
dynamic
so i was wondering if
that draft should say something like uh
if there are some conflicts between
definitions between local law contracts
or policy and draft and the dictionary
itself
you need to go on and look for your own
like legal advisor for any kind of help
i mean i learned over my career uh that
when there are conflicts i should try to
go and look to the legal advisor of the
company to understand
what should i do right
so it's kind of a suggestion just maybe
say there that that is hey guys if you
find in conflicts go on and find some
kind of legal
uh
advice or
something like that
and the second comment is i think that
the draft mentions there are 2.1 once
the registry is available
the definitions could change right
so
i think this is issues for some kind of
versioning so it's a definition change
it would be nice to know what was the
definition at a certain point in time
like at this point in time the decision
was this and then
on this specific point in time it
changed to this other thing because that
also could help in case there are some
legal
whatever things with you know with legal
stuff
so those are
yeah very interesting are you suggesting
that the registry should contain the
history of the definitions
uh even if they've changed over time
yes
i i think that's that's why what it's
suggesting because normally when you go
to an register you can see
like the current version right that you
don't have like a version i mean usually
right i don't know if in the general
street we have an example of
array history with versioning but some
kind of version it should be should be
there or notes or something that says
this change from this to this at this
point in time
yeah i understand what you're saying i
don't have any
direct experience with that uh in this
context are there people is this come up
in other situations where
uh
an iana registry
has revision history
as part of the registry
surely there is someone who is expert
and knows all of that
well i i i wanted to make a comment and
that is not
much i had to opt for a moment but
isn't it in the academic world the
definition is supposed to be a
definition and never changes anywhere in
the future
that's the definition of a definition
well you wouldn't want it to change very
often
i see somebody at the queue in the room
by the way but you have to register a
new echo first before you can speak
otherwise i cannot open the tube right
um
jim you're in the queue as well
making a comment about this
yeah um
you know i i um
i think you know in my mind as i think
about this uh for this document
um i don't know the answer specifically
to what ayanna does i'm not aware
personally of any history being
maintained and i am a registry but i
wouldn't consider myself an expert
there's just way
too much going on there so that's a
question that we could certainly ask
if we think it's useful
what does occur to me though is that um
there was a question earlier and i'm
sorry i i forget who asked the question
oh michelle is here um
and she's saying in the chat room that
there are examples of versioning within
ayanna registries
not many but she recalls a few she'll
have to find some examples for us
she's offering to do that which is very
kind so thank you michelle for that but
the other thing that occurs to me is um
there's a question earlier steve i'm
sorry i forget who asked the question
uh
but a a comment about uh whether or not
uh there's any concern about
um you know contracts and regulations
and laws that might impact what a uh an
element looks like and there was a
related question about should we care
more about the semantics or the syntax
of the element seems to me this fits
into the same category maybe it's
appropriate to take a little bit of a
step back here and just
think about where we're trying to go
with this document
i shouldn't say we uh at the working
group you know you where you want to go
with this document and um uh and and um
uh what you want to do there i i don't
know if that's that's that's a proper
thing to do
um so i i just leave the question
anyway thanks
yeah thank you well um
[Music]
the devil's always in the details uh
general attitude here is that we're not
trying to
um
solve
conflicts uh so much as provide common
terminology where common terminology is
sensible
and then if there are
uh issues about how it gets used or what
it means or something that those get
pushed up a level into the proper venues
but not this one
um
and
this this is intended to sit underneath
if you will uh any debates about uh
policy related things or
legal issues
but
inevitably i can i can envision
situations where
the mere fact of trying to make the
separation between what is commonly
understood and aware of the local
interpretations could lead to some
interesting things for example
and i'm just making this up as i go here
pretty much um
that
if we ask um
uh
if we have
there was a reference to a data element
that defines whether or not the um
the registration is for a legal person
or for a natural person the uh a
question that an attorney might ask is
where is the jurisdiction for that for
that uh
decision that is uh legal versus natural
in which jurisdiction
and so one that might force the addition
of yet another data element or some way
of adding that to the uh to the
dictionary
in which case
i would say
this exercise turns out to be useful in
bringing subtle things to the surface
that are otherwise implicit
but that's downstream a bit
and i have to interrupt you here a bit
steve because we're getting a little bit
short on time we have three more people
in the queue and we have one minute for
them
so
go ahead if you can make it quick
hello can you hear me
yep
perfect this is
just following up on the
the topic of this historical information
or or on ayana registries
one
i guess not quite exactly and
and
in a registry but the idn
repository
the repository of item tables
uses some form of
tracking of historical versions
considering that archived id and tables
are also available
as published by ayanna maybe that's one
approach that can be seen as a one
example
okay next jonathan okay do you have any
quick remark
i do i think i muted myself can you hear
me yeah
perfect uh thank you so i have to put on
my my hat as uh representing registrars
uh inside the icann world despite my
personal opinions about this i think is
a good idea
um there are some concerns about some of
the fields being collected or how
they're defined for the registrar
information
and
uh
the the hope was uh one
that registrars um
there's a lot of variation
in what information may or may not be
collected at registrars based upon their
business model uh and the presence of
fields um may beg the question among
those who are data collectors
as to why something maybe is or is not
there among those who might request data
that is
where they're seeking to get all the
data they possibly can
and
i think there's some some time and
thought needs to be put into
what what fields maybe
should or shouldn't be there
and and i'm just that's a collection of
feedback from among registrars and again
i'm i'm
stating that out of responsibility
despite maybe my personal feelings on
that
thank you
yeah thank you jordan and just dip
you have a comment go ahead and then
steve can perhaps give a closing remark
uh hi this is jasdeep singh erin
so
one suggestion um this is for steve and
heather
this is primarily right now sounds dnr
centric
but if you have rar side
so
one suggestion would be that the
starting point could be
this is just an input
if you look at rdap
that is one common protocol between dnrs
and rars
and it defines data structures pretty
well
covering the processes for both
types of registries and of course
epp then specializes that from the
provisioning angle further so one
suggestion would be that to help capture
the right
set of uh
data elements
that could be one of the good starting
points
so just wanted to suggest that
especially
thank you justin
um steve one closing remark five seconds
thank you and we need a document shepard
yeah okay thank you
then we will move on with the agenda and
we have one more presentation which is
new work
uh jim can you bring up the slides
and it's mario
who's going to present something
about epp over http yeah but i i don't
know if
it would be better to
leave the time
for
james presentation james
comment about
up
uh so are you saying don't do your
presentation but have james's comment
no jim james said you go ahead mario
okay you can make the
comment on the mailing list as well of
course okay okay okay no problem
uh
this is a presentation about the recent
document we have submitted
as a joint proposal
by
dot it and dot pl
a few introductory words about this
document
it doesn't aim to be a revolutionary
proposal
just aims to define the rules for
implementing app over http
next slide please
uh
what what
could be the motivation of implementing
fbp over http http is
as
is loosely coupled with the network so
you don't have to deal with all the low
level details typical of tcp programming
it provides
a well-known current server
communication model that is supported
by
largely by
all the
platform software platform available
it it's simple to
its simplicity
reduces the development time and
it must be noted that
most of the burden
of
handling
the connection this the http session and
the request and the responses is
normally done by a an application server
the
with regard to this gap the speed gap
between http and tcp
http has become faster
version vibration and now
we can say that
that gap is not so large as in the past
about load balancing we can say that
load balancing can be more easily
implemented at uh
lawyer 7 that at lawyer 4 because most
of the load balancer uh
our software are
instead
load balancer
at lawyer 4 are more dependent on the
hardware
and as
correctly pointed out by gavin in his
feedback
on the my little list
if
the migration to cloud is the future
migrating an http server to cloud
requirements effort then at ntcp server
next slide please
so
how
app messages are exchanged
in this proposal the client must use the
http post method tuition epp command
and the server receiving a request
returned the ppms the pp response in the
response body
setting the content length
either to indicate
the byte length of the entity body no
message information uh
must be issued
through any other part of of the request
or the response so there is a clear
distinction between the application
level
and the
transport level
next slide please
a
session
are implemented the epp sessions are
implemented by using the mechanism
described in rfc
server receiving an epp logging
must you
common must use this set cookie
responsibility to send a token also
known as the session id
uh that the client will will use to to
in the future request
in within the scope of the fpp session
the name of the cookie attribute is not
relevant
and
it depends on the implementation this is
an example of
a
set cookie attribute setting
the the session id and the use and the
client server using this the session id
in the in the
subsequent request
next
slide please
the session uh
uh ended by the client uh by submitting
the
the app logout command
a self-receiving mpp logout command must
end the ppp session invalidating the the
session after having issued the response
obviously
a pc ep session
that are considered the inactive for
more than several that they find a
period that
can be ended by the server itself
uh
next slide please
uh the command
does not
is the only common that can be issued
outside in a pc an epp session together
we obviously with the people login
to start the session in such a case the
service must return the greatest
response without starting a session
for example it can
no no cookie at all or it can
return a inspired cookie
obviously a client may issue the the low
command
within an ep session for example to keep
it alive
next slide please
just to emphasize the
clear distinction between the
application lawyer and the
transport lawyer there there is no mix
between the
return codes provided by http and epp so
each http error codes must be used for
signaling only http request failure
and app error codes must be used for
signaling app
common failure so
this means that the http retro code 200
is used for both successful and
successful
epp requests
next slide please
we have one more minute mario
okay
we have two implementation they are
stable they are
live implementation they are they have
been working for
many years
in more than a decade
next slide please
and
two words about the security
consideration
http over tls must be used to protect
sensitive information while in transit
services are
recommended to implement additional
measure to verify the client
there are some
measures suggested in the slide
service may require clients to present
valid
x
dot
digital certificate issued by recognized
certification authority next slide
please the final
and there are some other
possible
additional
security measures to protect to prevent
the session id to be uh from being
ejected and a
service are finally recommended to
control the number of simultaneous open
ep session and http connection to
mitigate
the risk of
resource starvation
there is two other slides but i would
like to stop here because they are about
a lot balancing and the and this
it is described in
in an appendix of the document
okay thank you mario we are waiting the
final note sorry is that uh
the authors would like
to
would like to ask the working group to
consider this document
for that option and then please take
that to the mailing list mario of course
okay yes
yes so this is always from the speech
registry
i have a super minor command i i i think
the document should be called epp over
https
and then
to hd
to https i want to say that the document
should reference the uh
for the security considerations from the
security working group about which tls
version to use and which tls ciphers and
and so on because that
i think is not an expertise of our
working group
and lastly i have the reference http 3
in the document
but http 3 allows you to
basically have several sessions inside
the same connection and something of
that mapping
would at least been
talked about in the document
okay thank you
uh gavin
yeah thank you kevin brown centronic um
all right already said what i said
wanted to say about http 3's streams but
i did want to note
in security considerations um
it makes uh the the the draft makes um
ip based access control a mutual tls
optional which is a regression from
the the current specification for a bpp
over tcp or opp over tls where they are
mandatory i think i've no particular
objection to that but i think it needs
to be noted in the draft that the the
the term there is a difference there in
the security profile of the two
different transport protocols
okay thank you gavin
and then final remark from jim jin go
ahead
thank you antoine the far too many gems
in this working group
my name is jim reed
i'm
just violently opposed to cookies in any
possible shape or form i just don't like
them and i don't understand why you
would need to complicate
the session for an app with having
cookies in there and deal with the
issues of stale cookies and refreshing
cookies and all that stuff why not just
to limit that what benefit do we get for
an epp session that has cookies i don't
see the need for it
can i answer
yes you can now
firstly i would like to answer to rick
we
decided the title of the
document uh that is
compliant to the the name of uh
rfc
uh 57
34 so
[Music]
the name of that document is
app over tcp no not over tls so
in the same way
i i
i i entitled the the document app over
uh app over http and on and not or app
over
https but in the document is stated that
tls is required so
why we use
the cookies because we adopt a
standardized
method to
map a
an applicative an application an
application session to a
an http session this is the
the the the
standard the way
we adopt
we have been adopting for many years so
there is no way there's no problem in
refreshing the cookies because it's
something that uh
libraries supporting http requests and
responses and sessions
are
accustomed to to to manage so
you don't need to
make
to to implement
nothing party nothing special because uh
you you
need only for for the client for example
to
enable cookies management
and that's it so uh
i i think that this is a a
a simple way to
to to manage a
session for for for an fpp client
in the sake of time we really have to
close here um in the form of cookies you
know just because people are standardly
using it doesn't mean that it's good to
use them so we may take that discussion
on the mailing list jim because we're
really running out of time where 10
minutes later okay thanks mario
yeah
um and with that we come to the end of
our agenda if there are no any other
business this is a last call for any
other business if we can do it in one
minute
and i don't see any hands
and with that i think
we ran a little bit over time that was
not expected but it was a good session
uh see you all on the mailing list and
let's continue the discussions there and
with that i adjourned this meeting thank
you all and thank you for who was taking
the minute jim
um there are a variety of people rick
and i brick wilhelm and i were mostly
putting notes in the in the chat in the
note-taking okay
we're taking the minutes and let's see
each other on the mailing list and
hopefully soon next time i think that
will be
philadelphia right philadelphia yep
okay bye
bye