one two three four
no i don't do this
three
yes
david i see
three decks of slides in the tracker and
no i see four decks of slides in the
tracker and three decks in me taco
so we appeared
there's a refresh button at the top
and that one shows four for me after i
push to refresh
david do you see the slides for
not a ctp not 3.1
yes
i do see them also i do after pressing
the refresh button
yeah they're there
okay
on the other hand me duck always just
showing me
a new deck is being shared so not
getting anything out of that
hang on let's see if that's working now
no i still have problems let me go take
out my corporate firewall see if that
improves things
so
okay
so this will be tsvwg
we will wait just a couple of minutes
for people to enter the room
as in other sessions we'll be taking the
queue via me techo
so if you want to speak please join the
queue in me techo and we'll try and
coordinate with
remote participants as well as people in
the room
and take you in line when you
are here and you wish to speak at the
mic
and when it comes your turn just go
ahead and speak at the mic
we currently have
three of our four decks of slides loaded
into mateco
and
we will start in
just two minutes time we'll need a note
taker
as usual
so we'd love to have a volunteer of a
note taker
so
right i guess we'll start this is tsvwg
welcome to vienna
welcome if you're a remote participant
welcome to our local participants
the three chairs of tsvwg are
myself gauri fergus
where's eddie who's remote and david
black who is also remote
so this meeting like all the meetings
that the ietf holds is covered by the
ietf notewhile
if you haven't seen this please read it
if you have seen it
please look at it again if you have any
queries about ipr and what to discuss in
front of other people
our policy is quite simple and quite
clear
please just stick to the policy
we need help in tsvwg with various
things
and of course to start a
tsvwg meeting we need help with the
notetaker
at this point we pause and we wait for
somebody to volunteer as a note taker
sure it will
okay this
gets an honorable point
and um we shall work harder to find
someone else next time but thank you
ever so much stewart
stewart cheshire will take some notes
and we will
publish those at the end of the meeting
if you're going to submit future work to
this working group it's helpful to tell
the chairs in advance
it's helpful to write an internet draft
probably essentially if you wish to
present
and please add tsvwg somewhere in the
draft name so we can flag it in the id
in the id tracker
we're using the meat echo mic here
so
this is your instructions for using meat
echo if you haven't used it um simply
press the hand button and we will see
you in the queue here
don't use the mic icon if you're
actually in this room
if you're using the
qr code to log in take the blue sheets
then you won't have a mic button on your
app
and that's a note that we do need people
to use the qr code so we can
take the blue sheet record of who's in
attendance so if you haven't scanned the
qr code please do
we have a number of documents that were
progressing through the working group
and as ever document quality relies on
reviews
so if you'd like the documents that you
care about to be reviewed please put in
effort to review other documents
review comments can be anything from
people
helping to improve particular texts
to people raising up issues to be
discussed
a lack of reviews probably indicates a
lack of care
that the document is finally published
so please do review
and if you wanted something new to look
at that's coming up towards a working
group last call
there's the udp options and dscp
considerations work which are two things
which
probably could do with reviews soon
so our achievements and accomplishments
are we have published no rfc since
ietf112
which is called a be kind to our area
director period
we have a number queued up to go to our
area director
and
we have one id still at the rfc editor
which has been through review and will
be published shortly which is 496 obese
five ideas are with working group chairs
and authors
indicating to our ads that things are
heading their way soon
the ecnn cups um still has some text to
be refined
and then we'll receive a shepherd write
up and be sent for publication
we don't anticipate the need for further
working group input here but we will
send the changes proposed to the list so
you can confirm that the document in its
final state is ready for progression
ecn for tunnels that use shim headers
has already been through this process
but is paired with the above draft
then we have the three l4s ids
um which wes might want to say a few
words to if you're online wise
sure
so uh
these are all post working group last
call at the moment
uh we've solicited on the mailing list
for
everyone who
had commented and was expecting
some changes to make sure that the
changes match their expectations
and
we discussed at the
interim meeting prior
the
solicitation of inputs on the shepard
write-ups and i have a huge
um number of responses on those which
have been working through
and i think there are only a couple of
small points
left
to be
taken care of still
so i think they're very close to
being complete and
i plan to wrap those up with the people
i've been corresponding with uh on
this week and
get these
to the area director
uh
in a week or so
so thank you and if you have any
questions about these particular drafts
please um send them to the chairs
and where's will be shepherding the
process
as they proceed towards publication
and we have a number of remaining
working group ids
we have the l4s ops guidance which we'll
be talking about
nqb which we'll also be discussing
udp options
and dplp mtud for udp options three and
four will be taken on friday
dtls and sctp an sctp nut will be taken
today
assigning a new recommended dscp and how
you might go about this and what might
be the hurdles to getting a good dscp
will be discussed on friday
and multipath dccp will also be
discussed on friday
we did a milestone review
and
when we did these slides we had three
milestones which were from may 2002
two or two two and september two or two
two
and
milestones which were being revised for
mpdccp dtls
and the dstp considerations
i think they're either approved or
they're in the process of being approved
so
they will appear in the tracker if you
look
um
various other milestones were
reviewed we've decided as working group
chairs we're going to try and keep our
milestones up to date
working groups have to decide what
they're going to do with milestones
whether they think they're superfluous
or whether they think they're helpful
we've decided that they're useful
targets
and therefore we're going to try and
refresh them and keep them sensible and
try and hope well try our best to
facilitate getting the documents
published before the milestone is due
so the milestone
is the date at which we expect this work
to conclude
beforehand is always good
we have a number of liaisons and
announcements
i'm not aware of any new liaison updates
david do you have anything to say under
the air zones
the wba liaison was responded to about a
year ago
we basically said
try not to use quite so many dscps and
suggest that wba and 3gpp
get coordinated on this nothing has been
heard since i think we can take this off
future agendas
okay and similarly the liaison requests
on
dtls
was encouragement to produce the
document to submit it to
publication so that e3 gpp could
reference it and the gsma relays on
related to multi-path dccp
and their expectations for that
which we discussed previously so nothing
new here
there is a request for doing proposed
work on a new ccid
i'm bringing this up here just for the
point of view of coordination
and this is relates to the datagram
congestion control protocol
it's a proposal to add a ccid relating
to bbr
and at the moment bbr is an item of
discussion as an algorithm in iccrg
so there is nothing that the transport
working group here will do until the
algorithm has been approved for
progression in the ietf and when it has
we can come and determine whether a ccid
is appropriate useful and interesting
for us to progress
so if you're interested in this space go
read the draft
help facilitate the work and encourage
the publication of a bbr spec and we
will move forward
in addition i want to mention that the
hpcc plus plus draft has a
uh has a an agenda slot in rtg wg
routing working group next at next hour
um yeah it's got some relationship to
routing but
it probably belongs over in transport
and i think the suggestion is that uh
iccrg ought to have a look at this uh in
general it'd be good to think about what
the transport area ought to be doing in
the way of data center
congestion control
thanks david as ever
data center and internet and not that
far apart and we have to understand how
to do congestion control involved
so that's a good comment keep your eyes
on that
and we have our agenda
the agenda asks what's currently
put up looks like this
if you're aware of it today is monday
and we have three topics for discussion
today
relating to
sctp and also the l4s ops draft
and
we'll take comments on the agenda if we
have any
if you wish to
suggest amendments or corrections please
do
i'll also show the agenda for the
friday meeting
the second slot
for tsvwg will be on friday
session two we'll look at these topics
we don't currently have any other
business scheduled
and we do expect some discussion of the
atss
um
work
in 3gpp which is a work item in the side
meeting probably following the friday
session i will send announcements
to the
to the list
with details about how to participate if
you're interested
any other agenda items or anything else
that you feel you wish to mention on the
chair slides then we've just
the first of our
topics for today
maybe the only agenda bashing will be if
when i go to the meet echo i don't find
slides for michael's item 3.1 we will
take michael at the end of the session
rather than the beginning because
that will give us time to work out how
we're going to get slides to you
we have michael's site here by magic so
michael you'll be
on first
to talk about a ctp
nut so this is a
item which we're encouraging discussion
on to figure out what the working group
should do
with a
id that's been around for probably one
of the longest
on our list
and
it's one that we need to determine what
the next steps are so michael go ahead
and talk and at the end we'll ask what
those next steps should be over to you
michael
okay thank you um
can you go to the next slide
yeah so this is this is about a draft
which has been around for a long long
time
um we had working group last call um
we got um
there was a transition
of the transport ads so we got two
reviews from magnus and martin
and
right now we have an alternate proposal
from ericsson which i
provided a link to go to the next slide
so
to given
a very high level view why we are
talking about sctp and net
it basically comes down that an an sctp
endpoint can have multiple ip addresses
but only a single port number
so
the partner my concept is shared between
udp tcp dccp
udp light and http but when it comes to
this multi-homing thing
it's only a single port number and that
has the consequence that if you have
multiple path towards your peer
if you want to change the part number it
has to be done
consistently on all the paths
so
assuming that the middle boxes are not
communicating to each other this means
you
can't translate the port number
and
this
has
then as a consequence what are you doing
if you have local port number collisions
so if you have two endpoints local
endpoints inside the private networks
which want to talk to the same
appear and they choose the same port
number udp or tcp based net would just
remap the port number and that's fine
and you can't do this for http so
this is why
to address this problem
a long time ago we
figured out that you can use the port
numbers and the verification tag which
is sap specific field
um like a connection identifier and then
you can
handle these local port number
collisions
so that's why
we thought it's a good or the authors
thought it's a good idea to specify
something um
http specific next slide
so this is basically a summary of the
comments
um
we got from the leds i haven't marked
with jd says
some of the comments were given by both
ads and
some only by one but it doesn't matter
um
we should address them
all or try to so the first one is that
um ip fragmentation handling um at the
net was an issue but i think we can deal
with that like using the same
terminology as done for udp or tcp
so that's not very hard
the
[Music]
the the question was how to
control the net friendly behavior which
is endpoints have to behave
in a specific way
when they are dealing with this net
scenario and
um the idea
was
was um just um if if one of the local
addresses is a private one you do this
or you have a socket option that's laid
out we can make that clearer that's not
that complicated um improved
multi-homing support was
um was asked for this means we can
have more even more examples um
showing that
um
it was asked for
that the nets support multiple external
addresses so we were focusing on the
simple case that only one external
address is available but this actually
means you have to have another field in
the netbinding table
then the remote address was taken out of
the net binding table based on a
research paper from
[Music]
australia
and that simplified a lot but
the question was
please bring it back at least if we are
not using this advanced version
um the the sap specific version of net
um it was asked
if the processing of http packets can be
simplified so that the net
function does not have to power the
packets
and
behave differently based on the chunk
type
when to add the state and whether an ad
function should send packets at all
because
right now the document
according to the document the net
function will send packets
and the last one is um the
the notion of http associations has to
be changed um because you
must support multiple associations with
the same port numbers
and that means you have to distinguish
them between
you have to distinguish them using the
verification tag
um
the issues here are have
ordered in a specific way
the
more easily to address one are on the
top of the more substantial ones are on
the bottom so if you go to the next
slide
i have listed possible ways forward um
the the first one is to stick with the
with this method
we are currently proposing
um
adding the
entries to the net table will add
complexity which is or i mean this is
already not
trivial so it adds complexity it gets
complexibility but we can address issue
two to five
um the nuts
the the the fragmentation stuff is just
wording i mean
you can't do anything wrong
um
we do have uh always uh the possibility
that the endpoints do not support this
additional mode so there is a fallback
mechanism on basically just using the
fallback mechanism taking out all the
sctp specific things
um is a possibility which would address
issue two to seven
um
so that would mean don't use the
verification tag don't disable restart
um add the external
remote addresses to the nut binding
table and basically this comes down to
a net function
which is not http aware it's just
outgoing packets establish
a relation you don't change port numbers
and that's it the drawback is that um
in case of a local port number
collisions you can't do anything um
so
the association can't be established
so that's the
well i would say um
the the
this especially this does not change the
definition of the association in the
endpoints
so this seems to be
addressing most of the issues the third
alternative is to drop this document at
all and go with the
ericsson proposal
or
the fourth way is to drop the work at
all and say
um if if we come up with a document
which
describes an almost http unaware not
we don't have to do
uh the work here
these are the four options i see and i
think it's the last slide right gauri
it is the last slide
and the fifth option
is propose something else
but do it now
so okay yeah i mean yeah
and my default option could be four or
could be one or two i mean um
literally we need people to come to the
mic and say whether
one or two is acceptable
as a way forward we've been working as a
working group on this for a while if
anyone who's commented or anyone who has
new insight
wishes to comment on whether one or two
is acceptable
i guess if you don't care then my job's
really easy
we've had a lot of review it's been
around for a lot of time we can go ahead
but if you care to
take up options one or two
can you offer some comment that
about this or agree to offer some
comment on the list
on the chat
colin asked if there are um
people having large-scale nets
i'm not aware of that
what i am aware of is
an implementation done by the australian
university
for freebsd and based on that
they did experiments and measurements on
scalability they took out they suggested
to take out the
remote address from the nut binding
table
yeah that was the remote address
discussion
okay claudio would you like to say
something
i mean
actually you need to speak up a little
bit we can't hear you i'm sorry
sorry it is
it doesn't work
i mean the the point here is
the reason why
i was trying to make some work here is
that rather than a big scaling that may
system may not exist yet
the
there is a problem
and if the problem is
that
what we are in instantiating today
in the cloud
so being interested in different name
phrasal and in different virtual
machines here
is network node that have acidity
connectivity so if this was not existing
before now the problem is actually and i
i think that and since the networking
the panel network using cloud is
provided here now
then we need to have a way forward
being one of
the ones
here or maybe
a brand new idea but
it is a problem that is just opened up
could i check if people in the room
heard the comment it was very difficult
on the stage to hear
ah um
can you
hear me
we could see you we could hear you but
it's very
[Music]
even soft is not the right thing it
could be the wrong mic is used
if you if you're using your headset
microphone
but moving the boom closer to your mouth
will probably help
can you hear me now
no it is still the same it is muffled
so moving
moving moving your microphone on your
headset close up to your mouth
now
not really no
hello
i think i have problems
that seems to be an improvement no it's
better
try again and speak up
yeah and if you talk loudly we can hear
you hello um but we missed the last
comment i'm afraid
okay you're coming through now please
repeat what you were saying
hello can you hear me now
yes hear me now
go ahead
i can't hear you
so
your microphone is now working so sorry
your microphone is now working and
now you just need you to be able to hear
us
okay we think i think one of the
comments he tried to make is that
the use case they have in mind is
something cloud based stuff
sure and
uh the document
the the original intention for the
document was not focusing on that
so
um
yeah i mean
michael my comment still is
can people live with
the
option one presented here and can they
live with option two uh the change of
scenario yeah it was understood in the
wicking group last call and it would be
good to address more cases if it's
possible
and
we need to decide on whether one or two
are acceptable i see martin in the line
and
i'd like to hear from martin i'd also
like to claudio afterwards
and if we can't get an audio connection
we can fold this up on a one-to-one
basis that would be easy so go ahead
martin yeah so martin duke google um
so with ad hat on um
i don't have a strong opinion here as
long as we have you know good consensus
in the group
um
as an individual i'd like to ask michael
as the editor um
if he has a preferred alternative of
these four
what his technical opinion is
well my opinion is
solution two addresses more issues
so it's more work than solution one but
um the issues brought up i mean
i can't argue them
and um
so solution two addresses
more of them
if it makes um
people happy in in a cloud environment
we have to see at least you don't have
to change the endpoints
you have the risk of higher
local port number collisions
okay thank you
thank you
claudio do you want to have one last say
or have you
decided we'll follow up off list go
ahead if you can either i can speak or i
can listen to so it is very hard for me
but i
what i say is that
we are running a prototype on option 3
and see what is possible to do
with that it's not ready yet but
hopefully it will be ready soon and i
will
share the result
the idea is that we will
work on the not support for linux and
then
possibly
do some implementation based on user
space http from vst
all of this will be
done in the open source
thank you and we'll follow up on the
list as well of course magnus please
yeah magnus western
my understanding of this problematic is
that we have three hexes we have one
which is can we support really support
multi
multi-homing well
the other axis is how many concurrent
sessions can we support
and that's the third is then the output
so to say is is how complex the solution
is so you can support multi-homing but
very few sessions with relatively low
complexity
or you can go
and i i think it's a question of
are we fine with maybe supporting
multi-homing
and how about supporting few sessions
and it might actually be sufficient for
the cloud uh
deployment cases
okay yeah and
we'll take collin
colin jenkins
so colin jones um
one i mean the issues in one seem sort
of broken and i don't see how to solve
them in any way but talking about so so
i'm not in favor of that but to also my
understanding of that uh and i could be
confused i don't
really see how that isn't true like any
time you just use the ip address and
have one-to-one mappings
um you have problems that anybody can
just scan through all the ports and now
your your nat is totally ddos like it's
totally trivial to ddos anything with
that type of scenario so i don't
actually really see how two works i i
think that as you dig into that
um you know there's no way to really
tell whether there was a conflict uh you
have to somehow drop the packets that
have a conflict otherwise you have two
two different things trying to use the
same port
um i mean i've seen many people not in
sctp but i've seen this tried in udp
multiple times and i've never seen it
work and i can't imagine why all the udp
problems with that type of solution
don't exactly map over to sctp as well
so i'm having a really hard time
understanding how to is a viable option
okay um maybe one point um
so right now
the
the the idea is that
um state can be added only by internal
hosts
and if there is a port number collision
the net box sends a packet back
indicating that so
um
a node in the private network can
can
um
can do a ddos by establishing a lot of
state yes that's true
um
if that if that is not a ddos but by
chance
and the local endpoint is not relying on
that particular port
it can
it gets a notification from the middle
box that this port is taken and it can
choose a different form and reconnect
but a local node can do adidas yes
thank you right we're going to have to
decide one of these ways forward and
we're going to have to decide shortly
after this meeting
there is obviously time to discuss on
list and obviously time to get people
together to find their opinions but we
do have to make a decision because the
working groups have the document for a
long time
so i'd encourage people to try and
follow up on what they've just said at
the mic or what they think on the list
if you're in any doubt please forward to
the chairs and we will try and help
to understand the positions and then we
will call out a possible way forward for
the working group
thank you for the talk
we'll take the next presentation
it was you
and
we have oh i have to press share
okay so magnus on dtls over http go
ahead minus yes so let's see just
trying to eat the mica um so i'm uh
magnus westland um my co-author is
claudio for theory and john matson um
next slide
so we've been working on this draft and
uh
i mean the highest point is here we're
trying to address the user message limit
of detail assist the paper rfc 623
uh we have this communication with gdp
etcetera they have a problem in the
several of their ram protocols
since last meeting we have received some
feedback from liang
we also hadn't
contracted out an implementation of the
specification we got some feedback we
have implemented some of these so far
and it continues
and i have to
remind you that there's
two ipr declarations from ericsson on
this document
next slide
so this update for this towards this
meeting was fairly significant
not in solution space but also a lot of
details clarifications etc about solving
issues
we clarified about the theoretical
message length limitations
and we're saying that basically up to
2.2 to the power 64 minus one byte is
is is i mean you won't really limit the
support of or say the need for
supporting pointers etc
um
but that's the potential for a message
size
which i think is reasonable
we also look into some of these ssb api
limitations might limit the sender
further
but shouldn't be an issue for a receiver
so
a sender that knows
he can deal with or ensure that you have
a stack that matches that um we also
looked into stream usage update
there's
this is minor in some sense but actually
most main point here is
detail ssdp before details process the
message doesn't know what's incoming if
that's user data or a detailer's message
that has some impact anyway of how you
can send this so we thought you were be
able to really relax the limitation of
how it's ending and it's up to the
sender so to say to
send on whatever stream they want to
because it's anyway doesn't matter until
the detailer stack process the message
uh we also looked into shutdown
procedures clarifying those we have a
new section on http api considerations
trying to note what kind of
special functionality you might need on
the satb stack to support as well
and the number of clarifications on
various things so it's a fairly large
update if you looked at the draft and
the diff so
next slide
so i want to remind you about what we're
really addressing in this draft compared
to rfc 683
so it's the message message length
we also have the
sap association handshake now negotiates
to support of details or sdp
we're trying to minimize the impact on
ulp protocol
basically having is
so if
what you can support in sctp we can
basically support over data ssdp also
and it's slightly wider than what 683 or
the number of features is that's
slightly easier to use
or say no limits
um
addressing this uh i want to note i mean
that 683
per its original publication it was
using details 1.0 had less limitation
and what it has now since rc 8996 forced
details upgrade to 1.2
because
for example to support a long-lived sap
association details 1.2 has the
renegotiation
security issues which has to do with
there are some challenges there are
implementing security there have been
some attacks etc so people has a
tendency to turn it off so availability
prospects and some challenge
implementations it also limits the
number of negotiations to 65k
and for detail is 1.3
there is no renegotiation longer with
mutual authentication
the only thing you can do is a key
update on and that doesn't update the
mast secret
which means that you don't re-key sstp
off either
so your session length is now much more
limited due to basically when you're
running out of stp health key usages
you have to terminate the session
restart
and you will not have any forward
secrecy during that re any updates you
do for details 1.3
so that's basically
some of these challenges here and and
then we also have the sntp auth
i mean uh hmac show one is is
is aging
you probably want something newer for
the future so um but yeah so let's go on
so that being some discussion on the
main list but
from my perspective
i think there's two realistic ways
forward
obsoleting rfc 683 when publishing draft
src
which would have been the default
publishing as an alternative rfc to 1683
without obsoleting is another
and that would allow people to update
and if etc if they want to do something
try to do something there which doesn't
infringe the ipr
um
or
see what you can do um
so i mean 683 has limited applicability
and has its security issues so i think
something maybe needs to be done anyway
but it's
uh so
yeah i think we can go into some
discussion i think michael had a
slightly different view of this so
i'd like to take discussion on this side
if we can yeah and
as a chair i can say that we would be
okay if the working group decides to not
obsolete 68
686083 using this draft we can make that
decision later if we wish to as a
working group so it is a possibility
so um what do people think about the
options and what do people want to say
in response to this particular proposal
for a way forward
anybody got any questions or comments
michael
go ahead michael
yeah i'm clicking
i am
um
i i
i answer to the to the mailing list so
from a technical point of view i think
rc 6083 needs to be updated um
i'm not arguing on any technical
things right now
my point is that
in my view dtls for http is something
like tls for tcp or dtls for udp so
um replacing
an rc which
which is which you can implement in open
source and which you can use by a
document
proposed by
a company
enforcing its own ipr
seems to me suboptimal i mean up to now
we have every everything we did in http
was
backed up by open source
and
at least when it came to working group
last call we had some implementations
and this is not possible here
so
[Music]
that's why
i'm not arguing technically but the ipr
stuff
hold by
the company
working on this document is something
which
i'm not in favor of
no
understood um
from my perspective i always want to
ensure that we're
i would say that we then in that case if
you're willing to maybe potentially
drive some alternatives here i would go
with then
b so we or at least two word speed is
for no so we don't get stuck in a
situation where no progress at all is
made
because
i mean we're doing this work to ensure
that gdp has a reference for something
that needs to resolve
uh and and and
ending up where we have no progress
and and just spend a lot of time working
on it that's
not productive at all so i wanted some
direction at least that enables us or 3d
people to make progress here in the end
and i i
i noticed that you might did suggest
that this should be taken to gdp but
that also doesn't feel particularly well
either so
i i see but i mean if we now decide that
this goes as an alternative um and it's
not updating rfc 6083 um i think
6083 needs an update so this would mean
bringing up another document at the ietf
um which doubles the load
and i'm so i'm
i mean and the other point is why should
anyone
i mean
normally things are brought to the ietf
to work on it in a community which
improves
the document quality and
for me
a company coming to the ietf wanting to
enforce its its ipr in a document just
means
if if i'm working for a competitor i
would just shut up and
don't say anything hope that there are
issues in the document and once the
document has been published file iprs
or even before that file ipr song
fixing this
so
but
i mean just leaving two documents
in parallel there and not saying
anything is also not i mean this helps
create gpp but
um
yeah but so i mean my question to you
michael are you willing to try to do
something about finding an alternative
here because i mean if if no one is
either doing an alternative
then we're at like some type of impasse
and it doesn't make any progress either
so
i would be willing on on what i would i
mean i would be willing to work on an
update on 6083 that's why i started to
to i'll be a co-author of your document
but
um
and if people are interested in it i'm
happy to do so but
um
if no one else is interested then it's
done
go ahead do whatever you want
i think i i can comment at this point so
um i will of course um offer the
opportunity for a ad to comment if he
wishes
but my understanding of what we've
talked about here is
that the working group could decide not
to update
um six or eight three by obsoleting it
so we we continue this work is is a
proposal that's on the table that
inevitably might mean that two further
things could happen
another id could emerge which updates
six or eight three
or by the time that this
what we're considering has reached
fruition we decide that 6083 should
finally be
obsoleted anyway because the ipr issues
have been either gone away or have been
encountered or
are well known whatever the outcome
so there is a way to proceed here which
means that we continue the work item
without doing the update with the
penalty that we may have to publish
another rfc either to obsolete 6083 or
to update it as a parallel spec
and i'm asking the working group and
we'll do via the mailing list whether
that is an acceptable way forward
does my id wish to say anything at this
point about creating two parallel specs
or does he wait want to wait and see
what the working group says
ah i i will confess to not having again
a terribly strong opinion here um
it is
it is a problem if we're in a situation
where
you know the bsd implementation which
thinks the relatively important one
cannot follow the spec
so um
i i i
i'm initially like fairly sympathetic to
the way you describe the story that that
may be
sticking this starting with b um i mean
i i don't hear anyone stepping up really
to write the the you know the the open
source ipr free
version of this
um
so if if
if if we want to
so it sounds to me like the unless the
ip unless the ipr rights are you know
loose enough to to allow this kind of
work
i it seems to me the outcome will be
that you have 60 83 still functional
and then a
then a alternative to 60 80 you know
alternative improvement to 6083 that
will be used by some implementations and
and i i i don't maybe necessarily
understand exactly what the
what the interoperability
implications of that are and and if
magnus can answer that that would be
interesting but um it seemed inevitably
we're driving in that direction yeah and
we may have to update 6083 anyway for
security reasons because the um the
security part of the spec changes
so
things security algorithms will be
obsoleted so
that may have to be maintained as a
separate document if we decide to go
along that path but i guess we
acknowledge this by going along this
path now and given that 3gpp needs this
um i don't think like doing nothing
doesn't strike me as a alternative
either so i know magnus can you speak at
all to
the interrupt the interoperability
issues of a 6083 and this
so i mean together the current draft is
of the new proposal is very clear on
when you're negotiating the handshake
using the uh
this uh
defined method for detecting it the 683
you basically
you have no clear indicator that you're
going to do 683 unless you you see it's
sctp off and then there's a detailed
handshake that's how you detect that
it's happening
and and this other one you're doing the
handshake in the association handshake
you will detect okay i want to do this
so you know that this is and and
if future proposal could do the same but
with the different identifiers you could
negotiate which you are doing so i think
there's
at least power existence is not an issue
okay excellent so then um if i
understand correctly
if you had a 60-83 endpoint um
well actually okay so let me back up so
with your draft if you had an employee
supporting your draft
and it
and try
they would not see this option from the
pier and so it would recognize what was
going on
with the 6083 endpoint it will see dtls
payloads
um and think that it is doing 6083 when
it's actually doing what your draft is
doing
no because so it's actually defined how
you fall back to 60 to 3 behavior from
from
from from our specified behavior and
it's it's you're never going to end up
there unless you have a policy for
willingly allowing it because it's
otherwise it will be security risk
so okay you will yeah all right i mean
it sounds like you've got an approach
and we can we can wordsmith it but
that's good um
uh yeah i mean i think ideally there
would be some sort of minimal update to
6083.
again
um
uh
it doesn't i don't it doesn't strike me
as there being enormous amount of energy
to do so um so it would be nice to
appear be in a place where we can live
without one
right i think that's a
a fair thing and if that emerges in the
future that can be always going to do
maintenance of aspects so this is okay
as well
okay
fine thanks this proposal will be taken
to the list and i'd happily work with
the people who've spoken here just to
make sure that the right proposal words
are written on when we send it to the
mailing list yeah okay how are we doing
on time we're a bit short um yeah let's
skip this then so and
there are additional slides shall we
yeah there was in time permits to
discuss an issue but it's actually
so
yeah um i think people can read those uh
i will post to the main list about the
issues or other things when we work with
it so we we have a few smaller there's
one thing with the first of those is
around details 1.2 is a bit
annoying but i think we probably have
one some way forward
we'll have to figure it something out
but yeah okay thank you yeah
please continue to discuss on the list
woo can we take one more talk
short no
you're asking me yeah i'm asking you
because you're in the room
which
how do we proceed on the lfs ops draft
in the few minutes we have remaining
even if we don't don't do the status
review on it
yeah let's just skip ahead to the
question and have some discussion yes
please
if there's room
for the next session we can go from
there
yeah we'll find room to discuss properly
but let's raise it
so the
you you have
the l4s
ops as the editing document you want to
cut straight to the question and give us
a very quick run through in one minute
to where we are are you online sure uh
yep i'm online
um yes let's get forward
yeah keep keep going um
keep going
um one there's one to do um left in the
draft um and so i'll be asking for
input from the working group on how to
um address that
uh that open question
um in the next slide
is the
um so no no updates to draft since the
last ietf um i do have a work in
progress draft o3 at this point only has
some typo fixes some misspellings etc
um uh
certainly new contributions would be
accepted if there are uh additional
uh materials that need to be covered in
the draft but i've not um
heard any contributions or comments of
that
nature since the last idea
so the original plan for this document
was for it to remain a draft during the
l4s experiment and
the
question here is is that still the
desired path forward
um
or should we be moving towards uh
finishing this and publishing as an rfc
i'll
give it to
comments
all right i'll do it myself i'll insert
myself in the mic um i would suggest
that it would benefit those who want to
work with l4s to declare victory on this
move it forward as an rfc shortly after
or with the alpharest drafts and then
immediately open a bisdraft uh to
capture things we learned dirt
learned during the alpha price
experiment um as
your slides show the draft is pretty
much stable i don't think there's any
major contributions and i think getting
it out a bit more broadly is probably a
good thing for all concerned
okay any other comments
yeah martin duke google um
during the l4s experiment is an
interesting phrasing to me like
like how long is that
at least one itf cycle
well that's that's no time in itf time
um i would just
i i have no i no no idea martin but i
would suggest having a draft open to
collect lessons learned as people learn
them would be a good thing and then
sometime the future we get to we we get
to have this slide on the best draft
fair enough i mean the question is
directed more to greg than to david's
proposal um
because i mean like you know
in theory the air force experience
continues until we publish ps
which seems like too long um
uh like i i don't know
i mean i guess my question would be to
what extent are operators like
either already running this or or like
poised to start like tomorrow
um like what are we expecting like very
quick operational experience to to
emerge in in like the next few months or
is it gonna be years and years before we
have
additional learnings to
improve this document
i would anticipate it's um
on the order of
small numbers of years before
we have significant deployment and and
operational experience um
not not weeks or
short numbers of months okay well then
as an individual um i would say that uh
that that answer tells me that maybe
david's solution is a good one
um but i'll give i know we're short on
time so okay thanks mirrors in the queue
yeah just a very quick plus one to
publish it right now okay i mean the
options we have in the working group to
consider are whether we freeze the
document
and we hold it because we think we're
going to immediately update it in the
short number of its cycles or we opt to
publish
so this is what greg's raising and this
is what we'd like feedback from we've
heard a few comments here we will of
course ask on the list to see if there
are any further comments but we've heard
the comments thank you ever so much for
contributing thank you for coming to
this meeting
and we will continue on friday with a
much longer slot
and do come and join us on friday please
thank you
[Music]
uh