um
[Music]
hi everyone
my name is thanks for joining this talk
i apologize for not being able to uh
be here live unfortunately i had a work
uh i had to take so i'm on in the
airplane right now
um lending in bologna
in just
one hour
all right let's start
so what we're gonna talk about
um
automated serverless security testing so
i don't know if anyone
uh if you all know uh serverless the
technology so we'll cover a little bit
about that as well
and then um
we'll dive into how you should be doing
security testing
um just
a little bit about me um
so i started working in serverless in
2017 very early for the technology just
started a year before
i started as head of security research
at protego labs um an israeli startup
that the runtime protection for service
applications
um the company got acquired by
checkpoint
and in 2019 um after six months i
decided to take this to the next level
and
co-founded a cloud essence another
israeli startup
doing uh security automated security
testing for serverless
we got acquired
last year
by contrast security now i'm leading uh
the country security research team
uh team is based in israel but i live in
florence not far away
so i'm not here also to answer questions
but if you want or you if you have any
feel free to reach me out at any um
channel
um let's start so cloud native uh
serverless is part of cloud native let's
talk about that so uh
actually um according to idc by 2021
which is
now
um
of newly developed uh enterprise
application will be developed as cloud
native applications it doesn't
necessarily mean just serverless but
based on hyper agile architecture we'll
discuss that a little bit
uh using containers microservices
services and functions uh serverless
functions
forester already
uh see um
a huge increase next year and this is
just uh trying to or going to grow and
grow with time
the transformation to cloud native i'm
sure you all experienced that
already began uh we're somewhere in the
middle where we have the
most advanced companies like uh or
pioneer companies like irobot and
skyscanner which
almost all tend to use mostly serverless
and cloud native um and then we have
uh along
a little bit down the road we have big
enterprises like coca-cola xerox att
mastercards and more which already
started this uh transformation but they
are still in the
hybrid
part cloud native part traditional
monolith application
but it's going there
all right so what is serverless or cloud
native development it's not just a
development pattern pattern it's a
different architecture it's a different
architecture instead of a monolith with
one flow there are
multiple dozens thousands and i've seen
application with ten thousands of
different resources each is a standalone
resource that is connected or configured
in some way to
continue the flow the cycles are not uh
not uh waterfall anymore there are
devops
devsecops if you heard super agile hyper
agile
flows
so the development process is really
fast
uh the processes are different usually
it's less manual so we don't have now a
new version a new server version that we
have to now have maintenance time or hey
now we release a new version so we
replaced the server completely no
everything is automated uh something new
new needs to come up the developer push
a function to production and configure
it to run as a blue green so it starts
with the old version whether together
with the new version and based on the
results
that takes place so everything is
automated
and also the decision making is
different it's not more top-down that
did the director the manager
takes the decision and
put it down or give it down to the
developer developers have more
responsibility they have more
power but of course as well
responsibility security is part of it
and we'll talk about that
security is now
in many cases part of the developer's
job not only to write secure code but to
understand security impacts in the cloud
and we'll discuss that
serverless architecture as i mentioned
it's kind of a puzzle because there are
many many different services this is
just
an example of a single app
each thing each uh component or each
resource or icon that you see here is a
different resource so the orange one are
usual lambdas you can see here these are
databases and some other buckets
and some other services
in this case aws based mostly
but each of it of those resources is
stateless
that means that you have to control
authentication access control input
everything within each of those
resources sometimes it's easy sometimes
it you can say okay this comes from a
tested zone so i'm not going to do that
it's a risk you take but fine
uh but you have to make sure
that this entire flow
is secured and you not don't just do it
at the perimeter
you don't put a session and then yeah
everything is sessions uh i can
take care of the user not always
functions are stateless
don't really understand so either you
maintain a state out of bound maybe in a
database or you have to take some
security measures and we'll discuss some
of those
during this talk
so what is gen serverless in general
there are a few
cloud providers
aws is the biggest one of course i think
it's
roughly 60 of the market then you have
azure ibm
google cloud
and some others
some of them like aws and azure
and some gcp offers a lot of services
some just small services like function
as a service you can find even in
cloudfront i think
um
alibaba has cloud and the other service
companies as well
but serverless just means a way of
executing code
which is
you don't have to maintain a server the
cloud will take care of everything of
everything apart from the code that you
run so when the code needs to run
a container spins up
by by the cloud provider and runs your
code but you don't have access to that
it's not it's not acting as a container
it just acts
as a wrapper to the code and then the
architecture is more event-based so it's
an event-based architecture
it's not
synchronous so it's not request response
typical
you also have that of course as part
part of the system maybe the apis
but it's more event based so something
happened and based on the configuration
that we've done in the cloud this
specific code will run it will write to
a database and then because the entry
based
entry was changed then another code
would run process the data
and upload it to an f3 bucket then
because there was an upload to the s3
bucket there is a service that pulls
this data process it sends an email or
whatever something like this
most of the environments are read only
depends on the provider in aws for
example all the system is read only
except from slash tab so you if you want
to write data inside your runtime just
to slash temp
when the code
terminates so it
reaches the end
then this
environment terminates it's closed you
don't it doesn't run anymore
it's not wired to the internet in terms
of you cannot ssh to it it's not that
you don't cannot do uh http calls you
can from inside out you cannot do
uh
outside in
um so
inbound data is temporary uh basically
when the execution terminates the data
is erased data
slash temp data i mean the data that you
wrote i put the stars next to it because
you do not control that basically
if another
event is coming in um they might use the
same environment so you might have the
same the data from the previous one of
the previous executions but this is not
something yet you can rely on
the code resides in the environment so
when the code needs to run aws basically
takes the code put it inside a container
inside a
um
a container and runs it so the code is
inside if you have access to the runtime
then you have access to the code as well
also the keys are also
inside the environment variables which
are also
accessible in the runtime and we'll talk
about that
what about security well not a lot um
you can see servos computing is growing
and but security several security
searches or on google for example is not
really high
i can see mostly zero
ones and maybe some picks with two
uh and i'm pretty sure that well it's
just one it's when i have to give a talk
about it or something else something
like that
um
okay so we have this environment and we
want to test it for application security
um or we want to understand first
uh
how the application security that we've
known before
applies to servers is it the same or not
so
let's understand some of the risks that
we have in serverless and then try to
see how we can
assess those
this is a function
lambda function was i don't know uh
if i expand this maybe 25 lines of code
basically what it done what it's doing
is it receives an event
uh when um through an api i assume yeah
through an api uh and then
uh put this data some data into
uh
a database dynamodb is a dyno is a nosql
database by aws put item is the action
that writes date one entry into
the table the database the table is
inside the environment variable and then
just a response
what is the problem that i'm trying to
solve here that
in order for it just to work the
developer
needs to uh
create the right access or give the
right im
policy so the permission for this
specific function in order for it to
work
the permission is a specific action and
resource and service that you have the
developer needs to choose between
more i think almost ten thousand
different actions so of course the
service is dynamic b so it's never as it
down but he needs to understand what
he's doing usually
the developer will go to stack overflow
or the documentation at least at the
beginning until they understand and just
put something that works uh what we see
in organization is that they don't want
the developer to
spend so much time on it so what they do
is they create
pre
defined roles that the developer will
use unfortunately these roles are
can be used or needs to give the
permission to the entire set of
functions in the application so they are
very permissive anyway what's the
problem here the problem is that
developer or the team that creates the
role will create something like this
dynamodb with a star a wild card which
means that this function now has action
action or access to do
uh any action inside the dynamodb
service that could be
create databases delete databases modify
data whatever change the permissions
whatever
whatever action is possible within the
service even if the data the database or
the table
does not belong to the application but
it sits on the same account
uh then this function could if you
change the code or if you do something
else like in runtime
could do uh any other activity while it
only does actually put item and as you
can see the resources also with the
wildcard means whatever table
there is in the system in the in the
cloud
right so that maps to this and this
which is bad because why do you need a
wild card with
maybe dozen or two three dozens of
available actions when you only need one
action what you have to be to do is to
find the right permission or the right
access in this case it's called action
uh in this case it's put item
and set it
just as this specific uh action
and give it the specific resource
this specific resource is the name of
the table in this case now the function
even if you change the code or hack the
function or in runtime you want do
whatever you want you cannot do anything
other than put one entry inside this
specific table because otherwise the
cloud will
will stop you the infrastructure and
this is one of the
biggest challenges in aws
mostly
yeah
here it looks yeah it's not so difficult
first of all it's very an easy example
but the bigger problem
is that it's a one function uh i have a
customer that claims to have three
million functions
of course you cannot do this manually
all right the other part of the problem
is the loss of perimeter
that means that if in the traditional
modernist web application we had one
entry point to the function
an api
where you put that go through the load
balancer or an api gateway or something
like this where you could put all your
security controls
that's not the case anymore
now in a serverless cloud native and
specifically service environment is an
event-based architecture that means that
the entry point to your code could be
multiple type of things it could be
data analytics it could be a file
management so you can upload a file to a
bucket and it will run a code you can
change um
data inside the database
it will access the code you can send an
email to someone it will write a code it
will execute the code so
you don't have just the entry point to
start to to block uh attacks maybe
um
and we'll see an example
all right so what are the serverless
risks that we know of uh first of all
it's called event injection it's like
the regular traditional ejection attacks
sql injection command injection
code injection etc
xxc output inside
but now instead of just an input
coming into the function or to the code
it's based on an event
input injection so you have to create an
event somehow
some sometimes it will be just but it
will be created by the application but
your injection should be inside this
event
uh broken authentication we talked about
the fact that they are stateless so you
have to
find the right where the right
authentication
uh and maintain that sensitive data
exposure of course in the cloud inside
the runtime of the function you have the
code and the keys these
data is sensitive
overprivileged function we talked about
that vulnerable dependencies sca yeah
everyone knows that it's not new logging
and monitoring taking back from the os
top 10 maybe
this is just another way you cannot put
um network monitoring or
put an access log suit it's not it
doesn't work the same the logs
are inside
the cloud and you have to be able to
extract them monitor them report them
metrics them it's just a different way
of doing it
open resources so misconfigured
functions misconfigured buckets things
like this denial service what control um
it gets denied wallet so either you get
dosed or you pay for the execution
and insecure share space which is
the data slash uh the data folder that
is could be shared between executions
uh and of course insecure secret
management
which could be let's see a demo
um
so in this demo there is one bucket file
and one lambda function that trigger is
triggered so executes whenever a file is
changed or uploaded to the bucket the
attacker is going to upload a file
directly to the bucket through an api
yeah but just to the bucket note
uh to the code
the bucket will execute the function the
function is vulnerable
so the file here will cause the function
to send a malicious
uh to
send the hit's own set of access keys to
the developer uh to the attacker and
then the attacker from his own
workstation now can interact with any
service in the cloud
based on those permissions so this is
why the permissions are
are important if they are too permissive
now the attacker can
steal data from database for example
even if the function doesn't actually
interact with the database um and this
is uh
this is something that has happened like
the capital one hack so let's see let's
see a demo
i have here a vulnerable application
we'll talk about that later
i open here an http tunnel just to be
able to run something on my computer
in this vulnerable application there is
a feedback form that you can fill
and you can also attach files right so
now i'm going to look at the network
here
and when i upload a file attach a file
sorry i see that the file
remains and i also get
a url
that points me to an s3 bucket it's a
signed url so i can upload files to
directly to the f3 bucket
now
i uploaded it now i'm going to change
the function
uh the file name to something the
vulnerable
that will exploit the vulnerable
function i'm going to do a curl here
into my own tunnel here
with the environment and there's a
command to run to capture the
environment variables and i'm going to
wrap it with base64.
and let's see what happens
if you can you can understand that the
function is vulnerable to command
injection here because i can put a
semicolon and run another command
and as you can see here i got a few
requests i'm going to look at the second
one and i'm going to see the base64 data
so now all i have to do is
decode it right it's just text so let's
decode that
and i got all the environment variables
these environment variables contain the
keys
to the lambdas
oh the keys that
um
used by the lambda to access with the
cloud so if i'm using those keys
i am now impersonating to the function
even though i'm running from my own
computer
i'm from the application or from the
cloud's perspective i am the function
until these credentials
uh are expired which is a few hours
i'm going to write
this aws cli command you can see that i
did f3ls which gives me all the buckets
inside the account even though they are
not related to the some of them not
related to the application
and i can go further
and inspect uh what files are inside i
can see a folder
and
if i get into the folder
and moving on
i'm going to see that there are so it's
a dates folder and inside that i can see
there are there are two files here so
now i'm going to do the api to the cli
command to get the specific file
so the bucket is the same bucket here
and the file is this file
i'm going to download it to my own
computer
now i'm going to read the file
yeah it's a receipt and now i can also
modify the file so i'll just
modify all the file
modify the file and then upload it back
to
the bucket
uh and we'll see in a second that this
file exists of course what i could do
also is not just upload the bucket maybe
i could
try to
understand what other permissions i have
in the
uh
in the system
so the function has in the cloud so
maybe i can delete the bucket or even
interact with other services
as well
the problem with this security is mostly
about scale not only but mostly about
scale because even though services are
functions are small
uh it's hard to scale that when you have
dozens hundreds thousands or maybe
millions i don't know so lots of
services that you have to understand how
to secure them um
we hear about three buckets they're open
as qs as soon as they're open
there are
frequent developments right so it's not
short it's short cycles so you have new
um new deployments
on a daily basis if not more production
pushed
data sorry code push to production
on a daily basis
what services talks
what resources talks to what services
appsec team or security team doesn't
know that it's really hard to understand
many developers view appsec or security
team it's hard to understand what is
important when you have
dozens thousands of resources
and you have to understand also if the
security is the same as i mentioned it's
not exactly the same you have the same
attacks but the entry point could could
be fair the impact could if could it be
different the attack surface
so
it's a little bit different
and if you have a problem in the cloud
who takes care of that is that
developers is that the devops is that
the security team who owns that
this is not something that is equal in
every organization and you have and you
see struggles with it
all right so we have this
system that we need to secure so we want
to go left right shift left have a
security before we go to production and
we want to run our security tools as
they
are does these tools work on serverless
not so much because um
serverless has not just
and as i said not just a perimeter front
edge that you can test so you cannot run
take zap or any dust system give it an
endpoint and
point it to an api and say hey start
fuzzing it it doesn't work like this it
will always get a response immediately
but then something that starts a chain
in the cloud
and something else will happen also most
of the functions if you look at a big
system does not have urls or endpoint
these are event based it's not something
that you can target through an api or or
an endpoint
if you run fast it's a little bit
different
most tools are hard to scale especially
on this type of environment and they are
very
disrupted to the development ccd
let's see how that works uh in uh take
the traditional tools and apply them on
a modern pipeline
so
mario the developer and luigi the apsec
team wanna run security uh
maybe sassed on the
uh
on the code repository but that
requires a lot of tweaking from the
security teams otherwise you get a lot
of false positive and then they want to
run uh i asked maybe uh but then yeah is
needs
code coverage testing coverage uh and
the f6 team needs to run that and to
make take care of that so they want to
run dust but that's hey it's not you
cannot really test everything with dust
and dust as you know needs configuration
and you have to run cycles so mostly
dust is not a cicd tool no i'm not
saying it's not possible but it takes a
lot of work from the developer to give
priorities to talk to the absent team or
the security team to hey we have a new
version now test this api that api so
it's different
so how do you test
serverless applications all right so
this is uh taken from aws my robot
architecture
where you have one api and a few
services and resources behind
let's see what i can do with this
all right i can run
sneak or
white source or black dock any kind of
sca basically or an image scanning but
that will cover
basically ten percent of my what about
my my actual custom code uh those are
it's not that it's not good it's
something that you should do but your
own code and your own configuration are
still at risk uh sca and image scanning
is so um
common that even the cloud providers
and many open source provider
so this is a good start but it doesn't
control your code your services and your
configurations in the cloud
so
what about infrastructure as code i've
seen some of those coming up
there are some good ones uh palo alto
uh recently acquired
um bridge crew and there are some other
good tools so
yeah that's a good thing to do it will
find some
misconfigurations or security
misconfigurations in the cloud
but zero code coverage uh it has limited
visibility doesn't see anything other
than the temp the yaml file or something
like this zero logic zero prioritization
just
text based uh configurations so
yeah it's a nice one it's shift left
really
doesn't take a lot of effort but you
don't get all the security
uh that you cover that you need
so about about oh yeah i asked ist is
one of the mode um modern apsec tools
it's very accurate
very dependable
but reliable but the problem is
uh
that there are no servers so it's hard
to instrument the server when
you don't have
servers
all right so let's run sas right static
analysis
well sas can see each resource
differently or separate
but it doesn't work like this there are
uh no
in many cases no
source
or sync that is based on http the code
or the flow doesn't start in one place
and ends in oh and start at the
beginning of the function adds at the
beginning of the function no then there
is an sqs in the middle and then this
code runs so this is one flow
basically
sas can give you a lot of noise running
don't take my word for it just try
then dust right so dust can fuzz
uh this api
so maybe maybe this code not not sure
depends on if it's synchronous or
asynchronous mostly
just arrow inside so it's asynchronous
so um dust will not be able to find
anything here not to mention these these
this this and that
all right
so it doesn't really work not saying you
cannot get anything out of it but it's a
lot of work
for uh an effort for a little value you
need something different in serverless
so
what
i would suggest is something different i
think that in the cloud serverless
application needs to be tested in a
different way and what we suggest
is that a different completely different
approach to what you suggest so you
you forget what you know from app stick
teams
or absent tools sorry and try to
understand a different concept which is
continuous
autonomous
and automated
so everything happens in the background
what happens is that you connect with
three clicks
that is possible with the cloud
then this service or what we do is
automatically discover everything
analyze all the code all the weaknesses
the attack services the flows between
the services
based on that we create a specific
simulation that relates to each and
every one of those
and because we're inside the cloud we
can actually validate what we're doing
so if we say let's try to upload
a file even if it's not allowed i can
then see if the file was uploaded
because it come inside
and then the nice thing is that apart
from reporting it
still we can still monitor it so
continually monitoring it so if a
developer now pushes
a new code deploys new code new api
we get that and we automatically scan
that so you don't have to take to the
app to the security team hey i built a
new api
it runs this code can you test this here
is the end point or
there is a new function
can you test that no everything happens
automatically in the background
so let's see an example the developer
pushes new api that runs a function
then what happened is that we'll notice
that there is a new api this api is
connected to the function the function
then uploads the file to the storage
then runs the function then sends an
email to the user
what we'll do is that we'll scan each
and every one of those endpoints or flow
and then we'll try to see where is
maybe we found there is a problem
and after we are able to identify there
is a problem
we can then extract the keys
again we're inside the cloud and then
tell you what is your impact
so not just there is a bug but also if
there is a bug here and someone access
it they can access this table
this is just one scenario a few
two years ago in black hats europe i
showed how with my voice i can
steal data from the database just
talking to alexa
this is available on youtube you can
look for it behind the lamb the
the alexa there was a function a
vulnerable function so this is just one
example
so for example if you have this policy
which gives a lot of permissions on our
three and dynamo
with an automated tool you can just get
the right one line
of the just the action that you need
and there whether there is an injection
attack or a vulnerable code you can get
the actual vulnerability and the impact
for it
all right so
let's wrap up
security needs to be different in
serverless security testing
and it can be much better in terms of
how you operate things and if you want
to know more and learn more about
serverless security
uh there is an os
uh serverless top 10 project which i
lead together with
with other team members um i'm working
on this there is also an open call so if
you have data like vulnerabilities
attacks things like this in serverless
please help us we are trying to build a
new version for this report but it's
open source so you can go and get it
also
there is a
open source project called dvsa damn
vulnerable service application
which i created with some contributors
of course
uh you can use it you can deploy it with
three clicks as i said it's easy
so you just click click and it deploys
it into your cloud
please please please do not deploy this
on any account with sensitive
information
or production or anything is important
because it's vulnerable that means that
someone can steal these keys for example
and access other services or other data
in the cloud
uh that's it for today thank you again
i'm sorry that i cannot answer questions
um
probably landed by now but i'm on a
security checks or passport checks uh so
shoot me an email catch me on
twitter
github whenever wherever you want
uh thanks again
and
see you around
the
remote