Ryan Spurs Sophie Antoine 20 devices in
45 seconds how to make back hunting an
IOT devices we cover program analysis
for vulnerability discovery demo
straining how to find new and
prayerfully now backs across 20 I Oh T
devices and he'll turning arguments are
research attendees will receive an
understanding of challenge of analyzing
finger and backless patterns for memory
corruption much for having me today
hello we'll try that again
I'm excited to be here today and I'm
gonna be speaking about a theme hacking
20 devices in 45 seconds but that's just
meant to be a flashy term and we'll do
it don't worry but it's really about how
do we automate a bug hunting in IOT
devices both to make our lives easier as
attackers and defenders today we're
gonna talk through the fundamentals of
program analysis as it applies for
vulnerability discovery I'll give a
little background on past work in the
field motivate why we want to use
automation instead of drinking a lot of
energy drinks and sitting around for 12
hours a day talk about some of the road
bumps some of the challenges in
automating analysis and talk about why
that's different in IOT systems from
other systems then we'll go through how
we've done some work to improve the
publicly available tools in this space
and then actually let's do the 20
devices in 45 seconds then we'll apply
the tooling to find some bugs we'll go
through those and talk through them so
as background for myself I'm a low-level
hardware and firmware our reverse
engineer my focus for a long time was on
802 15 4 and ZigBee systems I maintained
some of the open source frameworks that
people used to assess those so don't
send me any bug tickets here we'll all
be drinking tonight but but later I've
had the pleasure of speaking a number of
conferences but I'm super excited
to be here this has been one of the most
fun conferences so far and unless you
guys throw a lot of tomatoes at me it
will continue to be a fun conference I
am the CEO and feel free to flow I can
dodge no comprendo espanol so I'm the
CEO and the lead of firmware analysis of
the company called pilot security we do
automated firmware analysis to find bugs
in these types of devices and I'm also
privileged to be one of the partners at
river loop security where we do
consulting services along these lines
Sofia my speak Sofia
who's not able to be prickly here today
she apologizes is my co-author on this
presentation and did a lot of the work
for it so credit to her her thesis was
in exploiting CPU side channels back
before we knew that spectra in meltdown
were big things and she leads our
automated analysis at pilot security so
today let's talk through and sort of put
this in context in these type of
embedded devices there's the hardware
the physical plastic casing that looks
nice and shiny the circuit boards and
all of that and there's the firmware
whether that's the code that the vendor
wrote or libraries that they got or any
other code that's gluing together the
actual logic there and then last but not
least often there's a back-end right
these are Internet of Things devices
after the fact they are connected to
something maybe that's providing a user
interface driving a mobile app etc but
today we're gonna be focusing on the
firmware so how do people deal with this
today and many of you know these and
know many more approaches than we have
time to go through so first of all one
approach is to network scan the device
treat it like a network asset we're
gonna end map it we're gonna start going
through the services that are listening
well although when you google for
network pen testing and find stock art
they appear parently think that all you
have to do is put a laptop on top of a
box of donuts it's much more calm
located than that right especially on
embedded we're often hampered by
unstable network services that fall over
when we scan them and then we're also
limited at just looking at the exposed
network services we missed all of these
other important attack vectors including
a lot of these devices call out to their
servers instead of in right by the time
you take an IOT device and put it inside
an airplane fuselage it's no longer
something that has all of its ports
available for you to easily assess
another approach is doing manual
firmware analysis there's great
open-source tools I'm sure many of you
have used some things like bin wok that
can help you extract out of a firmware
image a file system and then we'll go
through those and look for outdated
versions hard-coded passwords all the
stuff that you find and probably pick
out some binaries as well to reverse
engineer but as some of you may have
found out or deal with on a daily basis
for some of us right this can quickly
become a lot more complex somebody
changed the file system binary format a
little bit there's a lot of important
items outside the file system that you
need to look at in the kernel and the
bootloader and then outdated libraries
are often statically compiled in and
it's not gonna just stick out like a
sore thumb alright so there's a lot of
struggles here but it's still an
important tool and lastly we could
physically probe the device right get
out the soldering iron maybe use some
open-source tools JTAG and new things to
find serial ports maybe listen to the
radio frequencies interact with those
but number one obviously we need
physical devices right as you saw some
of the talks yesterday and earlier today
we're using this is the basic low cost
tools the things that you may deal with
you know good fed app emote yardstick
they're great for what they were made to
do but quickly you know somewhat
different devices or security on the
devices can compose to sort of break
those hacker tools and we can only test
again some avenues right these expose
debug poised so today we're not going to
be talking about any of those right
we're going to be talking about how do
we use programming
to help us go through the firmware so
first of all to give some foundations
here I want to talk about bug class
patterns the good news is firmware on
IOT devices has the problem of the early
2000s right these do not have the modern
exploit mitigations that Adrienne talked
about there's no you know they're full
of stack buffer overflows we'll get to
plenty of those later constant size
buffers unchecked boundaries basically
we should be happy if we're wearing in a
black hat right there's limitless
possibilities some things we may look
for our indicators like stir coffee mem
copy things that could be used in a
vulnerable way but those alone are not
enough to be an issue right those could
be used totally safely copying a
constant and then of course we have
coming in externally provided input and
whether or not it has bounds checking is
another indicator so the objective of
taking bug class patterns into program
analysis is to encode these in a way
encode our knowledge as reverse
engineers and vulnerability researchers
into something that the computer can do
for us so all of those bugs that we
talked about right are really I would
argue to operations they're reads and
their rights and if we deconstruct these
bugs if we take them down to a level of
abstraction we can then express them in
terms of reads and writes put together
and if we do that successfully which is
not always easy we can express these
vulnerable neural properties of a
program in an intermediate language so
we can fully embrace the weirdness of
these bugs so let's take a look at an
example here right we have you know your
intro to hacking main function where we
have a constant size buffer right that's
been allocated on the stack we're gonna
read in some pleasantly unbounded user
input and we're going to write that to
the stack using in this case store a
copy now for the sake of doing this at
scale one thing that most people doing
program analysis do is
they abstract away the details inside
you know Lipsy functions like stir copy
so that we don't have to dig through all
of that that assembly code and by though
you know by the time we've gotten to
step three we've written the input to
the stack we get our buffer overflow and
you know this is the type of thing that
we want to find automatically at scale
especially when it's this simple so
let's define briefly what sources and
sinks are first of all a source is where
external input comes into the program
what is this operation that we know we
can control or an attacker can control
like receiving Network data right this
is the receive function the read
function whatever it is and this is
important because it helps us filter out
unreachable bugs secondly the definition
of a sink is where does the external
input get processed or written to memory
where does that write happen in this
case we're going to use these two also
filter out unreachable vulnerabilities
so before we go any further there's some
great past work that I would not be
doing it justice to skip over so first
of all from those you saw the title of
the talk it is deliberately a play on
this talk from Def Con 22 that a lot of
our friends gave called hack all the
things 20 devices in 45 minutes and they
like I have a counter counting down from
45 minutes but I'm not going to I you
know neither talk took only 45 minutes
to find all the bugs what I was going
for today is showing you how we can
automate a lot of this work so instead
of weeks or months of analysis how can
we show how the computer can do the
heavy work for us and run very quickly
there's also a number of good resources
on program analysis for those of you who
want to follow up and read more about
this these are some references that you
may find interesting
everything from role forces recon talk
to a number that Sophia have given to if
you want to pour through a master's
thesis Shawn healings thesis has some
great material on this
then there's of course a lot of tools
like we've probably all used right on
the left hand side is source code
analysis tools anything from a source
code analyzer to things that can do
fuzzing based on source code may be
things like LLVM compiler that I'll talk
more about in a second that can look for
bugs and then on the right binary
analysis tooling whether that's dynamic
or static so there are a lot of tools
out there and let's drill in a little
bit first to how compilers work as
program analysis tools first of all LLVM
lifting via clang is great and you know
from the developers side if any of us
are running product security programs we
probably should be looking at how can we
get our teams to use this right if you
start compiling through claying there's
a lot of built-in security checks that
can run on the intermediate
representation to find a lot of things
however is a compiler as reverse
engineers who just have the binaries we
need a lifter so it's maybe not the best
tool for looking at binaries some tools
like maxima have worked to lift from
compiled binaries into this intermediate
representation but unfortunately this
often produces a massive output you may
not get all the benefit right again it's
a compiler it expects to have rich type
information that we don't have when
we're coming from the assembly code so
using tools like binary ninja can help
lift from assembly to a intermediate
representation similar but different
from LLVM when we work on this
intermediate language and sometimes
you'll hear me talk about it as ml IL or
medium level intermediate intermediate
language in this talk we can run our
analysis there there's also a number of
other tools Ida Deidre they have
different limitations from the price to
the UI to where they're made to you know
the Ghidorah for example doesn't have a
native single static assignment form
which can be really helpful for program
analysis
so why automation
well we all enjoy keeping our jobs and
probably many of us by billing by the
hour however that won't scale right so
we have some source code analysis tools
today they're good at finding issues
maybe like command injection but it's
tougher especially in embedded devices
to find two other important types of
issues first of all when a binary
library that somebody has compiled in
introduces the issues think of a
hardware abstraction layer or library
that's given to you by a chip vendor
you're going to go ahead and compile
this in you may not have the source code
but you still want to analyze it to see
what types of issues it may introduce
likewise there's a lot of issues that
may get introduced during compilation
right the classic example here is memset
you're clearing out your crypto buffer
your zero izing that out and the
compiler says hey you don't need that
right why bother and so this is
something that we can see when we
analyze the binary but doesn't show up
it well in a source code analysis lastly
and I'd love to see a show of hands here
how many people have heard from their
development teams if you work at a
product security company or work doing
product security at a company hey your
source code analysis gives me so many
false positives I hate it I never want
to see it again this isn't even code
that's in the product anyone anyone
heard that wait
developers only complain in the US come
on okay thank you so you know things
that get compiled out do 2-pound defines
are things that again we can target the
analysis we're looking at when we look
in the binary form so this is the
classic slide that a marketing person
put up right it's a scary number there's
a lot of devices out there and there's
not enough of us but joking aside right
if you have 15 billion devices coming
online between now and 2020 - and
allegedly 1.8 million cyber security
positions unfilled and the numbers on
this vary from like none to 4 million
depending on who you ask this is you
know one of the reasons why I'm
passionate about finding
ways to automate also because I'm lazy
so what is this automation trying to do
right it's trying to find issues before
they can cause harm even if all of us
were busy 24 hours a day and we had
enough people to audit every IOT or
embedded product or every project in
general before it went out there's still
some issues first of all the cost of
fixing the bugs we find is
demonstratively much higher when it's
closer to the release right when it's
farther from when the bug was introduced
it's more expensive takes longer as more
more things have to get changed to fix
it and lastly if we can find it earlier
there's a lot higher likelihood that
more percentage of the bugs are going to
get fixed before we ship it to our
customers so how can we push finding it
left of shift of ship one example is
things like github does internally now
right where they're saying hey you have
some node.js code we're pretty good at
knowing when somebody reports a
vulnerability we're gonna send you an
email telling you a vulnerable code that
is great for some ecosystems with
well-defined package management they can
be scanned for and that's the type of
thing we're trying to find and apply to
more types of ecosystems specifically
embedded where if we had a package
manager for embedded if Yocto was well
used we'd all be a lot happier the
second thing is that we need to have
thoroughness in large code bases myself
tonight argue probably most of us as
human researchers aren't perfect if we
get a control flow graph that looks like
that frankly good luck right
good luck thinking that we're going to
be sharp enough well rested enough and
have the patience frankly to check every
potentially vulnerable code path in that
function and that's a real one so we
need to make sure the checks good
so in program analysis we're trying to
encode an expert researchers methods so
that the computer can run this in
multiple iterations
I choked aleppo Don things about Monster
energy drinks because this is how Sofia
finds bugs and she's not here to defend
herself for this methodology for her own
health we
need to have program analysis techniques
but let's see what are some of the
challenges are right it's not all just
the promised land so first of all the
question is can we apply techniques that
we've used in traditional computation to
solve these issues in embedded and the
answer is definitely very first of all
in traditional computation and I use
that as a general word for web apps
kernels etc there's been a growing
adoption of typesafe languages or
language extensions that can reduce
basic memory errors in embedded we have
yet to adopt things like well tested
techniques that Microsoft adopted in the
early 2000s to ban unsafe function calls
likewise there in traditional
computation there's well optimized tools
for static analysis but an embedded it's
been lagging behind in some reasons at
least some of the reason has been due to
a lack of good processor support for the
variations of architectures that we have
but now tools like binary ninja and
Ghidorah are really helping catch that
up in traditional computation you might
give your developers source code
analysis tools some of them may
integrate into their development
environments and highlight the bug right
as they type the code but in embedded
firmware not only is there widely
divergent development environments
because every single microcontroller
company gives you a different IDE but
also there's a lot higher frequency I
would argue of taking in binary
libraries and lastly in traditional
computation we have well used automated
fuzzing Suites whether it's the big
companies or whether it's things that
people apply individually all have
harnesses or often have harnesses that
are fuzzing for security vulnerabilities
but in embedded this is tougher right we
have Hardware interrupt handlers we have
custom chipsets and board layouts that
require instrumentation this raises the
barrier to entry so to answer a question
yes we can apply these things but it's
non-trivial to implement we can't just
port or use the existing tools
but we can apply techniques we can take
static analysis to screen for bug
glasses like we'll be showing today we
can use emulation or partial emulation
to drive and support some fuzzing we can
use techniques like satisfiability
solving to figure out some cases in the
control flow and importantly we should
be integrating into the development
cycle right so just like a shop is you
know using continuous integration to
build it send it to QA and get it back
so - if we automate it instead of having
us on the receiving end we can't I can't
turn around in ten minutes and give you
results or in 45 seconds but an
automated program analysis can give some
of that feedback in the build process
right to the developer hopefully meaning
they actually implement it and ship more
secure code so the reason I've been
focusing on and researching this frankly
for the past few years is because my
objectives are let the computer do the
majority and the majority of issues let
us focus on the more interesting things
and overall let's help our customers by
catching issues before they cause harm
but another challenge is determining bug
efficacy and I'm gonna go through three
specific technical areas where this
rears an ugly head first of all how do
we encode these read and write
primitives right I said you can just
simplify them to read and write
primitives well now I'm here to tell you
it's not that simple for example in some
of the vulnerabilities that I'll cover
in a moment tend a router manufacturer
has this call due system command it's a
dynamically linked library that they
bring in that basically calls system
vulnerably under the hood but because
this is a class of dynamically linked
library into a different program that
you're analyzing stuff like this can add
a complexity to encoding the sinks that
we talked about likewise information
flow analysis I'll dive more into this
and an example in a second but this is
basically making sure how do we know
that the variable one function is
touching how does the computer realize
that's the same one that's being used in
the different context
and lastly variable range recovery this
is important because for example if
something does a length check and then
it's used in a way that would only be
vulnerable if the length is over a
certain boundary we need to understand
that the computer needs to understand
that in the program analysis one way to
do this is to do symbolic execution on
everything that is unlikely to work and
it certainly won't work in 45 seconds so
let's look at an example of where we
have to do a range recovery if we take
that same vulnerable program from
earlier and now we add the code in blue
right
so still maybe not the best rate in code
but let's let's go with it we are now
checking that the input is if it's over
a hundred bytes we're going to air out
and we won't do the vulnerable copy into
the buffer so we have this base
assumption that store copy does a memory
write the right length is the length of
the source buffer to store copy but now
we've added this check in blue and now
we need to understand a few more things
in our program analysis first of all we
need to know the size of the destination
buffer and secondly we need to know what
we've bounded the length of the source
buffer in this case input two now the
exact techniques for this would be a
whole talk in its own right and so I'm
not going to dive into it here but I do
want to raise it as something that we
have to overcome when doing this so now
let's talk about two issues that we ran
into when preparing for this
presentation and how we're going about
fixing them and making that so others
don't run into it as well so the first
for those of you who have done reverse
engineering on binaries you probably
know that they lead to their own
challenges in this case binary ninja was
not able to find the main function and
when it couldn't find that it really
didn't find any other function so
nothing had any vulnerabilities well
that was a red flag because they
obviously had vulnerabilities so what we
wanted to do here was figure out what
was going on and our technique for this
we're saying yes it's MIPS because this
is where the issue was happening
we're gonna find this meu lib see this
function the entry point we're going to
extract the first argument and
dereference it and then grab those four
bytes then we'll do a sanity check to
see okay this is a function preamble
we'll set that as a function and then we
analyze the whole thing which is
expensive
luckily the binary ninja teams great and
after we found and gave them this patch
they've now put it in so if you're on a
recent version you should not run into
this issue if so blame them another is
going back to that topic I talked about
earlier with memory references this is
an example of how we have an issue
understanding what goes into system
right so in this case system is the
vulnerable sink and we want to
understand if the attacker could control
data going into it well what's happening
here is a variable is being assigned
based on a stack address reference then
data gets copied into it in this case
through s printf and then that same
stack address reference is used to set a
different variable which is what's
passed in the system as humans we look
at this and all of you are nodding and
being like yeah I don't know why the
computer can't follow this this clearly
is the same thing it's being set by
constants not an issue but this is very
difficult to generically trace from a
program analysis standpoint okay we've
gotten through the background of program
analysis I'm sorry that not everyone is
coding it up at this point but I'd be
happy to talk with anyone
afterwards who's interested in diving
more into that but now let's go through
some examples right I have a thing
against live demos so I have taken the
liberty of having the 45 seconds elapsed
earlier today and then taking
screenshots and putting them in here
because me zooming around my computer
screen while standing behind a desk is
certainly less fun than me me standing
up here where you can wear them within
range of your Tomatoes so let's go
through some examples we're going to go
through 20 devices we picked these by
looking at various lists of what we're
popular device is and different markets
and then to be honest with you the
toughest
because I was invited to give this talk
oh you don't want to see that re oh
that's fun huh
loading loading who hit the internet on
me
okay sorry about that so talking through
these devices the one of the toughest
part was I was asked to give this talk
about two months ago we give people
three months notice before releasing new
bugs on stage against their targets
so the toughest thing was five big
majority of devices the LD that we could
find automatically and then figuring out
if somebody had manually found those in
the past so that I did not feel bad or
get yelled at for releasing them here
now the last four don't fall into that
group so that's fine we'll just leave
out the exact memory addresses and no
one will figure it out so first of all
to start it off this is a tender router
and we're gonna go pretty fast through
this right so we're gonna look at this
one on how the HTTP requests are
processed and the great thing is I
figured we'll start with this one
because it has an awesome feature in its
product literature it has an T hacking
and I thought well that definitely means
we're not gonna find anything
automatically so here's what we found
automatically web requests came through
and get processed first by a this HT DB
D right it's gonna read the users data
from the socket and then it passes it
off to app data center which parses and
uses the data well the first thing one
that I saw popping up was this write a
vulnerable system call let's dive into
what that is
ah don't worry is nobody was reported
but unpatched it was actually reported
on a different device from this vendor
but through program analysis we were
able to quickly see that it was also
available on this model of device and
what it actually is is the inside
they're handling for USB injection which
obviously has to be available over the
web it copies in some data and an
unbounded form unsanitized as puts in
call system on it great typical command
injection hint none of these are gonna
be thrilling right what's interesting is
that we can find them automatically okay
on the next device on tenders AC 5
device again similar binaries one looks
a little different this case as a format
string vulnerability what this actually
is is that
it's reading in a parameter from the
HTTP web request and it's using this as
the format string so you could do
percent n or percent P your typical
format string types of attacks to
control the stack okay let's go
appreciate some stack buffer overflows
will stay on tended to start in this
device it's their AC 18 device and at
this memory address and don't worry the
only one I'm just closing is the one
I've highlighted and this is the one
that again has been disclosed previously
they're reading in the SSID field that
somebody sat through a webform and does
a store copy into a fixed size buffer of
hex 40 off of that this can be triggered
via this very complex exploit that you
see here yep so on AC 15 another one
from this family of quality devices
another store copy what this comes out
to be is this time they read in this
idea of where they should bind their MAC
address to some IP now what's
interesting here is think back to this
grid that I showed you earlier that
control flow graph of so many devices or
so many points in a program if somebody
manually finds an exploit they're likely
to find it in one place you don't need a
second one even if you report it to the
vendor it's incumbent I think most would
argue on the vendor to find all the
places the same exploit technique hits
and in this case basically any field
that you can submit to this web
application has a store copy buffer
overflow so program analysis is patient
enough to find all of them for you and
again can be triggered via a slightly
more complex vulnerability this time you
need to provide two arguments finding
another one in another in this time in
device number five AC 9 it's the NTP
server field on this device that is
vulnerable so ok let's give that a break
let's go look at some more command
injections we'll stay on them for a
little while longer
remember how I said earlier some of the
issues are trying to find a sync on a
device when it's
this is that one right where do system
command is where the vulnerable function
is in this case let's see what's going
on they're taking in a MAC address
passing it down this can be attacked
sophia wrote up a a really complex
proof-of-concept here where you have to
add a semicolon before you on your
command looking at a c7 now let's see
what we have here we have another
command injection through another
function where the device name is
vulnerable are we getting the feeling
here that tenda may not be what i
install in my house okay let's give them
a break let's go look at some other
vendors because this is certainly not
limited to one let's look at some more
command injections in this case and a
d-link modem I know a router in this
case it has this boa constrictor or
whatever binary they has system called
at this address in this case it's
reading in a command and kindly
processing it for you directly in the
system through s printf the nice thing
is it logs out what you did now a bonus
is that I want to throw in write
everything we're talking about is
program analysis but I don't want to
give the impression that the only thing
we can find automatically is things like
store copies or command injections
another example of things that we don't
want to look for as humans at least I
don't or things like hard coded
passwords right we're you know running
grep or looking at Etsy password on
every device you SS gets boring
remembering exactly which ones md5 and
not in the encoding is annoying so
additional things we can find on that
device ok let's go back to command
injections on the d-link der 816 they
use the go ahead which is an open source
web server open source and commercially
available web server and in this case it
takes in a command through an ASP
handler and passes it down again to
system why not let's look at wall way
knowing for some of the most secure
devices available on the market today
there UPnP binary universal plug and
play or the the network service as
they're calling down in the system at
this address in this case they decode
some user provided input from an XML
node and pass it right down the system
again this was found manually in 2017
but most of the work in finding these is
not finding them it's figuring out if
somebody else had previously found them
given as I'm sure you all know CVE
entries are really well written Asus has
an httpd server as well that we get a
hit on through the automated analysis
that system is is being called at this
address and if we look at what that is
is taking in an email form through
something and passing it down the system
in this case you can't use a semicolon
you have to have to use a pipe character
so very advanced exploitation ubiquity
makes a product and I include this one
here just to show that it's not always
system right we need to be aware of all
of the different sinks in this case exec
L that's again a vulnerable function
okay let's so take a look now at some
stack buffer overflows I've warned you
all out on command injections
let's hit another tp-link device in this
case again they have a web server it
calls ster copy the data coming into
that came from how they take in an IP
address through a web form this was
found manually earlier this year and
reported in an Asus device let's hit a
few of those against ur copy in this
case takes through a CGI binary that
takes the username passes it right down
copies it into an unbounded buffer
another Asus device slightly different
h2 DB binary in this case they do the
buffer overflow not through store copy
but through s printf right because this
can also copy off the edge of a
statically allocated stack buffer okay
let's look at a few I think just a few
more examples let's look at an example
of a controlled format string like we
touched on it first with tenda this time
in tp-link this is an R 600 VPN device
and we can just to see that this V print
VF print F call here is a format string
in this case that the attacker can
control through I forget exactly here I
think it's another email address field
that is used like a format string okay
now for the ones that I will
purposefully omit the actual memory
addresses from I'll just tell you the
binaries so law of you IP camera as a
binary called exact system command one
might think this is where you might look
for a command injection you are correct
we disclosed this earlier this month
still haven't gotten a response back
from the vendor we'll continue to follow
up on another I believe this is another
camera if you're gonna have hard-coded
passwords which I'd argue you should not
do you definitely should at least salt
them and in this case we see that the
automated analysis can call it out
because there's no salt being used
we finished disclosing that one on this
commercial DVR used to wreak record
security cameras there was a blog post
that was never formally reported in 2013
there they released a patch in summer of
2018 that specifically says in the
release notes that it's there to
mitigate a large number of security
vulnerabilities yeah no I still have not
heard back from them on those technical
details that we sent over on Linksys
camera the file dot cgi handler was
previously reported to be reachable and
allow for file access but automated
analysis also quickly was able to flag
that it had command injection as well so
I've gone through those in rapid
succession I'd be happy to talk to
anyone about more details about how one
of those is found the actual math behind
the processing or any other topic you
want thank you so much for having me
it's been a great time to be at this
conference and thank you for being so
welcoming and putting up with my
absolutely terrible Spanish I will work
on it I promise for next year I'm happy
to take any questions it looks like we
have a few minutes remaining or let you
get on to closing and drinking at
closing ceremonies
[Applause]
all right thanks Oh somebody's not
letting me off that easily
Oh Ryan thank you for being here uh you
kind of clear that what you're using for
things like you're doing different
functions but why are you doing to find
the source are you like doing model out
it you find like the different potential
source for your data flow analysis yeah
in this case in the examples we showed
today we're not pegging on specific
sources but instead we could covering
control flow back up from the sink and
seeing if we are able to concretize the
parameters to the sink and if we're not
able to concretize them we don't know
that they came from something that is
safe then we'll flag it for a human to
look at but absolutely to your point and
in some other tooling I didn't show
today we also look for specific sources
and in fact how we pick which binaries
to look at out of the whole file system
right these have hundreds of binaries
you want to know a few things which ones
are actually being run and we do a lot
of analysis to figure that out but also
which of those then bind on a network
interface so that you pick ones that are
more likely to have attacker controlled
input hey what's up how you ever
considered to take a look into ICS
devices yeah absolutely yeah and it on
those that are embedded Linux focused
this works well as as well okay cool
thank you
okay thank you very much
have a great rest of the day
you