Alex mattress over modern saguru attacks
many hardware vendors are and morning
modern security booth by maureen root of
trust of the hardware in this
presentation I explain new security
issues to bypass a specific
implementation of indelible who are
technology in one of the most common
enterprise vendors because I wake up a
tear and I'm glad to be on this stage
second time on this conference and my
talk it's about like a talking hardware
root of trust in common implementation
and u5 firmware so just a reminder I'm
Alex Morozov I'm working for Nvidia
leading offensive security research
there and I did a lot of stuff regarding
u5 firmware security research so just a
small disclaimer I'm not talking from my
employee point of view I just described
in my own research and all bad jokes and
mistakes
it's on me and of course zero days too
so for the target of this research I
take lean over P 50 lap top and before I
was mostly targeting gigabyte a stack
and a massage so no more webby targets
I took a serious enterprise laptop to
basically prove it has a lot of issues
too so in this talk we will be talk
about what is a hardware root of trust
is and also will be touch some
architectural mistakes not architectural
mistake but let's see in reference
implementation Intel provide a lot of
freedom to OMS who basically make
mistakes in their implementations also
we will talk about the compute race and
implementation of compute racing lenovo
laptops nor days laptops and interesting
thing I found recently over windows
management interface you can actually
call with my handlers and
probably as you remember from my
previous talk yesterday assume I can
list it's kind of like a callback
function from the operating system level
directly to the buyers and sometimes
it's directly called code inside in the
most privileged mode system management
mode on x86 systems so let's start about
what is the hardware root of trust and
what is a problem sexually
implementation of hardware root of trust
in most of the cases hardware root of
trust should be implemented in our tails
that's mean directly in the hardware in
silicon but silicon RTL level it's hard
to modify actually it's no way how you
can modify it after releasing the
product and of course it's create a lot
of limitation for the companies to
implement their route of trust that way
because if something happens they can
patch it and because of that hardware
root of trust is kind of mix between the
firmware level and the hardware also
common marketing tool even if one bit
inside the hardware lock something the
vendors say it's a hardware implemented
root of trust or harder implemented
technology for protecting something but
it's not exactly true because one bit
it's not really a security feature it
just lock mechanism which is in reality
have many ways codes can be bypass it I
will be back on this white and actually
probably you remember from my previous
presentation yesterday it's because as
example boot guard as a technology for
the macerate boot has root of trust
based on TPM and TPM already have a
proven research from Jeremy Boone and
trommel Hudson how they basically can
attack the TPM or attack
the TPM communication between the actual
former bias and the TPM and fake the
responses from TPM to the bias it's a
good flow for the boot guard and let's
see how it should be work in the perfect
world we have a CPU reset and the
microcode make attestation for boot
guard identification code model and
authenticated code model make
attestation before even before the reset
vector for IBB hash which is kind of
like hash for first stage of the boot
guard technology and it's mikage station
for for transition from the ACM to the
starting loading the bias on the actual
boot process so looks perfect all the
transitions secure and how's what it can
be wrong right so first of all boot
guard doesn't cover the microcode and
ACM so basically if we have any
vulnerable versions of a cm and micro
code we can downgrade them and we can
basically use one-day issues to attack
this technology so if boot guard ACM is
compromised and if we downgrade the
microcode with known issues it doesn't
make sense on or all the checks which is
exist on upper level boot process inside
the BIOS firmware because it's already
done it's compromised right so it's how
the reality are but why we don't lock
everything inside the hardware and let
the firmware just boot boot a trusted so
first of all oh my clock secrets because
of supply chain he'll support process
the cost
vulnerabilities is very high and I mean
cost for the vendor because you can't
release patch for the card we're and
basically you need to recall your
hardware to replace it as example google
recently make a recall for their dangles
for visit it on cheap first version and
probably it cost a lot of money for them
so the cost for the updates it's really
high and all the vendors try to
basically reduce the secrets which is
locked inside the hardware because of
that because the price for these issues
for basically fixing them it's very high
and in the most of the cases we can see
the mix of the hardware and firmware and
it's how the reality looks like but
let's talk about connection of operating
system level firmware and some of the
hardware related secrets so probably you
remember from my talk or you know what
is a system management interface is
summize so and it is a powershell script
which is basically get some information
from a CPI table about what version of
the laptop what version of the buyers
and etc it's basically the information
enough for the attacker to create
payload for specific version of the
laptop and you can get this
automatically also the same way with the
powershell can disable the boot guard in
enterprise laptops but i will not talk
much about that because I cover
yesterday let's go to windows management
interface directly and this picture
actually is still from Lenovo
Lenovo official documentation you can
see the links here and you basically can
look so basically we have this venom
windows management interface from Lenovo
which
which is basically communicating
directly with the BIOS settings and as
the researchers we will think what we
can basically change from that right and
actually we can change a lot but most
interesting ones I would say it is this
one's oh so it is this one's because we
can enable disable secure boot we can
enable disable txt we can enable disable
virtualization and even with the D for
protection of the may attacks direct
memory access
so think about basically if we have
privilege privilege it access to the
laptop we can do whatever we want even
from a P rating system level we don't
need actual physical access or BIOS
exploit because we have everything and
windows management interface so and also
of course you can find all these
structures for basically when we define
it in a CPI directly if you go to Deere
dsdt table a supply table you can found
everything related to this management
interface and it's a sample script which
is basically change password for the
BIOS administration from the operating
system level it's scary right so and
it's actually how this research get
started because it was thinking ok what
I can do more from this system
management of windows management
interface and actually I can do a lot
because Lenovo have a Dixie driver with
remote configuration it's the name of
the driver interesting it has a little
set up automation and set up under OS
SMM and it's get me a super super
interested what is inside especially
this ones
so Lenova set up under OS dixie driver
mostly communicated with Lenovo password
manager settings inside the firmware and
Lenovo under OS it's basically
responsible for wires passwords and bios
settings and it has a 12 is my handlers
which is actually huge attacks your face
Lenovo hidden Satan it's already kind of
interesting name right for for the
driver and it's has a two functions for
computer ace enable and disable and
compute race for you if you not remember
it's kind of a rootkit for basically
tracking your laptop and this technology
had been developed for anti-theft
purposes but honestly it's been already
in use for the malicious purposes by
some of the apt attackers and setup
automation have a four is my handlers
for configuration password and boot
order but boot order actually it's
important because it can as example
change the order of the boot boot
devices and if you connect physically
USB flash drive with something malicious
you can basically put on the first place
your drive before the operating system
boots also secure boot configuration has
a lot of other options I will talk about
a bit later on the next slide and
specifically automation for assume I
have a 12 other is my handlers and which
is I all this information it's under
command that I basically recover based
on reverse engineering and this one's I
not recovery yet it's books well very
interesting and promising to so but
let's back to compute race why compute
race is interesting first of all last
year is cert being discovered the
rootkit law Jack's which is based on
this technology to resist inside the
system and in Lenovo by
we do have a six Dixey drivers mostly in
the samam which is basically responsible
for arcus trade this technology inside
your machine and we have like
computerized instyler which is basically
installed operating system component on
your system automatically we do have a
computer ace enable which is basically
enables the technology and disabled but
I was thinking okay if we disable
compute race on your wireless settings
it will be really disable it or it will
be still persist on your system and also
the more remote configuration is
actually most interesting ones that mean
maybe you can remotely activate
computation your system if it's really
not a deactivated right so back to back
to research in 2017 what I did for
recover compute trace is my handler it
is actually a lot of interesting
information I will talk about on the
next slide but what I get from that
research we have this option current
setting disabled permanently compute
race you can see here so and honestly
it's a option computer is still
active on your system but basically it's
not doing something bad but it's still
active that's mean
the attacker can activate it you can
actually find my slice or previous
presentation by this link so honestly
it's no permanent disabled feature for
compute race if it's exists on your
laptop let's talk a bit about their
collector of compute race so we have
only know a security config and lanova
hidden satan which as i mentioned both
these configuration storages communicate
not communicate but dependent by Lenovo
trade services and computerized services
actually use the knowledge security semi
dispatcher and Lenovo mailbox for
orchestrate activation deactivation and
activity so I was looking on lanova
security config to recover this
structure and some of the fields it's
still unknown because I don't know what
they related with this but you can see
also a lot of things like access to the
chimera access to the microphone compute
race Intel VTD secure boot a rollback
prevention and many others even device
guard is there so it's kind of like very
interesting place to look v4 and I was
thinking ok what we can do it's compute
it's disassemble that computerized
services Dixie driver and actually it's
directly tried to modify values in this
configuration table so and of course
here is some services which is basically
orchestrate this activity from a
parading system level and the name of
this is my handlers its compute race
enable disable and computer a state
that's kind of scary because you can
just call one of them to do something
with Lenovo security configure it and
compute races my services actually it's
kind of registered callbacks in Windows
management interface that's mean you can
over windows management interface call
this object so and you can see basically
how this structure present inside the
ACPI table on your machine and where the
beats is zero sometimes it's just
orchestrate ok secure boot is on or
of secured booties Oh other option off
on off to end-user flash update which is
basically allow you from a parading
system level update your bias and I was
thinking okay but let's back to
permanent disable option because I want
to understand how it works and basically
after reconstruction this assembly
called it's just if secure config
compute raise true then compute race
enable is active if not then it's
disabled at false kind of like funny for
permanent disable option rate also for
disabling enabling you need to
communicate with computer a state which
is basically have kind of like specific
canary value but it's canary value is
hard-coded and you can see the defined
so back here it's about computer a state
so we have a four options basically
enable active disable in disabled secret
key which is basically deactivate
permanently compute race on your machine
and secret key is just four bytes so
it's at world value I was okayed world
value it's not very easy to brute-force
but when I was reverse engineering
deviation algorithm for key I can see it
clearly here is no four bytes it's
actually one bite because other whites
don't have any sense in this decryption
algorithm so then I was working on this
comparison key check function and it was
a constant time if it is a constant time
it's good for
of all because you basically can
understand when the key is different and
when key when key is good so you can
basically brute force fast to get your
correct value so basically it's side
channel attack possible on this
algorithm okay so we have one bite
secret key stir it and spy flash in vrm
we have different laptops of course some
of them have a different keys but I use
the chip sack it's open source framework
on github for basically causes a my
handler and just check specific value so
and in my case disable value been 57 in
hex not difficult and also kind of scary
for me because this option for permanent
disable and also after you use permanent
disable for compute race it's still
active on your system if we switch our
focus a bit further what else actually
we have in our laptops which is has
additional vulnerability landscape it's
embedded controller and the modern
controller in many cases it's not a
security boundary for the vendors who
develop the hardware so but it's quite
complex actually nowadays
microcontroller and in blackhat research
with Alex Gazette this year we've been
presented how we break this
microcontroller you can find the slides
on the blackhat website but let's
actually talk about other vendors
because we was breaking microcontroller
which is has a notification and we break
out enta fication but if you look on
this update here for gigabyte laptop it
doesn't have any identification you just
basically flash the
from a P rating system levels of binary
blob on your microcontroller and micro
control Ike embedded controller have
some callbacks to the bias and basically
this attack surface is not very known
and well-documented and never consider
it as serious problems so basically what
happens you change your security
boundary because architects was thinking
a case the attacker will come from the
operating system level but what happens
the tiger attack embedded controller and
attack from other side of the boundary
that's interesting different point of
view okay into a boot guard and let's
discuss some ways how we can bypass it
so how Hardware root of trust actually
became a software first of all recovery
mode is evil and it's hard to implement
security in hardware related to recovery
mod correctly security transition chain
of trust on different boot stages is is
very actually slow and it's why it's
hard to implement securely because if
you will be verify everything on each
stage your computer will be boots
probably minutes but all the vendors
won't blink your screen like in a second
so this means they should optimize
verification chain of trust and
specially the transition between
different boot stages in most of the
cases without hard reset of trust moves
purely from software for performance
proper purposes what that mean when you
go to the sleep and hibernate all the
transitions not verified from the
beginning basically from the root of
trust inside the hardware it's very fine
from the some state which has been
safely store it inside the buyers in
software enterprise hardware also need a
remote update tools and nobody use in
Tobias guard and mostly all the vendors
try to avoid this technology because it
makes recovery very hard so basically
it's flow for flush and bios image on
the NOC machine and we can see here
flush an image for recovery block
firmware image done and it was me
curious about what inside the V recovery
mode and we look on verification result
for this check it's stored inside the
bias in software so what does it mean we
have a hash which is kind of like make a
transition the route of trust from
hardware to this hash and if we make
recovery it will be rely on the Hessian
software so crashes like
shall 256 it's not good first of all
here is about we can change this hair
then when verification happens it will
be verified with our cache but for that
we need a vulnerability inside azzaman
so also I was thinking okay what else
but for recovery specifically on Knox
systems
it was just ignore this cache and make a
recovery started so this vulnerability
actually been presented by Alex your
model phone zero nights last year and
he found this one durability inside the
hope driver inside the bias so yeah here
is a flow reconstructed flow and you can
clearly see here is basically starting
the recovery process if - but what's its
mean we have two sides of the boot guard
technology both side is breaking it
inside the hardware and basically lock
it by the fuse and this fuse have a cash
value which is try to protect early
stages of the boot but we also have a
lot of components relies on the thermal
only K manifest and initial boot block
manifest all of them present only on the
firmware and if we don't need the
hardware part as in recovery mode spoken
before so we have only the firmer side
and all this can be modified to be to
present correct boot for the malicious
components or modified components so
basically back to this picture why it
happens also one more interesting thing
I found its boot guard Lenovo PCD need
option so basically in lenovo laptops
some of them they have a pc d platform
configuration value it stored inside the
BIOS inside the padding and when I was
reverse engineered Lenovo PC d need
driver I was found this check and
actually this check verify this value if
this value true then is disabled the
boot guard even if it's enabled on your
system and actually it sounds like
clearly as a backdoor or maybe recovery
or support mechanism I
so basically we can jig inside the
system and found a lot of things which
is sounds differently as a vendors claim
and my opinion actually this particular
check been created probably not and
backdoor purposes because when you have
your laptop and you came to support say
oh my laptop doesn't boots correctly
what they can do because if your laptop
is locked by hardware root of trust they
can't change anything even like access
to the bus and they create this kind of
mechanism it was hidden but as we all
know security by obscurity doesn't work
right so and of course it's easy to
discover so I don't know somehow this
driver get my attention and then I
figure it out we have this spreading and
this wedding doesn't protected by BIOS
boot guard so basically you can modify
it so also I want to pay attention on
this tool it's you vital in the two
years ago
I developed a mechanism to verify IBB
for the boot guard and these colors as
example red colors mean something it's
not protected fully on on the boot guard
here so and not colored values it's just
not covered for from wood guard at all
so when you can see the spread in
highlighted by blue just because I put
my cursor there so and it's not
protected at all and yeah you can just
modify it fresh bias back and actually
it's not affect integrity because it's
not protected by boot guard right in
when
so for usability purposes Enterprise
Warworld need some some mechanism for
recovery right and this many cases its
enemy of security the vendors understand
permanent disable differently as we are
so for my opinion permanent disable mean
I should burn the fuse which is will be
not allow this court runs again never
when the hardware waste root of trust
transfer the state of chain of trust to
software that's done because it's no
more hardware root of trust is exists
it's only software right and our system
specially x86 system it's very complex
it's has a lot of boot States as example
you have a sleep mode you have a
hibernate mode and it's a different boot
stage when you close the lid of your
laptop it doesn't mean your machine
switch off actually it's safe all the
states and it's why it's recover it very
fast when you open the lid again and
only when you make a hard reset and
reboot machine then all the states
basically started from scratch it's why
attacks your face it's very complex and
sometimes vendors they make it secure
from the heart reset but it's hard to
know like where it can be failed in
recovery in sleep or the hibernate
because they want the performance and
your system boot fast it's pretty much
it for today and thank you very much I
cope idea
[Applause]
so I would help you to answer the
questions yes please it's fused for the
hash for IBB yeah it's yeah but it's
it's not a fuse for the public/private
key yes exactly it's because a as format
yeah yeah nothing so I was used to work
for Intel before and I found a lot of
issues there but it's fixed internally
so okay I can't speak about that but I
like the way of how you're thinking it's
a right really right vector yeah
actually the complex parsers inside the
firmware it's really sweet vector
because it's no mitigations any memory
corruptions will be lead record
execution right hey a question so you
talked about how CPU microcode is not
being protected and can be altered so
yeah but my question is is this
certificate or the private key stored in
the TPM altered if I change the
microcode in this oh no no microcode
actually doesn't rely on any TPM
verification it has a some other
verification routine from CPU but
problem is if you have as example
microcode you do not modify microcode
you just downgrade the microcode with
known issues it's a bit different story
so basically the reef occation if the
keys or like this micro cut version not
been blacklisted it will be still able
to boot it
and yeah so it's kind of open
interesting room and especially as we
know it was a lot of speculative
execution issues past two years found on
intel architecture and especially
microcode downgrade can allow you to use
these known issues even if it will be
budget on new versions of micro code and
it's kind of like scary but new I would
say newest generation of Intel CPUs they
have some protection from that but back
to the skylark not thanks ok let's do a
question no questions thank you very
much guys
[Applause]