hello everyone I'm gang Johnny and I'm
here to talk to you today about deaf
first security so the different view of
how elusive approach security that tries
to sort of focus more on the sort of you
know modern development surrounding I'm
going to share my perspective a little
bit of a look at market stands as well
as what is that for security but maybe
more importantly I'll share a lot of
specific practices from smart people
that I have had the opportunity to talk
to about how they tackle security inside
their organization so we can learn from
that we can share so a little bit about
me I'm indeed camp attorney or guy
bottoms from the twisters and the likes
I'm the co-founder and president here at
sneaked and before that I was sitting at
my after after they acquired company I
found its called blaze during that
stretch I worked on what performance
very much probably another aspect of so
the world of DevOps and then prior to
that I spent about a decade in OPSEC you
could say before it was cool not sure if
it's cool today but definitely you know
kind of in its early days billing so
first what security products I also you
know do a decent amount of this little
cocklebur public interactions you know I
host the podcast that I'll refer to a
decent amount here talking to smart
people and trying to give them to share
their security practices and I've
written a bunch of books with the Reilly
including two that you know there's
links about you getting that you can get
a free copy to them on the right around
securing open source libraries and
serverless security so with that let's
dig into the the talk itself and gonna
start with a word that not everybody
likes which is digital transformation
and then snow it's a buzzword and
buzzwords can contain complexity but
it's also a very real thing it's a
change it's a big kind of wave of you
know evolution revolution in how
business has approached the world
digital build software run them and and
how we just operate our businesses
there's a lot of ways to slice and dice
digital transformation and I'm going to
use this split and say the digital
digital transformation you know and at a
very high level is composed of three big
buckets one is more software the second
is cloud technologies a difference of
foundation of technology on which
patience run which interact very closely
with a different set of methodologies
which I'll refer to as DevOps instead
office fully appreciative that again
this is there's a lot of ways to sort of
look at digital transformation so what
I'm gonna do is I'm going to dig into
each one of these three in the context
of security and and see how they affect
it and so more software simply put
equals more software risk and I'm not
gonna belabor this point too much but
really as businesses get digital is more
of your you know your business of your
revenue of your operation you know goes
online and goes digital then then really
more of your risk more if your data more
your revenue risk all of those become
digital as well this is a quote from a
James Kaplan who heads these cyber
security practice for McKinsey and he
has you know he was on the podcast and
he has this great blog post as well
about how securities the the linchpin
cyber security is the linchpin of
digital transformation but specifically
points out quite simply it's safe for
many companies cyber security is
increasingly a critical business issue
not just a technology issue and even
points out you know this reference to C
so conversation that he had but hedge
funds didn't really use to care about
cybersecurity for instance and now
they're obsessed with it just as one
example of many so not gonna belabor
this point too much definitely not a
technical point but but just to say you
know from many businesses if you live in
the technology world this might be
obvious that the tech is at the center
but from any business says it's this
shift of you know what is the chief
security officer focused on from maybe
more physical security or other aspects
to more and more being related to
software risk getting a bit more
technical the the second kind of aspect
of cyber security is cloud and cloud
there was a lot of you can say about the
security of cloud you know you can talk
about how its new technology and every
new technology introduces some risks you
can talk about how it's less mature and
it embraced a bit more quickly maybe and
then its security kind of aspects have
been researched or just about the sort
of the network perimeter change but a
datacenter is something that is posted
online but what I think is more
interesting is that
changes the scope of the application
let's dig into what I mean by that so in
the pre cloudier I again using a little
bit of black and white terms in the pre
cloudy rap you have this sort of heavy
IT stack on which applications are built
you know there's some hardware
management maybe some colossal data
centers some VMs of vSphere running
you've got some Cisco routers managing
these network access or is open some BMS
an Oracle database and singing on side
and then you have some code in some
libraries and if the app teams want to
engage with this sort of you know
central IT stack then you know they open
tickets there you know you asked for
some provisioning of some components and
and you interact and it's owned by teams
that are relatively central and they
manage those components in the cloud
surrounding the layers remain mostly the
same you still into control network
access it's still going to manage the OS
it's still need a database but suddenly
those might be you know a BBC on AWS
they might be a container that manages
that is that of OS and needs to be
patched it might be you know a cloud
database service that you are using or
maybe some more would it be that you
should have pulled in and so the
components are are there the
functionality is still there but the way
that these things are pulled is very
different you know now instead of being
managed by the centralized hateem there
are part of the application they get
deployed and they are packaged up in the
same in the same area and same
repository through the same built
pipeline as the code and the libraries
of the application itself that's very
significant because it means where are
the decision where the decisions are
made that impact these securities and
where the solutions needs to be placed
to help tackle security concerns with
each of these layers is different it
needs to go from IT security to
application security and and just to say
that this trend will continue like this
this motion of going into the app is
more and more and it's break it's on
DevOps we'll talk about that in a sec
but you know you can see data you can
see CDM I've seen a lot in Akamai you
know the API gateways or the use of
third-party services whether in the
cloud or otherwise all these are
becoming part of the app they're
packaged up into one unit one
self-sufficient
package that controls a lot of these
different aspects and and helps them you
know running a missive uniform you know
synchronization and so for security
that's very important we need to think
about IT security solutions and the IT
person central IT person in each unit to
tackle them two more apps I oriented
solutions you know and that need to be
addressed as part of the development
workflow and then last but very much not
least is DevOps and you know DevOps is
it's a it's a big thing again you can
define it in many ways but it predicates
a lot on these two core principles that
are very related one is continuous
processes continuous integration can be
a delivery no no slow down no manual a
non-stop for a manual process and then
the second is these empowered
self-sufficient teams that can do all of
that that you know they own that journey
end to end which you know very much
relates to what I talked about with the
cloud scope so they also control the
scaling of their system the network
access of that system the data of their
systems etc so they can tighten that
loop know from writing a lot of codes to
getting it to the market you know to
provide value to learning from it and
back again and so with all of these
changes security for the most part
hasn't kind of moved with the times it's
left behind security traditionally and
still very much today is done in this
type of element even if it's inside a
circle not an infinity loop it's done in
a way that is about gating it's about
stopping stop here I will do a security
review I will audit you know those are
done by team they're outside and it's
very very much counter to the way all of
these other activities are being done so
the motion to the change that were
applying and it creates a bunch of
problems first security teams are in the
critical path so they're slowing things
down they're not continuous and that
implies they're going against the
business motion they are slowing things
down which which just naturally
conflicts with what everybody else is
trying to do second and related is that
the security teams are siloed they're
outside of where the core decisions are
being made so they always need to be
chasing decisions that have been made
they don't have the right information
they're being worked around or not
pulled in
when they should be and that results in
just poor security just insecure
applications being shipped and to make
all of these things worse
Security's understaffed and it and it's
understaffed not just because
organizations are under investing in it
but rather because there's this big
talent shortage of 50 percent of jobs
remain unfilled and so even if you were
to sort of splurge and want to hire a
very big security team you can't there's
just not enough people for you to hire
and so there's this it's a challenge
security security practices haven't
changed nearly as much as you know these
other aspects of our technology stack so
what I would propose and again show some
examples of leaders and how they've
applied it is a different mindset to it
think about security from a developer
first perspective and what does this
mean when you say developer first in the
world of security most people
immediately say shift left they think
about shift left shift is this notion it
comes from the waterfall mindset it
comes from the fact that there's you
know a start and an end to the
development process and shifting left is
earlier in the timeline and it's a good
thing you know like she flux is a good
thing you want to find issues earlier
and address them before they become
bigger it's cheaper it is more secure
but when you develop in a continuous
fashion in this sort of infinity loop
type model where he's left you know it's
it's not really left it's about
continuous it's about that sort of
constant attraction you know you can say
that developers have expanded to the
right so at the very least it's expand
left versus shift left um but really if
you're going to choose the direction you
know in my mind that change is top to
bottom it's about changing ownership
from being this sort of controlling
entity that's more difficult to toriel
and kind of tells everybody what to do
to more of a bottom-up approach with the
relevant governance capabilities and
this requires changes on both sides on
the development side it requires some
empowerment by the organization of
developers to to to have the ownership
to tackle some of these security
responsibilities and to equip that those
teams with with the tooling right with
the ability to actually tackle it well
and of course development the
development teams need to step up in the
onus responsibility on the security side
you need to shift that mindset and go
from more of a controlling entity to
more of a supportive entity whose job
isn't to
find the problems understand the
problems but rather to allow or help
depth find the problems and understand
the problems and act on the problems and
that their focus is more about
governance and that tooling providers so
what we'll do now is we'll dig into each
of these sort of empower developers and
supportive security teams and talk a
little bit about some examples it's not
a comprehensive list of how can you
achieve this how can you help empower
developers and how can you help
transform security to be more of a
supportive security team let's start
with empower developers and I'll try to
weave in some examples from from those
specific leaders so the first step to
empower developers is to remember that
you need to be building tools that look
like the tools that they use are that
are designed that feel to them like
developer tools not like security tools
that I've been to chop down their
throats and very much like a very big
component of that is to allow self-serve
usage that is successful and it's there
very few security companies you start to
think about very very few security
companies that offer self-serve
solutions let alone self-serve solutions
for developers and they assume a lot of
knowledge and they're just not designed
for that security is it governance
competency it's oftentimes sort of
something that's fairly broad across the
organization and so it's not where
companies have invested but for
developers that's very very significant
they want to be able to start with
something try it out see it work within
their surroundings and some security
companies do this very well you know
hashable fault is a great example has
great onboarding great self-serve
capabilities of zero which is very
security affiliated also does a great
job with some great documentation that
allows also you have to think whether
you're building the steps of tooling
like whether you're a vendor providing
these types of solutions to others or
whether you're building these tools for
your internal consumption you have to
think about how do you enable developers
within the org or within the ecosystem
to self sort of try that out and it's
really a predicate is hard to think of
many successful developer tools that
permeated the ecosystem that do not have
a self-serve usage
the second you know the aspect that
might feel obvious is to think about the
problem from a developer's eyes and
understand how a vulnerability made it
in when you when you look at security
generally solutions have been built for
security auditors so their view is that
when you think about the big picture
view you think about consolidating the
same security risk across many
applications for a developer that's not
the big picture of you the big picture
view is my application and all its
different facets so I know that I pulled
in these libraries they know that I have
these performance aspects I know that it
has this functionality aspect and I want
to know there are security aspects
within the context of my application
within the context of the actions that
I've made that have all these
implications you know security being one
of them and so this how you do this
depends on the vulnerability itself for
the security threat you're tackling and
the world of dependencies you know one
thing we found to be very helpful is
this notion of the dependency tree so in
this example I could say you use five
libraries and these two are honorable
but it's much more productive for a
developer if I say well you're used to
libraries bjs locals and air handler and
they pulled in these other libraries
that are vulnerable it makes it's much
easier to understand how does this
relate to my app similar example is in
code you know I think this is maybe one
of the ones that has been done a little
bit better in the role of security which
is to show you in this land of codes
this is the problem this is a simple one
but oftentimes you also want to explain
what is the sequence of dataflow steps
that you've seen that allow a malicious
inputs together some vulnerable saying
anyone to show that vulnerability within
the conflicts with your code here your
code had this flaw over here and when
you think about the broader scope of the
app as we talked about for the cloud the
same concept applies to your code in the
context of say containers you know in
containers you can you should separate
for instance for developers it's a very
big deal that separates the base image
from what is inside the docker file it's
very different if owner abilities in the
base image you want to address it very
differently you would swap the base
image you wouldn't fix the point problem
that has been outlined versus if it's in
the docker file you know that that's
kind of your code that's the code that's
written for Europe
and then you want to be able just like
in that line of code to point to that
line of code said well here's the run
command inside your father's so think
about problems from an application
context from a developer point of view
another like a great practice that I've
really loved in the same vein you know
comes from from segment so segments you
know they have a lot of really really
smart practices one things they do is
they have this training where you know
they have a two-part training for a new
developer one of them is this thinking
like an attacker and in that practice
every example they use is one of a
vulnerability that was actually
previously in segments reported
otherwise found and what they found you
know as I highlight here is that it's a
lot easier to get developers to care
right to relate to this vulnerability
when it's a feature that you're familiar
with it's a world words it's your
context it's your code so I love this
practice it requires a bit more work of
course but you know it's just turned
these vulnerabilities into great
educational tools my highly recommended
for example all of us are for examples
in the silver and power development side
is to remember the developers don't have
the same level of security expertise as
the security person so you want to
provide not just the answers but also
security questions no you want to guide
the developer to say this is what's
important from a security perspective
for you to even probe you know for you
to ask that question and I'll give a
couple of examples here one is Pedro
duty so Pedro Duty can be used for
Incident Response as a whole and
specifically for security incidents as
well it has good capabilities and they
did this great job writing down what is
a security incident and what are the
steps you should do and clearly this is
the template and it can and should be
customized for different organisations
but I love the hand-holding is to say
this is what is a security incidents
these are the questions that you need to
do this is the sequence of steps that
you should do it should cut the attack
factor you know cut off the attack
vector that's the most important thing
you can't expect developers you can
expect developers to take responsibility
to note it to act on it but you can't
expect them to become security experts
the tooling has to embody that type of
expertise in our world in the world of
snake we see this a lot around
properties of vulnerabilities there are
a lot of vulnerabilities you know
unfortunately use a lot of open source
and these these are pieces of software
they have bugs including security bugs
known as vulnerabilities and so when you
have too many of them how do you help
developers deal with that faster and
examples of that are so saying for
instance is there an expert in the wild
and what should you ask about that
expert is in binary well no there's a
maturity element so say ok there is an
expert in the wild for this
vulnerability and it is mature so you
should ask them it emergency or when you
talk about a component
help understand where is the
vulnerability above and beyond what is
the vulnerability which all tools do
it's like this is across that scripting
this is an SQL injection tell me where
in the functionality of this component
is the vulnerability and that makes it
much easier to understand it to relate
to my application so all those are just
think about the security expertise you
want to embed
then the last bid I have as an example
here is his remediation and a simple
statement is a developer's job isn't to
find issues it's to fix them and
arguably an auditors job well they
should care about fixing is define the
issues and then they pass it on to
development to fix that they can fix it
themselves and so as a developer you
have like if you as a if you're trying
to get security solutions that
developers will embrace you have to
think about their full journey you have
to think about how do you get them all
the way to remediation and there are a
lot of examples for it I think and think
we're fairly well known around this sort
of open fix they are you know trying to
kind of help um I told you about a
problem and I'll also package it out
into a pull request it's how you can fix
it and now a bunch of other schools are
are mimicking this functionality which I
can help help simplify this you see that
sort of merge advice around telling you
whether it's likely that this would
break it or not that's all about making
this upgrade would break your
application or not you know it's all
about making it easy for you to upgrade
another cool example I've seen recently
sometimes you can't auto fix it but
still help support to that fix examples
this is an example from school called
deep code which is not actually security
focused but when they talk about problem
they show examples of how how it's been
fixed in other repositories so that's
pretty cool as well it's all about
helping your bring me pH maturity and
this is a great example internally when
you think about that remediation which
is you know Tulio has like many
organizations they maintain centrally
these internal golden images golden base
images for containers but they've seen
that that developers you know they need
help knowing when to pull them in and
pulling in the new versions of those
images get released and so what they've
done is they've created an automated
tools that it creates pull requests to
update those from statements in the
docker and they've seen that despite the
fact that I haven't done any internal
promotions because this is quite recent
and the community changed through
attention around two-thirds of these PRS
have been acted on and so you know I
love Josh because Roger like he has
broad security over there and I loved
his his comment says you make the tasks
as simple as possible they do the right
thing you really simplify
so this is one side of the fence right
it's about empowering developers there's
much more you can do around it but just
think like eye developer think about
what you would want on the other side
with security team we need to think
about how do we need to adapt the
security practices and so the first and
big change is aligning the organization
to it security organizations have
generally been aligned to IT org
for the most part because that was the
group that was addressing security so
you want to think about how do you want
to adapt it to the development and the
DevOps organizations have this sort of
simple diagram here where you have dev
dev is aligned to develop some one side
into Apps on the other side then you
have cloud security where does that fit
you know some of it is aligned to DevOps
some of it is aligned to app stack in
its nature of this activities from its
own thing so you want to think about
this a little bit more I would say that
you know this type of change comes in
three core levels there's an
organizational change literally who does
the system report to other people
business there's a skill set change you
know what do you need what are the
competencies that you needed members of
the security team with this problem and
and mindset change that's again that's
sort of controlling entity into a
supportive entity that's a big deal let
me show three examples from different
companies on these three items so
organizational change a great example is
what envision does so envision and this
was from a conversation with Sarah Donna
there's an outside person over there is
the you know they have an absolute
person that is aligned to a preset list
of development teams and I think at this
point the ratio is about one to ten I'm
not entirely sure but what what that
allows them to do is that it gives the
app site person an ability to learn the
domain of those specific applications to
participate in the stand-ups to to
create that bond and it gives the dev
teams a very clear person to talk to to
build that relationship and to go to
when they have a security question or
security need so I love that pairing
it's basically mimicking with finance
and HR 20
so so that's a good example and by the
way like for each of these examples
there's a whole bunch of other companies
that I've spoken to that repeats these
practices and I'm just sort of showing
you one example the second thing is
about skill set and actually before I
talk about Justin's coming here even you
know Yash that I've just mentioned
before from from Twilio talks about how
he likes within his team everybody to at
least be able to empathize the
development and so needs to be able to
code a little bit you know so that was
one example pretty much every security
leader today hiring highlights that
importance and Justins mania was a very
experienced security officer across many
companies he expects this to be a big
shift in the skill set within the world
of security says I would say security
team staff will rotate about 1/3 maybe
half for more of a process management
mindset that is being done today
generally into developers it points out
that you know what does that do to the
secure to work for us that's a big
rockin you know into it do you need to
lay off people and hire different people
rollin Cloutier who's a CISO of
tick-tock today it was at ADP when I
spoke to him ADP he did this big
training exercise he invested he put a
plan in place through a skill or you
know up level in the relevant skills his
reorganization and is done you know very
good job kind of retaining and growing
that talent but you should know to know
his justice says that this is a big
thing this is a big impact that will
take years to shift and evolve into it
so you have to think about the skills
that you need in that team and then last
but not least you know the mindset
change and you know I love Kelly
Shortridge is just brilliant you know
she's a security analyst and she's she's
a victory product in strategy at capsule
8 and she she talks a lot about DevOps
and security and you know one of her
comments says that the wait bill Act she
likes to refer to the relationship
between DevOps and security today's that
they're frenemies and I love that term
but really that inevitably these two
groups are going to need to partner
together and ideally this isn't an
antagonistic relationship so it's a mind
to the change that bills from I'm
telling you what to do to and
collaborate with you to get that done
so those were big changes that are at
the core to core practices one paved
road so making security easy using the
pavement road is is a concept that I
think came from on Netflix these are two
presentations explaining what is the
paved road which is not just the
security concept coming from from a
diamond Marsh as a presentation from
Netflix and you know I'll just kind of
quote her because I think she did define
this pretty well since first the paved
road is a concept formalizing the set of
expectations and commitments between the
centralized teams and our engineering
customers when we talk about security
what does it mean to be secure what are
the practices that you actually should
be doing to get security down right and
the second is technology that makes that
specific set of activities easy in a
specific surrounding so it's a well
integrated supported machinery to enable
engineers to focus on delivering the
porn business value and to socialize the
centralized can support so basically
it's a specific path where there's a
platform that already does a bunch of
the things that you need to do very
easily you know very well for you so it
makes it easy for you to stay on that
route and so this approach is good for a
lot of other sort of DevOps technologies
and it wasn't created for security but I
had a chance to talk to Jason Chen who
is the VP InfoSec there at Netflix and
you know they use that same concept for
security as well right so he says we
call that growth and I loved his terms
as you certainly you can separately
bushwhack and make your way through the
woods but if you have this sort of nice
smooth paved road that gets you to the
station you're likely to opt in there so
it's about making it easy to make the
right decision and they do have that
freedom of responsibility and so even
individual decides you know if it's team
decides to go who to AK you know and can
go off-road then they become responsible
for the concepts that are a part of that
paper out of what does it mean to be
secure so big Road I think is a very
powerful way to empower teams but still
trying to coalesce them towards the
right path and then last I'm very much
lost not least as a computer practice
that I mentioned is this celebrating
security success and it's amazing how
often it comes up in these successful
security leaders
I'll use this example for exact powers
at one medical
says he refers to his experience at
Salesforce as well and I'll just kind of
read it out a little bit so I think
that's great
it sails first we definitely tried a
range of positive incentives at which
he's carried on to one medical it says
someone is as simple as high-fiving
somebody for doing the right thing a
little bit hardness of Corona
surrounding but still like this notion
of just acknowledging that somebody did
something well already goes a long way
and part of it is just like small
incentives for bragging rights and you
know we have this whole conversation
about how everybody loves swag and
around you know who did driven security
and you know they actually invest a fair
bit at keeping it keeping it fresh
around those but what he points out is
that if you empower software engineers
then and you kind of ask them to and
expect them to sort of make decisions
then recognizing them for their a good
decision and good work is a very very
important and produces great results far
more than the steep approach this came
up in a lot of different conversations
I've had on the podcast but you know one
that really kind of grew especially fond
of is from a duo that's now part Cisco
and Mike Handley was the head of
security there talked about how they
actually built they automated a little
recognition BOTS so they have this
friendly neighborhood security bot on
that term that goes off and reaches out
to people and just sort of thanks them
for making good security decisions so it
could be that they updated their phone
to the latest release and done that you
know it's one of the first few people
and they just acknowledge it it could be
just a thank you it could be spot
bonuses to people and split bonuses to
people you know just raising their hand
and saying hey there's a security issue
here so when people do the right thing
just investing in internationally
building it um just for the absence of
doubt you know I called a lot of smart
people here I do provide value as well
when we're in those podcast you know for
instance in this conversation with Mike
you went on to talk about how you know
even little things get rewarded and that
they have a set of these stickers you
know special kind of edition of sticker
that says they were the first to report
a phishing attack or something that they
give and I contributed a lot of value
saying that's awesome I think any good
rewarding system should definitely fall
speakers so it's a lot of ways those
words
so to wrap up you know digital
transformation that's happening right
and whether you like the buzzword or not
that change is very real and security
practices haven't evolved anywhere near
as fast so we need to do something about
that and what I would propose here is
that we need to transform security to be
dead first you know to think about how
that development teams needs to be
making decisions you know we expect them
to make a decision and to be autonomous
and that everything should revolve
around that it should start from that
point and then we figure out how do we
achieve it and I'd like to leave you
with one more quote from a versatile
person you know that I had the chance to
have a podcast and that's Adrian Ludwig
who is the audacity and seaso and he has
this very broad kind of big picture and
he read out his code which I liked he
said that you know when we you worked at
Google you know he got the call from
them and they talked about Android is
coming up strong and they need to figure
out security and that was a seminal
moment for him because it was through
that mobile was an opportunity to
rethink reset how we go about security
and when you think about how good mobile
security is compared to you know desktop
security windows ecosystem likes it's
night and day it's much much much better
and he points out that the shift to
cloud is a similar fundamental shift for
companies so it's a chance for us to
rethink what is possible
so I love that you know it's an
opportunity for us to to think about
something that is different and again I
would posit that a start for that is the
step for security approach focused on
empowered developers and a supportive
security team that aligns this digital
transformation landscape that's for free
thank you awesome thank you very very
much going in fact we have the man
himself here hey guy how's it going
doing well how are you
yeah doing very very well and I'm black
I'm glad that you've set up your room
exactly as in the video tell of hanging
something on my board about the
cognitive dissonance you know really of
like you know sort of the discomfort of
yeah I can guarantee everyone having
worked with guy as well this isn't this
isn't just a zoom background that this
is this is your this is your
it is weird you know that hung up
exactly as it was in the video and
everything so thank you guys for a great
great session people in chat very very
really liked the idea of that
empowerment rather than that kind of
shift left and people recognized it's
obviously you know more than just a
shift left I've asked a question
actually in terms of in terms of this
empowerment you showed that that image
where the dev you know more and more is
looking like it's actually being wrapped
up into the application and less and
less is kind of on that more traditional
upside how does that how does that
obviously we have that balance on 100
devs 210 opted to one security which
we're all very familiar with what kind
of impact does that have on that ratio
is it exacerbate that even further if
more is being pushed to empower the
developers what what do you feel yeah I
mean it's a good question
I think there's kind of two flavors to
it you know one is is the ratio itself
so like the ratio today is unhealthy you
know it's a it's too many so I don't
anticipate a lower ratio maybe a little
bit like when you look at the indeed
companies like envision and and others
that are already kind of employing
already employing this type of pairing
they tend to still be in that sort of 50
to 1 ratio for these one ratio you know
so I don't I don't anticipate fewer
security people would be needed they
noticed maybe we can actually cope with
the load with them on the developer side
it does imply that you know it's just
that ratio alone just demonstrates to
you how you can't just expect developers
to just go off and do what the security
people did as well you know it's a I
guess that the ratio doesn't necessarily
help that because you are outnumbered
before but it still it's it's not
something that's realistic and it's also
gonna take them more effort so you have
to think as you sort of shift some of
that responsibility or the activities
you do have to have that come not just
for the responsibility but also with
tools and also with help to sort of say
how do you actually get that done and
and the other thing I would say is that
some things are actually easier for a
developer to do than a security look the
same security tasks might ease
for developer because the developer
actually understands the application
much better so evaluating for instance
vulnerability once you've acknowledged
it is a vulnerability how does it fit
into the application is all the trivial
for the developer and it's very hard for
a security person who needs to manage
you know interaction with many different
teams and doesn't live and breathe that
know the specific app yeah although you
know security ratios won't change much
but you know their activity will all
right cool
two more questions that just come in
first one from David's caronia guy
touched little on how to think about dev
first security from a product
perspective and I'd like to dive deeper
into that specifically what are the top
three things to consider when building a
dev first security product and what are
the top three pitfalls and mistakes yeah
it's always hard to kind of hold it down
to the top three but first of all I
would say that when you're building an
internal product you're building a
product just the same as when you're
building an external one like I said a
bit more captive audience but hopefully
you're aspiring for the same level of
success you know that so what was it the
top three always again the sin of the
earth so the love of the top three
pitfalls or mistakes and top three
things to consider when building a
deputy well you've got a couple more
questions so that's just going to top
one def so the top pitfall is the thing
that you can take an auditor product and
you can just integrate it into the
workflow of the developer and that would
make it a developer product so that's
probably the primary pitfall there's a
lot of options from it but actually put
yourself in their developers shoes and
think what is it that the developer
would would need to be successful in the
day today and actually you know go talk
to the developer you know you know the
audacity here you know instead of I'll
get that input and then I guess comment
related is the the top the top thing to
consider is ease-of-use probably kind of
coming back to the fact that developers
are expected to do a lot you know so
really fundamentally you want to raise
it you want to get them to care the
product has to be so do you know elegant
and you know very secure but if it's not
easy it's not gonna be used so it has to
be very straightforward for a developer
use case
No we have a few more questions near so
I'll encourage you to jump into the
Bella Latro and answer some of these
what I want to finish off this is a
really interesting one
Brad says thanks to great session what's
the metrics for efficiency you suggest
as a as best to measure dev empowerment
yeah it's it's really really like
metrics and security metrics is always
hard matters an earring and hard metric
and security measuring risk you know
it's super super hard I'll give a few
guidance oh I don't have like a magic
number to give but I'd say when you look
at security
you should look breaches they're not a
good feedback loop but you should
separate your backlog from your addition
of vulnerabilities from response so
those are the three bits I'll start from
the last responses like and you can set
SLA so how quickly do you respond when
an issue comes and reported to you
that's a process question it can be
optimized and it includes how quickly
can you make a decision do you have the
right information at the time even when
you chose not to address it that's still
like an SLA element so that's one the
second is this notion of not getting
worse can you stop the bleeding right so
try to measure how many issues since you
started as though you had no issues at
the moment how many new issues get
introduced that you find out about after
and maybe even how quickly did you find
so try to sort of figure out four new
issues forget the backlog four new
issues how are you doing that's probably
the fastest that's the measure you want
to do to focus on first right like
that's not the leaky bucket right
otherwise like you keep trying to
address the backlog but you're creating
more and more faster and then last is
really around that backlog we're really
it's about the strategy for addressing
you know the the rate of the issues in
the technology it's more but a constant
kind of model of constantly improving
constantly fixing things
all of those are overlaid of course on a
risk poster like you always have to
think about when you do address an issue
are you addressing the most important
issues so that's hopefully that kind of
gives you a place to start measuring is
hard you know especially insecure
wonderful guy thank you very very much
for your for the session and like I said
if you're able to spend some time
umbrella there's a there's a bunch on
the main stage more quite a little bit
so thank you very much and enjoy the
rest of the conference