thank you thank you for having me
alright so in the next half hour forty
minutes this is what I will take you
through so we'll get to know each other
a little bit maybe slightly more
difficult than if you were in person but
like let's just pretend I'll be great
we'll talk about what I said I was going
to talk about so hopefully those
promises will be fulfilled by the end of
the talk
a few fundamentals on so what is it why
should you bother I do have a crazy
theory even at this time on a Monday
what you should also make updating your
LinkedIn profile that could be a thing
and everyone lots of measurements and
then we'll have questions again great
all right everyone sitting comfortably
let's go so quick he's Sam so I've been
exiting this slide has not been updated
my jobs like he doesn't ask you at the
strategist I've been there for just over
a year but I've been doing security
since since the beginning of time so I
worked in support for a while I
definitely done Incident Response for
enough years to make me aged terribly I
was like my job title was not chief
apology officer strangely enough but I
did spend a lot of time saying sorry to
people but things that were nothing to
do with me but you know it's good to
have a full guy I think I don't product
management I've done product marketing
really like the cloud never file means
that you like the cloud nothing strange
or illegal should you require a DJ at
any point I am available for weddings
bar mitzvahs death gotten parties you
name it if you want some terrible music
I'm right there and if you'd love to
chat about old-school malware oh yeah I
can talk
Conficker and sanity over beer quite
happily right I take I talk too much
I've dumped around in front of
PowerPoint slides and if you'd like to
come say hi on Twitter and you can find
me at safe sex with NCS okay let's
pretend that I can see you if you could
just say your name what you do tell me
about yourself a little bit cool nice to
meet you that was great thank you okay
what are we going to talk about today
what are we not going to talk about
these things all come up if you google
saw maybe if you can't spell I have no
idea when that came up and this is a
complete mystery about these things all
available through the awesome power of
Google and other search engines are
available here's what we are going to
talk about so what is saw how it can
help you how you can think about
approaching saw what you should automate
what you shouldn't automate and then how
to measure success I do work for a
company that sells a sort product we're
not going to talk about it you're not
going to see it want to talk about it
there's loads of stuff on there this is
more really thinking about soars of
process and the ways of doing it so
let's talk about what sort is so sore
stands for security orchestration
automation and response and I imagine
given that the dev Sec part of the the
conference name automation isn't exactly
new in dev it's not really that new to
security either it's been around a while
and there were loads of lovely waves of
automating things I mean half my
hilarious automate it out of office but
automating tasks really is because
computers that said in security we often
are still doing things manually which is
just a bit weird sometimes I think that
there could be lots of reasons for that
trust me can be a challenge and if
computers are going to screw things up
they'll do it quickly
that's something I've said sorry for a
lot so getting getting this right and
understanding kind of where to start not
trying to literally boil the ocean or
indeed automate the ocean is is a good
thing so there are some good candidates
than some things that are maybe best
left for humans it turns out so lovely
friends at the Gartner this is I've got
their acquaintance or give you a second
to read this fantastic description but
ultimately it's about bringing the
pieces together within your your toolset
getting rid of that low-hanging fruit
and then understanding where humans fit
into that automation price
because it's not a good idea to go in
order to make everything you do in
security operations from start to finish
because things will and can be wrong
when people think about saw there's kind
of two real areas that kind of come up
when we're talking to organizations this
is kind of the first thing people talk
about playbooks and then having some
workflows you can have playbooks and
workflows without touching saw
whatsoever they can be completely human
operated but generally these things take
time
and time is not your friend in security
operations
so hopefully you kind of got a bit of
what soar is so you've got automating
kind of the things that happen and then
orchestrating we're bringing different
tools together to perform some of those
tasks and that's great but so up should
you bother is the first question I think
computers can do things very quickly and
if you haven't set things up properly
they'll do what you told them to do and
that can be bad or you know it might not
work so it may not be that they cause a
huge issue but then we might have to
something that's broken and not
performing well and if you're expecting
it to happen and it doesn't that can
have a whole host of knock-on effects
there is definitely concern if we do
loads of automation does that mean we'll
actually have a job at the end of it
especially if you are saying working in
a Security Operations Center just
getting started in a tier-one kind of
function does that mean my job's going
away that's a real concern right and if
you're kind of hiring people or you know
you're in the leadership position
somewhere does that mean then that
people become more expensive do you only
need seasoned analysts and we can talk
skills gap all day long but certainly
there are fewer seasoned analysts and
there are junior analysts coming through
what happens to my junior people how
would I attract their track new talent
so I have to describe for these people
who've been doing it for years and years
and years and years what I have been
sort of folks coming up from university
that are smart and keen and know others
new stuff what do we do with those guys
and then really it just becomes a bit
too much right so we can just automate
anything so where do I start
and then it just you know what should we
just not bother thank you very much
that's been my talk no we should bother
let's talk about why so these are some
good questions to start with as you're
approaching some sort of saw process and
thinking about what to automate within
security operations so you might have
folks currently who are not super
skilled but they're not spending time on
tasks that are kind of worthy of their
skillset especially if they're doing a
lot of manual processes if you don't
necessarily have a tiered system where
you've got different people on different
tasks with an escalation process you
might have folks who were loads of
experience and they're still spending
time doing a lot of manual querying lots
of manual investigations running running
malware and it's all it takes time when
you manual is generally bad when you're
up against a clock alerts are definitely
a challenge sims are brilliant
kind of security products have been
sending alerts in security products it's
very easy to get a lot of stuff coming
in from all over the place without
having real context and knowing what to
do first security technology does create
false positives refer you back to my
chief of policy officer whom I didn't
revile and so I thought that I have so
you know if you you're using software
that's the bad stuff sometimes it gets
it wrong and we did some research into
the while ago that security operations
teams are telling us that they are
spending around about 25 percent at that
time just on false positives that's a
lot of time you know you want to go
weapon security you want to do some cool
stuff chasing ghosts is not called
chasing case is boring and the
moralizing and ultimately and stuff that
really you know you could be doing
something more interesting is there a
bunch of work we aren't getting to I
think that's a fairly obvious one I
don't know anyone who works in a sec
opsi things Wow really don't
anything to do today hmm I should go and
find something it's busy right training
can be a real challenge as well again
more research we actually got some
research coming out yeah it's this is
something that comes up repeatedly in
security it seems we we work in an
industry where it's it's a given that
you spend your own time learning and
it's less likely you're going to get
learning time within the office
especially if you work in an operational
role you know where you are literally
churning through stuff all day long
taking time out to do formal training
can be really painful so no Kenneth it's
you can see working in a Security
Operations role if you're a manager of
that sort of team if you're a leader in
insecurity will you do you think about
like how often you training people or is
it like you think oh yeah they can go to
conferences on weekends or in the
evening or those fun things they can
learn in their own time and again that's
not necessarily a great commitment to
your folks but it's hard to do if you
are working in a busy operations thing
and then then a slightly random number
but if you were around on the break you
will have seen Trend Micro as well as
sponsors my lovely friend Rick Ferguson
avorite trend I caught one of his talks
last year he was saying that they've
done some number crunching and if you
had about a hundred thousand alerts
coming every day which is kind of
standard for like a large blanket swipe
soft so not not all of our security
operation centers may be like that but
to handle that level of alerts coming
through you'd need 217 analysts and I
can probably count on a hand
how many without the outsource MSP is
how many actually in-house security
operations teams have 217 analysts or
even 250 or 260 it emanates much smaller
operations so if you can answer these
questions chances are you've got a
requirement for security automation
orchestration and response
okay so here is really why you should
bother them there are load of good
reasons for doing this operational
efficiency it's cool
accuracy is cool take that with a caveat
first though second
there we go all right so yes efficiency
and accuracy we like those things
reducing risk and security you think if
you're given that with manual tasks
comes comes risk especially if you're
doing the same thing over and over again
I used to work in a team at a large
vendor who has a the original founder
doesn't work there anymore and his
surname is the name of that company so
I'll leave that with you as to where you
think that is
one of the processes that we had that
was a very daily event took thousand
mouse clicks from humans and if you
think you're doing a thousand mouse
clicks every day it's very possible that
you may think you've done that mouse
click today and actually you haven't
because you've done it every day
previously it's a big benefit behind saw
is where you're getting rid of those
manual tasks you're getting rid of that
human ability to also get maybe you're
right
you could also get more value from the
securities back linking security tools
together is a good thing generate as
long as they talk to each other properly
but being able to to use them as kind of
part of the whole rather than just
having them sat there as individual
Islands you get more funky and really
what this all boils down to is
eliminating wasted time and time is
probably the most valuable commodity in
security operations
ah John McAfee nice to see you say
here's my mad theory and having John
McAfee wrapped in tin foil is possibly
related a slightly madcap I see having
this in place as an HR benefit and some
of the reasons on one of the previous
slides around things like training and
interesting work or why that is not
having enough interesting work to do is
what in the top reasons for employees
leaving a company in security and it
seems obvious right you know we're
people who want to do smart stuff with
what people get into security for a
whole host of reasons but you know when
things are really bossing up you think
you've got something
potentially bad going on you're doing
kratsov work you're finding things
before they become a problem that's none
of the cool stuff sitting there chatting
through phishing emails trying to work
out if a links good or bad that can be
sold stirring so there is without doubt
an HR benefit to doing this and also
notice what is it being better for your
people from a doing more interesting
work point of view there's also the
benefit of bone out there's a real thing
in security right and if people are
doing manual work on wasting time
burnout can be very very easy so lots of
good reasons beyond you know we've got
computers and they should help us so
some research mechs have been the new
version of this is about to come out say
I can't get the new numbers yet but stay
tuned it's this week but some of these
things won't be that surprising most
security operations teams have some
challenge around staffing 38 so-called
out they were understaffed last year and
of the unless that we spoke to 42% said
challenging work is a reason that they
stay that's pretty high right on the
leadership end of the scale certainly at
the c-suite people are concerned about
staff inexperience and if you happen to
be in America and you're still awake at
this time great Sunday night if you
enjoyed that Monday morning experience
but training still aren't as regular
certainly where I am here in the UK to
have even quarterly training is is
pretty unlikely so again it's expected
that we go we learn in their own time as
opposed to getting training relevant to
our job during the hours that were being
paid so some third-party research in
case you think I've made it up because X
beam so again training has become an
issue this is a great report it's quite
long I see there must be a way that we
can get this across to you or you can
quickly scroll down that URL but a life
in terms of cybersecurity professionals
goes into a lot of detail on a lot of
subjects but some of the interesting
bullet points related to this training
the right level of training is not
being provided by the employer having to
do stuff in their own time more than
that people don't have enough time to do
any training anyway if it was available
and as far as the the thought process on
security automation pretty much
everybody I mean not the 22 so we like
the 78% there are friends