excellent okay so thank thank you very
much for joining this session about how
to verify for security early and often
so in many organizations the testing for
security usually is done as as can then
fix approach security teams are answers
caning to will conduct some pen test
that trashes the results and then
presents the development team with a
long list of vulnerabilities this is
usually offered referred to as the
hamster wheel of pain the question is
can we do something else better and this
is what we will explore as part of this
presentation where we will start the
discussion by talking about quality and
one of the most cut the one of the
companies that is best known for its
quality bill introduced is Toyota Total
Quality Control in Toyota is achieved
using two principles the quality is
built at every stage and the quality is
continuously continually improved to
achieve this total quality control H and
every member that works within the
company must ensure that only the best
work is then passed on to the next
process no defects no matter how small
they are allowed to move down the
manufacturing line so rather than having
the inspection at the end of the
manufacturing line third that relies on
each individual to be an inspector to
shoot only the best quality for thus is
passed
further down onto the production line
each member is responsible for the
quality of its own work and aims never
to pass poor quality to the next stage
in the process if anything unusual is
noticed then the member can trigger an
alert by pulling the and on cord and
this is a cord which runs alongside the
production line for the whole length
this stops the production line allows
time to investigate before continuing
when this is told then a team leader
will purse
go and see the issue at the respective
station and thank the operator for
stopping a defect from going down the
manufacturing line and that's the magic
ingredient any Toyota employer is fully
empowered and actually expected to pull
the unde on court every time they see or
are aware of a defect when first
discovered by Western manufacturing
companies the anthem court approach was
horrifying
how can you alright anyone on the
factory floor to stop a multi-million
dollars production line this was not
this was the kind of freedom the Western
senior executives were not used to
giving and this was the mechanism that
actually empowered everyone within the
company to stop defects and then fix
them before reaching the customers and
this proven success story has actually
has been later being taken over by the
company probably not more most
noticeable is the Amazon a little bit
about myself my name is Katie Anton and
I come from a software development
background I'm also a while either
running couple of cause projects in the
chapter and I currently work as
application security consultant at a
Varrick code and this is where I work
with development teams architects and
help them to correctly remediate the
security vulnerabilities that have might
have been identified by various tools so
the software development cycle consists
of some basic cycles are the
requirements for the simplicity of this
presentation are just considered the
requirements and designing the same
thing there are more thing that can be
added at the design stage but not within
this one this presentation then once the
requirements have been identified then
we have to implement the specific piece
of functionality coding then we have
testing to verify that the code is about
is being what it's about
to do and then deployment when the
software is packaged and deployed in
production great so let's start with the
requirements because one of the problem
is how can you think of security
requirement it might be a little bit
tricky especially for non security
people thankfully there is an ASP
project for this which is great to use
it as a for guidance and this is the AWS
application security verification
standard or for short SPS it's a
comprehensive project it has 14
categories security verification
requirements split on three levels as I
say that's for example someone wants to
you implement new functionality or
refactoring so for example
authentication and this is one of the
requirements from the latest version of
the SDS we should verify the application
generates a new session token all user
indicator authentication to consider
this requirement into the software
development what we can do is is to use
user stories these are theory focuses on
the perspective of the end user and
describes the functionality based on
what the user wants the system to do for
them for this we can use use cases and
this is a way to actually say as a user
I want to do X Y Z in order to achieve a
goal this is one way but we can also use
this particular one to think from a
tackers point of view and that's where
we can put our black hat on in this case
they are called misuse cases abuse or
misuse cases and this is what where we
can think of as an attacker
I want my system to not be able to do x
y&z in order to compromise steal
information disable any key function
moving back to our requirement so this
would translate the initial requirement
does it picked will translate into a use
case
an abuse case and both of them can be
then used to be converted in unit tech
the respective unit tests and functional
tests so let's say that we have
identified now the requirements and we
are moving into the development this is
the part where a developer will start
implementing the required code changes
into the so called
feature branch this is kind of a
standard into the software development
cycle at this stage when the developer
works in its home code what he can use
or she can use is to ensure that first
of all the software will have those
requirements that we have identified at
the requirement stage and to implement
any unit tests that can be derived from
that security requirement also this is a
great place to actually have some secure
coding and use the development for the
development secure coding some great a
great loss project is the Osprey series
what this house gives you specific
guidance for a wide range of life
languages and the white range of
security vulnerabilities and also the
this at this stage when writing the code
another tool that you can use is to use
an ID security plugin to actually help
scan law that code that has been
developed for that particular
functionality so that's another way to
test for security to verify for security
while you are still in your ID from the
comfort of your ID there is intelligent
eclipse visuals through your ever fancy
IDE you want
so at requirement after the code has
been done it comes the point when this
new development is merged
into the code this is another good point
for security verification and for this
can be used bog standard peer code
review if it is implemented where the
team is trained to take into account
various security standards there as well
various security coding basics this is a
good way as well to share the security
knowledge within the team and another
point to verify for security so we can
start from the requirement and this is
where we can use the ass as BS to
identify the security requirements for
the piece of software functionality we
want to develop refactor there during
the coding the implementation we can
start identifying the unit tests from
the edge this requirement applies secure
coding and have helped us a guidance the
ostrich's sheets and verify for security
using IDE plugin to help you test your
code in the comfort of your own ID and
again have the peer review as an extract
point of checking for security once the
code now has been into the main
development branch or master we can
actually trigger at this point test and
the first that can be used are the
functional tests which have been derived
from the SPS requirements but also can
trigger for example source code analyses
assess to verify for the security of the
entire code and when we deploy we
prepare the code to be deployed in
production
this is the point where you now are
creating your release candidate branch
and then this is when you start testing
of what is the code that will actually
go in production and at this point you
can actually you can have the entire
suite of functional tests including the
easiest ones that have been derived
sawdust but these are not the only one
and you can actually have other tools
you can automate some of these you can
also happen at raishin testing if that
will suit your cycle although the
penetration tests are manual so they're
more that can be done at this stage but
this is just a suggestion
great so hopefully in this very short
presentation I have give you an
understanding give the points and high
level of what we use at each of the
stages of the software development cycle
in order to verify for security from the
beginning from the requirements place
alert they can be in the ICD 5 line but
also can be humans like like during the
peer code review