all righty so we're back we're gonna
start our lightning sessions for that
I'm gonna welcome first Sabine walks
attack I am hoping I'm pronouncing that
correctly hello there hi how do you say
her name
zabi nirvash shocked sabina Vujicic were
shocked yes alright it's a little bit
complicated but it's fine
alrighty
alright I'll kick it off I'll go ahead
and now add your screen thank you for
joining us again I just introduced you
maybe shortly
Sabine is I need to see a stick agile
and DevOps neighbor from get next ID and
you can go ahead with it okay thank you
very much welcome everybody to the first
ignite which is obviously mine and the
title of my ignite is going DevOps why
top-down or bottom-up might be the wrong
question at the beginning of a
transition or your way to DevOps or dev
SEC many greetings from Kea my name is
Sabina vishesha and together with my
husband Mike we are running yet next IT
and would get next IT we help people on
the way to become more agile or to go to
being DevOps so that's a very
interesting topic the first time I
entered the international stage of
speaking at DevOps days was 2015 and
from this time one question came along
my way again and again and again and
this is how what is the best approach to
yeah implement DevOps top-down or
bottom-up and for me the whole question
feels somehow wrong but I didn't know
why it felt so wrong so I started my
journey to discover what is wrong with
the question I found out that all the
answers of is it better to go top-down
or bottom-up absolutely right and true
from the points of view and so yeah I
had a look at the top-down advocates and
they say we need the top the top
management to support the DevOps
initiatives because this costs money it
costs time and
if they do not support it we will not
make it but we also have the bottom up
proponents and they say okay it costs
time and customary but we need the
people at the bottom to do the DevOps
style to implement the whole culture
without them it does not work and we had
the third party the I it depends
champions and to be honest I'm more the
it depends style and they say just take
a look and look how the company and the
teams are working and then we can find
out what's better top-down or bottom-up
but still it was not the right thing for
me and I started to step back and had a
look on what's the goal of doing DevOps
and we have a left of different goals
but I picked just out some three of it
on the one hand we want to build better
products we want to build in a better
quality but in the end it's about happy
customers delivering value to them
delivering benefits to them put them in
the center of whatever we do so what do
we need to make our customers happy what
do we as a company as a team need to
make them happy and then the fast
changing times we have some special
needs and one of these needs is to get
rid of silos because silos slow down the
whole process and silos don't help with
interdisciplinary communication and yeah
continuous improvement so the first
thing is get out here it off silos the
second thing is eliminate the blame game
machinery because blaming each other
does not help to improve we want to
learn we want also to learn out of
failure and we want to learn fast and
for this we need to found the
communication and the decision-making at
eye level so we can talk about different
hierarchy levels different positions in
an open transparent way without blaming
without getting stuck in the silos but
with asking what is better top-down or
bottom-up we implicitly build silos we
implicitly built hierarchy and we
implicitly
we versus you depending on your point of
view so also this question what is
better implicitly
has the chance for blaming if we are at
the top and we start the top-down
approach and it does not work we can say
okay it's not a power failure it's their
failure because they are at the bottom
and what about the people in the middle
we all know when we want to do a
transition in the company the people in
the middle are extremely important for
making it work that all the
communication can work along the whole
stream and we can come to a stronger we
and I think this is the most important
thing we need to have a strong we to
come closer to DevOps to dev SEC or
whatever you want to do and therefore we
should ask the more beautiful questions
what do we want to achieve together what
do we need to achieve it and how can we
do it together so it's about we and when
you want to start asked who should start
and I can say it's you start with
yourself and be the change in the whole
company be the first one who asked the
question question what should we do
thank you very much thank you sir man
that was a quick one and a lot of a lot
of agile there yes
all righty I hope you enjoyed it we sure
did