so hi everyone and welcome to a quick
session about the infrastructure as code
security my name is Brook Foster I'm a
CEO and co-founder at breach crew a
cloud security startup that has both a
very large open source projects and a
great platform that solves some of the
issues that we've talked about today and
about cloud msconfig if any of those
open source projects around AWS security
terraform Confirmation kubernetes and
GCT security are in interest for you
please feel free to reach out to Twitter
its Barack's Oster camelcase
all right so let's take a bit step back
and think what was infrastructure
security a few years ago so back in the
90s it probably has been these old
firewalls with knobs and switches and
people that were responsible on the
security of the perimeter or actually
the people that brought it into the data
center like took the Heavyweight server
plugged in and the way for them to many
security is actually to play play with
it one generation after that came the II
management console of the firewall that
gave the IT professionals an idea of how
to manage the network and how to manage
the different configurations of it and
it was really centralized within the IT
or security team to hold the keys to the
kingdom which is the data center a few
years after or nowadays or at the past
two or three years we are not seeing
those kind of infrastructure as much as
we've seen in the past we're not seeing
those centralized team that manages
security within IT boxes what we are
seeing is a decentralized solution of
managing firewalls for example or
infrastructure generally using API calls
like the security groups or file manager
of the AWS cloud and this is really a
huge transformations because instead of
doing a manual work with a dedicated no
switches or dashboards we can now stand
up a new firewall
with just seven lines of code so over
here we have an example of a terraform
block therefore means an infrastructure
is code language that helps us defines a
firewall with the port of tls/ssl open
to the entire world which is usually set
save for web servers and it doesn't look
the same like it used to be so terraform
is one of those infrastructure as code
languages that gives us the flexibility
of creating new resources by the
throughput that we have on our business
it is part platform agnostic it has the
ability to manage a state and keep
history contracted the changes in your
environment and essentially version
control your infrastructure your
architecture using code and he says a
lot of upsides in terms of productivity
you can now move some of the workload
that was only centralized in the
security team into the developers teams
and application teams and cloud
engineering teams and what we were
seeing today is more and more
infrastructure is called languages
exists for different use cases so we
have terraform for infrastructure
provisioning we have cloud formation and
erm that does exactly that but only for
AWS raju
we have kubernetes which is a great
orchestration framework for containers
unstable for OS management and
serverless for lambda functions and as
your functions and puppet for some bare
metal configuration changes and it is
really great because you can stand up a
whole datacenter a whole production
environment in just a few lines of code
and minutes of deployments it lets us
much much faster and be sexualized
around business logic and really have a
great solution to how to scale that
business logic but when there is amid
the issue with this configuration is
called frameworks is is that it might
bring with them some on recognized risks
and it's not because those frameworks
creates a risk is because people are
writing more and more code more and more
configurations and they are not always
aware of miss configuration that are
inside those codes so where would you
find those these configs in those
infrastructure frameworks
probably at the open source or even
internally you have repositories or the
terraformer histories or blog posts
people are writing these boiler plates
step boiler plate templates to provision
a new web server for example or a new
database but they often might forget
maybe because of lack of knowledge maybe
because they didn't pay attention or did
have the capacity to review that code
they are not putting the best practices
of security into those configuration
frameworks so let's take a look on a
small research that we've done inside
bridge so in bridge who we've scanned
randomly 1000 and 800 different
terraform modules from the open source
and what we found is that 48% of those
were misko peer meaning had some kind of
security risks like unencrypted
databases or reports to the world and we
will see some of those examples
well 52 were configured correctly it's
still a lot of misconfigured modules in
the open source and how many downloads
did those misconfigured modules had over
10 million that means that over time we
had 10 million provision resources in
the public clouds that were
misconfigured at some point in time
while it does not really mean that don't
specifically were necessarily
exploitable it is still a huge risk to
bring into your cloud environment either
when using open source models or
creating your own and what are the kinds
of miss configurations are so most of
them
and the top top one issue is the lack of
logging and auditing and that means that
your security team really lacks the
visibility to the infrastructure that is
in the cloud backup and recovery is
really a reliability issue of what will
happen in case something that happens an
encryption obviously nowadays it's
really easy to encrypt
each and every resource we've managed
services like AWS kms and cmk or even
solutions like hash the corpse of all
the treaty is easy and quite cheap to
manage encryption of data that we are
not saying that implemented as a default
on each and every open source model and
there are obviously issues with
kubernetes networking and other
privileged I am roles and how does that
look over time what we're seeing here is
that every few months the pace of
contributing new models is going up and
up and this is great it gives us as
developers more and more power and more
and more pre-made
cookbooks of how to create new
infrastructure the issue that is that
over time the number of misconfigured
models is also rising in a huge space so
what we see here is that we had like a
very few new modules contributed every
month and at the passing month the pace
is like a hockey stick and this is June
which is still not completed and what
happened during Kabat we had a huge
spike probably because of productivity
and everybody are at home we had a huge
spike of new misconfigured modules in
the open source so how can we solve
those misconfigurations detect them and
fix them this is why we started breach
through which you can track every change
in your infrastructure code from the
change request that you've created in
your get have a beef Club account to a
scan a fix and then only after the fix
is being applied or a scan is being
approved and not rejected due to
security reasons any resources
set of resources can be provisioned into
your cloud environment from there rich
who will keep and continue to monitor
your production environment for any
configuration changes that are either
being done use the infrastructure code
or manually by an admin that has access
directly to that AWS console how does
that look like on the developers app
here we can see a pull request that has
an annotation that bridge web made a
bridge crew action on github on the
security group and it has the the
annotation that port 22 means SSH is
open to the entire world and that should
be actually fixed and the pro requests
of this developer that created a new web
server in telephone have failed due to
security checks that did not pass how
can we solve that at scale so let's see
let's think that we have those thousands
of lines of infrastructure code but
bridge we can help with is automated
pull request that detects bad
configurations and bad practices and
pushes the fixes to your github with
neopor requests that fixes this
infrastructure so we're here you can see
in DB instance that had didn't had
encrypted encryption turned on and it's
just getting turned on automatically and
opens up a new request sabri tree is
really about detection and fix of
infrastructure in the public clouds if
you'd like to learn more about which
group you can start for free at bridge
crew dot io if you'd like to take a look
on our open source tools that are about
static analysis of infrastructure code
and runtime analysis of infrastructure
code case visitor github page it github
/ bridge crew io and you can read more
about it that's what bridge crew dot IO
if you have any other questions please
feel free to direct message me at
Twitter it's varrick's Oster camelcase
thank you