okay awesome hi everyone I am Tanya
Dinka and today I'm going to talk to you
about what dedsec Ops is things are
changing and we have security people we
need to change the way we are doing
things and so I am going to talk about
how security needs to learn to sprint so
alright so I like to tell you what I'm
gonna tell you then tell you then repeat
what I told you to make sure that you
get it and you know it so we're going to
talk about how security is everybody's
job so the security team can't actually
do every single security activity so a
lot of our work is enabling others to be
able to do their jobs securely
um I'm also going to talk about how
DevOps can be turned into devstack ops
and how security becomes a part of
DevOps that's what devstack offices it
is us as application security
professionals adjusting ourselves and
our activities to make sure that they
leave nicely through the processes that
all the dev and ops people are doing so
no more gates no more stopping things or
say no all the time instead we have to
do a bit more improv and say yes I know
you need to accomplish this business
goal but let me help you do that at
security so the other thing we're going
to talk about is how some people in
security see DevOps they see the magical
DevOps unicorn who picking rainbows
because they're so amazing and then
security people some of them feel
they're cleaning up but that's that's
not what I see thanks to Francois who
you just saw he made this amazing
beautiful slide that I absolutely love
where the security person is enabling
the magical devops ponies and they're
you know giving other tools helping them
teaching them enabling them and this is
the way I've been in a dev site house so
there is going to be this very positive
slant on this just in case you couldn't
tell that's what was coming I'm so the
mandatory about me slide so look there a
add another deficit comment so I'm Tanya
Jenkin
the internet so I like punk rock music a
lot on the Internet
I am known as she hacks purple yes some
of my hair is purple because I'm a
purple team err like I do red and blue
team activities so attack and defense
types of activities so purple team means
you can't make up your mind I am really
obsessed with I lost the open web
application security project I am one of
the founders and am very enthusiastic
about will sack women of security and I
work at my company if she likes purple
death oh yeah so I hope after seeing
this you're like yeah she seems worth
listening to I'm gonna stay awesome
let's do this okay so let's learn some
stuff so I'm going to give you a few
definitions because I never know the
level of knowledge of the people that
are coming to my presentations and so
this will just take one or two minutes
to make sure we're on the same page and
then we're going to jump into cool new
stuff so application security
definitions so what is access I say apps
a lot instead of application security
because it's shorter so every activity
that you do towards the goal of making
your software more secure is absent it
doesn't need to be super formal you can
have an application security program
that's formal but if you are hiring a
pen tester to come in and assess the
security of a web app that's part of
that sec if you are looking through your
source code and you realize oh this
but it has no validation on it oh my
gosh
and then you got some that's pretty bad
sack it doesn't need to be really formal
oh it is fighting the good fight and so
that is what I consider enveloped in
application security and then I want to
tell you why it's a bit of a problem so
application and insecure applications
cause between 29 and 40 percent of
breaches um I haven't updated this slide
but the Verizon breach report continues
every year and so we won the worst place
or first place of causing the most
breaches in 2016-17 2018 and now 2019
I want us to lose and not win this
anymore and oh and here's here's one of
the this is from 2016 look at us causing
all the problems um another reason for
this is because application security is
missing in schools post-secondary
education they're teaching people how to
code but they're not teaching them how
to code securely and even in high
schools they're teaching them you know
hello world but they're not teaching
them how to sanitize that input that
they're getting and so quite often the
security courses that they get is just
it's not enough to ensure that those
software developers are making secure
software another issue in our industry
right now is the security as I
remembered see her see how she's all
alone
that's me when I'm on like so many
access teams I am that sec team the
whole to you and us being a member it
makes it really really hard for us to do
a good job so if we look at some of the
numbers they're approximately ten
operations folk and 100 software
developers for everyone the security
person and I've never worked somewhere
where my numbers were actually this
great it's usually hundreds of devs just
for me and that means you can't just
work you can't just work harder you have
to work smarter and the last thing in
this is water
all so software developers are moving in
droves towards DevOps because it works
it works so well
waterfall projects in software
development not with construction or
with hardware it works well for those
but for software it around 70% I saw in
a study fail that's a lot of failed
projects and at the security model that
went with it not good not good and so
now that dev and ops have like Joint
Forces I want us to join forces with
them and not only be awesome at making
kick-ass software I wants to make a
kick-ass software that's secure ok so
what is deficit cost what is she talking
about what is everyone talking about
this entire conference for 24 hours so
my friend Imran said this you tired
wrong give the keynote rep AIPAC
he's awesome if you didn't see it you
should watch it later he's amazing so he
taught me this
he's like Tonya dedsec Ops is what we've
always done it's just us doing acts SEC
but in a DevOps environment do just
change the way you do the things but we
shoot for the same goals and I was like
gosh this guy's so smart and then I
became his friend so now I'm gonna talk
about what DevOps is and how their main
goals fit in with the security's goals a
lot of people don't think of it that but
their goals actually mesh really nicely
with what we want and so that's why we
should be besties so first of all DevOps
people want improve deployment frequency
right there they want this so that
there's less risk right what I see is oh
good security emergencies can be fixed
right now that's awesome so if there's
actually an emergency you can you can
get that out right away like a true
emergency not you're missing this one
security header on this one page
um I worked somewhere once in a
waterfall shop and our release cycle was
16 months and an emergency the sky is
falling situation they said they could
get a release so in four months and to
me when I saw DevOps it's like much
I can't tell you how enthusiastic I was
as a security professional okay lower
failure rates that sounds awesome too
right okay
so what they call it is resiliency but
if we look at I'm sure you all know this
this is the mandate for IT security the
CIA triad
it is our jobs we get paid specifically
to protect protect the confidentiality
the integrity and the availability of
the systems and the data that we create
and collect that's our job and if you
look at availability that's almost like
it means resiliency if your app is
always up because this tough and it's
rugged
that means it's always available and
that is security people resting really
well at night so this is good so we are
still on the same page with these DevOps
folks we still be like where they're
going with this so there's one more main
thing that they aim for faster
time-to-market I've had a lot of people
stay Tonya I don't see how this relates
and I have to disagree there is no
security team if there's no business I
don't have a job if we are not releasing
software I have actually given talks to
security teams before as the consultant
explaining to them that they were the
main threats to availability with all
their gates that they kept pushing up
I'm like we will go out of business if
we follow your guidance we have to
release we have to create products we
have to release features if your job to
help us make sure we do that securely
it's not your job to
us and so security doesn't win if the
business doesn't win we lose then when
we all get laid off and so I feel that
faster time-to-market as long as we are
still able to ensure that it's secure is
a win for everyone and also I feel as a
side note that security is a feature now
people are interested consumers are
interested in knowing like this product
has had security testing my parents
bought a TV and it was a smart TV and I
was like well you have to only buy the
Smart TV that has actually had security
testing done on it because you know and
they were so proud that they the TV that
had the security testing guys like yes
because otherwise I was gonna make them
take it back to the store um but the
point is is like we don't win we as a
security team we lose it's a business
loses okay
so now we know oh yeah this is another
quote from me I feel DevOps is the best
thing to happen to application security
since the open web security project I
feel like a wasp is amazing offering
like the projects offering so much
opportunity tools books learning all
these things and the chapters around the
world constantly teaching people helping
them network DevOps is the it's the best
thing since that and I that is the
highest compliment that I can pay as an
OSP nerd and enthusiast okay so now that
we think that we want the same things
that DevOps folks what how do we how do
we make that a reality
so we need to learn the three ways of
DevOps so there are three ways basically
things that we need to do to make sure
that we're actually doing them so DevOps
is not just we installed some pipeline
software and like one of the dev teams
is using it we do DevOps nope I disagree
I read the devil
handbook the Phoenix project the uniform
project and accelerate which are all
awesome books which I should share a
link at the end actually to a book
review I wrote about them but the
basically the blog post has just me
fangirling but basically all of these
books written by a whole bunch of
brilliant humans that like were part of
the start and like perfection perfecting
of the DevOps movement the idea is is it
if you have these three things that then
you're doing DevOps so the first thing
is you need to emphasize the efficiency
of the entire system and not just your
part so I've worked out lots of places
where we have big silos and quite often
if you could break those silos down you
might see you oh I my parts actually
really quite efficient and fast right
now
I should go lend a hand at this other
part so that I can start receiving
things quicker and that is what it
focuses on efficiency of the entire
system not just your part so sometimes
it means going and working with other
teams which is really important the next
one is fast feedback loops so we want
feedback now that is white waterfall
doesn't work out so often because you
don't get feedback until after you know
nine months or a year and your clients
first of all things might have changed
your client has changed our opinion
there's just so many you could be on the
wrong path and quite often there's
misunderstandings and miscommunications
and if you can get feedback constantly
that means you can save so much time and
money and heartache and then the last
one is continuous learning risk-taking
experimentation failing fast and
spending time working on improving your
daily work so I wish that there was one
fancy word that I could used for that
but the idea is is that if we don't try
things won't know if there's like a
better way for us to do it so run an
experiment like where you take metrics
and then you see like oh actually this
tool is actually way more effective than
that tool or we could put these two
tools together
and then we would get even better
results and if you don't take the time
to remove your daily work then you'll
just keep doing things the old way and
that is definitely not what DevOps is
about okay so now that's now like I've
kind of given a brief overview of the
three ways of DevOps now I want to talk
about specific actions that you could do
to go kick butt at this all right first
the first way emphasize the efficiency
of the entire system so some people call
this left-to-right or speed or see my
super fancy animation right obviously I
should work for Pixar someday my amazing
skills
I'm a sarcastic but the point is is that
we want to go fast so below that so that
image at the bottom the little arrows is
the system development lifecycle
you must have requirements you just to
know what you're building because now
that software developers will build you
something but it won't be what you want
if you don't give them clear guidance
then you know you need to design plan
out what you're doing you code and test
your release and DevOps can do this it's
amazing but the point is is efficiency
and speed so what does this mean for
Devon ops it means first of all we need
your help we really really do we as
security people need your help assisting
and tuning our tools because we don't
want to waste your time we don't want to
give you false positives
it means reusing known good code so if
you have a secure coding library using
those code samples instead of
reinventing the wheel it means you know
if you're going to release a container
make sure that's up-to-date up-to-date
or scanned before you release it rather
than releasing the same image all month
you know updating those containers so
that you have the newest thing that day
making negative unit tests so I'll talk
a little bit about that but basically if
you're gonna write a whole bunch of
units has work with your security team
to ensure some of those units
help you fail gracefully so test that
your application can handle bad input
gracefully we need your help running so
I'm going to talk about an asynchronous
security pipeline so we need you to
participate in that and most of all the
thing that we need from the Devon ops
team is the permission to fail the build
if we find a real secure a serious
security flaw that's the thing we need
the most for you but this talk is not
really aimed at Devon ops this talk is
aimed at the security team so I'm going
to give you so there's seven slides
where I do the photos slide and this is
where you can take a screenshot so if
you're on an Apple computer you press
the command a button in the control
button and then the number four and then
just drag across and then you have all
your notes because I personally don't
like typing notes while I'm listening
I've trouble doing both at the same time
so I made these for you but this talk is
more about security so this what does
efficiency of the entire system and
speed mean for security it means we
cannot slow down things we can't be a
gauge and we cannot break the build
unless it's really serious right we
can't break the build because so I love
security headers but we can't break the
build over one security header I mean I
love them so it means we need to learn
to fit our work into Sprint's if Devon
ops are using Sprint's so if they're
doing three week time intervals where
they release their code that means we
need to figure out how to do our work in
those three weeks time intervals so we
can't do like a six week code review
because the code has the code base has
completely changed in that time that's
not effective so we need to review only
parts of it or adjust ourselves in ways
so that that works and we need to focus
on improving C
for all the different value streams and
show them how we're adding value to the
end product we can't say because I said
so that doesn't work unless you're
talking to a two-year-old
and most software developers are
significantly older than two so we need
to treat them like the adults they are
and actually explain you know why the
RISC matters and exactly what we need
from them um yeah so we can't have Devon
ops just waiting on us all the time we
can't be the bottleneck we really we
need to work within their processes and
if we are creating our own processes we
need to make sure it works with theirs I
have seen so many security professionals
who care a lot but they are thinking it
outside their own box and you know for
instance creating an 80 page
architecture document that they're
expecting teams to fill out and I never
get to fill them that's not happening
let's create processes that actually
work that enable them to create secure
software um so the next one is I
mentioned this briefly on the last slide
but like we can break up our work into
smaller pieces so that it fits into our
sprint so let's go back to code review
you know review code in one for one
feature or for just the new code or
break up the application into different
sections with different goals you can do
this with your your dynamic application
security testing you can do this with
threat modeling there's so many ways
that you can break things into smaller
pieces it's also extremely important
that we tune our tools and retune them
and listen to Devon ops when they give
us feedback if they're telling us you
know this is not working well for us
this is not helping us we need to listen
and then adjust right because because we
won't because they'll go around us
because they have the power
software developers make something out
of nothing every day and they don't have
to wait for us they're doing it because
they're supposed to they don't actually
and another item on this is if at all
possible provide secure templates for
them if you can ever provide templates
for them to use that our self-service
please please please please do because
that hopes they have a lot of time and
it also can create good relations when
they know they can count on you ok so
this is the next photo slide I would
like to tell you during the slide that a
secure coding library is a great thing
but you need to work with the software
developers to create it do not just go
into their code repo and might start
messing around the code repository is
like a woman's curse you do not just put
your hands in it
we are security people it belongs to
them and so you need to respect that or
it won't go well ok next slide so what
else does this mean for security another
so I think that I've seen a lot of
people talk about and that I've done and
it's I mean I'm a giant tech nerd so I
just find it fun you could create more
than one pipeline for the same patch so
you can have the release pipeline and
that's the pipeline that goes to prod
and you can just have your very serious
security tests in there that you can
have an asynchronous or parallel
security pipeline that does all the slow
tests that you want so oh they're gonna
run a static application security
testing sassed exercise on the entire
code base and I know it's going to take
18 hours so you can just kick that off
on Friday to come see the results on
Monday and not annoy anyone so when you
put that in the release pipeline
you're ruining everyone else's day on
that team but if you have your own
asynchronous pipeline you're not
bothering anyone and you're still
getting cool results and you're still
using automation you can chain all your
security tools together and then go dig
around and the results on Monday it's
really really nice another thing for
security is if you can buy licenses for
security tools if the developers really
want you know oh asks app which is free
or if they want
we don't know burps we or they want
Fiddler's or they whatever it is that
they want if it's a thing that they want
and you can afford it pay them a license
because they're doing some of your work
for you and that's really great I love
it when other people do my work trust me
yeah so just this repeats what I was
just saying so we'll just continue on so
there's more things for security this
does not mean doing 100 percent of the
security work yourself that is
impossible you can't do that so this
means teaching dev and ops and enable
then enabling them to do some of the
work
it also means potentially writing your
own cool libraries or tools if you feel
that you have a really specific need and
there's nothing on the market that can
do that for you
be creative and do anything you can to
make sure that they can get their jobs
done securely like their I've seen so
many creative ideas on this so here is
the next photo spy and I realize I'm
gonna have to go faster because I only
have 13 minutes left and I am like
halfway through okay so faster feedback
I pull this pushing left or shifting
left if you are invited
so starting security earlier in the
system development lifecycle let's get
people feedback right away so how do we
do that so developers and ops want
feedback right away great let's give it
to them so first of all this is a slide
that the Ponemon Institute created this
is the cost of finding a bug a security
bug or any kind of bug later in the
system development lifecycle what you
don't see here this is in production if
you find it if we would have to I don't
even know how much money it would be if
there's a breach there's a data breach
if there's a security incident it is it
just like the chart of money just goes
like this um it is way way way more
expensive to find a bug later and
for security bugs or security flaws so
like a design issue a business logic
issue when they show this to management
it helps me get them on board for
allowing me to start security earlier so
feel free to discreet about this because
this is great
so what does this mean for Devon ops it
means providing feedback to the security
team about things that you are concerned
about please tell us we don't know it
might seem very obvious to you but if
we're doing it it's probably because
it's not obvious to us we're not like
you'll be great
let's annoy the dev team whoa and
agitate them and cause them problems
that is not a conversation that's
happening on any security remember we
probably just are oblivious because it's
not part of our work our daily work so
then the security team when you hear
this we need to listen and then we need
to take action that is important so we
need to listen thank them for their
feedback try not to get defensive when
they call our baby ugly and then we need
to take action and improve we also need
the Devon ops team to participate if we
have security activities like if we have
a threat modeling exercise if none of
you show up that means we're missing out
on your opinions and your ideas and that
sucks because you're awesome that's why
you work where we work right and another
thing is if a major security test fails
it needs to break the build just like a
quality test and this is kind of a it's
like a change in decision-making process
like a thought process that we need the
Devon ops team to take on that security
is a part of quality and if a big
security test fails that that means your
build is not quality and it can't pass
ok so next what does doesn't mean for
security so besides the fact that it
means pushing left and I love that just
to be clear
it also means we need to provide
feedback earlier and wave win more often
we cannot just hire a penetration tester
to come
in two weeks before we go live and then
tell them you know there's like 25
security problems we need to be looking
at those requirements at the very
beginning we need to review the design
with them trap model with them like we
need to start at the beginning it's just
like they do we want to automate as much
of this as we can so that they don't
have to weed on us we want to teach them
to understand what the results of our
security tools are telling them whenever
possible so they don't have to wait on
us and we need to be very careful not to
get false positives because that breaks
trust it wastes their time and it causes
doubt and every other result we give
them so it's really really important
that we work hard not to give them false
positives
another thing is know another thing is
we really really need to listen to their
feedback I know I said that in another
slide that I made a whole slide just to
impress upon you how important that is
if they give us feedback and we ignore
it that is the start of the act okay so
here is a whole bunch of things
Netflix created a tool called repo kid
and it's open source and it helps you
automate least privilege and I think
that's wicked cool and there's startups
coming out with like even more advanced
things than repo kid but it is really
really cool and they've got that idea
from listening to their dev and ops
teams and then changing their actions
based on that feedback and that is why
it's extra cool okay so what does this
mean for security it means so unit tests
are positive tests a test does my code
do what it's supposed to do negative
unit tests tests as Mike does my app
fail gracefully if bad things happen to
it and if we can make negative unit
tests if we can work for software
developers to create these we can have
regressive security testing and that is
magical like if you've had a pen test
then put those results into unit tests
like there's so many cool things that
you
do with unit tests but it only works if
you talk to your dev and ops team also
invite Devon ops to participate in
security activities you might be
surprised you might find a whole bunch
of security champions that are just
waiting to happen so if there's an
incident if you can bring someone along
if you're a loud threat modeling
security Sprint's etc like let them know
they're welcome and wanted and you might
be surprised by who shows up and the
relationships that you can form and how
good how much that can help you with the
rest of the project
another thing is use tools like
vulnerable team management tools to
gather metrics and then base your
activities on metrics once I started
getting data about things oh my gosh I
put this down and start doing this put
all our money here put our time there
because you if you're gonna run an
experiment you have to measure to know
that you've done a good job and if
you're not taking the data out of all of
your tools and then analyzing it you are
missing out on a huge opportunity I know
I'm a data nerd so I'm like I seem
really biased by - because it's awesome
I also think it's it's important that if
you get a contest then that you take
those results and then search every
single app in your wheelhouse
for those same problems because quite
frankly your developers developed all
your apps and they probably made that
same mistake elsewhere and so you can
get more value from that one external
security tester then they might realize
but basically be creative that's what I
would like I would like you to be
creative yes okay so here is photo
number slide number five these slides
are on the internet so if you missed a
chance to take a picture of one of them
and I'm pretty sure this is being
recorded so you will be able to review
it later ok next so continuous learning
full circle I don't have a cute ASCII
image for this
right this is why I wasn't hired by
Pixar okay so what does this mean for
Devon ops
if we offer you security training please
come we need you
you can train yourselves there's so many
free resources I'm going to share a few
at the end share information widely when
you find a security bug tell everyone
else about it like tell everyone how you
fixed it or how this cool thing happened
share information I know that sometimes
software developers can be shy send an
email it's less scary but share share
the information if we have a security
simulation or a security exercise and by
that I mean a fake security incident
where we practice and refine our
processes participate if you can because
it's super fun it's so fun but for
security it means we need to offer
security training and I don't mean don't
click this link
I mean secure code training I mean
training on how to follow our policies I
mean secure design training we need to
show that how the threat model we need
to teach some of these skills if we
expect them to have these skills you
can't expect the average software
developer to understand how to create
perfectly secure code and we also should
base this training off of the metrics we
find so for instance if you are seeing
cross-site scripting everywhere across
your organization that should be the
first lesson that you teach another
thing it means for security is if you
can if you have the resources to run a
security simulation you would be
surprised all the problems that you will
find out and that you can fix before
real incidents happen you'll also
probably figure out that your other
teams don't know what you need from them
and then you will realize there's
training that is missing it is our job
to teach dev and ops how to do their job
securely it is our job to enable them
with the tools and the knowledge they
need that's what I want to get across so
much
in this slide so this is photo slide
number six we are lightning downs I have
three minutes left so what else does
this mean for security it means we must
perform blameless post mortems when we
have an incident pointing fingers will
not get us what we want and it means we
should talk about security incidents
after they are over enclosed so that
developers know what the cost is and
they understand the risk if we keep it
all a secret they won't understand we
need them on our side so we need to talk
to dev and ops like the adults they are
it also means teaching developers and
ops what the output from the security
tools means it means putting all the
stuff into a knowledge base or buying
access to a knowledge base so that we
don't have to repeat the same lessons
over and over again and they can do so
service it means creating
lunch-and-learn opportunities like
writing emails or wait papers allowing
job shadowing like doing whatever you
can to make sure they know everything
they need to know to create really
secure software and systems ok so now
I'm going to talk about culture change
in the few minutes that are left so
security needs to become a part of dev
ops we need to change culture and this
means we need to reinforce culture
change by celebrating wins when a team
does a good job get them fruit or
doughnuts or coffee or whatever it is
that is the thing in your office that
people do reward good behavior and
especially recognize good behavior tell
their boss if there is a software
developer or mots person that goes above
and beyond send an email to their boss
to say it that means so much try to work
more closely actually spend time with
them it's kind of our social events they
are humans you might like them having
relationships is all about what acts
like is
about we can't blame people like I said
when we do post mortems it's not Alice's
fault or Bob's fault
it's what safeguard is missing what
process is broken what policy doesn't
exist and needs to I cannot tell you how
much this matter it's because I have
made this mistake and had to eat a lot
of dirt and humble pie also if you can
create a security champions I took that
I chose this photo because I was just
like she's a badass like she I want her
to be my security champion um those are
the people that go out and help you
fight the good fight
they are your representatives when
you're not there and if you can
encourage someone to become a sturdy
champion buy them a book send them a
podcast or an article you think they
might like like all of that relationship
building will pay off tenfold okay so I
have a call to action I would like you
as is pretty professional to take this
very seriously and enable your it is
your job to enable dev and ops to do
their jobs securely it's our job to
enable them to teach those to help and
automate to different feedback
constantly if you can do anything take
this message home that is our main
responsibility now free resources
because that is how I end every
presentation I'm sorry I'm like one
minute over so ojas join our last
followed up second and the open
community that they have created
- I cops during your local watch chapter
if you're lost and you don't know how to
do something when you go in your
favorite search engine and you're like
ooh cross-site request forgery I don't
know how to do this put in a loss it
will find you a good answer or look me
up I have step two but look up that
first if you are a woman or identify as
a woman most set we're going to security
we both of you we have chapters all over
the world we have virtual activities and
every
single thing is free if you want to make
lots of other women friends that is
that's basically what we want we want
women to join InfoSec and then we want
them to have so much fun that they stay
and oh this should say cyber mentoring
Monday okay so the hashtag is cyber
monday on Monday
every Monday I run this hashtag to help
people find professional mentors on
Twitter
use the hashtag cyber mentoring Monday I
will retweet you every Monday until you
find a professional mentor to help you
join our field or switch within our
field or whatever it is that you need
because we will never have senior
security engineers if we don't have
junior security engineers and the last
resource isn't me follow me go to my
website go follow me on twitter or read
my blogs and check out with you to that
I am Jane heard on the Internet at large
and I released so much stuff and lots of
it's free because I'm bad at business
for good at apps attic and so I hope
today what did we learn we've learned
security is now a part of DevOps
and that makes us Deb SEK aunts thank
you so so so much for coming to my
presentation today I really hope that I
have given you things that you should
run off and do as soon as this
conference is over and you've had some
sleep so thank you thank you Simon for
having so so much if you take one thing
away from this presentation please
please follow she hacks purple on
Twitter because you know you know there
is so much amazing content that tanya
has and it's the best follow you'll have
this year so Tanya thank you thank you
so much for your support for Deb SEC on
not just today but over over over the
years and yeah we look forward to seeing
you again in person at a fruit that
Peter event hopefully as long as they've
plane things I think they're playing it
yeah airplane things one of those things
start flying again so
thank you thank you very much see you
again see