hi my name is Misha Ribeiro and I am the
CEO of spirit sank a Brazilian cyber
security company before I start let me
appreciate all the work done by the
organizers hosts other speakers and of
course our sponsors
it's an honor to me to be speaking up
that psycho and I hope you enjoy our
time together okay a little bit about me
I work with Linux and open source
security technologies since 1999
supporting governments and other
organizations chat up the latest
security technologies I have been
involved with the Debian project and
today's community as well I have a
b-side where I advise technologies I
advise comments about technologies and
international security as well okay
enough about me what is our agenda for
the next minutes well first let's talk
about our goal here my main goal for
this talk is to simplify your journey
into deficit cops so you can get early
and significant results to your
organization using open source tools to
secure your development pipeline or
agenda is the phone he will start of
course defining what is that Cecrops
then he will talk about how to introduce
secured until DevOps future and lastly
how to secure DevOps meant dumb design
technologies using open source tools
okay so to better understand what that
SEC Ops is he have to first revise how
he used to handle security before the
DevOps
moment so in the age of the waterfall
security in the waterfall development as
well he introduces
a series of sequential process to get
her code out and into the world from a
security standpoint of vo he act like
gatekeepers we for roll easily to the
final stages of the development he was
to schedule secured turned it and to
revise the application codes but only
after everything was done when the
developers believed that the worker was
fully completed he graded this code
against a series of requirements in a
predefined and started static list after
days or weeks TGIF we have a hundreds of
page that almost no one read now went to
the first sea level
first to the sea levels executives and
took another pair of weeks to reach the
developers and operators to revise the
code and make the necessary adjustments
and only the company lost time and money
not by not separating the secure code
from the on a private one but he fail to
deploy they required women they required
chains or sometimes the code and
application went into production and
anyway and we know where this this
finish right with the thought he could
ensure a faster development cycles but
our security Pratt's remained very
updated so and this can do even the most
agile in its DevOps initiative right I'm
sure almost everyone has experienced a
successful deploy that as affected by
the rules of the Web Application
Firewall and I think time here
in there of automated tracks that
require automated response there is some
studies that say that 58 percent of the
web traffic comes from human and 22
Kings from that goats and this number is
only expected to change so one of the
main challenges for
InfoSec pros are to bring their their
game from a reactive one to approach
it's a huge you need to integrate
security ensure pipelines from end to
end he needs to listen true lies and
ultimate vulnerability assessments and
give developers fast for the back so
they can to empower and make in have the
necessary training to fix to make
security assessment and fix different
abilities that they find as faster as
possible okay so here understanding the
problem that we have and he now
understand what kind of solution he
would need and how the Delphi cups is
the answer to all that I really like the
way that is NIC the CIO guy define
there's a cop's his explanation is the
following
sorry if the Rob's is composed of DevOps
future metal dollars and technologists
so that's a cop's
should mean to introduce security into
the rocks future to secure the web's
methodologies and to write simple right
okay
but how and if you are the verbs leader
I really strongly advise you to give a
special attention to the concept of CIS
eg because something difficult for
InfoSec cross he'll understand so keep
in mind the continuous its back
I'm sure the integration continuous
deployment and maybe to how can you say
that in English
maybe is a to her token side for us so
help us by making your constructor or
own pipeline this will be great for us
okay um what else this the concept of
shared ownership this is so important
and this is a number that I like and
almost every security manager loves as
well there is some research that say
that for any team of the ropes you have
100 deaths ten ops and just one security
professional this is our word that he
are losing guys so it's good to have
more soldiers on board right so think
about who assumes responsibilities for
across all the chains do the chains
received security education as
guidelines and pulse they feel
responsible and empowered to check
security to make secure assessments
ideally ideally a developer should be
familiar with the fundamentals of
security concepts such as this privilege
cryptography that secures in privacy and
this if
SEC pros are one of the best guys to to
talk about this so create programs among
the chins can work together transferring
knowledge between them creating and
sharing mechanism or tools to ensure
security of your applications and
platforms it's a great way to do it you
can create libraries and out education
then crepitation serves directors for
example with everything available and
easily searchable it's easier for
developers and operators to reuse the
secure code and disappeared scripts you
can create standard images with the most
use it systems such as partial databases
for example and when possible try to use
DevOps tools to handle security issues
most of the companies that are in
between that gym adopt the black ops 2
they are using the verbs for security
for the vault developers and operators
with the security issues are handled in
a different software what you can do is
to open issues in your guitar Burbage
help for security security
vulnerabilities as well this is a great
concept called shift to left Joan weed
is a long time ago not so long talk that
when you viewed music here so the
developers have to be comfortable and
terminate the security of their own code
well how can you do that you introduce
security scans into the developers of
flow
so that pipeline enabled them to find
and fix this one other builds before the
code lived their hands ensure constant
feedback the concept of shift laughs is
the most important one of desktop
because this is the contest that we will
remove that will stop InfoSec pros from
being thing as the bottleneck of
innovation how does this work in theory
when when you have a pipeline and all
the steps are successful the direction
of the pipeline is to the right right
and but when something fails you do what
he called shifts left you stop there the
build and you create an issue into your
repository your issue management such as
HR with hope or github and you create
something unless you to your developers
so this is the concept of shift left you
returned the codes to the one that built
it so as John Willis a you constructed
you security yeah you build your
security right and this is great because
different layers of security are created
and removing reducing the costs of
innovation and a slave accelerating the
process of chains because you create our
differentiation between security code
and the new product one okay you have a
hundred lines of coding and just ten
percent of it wasn't approved okay you
have
percent of the chains into your Butte
the 10% can wait for tomorrow
so until we reduce the costs of your
development okay so here he'd see
standard that's a cop's pipeline with
most of their more used well this is a
this can be updated when he is he the
name of some of the software that are
moving most use right now with into
deaths a cops and before I go forward
let me talk about something that most of
people don't keep in mind but it's very
interest when you are InfoSec Pro in
working with the verbs Qin try to use
your post Morton skills because here
used to to disasters right sadly so one
of the cuter one of the fields into the
develop scooter is to work with post
motor in a more agile and faster way but
InfoSec pros are really good into post
Morton and this is something that you
can use to convert to feel as part of
the job okay now enough about theory now
you're going to talk about action and
this is where I really like this is
really like because as you see my
English is not so good
talk about actions is something that I
that goes is what I hope
okay how to secure the cops Matt dollars
and technologies first let's take a step
back and remember that what we met
DevOps methodologies and
they're giant lavas moment they brought
into the markets a whole new mix of
concepts such as Microsoft's apic ICG
containers clusters private public and
multi-cloud of course nodebots cuter
notify the web's environment is equal to
another with different cultures and of
course different tooling as well
especially considering the amount of
options available if he includes only
the cognitive foundations options here
you have more than a thousand and three
hundred products it's virtually
impossible to be a desiccant engineer
and and say that you are able to secure
hot projects right to illustrate what I
am talking about everyone almost
everyone knows this figure is very
popular on the Internet when you are
when you search for that site DevOps
tools this is the the image that Google
shows and if you expand your search a
little bit more you you see this options
and the cognitive foundations list that
I was talking about so to make our
journeys simpler as a problems in the
beginning of this talk let's concentrate
ourselves into their cognitive security
forces code container cluster and proud
this is another nice take away from my
talk I hope ok let's start by code but
before you go
but before sort of talking about code
let's
you can see in the figure each one of
the seas depend on this huge of the
squares in which in which they fit so
for example your code is a secured as a
container and your container and your
codes is security as your cluster and
you code hotel and enclosures ease and
security as your cloud be it private
public or mochi cloud so remember if you
just have a code security strategy you
are not secured because you have more
three C's to all to concern yourself ok
let's start with code I'm def expect
line oops that box behind is generally
divided into phases and it's impossible
it's possible to start to bring more
security into the pipeline methodology
by automating security code scanners in
the previewed phase you can have a
static analysis test it's a test that he
performing and non production
environment such as a pipeline for
example and the sassed inspects the
application for coding failures
backdoors and hours some of the tools
and languages is specific such as the
goal and linked but so near cube of the
four ones are open source tools terminal
cube is able to check more than 20
languages so when you are searching for
sassed you have to search for one that
checks your code will be your Python or
whatever you are
coding these days and be shocked if the
language that you are using its cover
back down by the tools as a section
right it is a builder options in the
preview stage you can also have can you
can also scan the dependencies it's a
matter of inventory dependence of
binaries and executables and ensure that
this dependences are okay over which you
have no control it's more it's more
common nowadays to have open source code
introducing to your into your own code
so you have to check the divine movies
and the libraries and all the dependents
that you are using checking for
malicious code a market standard of
course is the possible defenses Shack
but you have more options out there is
nique it's a great company and I am
feeling that they're going open source
but I am Not sure and I cannot confirm
and after the deploy you can have
dynamic application security test at
best different from the static test
consists of test performance during this
equation monetary things such as system
memory functional behavior response time
and system performance overall this test
is similar to analysis that an attacker
would do to try to gain improper access
to your application and a good example
are the disaster and Mickey to a be
vulnerable to scanner and of course the
ethics plight as well there are many
more modern tools that you can use in
your pipeline such as last interactive
application security tests and Rask
real-time applications in huge
protection kind of next generation web
application file but big steps right
this is the start of your depth AQAP's
joining so try to include sass and
action to your pipeline and in no time
we use looking for you'll be looking for
other tooling okay what else okay I like
to you to treat as code but it's not
it's your CI CG plataform such as me
drop each hold leisure in etc from many
organizations they are the cornerstones
of their DevOps strategy and securing
these tools is as essential as securing
the code that is host that is hosting it
it's also a great starting point to
adopt the secure the secure strategy of
ownership shared ownership with
developers as they are the primary use
of these platforms together you can
create the story of the plataform users
and map how the different ways that they
could abuse the tool and plan actions to
minimize minimize these risks then you
can include these actions into the
roadmap creating issues and this is a
good starting point both to the
developers of the InfoSec pros as web
and remember that even if your plataform
your repositories is a sass the provider
is only responsible for the security of
the environment the configuration of
your instance is - up to you but get lab
and github they have security center
with the tale documentation be sure to
check them ok back to the first C's code
as part of the code your CIS eg
plataform what's nice container okay
the develops the hobbs environment and
the concept of containerization are such
important steps to improve the facings
efficients of application deliver and
deployment containers are powerful are
powerful security tools if while we use
as they are not the creation of image
standards to be use although many images
are available out there it has become a
city security cliche to ask for
moderation in its use jelly ideally your
team should create their own images from
following safety recommendations ok you
can have a series of steps to follow I
will not go into details right now
because I'd like to recommend you to
check the docker bench for security it's
a document created by the Center for
Internet Security seize and it's a
reference document designed to establish
a baseline for how to secure your docker
recently is NIC has an on-site Spanish
partnership with docker allowing users
to track their imaging and
it will be a great option as well but
back to the Center for Internet Security
document you can use the darker bench
for security script to Shaklee if you
you're in docker image is falling out
the guidelines accent the documents
another options is declare is clear the
open source project for static analysis
of vulnerabilities and docker containers
so a very fast revision you have the
docket the Tokyo Center for Internet
Security
document and you have the doctor bench
for security script and if you want
another open source tool you have clear
of course there is a large number of
options this is the more simple for you
to start okay
cluster many cabinets your district
cabinet will be as safe as the cloud
where which ones now so as the container
and the code including Collins Cuban
execution it's important such a P I and
controlling for another other computer
switches workloads or user runtimes and
such as memory used to prevent attack
the Center for International Security so
has a document about Cuba net secured
like likewise is a document designed
establish a secure configuration
baseline for Cuba nights and you can
check the documents of course and if you
want to
to test cabinets security against this
require the list you can use Cooper
bench to automate discussing your
insides your pipeline and you can use
also cube Hunter commander it's a kind
of penetration test both are developed
by aqua and aqua has a large amount of
documentation that it's they are I
really recommend our course website this
is not propaganda but I learn a lot with
them so okay for cabinets be sure to
check the documentation and about how to
secure and how to treat restrict up his
trip taxes to your cluster and also try
to use good invention hunter of course
there is a large amount of tools out
there but if you want to start a high
leg event convention hunter and finally
we have the left see cloud
the main message about cloud is that you
also do a concept of shared
responsibility this is something that I
took from Amazon website and I'm sure
Google has something similar because
they give the pulse are almost the same
the Securities the cloud is similar to
secure in your own private data centers
only without the cost of maintaining
facilities and hardware in the cloud you
don't have to manage physical services
or establish devices instead you use
social base security tools to monitor
and protector the flow of information to
and out of your cloud resource for this
reason classic
which is a shared responsibility between
the customer and AWS we're customers our
customers are responsible for security
in the cloud and AWS is responsible for
security of the cloud so is the same for
your gates elaborate Holden instance you
worst you are responsible to configure
the restrictions and all the secured
that needs to make your data secure and
of course be sure to check the security
center of your cloud provider AWS cloud
security has a large amount of
documentation and many free trainings
the same goes to Google Cloud and Asia
and if you want to use open source tools
to secure your environment you have
again a cause close exploit and else
called exploit is available you can use
it to check both both Asia
AWS and of course Google itself and
different in a different way for side
Security's specific for G Juicy J just
Google Cloud for Google Cloud and one of
the tools that I really like is the
security monkey Netflix technology chin
is famous for the series of tools that
make opening available such as the they
were secured date cows monkey and they
have nowadays security monkey as well
and you have is come to okay
conclusion this was not the one of the
best of my talks and I really apologize
guys
okay so now we have the basics to dig
into more details about this new
fascinating field I know it was a large
process and it's a lot to learn but here
it is a little to-do list of your next
steps into your dev psych ops journey
first let's revise what is DEP SEC ops
falling guy concept of deaths I got
three phases that suck-ups is to
introduce secure chain to develop secure
to secure the Maps methodologies and of
course to secure develops technologies
as well if you are ops or SEC
professional try to get on board with
the program learn how to code learn how
to use git and see your code your
configuration that's code this will be
your site of securities code but
remember now termination is just one of
the part of dev cycles you have to
change your mindset as well for dogs I
highly recommend you to learn about
secure development practices there is a
large amount of documentation what is on
the internet and your info SEC Pro is
available to help you remember about the
concept of shift left that is to include
security checks into your pipeline to
import empower your dev and ops
professionals to check security measures
and in other developed methodologies and
tools that you have to care about
concept concentrate yourselves or
yourself into the four C's codes
container closed and calm I haven't
heard that well VI PG because I see it
as a part of your code platform and this
is a nice
assessment for you to do is get lab
steps I cops test to check how mature is
your dad's a cop's strategy and it's
also how good how can I say that I'm
good
step by step oh wow what to do be sure
to review this depth that's a cop's plan
constantly and if you keep an eye on my
Twitter I will be sure to to share more
there's a cop's resource to help you out
I believe this very much concludes my
talk and I hope you guys have enjoyed
your time with me as much as I did thank
you for sharing your time with me of
course and perhaps we could start or key
in a session right now
awesome thank you very very much
Michelle and we actually have Michelle
here so welcome welcome Michelle thank
you very very much for your session
we've got questions coming in in the in
the in the chat was flying through now
okay cool
so we're late but we're gonna have five
minutes for questions so Michelle thank
you very much for your session really
enjoyed it and and welcome to Def Con 24
so first question from her Matt have you
had resistant have you had resistance
with DevOps people when talking of
security with DevOps I always kind of
you know wonder how different teams take
the you know the this shared
responsibility how well they want to
take that from a dev point of view how
have you found that well there is two
main point to ten points of view to
check this question before first you
have to consider that security doesn't
bring money to the business so for the
vault for business decision-makers they
don't take security of something crucial
to the work but when secured fails you
can lose a lot of money so this is
something that secured InfoSec pros have
to bring them word how much are you
going to lose if something happens so
this is the first thing that because
most of the time developers are
concerned about making chains bring more
money bring more features to the
sculpture and not taking care of secured
so of course they have some some haunted
haunted system some resistance to it
because it's not part of the innovation
that they are taking care so much so we
have to make their job very smooth and
bring them on board to this kind of
concerns so this is why I talk about the
repository as a first step into
the share ownership because this is
something fun to take care they didn't
know how to use and they know how to use
so this is something that you bring
their own work and really interesting
question coming in from Annie asking in
your experience which of the four C's
would you is generally more vulnerable
so that if I jump back to the slide
lucky because this is recorded I can see
this turn back to this slide there so
all of the four C's be a code C ICD plus
and cloud how would you prioritize that
in terms of which you know if you had
limited time which would you climb like
really prioritizes the areas that you
need most need to focus on yeah this is
something to be very careful because as
you say on the slide each of the the C's
is so secure as the other one so your
code is so secure as your container and
your container so secure as your cabinet
but I think most the most important
thing is caught because this is
something that people doesn't take care
they really doesn't bother because in
the mind of most of the managers and
developers okay you're going to know
strategy and my code and all my
infrastructure is on the cloud so I
don't have to take care of bottles but
this is the truth again
the cloud is something that we have to
have the mindset of shared
responsibility so you have your
responsibilities abundant route as so in
my view would beat the crowd I'm a
mature yeah I guess it's pretty much
depends on on a lot of points it's
difficult to say Oh be careful
just about your cloud but be more
careful about your cloud yeah and I
guess also you know depending on the
texts that you use if you're using maybe
like a lambda function style
architecture versus more of a monolith
style architecture the responsibilities
more heavily weighted towards you versus
the the cloud vendor as well right so
there's there's differences there as
well
one last question we can take from Seco
floods can it be enough to use it so can
it be enough to just use open source
tools to secure C ICD even though that
in case of a breach you'll probably lose
money and reputation well if you're if
you look at the supports terms of
companies that are your pain they're
they're commercial they they have a
limited responsibility as well so of
course you have support and if you are
not if you don't feel comfortable enough
to support your own infrastructure your
own develop your own pipeline please go
to a commercial one but if you are if
you feel secure enough to take care of
your own infrastructure I don't see that
there is a lot of difference then stop
talking about money because when
something happens to your to your
infrastructure there is an crowd for
example there is a limited
responsibilities that the company that
supports you can shake so this is
something for your business to chew to
consider are you going to gain more or
lose more of using open source I really
like open source tools because of as the
previous speaker said you are on the
edge of every innovation because most of
the companies they bring in open source
solutions to the commercial ones so this
is something that if you want to be on
match about your open source but if you
don't feel comfortable enough there is a
lot of good companies come
companies that can support you and of
course there's also like a mix as well
right so for example many vendors will
have luck
you mentioned snick for example many
vendors Walt likes Nick will have a
freemium offering well as like an
enterprise offering so there's there's
there's a balance there as well plus
you're not always limited to just one
tool so you can use a you know number if
if you choose the different areas in the
pipeline Michelle it's been a pleasure
it's been really great Chapman yeah
thank you very very much for your
session appreciate you supporting dev
second