lovely thank you very much so
my name is Catherine and I'm the global
director of solutions architecture at
sono type so at some type I deal with
software supply chain attacks all day
long you know kind of coming in to
Simon's talk just before myself the
software supply chain attack is all
about influencing the code that you
don't own yet the stuff that you use in
your software it's kind of in a mode of
attack that you know I think we've all
in the dev cycles sphere being talking
about talking about for years and years
and years but just as our practices
evolved the mode of the attack need
software supply chain attack itself
evolves so what I thought I'd do are in
this 15 minutes 15 minutes is walk you
through the evolution of this software
supply chain type of attack and just
kind of walk you through the strategies
of defending against each and every one
of them so we all know software has even
in the world it's 20/20 now you know
what a couple of world-changing events
later here we are
test line was spoken in 2010 by Mark
Anderson but looking at it looking at
with 10 years of hindsight one of the
main culprits was open source as Simon
mentioned you know depending on the
programming language depending on the
ecosystem various different types of
software nowadays are mostly open source
about depending on what report you read
you can say that about a 75 to 90
percent of your application is actually
not your own it's either library
libraries that you use libraries all of
those libraries the transitive
dependencies that you pulled in or the
containers that you run them in the old
burning system packages that you have
them in as well open source helps us do
our job that's why you use it right but
just with any revolution or any change
come with it comes with its own risks
right the software supply chain attack
has really been you know depending on
who you talk to the kind of chosen
chosen form of attack are in the cyber
security industry over the last couple
of years and it's many forms are now
behind many of them and many of their
bigger
is that you see out there on the
Internet so um so uh so I'm gonna go
through a few of these just to kind of
walk you through what they mean so um
let's start with the basic software
supply chain attack that was just
demonstrated out just before myself
right that is uh that is using known
security vulnerabilities in these open
source components and betting that you
as a developer forget to update those
dependencies right and it makes a ton of
sense right you know as uh as I
mentioned say 80 to 90% of your code is
open source what that really means is
that about is that you know typical Java
project you have about a hundred to a
hundred and ten different open source
projects on average in the Java world
especially when we were starting to use
our libraries libraries to our
boilerplate our projects we're talking
about three to four hundred modules very
very easily per project anyone who has
ever looked into their nodule directory
probably knows this joke for many many
years right and he all started on many
many years ago this type of attack is
actually a lot older and a lot more
impactful or earlier than we think
right uh one of the first kind of proper
examples of this type of attack of
finding a known vulnerability and
finding software that uses that
particular dependency actually comes
from 2015 with a common component course
called Commons collections that is as
the name suggests a very common piece of
open source it's used for D
serialization and what happened was it
contained a vulnerability that allowed
you to just like just like in the
previous examples run your own code now
what's interesting about this though is
it's very very popular it sits on fairly
many websites and in 2015 when they
looked a new security vulnerability
against it we saw that that
vulnerability was actively used against
the campaign that was really what made
the name for software supply chain
attacks it also had a huge impact for
example it close to Hollywood
Presbyterian Hospital in Los Angeles for
a while because someone used this
particular component to install
ransomware on their computers what's
more interesting is my employer sona
type are sponsoring this so actually run
maven central so we get to see the
patterns of people downloading
open-sourcing using them and when we
looked at it a year later we saw that
about 80% of all the downloads of this
particular component we're still against
that known vulnerable version well
another good example of this type of
attack is actually the one that made
software supply chain a thing
it's the 2017 struts to remote code
execution vulnerability this is an
interesting story because you know and
I'm sure anyone in this circle has
earlier many times but what's
interesting about it isn't that there
was an open source component and it was
very popular and had a security
vulnerability it's that it's the
timeline of it what ended up happening
was since since it was discovered within
a day of it coming out so March the 7th
in 2017 the Apache project logged a new
security vulnerability on under the
under the stretch project they released
a fixed version they released an a
notice to everybody saying hey this is
now a thing what ended up happening
though is the very next day the National
Security Agency of the u.s. the phones
that pentagon scanners themselves we're
seeing our other nation states looking
poking around the internet for servers
with this vulnerable struts instance
trying to run this exploitation code on
the same day a exploitation code of that
particular security vulnerability was
published on to exploit DB there was
also a POC on github and on the second
day March the 9th cisco actually are
later reported that they saw a huge
number of exploitation events running
through networks just packages blindly
trying to see servers with this on March
the 10th several well-known names our
code exploited by this particular
security vulnerability Equifax being one
of the better known ones and you know
three years later we all know that that
was one of the biggest data leaks of the
or decade but what was well less known
is there were several other wig things
including the Canadian Revenue Agency
the okinawa power agency in japan the
Aadhaar system in india and using that
particular component we still saw
several different types of iterations of
the same attack not even against newer
versions of that vulnerability but the
exact same vulnerability for example in
december 9 2017 the
crypto mining campaigns and even today
when we look at the stats and we look at
how often this particular version of
strats is downloaded we sit about 65% of
the population still goes for these
older more vulnerable versions so again
it's a type of attack that preys on the
fact that you as a developer are not
remembering to go in and update your
dependencies it has it's a known
security vulnerability it sits there and
it's being exploited but one of the
things that this kind of a mode of
attack proved was that was that you can
take over the upstream you don't have to
wait for a new security vulnerability to
come into play in order to in order for
you to arm execute a campaign you can
just manufacture one of yourself
probably the most famous example of this
happened a year later in November 2018
it was executed against a component
called event stream which was
compromised no this is a this was a
pretty clever attack because this is
really the first orchestrated campaign
against an open-source component so what
happened was a seemingly been a
favorable stranger joint the project
started contributing code eventually
eventually they got committer rights to
that repository what actually happened
was they introduced some particularly
obviously malicious code in that in that
open source component now everybody
noticed that in fact I think it took
about two hours for that vulnerability
degree publicized but what wasn't
publicized was that actually they
cleverly hidden another vulnerability in
an earlier version so when the newest
latest version was discovered to be
vulnerable what usually happens is these
links get posted on slack people are
downgraded to you know in oneness one
and that actually contained a targeted
campaign against a crypto mining
cryptocurrency and winning and snuck
away with wallet wallet contents so this
was the beginning a beginning of an ad
type of attack where not only are we
trying to influence find open source
that's clearly really federated itself
onto your software we're actually going
back to the source and we're trying to
influence the code itself so when you
start throwing these out on a map
you actually start seeing a pattern you
know there's plenty of a plenty of
attacks and not enough to talk about in
15 minutes but what you do notice though
is often these are these are attacks
that or harbingers of each other for
example in January 2018 there was a
famous medium article that went around
that spoke about harvesting credit card
numbers using a bogus JavaScript attack
it was kind of a parody that was written
but by the September of the exact same
year that exact mode of attack happened
with a small company called
British Airways where one of their one
of their our JavaScript libraries that
was sat on their payment page was
poisoned by an external attack in a
campaign where it started actually
sending credit card numbers away from
that payment form so in some ways the
prediction became the harbinger of those
types of attacks and open what we see is
when a new type of software supply chain
attacks in occurs in one ecosystem
there's some kind of prince looking at
it trying to replicate it in elsewhere
so good news is readable defenses you
know my employer and others came out
with tools that help you understand what
opens you have helped you bump these
versions give you pull requests give you
banners and github give you all the
badges that you need to tell your
community that you've got trouble but
but so too did the but fundamentally
what we ended up doing was automating
this for all your projects what we
really did we go my final my excellent
animation that I'm running here what we
did was really go through each and every
one of the components on the list and
ask the question are there known
security wannabes on this are there
known security vulnerabilities on this
or the known security vulnerabilities on
this and to encourage upgrading
fundamentally that's really what all of
these kind of go through but
unfortunately the attack types have
evolved as well they've actually also
taken or taken a new form to to attack
you as well this was described just a
couple of weeks ago by github the new
new type of attack called octopus
scanner it's an interesting type of
attack because it comes with your open
source or other projects that you might
download from github and in fact about
26 are dependencies there but it goes
after against a relatively
popular IDE called NetBeans witches are
used in the Java world very old for us
who have been actually using it now it's
an interesting thing because what it
does it actually contains a malicious
file called cache dot that which is
injected into your net based project
directory now what happens is it
actually Sneed's itself into the build
system every time you build cold whit
NetBeans this cache that the file
contains some code that is executed
whilst you build the code and what it
actually happens is it goes ahead and
infects all the class files that you're
producing and all the nested jars that
you generate are inside of your own
project so he adds its own code into it
now this code goes on to live somewhere
else and goes on to infect other
projects and in fact other projects and
other projects or other projects etc and
for good measure it also goes ahead and
backdoors your own machine and it
introduces it into into a botnet that
can be that can then retrieve and
execute some commands from some command
and control server somewhere else pretty
scary stuff and it also runs on pretty
much everything then and the kitchen
sink so that's the thought that I want
to leave you all with today what you
don't no longer need to do is just look
at the name unfortunately this attack
probably bears the message type of
attack bears the message that in the
future in the future there's gonna be
other types of attack that deliver its
target not your own code but your
development environment and what you
need to be doing is not only looking at
known security vulnerabilities in known
exploits but also whether or not your
code is a hundred percent open-source
canonical now there are tools like my
employers that can help you do that and
identify completely unknown and slightly
modified components but the final thing
to understand is controlling that list
unfortunately no longer is enough you
need to go deeper and find out what is
going on with these codes in order to
state these off it's a it's a
interesting future that we're developing
and I'm sure we're going to see many of
iterations of this going forward as well
so give it a go see if you've got it
yourself come talk to us on our stand at
some type and we'll be glad to answer
any questions for you too