[Music]
[Applause]
and the next talk i'm very proud to
announce
we have a speaker who's coming in from
sunny california
and he's an attorney he's uh working for
harvard he's doing so many things and
he's
fighting for our digital rights
and i'm very happy to say hi welcome
thank you um
yeah and uh
spot the surveillance is the topic um
we will see
what we haven't seen before and i'm very
happy
that you're here and could absol
please let us know what's up thank you
thank you
hello everybody my name is kurt opsahl i
am the deputy executive director and
general counsel of the electronic
frontier foundation
i'm here to talk to you about observing
police surveillance at protests
so why do we want to observe police at
protests
well because protests are political
expression
as the council of europe put it the
right of individuals to gather with
other people and make their collective
voice heard
is fundamental to a properly functioning
democracy and this is a right which is
protected by the european convention on
human rights
and other international rights treaties
but
surveillance can chill that right so
knowing what technologies are in use
can help you understand the threats to
your privacy and security
as well as provide tools to advocate for
limits on police user surveillance
surveillance that may chill people's
right to express themselves on these
public issues
just as analog surveillance historically
has been used as a tool for oppression
nowadays policymakers and the public
have to understand
that the threat posed by emerging
technologies
is a danger to human rights and they
need to understand this to successfully
defend
human rights in the dictionary so
journalists who are reporting on
protests and police action
should know the surveillance that is in
use activists who are advocating for
limitations
on police use or surveillance need to
know what surveillance is being used to
effectively advocate
and legal observers may need to document
the use of surveillance and protests
in order to challenge the police actions
at the protest or challenge police
policies that are being used after the
protest
with the footage they've obtained so
what do we go up today
we're going to provide a lot of
information about various types of
surveillance technologies in use by
police
around the world uh we're telling you
where to look
what the appearance is how it works what
kind of data they collect
and how they're used by police and at
the end we'll have a few
other resources available for those who
want to dive a little bit deeper
so police surveillance technology is
everywhere
it's on the police themselves on their
vehicles
on the roadways it could be above you in
the air
uh surrounding you in the environment
can be a lot of different places and you
need to know where to look
on police officers themselves you'll
often find in the form of either
body-worn cameras
or additional devices that they're using
which are basically mobile biometric
sensors
body one cameras are technology that's
uh come out and become more popular over
the last decade or so
originally was something that was being
used
as a way to provide police
accountability that
uh give a record of their interactions
with the public and maybe for example
could be used to show police brutality
or maybe deter
police brutality but there are two-way
streets devices are often used to
surveil protesters
and the footage may later be used to
support arrests
and charges for example
we use this npr story where after a
rally
weeks later the police went
identified people through body cam
footage and brought action against them
uh for obstructing the railway which is
part of the civil disobedience of the
protest
based on finding them on the body camera
footage
they can put you know a variety of
places so
uh if you're looking for body worn
cameras you gotta look in different
places to see where they might be
so a couple places they might see them
on the head a head mounted camera
so it might be on your glasses on the
side could be a lens right in the center
uh the center one is pretty hard to find
but
uh the ones on the side or it might be
part of the glasses or maybe a helmet
they're wearing
are generally pretty obvious these ones
they're not particularly common but they
do they do happen
um shoulder mounted cameras also a
little bit less common
but uh they have an interesting feature
in this case we're using the warrior 360
from blue light innovations as an
example and it is a
dome camera that looks all directions
uh so 360 degrees off of the officer's
left shoulder
well most cameras like a front-facing
camera
will capture only 180 degrees
chest mounted cameras are the most
common and these are being used
very very widely uh we give some
examples here from from amsterdam
madelberg and from west midlands police
uh
in the uh eu or
soon maybe not in eu for a case of
britain
and there are several known types uh
axon wolfcom and watchguard are very
common
uh they operate in similar manners uh
though
uh with some differences and
you can uh take a look at some of the
examples that are available on those
those companies web pages where they
will explain the products they have on
offer
and see what matches up for your
jurisdiction or you can also look in
for news articles oftentimes there's a
news article about when the
first policy to bring body worn cameras
is introduced in a particular police uh
there's also smartphone based cameras
and these are kind of the
the low end uh it's basically just an
android cell phone
using its internal camera with an app
that does recording
placed in a pocket so the camera is a
little bit above the uh the cloth
and can see forward uh but it's also a
very subtle technique it could be easily
confused if you weren't looking
with someone just storing their phone in
their pocket
it also might be clipped somewhere on
their uniform
but if you see anything where the camera
is facing outward
and it's attached to the officer there's
a good chance that that is a body worn
camera at least that app is in play
and last on the bodyboard cameras we'll
talk about the semi-obscure camera so
this is an example from a company called
body worn
sorry the product called body worn
company called utility
and it is partially concealed it
basically looks like a button
on someone's uh you know more uniform
that if you're not looking closely you
might not notice but if you see as you
led you know it appears where you would
expect actually not to have a button
it's slightly larger it looks a little
bit different it looks like a camera if
you look up closely
but if you're looking at a distance and
not particularly paying attention you
might not
see it at all in addition to body worn
cameras
police will often use uh mobile
biometric devices
so these can be handheld scanners uh it
could be
a tablet or a camera phone
um and in some cases it just is a camera
which just has a particular app on it um
but we'll see that uh you can sometimes
tell
whether they're using a phone or whether
using as a biometric scanner
by the body language so for example
if the police officer is holding up the
phone
trying to capture someone's face that is
most likely because they
have a capturing a photo and they may be
connecting that to a facial recognition
application
and you also will see mobile
fingerprinting
so uh here's an example in the united
kingdom
they have an app on the officer's phone
combined with a fingerprint
scanning device and it takes the
people's fingerprints and checks them
against some databases
one is a database of everyone the police
have detained both
putting it into the database and then
checking against it for for new people
and the other one is a database for uh
immigration
uh to collect it at the border when
someone comes into the uk
and this allows the the police to do a
very rapid check
of their records on somebody in the
field
some of these devices are multi-modal
they'll do both they'll be able to do
do fingerprints and take photos for
facial recognition
uh this here is the dataworks plus
evolution
does both um
and that can be you know convenient for
the officers
uh but it's a little bit more dangerous
to some of the ways
and some of the body warm cameras in
this example wolfcom
has a biometric capability built in
facial recognition so it can uh
use its regular camera functions and of
course all of them if they take the
picture
that picture could be uploaded to a
database and facial recognition will be
done later
but this one is designed to streamline
that process
so i'll take a moment as i decide to
talk about facial recognition in europe
uh per algorithm watch the organization
says that there are at least 11 police
agencies in europe who use facial
recognition
as shown on the map here the uk court of
appeal
found that automatic facial recognition
technology used by the south wales
police
was not lawful however elsewhere in the
uk they are still using it
the metropolitan police is doing in
london
is doing a live facial recognition
throughout the city of london and it
contends that the situation is
distinguishable from south wales
so now that doesn't doesn't apply to
them we'll see how that turns out
there's also been some pressure on the
european uh commission
to put a ban in place or put
restrictions on facial recognition
and uh in september there was a quote
from
the commissioners saying that they were
considering whether we need additional
safeguards or whether we need to go
further and not allow facial recognition
in certain cases in certain areas or
even temporarily
which is not a particularly strong
statement but it is a at least they are
considering the idea
and this is something that one can
advocate for in the united states
a number of jurisdictions at the local
levels uh cities
have put restrictions on their police
departments so they cannot use facial
recognition
it's a growing movement and while a
national
or international law that would limit
police use of facial recognition would
be the best for civil liberties
you can also start at your local level
all right once we move beyond the police
officers results where else
vehicles and roadways and this can come
up
for the vehicles roadways both adjacent
to the protests
and within the protests themselves so
adjacent to the protests
is looking at the exits and entrances to
the protest areas
and they may use existing alpr or place
new alpr
uh or ampr automated number plate
research called alpr in the united
states
and these are cameras generally we
pointed towards the roadway to where
cars will be
that are designed to uh take a picture
determine what the license plate uh
number plate is
optical character resolution they will
eventually
recognize them eventually be able to see
what it is
check the database and find out who's
registered for that
car and it can be uploaded to a central
server for place to search
can add vehicles to a watch list it is a
very powerful tool because many people
are using cars to get to and from
protests
uh and uh even if they're they're going
in in a group
at least one member of the group would
have had the car
and it has been used to go after someone
after a protest so in this case
it was from a number of years back but a
citizen in the uk
uh went to a protest and was later
pulled over
because they had captured the license
plate
while at the protest added to a database
and then use that to pull them up
so if there is a protest the police
might come in and use a portable
number plate reader uh so here's some
some examples what they might look like
they're either on a tripod or on a
trailer uh and they can set these up
basically anywhere
it would often be used at the entrance
or exit to the
zone in which the protest is expected to
see who's coming in
or who's coming out uh during the
protest time period
and trying to sort of capture the crowd
through their license plates it also
is now becoming more and more common on
police cars
uh you can see a couple examples we have
here uh
one it shows it uh rather obvious in the
top one that's a uk police car
and uh you can see the camera sticks out
fairly obvious that they have a camera
on the light bar
the lower one from the french police
less obvious it looks like an ordinary
light bar
uh you might be able to tell that it's a
little bit different
than some other ones because it has sort
of a
funny thing in the center but it's a
pretty subtle approach
um so there's all kinds they might also
be mounted on the hood or the trunk
and it may be more or less obvious but
take a look
at phones and also take a look at what
the police cars behavior
if they are driving for example slowly
down the street next to a whole bunch of
parked cars
it may be that they are doing gridding
practice known as gridding
where they are looking for capturing
every parked car's
license plate in a particular zone
you're trying to run
slow and steady in order to do that
uh and then there are the fixed number
plate readers
uh these are often at traffic lights and
intersections
on the highways uh any sort of
high-speed uh uh toll road will have
them
they also are you know they're used for
other purposes like to uh
uh establish uh fines uh to
check uh border crossings they are very
common fixtures on
on roadways so a protest happens in the
zone that already has them
the police will be able to access that
information and know who
entered or exited that area around
all right and then within the protest
itself
there may be adding additional
surveillance capacities
so in this example we have a
the santa fe police department uh knew
about a protest that was protesting
a uh statue uh and uh
there was a question by me so people
would take action and remove the statue
so in order to capture that through
surveillance they place this
trailer which has a number of camera and
audio capabilities
uh and just rolled it in right next to
the statue
to capture the protest action
and these cameras can come in a variety
of forms
uh in this case look at the watch towers
personal control cameras can be in
personnel controlling the cameras can be
in the watchtower
or they can be operating remotely as you
can see
uh you know they are using a scissor
jack to to raise it above that van
uh the other one is a uh an assembly
it's not easy for someone to get in and
out of there
so it may have a person but somewhat
inconvenient to
to actually have a person inside these
watchtowers but it's much more
convenient
to use their built-in surveillance
capabilities and remotely
uh observe the area around the
watchtower with those cameras
and then there are also pure
surveillance units uh there's this
example here
uh showing uh uh
four cameras uh raised pole
and just adding surveillance capability
basically to anywhere
and some of the uh
some of them are much more complex
thermal imaging cameras
uh thermal imaging uh often comes from
the leading company is fleur
that stands for forward-looking infrared
floor system makes a lot of these
devices and makes them available to
police departments
thermal imaging cameras allow the police
to be able to conduct surveillance
after dark where the lighting is poor
where they might not be able to
identify individuals very easily instead
they can use their heat signature
and be able to continue to monitor the
protest
when the lighting conditions are less
and a lot of things on protests will
happen at night
candlelight vigil is very commonplace so
police will be looking to thermal
imaging to make sure that they have
strong surveillance capabilities after
dock
another thing you might see around a
protest is an emergency command
vehicle uh these are often massive bus
sized vehicles
uh and they do have some surveillance
capabilities they might have some
cameras
uh but more often they are command
commanded control
so they are the places where somebody
would be receiving footage from cameras
and operating cameras remotely uh
making communications with other people
in the field
uh though they also may have some
built-in capabilities
and they may provide the focal point
where a local connection they're getting
information from local devices
and then they have the uplink in the
command center
one thing i wanted to point out is a
common misconception or something that
comes up
a lot when people are concerned about
police surveillance is they'll see an
unmarked vehicle a van with no windows
uh it may even have some antennas or
satellites
and while that is possibly an undercover
police
vehicle uh you shouldn't assume that
that vehicle belongs to law enforcement
uh that could very easily be a
news media vehicle news media also goes
to protests
they also have satellite uplinks and
antennas
uh they look very similar and in some
cases
the media has a security situation there
they're worried that there may be
theft of equipment and they have
unmarked vans
so uh is worth noting that there is an
unmarked vehicle
but you shouldn't necessarily assume
that it is a police unmarked vehicle
also sometimes people see especially
they see some antennas or satellite dish
on a vehicle
then maybe that's where a stingray is
this is a misconception
stingrays are pretty small
and they don't require an external
antenna to operate
you could put a stingray inside a trunk
of a car
uh you know maybe about briefcase sized
so it would be
unlikely that uh if you're going to use
a
stingray or shell side simulator or mc
catcher
that you wouldn't want to put it in a
vehicle you don't need to put in a
vehicle
that has its own antenna there have been
not very much documentation these
technologies have been used in the u.s
domestic
protests uh they have been used
we know in some protests in more
authoritarian countries
uh so it's unclear how often they will
be
are being used and they are very
dangerous things simpler
so in mse catcher it is able to
determine what cell phones are nearby
uh get a unique identifier with that
cell phone
and many cases be able to use that
information to determine what
individual's president approaches and
that information has been used after
some
protests in ukraine for example to send
a text message to people telling them
that you know
we're on to you we know you were there
which could be very intimidating
to individuals but the challenges if
you're trying to observe
police surveillance and every test it is
hard for you to observe it because they
are often hidden
uh you may be able to find out more
information later through
investigative journalism or public
record requests or news reports
if somebody is prosecuted using that
information it may become obvious
but it's difficult to see at the protest
itself
so next category look it up in the sky
there are lots of forms of aerial
surveillance
enforcement agency will surveil protests
from above
using traditional aircraft with onboard
pilots
and as well as smaller remotely operated
aerial systems
drones law enforcement may also use
these area vehicles to communicate with
the crowd
to use the loudspeakers to send a
message to the crowd order them to
disperse
and we've seen this actually drones with
loudspeakers being used by the german
police
in order to tell people to stay apart
corona
that same technology can be used for
protests
and these planes and drones will often
be equipped with high definition cameras
capable of either an extremely wide
angle to get the whole scene
or an extreme zoom where they might be
able to zoom out on a particular person
a particular license plate and then use
that data later
partnering that the aircraft with
license plate recognition face
recognition video analytics
and even a cell site simulator inside
the aircraft
and this you know we know this has
happened in a recent uh
protest in texas a texas police drone
uh caught some footage of a of a
protester allegedly throwing a water
bottle
they took that video they took the
picture put it out offered a cash reward
and anonymous temperature turned the the
kid in
and protest uh uh was prosecuted
so police are definitely using these
things to gather information
at protests so a common uh method for
actually larger police departments
uh is fixed-wing aircraft for smaller
ones they may use
private contractors to provide these
fixed-wing craft so this is an example
of the kind of plane used by a company
called persistent surveillance systems
it rents out a plan like this without
this exact one you look up that tail
number it's going to be to a different
company
but the same model of planet assessed by
and these will circle around the protest
uh
using their cameras to observe
protesters below
an advantage of planes is they can often
circle for
uh quite a long time and provide a wide
view of the
of the area also
helicopters helicopters will often be
seen hovering over a protest
uh they are a little bit easier to
maneuver and be able to go backwards and
forwards
over the protest uh and are used by by
police to
uh continually observe uh and
we use two examples here one of them
from the oakland police department the
other one from the ryan land police
department
in both cases they have a fleur attached
to the helicopter a forward-looking
infrared
that would allow them in addition to
regular cable capabilities
to use thermal imaging to follow someone
uh out of protest or follow what's going
on
after dark um you can also
see that some helicopters will have
spotlights so that they can
uh signal to officers on the ground
who to follow who to pay attention to
another thing for both fixed wing and
helicopters
you look for the tail number in most
jurisdictions they're required to have
the tail number
visible and then you can look up that
tail number on services like flightaware
and be able to uh find out further
information about
what that plane has been doing what the
helicopter has been doing as well as the
ownership
finally drones drones are becoming
a very common place because they're
getting cheaper all the time
and have any additional capacities
drones are also known as unmanned
aerial vehicles uavs uas unmanned aerial
systems
uh and a lot of police departments are
getting them
for their capabilities using most
commonly a quad rotor
and they can be controlled by remote
control have a
camera built into this and be useful for
getting
above the scene view um
so one way to spot it well first of all
just listen to it they make kind of a
distinctive noise
uh sometimes they'll be marked as police
uh you can also look for the pilots
operating nearby so oftentimes a
you can sell a drug file first of all
sometimes they're they're labeled like
in the
upper left there it says police drone
operator pretty easy to identify
uh other times they might have like
drone uav
aviation unit on their uniform on a
nearby police vehicle
the other thing is that if you identify
a drone
uh they're often within line of sight is
going to be the operator so once you see
the drone
look around and see if someone has the
wrong controls in their hand
is looking up at the drone you can
probably identify the operator
and go look for information they might
have on their uniform
about who is operating that particular
drone
but also keep in mind both for drones
and other aircraft
that is not necessarily the police uh
journalists and activists will often
file
fly drones uh over protests news
helicopters
for our large protests are going to be
more common than police helicopters
and many times they are labeled a
picture of the bbc news copter
uh but this means that just as you see a
helicopter
that has both the camera uh and is
flying over the uh
protest that does not necessarily mean
that it's a police
also another technology which is
actually not not very commonplace
outside of uh
protests in uh war zones uh but the
drone killer technology which is
basically a ray gun
that knocks drones out of the sky
sending uh radio signals to
uh interfere with the drones operation
and cause them to fall and crash these
have been used in
iraq and afghanistan and the technology
uh could be certainly used
but we really haven't seen it used more
frequently do you want to tell you about
it because
oh my god drone killers
all right last place to look for for
police technology
in the environment around you uh
there will be in many places camera
networks
so a lot of the cameras that you'll see
in a neighborhood will have will be
private cameras
uh will be police cameras will be
cameras being used by city uh non-police
agencies
there can be a lot of cameras this also
means that you're trying to observe what
cameras are going on there's gonna be
like too much information there'll be
so many cameras in many areas that you
can spend all your time documenting and
observing the cameras and just other
things
so you might not want to spend like all
your time paying attention to that
uh because you can go back later at any
point and see the fixed cameras
but there are a couple of things that uh
so first identifying them there are too
many different brands to identify but
here's some information about the kinds
of cameras that are available
uh bullet cameras are directional so you
could sort of see which way it's
pointing
and what it would be covering from that
uh then you have dome cameras
which are designed so you can't see
which way it's pointing or at least you
can see maybe somewhere in this
this area 180 degrees but uh the exact
direction is pointing is
obscured by the dome um
pan tilt zoom cameras uh can change
which way they're pointing
they can sometimes be coupled with a
dome camera so that the dome camera
can both change the way it's looking and
obscure which way it's looking
uh thermal imaging cameras
and aopr cameras are also going to be
common at fixed locations
uh lpr a lot having to do with the
traffic control
thermal is actually not as common uh
that is mostly used
as a uh technology that
is uh vehicles uh it's kind of expensive
uh but in this case the uh the picture
shown
is a uh thermal imaging camera so
sometimes people will go to that
additional expense
and one subcategory of all the cameras
that are in the environment
are going to be police observation
devices this is so the category of
sets of sensors which are operated by
the police and
they may include multiple cameras uh
gunshot detection
uh facial recognition uh for example
in the united kingdom said the city of
london is doing live facial recognition
uh so police observation devices are
sort of a collection of these
cameras in one location sometimes
they're marked as police
uh sometimes they are are not um
and it is the way you would sort of
suspect that it's a police observation
device is if it has a lot of different
sensors in one location trying to cover
the whole ground around
then that is the kind of thing that you
would see most frequently from a police
observation
uh and then finally smart street lights
now smart street lights
uh are have a number of wonderful app
applications
uh some initiatives like in the us smart
cities and the eu the e street
initiative
are imploring cities to use smart street
lights because they can
turn down the power usage uh when light
is less needed
uh and there are some some advanced ones
a a project by the art hall
university of applied sciences uh has a
technology which will
use motion detection sound detection
being able to
tell if there are people walking nearby
and brighten their path for them
sounds great but the same kinds of
technology being able to detect motion
being able to have audio signals video
signals
can be used for surveillance so here on
the slide we show
uh the smart lighting capabilities being
advertised by intel
uh in addition to some things that you
might
expect like being able to adjust it for
traffic patterns provide better lights
they talk about other things crime
investigations
monitor parking violations uh safety
announcements that are coming from the
smart cameras
so all of these technologies are are
possible
and hopefully this will not become a
commonplace use
but if it is it would mean that a
surveillance device is
everywhere along every street where
they're putting these devices in
uh if you blank in a city you're
flagging a city with surveillance
so has it been used yes the city of san
diego
uh had a number of protests uh
surrounding the uh george floyd
uh and they used at least 35 times
they searched the information gathered
through the smart streetlight network
for uh evidence in criminal cases coming
out of that protest
so what additional resources are there
there's plenty of additional resources
if you wanted to drive it more and i
encourage you
to take this only as a starting point
there's a lot more to learn
so we'll start out with a very important
resource if you're someone who's going
to go whether
uh as an activist as a protester as a
journalist
you should prepare yourself uh for some
surveillance
self-defense ssd.effork.org
we have attending a protest guide you
can go there
and learn important tips on protecting
yourself
when you're going to the protest um you
put your device with full disk
encryption a strong unique password
turning off the biometric unlock use nbn
encryption for messages and calls
walking or taking a bicycle to get to
the protest
instead of a vehicle which can be
subject to an alpr a npr
device uh you know wear a mask you
should wear masks for covet anyway
but if you're gonna wear a mask get a
big
the larger the mask the more it protects
you uh there's also recently a study
that uh showed that
um they're making efforts to try and
make
uh facial briquette recognition continue
on despite people's uses of masks
uh and there was a study that showed
that red and black masks were
harder for the ai to be able to
determine who was behind the mask so
wear a red or black mask uh if you get
one that covers more of your face like a
bandanna
it's going to be harder for the facial
recognition so do some things to protect
yourself
both from covered and from surveillance
uh if you want also just to try and
practice it out uh you can go to our
uh spot the surveillance uh this is a
online program you can use a desktop
version or virtual reality version
where it places you in a virtual street
corner
with some surveillance devices nearby
and you can look around and try to
identify
all the surveillance devices that you
see takes just a few minutes to go
through the exercise
but it's a good way to practice your
skills and identify
what surveillance might be around on the
street
and if you want to get a lot more
information about
any of these devices go to eff's
street level surveillance project
eff.org street level surveillance
this will provide more detailed
information about various technologies
that
are in use that can be a good starting
point
especially if you have found out what is
being used in your jurisdiction
uh you can go there and find out more
about it uh and you can also find out
just what is going on
more generally with these kinds of
technologies so eff.org
sls all right well thank you that comes
to the close of my talk
uh thank you for tuning in and now uh
let me
turn it over to my future self for q a
thank you
welcome back thanks
thanks so much card well
we have some time for questions and it's
getting more and more
i'm just hurrying up okay are there
devices
apps or services developed or run by
private companies and who makes sure the
data is not directly sold to third
parties
so yes there are uh private networks i
mean one of the things we talked about
uh just now is there's a lot of private
camera networks
that are providing information to the
police sometimes private networks
uh go into registry where police from
organize ask people to volunteer put
their information
into a registry so they are sort of
explicitly saying they're going to turn
over their information to the police
other things like amazon's ring camera
they have been promoting it as a
anti-theft tool
trying to stop packaging people's doors
but this also is creating a
you know panopticon of everyone's
doorbell camera
if they're all using ring will be uh
provided
uh get the video and we'll provide it to
the police so uh
and many of these uh organizations you
know if they're a larger one they will
have some some privacy practices
probably
policies but by and large they will talk
about
the privacy of the person who owns the
the case
and not really consider the bystanders
the people walking by
so if you have a doorbell camera at your
front door they can
hear uh audio so maybe someone can ring
your bell and say hello
it will also capture people walking by
and those people's privacy is important
and should be considered
all right
then we have what help do we have
against all this
which best case legal countermeasures do
we have when attending protests
and another one which i would connect
directly is it possible to intervene
against surveillance based on laws or
presumption of innocence
yeah i don't know if if that's if german
laws are meant but
maybe you still can say something well i
mean so there's many different laws that
might be at issue i mean we have an
international audience here
um but uh i think there are some there's
also basic human rights principles that
apply
to many uh jurisdictions but i would say
actually one of the most effective tools
to push back against this kind of police
surveillance
is working locally with the like a city
the mayor the
city council in a number of locations
have passed rules about what
their police can do against their
citizens so putting limitations on what
police can do
at the local level where your activism
in the city which you live taking things
to your representative government
uh and saying we need to have some
limitations on this we need to have it
within civilian control so the police
themselves are not deciding what
technologies to use
but it has to pass through an elected
representative and i think that is
probably
one of the most effective ways to at
least start change
where you live uh but you can also try
and promote that to
uh you know national legislature state
legislatures go up uh uh
up several levels and one of the things
that we hope comes
out of this guide video people getting
more information about what kind of
surveillance is available
is so that they can go to their
representatives go through the political
process
with the information of what tools use
ah i saw used by
a drone flying above go to your
representative and say
we need to make sure that that the
information that they're gathered
is being used in a manner consistent
with human rights principles
and we need civilian control from the
local government
on how to do who is controlling the
controller instances
yes yeah okay we have more questions
ah okay
so the police operate equipment like
ampr reader ms catchers etc that
get information that they could get in a
cheaper way
like reading traffic signs or license
plates
or sell info from operators
is there a reason for that especially
concerning eu because u.s differs a lot
and another question have has police in
eu
us been known to use illegal or
questionable tax for surveillance
so i think i'll hurt the first question
about you know using things like ampr to
determine
uh license plates uh this technology is
common in the uh
european union uh though by and large it
is being put in place for
other reasons not not to get after
protesters necessarily
they are looking for uh you know
making sure that people are paying a
toll or might be a speed trap on the
autobahn where it
uh takes a picture of the license plate
of anyone traveling
uh over a speed limit uh in the places
that have speed limits
only part of the automotive uh and i
think
also it's being used for enforcement of
things like uh
traffic citations your your car is
parked in a location too long
they know who to send the bill to uh
and i think these technologies could be
repurposed for
for sale surveillance and that's what we
really need is
policies that are ensuring that if these
things are being used for
a purpose that the sort of the
citizenship agrees with in that
jurisdiction to enforce parking for
example
uh that is not also being repurposed uh
against uh political activities and
being
used at a wider scale than it was
envisioned
also maybe you know it's it's not a good
thing to have perfect parking
enforcement
uh you know a lot of parking fines were
based on the notion that like
you might not get caught every time and
when you change it where
a system where previously uh the fines
were set with the notion that a lot of
people would get away with it you had to
like make an example of those who didn't
and then you change that to perfect
enforcement because the computer the
ampr
system surveillance knows exactly the
minute that that
a fine is due and then assesses that
fine that actually changes the dynamic
of power between the citizenship and the
state significantly
and it will often be phrased in forms of
well we're just trying to enforce the
existing laws
how would you be against that but really
it changes the dynamic and it's
something that
uh for those who want to be an activist
on this again talk to your local
jurisdiction and try and make sure that
these things have safe and sane policies
that respect human rights so i would
interpret that
like prevention of um
don't don't come into the idea that you
need to to protect your data right
yeah and then uh just turning to the
other one you know do we do we have
information about whether
uh police are misusing these
technologies
so i mean there's some isolated examples
uh where
uh people have misused their
technologies and i used a couple of them
in the slide so there was
someone who went to a political protest
their car was put into a database they
got pulled over later
uh and then also in
south wales the court found that their
the police use of facial recognition
was in violation of uh uk law
uh though as i noted uh not you know the
metropolitan police in london don't
agree with that they say it doesn't
apply to them and i think actually use
of facial recognition technologies
um is a very tempting thing by the
police they want to use it as much as
possible makes it
you know easy for them uh and i think
you will you'll see that
but the other piece of this is unless
there are rules that say
here are limitations on how you can use
these technologies then they can use
them without having to risk
violating them so we need to have those
rules in place i hope that
the council of europe uh puts a at least
a moratorium on facial recognition for
use for police
and you know until we can figure out how
to use this technology
safely like it's kind of cool that you
can unlock your phone or your face
without having to type in a password but
we want to make sure that technology is
used properly okay
so i think you're going to be around in
the 2d world you're going to explore
that you told me before
yeah there's more questions i hope
maybe maybe you find him in the 2d world
and you're just asking there
thanks so much thanks so much everybody
nice having you bye card
[Music]
bye
wow
you