[Music]
[Applause]
looks at congress our life translated
between english and german
and to one additional language we
appreciate your feedback
please use the hashtag c3t new
translators for this talk
are red on toast and os ten thousands
um
[Music]
from last year
and how it was built in three days we
are in vulnerable
things just continue and then
the robert institute said
the danger of this thing coming to us is
low
the problem with corona is not the
mortality
we have 30 000 deaths in germany which
is dramatic but
alcohol and smoking are more dangerous
we wanted to flatten the curve and we
saw it in
bergamo and
our hospitals were overtaxed
and this is why we have to flatten the
curve and this only works with a
shutdown
so we have to pivot our whole um
social and and health system
and the problem with corona is we don't
see it
and i don't see being infected and i
don't know any
corona deaths and when the human can't
see it
and then they don't uh observe it
they don't acknowledge it there's
plenty of small particles that um that
can do something
so now he's talking about um
carbon dioxide and he said if if it's
pink
then we would actually see it we would
we would feel it some carbon dioxide is
invisible and we don't really see
anything
but we can observe that carbon dioxide
generates
changes
already pivoted to the two neighboring
planets
mars
has more than 400 degrees because of co2
yeah with carbon dioxide you can
you can tilt a system
into a different state so
i advise those people go to venus and
have a look at the 400 degrees and then
you have some sense of what carbon
dioxide can do
so if we had
multiple percentages then
it would be impossible to live here but
we're here in parts per million
and
we have pushed it to something that has
not been seen for 300 million years
so this is not that much less than the
venus but we don't need 400 degrees
to change it to a few degrees the small
changes will be enough
and this is what we see is the
temperatures over the last 20 000 years
so since the last ice age
now on the right side we are now in a
warm period
the ice ice h ended about 10
000 years ago so if we look from
minus 20 000 to minus
five thousand years ago there's around
four degrees celsius
plus and if we look now in the
present there's this uh rapid increase
in the last hundred years this is about
one degree celsius equivalent to a
quarter of an ice
age to a warm period it's a very strong
increase in strong change fast change
so in comparison the um
the progress from the ice ice ice age to
the one period took about 10 000 years
but we have done this
in the in the very recent past
so we haven't seen this for a very long
time
of history the one degree
plus we can see pretty easily because we
have
appeared the northern arctic area
lower part is canada right as
it's russia and we compare us from the
70s to
today and we see a radical decline
in sea ice
we assume that in the middle of the
century we'll have an ice-free novel
but we also need to have uh
think about what will happen when the um
when the land ice is
uh melting so for instance green uh
greenland
there will be a large changes
we also see a lot of more fires for
instance
australia this year and siberia
so areas where you don't expect
a lot of white fires appearing or
california
so due to the changes in
participation through the
climate change we see the drastic
changes
this is the german forest we also have
here
lots of differences and changes to the
precipitation and rain have
basically the big uh dieback of
foresters here in germany
and this is just due to one degree plus
also there's a lot of dry
dryness here in germany so we have a
problem
of bringing up the resources for the
river rhine as you can see here
and climate change already produces
a lot of millions euro and euros
of damage to the economy and this is
just
one degree plus which from which we know
it's already there
and our models
predict as the business as usual to
to have an increase at the end of the
century of about four degrees celsius
so if in the in the next hundred years
temperatures will go up in the same way
they done before
we will have a change as if we coming
from an
ice age to a long period and um
for comparison in the ice age germany is
covered with 400 meters
ice so the planet will change
from ice time ice age to um
to the present warm period very rapidly
very much and that this will happen very
rapidly
and we are in a really big concern about
that
so what would be the worst case of um
sea level rise it would be about three
meters
and um yeah miami already has problems
but there will be vast areas which gonna
be
underwater so a lot of 100 million
persons there are people so um
there will be a lot of migration from
this areas
to the uh to other parts of the world
so in a moment it's not that much but
the
development will increase
the fasten up
we also see that participation
has changed it's not raining here
anymore but
at the other place of the earth it
started raining
much more and therefore water
distribution is not
uh not very good right now so
lots of areas in africa will have
dryness all year round
if there's no uh no rain then
we'll also have problems with food
product
food production so we've seen this in
germany
two years ago
it actually came to me the first time
as a real thing two years ago i'm living
in in the eastern of germany
and two years ago
people told me uh two uh people told me
during the german democratic republic we
would have now a real problem
you know about climate change
because i heard in the news we had 30
degrees
30 uh reduction of food production and
in the german democratic republic back
then
we couldn't have managed this
no the climate change isn't coming it's
already here
so in comparison if we're living in the
middle ages
we would have real famine here in
germany right now
it would be one of the greatest famines
here in
europe ever but today we have the
possibility to just buy the crops from
anywhere else
and people are starving another part of
the world
this is another study from colleagues of
mine
three years ago they done this and they
calculated for the worst case
45 degree celsius plus what will happen
to the to the
area where people live so the red areas
in this map
will be that hot that people shouldn't
be
outside for longer periods of time or
during the day because they might
actually die
so and you see that these are vast
amounts of land
for instance nearly all of brazil but
also
indonesia parts of africa so about one
to
one billion people would be um
would have to stay in the cellar during
the day
which would also lead to a lot of
migration
we wouldn't have a situation like on
venus where
so planet won't just start burning and
ignite
but um vast areas of land would be
inhabitable
one of the biggest or even the
biggest ever migration of humans on the
planet
and if we if you look at what europe is
doing with 20 000
refugees in greece so we
we assume that it will be a catastrophe
when billions of people are start
migrating
and we need to be concerned that maybe a
civilization
will destroy itself due to this so
we have to really um act
now to get uh to get this under control
in comparison to corona climate crisis
is a
complete over our order of magnitude
we have to act now we're always talking
about the end of the century this is a
bit difficult
because if my generation is start
calculating
and well it's not it's not
um our concern but the young generation
which is born 2010
or even now in 2020
the young generation will have to deal
with this catastrophe
at this full extent and so therefore in
the last years we saw
the fridays for future movement and
people are telling so young people tell
us in
school there's climate change and we
need to do something about it but
in real life see that there's nothing
done about it
so they have been going on the street
because we have to act now
so for in comparison to the corona
crisis
where there are also tipping points
we saw that it might be a period of time
where you can manage to
adapt to the situation but at some
points there are tipping points where
you can't
so we assume this is 1.5 degrees celsius
plus
and this might be a good comparison
might be bergamo in italy in
uh in march where at the at some point
the system
just tipped and they had chaos in the
streets
this actually has managed to um
to get to the politicians and we have
the paris
agreement where we agreed on
reduce climate change to about two
degrees celsius
and possibly less and
we have hope because uh us president has
um elected ps president has announced to
get back into the agreement and um
but now we have to look and how fast we
need to get active
um when should we
act when we don't wanna get over 1.5
degrees
we'll have just less than 400 gigatons
of cn2s
and in perspective we already emitted 2
300 trigger tones so what's the rest
budget
it's not that much anymore
so if the co2 emissions go down linearly
until
then 2040. then they must be at zero
um in order to not uh pass this boundary
and we see this doesn't look good this
is
faster than this at the moment at the
moment this is going down through
corona
but we expect that uh it'll go up again
after
there's no ambition from our politicians
to
accelerate this decrease
for the first few years are part of the
reunification of germany because um
the eastern industry has broken down
and then we've only had a decrease after
2000 and that's
so our plan is 40 through 2020
and unfortunately we will meet this one
this uh
takes the pressure off the government
but we expect that it'll go up again
the targets are not enough
if we really wanted to achieve our goals
then we would have
been down into that green zone
so with what we're currently committed
to we're going for
two degrees celsius
with our targets we cannot comply with
the
paris accord
production and the next 10 15 minutes i
would like to
describe this so here you see the
energy consumption
here you see the various renewables
biomass watercraft windcraft
voltaics doesn't look so bad
so here's the same diagram again but um
because we have other areas as well
so we have um heating
we have travel here
together
within 20 years to 100 renewables
i'm working here in engineering sciences
this is what it looks like many people
so whether we use those or not um
doesn't really make it
any difference we need
if you if you exchange your gas heater
with a
heat pump then you
then you will have lots of um
new energy reduction of fossil energy
if you think about it we don't even have
gas but uh german government is not
[Music]
doing this is not enforcing this now
example
traffic we need to have a different um
different behavior with regards to
traffic so people
uh germany has about 80 million um
inhabitants if we would translate this
to the whole world
we wouldn't need to build 30
billion 30 million more cars
so if we should if you would
like to
to bring our behavior to the whole world
we need to have a completely different
way of using traffic so
traffic is a much more difficult problem
when
um when heating because uh we are using
fossil fuels and
uh using them with just an efficiency of
20 to 30
percent
public transportation with trams
but if you want to have
private transportation it needs to be
electric because
electric cars have a um have an
energy efficiency of a factor free above
fossil fuels so we need to reduce the
energy consumption
this energy so here we see a typical
combustion engine will need about six
liters of petrol
and they'll get with one kilowatt hour
about 1.8
kilometers so we have the problem that
hydrogen is a bit
inefficient in um in production
and electric car would be a
bit more efficient than the combustion
engine
so on and all over um including
the production costs uh hydrogen car
won't get further than a combustion
engine conventional combustion engine
but if we would have a battery powered
electrical car
we wouldn't have that much of loss due
to the
hydrogen production and we would get two
and a half times the
the range from the um hydrogen car and
that's the key
so we need to get down with our energy
consumption and we can this done
by um by
forbidding fossil heating and
using electric cars if you don't use
this
few points very efficiently we could
reach the um reach our goal of the paris
agreement
actually if we enforce it now
and then the rest would have to be
covered
climate neutral this is the pathway
german government is enforcing right now
and we
plan about increasing renewable energies
a little bit
and doing this mainly by wind energy
and this is the current planning which
is not
nearly enough so there
you see there is no vision the
government brings here
to increase the energy change in germany
to renewables there is you have to admit
this
so there's a big question mark because
we have no plan how to reduce the energy
consumption right now
so we see we have
about a quarter of the speed we need to
get um our economy to climate neutrality
right now so okay
what can you do us you could uh you
could
use a solar thermic energy for heating
but this is not that much we can do with
this we could use
water power this year is norway but we
don't have this kind of environment here
in germany a little bit in southern
germany but that's not enough
so the really really most important
energy forms you can use in germany is
wind and solar and we have to increase
renewable energies then we would have to
use have an increase of three gigawatt
hours
per year on show offshore and seven
gigawatt
gigawatts per year uh onshore
the first thing we can do is to do this
offshore
people say if there's not going to
happen in the northern city we do it on
the east
in the baltic sea but this is baltic sea
it's much smaller
first thing we need to act on is using
all the places in our northern cv camp
so we need to reach about 8 000
wind mills in the northern sea and then
we need
to have a bit much much more onshore
we need to have about 70 um
67 000 wind windmills onshore
this would be nice we see it right
we see it right now the development
and the reds are new windmills
uh yellow these are repowering old
windmills
and blue is what we actually install
near offshore before
showed what we need and this is what
uh what is happening due to new
regulations a few years ago
so uh new windmills basically
aren't uh constructed anymore
uh changed a bit of the legislation but
this
wouldn't be nearly enough yeah so
and still we see if we build
a lot of lot of windmills all we can
then there is
still a gap in the energy production and
therefore we'll need solar energy
solar energy we need 18 gigawatts more
per year
and right now we built about four
gigawatts more this year last year
so we need to have a significant amount
in percentage
of our land area and if we
look for for example berlin berlin not
is not even using one percent of a roof
area
for solar energy that has to happen a
lot and
there needs to change a lot and also we
need to go on
the um on the farmland
because there is a lot of space for
photovoltaic panels for instance
in this way which can be used
[Music]
so we have about 180 000 square
kilometers of
uh agra area so
people say without solar panels they
were nicer but
uh we have to die and any death anyway
so what we also need is uh storage
because if there solar sun and there's
no wind
then we still need energy so
i think we will have
decentralized battery storages
for instance for cars
and for a longer periods of time
for instance what we have produced
in summer with sun energy we would
use something like power to gas where we
use water and
co2 to produce methane gas
methanol a methane gas and store
this in conventional storage facilities
using them in the winter to produce
electricity and
heat we calculated this also from an
economic
point of view and this is possible and
this for example
is the biggest energy storage place in
germany
it's the gas storage facility reading
the gas is stored under under the earth
and we can store the 4.4
billion cubic meters of gas
we have we have dozens of them so the
problem of
uh storage is is already solved
and and so switch to renewable energies
the economic feasible it's not that
expensive if it used the amount of money
we used for corona
then germany would be climber neutral
overnight
germany can do this actually for a
crisis like corona but
it seems strange that it's not doing
this
for energy change
which means we need a radical new policy
on climate change
and then we also but we also need to
change personally
and the big problem is that it hasn't
reached the people
how how difficult and how catastrophic
the climate crisis
there's a survey on what people think
can reduce
to uh have their uh have their carbon
footprint
to reduce a lot of people think they
wouldn't use
plastic bags but in fact this is not
something where you really reduce your
carbon footprint a lot
but um it's just for three kilograms of
co2 per year
but we produce 10 000 kilograms of
per person per year so for instance
we could do two beef steaks per week
which germans are using
consuming would be 300 kilograms of co2
per year
so we have to go for the meat
consumption
because just the meat con meat
production produces 10 percent of
the co2 and contributes to climate
change
also one uh one air travel
that produces four tons of co2 and these
are the big fish
okay sure we see with corona
we can do with dig with digital
technology a lot of without travel
driving cars per person is 1.5
tons co2 per per year
which is three times as much as people
in bangladesh
also german german home produces about
four times that much of co2 as
uh people in india
an energy car you would also reduce your
emissions by one ton per year a
photovoltaic
installation would uh would be
sufficient
and you don't need your own home you can
use your balcony
so actually there are ways we can do it
if we want to
really important is that the government
is making the policies we need
because people actually need to be
forced to the solution sometimes so we
need
the politicians next year here in
germany there will be general elections
and it's important that it would be a
big
point in the election decision how is
that stand to climate change
i think a good example for how we can
manage to do big things is um john f
kennedy said
we chose to go to the moon in 1962.
give an example this time we used a
punch card computers
so this was a really really big
challenge
back then because you have to hit the
moon people said
this will cost money it's really
really difficult but people's government
said
yes we pay this we do this and um
we pay what has has to be paid to reach
the moon
the us alone paid um three billion
dollars to reach the moon
if we would do the same for the future
of our
of our species of humans then we
we have a solution we should uh
we should make climate change to our new
man on the moon challenge
we shouldn't wait now we have to act
so with this thanks for your attention
here are a few links
where you can see all this uh
compact information i give you in a bit
more extensive way for instance on my
website on my youtube channel
and uh from three years from
for three months now there's a podcast
from uh with me
so thanks for your attention and um i
hope
that there's a bit of time to discuss
this topic
this was a lot of information
so if this is actually so important why
isn't it
so we see there are two points
um for instance there is the uh thing
like
with corona the people who think it's
all uh
all crazy and lies they're also the
people who deny climate change
and um this is this is a problem
for instance with the rfd here in
germany
if you tell the people you don't have to
uh to decrease your consumption
then people will vote for them and so
the big parties like cdu spd
people will actually vote for these
people
so and therefore you see that in terms
of renewable energies
cdu campaigns are pretty much the same
as
uh with rfd of deep campaign
so right populists here in germany but
also
familiar with it so
what can so people are asking how to use
combustion engines
with climate change no there is no way
for this
so also for uh for the car manufacturers
this is a problem because
um
a few years ago this was a good thing
because it's
brought them a bit a step forward and
they now have electric cars
but also there is the things like um
energy uh companies
and uh energy companies have long
running contracts
to use fossil fuels and if they break
these contracts then
it's a problem for them
and of course it's also nice to travel
by airplane to
holiday
last year 2019.
we're traveling by an airplane 97
but if in germany we say that um flying
away and
into holiday is not an option anymore
then that is a threat to
the elections still
okay i understand
the political aspect
you mentioned briefly nuclear energy
it's clean when we don't have a problem
but we've seen that
problems
[Music]
but you still have an incredibly long
legacy let's
ignore the risk let's just say
let's say we we manage the risk and the
long term
but everything is against it anyway
nuclear energy
covers three to four percent size
we would have to build hundreds of new
nuclear facilities in europe
it
then we'll use up all the uranium
and then we have to look for other stuff
we have to start hoping for fusion which
we will never know where that works
keep them running and then i can
continue to fly to my vacations
of society so that people might get an
awareness
the last year has helped a lot to create
we've been doing it longer for the last
20 years
two or three years ago we said that
we say go left and then the government
goes to all right
is
there's a lot happening for instance in
australia australia is the biggest
export of coal but
due to the big wildfires there's a
change of mind
also in other countries there is
moves to um to act on climate change
so but we are also
because um also we in the climate
movement
we produce co2 and lots of co2
and may i shortly interrupt we have a
lot of questions here
just a little bit because this is very
interesting
and there are lots of questions
questions uh we would like to
over overdue our time
so just a few sentences
me if is that the technology can we do
can we do it i would say
yes second question can we pay for it
and if i look on corona i would say yes
definitely
so we can say two times yes and
if you ask are we ready for it i'd sadly
say no
but this is a psychological problem and
a political problem but
if he can solve this if he can solve
this
i don't know but um
for instance if there is a asteroid on
collision course to earth
we wouldn't say no there is no solution
we would say yeah we can find a solution
so i interrupt again
technical questions how is it about
sustainability of solar
solar energy panels
so how long are they um how long can
they be used or
how what's about uh recycling of them so
yes of course every technology has a
footprint
and also renewable energies has a have a
renewable
footprint this is not zeros but it's uh
ten times smaller than fossil fuels and
conventional energy
and you have to think about this you
have to try to get it under control
silicon is a is a resource also
our materials are really resources for
instance for wind energy
copper and steel
the rotors are from cfk they
have recycling problems you also can of
course can recycle the
the steel from the tower so
if you compare it cars can't be recycled
fully
so this is a problem
and resources what's about the batteries
what's about the lifetime
um what's about their recyclings are
there provinces being made
yes definitely in terms of batteries we
are in the stone age
stone age so you could for instance use
solid state batteries which have
factor of 10 better energy efficiency
and in 10 years i think about today's
battery technology
would just love and
i think the prices will go down but
batteries will
become better and uh because of this
i think we will see a dynamic
development
and it is a good thing that we discussed
this
in comparison to the combustion engine
you can relativize
this but for instance there are
cobalt-free batteries in the development
so we'll have a lot of progress
another topic which wasn't uh discussed
so far
what about geothermal energy
yes right geothermal energy is really
interesting for instance eastland or um
turkey but here in germany the
geothermal energy is very very deep in
the earth
we have to deep we have to dig for three
to four kilometers
and one kilometer costs about a million
euros so this is very expensive so
therefore
uh geothermal energy can be used in
germany
but uh it's much more expensive than the
other forms of renewable
energies but you can use it for instance
in the rhine area
in bavaria but a lot of places in
germany it's not
not a good idea not feasible
how about co2 emissions you spoke about
um is the reduction real or is it just
that we exported our footprint to a
chimera for example
yes in parts
for instance if we close steel steel
production
uh plenty in germany and export it to
china then
our emissions go down and there's a
small
part in the reduction from this but
there are no real
numbers on this on that
i think that the decrease in emission
is actually real because we see their
power
coal plants which are turned off
and yes energy change
cause decrease in emissions but
also other factors play in but these
factors are just the smaller
smaller part
another question what's uh black
roads due to the um to the absorption of
energy from sunlight
on earth yeah of course
if i also was doing this on solar models
yes if you build solar modules it
depends on where you build them
if you put them on a roof then there are
black
then the roof already is black so it's
already
already absorbs a lot of energy so there
won't be a difference
but if you put them for instance in the
sand desert then it's
becoming a bit darker obviously
parts of that energy is absorbed is also
converted
to electrical energy so yes there's an
impact on the um on the balance of the
energy balance of the earth
but uh it's it's small so but
if you for instance look at germany uh
of uh lands uh land area is um
is human-made
so um in comparison to
our other infrastructure impact from
renewable energies on the energy balance
would be
neglectable
you know so what what about solar
roadways
yes they tried this
but i don't know if it's a good idea
because there is oppression
from the tires on the street and um
yes it's it's very
very difficult to do and it needs to
resist heavy loads so don't think that's
a real solution
so how about recycling of solar modules
so a counter argument would be um
it can't be recycled so um yes
solar modules can actually be recycled
they are milled down to very
small parts and then the essential
resources
like a silicon aluminium silver can be
recovered some parts
can't be recovered like like plastics
but the rest is really good in recycling
how can you prevent uh politicians from
uh pushing the solution to the future
like 2030 2040
2050 what can we actually do
yeah therefore actually fridays for
future help a lot
um so govern the government set the
deadline to 2030 2030 is not that
much away so it's about 10 years so we
actually will see very fast
if we are actually on track so still
germany needs to improve policies but
um actually we will see fast what's
happening
this pushing to the future won't be
working anymore for instance also for
the european union there's legislation
um which says 2030 we need to be climate
neutral
and now we have to ask the question
what's happening very
very frequently so
for instance just go to your member of
parliament
yes for instance go to your local
local member of parliaments ask them
if you want to have my vote next year
what are you doing
on climate change how do you
how do you want to achieve the european
union's goals
for climate change in 2030 of course
then a lot of times
you'll get a lot of warm words
just ask so from now we have
three quarters of a year to the general
election in germany
um we need to be um
we need to ask them and push them so
thank you for your talk
thanks for the invitation and have a lot
of fun for the rest of the
[Music]
conference
wow
bye