[Music]
[Applause]
translation of patents killed
live from the rcp hi
my name is
[Music]
i work as a consultant for global health
at the frankfurt ngo medical
international
and i will be talking about how politics
and pharma companies prevent fair access
to covet
vaccinations let me
quickly talk about medical international
medical was founded in 1968
in frankfurt with the aim to provide
medical emergency services
and aid during catastrophes and you can
see some pictures already
in the mid 1970s medical shifts
its focus onto politics going away from
exporting drugs and putting a spot
to how drug pricing works
and the role the pharma industry plays
in that process
since then medical advocates for
changing unhealthy living situations
and today supports project partners in
more than 40 countries
worldwide
sporting effort replaced by long-term
support of local project partners
supported by campaign efforts that
initially were very critical of the
pharma industry unless we arrived at the
topic of this talk
nairobi
on the first picture you can see
ethiopian workers that work
as domestic workers in nairobi and
who have been sitting on the streets or
living on the street since the major
explosion and waiting for the return
home
all the while being very exposed to the
virus
you can see an impression of
nairobi slum the kenyan
capital many there
are this is also a picture from nairobi
r2.2
get good quality masks
this is an image from moria the refugee
camp on the greek islands
on lesbos
not just since the fire they were
very exposed to the virus because the
health care provided isn't sufficient
and they definitely won't be among the
first to receive the vaccination
this last image shows the palestinian
refugee camp in beirut
no one is saved from covet 19 until
everyone is safe from it this is an
insight that we probably all share
including german federal president
steinmeier
who emphasized it during his speech
before the world health organization wha
even anyone who defeats covet within
their own national borders
will be jailed within them if it's not
defeated everywhere
the newly appointed eu council president
also says that the vaccination is our
universal property like
and stresses the universal right to
health
that means the deliverance from the
virus necessitates a global effort
and no one will honestly oppose that
there's just one
already secured more than half of the
vaccine that had yet to be produced the
rich
nations have already reserved
more than 5 billion doses of the
successful vaccine candidates
while only a small percentage of them is
available for the poorer countries
you can see this here if you take a look
at the map
if you look at europe
you see europe and the usa and other
industrial nations
they will be among the first to have
access to the vaccine
yeah now continues
and the poorest countries many among
them
from africa will probably among the last
to gain
access
if you look at the policy making
decisions
quickly becomes obvious that the
industrialized nations still stick to a
near liberal policy
that puts the right to profits
ahead of the human right especially the
fair access to the vaccine
that means this order of inequality is
being defended with all available force
which
you can take somewhat literally
this struggle for access to the upcoming
vaccines
shows you how the crisis is supposed to
be solved
i.e by taking advantage of the poor that
side effects will be deadly and will
lead to a sharp increase in
economical and social inequalities
and increase in poverty and certain
diseases
that cannot be treated sufficiently
anymore like hiv aids malaria and many
others
that means there will be a
divide in north and south even though
this
is supposed to be abolished if you
listen to
sunday's speeches there are no
there's no of alternatives a short while
ago the governments of
india and south africa have petitioned
so the world trade organization not the
who
or an exception to the trips agreement
agreement regulates or governs patents
and trade related aspects of
international property
the two governments argued
a comprehensive suspension of patent
regulations until the global population
has reached immunity
against the virus this
chips treaty which is still
controversial
it concluded in 95 at the initiative of
industrialized nations and international
companies
interestingly also pfizer which was one
of the manufacturers of the covet 19
vaccine
but there's also other companies that
are better known in the
world of chaos like ibm hp
and microsoft and
especially microsoft is important
because
for something that i want to explain
later
one of the companies with which the bill
and melinda gates foundation
generates its capital
which is also very important in the
realm of the
global health the explicit goal of the
trips agreement
was to um
to secure the patents against public
interests
the global concern that the global south
was
already uttering back then
provides
imports and thus bypassing patent
protection
the waiver that was proposed by south
africa in india
um
and it's clear that we have an
exceptional situation now
since it's obviously a global crisis
regarding
the help and then
[Music]
supply with affordable medical products
and that's
the production
that have the same ingredients but not
the same brand name
and are thus a lot cheaper than the
original
drugs
in the interest of um poorer countries
it's a great idea that the two countries
had
even the federal government so the
german government
we should be excited let me quote again
no one is safe from the virus until
everyone is safe
but it's not working at all the us the
eu
the
they all rejected the proposal outright
almost 100
has to agree or it has to decide on all
persons by a consensus
a few countries can just block the will
of the majority
there are 164 countries within that um
organization so 100 is actually
overwhelming
an interesting thing i want to note is
how the vaccine
was developed is
against this exception at the world
trade organization
that without the pharma industry there
will not be any development
of new vaccines but if you look at this
overview
you don't need to look at it in detail
it's enough to look at how much of
it is blue and yellow you can
see that the majority of the funds
for the vaccine development
given by the public or through
government funds
[Music]
but also alternative foundations like
garvey and the gates foundation
a much smaller percentage was provided
by the pharma industry itself
so the funds
here you can see the development of the
stock price
after the announcement of the
vaccination
so fair to uh
regarding the discussion at the world
trade organization
that the universal right to help
is um subordinated
this choice if you look at
the hiv and aids crisis of the
80s which is definitely
still happening today
more than half a million people um
die as a result of hiv and aids
as a result of the patent regulation
which the chips agreement is just an
example of
every price reduction of hiv and aids
medications
had to be wrangled from them by a global
fight for the
and tens of thousands had to die because
of the high
drug prices from eighth alone this is
the reason for the title
nevertheless this explanation
that there will not be scientific
research without the pharma industry
it's still stuck in the heads of many
even though it's just not true
the government
those are mostly public funds
[Music]
for the future vaccine in in public
interest
it should be obvious that
the prices at which the vaccines are
sold should be
public knowledge so
politics unfortunately i did not
learn from the experiences of the hiv
aids crisis
but they stuck to the logics which i
just
elaborated on
um
[Music]
for example say that incentives for
innovation are
provided by patents and
also the eu said
that
leads to inhibitions but
the negotiations at the wto
are still ongoing and
and accept the proposal by south africa
and india
as an intermediate conclusion we could
say
that the industrial nations governments
still are not ready to
work on their systems and adapt them
now um we're getting from the
wto to the who
with um support from the who
made a proposal at the very beginning of
the pandemic
knew about the danger of the patent
regime
towards a fair distribution of the
vaccine
so that is why
with costa rica's initiative they
founded a technology corporate 19
technology access
pool short c-tap
know-how data and software
and it's a very good approach to have
this knowledge open to everyone so that
everyone
can develop them further
this is not a revolutionary approach
because we've already
had it in in the hiv aids crisis with
very good results
it helped create processes
that made it possible for prices
for drugs for hiv and aids
to be made fairer
so how did this go on
mostly countries from the global south
only belgium the netherlands and
portugal
joined from the european countries
almost all the big pharmaceutical
industry
having countries didn't
[Music]
and also pharmaceutical companies
were quick to react pfizer for example
called the proposition that the proposal
dangerous and pointless
because instead it was suggested that
pharmaceutical companies could industry
make voluntary contributions
and almost all the pharmaceutical
companies
agreed to that
because they said it worked so well in
the aids
and hiv crisis
patterns impact how a
pandemic or an epidemic
this isn't revolutionary because it is
still
in the patent debate
still the industrial nations
chose a different path
they reacted differently to the crisis
it is clear then becomes it always
only becomes the clearer that they stick
to their old
principles and that they
actively prevent development
of course they have their own interests
they know that politically they will
have to find a way
and that is the internet why they do
exactly what has been so typical of the
industrial nations policies so far
public private partnerships
are the prime principle
that is applied here
there was an initiative called act
that was in the context of the kobach's
initiative where vaccination initiatives
work together with the who
and other organizations such as the bill
and melinda gates
foundation which in recent years
has become one of the most important
private funders of the who so i hope
that you
know um how this all works together but
we'll repeat it
again the trips agreement
that led to the crisis in life saving
medications
it led to a huge growth and process um
profits
and that money is now being used
to finance vaccinations
[Music]
uh
it's
to be eliminated
to provide funds
[Music]
that is clear but
it is not stressed enough that
vaccinations should be a
are still stuck in their role of
waiting for help that is provided
voluntarily and not
in a legal within a legal framework
we see and that patents
medication more expensive
and that is why we chose the slogan
patterns are expensive but unfair
and this unfairness it's not just about
the vaccine
here you can see a demonstration of
textile workers
in pakistan
from a pakistani union
and they have huge
economic difficulties because
they're deliveries
we're not
this is not just a question of vaccines
but also other capitalistic impacts on
production
are the impacts of the pandemic
this is a more optimistic picture
this is those are cuban
health workers who went to south africa
to support the local health in
health industry so the solution would be
essentially that we eliminate
patterns on vaccinations and medication
this is a
small film from our organization
describing the problem which i also just
described in
the talk
and the solution
that vaccinations must be public
property
and um it calls to sign our
petitions so let's get
to the conclusion
a global health policy can only
work if we apply humanitarian principles
if we globalize patents
who do the patents belong
[Music]
and just as well as he wouldn't patent
the sun
he wouldn't patent his vaccine and this
is how
polio was eliminated or almost
eliminated
so we need something else than the
models proposed by
the
as
adjust the prices for medication
so that innovations are made available
to anyone
and questioning this principle
only
the whole system and that isn't going to
happen on its own
so this is why we created a global
initiative
to make
[Music]
we are taking first
the prices for drugs and medications are
and
we can only hope that those who get the
vaccination
first will feel like um
we feel when we were clothing unfairly
produced
in the global south
i'm very grateful to have been able to
talk about this in this format in this
congress
thank you for the presentation
we have some questions from the internet
and i'll start right
develop
[Music]
so that they're affordable
this question about financing is
something that is posters a lot but
the assumption is that without obama
industry there
is not going to be any development or r
d
but in our point of view
this has been um calculated
[Music]
there are many organizations that stress
that it's definitely
they can be financed from the public
funds
with public money because we would save
so much money
in the long run and
already it's it's already true that many
of the funds come from public money
and you will get a good result if you
would just switch to financing where
it's all
public and we're we're not demanding to
um disappropriate the or disenfranchise
the
drug industry
they will definitely earn a lot of money
still from um the production and the
distribution of funds
but we also support a claim to um
cap drug prices thanks
if um governments are providing funds
shouldn't it be public good yeah
this is basically the gist of it or the
core of the question
at the moment we have the situation that
the risks are
being shouldered by the public by all of
us
where is the drug industry
and the profits are being privatized
the absurd thing about it is
that there are a lot of contracts
including
the german republic and the pharma
industry
and it they don't involve the final
price for the drug that is being
developed
the terms are not clear and they're not
being met
at the same time you can see a deficit
of democratic
um involvement here yeah another
um question that fits this
poor countries even have the possibility
to create those vaccine themselves
not automatically it's clear that
on the african continent where i'm
rather knowledgeable since
i'm responsible for that region within
my organization for many years
there is definitely a shortage of
production capacity
and definitely the production is very
complex
and you can't just tell a textile
manufacturing factory to
just switch over to drug production
and we would have to have started that
earlier but
it's definitely true that we also need
to think
longer term just even after covet
the problem doesn't go away but for
example in
many asian countries like india or
bangladesh
there are many factories that are
already producing drugs
for the west
but it's also true that this production
has been weakened by the
patent regulation regime and it would
already be
possible for many of the poorer
countries to produce the drugs that they
need
follow-up questions
how
[Music]
just for your example regarding the
corona vaccine
interesting
so look at the look at the news in
germany
it's already true that biontech is not
able to produce the vaccine as quickly
as would be needed right now
and it's already being considered to um
offshore that or to put to the
even in this new capitalist um or
neoliberals regime we're already
thinking about licensing and franchising
the recipe for the vaccine is
being passed on to them
this is a problem that threatens the
whole of humanity and that needs to be
solved
and now that it's there is a problem in
germany we're starting to think about
this even though we denied their
claims beforehand and
the core of the problem at the moment is
that there's a lack of political will
easy to get funding
that affects the industrialized world
but not for the the rest of the world
the next question how many companies
are part of their trips agreement and
how many profits did they make from that
not like it's just companies that
sponsored the trips agreement
with the wto are the ones that are
involved
the regulations extend to all companies
smaller companies that build a kind of
um
interest group
propel the protection of the ip
the pros for the companies
another comment from the chat somebody's
asking
if companies i think it's about
licensing
patents
wouldn't it also be a possibility
something about patents that's
definitely
a possible solution
actually the the same thing that the who
is
proposing they're not uh announcing
socialism
but they actually made a very wise um
proposal to get
the vaccine in the safest and quickest
way possible to all
people
it's also true that these these licenses
are not given out voluntarily
it just didn't happen at all
considering for example hiv and aids
medication
there's always some licensing fee that
has to be
paid to all the involved companies
and then it's produced somewhere
but else of the companies don't want
that
astrazeneca was doing it that's why
there's already a lot of vaccines that
are being produced in india
but the others are trying to oppose that
and
in the trips agreement but there's also
the possibility
to um declare a global emergency
or a global medical emergency with wh o
and then
there are certain public safety
regulations that your laws that you
could employ
for to have extra options
and if you take all that into account
made a very conscious decision to put
the profits of the company ahead of the
public safety
not just because of corona but generally
that have been afforded to the very
poorest of countries
in the past and they fought for that
over years
and they paid a very high price for that
you have to take that title literally
patents kill
many ten thousand probably hundreds of
thousands of people have died
because they didn't have access or
affordable access to necessary
medication
but the danger for this very poor
country is very real
for them it's just not possible to get
access to
corvona vaccination
[Music]
i mean what are they gonna do steal it
from the production line or uh
and then just distribute it but even
that wouldn't be possible really
if countries said
we need to produce drugs
it's just in the public interest and
critical to the
to the health of our populace
they were punished by
uh cancelling their development fund
for example this is a very ugly
[Music]
even on a more simple level
we could see that for example in mexico
when the government
tried to ban certain highly refined
sugars imported from the usa
because they had a spike in type 2
diabetes
and then the us employed the trade
agreement nafta
using that treaty the american sugar
industry
sued the mexican government
a risk to the public safety with the way
that these
treaties are set up there's always the
question of
human rights on the table when you do
these trade agreements
and the profits always get priority
so we're running out of time
unfortunately
but thank you again for this fascinating
presentation and for answering our
questions
there are some more questions
but unfortunately we don't have time
you can email me with the questions
actually
and we're also reachable on medico.org
and you can send us the
questions by mail and we'll be happy to
answer them
thank you
to the chat to those watching the
streams
go on the medical website and ask your
questions
now um on to the harold news show
have fun during the next few days see
[Music]
you
wow