[Music]
[Applause]
this is not anderson and he's
giving a talk to us today and the title
is
what priced the upload filter from cold
ward crypto wars and back again
and we're very happy that he's here
today um
and for our non-english speaking
pub public we have translations
these are talk but of deutsche
is
ready to start let's go have a good have
a good time
enjoy yes ready to go thanks
um okay um as
as the um as has been said
um i'm ross anderson and um i'm in
the position of being one of the old
guys of this field and that i've been
involved in the crypto wars right from
the start
and in fact even since uh before the
clipper chip actually came out
if we could go to the slides please
right can we see the slides
that had supplied the u.s armed forces
and
guess what happened well in the 1950s
boris hagelin had set up that company
secretly sold it to the nsa and for a
number of years
uh quite a lot of years um countries um
as
diverse as that latin america and india
and
even later countries such as italy were
buying machines from crypto again which
the nsa could decipher
and this had all sorts of consequences
for example it's
been revealed fairly recently that
britain's success against
argentina in the falklands war in 1982
was to a large extent due to signals
intelligence that came from these
machines
so um next slide please and
in this pre-history of the crypto wars
almost all the players between
governments
there was very little role for civil
society there was one or two
journalists who were engaged in trying
to map what the nsa and friends were up
to
as far as industry was concerned well at
that time i was working in banking
and we found that encryption for
confidentiality was discouraged
if we tried to use lining cryptos then
faults mysteriously appeared on the line
but authentication was okay we were
allowed to encrypt pin pad
thin blocks and we wrote a lot of boot
macs and messages
there was some minor harassment for
example when
uh revesh shamir and adelman come up
with their encryption
algorithm um the nsa tried to make it
classified but the provost of mit jerome
bison persuaded them
not to make that fight um the big debate
in the 1970s though was whether the nsa
affected the design of the data
encryption standard algorithm
and we know now that this was the case
it was designed to be only just strong
enough
and what if he predicted back in the
1970s that two to the power 56
key search would eventually be feasible
the eff built a machine in 1998
and now of course that's fairly easy
because each bitcoin block costs 2 to
the power 68 calculations
next slide please so where things get
interesting
is that the nsa persuaded bill clinton
in one of his first cabinet meetings in
1993 to introduce key escrow
the idea that the nsa should have a copy
of everybody's keys
and um one of the people at that meeting
um
admitted there so that president bruce
lee alder had been asked and had refused
but clinton when he got into office was
naive and thought this was an
opportunity to
fix the world now the clipper chip which
we can see here was tamper resistance
and had a secret block cipher and an nsa
backdoor key
and the launch product was an att secure
phone
next slide please now the clipper
protocol
was an interesting one in that each chip
had a
a unique secret key ku and a global
secret family key
knsa burned in and in order to say
send data to bob anas had to send her
clipper chip a working key kw
which is generated by some external
means such as the diffie-hellman key
exchange
and it made up a law enforcement access
field
which was basically alice and bob's
names
with the working key encrypted under the
unit key
and then a hash of the working key
encrypted under the nsa key
and that was sent along with the cypher
text to make authorized while tapping
easy
and the idea with the hatch is that this
would stop cheating
bob's clipper chip wouldn't use a
working key unless it came with a valid
leaf
and i can remember a few of us can still
remember
the enormous outcry that this cost at
the time
american companies in particular didn't
like it because they started losing
business to foreign firms and in fact a
couple of our students
here at cambridge started a company n
cipher that
grew to be quite large because they
could sell worldwide unlike u.s
firms people said why don't we use
encryption software well that's easy to
write but it's hard to deploy at scale
as phil zimmerman found with pgp and the
big concern was
whether a key escrow would kill
electronic commerce
a secondary concern was whether you know
how on earth would we know if government
designs are secure
why not should you trust the nsa
next slide please well
the first serious fight back in the
crypto wars came when matt blais of bell
labs
found an attack on clipper he found that
alice could just try lots of leafs until
one of them works
because the the the um the tag was only
16 bits long and it turned out that 2 to
the power 112
of the 2 to the power 128 possibilities
work
and this meant that alice could generate
a bogus leaf that would pass inspection
but which wouldn't decrypt the traffic
and bulk could also generate a new lease
on the fly so you could write
non-interoperable vlog applications that
the nsa had no access to
and with a bit more work you could make
wrong applications interoperate with
official ones
and this was only the first of many dumb
ideas
next slide please okay so why don't
people just use software
well at that time the us had export
controls on intangible goods such as
software or thought
european countries generally didn't and
this meant that u.s academics couldn't
put crypto code online
or thought we europeans couldn't we did
and so phil zimmerman achieved fame by
exporting
pgp pretty good privacy some encryption
software had written from america as a
paper book
and this was protected by the first
amendment they sent it across the border
to canada
they fed it into an optical character
recognition scanner
they recompiled it and the code had
escaped for this
phil was subjected to a grand jury
investigation
there was also the bernstein case around
coda's free speech
and bruce schneier rose to fame with his
book applied cryptography
which had protocols algorithms and
source code in c
which you could type in in order to get
cryptographic
algorithms anywhere and we saw export
controlled clothing
this t-shirt was something that many
people wore at the time i've actually
got one
and i plan to to wear it for this but
unfortunately i
came into the lab in order to get better
connectivity and i left it at home
so this this t-shirt has got an
implementation of rsa written in peril
plus a barcode so that you can scan it
in and in theory you should not walk
across the
border wearing this t-shirt or if you're
a u.s citizen you shouldn't even
let a non-u.s citizen look at it so by
these means
people probed the outskirts of what was
possible
and you know an awful lot of fun was had
it was uh
it was a good laugh to tweak the
tyrannosaurus tale
next slide but this wasn't just
something that was
limited to the usa
the big and obvious problem if you try
and
do kiasro in europe is that there's
dozens of countries in europe
and what happens if someone from britain
for example has got a mobile phone that
they bought in france with a german sim
card
and they're standing on the streets in
stockholm and they they phone somebody
who's in budapest who's got a hungarian
form of the spanish sim card in it
then which of these countries secret
police forces should be able to listen
to the call
and this was something that stalled the
progress of key escrow if that's a good
way to describe it in europe
and in 1996 gchq got
academic colleagues at royal holloway to
come up with a proposal for public
sector email
which they believe would fix list now at
the time
after clipper had fallen into distribute
the nsa's proposal
was that also certification authority
should have to be licensed
and that this would enforce a condition
that all private keys would be escrowed
so you would only be able to get a
signature on your
public key if the private key was was
held by the ca
and the idea is that you'd have one ca
for each government department
um and civilians would use trusted firms
like barclays bank or the post office
which would keep our keys safe
and it would also work across other eu
member states
so that somebody in britain calling
somebody in germany
would end up in a situation where a
trustworthy ca
from the nsa's point of view that is an
untrustworthy ca from our point of view
in britain would be prepared to make a
key and solid one in germany
this at least was the idea so how did
they do this
next slide on the gchq protocol
so here's how it was designed to work in
the uk government
if alice at the department of
agriculture wants to talk to bob at the
department of business
she asks her departmental security
officer d.a
for ascend key for herself and a receive
key for bob
and d a and d b get a top level of
interoperability key
k tab from gchq
and da calculates a secret send key of
the day
as a hash of key tab and alice's name
and um
the dso's identity for alice which she
goes to alice
and the similarly a public receive key
of the day for bob
and alice sends bob her public sen key
along with the encrypted message
and bob can go and get go to his dso and
get his secret receive key of the day
now this is slightly complicated and
does all sorts of other things are wrong
with it once you start to look at it
next slide please the first is that from
the point of view of the overall effect
you could just as easily have used
kerberos
because you've basically got a key
distribution center at both ends which
knows everybody's keys
so you've not actually gained very much
by using complicated public key
mechanisms
and the next problem is what's the law
enforcement access need for centrally
generated signing keys
um if this is actually from law
enforcement rather than intelligence
well the police want to be able to read
things not forge things
a third problem is that keys
involve hashing department names and
governments are changing the name of
their departments all the time as the
prime minister of the day
moves his ministers around and they chop
and change departments and
this means of course that everybody has
to get new cryptographic keys and
suddenly the old cryptographic keys
don't work anymore
and there's a horrendous complexity
comes from this
now there are about 10 other things
wrong with this protocol
but curiously enough it's still used by
the uk government for the top secret
stuff it went through a number of
iterations it's now called maikiseki
those details in my security engineering
book
and it turned out to be such a pain that
the staff below top secret
now just uses a branded version of g
suite
so if what you want to do is to figure
out what speech boris johnson will be
making tomorrow
you just have to guess the password
recovery questions for his
private secretaries and officials
next slide the global internet trust
register
this was an interesting piece of fun we
had around the 1997 election when tony
blair took over
and introduced the labour government
before the election labour promised to
not seize crypto keys in bulk without a
warrant
and one of the first things that
happened to him once he was in office is
vice president al gore
went to visit him and all of a sudden
tony
decided that he wanted all certification
authorities to be licensed
and they were about to rush this through
parliament
so we put all the important public keys
in a paper book
and we took it to the cultural secretary
chris smith and we said you're the
minister for books so why are you
passing a law to ban this book
and if you'll switch to the the video
shot i've got um the initial copy of the
book that we just put together on the
photocopying machine in the department
and then we sent the pdf off to mit and
they produced it
as a proper book and this means that we
had a book
you know which is supposedly protected
um
and and this enabled us to get the um
the topic onto
the agenda for cabinet discussion
so this at least stopped precipitous
action we ended up with a regulation of
investigatory powers bill in 2000 that
was far from perfect
but that was a longer story so what
happened back then is that we set up a
an ngo
a digital rights organization the
foundation for information policy
research
and the climate at the time was such
that we had no difficulty
raising a couple of hundred thousand
pounds from microsoft and hewlett
packard and red bus and other tech
players so we were able to hire casper
bowden
for three years to basically be the
director of fifa
and to lobby the government hard on this
now if we can go back to the slides
please
and go to the next slide the slide on
bringing it all together
so in 1997 um a number of us
um harley wilson and i and steve belafon
um
and uh josh bernal from microsoft and
matt blais have a broken
clipper and whit diffy who'd invented
digital signatures
and john gilmer of eff peter neumann of
sri
ron rivest and jeff schiller of mit and
bruce schneier had written applied
cryptography
got together and wrote a paper the risks
of key recovery key escrow and trusted
third-party encryption
where we discussed the system
consequences of giving third party or
government access to both traffic data
and content
without user notice or consent deployed
internationally and available around the
clock
we came to the conclusion that this was
not really doable
it brought in simply too many
vulnerabilities and too many
complexities
so how did it end well if we go to the
next slide
the victory in europe wasn't as a result
of academic argument
it was a result of industry pressure and
we owe
a debt to commissioner martin bangaman
and also to the german government who
backed him
and in 1994 martin had put together a
group of
european uh ceos to advise him on
internet policy
and they advised him look keep your
hands off until we can see which way
it's going let's just run with this
thing and see what we can do with it
and the thing that he developed in order
to
drive a stake through the heart of ki
escrow was the electronic signatures
directive in 1999
and this gave a reversible presumption
of validity to qualifying electronic
signatures
but subject to a number of conditions
and one of these was that the signing
key must never be known to anybody else
other than the signer and this killed
the idea
of licensing cas in such a way that the
the nsa had access to all the private
key material
the agencies had argued that without
controlling signatures you couldn't
control encryption
but of course as intelligence agencies
they were as much interested in
manipulating information
as they were in listening into it and
this created a really sharp
conflict with businesses in the uk with
a regulation of investigative
players bill went through the following
year and there we got strong support
from the banks who did not want
the possibility of intelligence or law
enforcement personnel
either getting hold of bank keys or
forging banking transactions
and so we managed to uh with their help
to insert a number of
uh conditions into the bill which meant
that if a court or a chief constable for
example demands a key from a company
they've got to demand it from somebody
at the level of a director of the
company
and it's got to be signed by someone
really senior such as a chief constable
so there are some controls that we
managed to get in there
next slide what did victory in the usa
look like
well um in the middle of 2000 as a
number of people had predicted
al gore decided that he wanted to stop
fighting the tech industry in order to
get elected president
and there was a deal done at the time
which was secret it was done at the
fbi headquarters at quantico whereby u.s
law enforcement would rely on naturally
occurring vulnerabilities rather than
compelling their insertion
by companies like intel or microsoft now
this was secret at the time and i
happened to know about it because i was
consulting for intel
and the nda i was under had a four year
time limit on it so
after 2004 i was at liberty to talk
about this
and so this basically gave the nsa
access to the search feed
and so as part of this deal the export
rules were liberalized a bit
but with various hooks and gotchas left
so that
um the the authorities could bully
companies who
got too difficult and in 2002
robert morris senior who had been the
chief scientists at the nsa
at much of this period admitted that the
real policy goal
was to ensure that the many systems
developed during the dot-com boom were
deployed with weak protection or none
and there's a huge long list of these
next slide please
so what was the collateral damage from
crypto war one
this is the um the first novel part of
this talk which i got together
as a result of spending the last
academic year writing
the third edition of my book on security
engineering
as i've gone through and updated all the
uh chapters on car security
rollout security and web security and so
on and so forth
and we find everywhere that there are
still very serious costs
remaining from crypto war one for
example almost all of the remote key
entry systems for cars
used in adequate cryptography pro random
number generators and so on and so forth
and car theft has almost doubled in the
past five years
um this is not all due to weak crypto
but it's substantially due to
a wrong culture that was started off in
the context of the crypto wars
second there are millions of door locks
still using my fair classic
um even the building where i work for
example
um the university of cambridge changed
its door lots around 2000 so we've still
got
a whole lot of my fair classic around
and it's very difficult when you've got
100 buildings and change all the locks
on them
and this is the case with thousands of
organizations worldwide with
universities with banks with all sorts
of people simply because
changing all the locks at once and
dozens of buildings is just too
expensive
then of course there's a ca in your
browser most nations own
or control certification authorities
that your browser
trusts and the few nations that weren't
allowed to own
such cas such as iran put up to mischief
as we found in the case of the digital
hack a few years ago
and this means that most nations have
got a more or less
guaranteed ability to do man in the
middle attacks
on your your web logons
now some companies like google have of
course started to fix that
with various mechanisms such as
certificate pinning
but that was a deliberate vulnerability
that was there for a long long time and
is still very widespread
phones 2g is insecure that actually goes
back to the cold war rather than the
crypto war
but thanks to the crypto wars 4g and 5g
are not very much better
the details are slightly complicated and
again they're
described in the book bluetooth is easy
to hack
that's another piece of legacy and as i
mentioned the agencies on the
certs responsible disclosure pipeline
which means that they get a free far
hose of zero days that they can exploit
for
perhaps a month or three before these
end up being patched
this next slide please
last year when i talked at the chaos
communications congress the audience
um chose this as the cover for my
security engineering book
that's now out and it's the process of
writing this that brought home to me
the scale of the damage that we still
suffered as a result of crypto war one
so let's move on to the next slide and
the next
period of history which we might call
the war on terror
and i've arbitrarily put this down as
2000 to 2013.
although some countries stopped using
the trey's war on terror in
about 2008 once we have got rid of
george w
bush and tony blair but that's a
historical convenience
this is if you like the central period
in our tale
and it starts off with a lot of
harassment around the edges
of um security and cryptography for
example
in 2000 tony blair promoted the eu drill
use regulation
number 1334 to extend export controls
from tangible goods such as rifles and
tanks to
intangibles such as crit to suffer
despite the fact
that he had you know basically declared
peace on the tech industry
two years later in 2002 the uk
parliament bolted an export control bill
that was going to transpose this
because it added controls on scientific
speech
not just crypto code but even papers and
cryptanalysis and even electron
microscope scripts
and so parliament inserted a research
exemption clause at the arguments of the
then president of the royal society
um sir robert may but what then happened
is that gchq used eu regulations to
frustrate parliament
and this pattern of extra legal behavior
was to continue
next slide because after export control
the place shifted to traffic data
retention
another bad thing that i'm afraid to say
the uk exports into europe
back in the days when we were in effect
the americans consigliere on the
european council
sorry about that folks but all i can say
is at least we helped start
edri um a year after that
so one of the um interesting aspects of
this was that our then home secretary
jackie smith
started talking up the need for a comms
database a database of all the metadata
of who had phoned whom when
who had sent an email to whom when so
the police could continue to use the
traditional contact tracing techniques
online
and the line that we got hammered home
to us again and again and again was if
you've got nothing to hide
you've got nothing to fear what then
happened
in 2008 is that a very bad person
um walked into parliament and went to
the pc where
the expense claims of mps were kept and
they copied all the expense claims onto
a dvd
and they hopped it around fleet street
until the daily telegraph bought it from
them for 400 000 pounds
and then for the best part of the year
the daily telegraph was
telling scandalous things about what
various members of parliament had
claimed from the taxpayer and it turned
out that although jackie smith may have
been innocent
her husband had been downloading
pornography and charging it to her
parliamentary expenses
so she lost her job as home secretary
and she lost her seat in parliament
and the communications data bill was
lost
so was this a victory well in june 2013
we learned from ed snowden that they
just built it anyway despite parliament
um so maybe um the victory in parliament
wasn't what it seemed to be at the time
but i'm getting ahead of myself
anyway next slide please
the other thing that we did in the 2000s
is that we spent
um i spent maybe a third of my time and
about another 100 people joined and we
developed
the economics of security as a
discipline we began to realize that many
of the things that went wrong
happened because alice was guarding a
system and bob was paying the cost of
failure
for example if you've got a payment
system then
in order to prevent fraud what you
basically have to do
is to get the merchants and the banks
who buy transactions from them to take
care
but the costs of fraud fall on the
cardholder on the banks of issue them
with cards
and the two aren't the same and it's
this that causes the government's
tensions
and causes governance to break down and
makes fraud higher than it should be
now after that one of the early topics
was patching and responsible disclosure
and we worked through all the issues of
whether you should not patch at
all which some people in industry wanted
to do or whether you should just put all
the bugs on bug track or some hackers
wanted to do
or whether you would go through the
start system despite the nsa compromise
because they at least would give you
legal cover
and you know would be microsoft into
patching the bug at the next patch
tuesday and would then do disclosure
after 90 days
and we eventually came to the conclusion
as
an industry followed that responsible
disclosure was the way to go
now one of the problems that arises here
is
the equities issue suppose you're the
director of the nsa and somebody comes
to you with some super
new innovative bug you know say they had
pre-discovered spectre for example
and so you've got a bug which can be
used
to you know penetrate any crypto
software that's out there
do you report the bug to microsoft and
intel to defend 300 million americans
or do you keep it quiet so you can
exploit 450 million europeans and a
thousand million
chinese and so on and so forth well once
you put it that way it's fairly obvious
that the nsa will favor attack or
defense
and there are multiple models of attack
and defense you can think of
institutional
factors and politics for example if
you're the director of the nsa
and you defend 300 million americans you
defend the white house against
the chinese hacking it
you know the president will never know
if he's hacked or not because the
chinese will keep it quiet if they do
but if on the other hand you managed to
hack the politburo
land in peking you can put some juicy
intelligence every morning with the
president's breakfast cereal
so that's an even stronger
um argument why you should do attack
rather than defense
another thing that i'll mention in
passing is that throughout the 2000s
governments also scrambled to get more
debt of their citizens
for example in britain we no longer
debate about whether medical records
should be centralized
in the beginning we said if you were to
centralize all medical records that
would be such a large target that the
database should be top secret and it
would be too inconvenient for doctors to
use
well blair decided in 2001 to do it
anyway
we wrote a report in 2009 saying that
this was a
red line that this was a serious hazard
and then in 2014 we discovered that
cameron's buddy who was the transparency
tsar in
the nhs has sold the database to 1200
researchers
including drug companies in china so
that meant that all the sensitive
personal health information
about one billion patient episodes you
know had been sold around the world and
was available to
not just to medical researchers but to
foreign intelligence services
and this brings us on to snowden
in june 2013
we had
one of those um game-changing moments
when ed snowden
uh leaked a whole bunch of papers
showing that the nsa had been breaking
the law in america
and gchq had been breaking the law in
britain that we had been lied to that
parliament had been misled
and a whole lot of connection and
interception was going on
which supposedly shouldn't have been
going on now
one of the things that got industry
attention was a system called prism
which was in fact legal because this was
in
you know done as a result of warrants
being served
on the major internet service providers
and if we could move to the next slide
we can see that this started off with
microsoft in 2007
yahoo in 2008 they thought it's in court
for a year they lost and then google and
facebook and so on got added
and this basically enabled um the nsa to
go to someone like google
and say ross j anderson at gmail.com is
a foreign national where there for
entitled to
read his traffic kindly give us his
gmail and google would say
yes sir for americans you have to show
probable cause
they've committed a crime for foreigners
you simply have to show probable cause
that they're a foreigner
and next slide this
disclosure from snowden disclosed
that prism despite the fact that it only
cost about uh 20 million dollars a year
was generating something like half of
all the intelligence that the nsa was
using
by the end of financial year 2012
but that was not all next slide please
the thing that really annoyed google was
this slide on a deck from a presentation
at gchq
showing how the nsa was not merely
connecting stuff
through the front door by serving
warrants on google in mountain view
it was collecting stuff through the back
door as well because they were
harvesting the plain text
copies of gmail and maps and docs and so
on
which were being sent backwards and
forwards between google's different data
centers
and the little smiley face which you can
see on the sticky
um got sergey and friends really really
uptight
and they just decided right you know
you know we're not going to allow this
they will have to knock and show
warrants in the future
and there was a crash program at all the
major internet service providers to
encrypt all the traffic
um so that in future things could only
be work
got would mean by means of a warrant
next slide please the eu
was really not was was really annoyed by
what was called operation socialist
um operation socialist
um was um
[Music]
basically the hack of belgiacon and the
idea
was that gchq spearfished some um
technical staff at belgiacom and this
enabled them to wire up all the traffic
at the european commission in brussels
and you know as well as
mobile phone traffic to and from various
um
countries in africa and this is rather
amazing it's as if nicola sturgeon the
first minister of scotland
had tasked police scotland with
packing bt so that she could work out
what was going on with the parliament
in london so this annoyed a number of
people
with the next slide we can see
that the um the operation bull run
um and operation edge hill as gchq
called their version of it
have been aggressive multi-pronged
efforts to break widely used internet
encryption technologies
and we learned an awful lot about what
was being done to break vpns worldwide
um and what had been done in terms of
inserting
vulnerabilities in protocols getting
people to use
vulnerable prime numbers for
diffie-hellman key exchange and so on
and so forth
next slide thrust slide and bull run and
edge hill
sigin's enabling project actively
engages the u.s and foreign i.t
industries to cover the influence and or
overtly leverage
their commercial products designs these
design changes make the systems in
question exploitable through cigarette
collection
endpoint midpoint etcetera with full
knowledge of the modification
the consumer and other adversaries
however the system security remains
intact next slide
so the insert vulnerabilities into
commercial systems i t
systems networks endpoint communication
devices used by targets
next slide
and he also influenced policy standards
and specifications for commercial public
key technologies
and this was the smoking gun that crypto
war
one had not actually ended it had just
gone
undercover and so with this things come
out into the open next slide so we could
perhaps
um date crypto war ii to the snowden
disclosures in their aftermath
in america it must be said that all
three arms of the u.s government showed
at least mild remorse
obama set up the nsa review group and
adopted most of what it said
except on the equities issue congress
dropped debtor retention when it renewed
the patriot act
and the fisa court introduced an
advocate for targets
um tech companies as i mentioned
starting started encrypting all their
traffic
in the uk on the other hand governments
express expressed no remarks at
all and they pass the investigatory
powers act and legalize all the unlawful
things they've already been doing
and they can now order from secretly to
do anything they physically can
however debtor attention was mixed by
the european courts
the academic response in the next slide
keys under doormats
much the same authors as before we
analyzed the new situation and came to
much of the same conclusions
next slide the 2018 gchq proposals
from ian levy and crispin robinson
proposed to add ghost users to whatsapp
and
facetime calls in response to warrants
the idea is that you've got an fbi
key on your device keyring you still
have end-to-end crypto you just have an
extra end
and this of course fails the keys under
doormats tests
your software would abandon best
practice it would create targets and
increase complexity
and it would also have to lie about
trust
next slide please
this brings us to the upload filters
which were proposed
over the past six months they first
surfaced in
early 2020 via stanford think tank
and they were adopted by commissioner
ulva johansson
on june the ninth start of the german
presidency
on the 20th of september we're going to
meet tech paper
whose authors include our gchq friends
ian levy and crispin robinson
the top options are that you filter in
client software
assisted by a server as client side only
filtering is too constrained and easy to
compromise
the excuse is that you want to stop
illegal materials such as child sex
abuse images
being shared over end-to-end messaging
systems such as whatsapp
various ngos objected and we had a
meeting with the
commission which was a little bit like a
stockholm syndrome event
we had one official there on the child
protection front
uh thanks by half a dozen officials from
various security bodies departments and
agencies
who seem to be clearly driving the thing
with child protection merely being an
excuse
so where might this lead
well the obvious things to worry about
are as a similar language in the
new terror regulation you can expect the
filter to extend from child sex abuse
material to terror
and static filtering won't work because
if there's a bad list of 100 000
forbidden images
then the bad people will just go out and
make another 100
000 child sex abuse images so the
filtering will have to become dynamic
and then the question is whether your
formal blockers are reported
and does an existing legal duty in a
number of countries and
um in the uk too although this is
obviously no longer a member state
um an existing duty to report terrorist
stuff
and the question is who will be in
charge of updating the filters
what's going to happen then next slide
well we've seen um an illustration
during the lockdown
in april the french and dutch government
sent an update to all emperor chat
mobile phones with a rootkit which
copied messages crypto keys and lock
screen passwords
the anchor chat was a brand of mobile
phone that was sold through
underground channels to various criminal
groups
and others and since this was largely
used by criminals of various kinds
the uk government justified bulk
intercept
by passing it off as targeted equipment
interference in other words they wrought
a targeted warrant
for all 45 000 encore chat handsets
and of 10 000 users in the uk 800 were
arrested in june when the raw tapping
exercise was completed
now again this appears to ignore the
laws that we have on the books because
even our investigatory powers act
rules out bulk interception of uk
residents
and those who follow such matters will
know that there was a trial at liverpool
crime court
a hearing of whether this stuff was
admissible
and we should have a first verdict on
that
early in the new year then that will no
doubt go to appeal
and if the material is held to be
admissible then there will be a whole
series of trials
so this brings me to my final point
what can we expect going forward china
is emerging as a full stack competitor
to the west
not like russia and cold war one because
russia only ever produced things like
primary goods like oil and weapons and
trouble of course but china is trying to
compete all the way up and down the
stack
from chips through software up through
services and everything else
and developments in china don't exactly
fill one with
much confidence because in march 2018
president xi declared himself to be
ruler for life
basically tearing up the chinese
constitution
there are large-scale state crimes being
committed in
tibet and sinkiang and elsewhere just
last week
britain's chief rabbi described the
treatment of we girls as an unfathomable
unfathomable mass atrocity and in my
book
i describe escalating cyber conflict
and various hacks such as the hack of
the office of personnel management which
had clearance
files on all americans who work for the
federal government
a hack of equifax which got credit
ratings and
credit histories of all americans and
there are also growing tussles and
standards for example the draft eyes of
27553 and biometric authentication
for mobile phones is introducing at the
instance of chinese delegates a central
database option
so in future your phone might not verify
your
face print or your fingerprint locally
it might do it with a central database
next slide how could cold war 2.0 be
different
well there's a number of interesting
things here and the purpose of this talk
is to try and
kick off a discussion of these issues
china makes electronics not just guns
the way the old ussr did
can you have a separate supply chain for
china
and one for everybody else um
but hang on a minute consider the fact
that
um china has now collected very
substantial
personal uh data sets on the office of
personnel management they've got
us government employees
by forcing apple to set up its own data
centers in china for iphone users in
china
they get access to
all the data for chinese users of
iphones that america gets for american
users of iphones
plus maybe more as well if the chinese
can break the hsms in chinese data
centers as we expect they would be able
to
equifax got them data on all
economically active people in the usa
care dark data gave them medical records
of everybody in the uk
and this personal data is already being
targeted
in intelligence use when western
countries for example
send diplomats to countries in africa or
latin america
the local chinese counter intelligence
people know why are there bona fidi
diplomats or whether they're
intelligence agents undercover
why from exploitation of all this about
personal information
now given that this information is
already in efficient targeted use
the next question we have to ask is when
will it be used at scale
and this is the point at which we say
that the equities issue now needs a
serious rethink
and the whole structure of the conflict
is going to have to move from more
offensive to more defensive
because we depend on supply chains to
which
the chinese have access more than they
depend on supply chains to which we have
access
now it's dreadful that they're we're
headed towards a new cold war
but as we head there we have to ask what
are the respective roles of governments
industry
and civil society academia
next slide please and so looking forward
my point is this that if cold war 2.0
does happen
i hope it doesn't but we appear to be
headed that way despite
the change of government in the white
house then we need to be able to defend
everybody not just the elites
now it's not going to be easy because
there are more state players
the usa is a big block the eu is a big
block there are other players other
democracies there are other
non-democracies there's other failing
democracies
it's going to be complex and messy it
isn't going to
be a situation like last time where big
tech reaches out to civil society and
academia
and we get a united front against the
agencies
and even in that case of course the
victory that we got was only an apparent
victory
a superficial victory that's only lasted
for a while
so what can we do well at this point i
think we need to remind all the players
who listen
but it's not just about strategy and
tactics but it's about values too
and so we need to be firmly on the side
of freedom privacy and the rule of law
now for the old timers you may remember
that there was a product called tom
skype
and which was introduced in 2011 in
china
the chinese wanted their citizens to be
able to use skype but they wanted to
be able to wiretap it as well despite
the fact that skype at the time had
end-to-end encryption
and so people in china were compelled to
download
a client from skype called tomsky tom
was the company that
distributed skype in china and it
basically had built-in wiretapping
so you had end-to-end encryption using
skype in those days
but in china you ended up having a
trojan
client which you had to use and what we
are doing at the moment
is basically um the the eu is trying to
copy tomsky
and saying that we should be doing now
what china was doing eight years ago
and i say we should reject that we can't
challenge president xi
by being down that road instead we've
got to restate our values
and we've got to think through the
equities issue and we've got to figure
out
how it is that we're going to deal with
the challenges
of dealing with non-democratic countries
when there is serious conflict in a
globalized world where we're sharing the
same technology
thanks and perhaps the
uh the last slide for my book can come
now and i'm happy to take questions
yeah thanks a lot ross for your talk
um it's a bit depressing to listen to
you i have to admit
let's have a look
okay so i have a question
i'm wondering if the export controls at
eu level became worse than uk level
expert controls because
entities like gchq had more influence
there
or because there's a harmful franco
german security culture or what it was
do you have anything on that well the
experience that we had with these export
controls once they were in place
was as follows it was about 2015 i think
or 2016.
um it came to our attention that a
british company
um sophos was selling bulk surveillance
equipment
to president al-assad of syria and he
was using it to
basically watap his entire population
and decide
who he was going to arrest and kill the
following day and it was sold by sophos
in fact through a german subsidiary
and so we went along to the export
control office in
in victoria street um a number of um
ngos the open rights group went along
and privacy international and us and one
or two others
and we said look according to the eu
dual use regulation
right bulk intercept equipment is
military kit it should be in the
military list therefore you should be
demanding
um an export license for this stuff
and they found every conceivable excuse
um
you know not to demand it and it was the
lady from gchq there
in the room who was clearly calling the
shots and she was absolutely determined
that there should be no
export controls on the staff being sold
to syria
and eventually i said look it's fairly
obvious what's going on here if there's
going to be black boxes and president of
assad's network
you want them to be british black boxes
or german black boxes
um not ukrainian or israeli black boxers
and she said
i cannot discuss classified matters in
an open meeting
which is as close as you get to an
admission
and a couple of months later angela
merkel to her great credit actually came
out in
public and said that allowing the
equipment to be exported from utimako to
syria was one of the hardest decisions
she'd ever taken as councillor
and there was a very difficult trade-off
between maintaining intelligence access
given the possibility that western
troops would be involved in syria
and the fact that the kit was being used
for very evil purposes
so that that's an example of how the
export controls are used in practice
they are not used to control the harms
that we
as voters are told that they're there to
control
right they are used in all sorts of dark
and dismal games
and we really have to tackle the issue
of export controls with our eyes open
yeah yeah there's a lot
a lot to do and now germany has left the
uh eu uh un's uh security council
so let's see what happens next
um yeah
we'll see ross anything else you'd like
to add
we don't have any more questions
oh no we have another question it's just
come up
second good do you think that refusal to
accept backdoors will create
large uncensorable applications
well if you get large applications um
which are associated with significant um
economic power
um then you know pressure gets brought
to bear in those economic players to you
know do their social duty
um and
this is what we have seen with the
platforms that intermediate content
that acts as content intermediaries such
as facebook and google and so on that
they do a certain amount of filtering
but if on the other hand you have
wholesale
um surveillance before the fact of
end-to-end encrypted stuff
then are we moving into an environment
um where a private speech
from one person to another is no longer
permitted you know i
i don't think that's the right trade-off
that we should be taking
um because we all know from hard
experience that when governments say
think of the children they're not
thinking of children at all
if they were thinking of children they
would not be selling weapons to saudi
arabia and the united arab emirates to
kill
children in the yemen and they say think
about terrorism
but the the censorship that we are
supposed to use in universities around
terrorism the so-called prevent duty is
is known to be counterproductive it
makes muslim students feel alienated and
marginalized
so the arguments that governments use
around this are not
in any way honest and we now have 20
years experience of these dishonest
arguments
and for goodness sake that's a more
grown-up conversation about these things
now you're totally right
even if i have to admit it took me a
couple of years not 20 but a lot
to finally understand okay
this i think that's it we just have
another comment and i'm thanking you for
your time
and um are you in an assembly somewhere
around hanging around
in the next hour or so maybe if someone
wants to talk to you you can just pop by
if you ever if you if you have used this
2d world
already no i i haven't been using the 2d
world
um i had some issues with my browser and
getting into it but
you know i've got my my webpage and my
email address is public and anybody who
wants to discuss these things is welcome
to get in touch with me
all right so thanks a lot
thank you for the invitation yeah thanks
a lot
wow
you