[Music]
[Applause]
and
the talk that is about to begin now is
by christoph schmon from eff and
elizabeth from accessnow
and they were talking about this
probably maybe the biggest legislative
initiative
since the gdpr in brussels it's called
the digital services act and onto
youtube
muted i realized hello uh
first of all thank you very much for
having us today it's a great pleasure
to be the part of this event i think for
both of us
it's the first time we are actually
joining this year
so it's fantastic to be a part of this
great community
um and today we are going to talk about
the legislative proposal still a
proposal which caused
a lot of noise all around europe but not
only in europe but also beyond
and that's the digital services act
legislative package that today we
already know that this legislative
package actually consists of two acts
digital services act and a digital
market act
and both of them will significantly
change the
regulation of online platforms with a
specific focus on very large online
platforms also often referred to as
gatekeepers so those who actually hold a
lot of economic dominance
but also a lot of influence and control
over users rights and the public
discourse
and so i'm going to start with giving
you a quick
introduction into what's the fuss about
what is actually the essay all about why
we are also interested in it and why we
keep talking about it
and why this legislation will keep us
preoccupied
for the years to come the essay was
already announced
two years ago as a part of european
union uh
digital strategy and
it was appointed as one of those actions
that the digital strategy will be
actually consisting of
um and it was the promise that the
european commission gave us
already at that time to create the
systemic regulation of online platforms
that actually places hopefully the users
and their rights
into the center of this upcoming
legislation
so the promise behind the esa is that
this ad based internet bill
and i'm speaking now about aztec and
online targeting the internet as we
actually knew will be actually replaced
by something that puts
user and uses controls and uses right as
a priority
so both of these legislations if
implemented and drafted right
should be actually achieving that goal
in the future
now previously before dsa actually was
drafted
there was some so-called e-commerce
directive in place that actually
established
the basic principles especially in the
field of content governance
i won't go into details uh on that
because i don't want to make this too
legalistic but ultimately the sa
legislation
is supposed to not completely replace
but build up on the top of these
legislation that actually created the
ground and the main legal regime for
almost 20 years in europe
to regulate the user-generated content
so
a dsa and dma as the legislation will
seek to harmonize the rules addressing
the problems such as online hate speech
disinformation
but it also puts emphasis finally on
increased meaningful transparency in
online
advertising the way how the content is
actually being distributed across
platforms and and also
will develop a specific enforcement
mechanism
that will be actually looking into it
now before i will actually go into the
details on the essay and why dsa matters
and do we actually need such a
big new legislative reform that is
coming from the european commission
i want to just unpack it for you a
little bit uh this dsa legislative
package
actually consists of so as i already
mentioned two regulations so regulation
the strongest legal instrument
european commission actually hacks in
has in its hands
which is supposed to achieve the highest
level of harmonization across the member
states
and we all can imagine how difficult
that will be to achieve especially
in the realm of freedom of expression
and particular categories of user
generated content which is so deeply
complex dependent
all of those related to content
moderation and content curation
will be mainly in the realm of digital
services
act and then the second regulation the
digital market act will be specifically
looking at the dominance of the online
platforms
economic dominance competitive
environment for
smaller players the fairness in the
competition
and and it will also establish the list
of do's and don'ts for gatekeepers
platform so something that
uh so the platforms that actually hold
that relevant dominance
and now based on these new proposals we
know that these
platforms are mainly called as very
large online platforms so this is
exactly how the legislation refers to
gatekeepers now
um now i think one more point that i
want to make is
that uh it the dsa and dma were launched
on the 15th of december 2020 so
it was literally a christmas present
given to the digital rights community by
the european commission along long
time anticipated one the work on the
essays started however much earlier
electronic frontiers foundations as much
as access now together with edri
were working very hard to come up with
the priorities and recommendations what
we would like to see within these
legislations to be unfriend
because from the beginning we understood
the importance and the far-reaching
consequences this legislation will have
not only inside of the european union
but also beyond
and that brings me to the final
introductory point that i want to make
before i will hand over to chris which
is why and do we actually need the dsa
we strongly believe that there is a big
justification and good reason to
actually establish a systemic regulation
of online platforms in order to secure
users fundamental rights
empower them and also to protect our
democratic discourse
and this is due to the fact that for
many years we're witnessing this space
a quite bad regulatory practices in
platform governance
that are coming from member states and
chris will provide for a very concrete
examples in that regard
but also coming from the european
commission itself
mainly the proposed online terrorist
content regulation for instance
or we all remember the story of
copyright that crystal will discuss a
little bit further
we saw how not only the member states
but also
european commission or european union in
order to actually um
uh establish some order in the digital
space
they started pushing the state's
obligation and especially states
positive obligation to protect users
human rights in hands of online private
platforms that started replacing
uh state actors and public authorities
within the online space
they started assessing the content the
legality of the content
deciding under very short time frames
what should stay online and what should
go offline
with no public scrutiny or transparency
about practices that they kept deploying
and they keep deploying to this day
uh of course platforms under the threat
of legal liability
uh often uh had to rely and still have
to rely on the content recognition
technologies for removing user-generated
content
a typical example could be also avial
law which will be still mentioned today
during the presentation
and the typical time frames are usually
those that
extend from one hour to 24 hours which
is extremely short especially if any
users would like to appeal such a
decision
or seek an effective remedy at the same
time due to the
lack of harmonization and lack of proper
set of responsibilities that should lie
in hands of these online platforms
there was a lack of legal certainty
which would only reinforce that vicious
circle
of removing more and more of online
content in order to escape any possible
liability
and at the end to this day due to the
lack of transparency
we lack any evidence or research based
policy making
because platforms do not want to share
or inform the public authorities what
they actually do with
the content how they moderate and those
transparency information that we receive
within their transparency reports are
usually quantity oriented instead of
quality
so they focus on how much content is
actually being removed and how fast
which is not enough in order to create
laws that can actually provide
any more sustainable solutions and
ultimately as we all agree
um the core issue doesn't lie that much
with how the content is being moderated
but how content is being distributed
across platforms
um within the core of their business
models that actually stands on a
on a attention economy and on a way how
sensational content is often being
amplified in order to actually prolong
that
attention span of users that visit
platforms on regular basis
i'm at back i'm unpacking quite a few
issues here and this is supposed to be
just a quick introductory remark
uh i will now hand over to christoph who
will elaborate on all this point a
little bit further and then we take a
look and
unpack few quite important parts of the
essay
that we feel should be prioritizing this
debate
at the moment chris over to you
thanks alicia hi everybody um i'm quite
sure that
many of you have noticed that there's a
growing appetite from the side of the
european union to
regulate the internet by using online
platforms as their helping hands
to monitor and sensor with users can say
share do online
as you see on the slide the first
highlight of this
growing appetite was corporate upload
filters which are supposed to spot
copyright protected content online
thousands of people od and young went on
the streets to demonstrate for
free internet and to demonstrate against
technical measures to turn the internet
into some sort of
censorship machine we've made a point
then and we continue making the point
now that
upload filters are prone to error that
upload filters cannot understand context
that they are unaffordable by all but
the largest tech companies
and which happen to be all based in the
united states but as you well know
policymakers would not listen and
article 13 of the copyright directive
was adopted by a small
small margin in the european parliament
also because some members of the open
parliament had troubles to press the
right buttons
but i think it's important for us to
understand that the fight is
the fight is far from over the member
states must now implement the directive
in a way that is not at odds with
fundamental rights
and we argue that mandated automated
removal technologies are
always in conflict with fundamental
rights and this includes data protection
rights
it is a data protection right not to be
made subject to automated decision
making online if it involves your
personal data
and if such decision making has a
negative effect
but if you leave all those legal
arguments aside um
i think the most boring experience with
upload filters is that they had a
spillover effect
a spillover effect to other initiatives
sure if it works for copyright protected
content it may well work for other type
of content right
except that it doesn't many considered
now a clever idea that
platforms should proactively monitor and
check all sorts of user
content may just be communication
pictures or videos
and they should use filters to take it
down or to filters to prevent the
re-upload
of such content an example of such um
spillover effect and english as i
mentioned is the huge draft regulation
on terrorist related content
it took a huge joint effort of civil
society groups and some members of
parliament
to reject the worst of all texts
we had recent negotiations going on and
at least we managed to get out the
requirement to
use upload failures but there's still a
24 hours removal obligation that may not
platforms to employ those filters
nevertheless
and we see that particularly national
states are very fond of the idea that
platforms
rather than independent judges should be
the new law enforcers
there are several states in the european
union that have adopted laws that would
either oblige
or nudge platforms to monitor use of
speech online
first up was the german net dg which set
out systematic duties for platforms then
we had the french lavia
which copy based at the nasdg and made
it worse and last we have the austrian
hate speech bill which is a mix of both
the german and the french proposal
they all go much beyond copyright
content but focus on hate speech and all
sorts of content that may be considered
problematic or
in those respective countries not
necessarily in other countries
and this brings me to the next problem
how do we deal with content that is
illegal in one country but legally in
another
a recent court of justice ruling had
confirmed that a court of a small state
like austria
can order platforms not only to take
down deformatory content globally but
also to take down
identical or equivalent material using
automated technologies
for us this is a terrible outcome as
this will lead to race to the bottom
bottom where the countries with the
least freedom of speech friendly laws
can superimpose
their laws on every other state in the
world
we really believe that all this nonsense
has to stop
it's time to acknowledge that the
internet is a global space a place of
exchange of creativity in the place
where civil liberties are supposed to
exist
so we are fighting now against all those
national initiatives
we had the great first victory um when
we had to bring down the french
lora via the avia bill that had imposed
a duty for platforms to check
and remove potential potentially legal
content within 24 hours
before they can say constitutional the
french supreme court we had argued that
this would push platforms to constantly
check what users post
and if platforms face high fines
of course steve would be rather
motivated to block as much contestable
content as possible
you've made a point that this would be
against the shadow fundamental rights
including freedom of information and
freedom of expression
and it was a great victory for us that
the french supreme court has struck down
the french avia bill and followed our
argument as you see it on the slide
we also see that now that there's a push
back at least against the update of the
german netsdg
which would have provided new access
rights for law enforcement authorities
this and other provisions are considered
unconstitutional and as far as i
understand
and that's listeners can correct me the
german president has
refused to sign the bill and the
austrian bill goes a similar pathway
got recently a red light from brussels
the commission considered
considers it in conflict with your
principles
also thanks to joint effort by epicenter
works
and this shows that something positive
is going on is that positive development
the pushback
against our midfielder technologies
but it's important to understand that
those national initiatives are not just
purely national attempt to regulate hate
speech
it's an attempt of an eu member state to
make their own bills
as badly as they are some sort of a
prototype for you white legislation
a prototype for the digital services act
and as you know national member states
have the same new law making
their voices are represented in the
council of the eu and the european
commission
which will will be disincentivized to
propose anything that would be voted
down by council
i think that's a nice takeaway from
today that law making and national
member states
are not an isolated event it's always
political it's always nets politic
um the good news is that as far as the
ump commission proposal for the digital
services act is concerned
that it has not followed the footsteps
of those bad
badly designed and misguided bills it
has respected our input the input from
access now from eff from the
network from academics and many others
that
some key principles should not be
removed like that liability for speed
should rest with the speaker
the dsa gives also red light to channel
monitoring of user content
and there are no short deadlines in
there to remove content that might be
illegal
instead the commission gives more
selective platforms to take down posts
in good faith
um which is or what we which we call the
eu style good samaritan clause
looking through the global lenses of law
making it's very fascinating to see that
that whilst the united states is
flirting with the idea to move away from
the good samaritan principle in section
230 of the communications decency act
so the idea that platforms can
voluntarily remove content without being
held liable for it
the european union flirts with the idea
to introduce it
to give more options to platforms to act
that being said the major differences
between the us and the eu is that
in europe platforms could be held liable
the moment they become aware of the
illegality of content
and that's an issue because the services
act has now introduced a relatively
sophisticated system
for user notification complete mechanism
dispute resolution
options which all lead to such awareness
about illegality or could lead to such
awareness
and it's not quite clear for us how
platforms will make use of voluntary
measures to remove content
that being said um we think that the
commission's proposal could have been
much worse
and the parliament's reports on the
digital services act have demonstrated
that the new parliament is a bit better
than the old one they have a lot of
respect for fundamental rights
the many members of parliament that are
quite fond of the idea
to protect civil liberties online but we
know that this was
only the start and we know that we need
another joint effort
to ensure that users are not monitored
and not at the mercy of algorithmic
decision making
and the think alicia is now going to
explain a bit more about all this
thank you thank you very much chris um
so we can actually move
now further and unpack few
relevant provisions for everything that
has already been mentioned
mainly in the realm of content
moderation and content curation
which ultimately lies in the core of
digital services
act and maybe not to make it all so
abstract um
i also have the printed version of the
law here with me
and if you look at it it's quite a
impressive piece of work that the
european commission did there
and i have to say that even though it's
a
great start it still uh contains a lot
of imperfections
and and i will try to summarize those
now uh for you especially in the light
of our arm positioning
uh and as i mean uh civil societies in
general
because i believe that on all those
points we have a pretty solid uh
agreement among each other um and what
we were actually hoping that digital
services act
will do what it actually does and where
we see
that uh we will need to actually
continue working very closely
especially with the members of the
european parliament in the future
once the draft will actually enter
european parliament which should happen
relatively soon
so as it already as i already mentioned
at the beginning
quite briefly is how actually dsa
distinguishes between online platforms
which are defined within the scope of
the law
and uh between very large online
platforms
which is exactly that scope where all
large online gatekeepers fall into
the essay specifically then
distinguishes between obligations or
responsibilities of these actors
some assigning to all of them or
including online platforms and some
being extended specifically due to the
dominance and power these online
gatekeepers
hold uh this is mainly then the case
when we discuss the requirements for
transparency there is a set of
requirements for transparency that apply
to online platforms but then there is
still specific
additional set of transparency
requirements for larger online platforms
what dsa does especially and this is the
bid which is extremely relevant for the
content moderation practices
it attempts to establish a harmonized
model for
notice and action procedure for
allegedly illegal content
one of our red lines before i go into
the details on this
uh was that dsa will be touching only
uh or trying to regulate only allegedly
illegal content
and stay away from vaguely defined
content categories such as potentially
harmful but legal content
there are other ways how the legislation
can tackle these content mainly through
the
meaningful transparency requirements
accountability
tackling issues within the um open
content recommender systems and
algorithmic curation
but we didn't want this specific
category of the content to be included
within the scope of the essay
this is due to the fact that vaguely
defined terms that find their way into
legislation
always lead to human rights abuse in the
future
i could give you examples from europe
such as the concept of online harms
within the uk but also as a global
organizations both of us
we actually often see how wake
terminology can quickly lead
to even over criminalization of speech
or suppressing the descent
now if we go back to harmonize notice an
action procedure what that actually
means in practice
as christoph already mentioned europe
has so-called conditional model of
intermediate reliability
which is being provided already and
established by the initial legal regime
which is the e-commerce directive under
article 14 of e-commerce directive
which actually uh states that um
unless the platform holds the actual
knowledge and according to the wording
of the essay now
it's the actual knowledge or awareness
about the presence of illegal content on
their platform
they cannot be held liable for such a
content
now we were asking for a harmonized
procedure
regarding notice and action across the
eu for a while precisely
because we wanted to see reinforced
legal certainty
lack of legal certainty often translated
into over-removal
of even legitimate content from the
platforms with no public scrutiny
um dsa does a good job it's a good
starting point that
actually it tries to attempt to
establish such a harmonized procedure
but it's still
lacking behind on many aspects that we
consider important
in order to strengthen protection of
fundamental rights of users
one of them is for instance that
harmonized notice and action procedure
as
envisioned by dsa is not specifically
tailored to
different types of uh categories of
user-generated content
and as we know there are some or many
categories of content that are deeply
context
dependent linked to the historical
and socio-political context of member
state in question
um and due to their of due to their
reliance on automated measures that are
usually context blind we are worried
that if notice an action doesn't reflect
this aspect in any further ways
we will end up again with over removals
of the content
what is probably another huge issue that
we are currently lacking
in the draft even though dsa is trying
to create a proper appeal and
enforcement mechanisms
um and also appeal mechanisms for users
and different
alternative dispute settlement that the
law draft currently contains
there is no possibility for a
content provider so a user that uploads
the filter
uh sorry that was a nice uh
friday and sleep there um the youth for
a user that actually upload the content
to appeal to that to directly actually
uh
use the counter notification about that
notified content that belongs to that
user
nor platforms are obliged to actually
send a notification to a user
prior to any action that is being taken
against that particular notified content
these are for us a procedural safeguards
for fairness that users should have
and currently they are not being
reflected in the draft
um however this is a good start and it's
something that we were pushing for but i
think there are many more aspects that
these notice and action
procedures will need to contain in order
to truly
put users at first now
the notice and action procedure is
mainly focusing on the illegal content
but there are ways in the draft where
potentially harmful content
which is still legal so the content that
actually violates the terms of service
of platforms
is being mentioned throughout the draft
so for us it's not at the moment
exactly clear how that will work in
practice
uh so that's why we
we often use this phrase that is also
put on the slide good intention with
imperfect solutions
however i want to emphasize again that
this is just the beginning and we will
still have time and space to work very
hard on this
uh another kind of novel aspect that dsa
actually brings about is already
mentioned
good samaritan clause and i tend to call
it the eu model or eu
version of good samaritan clause good
samaritan clause originates in section
230 of communication decency act as
christophe already mentioned
but uh within the european realm it goes
hand in hand with this conditional model
of liability which is being preserved
within the dsa
legal draft that was also one of our
main ask to preserve this conditional
model of liability
and it's great that this time european
commission really listened
why we consider the good summer written
clause being important
uh in the past when such a security was
an enshrined in the law
uh but it was just somehow wiggly
promised to the commission that if the
platform will proactively
uh you know uh deploy measures uh to
fight against the spread of illegal
content they won't be held liable
without acknowledging that through such
use of so-called proactive measures the
platform could in theory
gain the actual knowledge about the
existence of such a type of content on
its platform
which would immediately trigger legal
liability
this threat of liability often pushed
platforms to the corner so they would
rather remove the content very quickly
than to face uh more serious
consequences later on
uh that's why we see the importance
within the good summer written clause or
the european model of good samaritan
clause
and we are glad that it's currently
being the part of the draft
one of the biggest downfalls or one of
the biggest
uh disappointments when dsa finally
uh came out on the 15th of december
for us was to see that it's still online
platforms that will remain in charge
when it comes to assessing the legality
of the content and deciding
what content should be actually
restricted and removed from a platform
and what should be available
we often emphasize that it's very
important
that uh the legality of the content is
being uh
assessed by the independent judicial
authorities
as in line with their rule of law
principles we also do understand that
that such a solution creates a big
burden on the
judicial structure of member states many
member states see that as a very
expensive solutions they don't always
want to
create a special network of course or
e-course or
other forms of judicial
review of the illegal or allegedly
illegal content
but we still wanted to see more public
scrutiny
because for us this is truly just a
reaffirmation of already existing status
quo
as at the moment under many
jurisdictions within the eu and in the
eu itself
it's still online platform that will
call the final shots
uh what on the other hand is a positive
outcome that we were also
hardly pushing for are uh the
requirements for meaningful transparency
so to understand better what platforms
actually do with the individual pieces
of content
that are being shared on these platforms
and
and how actually transparency can then
ultimately empower user
now i want to emphasize this because
this is still ongoing debate
and we will touch upon those issues in a
minute but uh
we don't see transparency as a silver
bullet to the issues such as
amplification of potentially harmful
content
or in general that transparency will be
enough to actually hold platforms
accountable absolutely not it will never
be enough but it's a
precondition for us to actually seek
such solutions
uh in the future the sa contains
specific requirements for transparency
as i already mentioned
a set of requirements that will be
applicable largely to all online
platforms
and then still specific set of
requirements on the top of it
that will be applicable only to very
large online platforms so the online
gatekeepers
we appreciate the effort we see that the
list is very promising
but we still think it could be more
ambitious both
uh eff and access now put forward a
specific set of requirements for
meaningful transparency
that are in our positions and so did
edri and
other civil society or digital rights
activists in this space
um and final point that i'm going to
make is the
so-called pandora box of online
targeting and recommender systems
why do i refer to these two as
pandorabox
when a european parliament published its
initiative reports on the essay there
are two reports
one being a table by yuri committee and
another
one another one by inco especially the
yuri report contained paragraph 17
which calls out for a better regulation
of online targeting and online
advertisements
and specifically calling for a ban of
online targeting and
including the face out that will then
lead to a ban
we supported this paragraph which at the
end
was voted for and is the part of the
final report
nevertheless we also do understand that
this wording of the article has to be
more nuanced in the future
uh before i go into the details there i
just want to say that
this part has never made it to the essay
so there is no ban on online targeting
or online advertisement of any sorts
which to us to some extent it was
certainly disappointing too
we specifically would call for a much
more stricter approach when it comes to
behavioral targeting
as well as cross-site tracking of online
users
and but unfortunately and as we
eventually also heard from commissioner
west again that was simply
like a will or maybe too much pressure
from other law lobbyists in brussels
and this provision never found its way
uh to the final draft of the sa
that's the current state of art we will
see what we will manage to achieve
once the dsa will enter the european
parliament
and finally uh the law also contains a
specific a provision on
recommender system so uh the way how the
content is being distributed
uh across platform and uh how the data
of users are being abused for such a
distribution and personalization of user
generated content
in both cases whether it's online
targeting and recommender systems within
the dsa
the essay goes as far as the
transparency requirements the
explainability
but it does very little for returning
that control and empowerment back to the
user
so how use whether user can obtain or
opt out from these algorithmic curation
models
uh how it can actually optimize if they
decide to optimize it
all of that is at the moment very much
left outside
of the scope of the sa and so does the
issue of interoperability which is
definitely a
one of the key issues being currently
discussed and main
kind of possible hopes in the future for
returning that control and empowerment
back to the user and i keep repeating
this as a mantra but it's truly
the main driving force behind all our
initiatives and work
we do in these fields so the user and
their fundamental rights
and on that note i would like to hand
over back to chris who will
explain the issue of interoperability
and how to actually empower you as a
user
and to strengthen the protection of
fundamental rights further chris
it's yours now
thank you um
[Music]
i think we all know i feel that the
internet has seen better times
if you look back over the last 20 years
we have seen that a transformation was
going on from an open internet
towards a more closed one monopolization
big platforms have built entire
ecosystems and
it seems that they alone decide who gets
to use them
those platforms have strong network
effects that have pushed platforms
or those platforms into gatekeeper
position which made it so easy for them
to avoid any real competition
this especially is especially true when
we think of social media platforms
this year we celebrate the 20th birthday
of the e-commerce directive that alicia
had mentioned the internet bill that
will now be replaced by the digital
services act and we believe it's a very
good time now to
think and make a choice should we give
even more power to the big platforms
that have created
a lot of the mess in the first place or
should we give the power to the users
give the power back to the people for us
the answer is clear
big tech companies already employ a wide
array of technical measures they monitor
they remove they disrespect user privacy
and the idea to turn them into the
internet police with a special license
of censoring the speech of users will
only solidify the dominance
so we wouldn't like that what we like is
to
put users in charge over the online
experience
users should if we had a say choose for
themselves which kind of content they
can see what services they can use to
talk to their friends and families
and we believe it's perhaps time to
break up those
silos those big platforms have become to
end the dominance of the data
one element to achieve this would be to
tackle the targeted ads industry
uh silicek mentioned it perhaps to give
an actual right to users not to be
subject to targeted ads
or to give more choice to use to decide
which content they would like to see
or not to see in the digital services
act the commission
went for transparency when it comes to
ads and better options for users users
to decide on recommended content which
is a stuff we can work with that
another important element to achieve
user autonomy over data is
interoperability
if the european union really wants to
break the power of those data-driven
platforms
that monopolize the internet it needs
regulations that enables users to be in
control over the data
we believe that users should be able to
access data to download data to move
manipulate their data as they see
fit and part of that control is to board
data from one place to another
but data portability which we have under
the gdpr is not good enough
and we see from the gdpr that it's not
working in practice
users should be able to communicate with
friends across platform boundaries or to
be able to follow their favorite content
across
different platforms without having to
create several accounts
or to put it in other terms if you're
upset with the absence of privacy and
facebook or how the content
is moderated on facebook you should be
able to just take your data with you
using portability options and move to an
alternative platform that is a better
fit
and this without losing touch with your
friends who stay behind who have not
left the incumbent big platform
so what we did for digital services act
is to argue for
mandatory interoperability options that
would force facebook to maintain
apis that let users on other platforms
exchange
messages and content with facebook users
however however if you look in the dsa
we see that the commission completely
missed the mark on interoperability
which is supposed to be dealt with by a
related legal act and now it gets
complicated it's the digital markets act
the dma another beautiful acronym
the digital market act wants to tackle
certain harmful businesses practices by
those gatekeeper platforms they're very
large tech companies that control
what is called core services a core
service is a search engine a social
networking service a
messaging services operating systems and
online intermediation services
like think of how amazon controls access
to customers for merchants that sell on
its platforms or how the android and
iphone app stores
us chokepoints and delivering mobile
software
there are many things we like in the new
proposal that proposal on the digital
markets act
for example there's a ban on mixing data
in there
the dma wants to ban gatekeepers from
mixing data from data brokers with the
data they collect on the customers
another rule is to ban cross tying so
the practice that
end users must sign up for ancillary
services so you should be able to use
android
without having to get an email account
for example we believe that this is all
good
but the dma like the dsa is very weak on
interoperability
what it does is to focus on real-time
data
ability instead so instead of having
interoperable services users will only
be able to send their data from one
service to another
like from facebook to diaspora meaning
that you would end up having two
accounts instead of one
or the quote corey doctor who spoke
yesterday already
users would still be subject to the
sprawling garbage novella of abusive
legalese
facebook lovably calls its terms of
service
we believe that this is not good enough
um in the last slide you see a a quote
from margaret vestaia
um who made a very good statement last
month that we need trustworthy services
fair use of data and free speech and
interoperable internet
we fully agree on that and in the next
months and years we will work on this to
actually happen
however you can imagine it would not be
easy we already see that european union
member states
followed a trend that platforms should
systematically check undesirable and
insightful content and share those data
with enforcement authorities which is
even worse
we see an international trend going on
to move away from the immunity of
platform for user content
towards a more active stance of those
platforms and we see that
recent terror terror attacks have fewer
ideas that monitoring is a good idea and
that end
to end decryption is a problem
so whatever will be the result you can
bet the european union will want to make
the digital services act
and the digital markets act another
export model
so this time we want to have numbers
right in parliament and the council
and we want to help members of
parliament to press the right buttons
and for all this we will need your help
even if it means to learn yet another
acronym or several acronyms after the
gdpr
and that's it from our side we are
looking forward to the discussion thank
[Music]
you
okay thank you uh and um
and christoph um there are questions
from the internet
and the the first one is basically
be just hard and as you mentioned in
your slide sequence of the
copyright in the digital single market
with
both accountability and
liability provisions you also briefly
mentioned
i think even the evidence proposal also
how do all these proposals relate to
each other especially for a lay person
that is not into
all the brussels jargon
[Music]
unintentionally but yeah i kind of did
um i
i can start and then let you kristoff to
to step in um yeah that's a very
very good question um and this is
specifically due to the fact that
when you mention especially online
terrorist content regulation but also
a recently proposed interim regulation
on
child sexual abuse they
all these we call them sector
legislation so
kind of a little bit departing from
these horizontal approach
meaning um an approach that tackles all
categories of illegal content in one way
uh instead of going after specific
categories such as online terrorist
content
in the in the separate way so it's a
little bit paradoxical thing
uh what is currently also happening at
the eu level because on one hand we were
promised this systemic
regulation that will once for all
established harmonized approach to
combating illegal content online and at
the same time
which is specifically bsa the digital
services act
and at the same time we still see
european commission allowing for these
fundamental rights harmful legislative
proposals happening
in these specific sectors such as
proposed online terrorist content
regulation
or other legislative act seeking to
somehow regulate specific categories of
user-generated content
uh this is quite puzzling for us as a
digital rights activist too
very often actually and and so i would
maybe separate the essay from this for a
moment
and say that all of these sector
legislations what they have in common
is first of all continuing these
negative legislative trends that we
already described and that we constantly
observe in practice
such as shifting more and more
responsibility on online platforms
and at the same time what is also very
interesting what they have in common is
the legal basis that they stand on and
that's the legal basis that is rather
connected to the cooperation within the
digital single market
where even though they seek to tackle a
very particular
particular type of category of content
category which is manifestly
illegal so logically if they should
have that appropriate legal ground it
should be something more close to police
and judicial cooperation
which we don't see happening in practice
specifically
because there is this idea that
platforms are the best suited to decide
how the illegal content will be tackled
in the online space
they can be the fastest they can be the
most effective so they should actually
have that main decision making
powers and forced into taking those
responsibilities which however
ultimately according to the rule of law
principle
should and have to be in hands of the
state and public authorities
as preferably judicial authorities so
um i would say they are all
bad news for fundamental rights
protection of online users
civil rights organizations uh
all of us that are on the scope today
were fighting very hard
also against the online service content
regulation there was a lot of damage
control done
especially with the first report that
was tabled
by the european parliament and also now
during the last trilog
since the negotiation seems to be
concluded and the outcome is not great
it's far from ideal and i'm worried that
with other sector legislative attempts
coming from the european commission
we might see the same outcome it will be
very interesting to see
how that will actually then play
together with the digital services act
which is
trying to do the exact opposite to
actually fix this negative
uh legislative efforts that we see at
the eu level
with the sector legislation but also
with the member states at the national
level
um i could also mention the european
commission reaction to the nets to some
national legislative proposals but
christoph i will leave that to you
and please step in
i think you explained it perfectly the
only thing i can supplement here is that
if you look at this move from sector
legislation asylum legislation to
horizontal legislation now back to
sector legislation it's a problem it's a
mess
first the those files are very good
coordinated which brings in um
troubles for legal certainty it makes it
very troublesome for platforms to follow
up
and it's problematic for us for us in
the space
we are some sort of lobbyist as well
just for public interest
but if you have to deal with copyright
we see some with steric with
end-to-end encryption dsa dma and 15
other files that will pop up
content by content it's very hard to
manage to have the capacity ready
to be early in the debate and it's so
important to be early in the debate to
prevent the verse from happening and i
think that's a huge challenge for us to
that perhaps something for us to reflect
during the next days how can we join
forces better
in a more systematic way in order to
really follow up on all those
initiatives and that's for me a
a very problematic development
so in summary it's it's a mess
so it is related but we can't explain
how because it's such a mess
fair enough i have another question for
you elishka and that is
someone was asking how the proposed good
samaritan clause
works compared to how it currently works
in germany
but i think it's a bit unreasonable to
expect everyone to know how it works in
germany
i would rephrase it as how does this
proposed good samaritan clause work
compared to how it is now under the
e-commerce directive
thank you very much um yeah so uh
great question again i think the first
uh
if we put it into the context of the eu
law and
apologies that i cannot really answer
how you know compare the german context
i really don't dare to i'm not a german
lawyer so i wouldn't like to stop those
voters but
um first of all there is no good
samaritan clause per se
within the scope of e-commerce directive
it did not really
exist within the and i'm using the
the past sentence now because dsa is
trying to change that so
that level of legal uncertainty was not
really
really there for the platforms uh there
was the conditional model of the
liability which is still preserved
within the regulation
but the if we think of a good samaritan
clause as we know
it from the section 230 or let's use
that good samaritan clause as an example
because also e-commerce directive was
actually drafted as a response to
communication decency act that was the
legislation that puts things into
motions
um um so that's the that's the first
ultimate point
um i explained at the beginning in my
presentation
uh what was then happening in the space
of combating illegal content at the eu
level
um and especially i would refer to the
communication that the european
commission published i think back in
where it actually encouraged and called
on online platforms to proactively
engage with
illegal content and use this proactive
measure to actually seek and adequate
responses to lead to illegal content
now to mix that with this conditional
model of liability
uh which is of course defined by the
obtaining actual knowledge by the
platform that created a perfect storm
that i already explained so the
platforms knew that they are kind of
pushed by the legislator to actually
seek these active responses to illegal
content
often deploying automated measures but
they didn't have any legal certainty
or security on their side that if they
do so they won't end up ultimately being
held legally liable and face legal
consequences as a result of obtaining
actual knowledge
through those proactive measures that
were kind of the the tool how they could
possibly actually obtain that knowledge
um now uh what dsa does
it specifically actually simply states
and i think it's article 6
in the digital services act if i'm not
mistaken and i can even open it
it specifically basically says that that
platforms can
use these proactive measures or you know
uh
continue um using some tools that
uh actually uh seek to provide some
responses to this type of content
without the fear of being held liable
so it's a it's an article which has
approximately i think two paragraphs
um but it's finally in the legislation
and that means that it will help to
reinforce the level of legal certainty
i would also emphasize that very often
in europe when we discuss good samaritan
clause and good samaritan is actually a
very unfortunate
term because it's very much connected to
the american legal
tradition but when it's being mixed up
with the conditional model of liability
and with the prohibition of general
monitoring which is still
upheld and these are the main principles
of the european intermediary reliability
law
and the regime that is applicable within
the eu
such a safeguard can be actually
beneficial and it won't
lead hopefully to these blanket blanket
immunity for online
platforms or to this idea that platforms
will be able to do whatever they want
with the illegal content without any
public scrutiny
because there are other measures
safeguards and principles in place as a
part of conditional model of liability
that we have here in europe
um so i'm sorry maybe that was too
complicated legalistic explanation there
um but this how this is how these
provisions should work in practice we of
course have to wait
uh for the implementation of the law and
see how that will turn out
but the main purpose is that this legal
certainty that was lacking until now can
finally come to its existence
which should help us to prevent over
removal of legitimate speech from
online platforms
okay thank you um i've two other
questions
from the internet about interoperability
and i suppose
i should look at crystal for them um
the the last one i'm going to ask first
is
would such interoperability make it's
much more difficult
to ha to combat harassment and stalking
on the internet
how do you police that kind of
misbehavior if it's across
different platforms were forced to
interoperate and also
be conduits for such bad behavior
and i'll come to the earlier question
after you've answered this question uh
christoph
it's a good question um first to
understand our vision on
interoperability
um is to understand that we
would like to have it between platforms
that are in power
large platforms and the right
of smaller platforms actually to um
make use of interoperability so it
should not be among the big platforms
so small platforms should be able to
connect to the big platforms and second
we believe
it will help and not make it worse
because
we have not a problem of hate speech of
with not a problem of a lack of privacy
we have now the problem
that um of the attention industry that
works
with um you know certain pictures are
putting certain frames to trigger the
attention of users um because users
don't have a choice of a content
moderation practices users don't have a
choice to see which kind of content
will be shown and users don't have
options to
regulate the privacy the idea of more
competitors would be exactly that i can
move to a space where i'm not
harassed and not be made subject to
to certain um content that hurt my
feelings right
and that moment i got to get control i
can choose
a provider that gives me those options
and we would like even to go a step
further
um back end of interoperability is
faster start
we believe if users want to they should
be able to delegate a third-party
company or a piece of a third-party
software to interact with a platform on
their behalf
so users would have the option to see a
news feed in different order
calibrate their own filters on
misinformation
so in this sense interoperability can be
a great tool actually to tackle
um hate speech and those sort of
negative developments
of course there's a risk to it i think
the risk comes from rather from the data
um industry side again that we need to
take care not to place one
or another data selling industry on the
one that we already face
um but for this we have options as well
to avoid that from happening
but to answer the question we believe
interoperability is a tool actually do
to escape from the negative developments
you had mentioned
um critical counter question for me dan
aren't you actually advocating for just
all your own recommendation engines
to be able to do so and can't you
achieve that without interoperability
sure um recount a question do you think
and ever choose i can accomplish that
quite easily
um you know like when we look at
the internet through the lenses of
market competition then we see that it
is the dominance of platforms over data
that have created those um those spaces
those bullet gardens where users have to
feeling their trap you cannot escape
from
and there are so many alternative
options that cannot get off ground
because users
feel trapped don't want to leave their
friends behind and don't have options
actually do you have a better moderation
system
of course you can be creative and you
know use plugins on whatever you see fit
but
you need to stay within the platform
barriers what we would like to enable
users is to
actually leave the wallet garden go to
another place
but still stay in touch with friends who
have made a choice to remain there
and i think that's perhaps the
difference to what you had in mind
i have a follow-up question well another
question from the internet regarding iso
mobility
and that is historically speaking
as soon as the big players get involved
in setting standards they tend to also
shape policy by
being involved in that how would that be
different
in the case of interoperability and uh
it's specifically mentioned
by the uh the person who asked the
question that mastodon probably fuller
issues because nobody else was involved
in setting that standard
it's an excellent question and we
struggle the
the question of standards ourselves um
now a policy paper
which is our recommendations for the
european union to enact
certain provisions in the judicial
services act
um we abstain from asking to
establish new standards like api
standards we believe it's a bad idea
to regulate technology like that what we
want to do is that
big platforms just offer
interoperability
however they see fit we don't want to
have a standard that can be
either again monopolized or lobbied by
the big platforms
because then we end up with the
standards we already see which
which we don't like but it's a good
question and
what we did is with our policy
principles on interoperability to give
kind of a food for thought how we
believe
the end version should look like um
but there are many questions that remain
and we don't know exactly
how to go there
yeah and i'm sorry i'm sticking to the
topic of interoperability because
most questions are actually about that
one of the other questions is
um how do we prevent this from be
getting messed up like it happens if
peers do
psd psd2 and for the audience that don't
know about psd2
pg2 is a directive that forced banks to
open up the apis to other financial
service providers
which is also interoperability between
platforms in this case for banking
platforms
which comes with all sorts of privacy
questions that parents
completely thought through when that
legislation came about
sorry for having this long-winded
interaction in the crystal that's
i think it was needed for for people
that don't know what psd2 means
it's a good question interestingly we
never use psd2 or the telecommunications
act because both have
interoperability options as those
negative examples we always use it as
examples that hey it's already
possible so you don't have an excuse to
say it's impossible to put it in the law
what is true is that there's a lot of
mess around it and the question
of how do volumes is a question of
um that's politically again um so the
question of whether policymakers are
actually listening listening to us
or listening to industry lobbyists so
the the one who raised their questions
absolutely right there's a huge risk for
every topic we talk about but it's
interoperability whether it's
user control over content and targeted
ads
liability everything that we believe
should be in law of course
could be hijacked could be
redesigned in a way that it will lead to
more problems than fewer problems
um so indeed for every policy question
we raise we need to ask ourselves is it
worth the fight to be risk open in the
box of the pandora do we make it worse
would be sad as um on that front
we are happy to make pressure and what
we need to do in the next series is to
convince them that we are the right
person to talk to
and that's perhaps a challenge how to
make tech explicable
to um policymakers so those who ask the
questions i think those should
should help us to come to process to the
parliament and tell energies how it's
going to work
on that note question to both of you
you said citizen involvement i prefer
the term citizen of users
would it be helpful to push for a
maintenance in the parliament
for at least the the targeting
points you both mentioned before and if
so how so um uh i guess that i will
start just so christoph can
rest a little um so the question was
whether it would be useful to push for
those amendments was that
for amendments that cover targeting of
of citizens
absolutely um so there is of course
short and long answer
as to every question and so the short
answer would be
yes but given that the wording of such
an amendment will be precise and nuanced
uh we are still working out our
positioning on online targeting and i
think we all
uh no one can name those practices that
we don't want to see being deployed by
platforms and where we can actually
imagine a proper ban on such practices
we have recently published one of our
blog posts where we actually
um unfold the way of thinking
uh that access now currently you know
how we are brainstorming about this
whole issue
and as i said especially those that's
targeting that uses behavioral data
of users citizens then maybe let's go
for individuals because states are also
obliged to protect rights of
individuals that are not their citizens
um
so i uh that that's definitely one form
where we can definitely see and will be
supporting the ban and possible face out
that will actually lead to a ban
the same goes for the uh cross-site
tracking of users
and uh due to the fact how users
data are being abused again as it's
being the integral
integral part of the business models of
this platform and so on and so forth
um so that's one of the direction we
will be definitely taking and again
we are inviting all of you to help us
out to brainstorm together with us to
assess different options directions that
we should take into consideration
and not forget about uh but i personally
think
that this will be one of the main
battles when it comes to dsa
where we will definitely need to be on
the same page and harmonize and join the
forces
because dsa gives us a good ground at
the moment but it doesn't go far enough
and so uh yes definitely the answer is
yes but given that we will have a very
nuanced position so we know what we are
asking for and we are taking into
consideration
also those other aspects that could
eventually
play out uh badly in practice so
good intentions are not enough when it
comes to dsa
thank you we sli running slightly over
time but i've been told beforehand
that's okay that they do so
for a few minutes and there's three
questions that are open one of
one of them i will answer myself that is
basically half the member states
responded and the answer to that is no
the member states have not taken any
position
and two others i think are quite
interestingly important from our techie
perspective
one is is there anything you see that
might affect current decentralized
platforms like the fedivers macedon
and the other is will
any review of the data protection uh
sorry the database
uh protection directive uh affect meta
search engines and interactivities again
perhaps i jump in english can you take
over um
first member states have given opinion
actually on the dsa
they've been one two official
submissions plus joint letters
plus discussions in council and where
the dsa was presented
i have some nice protocols which show
the different attitude of member states
towards it um
so for us it also means we need to work
straight away with the council
to ensure that the package would be good
what was the question i guess um i think
the
the answer to the question depends on
the um what lawyers call materials cope
applications whether it would apply to
those platform models at all
and perhaps initially can help me out
here we have always criticized
for the e-commerce directive that it was
not quite clear how it would relate to
first non-for-profit uh platforms and
many of those alternative platforms are
like that
because there was this issue of
providing a service against remuneration
and it was not quite clear what it means
would it apply to wikipedia if you get
like donation would it apply to a
blogger
if you have like pop-ups of you know ads
or something like that
so that's i think one huge question and
the second question is in as much those
new due diligence obligation
would force alternative platforms um
governance models to redesign the
interfaces
and those are open question for us we
have not analyzed that in detail but we
see that
we have worried that it would not only
impact the large platforms but many
others as well
what do you think alicia yeah i can i
can only agree
um especially regarding the non-profit
question
um yeah this is also or was and always
been one of our main asks for
non-profit organizations um and actually
it's not quite clear how that will play
out now in practice with the way how dsa
is standing because at the moment it
actually speaks about online platforms
and then it speaks about very large
online platform
but what it will be and how it will
impact non-profit organizations whether
these are broker bloggers or
organizations like civil rights
organizations
um uh that remain to be to be
seen and i also know that the european
court of human rights and its
jurisprudence tried to
establish some principles for the
non-profit uh
since delphi vs estonia and then with
the
mte decision and the swedish case that
followed afterwards
um but i'm not sure how well it was
actually elaborated later on
um but this is something we will be
definitely looking at and working on
further
um and regarding the impact on the
smaller players
and the also the
the interface idea this is still
something we are
actually also wondering about um
and thinking how this will turn out in
practice and
um we are hoping to actually develop our
positioning further on these issues as
well because
um we actually started working all of us
uh
on dsa and on our recommendations
already i think a year ago maybe a year
and a half ago
uh when we were working just with the
leagues that political or other
uh media platforms in brussels were
actually sharing with us and we were
working with the bits and pieces and
trying to put our thinking together
now we have the draft and i think we
need to do another round of very
detailed thinking and
what will be ultimately our position or
what will be those recommendations and
amendments in the european parliament we
will be supporting and pushing for
so it's a it's a period of a hard work
for all of us
not mentioning that i always say that um
you know we stand against a huge lobby
power
uh that is going to be you know and is
constantly being exercised by these
uh private actors and but i also have to
say that we had a very good cooperation
with the european commissions throughout
the process and i think that i can say
that on behalf of all of us
that we feel that european commission
really listen this time
so um yeah more question marks than
answers here from me i think
that's okay with me not knowing
something is fine i think you
definitely run out of time thank you
both for being here
and um well enjoy the the 2d
online board as a congress thank you
that wraps up this session of us thank
you all
thank you very much bye
wow
bye