[Music]
[Applause]
all right so again
let's um introduce the next talk
accessible inputs for readers
coders and hackers the talk by david
williams king about
custom off well not off the shelf but
custom accessibility solutions
he will give you some demonstrations and
that includes his own custom-made voice
input and eyelid bling system
here is david williams king
thank you for the introduction um let's
go ahead and get started so yeah i'm
talking about accessibility particularly
accessible input for readers coders and
hackers
so what do i mean by accessibility i
mean
people that have physical or motor
impairments this could be due to
repetitive strain injury carpal tunnel
all kinds of medical
conditions if you have this type of
thing you probably can't use a normal
computer keyboard computer mouse
or even a phone touch screen
however technology does allow users to
interact with these devices just using
different forms of input
and it's really valuable to these people
because
you know being able to interact with a
device provides some agency
they can they can do things on their own
and it provides a means of communication
with the outside world
so it's an important problem to look at
and
it's one i care about a lot let's talk a
bit about me for a moment i'm a
systems security person i did a phd in
cyber security at columbia if you're
interested in low-level
software defenses you can look that up
and i'm currently
the cto at a startup called alpha secure
i i started developing medical issues in
around 2014
and as a result of that in an ongoing
fashion i can only type a few thousand
keystrokes per day roughly 15 000 is my
maximum
that sounds like a lot but imagine
you're typing at 100 words per minute
that's 500 characters per minute which
means
it takes you 30 minutes to hit 15 000
characters
so essentially i
i can work like the equivalent of a fast
programmer for for half an hour
and then after that i would be unable to
use my hands for anything including like
you know preparing food for myself or
opening and closing doors and so on so i
have to
be very careful about my hand use and i
actually have a little program that you
can see on the slide there
that measures the keystrokes for me so i
can tell when i'm going over
um so what do i do well i do a lot of
pair programming
for sure i log into the same machine as
other people and we work together
i'm also a very heavy user of speech
recognition and
i gave a talk at that about voice coding
with speech recognition
at the hope 11 conference so you can go
check that out if you're interested
so when i talk about accessible input i
mean
different ways that a human can provide
input to a computer so
ergonomic keyboards are a simple one
speech recognition
eye tracking or gaze tracking so you can
see where
where you're looking or where you're
pointing your head and maybe use that to
replace a mouse
that's head gestures i suppose and
there's always this distinction between
bespoke like custom input mechanisms and
somewhat mainstream ones so
i'll give you some examples you've
probably heard of stephen hawking
he's a very famous professor and he was
actually a bit of an extreme case he had
he was diagnosed with als when he was 21
so his his physical abilities degraded
over the years because he lived for many
decades after that
and he went through many communication
mechanisms initially
his speech changed so that it was only
intelligible to his family and close
friends
um but he was still able to speak and
then after that
he would uh work with a human
interpreter and raise his eyebrows
to pick various letters and then
and keep in mind this is like the 60s or
70s right so
computers were not really where they are
today
later he would operate a switch with one
hand just like on off on off
kind of morse code and select from a
bank of words
and that was around 15 words per minute
uh eventually he was unable to move his
hand so
a team of engineers from intel worked
with him and they figured out
they were trying to do like brain scans
and all kinds of stuff but again this
was
like in the 80s so there was uh not uh
not too much they could do so they
basically just created
um some custom software to to detect
muscle movements in his cheek
and he used that with predictive um
predictive words the same way that a
phone
smartphone keyboard will predict like
which word you want to say next
stephen hawking used something similar
to that except instead of swiping on a
phone
he was moving his uh his cheek muscles
so that's obviously a sequence of like
highly customized
input mechanisms for for someone and
very very specialized for that person
i also want to talk about someone else
named professor song mukli
whom i i've met that was me when i had
more of a beard than i do now um
he uh he's a professor at seoul national
university in south korea
and he he sometimes called like
the korean stephen hawking because he's
a big advocate for people with
disabilities and whatnot
anyway what he uses is you can see a
little orange device near his mouth
there
he it's called a sip and puff mouse so
he can blow into it
and suck air through it and also move it
around and that acts as a mouse
cursor on the android device in front of
him it will uh
move the cursor around and click when he
when he blows air and so on um
so that combined with speech recognition
lets him use
mainstream android hardware right he
still has access to
you know email apps and like web
browsers
and like maps and everything that comes
on a normal android device so
he's way more capable than stephen
hawking was because stephen hawking
could
communicate but just to a person at a
very slow rate right
part of us due to the nature of his
injury but it's also
a testament to how far the technology
has improved
um so let's talk a little bit about what
makes good accessibility uh
i think performance is very important
right you want high accuracy you don't
want typos
low latency i don't want to speak and
then five seconds later have words
appear
it's too it's too long um especially if
i have to make corrections right
and you want high throughput which we
already talked about oh i forgot to
mention stephen hawking had like you
know 15 words per minute
a normal person speaking is 150 so
that's a big difference the higher
throughput you can get the better
and for input accessibility i think and
this is not scientific this is just what
i've
learned from using myself and observing
many of these systems i think it's
important to get
completeness consistency and
customization
for completeness i mean can i do any
action so
stephen or um uh professor sung mukli
uh his his uh orange
mouth input device the sip and puff is
quite powerful but it doesn't let him do
every action for example for some reason
when he gets an incoming call
the the input doesn't work so he has to
call over a person physically to like
tap the accept call button or the reject
call button
which is really annoying right if you
don't have completeness you can't be
fully independent
um consistency very important as well
the same way we develop
motor memory for a muscle memory for a
keyboard
you develop memory for any types of
patterns that you do but if the thing
you say or the thing you do keeps
changing
in order to do the same action that's
not good
and finally customization so the
learning curve for beginners is
important for any accessibility device
but
designing for expert use is almost more
important because
anyone who uses an accessibility
interface becomes an expert at it
the example i like to give is screen
readers like a blind person
using a screen reader on a phone they
will crank up the speed at which
the speech is being produced
and i actually met someone who made his
speech 16 times
faster than normal human speech i could
not understand it at all instead of like
but he could understand it perfectly and
that's just because he used it so much
that he'd become an expert
at its use um let's analyze ergonomic
keywords just for a moment because it's
fun
uh you know they are kind of like a
normal keyboard they'll have a
you'll have a slow pace when you're
starting to learn them but once you're
good at it
you have very good accuracy like
instantaneous low latency right you
press a key
the computer receives it immediately and
very high throughput
is as high as you are on a regular
keyboard
so they're actually fantastic
accessibility devices right they're
completely compatible with original
keyboards
and if all you need is an ergonomic
keyboard then you're in luck because
it's a very good accessibility device
um i'm going to talk about two things
computers but also android devices so
let's
start with android devices um
yes the built-in voice recognition in
android is really incredible so even
though the microphones on
the devices aren't great google has just
collected so much data from so many
different sources
that they've built like better than
human accuracy for
for their voice recognition the voice
accessibility interface
is kind of so-so we'll talk about that
in a bit that's the interface where you
can control the android device entirely
by voice
for other input mechanisms you could use
like a sip and puff device
or you could use physical styluses um
that's something that i do a lot
actually because for me
my fingers get sore and if i can hold a
stylus in my hand
and kind of not use my fingers then
that's
you know very effective so and the
elecom styluses from a japanese company
are
the lightest i've found and they don't
require a lot of force so the
ones at the top there are um
they're like 12 grams and the one the
bottom is 4.7 grams and
you require almost no force to use them
so very nice on the left there you can
see
the android speech recognition is built
into the keyboard now right
you can just press that and start
speaking it supports different languages
and it's very accurate it's very nice
and actually
when i was working at google for a bit i
talked to the speech recognition team
and i was like
why are you doing on server speech
recognition you should do it on the
devices
but of course android devices are
they're all very different and many of
them are not very powerful so they were
having trouble getting
um satisfactory speech recognition on
the device so for a long time
there's some server latency server lag
right you do speech recognition and you
wait a bit
and then sometime this year i just was
using speech recognition and it became
so much faster i was extremely excited
and i looked into it and
yeah they just switched on my device at
least they switched on the on-device
speech recognition model and so now it's
incredibly fast and also incredibly
accurate i'm a huge fan of it
um on the right hand side we can
actually see the voice access interface
so this is meant
to allow you to use a phone entirely by
voice again while i was at google i
tried
the beta version before it was publicly
released and i was like this is pretty
bad
um mostly because it didn't it lacked
completeness
there would be things on the screen that
would not be selected so here we see
show labels and then i can i can say
like four five six whatever to tap
on that thing but as you can see at the
bottom there's like a twitter web app
link
and there's no number on it so if i want
to click on that i'm out of luck
and this is actually a problem in the
design of
the accessibility interface it it only
it doesn't expose the full dom
it exposes only um a subset of it and so
an accessibility mechanism can't ever
see those other
things um and furthermore
the way the google speech recognition
works they have to re-establish a new
connection every 30 seconds
um and if you're in the middle of
speaking it will just throw away
whatever you were saying because it just
decided it had to reconnect
which is really unfortunate um they
later released that publicly and then
sometime this year they did an update
update which is pretty nice it now has
like a
a mouse grid which lets which solves a
lot of the completeness problems like
you can
you can use a grid to narrow down
somewhere on the screen and then tap
there
um but the server issues and the
uh like expert use is still not good
like okay if i want to
turn up if i want to do something with
the mouse grid i have to say mouse grid
on
six five mouse grid off and i can't
combine those together so there's a lot
of latency
and it's not really that fun to use but
uh
better than nothing absolutely um
i just want to really briefly show you
as well that this same feature of like
being able to select
links on a screen is available on
desktops this is a plug-in for chrome
called vimium
and it's very powerful because you can
then combine this with
keyboards or other input mechanisms and
this one is complete
it uses the entire dom and anything you
can click on will be highlighted so it's
very nice
i just want to give a quick example of
me using some of these systems so
i've been trying to learn japanese and
there's a couple of highly regarded
websites for this but they're not
consistent
when i use the browser show labels like
you know the the thing to press
next page or something like that or like
you know i give up or whatever
is it keeps changing so the the letters
that are being used keep changing and
that's because of the dynamic way that
they're generating the html
so not really very useful what i do
instead is i use
a program called anki and that has very
simple shortcuts in his desktop app one
two three four
so it's nice to use and consistent and
it syncs with an android app and then i
can use my stylus on the android device
so it works pretty well but even so
you know as you can see from the chart
on the bottom there there are many days
when i can't use this even though i
would like to because i've overused my
hands
or i've overused my voice um when i'm
using voice recognition all day every
day i do tend to lose my voice and as
you can see from the graph sometimes i
lose it for like
a week or two at a time so same thing
with any accessibility interface you
know
you've got to use many different
techniques and
it's always it's never perfect it's just
the best you can do at that moment
um something else i like to do is read
books i read a lot of books
and um i love ebook readers you know the
dedicated e-ink displays
you can read them in sunlight they last
forever battery-wise um
unfortunately it's hard to add like
other input mechanisms to them they
don't have microphones or other sensors
and you can't really install custom
software on them but for android-based
devices
and they're also like ebook reading apps
for android devices
they have everything you can install
custom software and they have
microphones and many other
sensors so i made two apps that allow
you to read
ebooks with an ebook reader the first
one is voice next page
it's based on one of my speech
recognition engine called sylvias
and it does do server based recognition
so you have to capture all the audio
use 300 kilobits a second to send it to
the server
and recognize things like next page
previous page
um however it doesn't cut out every 30
seconds
it keeps going so that's that's one one
win for it i guess
and it uh it is published in the play
store
huge thanks to sarah leventhal who did a
lot of the implementation
very complicated to make an
accessibility app on android but
we persevered and works quite nicely so
i'm going to actually show you an
example of voice next page
this is uh this over here this is my
phone
on the left hand side just captured so
that you guys can see it so here's the
voice next page
and um basically the connection is green
i can do the the servers up and running
and so on i just press start and then
i'll switch to
an android reading app and say next page
previews page i won't
speak otherwise because it will it will
chapel everything i'm saying
next page next page
previous page
center center
foreground stop listening
so that's the demo of the voice next
page and it's extremely helpful i i've
built i built it a couple of years ago
along with sarah
and i use it a lot um so yeah you can go
ahead and download it if you guys want
to try it out
and the other one is called blink next
page so the idea for this
i got this idea from a research paper
this year that was
studying eyelid gestures um i didn't
use any of their code but it's a great
idea so the way this works is
you detect blinks by using the android
camera
and then you can trigger an action like
turning pages in an ebook reader
this actually doesn't need any
networking it's able to use the on
device
face recognition models from google and
it is still under development so it's
not on the play store yet
but uh it is working and uh
you know please contact me if you want
to try it so just give me
one moment to set that demo up here and
so i'm going to use the the main problem
with this
the main problem with this current
implementation is that it uses two
devices
so that was easier to implement and i
use two devices anyway
but obviously i want a
a one device version if i'm actually
going to use it for anything so here's
how this works
this device i point at me at my eyes the
other device i put wherever it's
convenient to read
oops sorry and if i blink my eyes
the phone will buzz once it detects that
i've blinked my eyes and it will turn
the page automatically
on the other android device
now i have to blink both my eyes for
half a second if i want to go
backwards i can blink just my left eye
and if i want to go forwards like
quickly i can blink my right eye
and hold it
anyway um it does have some false
positives that's why like
you can go backwards in case it detects
that you've accidentally
flipped the page and lighting is also
very important like if i have a light
behind me
then this is not going to be able to
identify whether my eyes are open or
closed properly
so it has some limitations but very
um very simple to use so
i'm a big fan
uh okay so that's enough about android
devices let's talk
very briefly about desktop computers so
if you're going to use
a desktop computer of course try using
that show labels plug-in in a browser
for native apps you can try dragon
naturally speaking
which is fine if you're just like using
basic things but if you're trying to do
complicated things you should definitely
use a voice coding system
you could also consider using eye
tracking to replace a mouse i
personally i don't use that i find it
hurts my eyes but i do use a
trackball with very little force and a
welcome tablet
some people will even scroll up and down
by humming for example but i
don't have that setup there's a bunch of
nice talks out there on voice coding
the top left is tavis red's talk from
many years ago that got many of us
interested
emily shia gave a talk there um about
like
best practices for voice coding and then
i gave a talk a couple years ago
at the the hope 11 conference which you
can also check out
um it's mostly out of date by now but
it's still interesting
so there are a lot of voice coding
systems
the um sort of grandfather of the mall
is
dragonfly it's become a great grammar
standard
caster is if you're willing to memorize
lots of
unusual words you can become much better
much faster than i currently am at voice
coding
aenea is how you originally used dragon
to work on a linux machine for example
because
dragon only runs on windows talon is a
closed source
program which is uh but it's very
very powerful has a big user base
especially for mac os there are ports
now
and talon used to use dragon but it's
now using
a speech system from facebook
um sylvia's is the system that i created
the models are not very accurate but
it's a nice
architecture where there's client server
so it makes it easy to build things like
the voice next page
so the voice next page was using soleus
and then
the the most recent one i think on this
list is keldi active grammar
which is extremely powerful and
extremely customizable and it's also
open source
it works on all platforms so i i really
highly recommend that so let's talk a
bit more about county active grammar
but first um for voice coding i've
already mentioned you have to be careful
how you use your voice right
breathe from your belly don't don't
tighten your muscles and breathe from
your chest try to speak normally
and i'm not particularly good at this
like you'll hear me when i'm speaking
commands
my inflection changes so i do tend to
overuse my voice but
uh yeah yeah i just have to be conscious
of that the microphone hardware does
matter
i do recommend like a blue yeti on a
microphone arm that you can pull and put
close to your
close to your face like this i'll use
this one for my speaking demo
and uh yeah and the other thing is your
grammar is fully customizable so
if you keep saying a word and the system
doesn't recognize it just change it to
another word
and um it's complete in the sense you
can type any key on the keyboard
and the most important thing for expert
use or customizability is that
you can do chaining so with a voice
coding system you can say multiple
commands at once
uh if there's and it's a huge time
savings you'll see what i mean when i uh
when i give a quick demo um when i do
voice coding i'm a very heavy vim and
t-mux user
um you know they've been
i've worked with many people before so i
have some cheat sheet information there
so if you're interested you can go check
that out
but yeah let's just do a quick demo of
voice code in here
turn this mic on desk left two
control delta open new terminal charlie
delta space
slash tango micropapa enter command vim
hotel hotel point charlie papa papa
enter
india hash word include space langle
in the oscar word stream wrangle enter
enter
indianoi tango space word main
nope mike arch indianoi lan ran space
lace enter interrace up tab
word print fox scratch nope
code standard charlie oscar uniform
tango space language space
quote sentence hello voice coding bang
scratch six delta india golfbang
backslash
quote semicolon act
skyfox mike romeo noi oscar word return
space number zero semicolon act
vim save and quit golf plus plus space
hotel hotel tab minus oscar space hotel
hotel
enter point slash hotel hotel enter
desk right too
so that's just a quick example of voice
coding um
you can use it to write any programming
language you can use it to control
anything on your desktop it's uh very
powerful
it has a bit of a learning curve but
it's very powerful
so the creator of county active grammar
is also named david
i'm named david but just a coincidence
um
and he's he says of county active
grammar that
um i haven't typed with a keyboard in
many years
and cal deactor grammar is bootstrapped
in that i have
been developing it entirely using the
previous versions of it
so uh david has a
medical condition that means he has very
low dexterity so it's hard for him to
use a keyboard and yeah he basically
got cal deactive grammar working through
the skin of his teeth or something
and then continues to develop it using
it and
yeah i i'm a huge fan of the project i
haven't contributed much but i did give
some of
the hardware resources like gpu and cpu
compete compute resources
to allow training to happen um but i
would also like to show you a video of
david using caldi active grammar
just so you can see it as well
so the other thing about david is that
he has
um he has a speech impediment or a
speech
i don't know an accent or whatever so
it's difficult to
for a normal speech recognition system
to understand him and you might have
trouble understanding him here but you
can see in the lower right
what the speech system understands that
he's saying
oh i realized that i do need to switch
something in obs so that you guys can
hear it sorry
there we go tab
number one simple camera space
number one on one content line
control shift enter text
okay one assignment apostrophe
account for entering two times okay
space
anyway you get the idea and hopefully
you guys are able to hear that if not
you can also find this on the website
that i'm going to show you at the end
oh one other thing i want to show you
about this is
david has actually set up this humming
to scroll which i think is pretty cool
of course i've gone and turned off the
obs there but he's basically
and it's understanding that and uh and
scrolling down so
something that i'm able to do with my uh
my trackball but that he's
using his voice for so it's pretty cool
um so i'm almost done here in summary
good input accessibility means you need
completeness consistency and
customization you need to be able to do
any action that you could do
with the other input mechanisms and
doing the same input should have the
same action
and remember your users will become
experts so
the system needs to be designed for that
for ebook reading
um yes we're trying i'm trying to allow
anyone to read even if they're
experiencing some severe physical or
motor impairment
because i think that gives you a lot of
power to be able to turn the pages
and read your favorite books and for
speech recognition yeah
android speech recognition is very good
silvius
accuracy is not so good but it's easy to
use quickly for experimentation
and to make other types of things like
the voice next page
and please do check out cali active
grammar if you have some serious need
for voice recognition
um lastly i put all this onto a website
voxhub dot io so you can see voice next
page
blink next page cody active grammar uh
and so on just instructions for how to
use it and how to set it up
so please do check that out and
tons of acknowledgements lots of people
that have helped me along the way but i
want to especially
call out professor song mugli who
actually invited me to korea a couple of
times
to give talks uh a big inspiration and
of course david zero has actually been
able to bootstrap
into a fully voice coding environment so
that's all i have for today
thank you very much
right um i suppose i'm back on the air
so
let me see uh i want to remind everyone
before we go into the q a
that um you can ask your questions
for this talk on irc the link is under
the video or you can use twitter or the
fetiverse with the hashtag
rc32 again i'll hold it up here rc
number three two and um
wow thanks for your talk david that was
really interesting thanks for talking
david um
i yeah
i think we have a couple of questions
from the signal angels
um before that i just want to say i
recently spent some time playing with a
like the voice over system in ios and
that can now actually tell you what is
on a photo
which is kind of amazing oh by the way i
can't hear you
here on on the marvel yeah sorry i
wasn't saying anything
uh yeah no it's it's so i focus mostly
on input accessibility right which is
like how do you get data to the computer
but there's been huge improvements in
the other way around as well right the
computer
yeah so we have about let's see five six
minutes left at least
for q a we have a question by toby plus
plus he asks your next page application
looks cool do you have statistics of how
many people use it or
found it on the app store
uh not very many the voice next page was
advertised
only so far as a little academic poster
so i've gotten a few people to use it
but i run eight concurrent workers
and we've never hit more than that
so not super not super popular but i do
hope that some people will see it
because of this talk and go and check
that's cool uh
next question how error prone are the
speech recognition systems
at all e.g can you do coding while doing
workouts
so one thing about speech recognition is
very sensitive to the microphone so
when you're doing it
[Music]
any mistakes right that's the thing
about having low latency you just say
something
and you watch it and you make sure that
it was what you wanted to say
i don't know exactly how many words per
second words per minute i can say with
voice coding but i can say it much
faster than regular speech so i would
say at least like 200 maybe 300 words
per minute so it's actually a very high
bandwidth that's pretty awesome
a question from pepe j and devos
any advice for software authors to make
their stuff more accessible
um there's there are good web
accessibility guidelines
so if you're just making a website or
something i would definitely follow
those
they tend to be focused more on people
that are blind because
that is you know it's more of an obvious
fail like they just can't interact at
all with your website
um but things like you know if
if duolingo for example had used the
same
like a the same accessibility um access
tag on their like
next button then i would they would
always be the same letter for me and i
wouldn't have to be like
fox charlie fox delta fox something
changes all the time so i think i think
consistency is very important
and integrating with any existing
accessibility apis is also very
important
web apis android apis and so on because
you know we can't make every program out
there like voice compatible we just have
to
meet in the middle where they interact
at the keyboard layer or the awesome
american has a question uh wonders if
these systems use similar approaches
like stenography
with mnemonics or if there's any
projects working having that in mind
a very good question so
the first thing everyone uses is the
nato phonetic alphabet to spell letters
for example
alpha bravo charlie some people
then will substitute letters for things
that are too long like november
i use noi sometimes the speech system
doesn't understand you
whenever i said alpha dragon was like oh
you're saying offer
so i changed it it's arch for me arch
brav char
um so and also
most of these grammars are in a common
grammar format they are written in
python and they're compatible with
dragonfly
so you can grab a grammar for i don't
know for a nia and get it to work with
county active grammar with very little
effort
i actually have a grammar that works on
both aenea
and kelly active grammar and that's what
i use
so there's a bit of lingua franca i
guess you can kind of guess what other
people are using but at the same time
there's a lot of customization you know
um because because people change words
they add their own commands
they change words based on what the
speech system understands ellie b
asks is there an online community you
can propose for accessibility
technologies
um there's a there's an amazing forum
for anything related to voice coding
all the developers of new voice coding
software are there
sorry to see a drink
so it's a really fantastic resource i do
link to it from
voxhub dot io i believe it's at the
bottom of the cali active grammar
page so you can definitely check that
out for general accessibility
um i don't know i could recommend the
accessibility
mailing list at google but that's only
if you work at google other than that
um yeah i think it depends on your
community right i
i think if you're looking for web
accessibility you could go for some
mozilla mailing lists and so on if
you're looking for desktop accessibility
then maybe you could go find some stuff
about uh the the windows
speech api and the ones one last
question from joe nielsen
could there be legal issues if you make
an e-book into
audio i'm not sure what that refers to
yeah so if you are like doing uh you
if you're using a screen reader and you
like you know try get it to read out the
contents of a uh
of an e-book right so
most most of the time there are fair use
exceptions for copyright law
um even in the u.s and
making a copy of yourself for for
personal purposes
so that you can access it is usually
considered fair use
um if you if you were trying to
commercialize it or make money off of
that or like
i don't know you're a famous streamer
and all you do is highlight text and
have it read it out
then maybe but i would say that that
definitely falls under fair use
all right so i guess that's it for the
talk i think we're
hitting the timing mark really well
thank you so much david for
that that was really really interesting
i learned a lot and
thanks everyone for watching and uh stay
on i think there might be some news
coming up thanks
and everyone
wow