and so we are starting
to switch into the english language and
i
start to present my slides afterwards
after the slides we will go into a
little workshop and hands on
with you together hopefully yeah and
let's have some fun on the devices well
some things about me my name is andre
halen
i was born in the 80s in berlin
and i'm a member of this ebay since 2001
and since a couple of years also on the
board of
vst based yeah i'm working as a system
and
cloud engineer so this means i have very
many things to do with automations
and um home automation is my personal
favorite here yeah an ethical hacker who
breaks
only his own things i don't do any
really
bad uh only
an accident
um yeah i started
back in 2014 with just quite simple
things like uh turning my digital
light marks on and off and changing the
color so
this was quite simple in the beginning
but later i started
to do more things away from the
window applications and i would like to
enable you today to do the same
what we expect um
first of all i started with this around
30 minutes
intro about home automation in general
some hardware aspects some
software aspects um i would like to do
some definitions and wording because
this can
be getting very confusing later
and after this small talk we will
have a hands-on hopefully we
have one and a half hour or more and
around
we will integrate together if you
already have
exiting hardware that is capable to be
integrated we can do this or if you
don't have any hardware yet
don't be sad we can fake them or
find other interesting digital stuff
that we can integrate into your home
automation
and yeah we will for sure chat about
automation in general
share our experience we love each other
so smart what
what means smart or what people think
is smart is a really huge web usually
because people it's not everything
remote stuff is plug and play and
everything
work for everything you need you can get
from a single vendor
but this is not true you are far away
from this
if you want to get things smart you have
to do
uh tons of you have to choose
different vendors and we have two of
them everyone have
another kind of implementation somehow
um some of them are also locked into the
cloud so then you have to
free the film somehow or free your
device
from this evil firmware that
by default connects to the new land
and yeah for sure you have
incompatibilities
between different vendors and they don't
like it
if you integrate stuff from other
vendors into war
solutions um that makes everything
more complicated than it should be
so yeah how to start usually
people get started quite easy and simple
as i started
with some simple light bulbs these
philips hue
are very common or ostram lightify
yeah and in the beginning okay for them
if they only do controlling the lights
or they want to see the status means in
the beginning it's okay for you
if you turn on your lights arranging the
color
or receive from remote if it's on or off
when you leave the house quickly and on
the way to somewhere
and can take a look on your mobile to
see
if you forgot to change some lights off
or
i don't know what this is for the
beginning quite simple
and you can start very easily with this
um so what you what you get
out of the box in the beginning from the
vendors directly i'm
staying at these light bulbs because
this is the most
easy example to show you
um what what the vendors does or what
the vendors give you
and yeah an easy way to to get started
somewhere later we will try to find some
some more interesting examples
but these are reserved for the workshop
so
if you want to get in touch and talk
about
more things
like
this will be done later
um
and
then there is
um
and then
[Music]
yes
okay ladies and gentlemen that's the
next thing
that's live and the bandwidth from tico
is
another somewhere i don't know
um yeah what we should do now um
i think the talk is good and
we will just wait a few seconds
or a minute so that we can
start again maybe yes so i can
see a t for tickle
and hopefully it will be
going better now
what happened
um
can we continue
is it better now
oh
[Music]
yes so take a deep breath
keep calm and here we go again
so most of the queens are not really
smart out of the box
except from kinds like uh wake up scenes
when you want to wake up
um by light over a specific amount of
time
means when you want to wake up at around
six
just uh configure your light that it
starts
increasing the percent of light edge uh
over a couple of times and says yeah
when you wake up at six
ten minutes before six it starts to
increasing the lights
uh ten percent per minute and after
ten minutes uh the light is on hundred
percent and you have a very smooth
wake up this is nice but that's not
what i understand of smart things this
is just yeah dimming or increasing the
light over a specific amount of time
another thing that came out of the box
is a delayed shut off timer if you go to
bed or something like that
and you are away far away from your
digital switch
just push the button say it shut down
in 10 minutes and after 10 minutes the
light goes off
another thing that come out of the box
if there is supported hardware is
turning lights on and off by movements
detected
in general you have just the movement
sensor
and this movement sensor triggers the
light to get
on and after a couple of minutes when no
movement was detected it turns off again
this is quite nice
when you go through a room where you're
just
passing by and you want to enable
the lights without touching anything
this is
uh fully automated this is nice this is
kind of smart
or what i think what could be smart
but the problem is
this only works with supported hardware
when you stick on a window
so usually some windows don't have
movement detectors other have them
but they are quite expensive
so what is on my personal wish list
to have things more smart
is to combine way more things than just
a light with a movement sensor
for example i have
a window open detect detection so i can
detect if a window is open
or not and if the window is open
more than 15 minutes uh because this is
way
enough to get fresh air into the room um
then start blinking indicator in
the living room for example to notify me
that i should close this window or send
me a message
to my mobile over i don't know telegram
push message
whatever you name it and
i won't like to know that i have to
close the window
yeah you can or i would like to
implement also unsupported hardware
um i would like to combine lights with
movement sensors
that i built myself because usually you
can get this developer board with a
wireless chip on it
putting a movement sensor on it and just
use this for your movement detection and
you can
save a lot of money instead of buying uh
very expensive things from the vendor
itself
but this won't happen the easy way
because you stay in the vendor login
and the vendor don't don't want you to
use other things
um so all in all
is this an easy piece of cake yes but
no i would say it depends on or
depends on what you really want to do if
you if you have some simple things that
you want to do
you usually can do this out of the box
with
vendors but when you want to like
to have more advanced tasks when
combining
things from different different vendors
or building your own
sensors or actors or whatever
you can't do this the easy way usually
um yeah combination with other devices
is not possible the easy way or
not with that what what you get shipped
by the vendors so we need to close the
gap by ourselves
we will do this later so for now we will
talk a bit about sensors actors what the
and um yeah sensors i
gave you some some example already we
have um
for example movement sensors we can
measure
temperatures we can measure the light
and looks
um yeah anything that can be interesting
for you can be measured
um for example the actual bitcoin price
uh for some people i heard it's quite
interesting to know the actual bitcoin
price
and yeah with a smart home automation
you can also send notifications to your
tv
or whatever um to give you an
information about the actual
bitcoin price yes cpu load of a host is
just an example
to show you what you can use as a sensor
because you can
vary um every web page
you can send shell commands
whatever you want as a sensor and the
result of it
can be used later for
other things and we mostly talk about
homosystem today
later i will present you some some other
alternates or what i
what i've seen in the past but don't
like
to use um and that's why i
linked here the home assistant
integration
uh of the available sensors that came
out of the box if you go there
have a look you will find a lot of
sensors that you can use
even things like sensor type rest
where you can send rest api calls to
whatever you named so these are
sensors um you also have actors
actors um usually just
simple relays means um
when you want to start a heating pump
yeah temperature is too low start
heating pump or start heating whatever
this is
your actor you can also um
switch power socket
shutter actors are a bit more specific
specific than just switching on and off
because usually you when you close a
shutter you need
the power for a specific amount of time
means shutter actor is a bit more than
just
switching because it's switching over a
time span
and yeah usually actors are everything
that can be
switched somehow
next thing would be automations
automations
um yeah if a sensor
has a specific state do something this
is quite easy if you push the button
turn the light on this is the most
simple
automation you can have but for sure you
can
extend these automation far far far
beyond that
um another thing yeah when pushing
button
light goes on the example from before
if a bitcoin provides is over 90 000
send a message
and let all lights in the house blink
like insane
um because you can do a party or i don't
know
and these are things you can do with
automations
so now we will have a short look about
types of hardware you will
find on your way and i will give some
not not not really recommendations but
what i've used in the past and
for sure there are always way more
examples than
just the shown one um yeah in general
you have lights
for sure as i told you the the the most
common
are philips hue or osram lightify
and the less expensive version is
the thing like lumi lumineer um
but you need to know that some of them
are working on
zigbee standard and maybe needs an own
bridge or something like that
and others are just with these
um esp with these small esp
chips on it to be able to use
wi-fi yeah and then you can simply
connect it to your wi-fi and it's a
client in your wifi and for sure
if you have a look at ali express you
will find many many more
vendors but in general you have usually
zigbee in it or bluetooth or wi-fi
that's it
yeah another thing that you for sure
will be neat is switches for switches
you can have
again you you have uh
nice switches that you can uh put on a
plate on the wall
or on a magnetic um on some you can put
it on metal and it keeps there or you
move around and just use it like a
remote
um xiaomi also has
um switches same for zonov
and shelly these are used here if you if
you have
a voltage that you want to switch
or a power plug you can
control these by zonov or shelleys and
for sure there are also many other
switches
available um
heating control heating control is um
quite interesting if you have an house
but if you live in a flat this can also
be
nice to heat up uh your bathroom or
something like that
yeah in the morning if you don't like it
too cold in there
just two or three hours before you wake
up start increasing the temperature
by your automation this can be done home
automatic
is used for underfloor heating mainly
at hardware and avm are for
these generic heaters that's put
to the wall and can be controlled by
turning
the vessels off and on
yeah in general you can connect
any device that can be connected somehow
yeah by bluetooth wifi zigbee
and some some other standards but these
are the most
common things that you that you
connect yeah on the vendor side it's
it's a bit sad you for for every
from every window you get different
applications and you can't
combine them together as i told you
before this is quite
pain in the ass and i don't like it i
like it on a single
single page and a general overview about
everything without
uh usually if you if you want to if
you have lights yeah and you have two
lights from different windows that are
not compatible to each other
and you have two of them in a single
room and you want to
activate both at the same time this is
only possible if you open
f1 say light on going to the second app
turn light on and yeah i i think nobody
wants to do this or the other way is
stick at a single vendor but this is
most of the time not the case
um yeah usually the the
source code of the valuer is closed so
i'm very happy if there is a custom
firmware built by
uh hardcore nerds who yeah generate new
new possibilities to the same hardware
that the vendor wasn't able able to
send to the customer yeah some also have
xml and rest apis um but
mostly they are just reverse engineered
somehow and not really well documented
documented online
so what we need to close
the missing gap we need to put
put some glue in between and this
glue is called generally smart hub and
there are
some solutions for it that i would like
to show you
right now so the first
thing that you maybe already heard of
and
most people who looking into home
automation
finds it or if you
if you have it in mind for a longer time
i'm sure you already struggled about it
the first thing is
fhem in german it is french
house automation and in english it is a
friendly
home automation and energy measurement
this was developed in 2005
and written in pearl um
but i have to say pro isn't my personal
preference
um you can do very much things with it
it's quite lightweight it would be run
on a raspy
but yeah i don't really like to do
everything in pearl
if you have affinity to pearl you can
use it for sure
it's nice there are a lot of things but
you have to do very many things manually
and yeah if you have something more
exotic you always have to
yeah write your own code
another thing that exists is um openhab
um it was developed in 2010
and it's written in java i don't know
what you think about java but i think
java is just a huge mess and my personal
preference is always to have it as small
as possible
and it should be fit on a raspy or some
small device yeah for openhab this is
not possible to have it run
on such a lightweight device
here we go in 2013
um home assistant was developed and
written in python
and this is my personal favorite i will
show you in a second
how why
um another thing is io broker
um this was developed in 2014 and is
written in javascript so it's
mostly node.js applications somehow
but to be honest i haven't tested it yet
so i have no real experience with io
broker just
reach some some stuff and i don't really
like javascript at all so
this is a no-go for me personal and
i like it way more in the python world
so my personal decision was in this case
home assistant i've started with
fhtm in the beginning and had a very
very very short look
into openhab in between but
since a couple of years for three years
now i'm using
no two years now i'm using home
assistant and started quite
quite simple yeah it and there are some
some reasons why
um first of all it's it's slim or
lightweight enough to be run on a
raspberry pi
starting from version three b
plus i guess um it has a focus on
security
the focus to keep your data at home yeah
because you don't want to
publish all your home automations to the
interwebs because um
yeah i want to free the devices from the
clouds
uh not to give it back to the cloud um
i would like to have it at home yeah
it's pure open source
written in python as i told you before
and uses the jamil syntax for
configuration
and because i use it at work it's a
personal plus i have to do it
i have to work with it every day and i
really like
really much like the way of configuring
things in home assistant and that's why
i use it
yeah it's very easy to start with so in
the beginning
you you can get in home automation
system quite fast but later if you want
to
get way more in detail um
you can you can also get way much deeper
and develop your custom integrations or
whatever you want
but these are the same things you could
do with fhm
for sure as well yeah if you want to
write your own stuff you could do this
with them as well
but home assistant i think is the yeah
in the middle of everything yeah it's
easy to start but good enough could get
way way deeper they have really fast
development and release cycles have a
very very active
community um
and i never had any problems with with
updates in the past so
the good things about home assistants
it's
very very easy to start it is
the documentation is awesome so for
every module you find
a good good
overview page where you find examples
for configurations
and if you have to keep something in
mind this is also noted on the
documentation page
it has a really nice performance
depending on some some things i will
talk a bit later about um
they continuously improving the user
interface
one year ago i guess there was a huge
update for the
lovelace interface to be more
drag and droppable for beginners
that they are able to configure
everything
the nice thing on home assistant as well
is that you can configure
things on the graphical user interface
as well as
in your configuration files by yaml
yeah it's very easy to maintain if you
need to do updates
you get notifications you can do the
updates by
simply clicking on your web interface on
updates and in the last two years i
didn't have any issues with it
yeah i also had to migrate once from a
raspberry p pi 3 b
plus to a newer version and this also
works like a charm
um just do a backup of your actual
system by pushing a button download the
file
and import this backup into the new
um system and everything works again
like before
so this is quite nice but there are also
some bad things
or not so good things um first of all
sometimes it's a bit hard to find
debugging information
um i had the problem that i was looking
for debugging information
but at the end i found out there was no
problem
because it was just a broken wire or
something
in this case it's a bit hard to find
some some errors but there was no error
for sure
that's why it was not working but it
could be better but
i will show you in the workshop some
some some overview about home assistant
and guide you through the different
levels of loggings
and then you maybe will see what i mean
yeah
a very important thing is that you don't
choose a too small
sd card in the beginning i was using a 8
gigabyte sd card
and thought it would be enough but you
have
historical data that will be saved on a
specific
time and depending on number of sensors
you have this can be increased very
fast so don't choose it
too small but yeah i think 64
128 gigabyte should be way more than
enough
um another point is don't use two slow
sd cards
um because
or in the past it was only possible to
have
everything on an sd card and if the sd
card is too slow
this takes a much of time to boot the
system
it's always kind of leggy but yeah
you know if you put in very old hard
drive
into a up-to-date computer you will get
the same for sure so have a look on the
performance of the sdk
card i can give you some recommendations
later um
but for now it's just the hint to
take care of the speed of your card
um yeah another thing that
disturbs me is that you sometimes have
duplicated items
if you're using bluetooth tracking or
something like that
over time you get duplicated items or if
you have
multiple devices with the same account
locked and you get duplicated items
and it's quite a mess to delete these
duplicated item afterwards
um yes
so a very very very short preview to the
workshop
that should be started really soon
if you want to attend or to
to have you to want to attend
i will give you a short overview for the
beginning so we will
insta some home assistant on a raspberry
pi or if
you want to use virtualbox we can also
install it in virtualbox
i will give you an overview about the
user interface
we will create some sensors together
we will create some actions and
yeah i will show you some some useful
hardware
like these node mcus or these d1
mini to build your custom
sensors for your personal needs
because the huge problem is that you
start a specific
point and want to increase over time
everything because usually you can't
plan everything
right now or maybe you don't have the
money to buy everything right now and
you can go step by step and
to save some money it's way more cheap
to
solder those things by hand
yeah and for sure i will show you how to
extend the
possibilities by adding community
integrations
you have a lot of integrations already
built in but sometimes
you need a bit more and therefore the
community integrations are quite nice
and i will show it to you in the
workshop later
uh yeah also we have the the
esps i will show you how to flash these
esps
quite easy i will show some some
examples with a movement
and temperature sensors i also have some
some some relays
in my home to to open and close the
garage
door or something like that that can be
shown later
and yeah an interesting tool um that i
would like to show you
is the esp home thingy because flashing
those esp's is
quite easy with esp home and also
configuration of different
components is very very easy
so um now we can go
to the workshop um if you have questions
you can ask these questions in the
workshop later
um you can go to the jitsi room
at jitsi.cbase.org
rc3 rt3 foo
and the super secure password 2342
and yeah if you would like to
start by yourself you can simply go to
the
url on this checkout link
um home assistant i o has io
installation
have a look on the type of installation
you want to do
as i told you you have different
possibilities you can install it as a vm
you can put it on a raspy and even for
putting on a raspy there are
several ways to do this the most easy
way is just
to use the generic
os image where you have an
home assistant operating system
and everything is installed
inside a docker's contact docker
container
[Music]
can the raspbian or something like that
install it by yourself
via docker or directly
okay we can see that a lot of people
will attend the workshop from
function we
stop our stream now with tico and
take or have fun with your workshop good
luck
toy
[Music]
thank you see you