[Music]
[Applause]
[Laughter]
so about our next speaker
um he's a security researcher
focused on embedded systems secure
communications and
mobile security he uh was
he was nominated by forbes for uh
the 30 under 30 in technology
and also has won a volva
obas absec ctf um
he has also found and disclosed
responsibly
multiple vulnerabilities and especially
for you nintendo aficionados
i want you to watch out for the next
intro which is
really amazing and you will all love
thank you very much
oh damn it
[Music]
hmm
um
oof what a trip welcome to my talk on
hacking the new nintendo game and watch
super mario brothers
my name is thomas roth and i'm a
security researcher and trainer from
germany
and you can find me on twitter at
geekdryninja and also on youtube at
stacksmashing
now this year marks the 35th anniversary
of our favorite plumber
super mario and to celebrate that
nintendo launched a new game console
called the nintendo
game and watch super mario brothers
the console is lightweight and looks
pretty nice and it comes pre-installed
with three games and also this nice
animated clock
the three games are super mario brothers
the original nes game
super mario brothers 2 the lost levels
and also
a reinterpretation of an old game and
watch game called
ball now as you probably know
this is not the first retro console that
nintendo released
in 2016 they released the nes classic
and 2017 they released the snes classic
now these devices were super popular in
the homebrew community
because they make it really easy to add
additional roms to it
they make it really easy to modify the
firmware and so on
and you can basically just plug them
into your computer install a simple
software and you can do whatever you
want with them
the reason for that is that they run
linux and have
and have a pretty powerful arm processor
on the inside and so it's really
it's really a nice device to play with
and so on
and so when nintendo announced this new
console a lot of people were hoping for
a similar experience
of having a nice mobile homebrew device
now if you were to make a venn diagram
of
some of my biggest interests you would
have reverse engineering
hardware hacking and retro computing
and this new gaming watch fits right in
the middle of that and so when it was
announced on the 3rd of september
i knew that i needed to have one of
those and given how hard the nes and the
snes classic
were to buy for a while i pre-ordered it
on like four or five different sites
a couple of which got cancelled but i
was pretty excited because i had three
pre-orders
and was supposed to ship on the 13th of
november
and so i was really looking forward to
this
and i was having breakfast on the 12th
of november when suddenly the doorbell
rang
and dhl delivered me the new game and
watch
one day before the official release now
at that point in time
there was no technical information
available about the device whatsoever
like if you searched for game and watch
on twitter you would only find the
announcements or maybe
a picture of the box of someone who also
received it early
but there were no teardowns no pictures
of the insides
and most importantly nobody had hacked
it yet
and this gave me as a hardware hacker
the kind of unique opportunity to
potentially be the first one to hack
a new nintendo console and so i just
literally dropped everything else i was
doing
and started investigating the device
now i should say that normally i stay
pretty far away from
any new console hacking mainly because
of the piracy issues i don't want to
enable piracy
i don't want to i don't want to
deal with piracy and i don't want to
build
tools that enable other people to pirate
stuff basically
but given that on this device you cannot
buy any more games and that all the
games that are on there
were basically already released over 30
years ago
i was not really worried about piracy
and felt pretty comfortable
in sharing all the results of the
investigation
and also the basically the issues we
found
that allowed us to customize the device
and so on
and in this talk i want to walk you
through how we managed to
hack the device and how you can do it at
home using relatively cheap hardware
and yeah hope you enjoy it
now let's start by looking at the at the
device itself
the device is pretty lightweight and
comes with a nicely
sized case and so it really for me it
sits really well in my hand and it has a
nice
320 by 240 lcd display a d-pad
a and b buttons and also three buttons
to switch between the different game
modes
on the right side we also have the power
button and the usb c
port now before you get excited about
the usb port
i can already tell you that
unfortunately nintendo decided to not
connect the data lines of the usb
port and so you can really only use it
for charging
also because we are talking about
nintendo here they use their proprietary
tripoint screws
on the device and so to open it up you
need one of those special tri-point bits
luckily nowadays most bit sets should
have them but it still
would suck if you order your unit and
then you can't open it up because you're
missing a screwdriver
after opening it up the first thing you
probably notice
is the battery and if you've ever opened
up a nintendo switch joy-con before you
might recognize the battery because it's
the exact same one
that's used in the joy-cons this is very
cool because if down the line like let's
say in two or three years
your battery of your gaming watch dies
you can just go and buy a joy-con
battery which you can have really
cheaply
almost anywhere next to the battery on
the right side we have
a small speaker which is not very good
and underneath we have the main pcb with
the processor the storage
and so on and so forth let's take a look
at those
now the main processor of the device is
an stm32
this is a cortex m7 from st
microelectronics with 1.3 megabytes of
ram
and 128 kilobytes of flash it runs at
280 megahertz and is a pretty beefy
microcontroller
but it's much less powerful than the
processor in the nes or snes classic
like this processor is really just a
microcontroller and so it can't run
linux
it can't run let's say super complex
software instead it will be
it will be programmed in some bare metal
way and so we will have a bare metal
firmware on the device
to the right of it you can also find a
one megabyte spi flash
um and so overall we have roughly 1.1
megabyte of storage on the device
now most microcontrollers or basically
all microcontrollers
have a debugging port and if we take a
look at the pcb
you can see that there are five
unpopulated contacts here
and if you see a couple of contacts that
are not populated close to your cpu
it's very likely that that it's the
debugging port
and luckily the data sheet for the stm32
is openly available and so
we can check the pin outs in the
datasheet
and then use a multimeter to to see
whether these pins are actually the
debugging interface
and turns out they actually are and so
we can find the swd debugging interface
as well as vcc and ground exposed on
these pins
now this means that we can use a
debugger so for example a j-link or
an st-link or whatever to connect to the
device and because
the the contacts are really easy to
access you don't even have to solder
like you can just hook up a couple of
test pins
and they will allow you to to easily
hook up your debugger now the problem is
on most devices
the debugging interface will be locked
during manufacturing
this is done to prevent people like us
to basically do whatever with the device
and to prevent us from being able to
dump the firmware uh potentially reflash
it and so on
and so i was very curious to see whether
we can actually connect to the debugging
port
and when starting up j-link and trying
to connect we can see it can actually
successfully connect
but when you take a closer look there's
also a message that the device
is actively protected
this is because the chip the stm3d2 chip
features something called rdp protection
level or readout protection level
this is basically the the security
setting for the debugging interface and
it has
three levels level zero means no
protection is active
level one means that the flash memory is
protected and so we
can't dump the internal flash of the
device however we can dump the ramp
contents and we can also
execute code from ram and then there's
also level 2
which means that all debugging features
are disabled
now just because a chip is in level 2
doesn't mean that
you have to give up for example in our
talk wallet.failed a couple of years ago
we showed how to use fault injection to
bypass
the level 2 protection and downgrade a
chip to level one
however on the game and watch we are
lucky and the interface is not fully
disabled
instead it's in level one and so we can
still dump the ram
which is a pretty good entry point even
though
we can't dump the firmware yet now
having dumped the ram of the device i
was pretty curious to see
what's inside of it and one of my
suspicions was that potentially
the emulator that's hopefully running on
the device
loads the original super mario brothers
rom into ram
and so i was wondering whether maybe we
can find the rom that the device uses
in the ram dump and so i open up the ram
dump in a
in a hex editor and i also open up the
original super mario brothers rom
in a second window in a hex editor and
try to find different parts of the
original rom in the ram dump
and it turns out that yes the nes rom is
loaded
into ram and it's always at the same
address and so it's probably like during
boot up it gets copied into ram
or something along those lines and so
this is pretty cool to know because it
tells us
a couple of things first off we know now
that the debug
port is enabled and working but that
it's unfortunately
at rdp level one and so we can only dump
the the ram
and we also know that the nes rom is
loaded into ram
and this means that the device runs a
real nes emulator
and so if we get aki we can for example
just replace the rom that is used by
by the device and play for example our
own nes game
next was time to dump the flash chip of
the device
for this i'm using a device called mini
pro and i'm using one of these really
useful
syc8 clips and so these ones you can
simply clip onto the flash chip
and then dump it now one warning though
the flash chip on the device is running
at 1.8 volts and so you want to make
sure that your programmer
also supports 1.8 volt operation if you
accidentally try to read it out at 3.3
volts
you will break your flash trust me
because it happened to me on one of my
units
now with this flash dump from the device
we can start to analyze it
and what i always like to do first is
take a look at the entropy or the
randomness of the flash dump
and so using bin walk with the dash
uppercase e option
we get a nice entropy graph and in this
case you can see we have a very high
entropy over almost the whole flash
contents
and this mostly indicates that the flash
contents are encrypted
it could also mean compression but if
it's compressed you would often see
more like dips in the entropy and in
this case it's one
very high entropy stream we also notice
that there are no repetitions whatsoever
which also tells us that it's probably
not like a simple xor based encryption
or so
and instead something like aes or or
something similar
but just because the flash is encrypted
doesn't mean we have to give up on the
contrary
i think now it starts to get interesting
because you actually have a challenge
and it's not just plug and
plug and play so to say one of the
biggest questions i had
is is the flash actually verified like
does the device boot even though the
flash has been modified
because if it does this would open up a
lot of
attack vectors basically as you will see
and so to to verify this i basically try
to put
zeros in random places in the flash
image and so
i put some at address 0 so i'm at hex
2000 and so on
and then i checked whether the device
would still boot up and with the most
flash modifications it would still boot
just fine
this tells us that even though the flash
contents are encrypted
they are not validated they are not
check sum or anything and so the device
and so we can potentially trick the
device
into accepting a modified flash image
and this is really important to know as
you will see in a couple of minutes
my next suspicion was that maybe the nes
rom we see in ram
is actually loaded from the external
flash
and so to to find out whether that's the
case
i again took the flash and i inserted
zeros
at multiple positions in the flash image
flashed that over booted up the game
dumped the ram
and then compared the nes rom that i'm
now dumping from ram
with the one that i dumped initially and
checked whether they are equal
because my suspicion was that maybe i
can
i can overwrite a couple of bytes in the
encrypted flash
and then i will modify the nes rom and
after
doing this for like i don't know half an
hour i got lucky
and i modified four bytes in the flash
image and four bytes
in the ram sorry in the rom that was
loaded into ram
changed and this tells us quite a bit
it means that the rom is loaded from
flash into ram
and that the flash contents are not
validated
and what's also important is that we we
changed
four bytes in the flash and now four
bytes in the
decrypted image changed and this is very
important to know because
if we take a look at what we would
expect to happen when we when we change
the flash contents
there are multiple outcomes and so for
example here we have these by flash
contents on the left
and the ram contents on the right and so
the ram contents are basically the
decrypted version
of the spyflash contents now let's say
we change four bytes in the encrypted
flash image to zeros
how would we expect the ram contents to
change for example if we would see that
now
16 bytes in the ram are changing
this means that we are potentially
looking at
an encryption algorithm such as aes in
electronic codebook mode
because it's a block-based encryption
and so if we change
4 bytes in the input data a block size
in this case 16 bytes and the output
data would change
the next possibility is that we change 4
bytes in the spy flash
and all data afterwards will be changed
and in this case
we would look at some kind of chaining
cipher such as
aes in the cbc mode however if we change
4 bytes in the spy flash and only 4
bytes in the ram changed
we are looking at at something such as
aes and counter mode
and to understand this let's take a
better look at how aes and ctr works
aes ctr works by having your clear text
and xoring it
with an aes encryption stream that is
generated from
a key a nonce and a counter algorithm
now the aes stream that will be used to
xor your clear text will always be the
same if key
and nonce is the same this is why it's
super important that if you use aes ctr
you always select a unique nonce for
each encryption
if you encrypt similar data with the
same nonce twice
large parts of the resulting cipher text
will be the same
and so the clear text gets xored with
the asctr stream
and then we get our ciphertext
now if we know the clear text as we do
because the clear text
is the rom that is loaded into ram and
we know
the cipher text which we do because it's
the contents of the encrypted flash we
just dumped
we can basically reverse the operation
and as a result we get the aes ctr
stream that was used to
encrypt the flash and now this means
that we can
take for example a custom rom
xor it with the asctr stream we just
calculated
and then generate our own encrypted
flash image for example with a modified
rom
and so i wrote a couple of python
scripts to to try this
and after a while i was running hacked
super mario brothers instead of super
mario brothers
so woohoo we hacked the nintendo game
and watch one day before the official
release
and we can install modified super mario
brothers roms
now you can find the scripts that i used
for this on my github
so it's in a repository called game and
watch hacking
and i was super excited because it mean
it meant that i succeeded and that i
basically hacked a nintendo console
one day before the official release
unfortunately i finished the level but
toad wasn't as excited he told me that
unfortunately our firmware is still
in another castle and so on the monday
after the launch of the device
i teamed up with conrad pacman a
hardware hacker from sweden who i met at
the previous congress
and we started chatting and throwing
ideas back and forth and so on
and eventually we noticed that the
device has a special
ram area called itcm ram which is a
tightly coupled instruction ram
that is normally used for very high
performance routines such as interrupt
handlers and so on
and so it's in a very fast ram area and
we
realized that we never actually looked
at the contents of that itcm ram
and so we dumped it from the device
using the debugging port
and it turns out that this itcm ram
contains
arm code and so again the question is
where does this arm code come from does
it maybe just like the nes rom come from
the external flash
and so basically i repeated the whole
the whole thing that we also did with
the nes rom and it just put zeros at the
very beginning of the
encrypted flash rebooted the device
and dumped the itcm rom and i got super
lucky on the first try already
the itscm contents changed and because
the itcm contains
code not just data so earlier we only
had the the nes rom which is just data
but this time the ram contains code this
means
that with the same exo trick we used
before we could inject
custom itcm code into the external flash
which would then be loaded into ram when
the device boots
and because it's it's a persistent
method
we can then reboot the device and let it
run without the debugger connected
and so whatever code we load into this
itcm area
will be able to actually read the flash
and so we could potentially write some
code that
gets somehow called by the firmware and
then copies the internal flash
into ram from where we then can retrieve
it
using the debugger
now the problem is let's say we have a
custom payload
in somehow in this itcm area
we don't know which address of this itcm
code
gets executed and so we don't know
whether the firmware will jump to
address 0
or address to 100 or whatever but
there's a really simple trick
to still build a successful payload and
it's called a knob slide
a knob or no operation is an instruction
that simply does nothing
and if we fill most of the itcm ram with
knobs and put our payload at the very
end we build something that is basically
an upslide
and so when the cpu indicated by mario
here
jumps to a random address in that whole
knob slide
it will start executing knobs knobs
knobs knobs and slide down
into our payload and execute it and so
even if mario jumps
right in the middle of the knob slide he
will always
slide down the slide and end up in our
payload
and conrad wrote this really really
simple payload which is only like 10
instructions which basically just copies
the internal flash into ram
from where we can then retrieve it using
the debugger
so woohoo super simple exploit we have a
full firmware backup and a full flash
backup and now we can really fiddle with
everything on the device and we've
actually released tools
to do this yourself and so if you want
to backup your nintendo game and watch
you can just go
onto my github and download the game and
watch backup repository
which contains a lot of information on
how to back it up
it does it does check something and so
on to ensure
that you don't accidentally brick your
device and you can easily
back up the original firmware install
homebrew and then
always go back to the original software
we also have an awesome
support community on discord and so if
you ever need help
you you will i think you will find
success there
and so far we haven't had a single
bricked game and watch and so
looks to be pretty stable and so i was
pretty excited because
the quest was over or is it
if you ever claim on the internet
that you successfully hacked an embedded
device
there will be exactly one response and
one response only
but does it run doom literally my
twitter dms my youtube comments and even
my friends were spamming me
with the challenge to get doom running
on the device but to get doom running
we first needed to bring up all the
hardware and so we basically needed
to create a way to develop and load
homebrew onto the device
now luckily for us most of the
components on the board are
very well documented and so there are no
nda components and so for example the
processor
has an open reference manual and open
source library to use it
the flash is a well-known flash chip
and so on and so forth and there are
only a couple of very proprietary or
custom components and so for example
the lcd on the device is proprietary and
we had to basically sniff the spi bus
that goes to the display
to basically decode the the
initialization
of the of the display and so on and
after a while we had
the full hardware running we had lcd
support we had audio support steep
support buttons and even flashing tools
that allow you to simply use an swd
debugger
to dump and rewrite the external flash
and you can find all of these things on
our github
now if you want to mod your own game and
watch all you need
is a simple debugging adapter such as a
cheap
three dollar st-link a trading one s or
a real st-link device
and then you can get started we've also
published a base
project for anyone who wants to get
started with building their own games
for the game and watch and so it's
really simple
it's just a frame buffer you can draw to
input is really simple and so on
and as said we have a really helpful
community
now with all the hardware up and running
i could finally start porting doom
now i started by looking around for
other parts of doom 2 and stm32
and i found this project by floppis
called stm32doom
now the issue is stm32doom is
designed for a board with 8 megabytes of
ram
and also the data files for doom were
stored on an external usb drive
on our platform we only have 1.3
megabytes of ram
128 kilobytes of flash and only one
megabyte of
external flash and we have to fit all
the level information
all the code and so on in there
now the doom level information is stored
in so-called wad
what where's all my data files
and these data files contain the sprites
the textures the levels and so on
now the what for doom 1 is roughly 4
megabytes in size and
the what for doom 2 is 40 megabytes in
size
but we only have 1.1 megabyte of storage
plus we have to fit all the code in
there so obviously
we needed to find a very very small doom
what and as it turns out there's a thing
called
mini what which is a minimal doom iwad
which is basically all the bells and
whistles
stripped from the wad file and
everything replaced by
simple outlines and so on and while it's
not pretty
i was pretty confident that i could get
it working as it's only 250 kilobytes
of storage down from 14 megabytes
now in addition to that a lot of stuff
on the chocolate doom port itself had to
be changed and so for example
i had to rip out all the file handling
and add a custom file handler
i had to add support for the game and
watch lcd
button import support and i also had to
get rid of a lot of things
to get it running somewhat smoothly and
so for example the infamous wipe effect
had to go
and i also had to remove sound support
now
the next issue was that once it was
compiling
it simply would not fit into ram and
crash all the time
now on the device we have roughly 1.3
megabytes of ram
in different ram areas and for example
just the frame buffer that we obviously
need
takes up 154 kilobytes of that
then we have 160 kilobytes of
initialized data
320 kilobytes of uninitialized data and
a ton of dynamic allocations that are
done by chocolate doom
and these dynamic allocations were a
huge issue because
the chocolate doom source code does a
lot of small allocations
which are only used for temporary data
and so they get freed again
and so on and so your dynamic memory
gets very very fragmented very quickly
and so eventually there's just not
enough space to for example
initialize the level and so to fix this
i took the chocolate doom code and i
changed a lot of the
dynamic allocations to static
allocations which also had the big
advantage
of making the error messages by the
compiler
much more meaningful because it would
actually tell you hey this and this data
does not fit into ram and eventually
after a lot of trial and error and
copying as
many of the original assets as possible
into
the minimal iwad i got it i had
doom running on the nintendo game and
watch super mario brothers
and i hopefully can't the internet gods
that forced me to do it
now unfortunately the usb port is
physically not connected
to the processor and so it will not be
possible to hack the device simply by
plugging it into your computer
however it's relatively simple to do
this using one of these
usb debuggers now the most requested
type of homebrew software
was obviously emulators and i'm proud to
say that by now we actually have
kind of a large collection of emulators
running on the nintendo gaming watch
and it all started with conrad backman
discovering the retro gold project which
is an emulator collection
for a device called the odroid go and
the odroid go
is a small handheld with similar input
and size constraints as the nintendo
game and watch
and so it's kind of cool to port this
over because it
it basically already did all of the hard
work so to say
and retro go comes with emulators for
the
nes for the game boy and the gamer color
and even for the sega master system and
the sega game gear
and after a couple of days conrad
actually was able to show off
his nes emulator running zelda and other
games such as
contra and swan on the nintendo game and
watch
this is super fun and initially we only
had really a basic emulator that
you know could barely play and we had a
lot of frame drops we didn't have nice
scaling v-sync
and so on but now after a couple of
weeks it's really
a nice device to use and to play with
and so we also
have and game boy emulator running and
so you can play your favorite
game boy games such as pokemon super
mario land and so on
on the nintendo game and watch if you
own the corresponding rom backups
and we also experimented with different
scaling algorithms to make the most
out of the screen and so you can
basically change the scaling algorithm
that is used for the display
depending on what you prefer and you
could even change the palette for the
different games
we also have a nice game chooser menu
which allows you to basically have
multiple roms on the device that you can
switch
between we have safe state support and
so you if you turn off the device
it will save wherever you left off and
you can even come back
to your save game once the battery run
out you can find the source code for all
of that
on the retro go repository from conrad
and it's really really awesome
other people build for example emulators
for the chip 8 system and so
the chip 8 emulator comes with a nice
collection of small
arcade games and so on and it's really
fun
and really easy to develop for and so
really give this a try if you own a game
and watch
and want to try homebrew on it
tim scherving is even working on an
emulator for the original game and watch
games and so this is really cool because
it basically
turns the nintendo game and watch into
an emulator for all game and watch games
that were ever released
and what was really amazing to me is how
the community came together
and so we were pretty open about the
progress on twitter
and also conrad was twitch streaming a
lot of the process
and we opened up a discord where people
could join who were interested
in hacking on the device and it was
amazing to see what came out of the
community and so
for example we now have a working
storage upgrade that works
both with homebrew but also with the
original firmware
and so instead of one megabyte of
storage you can have 60 megabytes of
flash
and you just need to to replace a single
chip which is pretty
easy to do then for understanding the
full hardware
daniel cuthbert and daniel padilla
provided us with high resolution x-ray
images
which allowed us to fully understand
every single connection even of the bga
parts
without desoldering anything then jake
little of upcycle electronics
traced on the x-rays and also using a
multimeter every last
trace on the pcb and he even created a
schematic of the device which
gives you all the details you need when
you want to program something also
and what's really really fun senator van
der wehl for example even created a
custom backplate and now there are even
project that projects that try to
replace the original pcb
with a custom pcb with an fpga and an
esp32
and so it's really exciting to see what
people come up with
now i hope you enjoyed this talk and i
hope to see you on our discord if you
want to join the fun
and thank you for coming
hi um wow that was a really amazing talk
thank you very much
uh thomas um as announced in the
beginning
we do accept questions from you and
we have quite quite a few
let's see if we managed to make it
through all of them
the first one is did you read the
articles about nintendo observing
hackers like private investigators etc
and are you somehow worried about this
oh what's going on with my camera looks
like luigi messed around with my video
setup here
uh-huh yeah i've so i've read those
articles but um
so i believe that um in this case
the there is no piracy issue right like
i'm not allowing anyone to play any new
games if you wanted to
to dump a super mario rum you would have
done it 30 years ago or
on the nes classic or on the switch on
any of the 100 consoles nintendo
launched in between
and so i'm really not too worried about
it to be honest
um i also think the the the aspect of of
the uh target audience is
uh is to be uh seen here um so off to
the next question
uh which is um is the do you think that
there is a reason
why an external flash chip has been used
yeah so um the internal flash of the
s732h7b0 is relatively small it's only
128 kilobytes
and so they simply couldn't fit
everything
in like basically even just the frame
buffer um
even just a frame buffer picture also is
larger than the internal flash
and so um i think that's why they did it
and i'm glad they did
yeah sure um and um
is the decryption done in software or is
it a feature of the microcontroller
so the microcontroller has an integrated
feature called otf
dec otf deck and basically the flash is
directly mapped into memory and they
have this chip peripheral called otf
deck that
automatically provides the decryption
and so on and so it's done
all in hardware and you can even
retrieve the keys from hardware
basically
okay very nice and um
also um and the next question is somehow
related to that
uh is uh in your opinion the encryption
nintendo has applied
uh even worth the effort for them it
feels like it's just there to give
shareholders a false sense of security
how
what would you think about that i think
from my perspective they choose just the
right encryption because it was a ton of
fun to reverse engineer and try to
to bypass it and say uh it was an
awesome challenge
and so i think they did everything right
but um i also think
in the end it's it's such a simple
device and it's like if you take a look
at what people
are building on top of it with like
games and and all the kind of stuff
um i think they did everything right but
um
probably it was just a tick mark of yeah
we totally locked down jtag and um
yeah but i think it's fun because again
like it doesn't open up any piracy
issues
sure and the the one thing is related to
the knob slide which you
very uh very uh well uh animated
um so um
wouldn't uh wouldn't start of sub
routines be suitable
as well for that uh for that uh
goal um uh the the person asking
uh says that a big push r5 r4
r5 etc instructions are quite
recognizable
um how would yeah
yeah so um absolutely so um the
the time from finding the data in the
itcm ram and actually exploiting it was
less than an hour and so um if we would
have tried to reverse engineer it it
would be more work like absolutely
possible and also not difficult
but just filling the ram with knob took
a couple of minutes and so
it was really the easiest way in the
fastest way um without fiddling around
in gydra also
okay cool thanks and
this is more a remark than a question
the person says it's strange that an
estes an 5281 does not mention a single
time
that the data is not verified during
encryption
i think it's more a fault on st than
nintendo's side
what would you think about that yeah
i would somewhat agree because in this
case even if you
don't have jtag like an arm thump
instruction
is two to four bytes and so you you you
have a relatively small space to brute
force to potentially get an interesting
branch instruction and so on
so i think it's yeah i mean it's it's
not perfect but also
um doing verification is is very
expensive computational wise and so
i think it should just be the the
firmware that actually verifies the
contents of the external flash
okay um so we i think we should uh
two questions more and then uh we can go
back to the studio
um the uh there's a question about
the aes encryption key um have you
managed to recover them yes we did
um but so there is an application up by
st
and they do some crazy shifting around
with the keys but i think even just
today like
an hour before the talk or so a guy
who's also or sorry i'm not sure this
guy uh
a person on our discord actually managed
to to
um rebuild the full encryption but we i
personally was never interested in that
because um
after you've downgraded to rdp0 the
device you can just
access the memory map flash and get the
completely decrypted flash contents
basically
sure thanks and last question about the
lcd controller
whether it's used by writing pixels over
spi
or if it has some extra features maybe
even backgrounds or sprites or something
like that
so um the the lcd itself doesn't have
any special features
it has a one spi bus to configure it and
then a parallel interface where you
uh so it takes up a lot of pins but the
chip itself has a hardware called ltdc
which is an lcd controller
which provides two layers with alpha
blending and some basic windowing and so
on
okay cool then thank you very very much
for the great talk and the great intro
and with that back to our main studio
in the orbit thank you very much back to
orbit
[Music]
wow
you