[Music]
[Applause]
hello everyone my name is camille i am a
researcher at toyotaro cooperation
and this is a presentation about ramen a
platform that's been developed to make
education and research in automotive
systems more accessible
the automotive industry can be
inaccessible to many people because
automotive projects may involve
prohibitive costs and be tied to ndas
that not
everybody is willing to sign what we
want to propose with this project is an
inexpensive testbed
to study and research automotive systems
which is both open source
and developed with open source tools so
that at least
anyone can get access to a good
alternative for education and research
the main focus of this test bed is
security but you will see that the usage
of the test bed is not limited to
security
and i will keep the security talk mostly
for the end of the presentation
i will start by giving a short
introduction about automotive systems
then i will present the design details
of that testbed
with various demonstrations and concrete
details about its hardware and software
as an example of how the testbed can be
used i will spend some time
experimenting with boost control
and by that i mean i will go through the
whole development process starting from
evaluating the
differential equations of a simple
mechanical model
i will experiment with various control
strategies implement them
in c and make measurements in a driving
simulator using only data from the
canvas
and i will do all that using only open
source tools
this is to demonstrate how the testbed
can be used but also to have a concrete
project
that i can use as a reference to explain
after what corporately would have been
different
if you were experimenting with a real
electronic control unit
i will also explain how we can get close
to automotive hardware and software
without signing ndas so the second part
of the talk is mainly here to give you
more information about the automotive
industry
in case you are not familiar with it
before i start let me just clarify that
this is not an advertisement we are not
selling
anything represent here and we do not
profit financially from it
we are simply sharing design files with
privacy licenses and without royalties
ok so first let me give you a very quick
introduction about automotive systems
you can see a car as a collection of
systems divided in four different
domains
the powertrain domain which includes the
engine and the transmission
the chassis domain which includes the
steering column and suspensions
the body domain which includes the
lights the doors and heating
and the infotainment domain which
includes navigation and connectivity
many of the different systems that can
be found in the car are controlled
by electronic control units or ecu's or
shorts
there are many kinds of ecu's in the car
sometimes hundreds of them
and usually they're not hard to
understand they have a limited number of
inputs
generally data from sensors and
actuators and they have a limited number
of outputs
generally to control actuators
so for example an airbag ecu may use an
accelerometer as its input
and an airbag trigger as its output the
role of the ecu will be to use data from
the accelerometer to detect a shock
and output a signal as actuator
to detonate an airbag when the shock is
detected
it is very common for ecus to the data
from other ecu's
most of the time ecu's we need to share
data with other ecu's on the same domain
in the case of an automatic core for
example the transmission control unit
needs input from the engine ecu to
determine the correct gear
if that data is critical that connection
may even be redundant
ecus may also need to communicate with
ecu's on a different domain
for example the brake system usually in
the chassis domain
we need to communicate its state to the
stock map usually in the body domain
most of the time the technology that is
used for communication is scanned
and kind technology uses a bus topology
which means a cam message will be
received by all ecu's on the same can
bus
there is no authentication or encryption
at the link layer
so any message can be sent by any ecu
and security features need to be
implemented
at higher layers the standard time frame
consists mainly of an arbitration id of
11 bits and a payload of 8 bytes
plan fd is a recent evolution of can
where the payload size may be extended
up to 64 bytes
for an ecl network manufacturers will
assign a meaning to each arbitration id
and each bit in their payload the file
that determines the traffic on the can
bus is often referred to as a dbc
file for example assuming a log
controller
and two lamps are the canvas the
manufacturer may decide that id123
is used by the long controller to
communicate the command of both lamps
that id124 is used by the left left lamp
to give feedback about the status and
that id125
is used by the right lamp to give
feedback about its status
each of those messages will be
broadcasted periodically by the assigned
ecu on the canvas
and will serve as the basis for most
data exchange between ecu's
so that's it for the introduction there
are many reasons why people will be
interested
in automated system and ecu networks the
activity that gets by far the most
attention from the media is
vulnerability research
but there are also other reasons for
example owners they want to check
their car's compliance with regulations
such as emissions regulations
and privacy regulations for example gdpr
gdpr other owners may want to exercise
the rights to repair
if they are guaranteed by the country
they live in and finally some owners may
want to experiment
and innovate with diy features or simply
satisfy the curiosity
and educate others and while those may
be valid reasons to experiment with the
car
manufacturers are typically against
people tinkering with a car because they
may be worried about the intellectual
property being stolen
about vulnerabilities being exploited or
people hurting themselves and others
while
injury and what probably suffers the
most from this dedicated situation
is education and research innovative
security
because people cannot easily get access
to safe equipment
or access to the information that they
would need
in the long term this may mean that
manufacturers will have less security
technologies to choose from to secure
their cars
and that less talents would be available
to develop and evaluate them
and the development of course involves
many people from many companies so it is
important to make sure that everyone
involved
involved is competent in automotive
security
and some people are pushing for more
open sourcing cars and who knows maybe
one day
a car will be 100 open source
but if it happens it is going to take a
long time
and manufacturers themselves do not have
access to 100 of the source code
of the cars they make because ecu's
contain
intellectual property from other
companies so this is mostly a political
topic
so there is not much we can contribute
to as researchers
however one way you can contribute
technically right now is to try the
other way around
and use what is publicly available to
make it accessible to learn
and research automotive systems
and that is what we try to do with ramen
which is a topic of this presentation
the objective is to provide a platform
for research that is
open and by that we mean it should be
easy to modify the source code and
reprogram the ecu's
accessible and by that we need
inexpensive
small and requiring no prior skills in
automotive systems
safe with no risk of accidents or legal
repercussions
and motivating something that you can
interact with so that you get the same
kind of experience as you do when you
experiment with a real car
there are already some solutions
available if you want to experiment with
an ec network
besides of course a real car the first
one is making your own test bed
from real ecu's so we can see many
hackers sharing that testbed and
security conferences
and usually if you see something like
this you stop and you immediately get
interested
so it is a nice way to motivate people
to learn unfortunately
those are not easy to reprogram because
manufacturers do not share information
about the ecu's
and they require a lot of skills to
build so it's not accessible to everyone
another option is to use development
boards such as arduino
and that is what you can see mostly on
academic papers
they have the advantage of being
reproducible and you can modify the
source code as you want
so they can be used in many cases for
research
but they lack many safety features often
found on actual eco hardware
and software even if you are even if you
are
able to simulate a can bus you don't get
the same level of direction as you do if
you re
with a car so it's not something that
motivates people and makes them want to
run more
and the third option is to use a
professional test bed such as pasta
and other work from our team this is a
good option because you get access to
the source code and you can reprogram
the ecu's and the canvas network is
already simulating a full car
so the groundwork is already done it's a
major drawback so
that it is very expensive so it is not
accessible to everyone so there are some
options to study and research automotive
systems but none of them seem to be both
accessible and motivating at the same
time
so many people don't even think of
learning about automotive systems
because it never
occurred to them that they could like it
and in comparison
with other industries you have so many
ways to get started if you want to learn
about linux you can
start with a raspberry pi if you want to
learn about electronics you can start
with an arduino
and so on so we wanted something that
would give
a similar experience but for automotive
systems
so we noticed that most of the test beds
that people are using to experiment with
ecu's are made of four ecu's
so the ecu's are often communicating
with each other using a can bus
so we try to fit all that in a pcb the
size of a credit card
and we name that pcb ramen it features
four ecu's connected over
a common can bus or kind of debuss which
is accessible from outside
by your terminal block one of the ecu
of the ecu's is also connected to
connect to usb
which is also the power supply pin
sockets can be used to connect sensors
actuators and additional hardware
and the board features many probes to
easily access important electric signals
[Music]
the four ecu simulate a car network with
messages identical to pasta
the name ramen is obviously a reference
to pasta since it is a cheap alternative
mostly aimed at students
in real course cam messages typically
have different payload sizes
but by default we operate with maximum
paired size to demonstrate heavy traffic
so basic format is like this arbitration
id
two bytes for the data two bytes for a
counter and four bytes of additional
data
random data used as a placeholder for
additional data such as checksum or mac
you can easily modify the messages
arbitration id in format
and here we are assuming a full by-wire
vehicle which means all physical
functions of a car
are accessible to the canvas which is
usually not the case on current cars
the block diagram of ramen looks like
this and as i explained earlier
all ecu's are periodically exchanging
messages on the canvas
if you connect a giant adapter and have
a look at the traffic
it will typically look like this
so the port itself is enough to simulate
an issue network
but it does not look very motivating
what we wanted on top of this was some
sensors and actuators to make it more
interactive
so we created four expansion boards for
sensors and actuators
to simulate the infotainment domain we
simply use a screen
for the body domain we use an engine key
and some leds
for the chassis domain we mainly use a
slide switch
to simulate the side brake and the
rotating potentiometer potentiometer to
simulate the steering wheel
and for the powertrain domain we use
slight potentiometers for the brake and
accelerator
and the joystick for the shift lever
the ec connected to usb implements a
standard cam or kfd interface
either over a standard ceiling port
using excel can or
over a native interface on linux thanks
to the condor light firmware projects
if you connect the board to usb ports on
a computer it should be recognized as a
usb to cam adapter
so it is not necessary to own an
external can adapter to get started
this is a remote of what it looks like
to use ramen just connect it over usb
if you use linux linux you can get it to
be recognized as a standard
kind network interface so it will show
up in this config
then you can use various tools available
on linux to observe the traffic
for example can sniffer here you can see
the traffic explained earlier
the giant ids on the left on the left
and the payload on the right
so with this we can simulate an iso
network with sensors and actuators
basis enough for basic interactions but
it still does not feel like you are
actually experimenting with the car
ideally the ecu should be performing
realistic ecu functions
not just lighting up leds based on some
switches and potentiometers
and for this we found that the
connection in a closed loop with an open
source driving simulator would be an
affordable and safe solution
to feel like you are driving the ecl
network
fortunately there is a great open source
driving simulator for autonomous driving
research
it is called corner it features a python
api so it is very easy to interact with
it
and it also comes with an example
central algorithm so you can
immediately start experimenting with a
virtual self-driving car
so we wrote some scripts so that most
sensors value
for example speed and altitude would be
simulated on the computer in kerner
then broadcasted on the canvas on the
other side
we made it so that all controls of color
such as throttle steering
and brakes would be decided by the issue
network
and this is what you could refer to as
hills or hardware in the loop simulation
in the automotive industry ramen is not
as advanced as professional tools
but at least it is accessible
so to achieve manual control it is not
complicated with color
on the manual control example provided
with the api
there is a right through game loop that
reads events on the keyboard
applies controls then updates the
physics simulation
so kara does not simulate a canvas by
default so we created a python class to
easily interact with the canvas using
the time message specifications of raman
to integrate it with caller we just need
to replace keyboard controls with
actuator control
data read from the campus to close the
loop
we broadcast sensor data using 10
messages based on data retreat
retrieved from the python api of the
physics simulator
and with this were able to control the
car manually with the potentiometers on
the board
here i gently press accelerator release
the hand brake
and i can control the car using the
steering wheel on the expansion board
[Music]
so manual control is nice but automatic
control is better because ultimately we
want to focus
on working on the canvas so on the
original project there is also an
example script for automatic control
again there is a white true loop where
the code basically simulates the physics
lets the center of the ai make a
decision then apply the controls to the
physics simulation
to integrate one man with a self-driving
algorithm again we need to replace the
apply control part with the controls
from the eco network
we also need to send cam messages with
sensor data retrieves of the python api
of the physics simulation
that is identical to having manual
control what we need to do more is also
send message
to broadcast the status
of the ai to the ecu network
so that the ecl network knows what
control the ai
algorithm is requesting
so periodically the ai will broadcast
its status by sending messages over usb
which are converted into canned messages
by the ec connected to usb
all ecu's on the network will receive
those messages
and will decide the actual controls of
the car based on their own algorithm
for example the part-two ecu may decide
to apply breaks
depending on the highest value between
the ai brace
and the brake potentiometer
all ecu's will receive the cam message
that applies the control
some ecu's may filter that message if
they do not need it
some ecu's like the body ecu may process
it
and take action for example if the
brakes are engaged the body ecu
will light up the stop lamp on the
expansion board
finally the ecu connected to usb will
forward the brake controls to the
simulator
that will apply the brakes in the
physics simulation
so this is what it actually looks like
all i need to do again is release the
handbrake
and the car will drive itself so the car
is controlled by the easter network
so when the car stops in the simulation
it is because the controls were applied
as a portrait ecu you can see that the
stop lamp lights up
because the body ecu also received and
processed the breakdown message
since the ecu is in charge of the
controls i can force the car to stop any
time
by forcing brakes on the powertrain ecu
potentiometer
so if you connect an external can
adapter to the canvas you will be able
to send and receive messages
so using ramen you can experiment with
the canvas of a self-driving virtual car
when you want to reprogram an ecu in the
real world you have two options either
you interact with the hardware
bootloader or the ecu's microcontroller
which depends on the microcontroller's
model and manufacturer
or you interact with diagnostics and
calibration software which depends on
the car model and manufacturer
diagnostic and calibration are often
done on the canvas
but other options may be available
protocols
are defined by standard documents you
often hear about uds and obd2
which both rely on the same transport
layer isotp
but there are also other protocols such
as keyword protocol 2000
or xcp all those protocols
can often also be implemented over other
layers
for the hardware bootloaders it depends
on the microcontroller manufacturer
for example for an xtm32 microcontroller
you can reprogram the firmware by
interacting overcam
according to the application note 3154
over usb according to the application
nodes 3156
or using other protocols defined in
other application nodes
in the case of raman we use the hardware
bootloader to reprogram the ecus
and we can also use the uds protocol
over cad
and in the future we may consider adding
xcp and kwb to fast
how to reprogram an ecu using
calibration and diagnostic software
is a topic that is already heavily
discussed at automotive security
talks i will not spend time on this
topic
you can find the definition of the
standards online usually you need to
spec you need to pay for them
but you can also find summaries for free
on some websites
for example wikipedia
what is more interesting to discuss here
is a hubbub loader
the various ways to force a
microcontroller into bootloader mode are
described in the application node
application node 2606 the format of cad
messages you need to send to interact
with the bootloader is defined in the
application node
3154 and it's not complicated
the format is simply command byte plus
argument
all that within the same canned message
payload
so we wrote some script to make it
easier to interact with the bookloader
so here i am showing the script that we
use to interact with the plotter
first thing i do is retrieve all
information from the bootloader
including the version the supported
commands and the chip id
i then use a read memory command to the
unknown sections of memories
this includes the ecu firmware
so it can be a good start to start
experimenting with reverse engineering
you can also activate memory without
protection and see what happens when you
try to dump the memory again
and in this case it's not allowing
memory terms anymore
you can remove the memory protection
which will wipe out the memory
and after you do that you can you can
use the bootloader to reprogram
the ecu's
[Music]
for the hardware we also designed
additional expression boards before your
speeches
first one is an expansion to connect a
jtag debugger
second one is a board to add external
quad display memories which have soic
packages such as eprom
fram flash no then sram and so on
the third one is a board to add a
trusted platform module
and the last one is an interface to
easily connect a chip whisperer
all those expansions are compatible with
each other so you can stack them
and create a very advanced eco network
with all issues between a tpm and one
gigabit of memory
and it looks better when many expansions
are stuck on top of each other
since we would like to use ramen for
education we try to vary the type of
electrical signals
used in the expansions and we added many
excellent probes to easily connect
external tools
you can use one of the many external
probes to connect an oscilloscope
and have a look at analog signals
for example here's a bright
potentiometer
or connect a logic analyzer and have a
look at digital signals
for example to analyze spi communication
between the ecu and the screen
for the hardware design we kept it
simple using only two layers and keeping
all components on the same side
we designed the hardware with large
tolerances so it should be easy to
produce with both
pcb fabrication services we use
components with large size so
if you have some skills in soldering you
should be able to solder one yourself
we designed the hardware using kicad
which is an open source tool for
designing hardware
you can easily modify the schematics
layout and even generate nice pdus
so firmware is designed using stn42 cube
id
it is accessible to beginners and you
can easily reconfigure peripherals and
clocks from the graphical interface
you will you will ever get some
statistics such as the estimated power
consumption
but of course you do not need to use the
vertical interface and libraries if you
would rather program everything yourself
by interacting
directly with registers
use freertos as a real-time operating
system the basic software of ecu's have
several tasks running in parallel
wi-fi receiving messages one for sending
cam messages and several periodic tasks
to take care of the ecu control loops
those tasks receive data from different
interrupt services within
using queues and dm memory overwrites
the task can also exchange data between
each browser using cues
or memory overwrite
again to keep the project accessible to
beginners we did the os configuration
using the graphical interface
where you can see all tasks as a
configuration for example the priority
you can add or remove interrupts and you
can also configure the value skews in
memory
there is still a lot of memory left even
even on the microcontroller with less
performances
so you can easily add your own
application on double bass
so that's all that's all for the
hardware and software section you can
find more details on github
i would like to move to the next section
now and show you a usage example
there are usually two patterns for
people working in automotive security
either there are automotive engineers
who learn about security or there are
security engineers
who learn about automotive systems since
this is a security conference and i
assume most people do not need me to
explain how the platform can be used to
study
and research basic security topics i
will focus on the automotive side
the diagnostics and calibration topic is
already covered
by many security talks so i will not
spend time on this
so i will spend time on i will spend
time
on something that is not often mentioned
in security conferences
control algorithms and safety critical
hardware and software
and for this i would like to demonstrate
the design of a pid controller for
cruise control as an example
i will show you how being knowledgeable
in control systems may be relevant to
security engineers
and how many of the activities that are
done by engineers in the automotive
industry
can also be simulated using open source
tools including ramen
once we have an implement implementation
in c that works
i will then use it as a reference to
talk about safety critical systems
and the differences differences with
real ecu hardware
and software
so let's get started cruise control is
very simple when a human is controlling
the throttle with the accelerator pedal
depending on the skill thus the car may
have an
evil speed what we want is an ecu that
optimizes the control of the throttle
so that you can maintain a steady speed
an automatic car can be very easy to
model if you press the accelerator pedal
which opens the throttle you will get
speed out of your car
but the relationship between speed and
throttle is not as simple as the
multiplication
no we have to follow the laws of
dynamics in this case that the sum of
forces on the car
is equal to its mass times its
acceleration
we can consider that there is a force
pushing the core that is proportional to
the throttle
and that there is an opposite force
proportional to the speed due to
friction
when we solve this differential equation
equation what we expect to see
is the speed follow an exponential curve
and a simple way to control the speed
that may come to your mind is open-loop
control
you make some measurements on the flat
road of the relationship between
throttle and maximum speed
and you keep it in a lookup table when
the user asks the ecu to reach a certain
speed
the ecu can use the lookup table to find
what photo controls should be applied
based on path measurements
and this may work in some situations but
according to the laws of dynamics
as soon as we reach an upward slope the
card will lose speeds
will lose speed because of gravity
so at least that is what we expect but
we should verify that on the canvas
this is something we can use ramen for
here i am using an external kind of
can adapter it to a second pc
on that pc i simply receive data from
the physical canvas
for the rest of the section i will only
be modifying the firmware
on the powertrain ecu i will not change
the simulator
i will not even reboot it
so in the simulator i drove around in
the city to find
to find a nice place to experiment more
precisely i looked for a place with a
flat road
followed by another and upward slope
then i programmed the portrait ecu to
apply a constant photon
which is only one line of code and after
reprimanding the ecu
i left the car drive straight and i
recorded data
from the canvas
i use an open source tool for campus
analysis called bus master
bus masters allows you to load dbc files
or to input manually the format of your
account frames here
i simply told bus master what were the
kind objection ids of the photo control
message
and the speed sensor message and what
was the format of the payload
once i do that i can blow the evolution
of the photon and speed
over time and the results we get are
exactly what we expected from our
differential equations
the speed of the vehicle is following an
expansion curve and as soon as we reach
the upward slope we start losing speed
because the throttle is constant
there are some noise and non-linearities
at low speed but overall it seems our
model of the car is correct
we are approaching the problem correctly
what we can see here
is that it takes around 40 seconds for
one test drive
and 40 seconds it's already too long so
before testing the ecu in the driving
simulator
we want to use a software that can
simulate different set equations
so that you can see the impact of the
cruise control algorithm directly
without having to wait 40 seconds most
of the time this is done using a
professional 2
tool such as matlab or simulink matlab
and symmetric
but here we will use the open source
tool scilab
it has a graphical interface where we
can connect inputs and outputs
from a block diagram
differential equations are a bit hard to
deal with because the relationship
between inputs and outputs is
complicated what you typically do in
controlled theory
is use the laplace transform which will
change the variable from time t
to a complex number called s this may be
complicated without controlled fury
background but you just need to know
that the differentiation is equivalent
to multiplication by s
and that an integration is equivalent to
division by s
and our system easy is easier to model
with the laplace transform
because we now have a simple
relationship between throttle and speed
speed equals transfer function of car
times portal
and based on the measurement for the
canvas we can evaluate the transfer
the transfer function of the car to be
equal to
approximately one over one plus four s
we can simulate the core in scilab by
using a block function which has the
exact same transfer function
using scilab we can notice various
scenarios and get the results
immediately
here i am testing the scenario in which
we start from zero speed
apply a constant throttle and after 20
seconds we add a new force gravity
which corresponds to the slope and this
is what we call here the disturbance
and with scilab simulation we can verify
we get waveforms similar to
measurements on the can bus with a
constant photon the speed follows an
exponential curve that is close to
maximum speed
after around 14 seconds
and as soon as there is a disturbance
the gravity here showing green we can
check that the car loses speed
because there is no reaction from the
photon
so to fix that the solution is obvious
the ecu's need to have feedback
we need the ecu to make use of the speed
sensor data
that it can find on the canvas so that
it can adapt the throttle to the
actual speed of the vehicle
the first solution that may come to mind
to software engineers
is bank bank control the employment
control is quite simple
you measure the speed and if it is above
a certain threshold
you stop applying the throttle if it
goes below a certain threshold
you apply the throttle again this is
extremely easy to implement in c
on the ecu
and once we reprogram the ecu the ecu on
ramen we can make measurements of the
can bus
and verify that this time we are not
losing speed anymore
when we reach a slope but as you can see
there are some oscillations
and as you can imagine the oscillations
are not something very nice for
passengers
apparently people driving like this is
the reason cruise control was invented
i do not know that story is true but i
can't believe it
so my control may be a good start but it
is not good enough for cruise control
and the most famous algorithm used in
control theory is a pid controller
you can find a lot of resources online a
pid controller
is one of the control mechanism used in
software by the centralizing ai of
caller
in the pid controller you measure the
difference between the target speed and
the current speed
you call that difference the error
and you can control the throttle using
the sum of three control blocks
the error multiplied by kp the integral
of the error multiplied by ki
and the derivative of the error
multiplied by kd
kp ki and kd are called by constants
called gains
and you need to have a very fine tuning
of those gains to achieve optimal
control
here i can simulate a kd controller
using scilab
with different blocks remember that the
division by s
is an integration and then the
multiplication by s is a derivation
thanks to the simulation i am i am able
to try many values without having to
actually drive the car
and when we are able to find brake
values when we are able to find
correct values for the pid controller we
get this
so ecu is able to reach a target speed
quickly without oscillations and without
overshooting
the maximum speed
and when there is a disturbance to
gravity it will dynamically
adapt the controls of the throttle so
that the target speed is maintained
so this is good because this is what we
want for a cruise control
but either gain of only one control
block isn't correct
the speed of the vehicle may look like
something totally different
potentially dangerous and this is why
the integrity of calibration data is
important
not only from a safety point of view but
also from a security point of view
because an attacker should not be able
to make an ecu have a dangerous behavior
behavior with only one small change
and last thing i need to explain is how
to implement this algorithm in c
and this is not obvious because we are
dealing with integration and derivations
which are not
on which are not possible for digital
functions
so there are many ways to implement this
in a digital 3d controller in c
i will just explain two approaches
the first approach is to stay in the
stand in the time domain
and approximate the derivation by the
difference between two successive errors
divided by the sampling time and we can
approximate the integral
operation with a riemann sum
which is a running sum of all errors so
far multiplied by the sampling time
this may look a bit intimidating but
when you look at it closely
you can see it is just a combination of
constants
and values that can be computed from
current and past sensor values from the
canvas
so actual implementation in c looks like
this
we need to define two variables one to
store the running sum of errors
and when to store the error from the
previous control loop execution
in the control loop we define constant
gains for each stage
we compute the current error
we add the error to the sum of all
errors
we compute the difference between
current errors and previous error
we then add all those values with that
respective gain
to the output variable and we clone that
output
in case it goes out of bound
we then apply the throttle control and
save the current error
in the previous error variable for use
in the next iteration
the second approach is to use the
laplace the laplace transform of the pid
controller
we first need to convert it to a z
transform the equivalent of laplace
transform but for digital signals
it looks a bit complicated but there are
many tools to do the conversion for you
if you want to do the conversion by hand
one way is to use the
bi-linear transformation
in which we you replace s by this
to approximate the z transform of your
ecu
and again this me this may all look a
bit intimidating but you can actually
compute the throttle output
by using the throttle output from two
iterations ago
the current error the previous error and
the error before that
which can all be computed from sensor
values on the canvas
and while this control algorithm is
equivalent to our previous
implementation
it looks totally different
and what i would like to stress here
that identical control algorithm
may have very different software
implementations which may be relevant
for reverse engineers
i only show the first implementation not
waste time but you can see
now that the ecu in ramen is able to
make the car maintain a constant speed
with dynamic control of the throttle
so that's it for the example i just
wanted to show that ramen can be used
for realistic activities on the campus
and that the ecu's are not just doing
some random busy work
the control theory part may be
complicated and if that was going too
fast for you at least i hope it proves
there is a lot of things to discover and
experiment with
and that all that learning can be done
with open source tools
now i would like to discuss what would
have been different with ecu's because
as you can imagine
actual eco software is not as simple as
this
i will also also show you what
alternatives we have
technologies hidden behind ndas so that
we can get as close as we can to real
easy use
we show that ramen in ramen that this
cruise control ec worked
but we only tried it on a single
scenario namely a flat road
followed by an upward slope
but what about the scenario in which a
car in front is driving slowly
or what about the scenario in which we
are in a downward slope
in this case the ecu will not be able to
prevent the car from going too fast
because it does not have access to the
brakes which could lead to an accident
and the difficult problem here is not
whether you can think of one more
scenario
the difficult problem is can you think
of them all and are you sure
and thinking of all dangerous scenarios
quantifying the risk
and implementing countermeasures is what
makes automotive systems
really different
and to prove that an ecu is reasonably
safe you ideally need to follow iso
standard which is a standard for
functional safety the standard safety
the standard defines different
requirements at many levels
not all ecu's are equally critical so
safety relevant ecu's are assigned
an automotive safety integrity level
or ac for shots and ac a is a less
critical
level and sld is the most critical level
so if you were to design a real cruise
control ecu for use in a real car you
could not just
connect some random ecu to the canvas
and try it on the highway
you will need to go through a lot of
analysis just such as hazop hara
fme sdpa and so on usually there are so
many requirements
so they cannot be tracked with only a
human and a sheet of paper
they are managed using dedicated
dedicated tools such as rational doors
now let's discuss how the software will
be different
the main contribution of automotive
software is to realize control
algorithms safely
but without confirmations many things
could go wrong
for example there could be bugs in the
ecu application code
even without any bug the software may
not be robust enough when there are
transit errors in the hardware
there could be there could also be
problems with the two chains that
compile the firmware
and problems with the libraries and arto
and artos
and and when we have a close look at the
prd controller implementation
which seemed good enough in our testing
we can see it is actually a terrible
implementation
we are mixing integers and unsigned
integers and floats before
proper checks and type casting we are
not checking for overflows
and other random software issues
and this is not acceptable but for
safety and security
and in this case the problems were
obvious on purpose but sometimes it can
be very hard to spot because they stem
from very subtle computing issues
and those issues may lead to system
failures
so to avoid such scenarios the
automotive industry usually mandates the
use
of a language subset which restricts
what developers can do
but make sure that numerical errors are
less likely to happen
so usually usually in the automotive
industry the star that is used is
misracy
and it is very similar to certsi which
is popular in the security industry
using a language subset is only one
other requirements that are dictated by
iso 26262
there are many other requirements at a
high level they try to enforce a low
complexity of the software
for example by restricting the size of
components restricting the coupling
coupling between software components and
making sure the scheduling
is appropriate and there are not too
many interrupts
but they also have more concrete
requirements such as restricting
functions to one entry and one exit
point
forbid dynamic memory avoid global
variables
limit the use of pointers and so on
the other issues we have to deal with
which is unrelated to bugs
is 20 errors in the harsh environment
data is not always reliable there may be
bit flip
occurring outside of memory for example
because of noise
uncognition communication lines but
there also may be bit flips occurring
inside a microcontroller's memory
for example because of cosmic rays those
issues do not originate from software
they are originally from hardware
but they do need to be addressed by
software because remember
in the case of the example cruise
control ecu just one bit flip
could lead to unwanted behavior of the
ecu
of the car so to address these issues
automatic even controllers need special
counter measures for example having
redundant memory
or having redundant cpus
in easy use you will typically find
microcontrollers that have been designed
specially for automotive use all those
microcontrollers require you to sign an
nda
so you cannot just buy them and start
programming them
so that makes it a bit hard to study an
actual
ecu map controller and real automative
software
but iso 26262
is not the only standard for safety
critical systems
iso 26262 is actually derived from iec
6.508
so therefore and they are both similar
in their concepts
and iec61508 microcontrollers they do
not require ntas for most other
activities you may be interested in
and more completely brandman can be used
with stm42l4
or stn42l5 microcontrollers and for
those microcontrollers you do not need
an idea to download guidelines on how to
implement safe software
for example you can find a list of
features that are required for safety
applications
and you can request more data that you
would need to actually achieve
compliance with iec 6.508
such as the fmea and fmeda
but to obtain those data you would need
to sign an mda
no i personally do not think that those
data are essential for
education and research so using such
microcontrollers
is a good alternative but again let me
stress that this is unhappy for learning
and researching not for actually using
the car
i don't have time to detail other safety
features let me just talk about memory
redundancy
since this one impacts the code of the
application
of the example cruise control ecu
so in the example we wrote the gain of
each stage in code memory
defining them as constants for a safer
application they should not be here
they should they belong to another
section the data flash where ecc
protection can be activated
if possible calibration data should be
stored twice with checksums and
preferably max
if you are not familiar with ecc memory
it is a kind of memory
that can detect b flips and sometimes
automatically corrects them
renault memory is also available for the
ram but not at all addresses
so in the application we have to ensure
that 50 critical variables
are placed in a section of ram in which
bitflips can be detected
in this case in section scrum 2 for data
in ram that
are actually constant such as the games
you may also want to activate script
activate
write protection a feature that is only
available in sram
2. okay last slide about software
in the example cruise control we're
using gcc2 chain
in iso 26262 it is a requirement to have
what is called
a dual confidence level to ensure that
two chains will not introduce errors
as it could be the case with some
optimizations so normally you could not
use gcc
real-time operating systems and
libraries may also add problems that is
why they need to be certified
both st 42 hull and free rotors are
compliant with biswasi
which is nice but they are not compliant
with iso 262
however it looks like it looks like st
is bringing azure archos into the
ecosystem
and that one is actually pre-satisfied
iso 2662 so
maybe in the future it would be an
option to experiment with actually with
an actual
iso 26262 operating system
so now let's talk a bit about hardware
in case it was not clear to you you
cannot use commercial electronics to
implement an ecu
smartphone vendors will offer why you
want you not to let a device in your car
because a parked car can reach excellent
temperatures
that commercial electronics are not
designed to resist
and if you and if you think that the
life inside the cabin is hard you should
think about an ecu
which has to stay in the engine
compartment and operate without failures
and you would not think of putting a
smartphone on an arduino here
and trust your life with it
and extreme temperatures are just one of
the many environmental factors that make
it difficult for this you to stay
reliable
the ecu also need to resist high
humidity
corrosive gases vibrations microcuts
load damps electrostatic discharges
electromagnetic noise
and so on
and when subjected subjected to such a
harsh environment
many things could go wrong with
electronics you probably know about
corrosions
but many other physical phenomena are at
risk of happening
to the components solder cracks
incremental
growth whiskers dendrites
electromigration
etc for example whiskers are later
growing out of electrical components and
dendrites are meta leading the plus side
towards the minus side
and many other phenomena may result in a
dangerous fader
so obviously ecu's need to be designed
to resist harsh environments
and heart control measures against all
those potential failures ecu's need to
pass various tests that simulate
that simulate harsh environments those
tests are usually defined by
manufacturers and the test
specifications
are made are not made public what is
made public however is the test
specifications for individual
electronic components and those tests
are usually defined by ac
so electronic the automotive electronic
console
and you can have a look at them online
for ramen we try to follow design
deadlines similar to those of weak ecu's
but of course we cannot follow actual
rules as it would be much less
accessible
completely we selected ac 200 grade zero
components for everything
except connectors and microcontrollers
because those may require nda or not be
easily accessible
depending on the path reference ecu
microcontrollers may be usable from -40
to 125 degrees
ramen try to stay close to automatic
grade but it is still not automatic
grade especially in the reliability
department
so it cannot be used as a real pc
and the reason we try to stay close to
automotive hardware is to help
researchers evaluate the impact of
manufacturing tolerances and
environments
because remember manufacturers are
making millions of cars
candy that needs to operate on a large
operating range
so if you are developing for example a
security technology that relies on
hardware characteristics
such as the clocks of the ecu's we need
to prove that
the technology works despite manufacture
manufacturing tolerances
and harsh environments and with ramen it
is easy to have a large sample of eco
networks
and since they are they can easily fit
in various testing equipment
and now let's move on to the last
section security
so in the automotive industry you just
cannot apply the same reasoning as you
do in many other industries
for example a credit card if it detects
it the temperature is too cold
it may think that it is a tempering
attack and decide to shut down
because it is not safety critical on the
other hand
the car needs to start quickly because
the user should not be left out in the
code
and also credit cards have an expiration
date
so they do not need to guarantee
security for more than a few years
but cars do not have a course do not
have an expiration date
if they are well maintained they may be
used for several decades
and the security technologies should
keep on working
so in the end automotive security
technologies have different requirements
unfortunately according to past research
a security technology
is often less reliable when you extend
its operating temperature range
and its lifetime for example at low
temperatures you may become vulnerable
to cod boot attacks
at high temperatures it has also been
shown that electronics tend to be less
reliable
concerning leaching attacks and in those
papers high temperature means something
like
60 degrees or 100 degrees celsius
far from the maximum temperature
required for some issues
also it has been shown that a higher age
for electronics usually results in
different security properties
and you may think that the safety
features of automotive microcontrollers
will prevent some attacks such as
glitching attacks
but it has been shown that ecc memories
are also susceptible to engineering
attacks
and that even iso26262 slt
microcontrollers with the highest level
of safety
may be susceptible to glitching so
safety features
often have but they are really enough to
ensure security
what is also different with automotive
is what you need is that you need
to rethink the strategy in case of
security problems
for example with credit cards it is not
uncommon for office
authentication to fail randomly when the
credit card fails to work
usually you just need to try it once
more and it will be it will probably
work
and even if it fails again no light is
at risk
but the car cannot have the same
strategy if you add authentication to
the cam break
if you add authentication to the
breakdown message
and you start receiving break request
messages that fake authentication
what should the card really do should
the card really do
because it may be a cyber attack which
you want to avoid
but you should not rule out the
possibility of a roundabout function
or a false positive for an intrusion
detection system
and by adding complexity into the system
you always increase the odds of
the odds of a problem and which one
would be worse between breaking because
of a cyber attack
or not breaking because of a malfunction
and there is no easy way to answer that
question but what i want to stress here
is that many security countermeasures
that people suggest for car
such as encrypting the canvas
permanently disabling the backboards
debug ports or obfuscating the firmware
they may not necessarily be the best
ideas because if you suspect a
malfunction with an ecu
you need to investigate the problem
seriously because it may
harm people you cannot just replace the
car as you would
with a credit card or a smartphone
so technologies that can really take
into account both automotive
requirements
and security requirements are better and
we should make sure that education and
research in these areas
are accessible to many researchers
without ndas or prohibitive costs
now of course you can use ramen to try
out different attacks the first obvious
one
is to inject messages to alter the
behavior of the car
here for example the brakes
another kind of security that i did not
mention in this presentation is physical
security for sensors and actuators
here i am demonstrating what happens
when i overtake the control of the
steering wheel
activator a human will probably break
in this situation the self-driving
algorithm in kara here does not realize
it has lost control of the steering
wheel
and it is still trying to correct the
trajectory when a better decision
would be to stop the car
so this is the end of the presentation
we developed an inexpensive
safe and interactive platform to study
and research automotive systems
the platform is accessible to beginners
it is not
automotive grade but it is close enough
for research and educational purposes
the project is open source and with
permissive licenses
if you have questions or ideas do not
hesitate to contact us
especially if you are involved with
education research trainings ctf
etc and thank you for watching
kami thanks for this comprehensive talk
this was
amazing um we unfortunately don't have
much time for a question answers but
there's one
uh question that popped up which is
about the hardware and your pcb how did
you design it how much does it cost
actually how can you how can you get
actually hold of that thing
yes so i designed everything with
keycard and i mean
i think a few years ago it was very hard
to design hardware hardware
but now you have footprints libraries
available
online it has become very easy the bomb
was between 50 to 100 euros for a
quantity of one
the microcontrollers are obviously the
expensive parts
and the pcb pcb and assembling part it
is up to the pcb
fabrication fabrication service if you
have questions
just ask me on github i would be happy
to answer
wow
bye