all right it's five o'clock somebody get
started thanks for coming out I'm gonna
be talking about a tool I developed
called ice breaker it's a pretty dope
tool not gonna lie it's great we're
getting a foothold on Active Directory
domains so the use case for this tool is
going to be when you have a Dropbox on
the internal network and you need access
to the Active Directory environment but
you don't have credentials you don't
have anything to enter that Active
Directory environment with so Icebreaker
will give you credentials just by being
on the same internal network it'll do it
all automatically with one command I'm
Dan McInerney I'm a senior pentester
with coal fire I'm gonna get coal fire a
big shout out here because they paid for
months of my development time on this
which is awesome I'm part of the coal
fire labs R&D team which is headed up by
Red Team legend Ryan Jones and tool
master marchello Salvati who wrote crack
map exec and Deathstar and some other
stuff that we all use every day I love
those people and I'm really happy to be
part of their team well that's my github
that's my Twitter I really only tweet
about like my tools and stuff so it's
kind of boring now so let me give you a
little overview here you have say a
cally box on an internal network or any
kind of Linux box really what this is
going to do is perform five different
attacks automatically these five attacks
will be executed with the goal of
getting either plaintext credentials or
ntlm hashes whenever it gets net ntlm
hashes it will attempt to crack those
hashes automatically using John the
Ripper and a custom word list the custom
word list I'm using
comes from sec lists github
downloaded all 32 million passwords on
the sec lists github and then i narrowed
that list down to default active
directory passable passwords so for
instance I got rid of all the passwords
that are all numbers I got rid of all
the password through all uppercase all
the passwords that are all lowercase
because by default Active Directory
enforces a seven character minimum with
three out of five of the rules being
uppercase lowercase symbol number so on
and so forth so essentially I just
narrowed that 32 million password list
down to Active Directory specific of 1
million passwords so password cracking
goes very quickly and it also saves all
the hashes just in case it doesn't
actually automatically crack them you
can just crack them on your own cracker
machine if you want to do that so here
the five attack that's going to do we're
gonna do rid cycling in a reverse
brute-force SCF file upload SCF actually
stands for shell command file so I'm not
really sure I always keep saying SEF
file I'm probably gonna say it again
it's like hey say an ATM machine but
whatever SCF file upload llm in RMB TNS
and mdns poisoning which is highly
effective net ntlm version 2 relaying
using the in packet library which is my
favorite attack and then IP version 6 at
DNS poisoning this is the newest attack
that includes using a tool called MIT m6
from fox IT or maybe it's fox it again
I'm not really sure but that's a really
cool tool that does some really neat
like complex attacks to get network
hashes from people on the Active
Directory environment it's pretty easy
to set up you're gonna want to just get
clone it then you just CD into the
folder that you just get cloned you're
gonna run the setup script and then
you're going to do pip end install - - 3
which creates a virtual environment for
Python and then pip end shell to enter
the virtual environment and finally you
can just run it as simply as this
iceberg ergot PI - L targets - Ella's
list of targets so that's gonna be a
list of IP addresses or cider notations
things like that you can also give it an
XML file
so if you want to do the end map
yourself then you can do the end map
save the output as an XML file and then
give it the - X and then the path to the
XML file that you just scanned it with
it will do the end map by itself it
you want it to so it could save you a
little bit of time but you know it'll be
more customizable if you give it a
heading off yourself I'd really like to
do a docker of this because it takes a
while to install if you have a if you're
on a system that has low resources I
mean it can take like an hour to install
because compiling John and some other
stuff so if anybody knows anything more
about docker than I do and I'll give you
20 bucks to make a docker file so
largely this script is just glue between
known attacks this is not a novel
there's no novel attacks in this tool
I'm just taking all of the best Network
attacks for getting Active Directory
credentials when you don't have access
to the Active Directory environment
whatsoever and I glued them together a
bit so this is the pipe on each dozen
here are going to look at this and be
like what you're just using sub-process
for all this yes sub-process is the core
because I'm calling other tools but
there's quite a bit of complexity that
went into this based on my personal
experiences as a pen tester for three
years of Fortune 500 companies what
works the best how to automate the whole
process so it's like 1500 lines of code
or 1600 lines of code or something so
although this is the core it's not just
calling sub-process alone it also has
some async features a sync feature
specifically to speed up the reverse
brute-force which I'll talk about in
just a second so attack number one the
way this script works is we're gonna
have it do the fast attacks first and
then it'll just linger infinitely on the
long attacks that you can just wait for
people to send you their credentials so
this is gonna be the fastest attacker
it's gonna be rid cycling in a reverse
brute-force the difference between a
brute force and reverse brute force is
that a reverse brute force is going to
take a short list of user names
I'm sorry a long list of user names and
a short list of passwords the reason
we're doing that is that we don't get
account lock outs so if there's a null
session an OS MB session meaning an SMB
session that a computer can connect
connect to another computer using just a
blank username and password if we have
that we can do an attack called rid
cycling now every account in an Active
Directory domain is going to have a SID
a security identifier the SIDS a big
long number
the
are the last numbers after the - of the
city so what you can do is cycle the rid
number because you start at 1,000 cuz
that's when all regular users start at
regular user is gonna be like a big long
number - 1000 that'll be the first
domain user second domain user will be -
1,001 so what you can do is you can
connect over SMB and you can cycle those
rid numbers to get actual user names out
of them then you take that list of valid
user names and you pass it to another
computer and you try various passwords
in order to brute-force so this is going
to be a fast and dumb attack nothing too
extraordinary here but it will be
asynchronous add some asynchronous city
asynchronous for those who don't know is
when you want to do concurrent
programming python has had a problem
with concurrent programming since its
inception because it has something
called the Gil the Gil prevents you from
truly having a threaded program at any
given time you'll only be using or
interacting with a single thread so they
have they have the threading as a
library but a lot of problems with it
so what Python did was moved to a
synchronicity where there's a little
event loop it spins in a circle and
whenever something happens it react to
whatever has happened and if nothing's
happening in this event over here it
just keeps on going so I have a
synchronously testing all the past the
user names that you can get out of a
null SMB session we find the null
instead be session through and map and
then we pass it these two passwords I
chose these two passwords specifically
because they are the most common
passwords I see in Active Directory
environments over my past three years I
see them all the time if you have a list
of 50 to maybe 75 usernames one of these
passwords will pop one of those
usernames we've got password with an @
and a zero and we've got spring 2018 or
summer 2018 the script is smart enough
to recognize what season to this and so
it'll automatically update this password
as the season change the reason this is
so common is because there's a ton of
Active Directory corporations and group
policy that says you have to change your
password every three months so humans
being lazy they'll be like alright well
spring 2018 and then when they have to
change it in
more months it'll be like alright well
and now it's summer 2018 so we'll change
it to that so this is highly highly
effective for these two passwords you
can add other passwords to the brute
force if you want you can feed the
script to lists there's an option for
that I generally don't just because
there's no need to this captures an
enormous amount of them so in addition
to the read cycling to get user names we
can also use the harvester for user
names so a lot of corporations will have
an email address like Dee McInerney at
coal fire com so if you can scrape their
website for email addresses you can just
take the first half that email address
and use that as a valid Active Directory
user name so you can also pass it the
harvester which will scrape it for more
user names you'll get a nice long list
of user names that you then reverse the
brute force with these two and you'll
very surprisingly catch a lot of people
with these two passwords this is what it
looks like in practice
you'll see it says the domain was found
no session found so now we're doing RPC
client I'm sorry Rhydian um to do the
actual rid cycling and we found some
passwords we got Steve and bomb attack -
so attack ones just gonna take new
minutes we're gonna be done with that
now we're move on to attack - SCF file
upload SCF files are a strange thing in
the Microsoft world
they're called shell command files I
don't really understand why they exist
I'm happy they do but basically they're
supposed to be used for doing simple
Explorer actions or something like let
you double click an SCF file and you can
open up Explorer - I don't know a share
or something I don't really get it I
don't really care what I do care about
is the fact that it will send your hash
to me via an SEF file so what the script
does is use an nmap NSC script
identifies all the anonymously writable
shares on the network now granted this
is not super common but if you have a
large enough organization there will be
some anonymously writable shares once it
finds an anonymously writable share such
as Windows 10 slash pictures it will
create an S CF file with an icon
that points to the attackers machine now
what's crazy about this is that when a
user opens this share windows 10
pictures without even opening the SCF
file or interacting with the SAF file in
any way shape or form their hash is sent
to you the net ntlm version - hash of
their account for active directory is
sent to you they don't even have to know
this SDF file exists they don't have a
double click it they have to do nothing
all I would do is open up the share and
their password sent to you this was
patched in Windows 10 not patched in
Prior versions so if you've done any pen
testing recently you'll notice that
Windows 7 is the most common operating
system Windows XP still has a huge
market share but it doesn't really
matter that this was passion Windows 10
just because somebody's gonna have
Windows 7 or Windows 8 3rd and
double-click on that sharing and you're
gonna have the password you're gonna get
the hash and then it'll automatically
crack the hash like I said earlier this
is what it looks like it's super simple
we've got shell command - I don't know
if that does icon file equals that's
what matters that's the important part
that's my attacking machine right there
I filed the ICO doesn't have to exist
like I don't even get it I don't get
anything about this this file or why it
exists but I don't have to you just
upload that to the anonymous notable
shares and whenever someone connects you
get the password you do have to be
running responder or some sort of
multicast or broadcast based poisoner in
order to capture their hash but this
tool already does that so you don't
worry about that this is what it looks
like in practice
so it'll find the writable shares it'll
say attempting to write it will then run
SMB client to write the file it keeps a
log of all this - so if there's the
option to delete these files after the
review hit ctrl C on the program and
then it also after it writes the file
sometimes I'm gonna false positive and
I'll say successfully wrote it then
checks to make sure that the file is
actually there so it goes out and then
does a list of that file share and make
sure that the SCF files is actually
written there
so attack number 3 attack 1 1 fast
tattoo going to be really fast as well
attack number 3 is going to be a complex
name but
simple attack l-lemon R&B TNS mdns
poisoning
what all of these are are multicast or
broadcast based protocols what that
means is it's sending out a message to
either some or all of the local subnet
or a layer 2 which will usually be the
subnet what these protocols do is
essentially identical to DNS it's just
mapping an IP address to a hostname and
like DNS it implicitly trusts responses
unlike a DNS there's nothing like a TX
ID field in in LM in our 10 p TN s and M
DNS which means that poisoning it is
just silly easy so I'm gonna use a tool
called responder by Laurent Gaffey I
don't know if he's actually French but I
like to pronounce it like it's French
because it looks like it I think he'd be
ok with that
so because it implicitly trusts
responses you can just run responder and
then whenever a computer I think I've a
diagram here whenever a computer sends
out hey I'm looking for the Google host
will say slash slash Google DNS is going
to be number 1 if DNS can't find it then
it falls back to L LM in our mb t NS or
mdns most the time it's ll M&R once it
falls back it sends out a blast of
packets saying hey where is google dns
can't help me where is this host named
Google and then what you do is responder
is say I'm Google you know connect to me
that's great and then they say oh okay
cool and they pass you their net ntlm
version to hash that's quite nice of
them it's also quite an easy attack to
perform because all you do is run
responder so what this is just gonna do
is just run responder and it's one
responder for 10 minutes because you'll
catch pretty much the same passwords
hashes when you run responder alone as
when you run it in conjunction with the
next attack which is ntlm relay most the
time I skip attack 3 specifically for
that reason I'll just move on straight
to attack for one thing I didn't mention
is you can skip any part of these
attacks you can skip the LR poisoning
the SCF file upload the the RP there
so a lot of my friends like to just use
this script solely for the ntlm relay so
they skip everything except attack 4 & 5
which is fine I mean that's what I built
before it looks like in practice this is
the ntlm version to hash right here we
get it from the username fob domain lab
and then this is the actual hash so
we'll say it'll say hash found and then
I'll say running John the Ripper so John
the Ripper will run a max of 10
processes at a time and it'll just do a
quick little word list and rule-based
attack there now it says password found
lab Bob password you'll notice that
didn't come from responder this is all
you get from responder that password
found came from the John cracking the
net ntlm version 2 password oh it's nice
of responder to that it actually skips
Bruce the captured hashes I don't know
small detail oh yeah one last thing on
this one is all of these hashes are
stored in the hashes folder every time
it gets in that until I'm hash it stores
it hashes folder it's pretty easy just
to concatenate all those hashes if you
want into one file and then send it off
your cracker box if the 1 million
password list fails you attacked and
reformed this is probably a favorite one
Doug reports ntlm relay so SMB relay is
a very old attack we've known about it
since I think like 2001 or something
it's a man-in-the-middle attack its SMB
SMB is the method of file sharing
essentially between windows computers to
oversimplify it so two computers can
connect to each other or SMB and they
can trade files and they can you know
read system information and stuff like
that it's over port 445 so this script
is going to use the impacted library
which is an incredible library written
by Alberto Cellino somehow one dude it
just maintains his whole library he's a
superhuman but he's got a tool called
ntlm relay X which is probably the
easiest way of doing ntlm relay ntlm
relay is necessary because net ntlm
hashes are different than ntlm hashes
ntlm hashes
the hashes that are stored in the Sam
database of the Windows computer you can
pass ntlm hashes as if they were just a
plaintext password so those are
fantastic net ntlm is a handshake based
protocol which means you can't just pass
that hash we saw on the last slide to
another computer and have it
authenticate for you because it's going
to be a different hash every time you
use it
so what ntlm relay does is it relays the
hash instead of passing the hash so you
can be right in the middle of the
connection the hash will be sent to you
and you just pass it right on to the
next computer in the next computer that
you're trying to run next commands on
will say yes that works fine what would
you like me to do and you say you drop
what the victim wants it to do and you
give it what you want to do one caveat
is SMB signing has to be disabled SMB
signing is when you sign the SMB
connection so that you can't jump in the
middle of it it'll break the connection
that was SMB signing being disabled has
been default since I want to sell like
Windows 7 I think the latest versions of
Windows 10 now have it enabled by
default my purposes sure about that but
there's a very valid reason to disable
SMB signing which is what many - most
system administrators do and that's
because it's a 15% network latency
increase so there is a very valid reason
for not having SMB signing enabled and
it's also disabled by default for all
older versions of Windows you also have
to have SMB version 1 enabled that's
also default I think the latest versions
of Windows 10 probably take that out but
if you're running a network then there
is an excellent chance they're gonna
have SMB version 1 open because of
backwards compatibility issues and
you're gonna have SMB signing disabled
for the speed of it so those are not
those are caveats but their caveat that
I rarely encounter in the wild vast
majority of time I see both SMB version
1 enabled an SMB signing disabled at
Walter Cellino is working on a release
for ntlm relay that will work with SMB
version 2 so that's nice cool but it's
not really that important so let's start
what the difference is between the ntlm
hash and net until I'm hash that's an
ntlm hash that's a net until I'm hash
hache will change every time that
computer makes a connection another
computer that hash will not change
because that's just the had the MD for
hash of their actual Active Directory
password this is what gets sent when SMB
connections are being made and that's
where you're going to capture most of
the password hashes is when SMB
connections are being made across the
network and you're poisoning them
remember these can be passed just like a
password these cannot so you can see
that these are names the admin the
domain is lab the challenge is Oh 8 CA
blah blah the LM hash LM is the old
version of how windows hash passwords I
literally in three years have not
encountered an organization that still
loud LM hashes when so I wouldn't really
worry about that for now the ntlm hash
is the actual final part of it starts at
that v right there and moves on down
that's the MD for hash of their Active
Directory password with some with the
challenge mixed in and some other stuff
too so it changes every time so here's
the current state of passing the hash
verses relaying relaying the hash again
can be done through SMB connections and
network connections and network shares
the computer sends the net ntlm hash and
you can relay that but you can't pass it
passing it is using the NT lan hashes
like a password so you can collect until
i'm hashes through tools such as
Metasploit hash dump so if you have an
administrative console on any computer
you can dump the Sam database there's a
PowerShell tool called invoke power dump
great name that you can also use to dump
the ntlm hashes and once you have those
ntlm hashes you can pass them now
Microsoft made a big thing maybe a year
ago or a year and a half ago about
having a pass the hash patch I think
that's what they actually called it was
patch for pass the hash which scared all
his pen testers because pass the hashes
dope and you can use it all the time you
don't even need their password you need
to crack anything just take this long
string of numbers it's the equivalent of
password it's very useful so there's all
these people up in arms like oh no they
they finally got rid of passed the hash
key component and pen testing well it
turns out it's actually not that simple
what they did was disable pass the hash
for everything other than the rid 500
account now we talked about the rid
every usernames gonna have a rid on a
network the rid 500 is the built-in
administrator domain user starter 1000
the rid 500 dollars gonna stay the same
now you can still pass the hash of the
rid 500 account which is like the most
important account I mean so although you
can no longer pass the hash of
administrators that aren't built-in
administrators you can still pass it for
the rid 500 so if you can dump the ntlm
hash database like you'll get the rid
500 it's just it's their patch was was
like new tour from the beginning I don't
really get it but that's fine and what's
even more fine is if you have
administrative access to these boxes you
can just flip a bit in flip a switch in
the registry and make it so you can pass
the hash of all the administrators
that's the filter administrator token
we're going to switch that to one so
that's no big deal
net until in version 2 hashes can't be
passed first of that like six times if
you want some more information about
this harm Joey has a blog it's really
tiny you can't read it it's just there
for reference I'll post the slides
online after this harm julie has a
really cool blog about pass the hash
patch that Microsoft tried to spit out
which details everything about it but
the most important thing is you can
still pass the hash you just can't pass
the hash with non built-in administrator
accounts here's what ntlm real a kind of
looks like so the victim there is going
to go she ate authentication you are
going to intercept that and pass it
along now the server is going to send
the the victim a challenge to add to
their hash essentially you're going to
copy that server challenge over the
victim the victim is gonna sign it
authenticate with the sign challenge and
then you're gonna pass it over to that
to the the server but here's where you
get a little tricky on the server says
your authentication is good to go you
the attacker say no no your
authentication is messed up and then you
can perform whatever actions you want on
the server so in this case we're going
to want to do things like add
administrative users
dump the password database things like
that so here's actually what the tool
does by default through ntlm relay once
it relays a hash and that hash the user
of that hash is an administrator on the
server that you are relaying it to it
will run several commands these are the
commands it's gonna be hard to see first
command it's going to do net user add
icebreaker with a set password and then
it's going to add that icebreaker user
the local administrators so even if
everything else fails on the rest of
this command you have administrative
access to this box until you don't want
it anymore
after that it's going to do spin up a
web server locally on port 443 and then
it's going to tell the remote server to
download invoke Kats ps1 invoke Kats is
an obfuscated mini cats command I have
added MSI bypass that I have tested
yesterday it still works
well a MSI is what Windows Defender uses
to like scan memory for PowerShell stuff
so I have an AMS I bypass in there so
Windows Defender is not going to catch
it it's also obfuscated using a tool
called invoke obfuscation by Daniel
Bohannon I want to say his name is
awesome tool really really cool you can
encode it through ASCII you can get rid
of all the strings
it just completely messes up antivirus
defenses so I have it encoded and I have
a MSI bypass and I have it local so that
you don't even need to have that
computer call out to the Internet to
pull this script down you just call out
to me and it'll run invoke mimikatz I
also changed the core function names for
me me cats so instead of doing - dump
creds I think is the original one you're
gonna do - passwords or PWS and actually
you're not gonna do any of this the
scrip is gonna do all that for you after
it's done invoke mimikatz
Nina Katz is going to scrape all of the
passwords and plaintext from memory
after it does that now we're going to
download the Sam database so we're gonna
the exact same thing we're gonna have
spin up a web server port 443 we're
gonna serve invoke power dump but I've
renamed it to invoke passwords PWS and
obfuscated it and added the a MSI bypass
so this is just going to fly through
antivirus it's not going to touch disk
at all and it's going to bypass Windows
Defender
then it runs invoke power dump so you
get all the plaintext credentials from
memory and you get all the ntlm hashes
which can be as good as a password using
invoke power dollar it's gonna do all
this in a hidden window and using an
encoded PowerShell command so let's talk
about attack of number five this is the
latest attack this is IP version 6 DNS
poisoning this is cool because Windows
networks are vulnerable by default to
this I don't know of more beautiful
words in the English language than
vulnerable by default because windows
networks prefer IP version 6 so if you
have a Windows network that's not set up
for IP version 6 you better windows
network that's just IP version 4 it's
gonna call your every computer that
connects to that Active Directory
environment it's gonna call out and say
hey what should my IP address be where
is this webserver and so on and so forth
you can just hijack that using this MIT
m6 tool because it's going to say no
this now works action IP version 6
network so ignore everything the
administrator setup and listen to me and
it does this attack in a sort of a
complex way Microsoft tried to patch
this so pentesters have used the w pad
file for a long time to get password
hashes w pad file is Windows proxy
auto-detection whenever you join in a
domain your computer's automatically
gonna go out and search for WPD domain
name or whatever
now attackers are taking advantage of
this by doing things like spinning up
their own W pad server on the network
and forcing it to take ntlm
authentication then you can get an ntlm
hash but net until i'm hash marks a
patched at though so you can't do that
anymore but MIT m6 just kind of skirts
around that patch by pretending to be a
W pad server so that whenever a computer
tries to connect to the Internet they
will use your computer as a proxy but
instead of asking for authentication
immediately it says there's no
authentication just go ahead and query
whoever you want so their query Google
comm as soon as I am an in the middle
six it gets that query for an outside
website it says oh well I didn't need
authentication to become your W
server but Google needs your
authentication in order to visit the
site and of course the computer just
complies because that's Microsoft's way
and it sends the net until on hash to
you so it's a it's a convenient little
workaround to Microsoft's patch of the W
pad attacking issue now the final attack
here I'm sorry let me mention one more
thing is that when we're doing attack
number five reps are wearing three
programs at the same time running ntlm
relay X we're running IP version
we're running MIT m62 poison the IP
version 6 and then we're also running
responder to capture the hashes
themselves all of the configuration
files and everything are written by
already by the script Icebreaker dot pi
so you don't have to worry about setting
anything up Icebreaker just does
everything for you you just hit enter
and you'll win now the final attack it's
sort of a tongue-in-cheek it's tack
number 6 this is once you get
credentials once Icebreaker is able to
get credentials attack the fake attack
number 6 is just gonna send you straight
to domain admin so marchello Salvati
one of my best friends and co-workers
what a tool called Death Star Death Star
is a tool that hooks into the API of
Empire Empire being like Metasploit it's
like a c2 server so Empire can go get an
agent on a computer and you're running
the Empire server and then you can run
PowerShell scripts on the remote server
like invoke power dump and Nina Katz and
stuff so it's just like Metasploit so
what ice breaker does is it kicks off
Empire and it kicks off Death Star and
then Death Star just sits there waiting
for a shell from Empire and as soon as
icebreaker can relay a hash from an
administrative user to another computer
then it'll automatically run the Empire
launcher agent code on that remote
computer so that means that we get an
agent in our empire shell and our Empire
server and then Death Star sees that
agent and then starts just automatically
kicks off the domain admin acquisition
it automatically does domain recon
but automatically does lateral spread so
it just bounces around computer the
computer dumping credentials from
plaintext capturing ntlm hashes until it
finds a computer that has a domain admin
logged in and you get the domain admins
password and then it'll just keep Empire
up for you so it'll be two windows guest
star will say hey we got domain admin on
this shell and you can just go over to
the Empire window and just interact with
that shell and now your you guys don't
you have any shell on there when you
cancel icebreaker when you close out of
icebreaker these windows will stay up so
you're not going to lose your sessions
to Empire anything by by killing
icebreaker you will keep all of that I
did give it two options so in order to
run this you do - - Auto and either team
ox or X term
this was because X term feels this whole
thing is just kind of bolted on is like
a second like a fake sixth attack
because it would just make my life
easier even though it's not really core
functionality program I don't think so I
called it I have X tournament team X X
term does not require any user
interaction - you - - Auto space X term
little extra mental pop up but X term
feels I don't know it feels kind of
dirty it's kind of a nice looks gross
and amateurish
so I also included the T MUX option
which requires you to open a new
terminal start up a team-up session and
then this will just use the to the
team-up session instead that's in case
you don't have a graphical interface
external requires a graphical interface
T MUX does not so if you're on a remote
device and you're deploying icebreaker
and you want to use this tap you'll want
to use the T MUX option so you don't
have to forward x11 and have these ugly
windows popping up and stuff but I'll
show you a little demo of what this
looks like here so we're gonna do a live
demo which is never recommended I didn't
sacrifice anything but my sleep and the
problem with live demos is that you have
to have a full lab environment in
addition to the code and it's the lab
environment that really messes us up
sometimes because Windows 8 has an
expired license and you'll notice it's
not powered on because it shuts off
every hour because it's a trial version
I ran out of rearm x' so that was a
problem one time so we're gonna let that
boot up and then I am going to kick off
ice breaker and I'm going to explain a
little bit about this lab we have three
machines in the lab we have Windows
Server 2016 we have Windows 10 and
have windows 8 eventually Windows 10 has
a user on it who is not a local admin
this is Steve everybody say hello Steve
you will know I'm sure you can't read
this let me see if I can zoom in or
something I can't so I'll just read it
out net local group administrators and
we will notice that Steve is not an
administrator on this machine Steve is a
regular domain user Steve is however an
administrator on Windows 8.1 so we are
going to log in first as Bob spring 2018
in case anybody's wondering so we're in
login is Bob here it is it summer oh and
then we're gonna log it we're gonna
login as a domain admin here as well
switch account damn da core D 1 D a very
secure QWERTY one da however is not in
the password list so all right here
we're gonna run so we have Windows 10
was Steve logged in Steve is a like
regular domain user on this box he is an
administrator however on Windows 8.1
which also has a domain admin logged in
and whenever a domain admin is logged
into a box you can pull those
credentials out of the memory and you'll
notice that we're window we have the
domain admin logged in at Windows 8.1
because by default Windows 10 does not
allow me me cats to dump plaintext
potentials unless you switch a registry
key again like Microsoft puts in all
these fun little security services and
then it gives you a very easy way of
disabling them either way I want to make
this lab as default as possible so the
only things I have disabled on here I've
actually manually enabled SMB version 1
on Windows 10 and then I don't think I
actually had to do anything with Windows
SMB signing I think that was already off
so I've made very little changes to this
domain and here's the command were gonna
run we're gonna do icebreaker - X X
being XML I'm speaking zoom in here
definitely zoom in here I'll just keep
zooming whatever icebreaker - X means
we're going to use XML so I have already
run the end map because you know
interests of time savings I'm going to
skip a TAC 3 Secretary's Ella responder
LM in our poisoning
you can again you can skip any of these
attacks a one through five you could
have it just do one of them you can do
all of them I'm gonna skip tech 3 just
in the interest of time because it runs
for 10 minutes and it will get the same
demo effect out of the attack 4 and 5
and then finally running it with the - -
auto X term so because we're not
remoting or SS aging into a remote box
we can use the X term windows and not
forward x11 and all that ugly stuff so
we will hit enter wait let me just
we just confirm everything's here okay
we've got Steve logged in we got Windows
server running and everybody is
connected cool we're good to go
okay parsing hosts we found SMB open on
those hosts the domain controller was
found via a port scan Jesus slow down
yeah I'm I'm gonna wait one second here
wait for death star to kick off so
Empire just kicked off because we're
already on attack 4 it's just blazingly
fast
here's Death Star Death Star's kicked
off okay good now let's go back to here
and let's scroll up a little bit I don't
even know we can't screw up anymore so
if i zoom out there we go okay so we
parse the hosts we have SMB open we have
domain controller found based on the
port scan we're starting to attack one
read cycling and anole SMB sessions into
reverse brute-force so first of checks
for Nolan Bessie and null SMB sessions
and this is what it's going to do to
check for the no SMB sessions we need
RPC client so actually some research was
done recently they said RPC client can
give
negatives when looking for usernames and
rid cycling so I'm gonna replace our PC
client with the new Python tools that
have come out but for right now this is
fine username nothing so we're using our
PC client to connect over SMB to 1 to 9
we're not using a username we're not
using a password and we're just going to
execute the LSA query that'll give us a
little bit of information about the
domain it's really just there to see if
we get any information back and if we
get information back we know we have no
lesson B session and we can move on with
the attack so we have a bunch of users
found we got Dan da Dan Winton Bob Jace
Nichol and Steve so we reviewed reverse
brute-forcing using spring 2018 are you
sure it's summer
that's only June first all right I'll
have to also check that out I could have
sworn someone start like June 6th or
something
but anyways we've got we're doing spring
2018 and password against and we're
testing these usernames against this one
IP address so this was actually a little
bit complicated to figure out how to
balance the speed here in the
asynchronous 'ti how to test these
usernames against a single IP address
and only test them once but you know
I've got it worked out we found the
passwords found and I win 10 and we
found Bob who is spring 2018 NEX we're
going to attack - so these passwords
gonna be saved and the file called found
passwords that txt and it moves on to
attack - SCF file upload - anonymously
writable shares for hash collection we
found a writable share at pictures we
wrote it it seemed that worked looking
good
fine now we move on that's a very fast
one that's only gonna take like a couple
seconds we're skipping attack 3 or
moving straight to attack 4 which is
ntlm relay with responder and ntlm relay
X so we started the web server to host
the PowerShell payloads for once we
relay and then we are running Empire and
Deathstar oops oh my god
so this long thing is you'll notice
right here it says - - see PowerShell
knops one ball that this is the actual
command that's going to get run on the
remote system once the relaying has been
performed and it's very long then I
attack five kicks off we're running MIT
m6 so at this point we're running three
three programs until in relay MIT m6 and
responder we did get a connection and we
did find a password already that would
be John the Ripper cracked that password
and ulster okay now we'll go to the
actual the fun part here so we've
already captured a bunch of passwords
here is Death Star Empire running we're
gonna go over to Windows 10 now Windows
10 has Steve in here Steve a regular
domain user not an administrator on
Windows 10 he's an administrator on
Windows 8.1 so as Steve we're going to
type net use to connect to a share and
we're just gonna put in a fake share
this way DNS fails and Steve will fall
back to ll M&R which we can then poison
so we'll hit enter username lab - Steve
password San Diego seven and I'll say Oh
an error occurred the password is not
correct
well shocks now you'll notice here a
little you won't notice because I can't
zoom it on these but a new agent was
formed right here
we've got a new agent in Empire and as
soon as Empire gets the agent now Death
Star is gonna take off I wonder if I can
zoom in here no no zooming alright I'll
just guess almost read it an empire is
running under the user Bob I know I'm
sorry they had some processes that were
found in the user Bob some processes
they're found Lord and da and now we're
PS injecting into the process that the
domain administrator is running
that way after repeat inject we can
steal their token if you steal a token
you have the authority of the domain
admin so that's what my death star is
doing right now
now Death Star there's a major problem
and the problem is that entire empire
changes all the time it has only one
maintainer god bless his soul Chris and
it's just more bug-ridden today than I
think I've ever seen it before so I have
this pegged to a specific version of
Empire that I know works and I have
death star peg to the right one but
Empire is constantly changing its
options and stuff so Death Star breaks
pretty much with every new empire
release it's a big problem it's not a
problem here I pegged them to the
versions at work but it'll be a hassle
to update those so what I'm doing
actually is running a tool called MSF
net pone it's Death Star but it's for
Metasploit because Metasploit API hasn't
changed in years and that way I won't
have to update that tool like every week
eventually I'll just incorporate that
into this program instead of Death Star
Empire Death Star has started lateral
movement started domain Prive esque in
order to do domain probe ass get checks
for the group policy passwords file and
if there's no group policy password file
and it just does lateral movement and
then dumps the credentials and so on and
so forth that's their what's called the
credential shuffle it'd be cool if we
could incorporate bloodhound into this
too yet you can you can actually
download the bloodhound graph into CSV
format and so I'm looking into a way in
MSF net poem to either ingest bloodhound
or just do the manual lateral spread
technique stuff
so now RPS injecting PS injecting means
we're injecting into a separate process
and then we can steal our token
another problem with Death Star is that
although it's threaded the threading
doesn't really seem to work so it seems
to be a synchronous program not a
concurrent one which is why this is
going to take a really long time so I'm
basically just gonna wrap up my
presentation especially since you can't
read any of this and if anybody has any
questions I'll answer some questions for
the next couple minutes while this tries
to get domain admin
yeah this is not a stealth tool not a
stealth tool no this is for when you are
dropped in and they know you're there
yeah so the reverse brute-force is going
to send off alarms the SCF file upload
is probably the sneakiest of the attacks
and tell them relay I don't know how
well a antivirus and IDS's handle and
tell'em relay I I'm just not sure how
well they do that I don't think that
there's a lot of them that are gonna
alert on that because it's it's a
network based attack you'd have to have
I don't know I'm sure the high-end ones
do but for my intents and purposes I'm
gonna say this is not as Delta not a Red
Team tool yes funny you should ask
I actually meant to say this a little
bit earlier in the presentation one
thing you may want to do is not run the
IP version 6 DNS attack if you are okay
so Deathstar that little red thing means
Deathstar found a domain admin logged in
on a system that you have administrative
access to so now it's just a matter of
like a couple minutes before it says you
have domain admin in the shell but so
MIT m6 MIT m6 will poison IP version 6
which exchange does not like exchange
despises this as a matter of fact so if
you're trying to stay under the radar or
you I would recommend just running MIT
m6 for like a few minutes so you can run
Icebreaker skip all the attacks until
attack four and five and then just let
that run for a couple minutes and that
way when people get some exchange email
connectivity issues you can just cancel
it and you'll be fine but if you don't
want to mess up the network and you want
to eliminate all possibilities of
messing up the network
don't use MIT m6 don't skip attack
number five otherwise no it doesn't work
cause any problems thank you
see I knew it I was like it has a bug
already darn it any other questions No
all right cool
well I'm just gonna let this run for the
next couple minutes I suppose because it
should pop it in just a minute even
though you can't read a single thing up
here but if there's any other questions
feel free to hit me up on Twitter or
github