go ahead all right good morning
sounds like we're good we're gonna get
going this talk is classic cons in
crypto we're gonna be looking a lot at
cryptography and cryptocurrency which is
mostly him we're gonna be talking about
some of those classic confidence games
have seen forever and how they're
playing out with this newer technology
hi I'm Zack Sarah Kane I'm a security
analyst at CBI yeah and so I'm Wolf
Gorelick also at CBI and on the
Twitter's and on the youtubes where this
talk came out of is Zack and I will get
coffee in the morning if Zacks like this
is a new great thing that's going on
cryptocurrency I'm like that's great how
many wallets were stolen I think by the
way Venezuela is gonna run i
cryptocurrencies going to spend more
power on the entire cryptocurrency thing
that energy I'm like that's great
so what's what's your Bitcoin trending
right now it was also funny every day
it's like my bitcoins up my big ones
done but the cons right so we have a lot
of these things going on and it occurred
to me that with this new technology
we're making a lot of the same mistakes
we made forever in a day which is of
course the old man of me coming out and
we're falling prey to some of the same
confidence games and we've seen repeated
over and over and over again and so
while the entire cryptocurrency world
focuses in on solving the 51% attack
someone overhears like yeah but I
couldn't get your keys ha now I don't
have a garden so it's craziness so
that's some of the things we're going to
explore today and some of the things
we're going to talk about so the way
it's gonna work is we're gonna break out
some fundamental concepts of
cryptocurrency and blockchain and off
chain and on chain near chain and I
don't know how many chains fire chains
and one or two teeth and then we'll go
ahead talk about some of the pros and
cons that we're seeing and then we'll
talk about some of the classic cons in
that space yeah so what is black chain
besides
fire buzzword no one really seems to
agree on this the wolf will kind of wolf
what kind of touch on that soon so if
you google blockchain right now you'll
see Google calls it a digital ledger in
which transactions made in Bitcoin or
another cryptocurrency are recorded
chronologically and publicly but already
there's like a ton of problems of this
definition because elections are not
limited to just cryptocurrencies and not
all block chains are recorded publicly
there are black jeans like Manero for
example that you can't go publicly view
those transactions you might build a
verify you might be able to verify them
but you can't be you can't view them so
that leads us to the question should we
think of it as a technology or design
pattern
there's no blockchain version numbers
there's no blockchain I Triple E there's
no awful blockchain certification exams
yet hopefully no this is great
I will not go get anyone knows CompTIA
and could put me in touch with them I'm
Tia block I lost I am not getting my
black chain plus I'm not am i right like
cow plus blockchain plus it's the new
house thing man hopefully you've got a
quarter dessert so let's see so because
of those reasons I invite you to think
of it as a design pattern so I'll block
teen is essentially a construct wherein
a cryptographically authentic record of
events is distributed amongst
participants in a network and
permanently updated once a majority
consensus of knowit's ratifies the entry
this design pattern could be tweaked and
applied to solving many different
challenges that has its real-world
origins powering cryptocurrencies it was
eventually it was originally invented
with Bitcoin so some of the use cases
for Bitcoin are cryptocurrencies of
course which is the primary use case for
this presentation distributed cloud
storage such as storage i/o so the
shifted cloud storage is think of like
Google Drive only decentralized so
everyone holds encrypted portions of a
file no one person holds the whole file
and then it's it's redundant because you
can't trust everyone to hold on your
files and then when you pull that back
up and then when the user calls it
everyone serves up those files you have
decentralized DNS name coin is a project
that works on that and then etherium dot
domains are happening you've seen a
similar gold Buster right now where
everyone's buying up daddy's domains you
know pets studies and all of that all
over you can do you can use blockchain
for voting you can fought you can follow
follow your vote and their verify that
an election was was legitimate Agora and
follow my votes are using that Sierra
Leone did use Agora in a public election
which is actually kind of interesting
and it was for about 70% of the votes
that so I mean 70% of the votes that
were counted were used collecting Agora
we have malware tech bogs best use one
of the best use cases is using military
applications like boring your enemy to
death by telling them how it could solve
all their problems
I've almost killed wolf with that so
how's that project going let me tell you
about block can a good stats report have
you heard about the good news of
blockchain and then another use case
which we'll be talking about later is
smart contracts so the etherium project
was built for smart contracts and then
eos which is a IC o---- that I believe
launches like today or tomorrow or
something so one of the the most
profitable use case so far yeah I'll
cover that we're gonna get back to smart
contracts which is fun but think about
this for a minute and this is this is
the most exciting thing to me about
blockchain are you a criminal who makes
a living the good old hard fashioned way
stealing people's information right are
you sad because when anthem happened it
went from $200 a record to $10 a record
doesn't that suck hey goodness for
ransomware right we no longer have to
steal people's information and sell it
to some stranger we can still sell back
to them this is fantastic and
fundamentally like the only real use I
can't buy coffee with the point I can't
pay my hotel there's a million one
things you can't do huh but by god we
can do rants where did you guys see the
ransomware talk like yesterday its
dotnet I know dotnet this is phenomenal
so this it's really fundamentally at
moment being a used primarily in the
criminal space that I'm seeing obviously
there's a lot of great uses for there
but I think that's too true why it's
exciting right crypto you wouldn't
really know cryptography I might do a
lot with cryptography anywhere right no
other than I click the right setting and
don't use SSL anymore No so crypt is
magic which is fantastic sure and the
criminals are using it right Robin Hood
all these like fundamental like day and
old criminals so it's sexy so you got
magic sexy money it's fantastic no
wonder the kids love it so some of the
some of the concerns around blockchain
today are the the risk factors
associated with them so you have
scalability issues scalability are
transactions per second that it can work
transactions per day whatever that can
handle transaction fees grow as black
chains get congested you have key
management you have a lot of people
coming to this space I have never dealt
with private keys or held private keys
before I have no idea how to manage them
etc but the scariest of them all is the
infamous theoretical 51% attack and we
can't even call this theoretical anymore
this actually happened to Bitcoin gold
which is one of the force off a bit more
about Forks in a minute
and it happened about this week so the
network is market regulated and open so
if one entity was to have 51% of hash
power there's no central government
Treasury Corporation no Bitcoin CEO to
stop them from doing what the attackers
can't just magically change change the
rules if they were changing code they
wouldn't be running the same protocol
but they could reverse transactions the
attacker sends will in control prevents
some or all transactions from gaining
confirmations by not mining them
preventing some or all miners from
mining any valid blocks and then what we
were seeing this week is early reports
we're showing some double spending so
how exciting with double spending is in
a little bit - so let's do it let's
crash Bitcoin less 51% attack let's make
all the money the problem with this
approach and why you don't really you
should be worrying about the classic
kind
way more than you should be worrying
about this is if you had the billions of
dollars in equipment it took and the
millions of dollars in electricity per
day that it took to have 51% of that
hash power you might as well mind with
it it would be much it would be much
more profitable rather than have a 51%
attack crash the price and then not be
able to do anything with what you with
what you've been sealing with the the
network you destroyed you might as well
be mining and then from a competition
standpoint as a Sikh chips are getting
better and better it's getting easier
and easier for Joe schmo's to buy my
equipment and running out of their
basement garage and when we are talking
about this last one right the the
billions of equipment and everything
we're like who could possibly do that
where to come fairness thirds oh who
could possibly do that of course we're
thinking like Elon Musk right see the
humanity how must going flamethrower got
it
SpaceX rocket got it I could crash
Bitcoin I mean who's gonna do that it
doesn't make any sense so we as an
industry Bitcoin and the blockchain
folks spend a lot a lot of time on that
but the reality is that's not
necessarily is going to happen the
reality is at the moment the the second
greatest use of the blockchain of beyond
ransomware stealing money from you is
marketing stealing money from you
right so we already heard conferences
are better with blockchain Aaron saw
that in the opening that's fantastic you
want to do cybersecurity block team
marketing now marketing blockchain with
their ad platform the future of stock
trading needs to do a lot of stock
trading and this is the one that was
almost like that sounds so cool because
a fixed protocol if you guys have ever
looked at it has got awful if anyone
wants to talk to me afterwards and I can
do anything on camera about it but the
fixed protocol is clear text and like
there's only like one bit that's very
easy to change to to manipulate but it's
okay what we'll do it blockchain
blockchain makes everything better even
IBM so fundamentally you know it's like
hello how's it going have I told you the
good news about blockchain that magic
elixir con
is is so frustrating to me because we
talk as about being hackers and
information security we're supposed to
be a little bit brighter we're supposed
to be little bit faster we're supposed
to be the nonconformist
we don't listen to the man unless the
man gives us a really shiny white paper
and tells us this cat black sheep
what the hell so this concept magic
elixir goes all the way back to when
people were going hey look I've got the
ingredients from this Native American
tribe who distilled it upon ages let me
show you this bottle and yet again we're
still making these same mistakes
hundreds of years later sure it's that
classic preying off of misinformation so
get into the use cases
what is cryptocurrency besides magical
internet money sexy magical internet
money sexy magical internet money so
think of a cryptocurrency as a protocol
introductions for instructions for
moving and storing data a particular
cryptocurrency as a particular protocol
where encryption is used to regulate
data and verify the transfer of units so
Ivan
some people are messing going gold some
people invest in silver I'll take a
pound please bitcoin only exists
digitally and it can be broken up into
almost infinite units so the smallest
unit of a Bitcoin is one Satoshi which
is dot zeroes Vic when I'm accompanied
them all off and that number woods could
scale to be just off off based off that
number it could scale to be the main
currency of the world if that were to
ever happen and then even if you needed
more decimals you could software to add
more if needed more on sophomores later
good yeah so of course the other great
use of this is crypto mining today's
right so why steal your data and have
you pay me a Bitcoin when I can just
have you run my software and now we can
mine Bitcoin right off of your computer
it's great and in fact we're starting to
see more and more criminals switching to
that model the old drive-by days of
doing advertising oh I'm going to trick
you to click stuff is now been replaced
with I'm going to run coin hive a
JavaScript in your browser and run it
forever and
my encrypt Oh as well as some of the old
attacks that used to break in the data
centers I've got a good friend who runs
a web hosting company right in the cloud
my other favorite buzzword and he's was
investigating because notice that the
performance was starting to dip and what
he actually found out was a great swath
of his machines were infected they were
compromised there was holes in the web
applications that were used to load up
exploits in the old days they would have
brought in broke in and he faced it look
how cool I am or broke in and stole
indeed oh oh look I can sell in the
market no instead they've broken into
all these web servers that were mined in
the tune of 1.6 million dollars a month
off of crypto miners throughout the
environment craziness craziness so
that's the other great use case today
crystal money so some of the pros of
cryptocurrency is you have a controlled
supply so you don't have the the
photocopying of money that we have we
have problems with with other currencies
you have decentralization so no one
person can mess it up by accident or
into intentional action when the when a
blockchain is running properly and
you're not in some type of 51% attack
scenario you don't have you don't have a
double spending problem so bitcoin is
not the first cryptocurrency but it
solves of the double spending problem
the double spending problem is the idea
that if I have one Bitcoin and I give it
to you and I give it to you and I give
it to you and I hurry up and spend those
again and again and again before those
transactions are valid I've just spent
that three times and so it doesn't
really work as a sort of value or medium
of exchange anymore at that point and
then of course you have authenticity
backed by that blockchain so there's no
real such thing as a counterfeit Bitcoin
some of the kinds of it are that's what
the price chart looks like on any given
Tuesday morning you have you have
several you have several wonderful
cycles here where media starts to talk
about it people get super greasy greedy
we have the new paradigm at the top
everyone's talking about it
we don't need governments anymore
need cash anymore this is the whole new
thing we have a dip people people get a
little shaky for a minute and then we
have the return back to normal or
everything everything is cool we're good
we're gonna we're gonna keep going up
and then we have this and they kind of
and I got crazy with mspaint it just
kind of goes nuts and so that's
definitely this definitely hurts it as a
sort value and I do too by the way love
it when I'm talking to Zach in the
mornings like this is the greatest day
ever and everything's great
I want to kill myself can I work here
forever can I get a read no everything's
good the media like names these things
crazy stuff to write okay like a return
to the beach man trap shark all right
yeah so this this pattern that this
pattern we see here would be an inverse
shark returning to the beach and it's
bullish yeah I used to work in the stock
market and it's the craziness I they say
well that's what we would have expected
to see from the inverse shark attack
well is that what you have is a bunch of
people my generation trying to do the
same thing you know without any of the
into institutional Minds behind it so we
don't know sometimes yeah so some of the
cons around it well of course that price
volatility this is as much as we'd love
to believe that it's matured and it's
great it's still in a long valuation
phase we saw we still have a long way to
go before it's it's stable enough that
people would actually trust it not as a
medium of exchange but as a store of
value you have scalability issues so
every time networks get congested
transaction fees go through the roof
transaction times take forever which
hurts it as the medium of exchange
there's no forgot password button on the
on the on the protocol so for a lot of
people because it's decentralized
there's no central entity to go
convinced that you're that person and
that you you deserve that those keys you
deserve that wallet so that makes that
makes it really difficult from a UX
perspective for a lot of people and it's
boiler alert we'll come back to that a
few times yeah it's not at all widely
accepted no matter what no matter what
believers of it will tell you about
there are some there are some solutions
like having
you can get a special debit card tied to
a wallet so you can use that anywhere
but you can't directly use that
everywhere yet and then a huge con about
it is your spouse won't let you buy any
odd no matter how much you try to
convince her that it's the future that's
nice a future he or she will let you buy
any she hasn't heard about blockchain
that's the problem so in this day and
age of this decentralized currency right
this is this sexy magic internet money
where no one bank will tell us what to
do I love the story of Mount GOx if you
guys haven't heard the story of Mount
GOx it all starts with Magic the
Gathering which used to cost about one
Yoshii Yoshii yeah okay one magic money
and so Magic the Gathering they want to
exchange cards online and this came to
Magic the Gathering online mount Cox so
mom Cox actually started out as a
trading platform for fake cards and then
moved to a much more legitimate model of
trading fake currency and pretty soon
they had about three-quarters of all the
currency was flowing through mouth Cox
now it's fundamentally my problem with
so many these technologies basically
every new technology is I'm like why why
do I keep making the same mistakes why
are we not catching why we're not
putting a 2-man principle why are we not
using to a fake yada yada yada
every single thing you hear everyone in
this industry who's been around for a
while complaining about why don't you
use two of a Sony in my day so that's
the problem in what ended up happening
was mom Cox ran off with all the money
now it's never been proven it's never
been definitively found if anyone says
yes it has please give me the links I
didn't find it they investigated for
years yeah they investigated for years
but every indication shows us insider
threat all right there was not good to
man controls there's not good financial
controls and for how much we in the
financial industry hate things like Sox
and the SEC telling us what to do the
man tell us what to do
a little bit of control would have
probably prevented a whole lot of
cryptocurrency way think about this from
a conceptual standpoint inside of a
model where decentralization is supposed
to be the answer to everything here you
have one entity handling 70%
the transactions on the network that's
not the essential position at all and
it's it's a huge problem when we see it
we see it's not quite as bad but we see
similar things happening right now with
with coinbase being as successful and
easy-to-use as they are so with that
we've got we've mentioned it a couple
times let's talk about mining
so mining as the way mining works is
though you have doges in a cave
they take GPUs with them and they beat
up math problems and you give rewards
for that so legitimately oh that's great
I'm Bitcoin the ways you make money
mining is introducing new coins to the
blockchain through solving complex
mathematical nevermind it's more like go
fish with random number guessing you
guess the correct you guess you guess
the correct number you get a reward and
that is how that is how new coins are
added into the economy up to the 21
million coin limit the other way that
you make money mining and this will be
where we originally eventually shift to
fully is if I send a Bitcoin for me to
Wolff and again this is theoretical
because willful know what never own it
is the people on the way from me to wolf
there that see that that see that
transaction recorded as valid and add it
to the blockchain our miners they take a
small fee from that from that
transaction in order to cover their
electricity overhead or whatnot so
anyone can mine with a with a modern
computer smartphone etc the question is
profitability can you do this on top of
your electricity cost and part of that
too is as you mind more and more
currency the mathematical problems get
harder and harder because they took into
account Moore's law and other things so
the proof will work and to use to get
more difficult to the amount of energy
and computational cycles are increasing
so back in the day when it first came
out and I was mining a Bitcoin here or
there it was much easier to do it much
quicker right and again uses a ton of
electricity so with that some of a lot
of the today's concerns around mining
are a lot of these headlines that you
see about the earth will not be
inhabitable and if Bitcoin continues to
increase and it's it's kind of like
telling a pregnant woman who is three
months pregnant that ma'am your baby is
this big right now and if it continues
if it continues at the rate it's growing
in in ten years it's going to be the
size of this room
it doesn't take the statements like that
don't take into account hard we're
getting more efficient improvements in
the technology changes in algorithms etc
so with that let's talk about some of
the some of the systems that these work
under so where we have the big in the
big energy problems is in a
proof-of-work system rewards are granted
based on the amount of work completed so
what that looks like is when back in the
day when wolf used to take his trusty
pickaxe down to the mine he'd mine he'd
mind some gold the gold that he has as
the gold that he's received there is the
proof of his work that's that's what he
can show for the work that he put into
mining that gold so again that's that's
the energy use concerns in a proof of
safe system rewards are granted based on
amount of coins state in a in an a
sql-like situation it's more of like a
passive income to ideal the economics
behind it get kind of funny so it's
worth it's worth looking into and
deciding for yourselves if you think
that's the route that these currency
should go so the Lightning that the
Lightning Network on Bitcoin is a used
as a proof of stake system backed by the
original proof-of-work blockchain and
more on that in a little bit and then
aetherium is Casper is a introducing
proof of stake to aetherium
and the eventual goal is to get
aetherium to 100% proof of stake go
ahead sure sure so some classic cons the
classic printing money con right is
vistor Lustig's gotta love vistor Lustig
you guys haven't seen this check it out
the basic concept was very simple he had
a box you put in paper you crank the box
out came 100 dollar bill and you would
overtime work with amar
convince them hey look here's 100 maybe
won the day right so now you're in two
three four hundred dollars and he's got
this magic box he said look I can no
longer I have this magic box I'm gonna
ride off in the sunset but I'm willing
to sell it to you for only three
thousand dollars so you start doing the
math and okay so if I print a dollar a
day I'll be profitable right and pretty
soon it's like thirty days I'm good and
so he sells the magic box and takes the
money guy at home cranks the Box gets
hundred bucks good cranks the Box gets
hundred bucks good cranks to box out
comes paper those pre-staged with money
and after you would run it so many times
nothing but paper and by that time
picture was long gone so classic classic
money box con classic con apparently
second one apparently when I was mining
back in the old days yesterday like gold
rush eighteenth-century
with my trusty mule who I named Lucy
this is a good name for me
so there is this kind of up salting the
mines here's the way that worked you
wouldn't mind and mind of mine get as
much gold as you could and eventually
you tap out the vein right there's no
more gold to be had what are you gonna
do you're now stuck to this property so
you take some of the gold you had and
front-loaded into the beginning of the
mine so you take your mark in and go hey
Zack this is a gold mine
and I'm tired I'm old Lucy needs a home
I'm going to ride off in the sunset but
I will sell you this gold mine for the
low low price of ten thousand marks or
whatever and that person music that's
great look at all this gold is right
here in the beginning I'm gonna be rich
and so they'd buy it and again for
casting in about a year I make all my
money back and within a couple days
they'd mind through the gold that i the
con artists had left for them so keep it
in mind Victor Lustig money box
keeping in mind salting the mines I will
now tell you about this great
opportunity I have for you guys for the
low low price of just a few pennies I
will sell you mining rights
cryptocurrency mining is hard it's
complicated trust me you don't want to
do it but you can buy a mining right and
I'll give you this great plaque that's
got a certificate
on your stick and for the next five
years as long as you have this mining
right you are welcome to all the Bitcoin
that my mining farm mines hey I did not
consent to you posting a picture of my
garage yeah you're wishing and a lot of
a lot of baby boomers all my friends or
my age a little bit older are coming up
to me going yeah I wanted to get in and
this friend of mine is trying to tell me
that I can buy a mining right and I get
certificate and that's that's how mining
works right it's all over the place
right so I heard that immediately I'm
thinking about gold and printing Mike
maxes and we're using these same old
confidence tricks again with the smart
technology and unfortunately people are
falling for it because you know sexy
magic internet money is hard right it's
very hard to do so if we just had a
mining stake you know also to a lot of
times were like hey you want to split
this money with us because they tell us
to sell shares of our shares yeah it's
not preying on this misinformation over
and over
absolutely so for the next thing we'll
be talking about going beyond that
original blockchain to help with
scalability issues so like I mentioned
earlier scalability issues are as they
relate the black chains problems around
transaction times transaction fees etc
so we're going to talk about Forks and
layer 2 solutions so what I mentioned
earlier was the the Lightning Network
which is a proof of sake system that is
a second layer solution to Bitcoin so
think of think of it like this paper
money was originally a layer 2 solution
to scaling gold when they first started
when they first started using paper
money wolf was extremely excited they
didn't have to go to the go to the
merchants anymore and shave gold off his
bars this was a lot more convenient for
him so it's a similar situation to what
we have here so the Lightning network is
layer 2 option solution so it uses micro
payment channels to scale that you open
that you open payment channels from node
to node and that that that allows the
scalability reducing the load on the
main chain exponentially it has a
I shouldn't call it onion like it's a
it's Onion Routing it's just like just
like tore foes you are familiar with
that transaction times are instant you
can look up YouTube videos or whatever
on the test net or the main net
transaction times are ridiculously fast
and this aims and seems to enhance
bitcoins utility as a medium for daily
use so you gotta use those those payment
channels to a lot of people to send
transactions to each other without
actually using the blockchain so what
this allows the this allows Bitcoin to
become much more than a justice store of
wealth that allows it to become a better
medium of exchange so now if I want to
know if if a if a coffee place ever
decides to accept it when I buy a coffee
I don't have half of that cost being a
transaction fee it will scale much
better for smaller micro payments yeah
just one thing on that the first time I
heard about this I'm like I don't care
what you young punks a layer two will
always be data like if I write don't be
making layer two shaved off go ahead go
ahead
so datalink yes okay all right OSI model
guy over here so so then we'll talk
about another way that people try to
scale black chains which are forced so
it's not it's not nearly as complex of a
concept as it sounds think of just like
a programming port so if I've got these
transactions or these blocks going in a
line like this and someone decides that
at this block at this block number I
want to decide to fork off of it and
have an it and have a new list of
transactions that's that's all that
happens they decide to change the code
they have their own new miners etc etc
so a hard fork is ditching the old chain
for a new chain with new rules this old
chain can continue if people are still
mining blocks on that new chain the
difference between a hard fork and a
soft fork is a software is backwards
compatible in the way that you you
maintain eventually one chain is
somebody will come out with a proposal
and Segway is a good example of a
proposal that happened on the Bitcoin
Bitcoin core chain
which is the the main chain and they say
I want to have X consensus by X number
so if you decide to vote for that you
vote with your hat you vote with your
hash pal
and then when you reach that block block
number if you have enough consensus
everyone switches over and you and at
that moment everyone is using new code
Segway it was a great example of this it
increased the block size helped with
scalability a little bit fixed with a
couple fix a couple potential security
vulnerabilities but what's what's worth
mentioning here is Segway it was
interesting because it showed that
everyone that people can agree on
something in a decentralized manner and
that we could we can do code changes so
that it potentially can survive into the
future so some in today's concerns
around going beyond the blockchain is
the concerns around not having the real
coin anymore so anytime Bitcoin cash
Bitcoin gold said what to X Bitcoin
unlimited there's so many of them any
time one of those come around and start
saying hey we're going to work and this
is the new Bitcoin it's faster and it's
better yada yada
the everyone freaks out and there's a
bunch of there's a bunch of what we call
flood for your uncertainty fear
uncertainty and doubt going on
everyone's panicking and so when these
sports happened you have exchanges that
crash point a coin base is a perfect
example to those of us that own Vic when
we've probably all seen the you know
sorry can't handle your transaction and
you know we begin to cry is our
retirement account you know begins to
crash to nothing so getting over the
last one the etherium and ethereal just
kidding aetherium
and aetherium classic are it's actually
a great example of a heart of a
successful hard fork what happened is
back in the day aetherium which is now a
thorium classic had a smart contract on
it and more on that in a minute
that was hacked and people decided no
you can't just steal a hundred fifty
million dollars we need a solution here
that was the solution they decided is
hard working to what we now know as eth
aetherium so you can have a bitcoin
crash if you don't have any exchanges
online
so hard fork Softworks Zack tells me
that old hackers like me can still do
hard Forks they have a bunch of medicine
for that now I'm not very sure I got
that joke but alright a couple different
things remember earlier we said you
can't change your password right because
it's private key and also when I was
talking about the on the baby-boomers
side cryptocurrency sounds harder so we
want to buy like mining rights similarly
we've got nice hash which is targeted
more at the younger audience because
cryptocurrency is harder so download
nice hash if you download a nice hash it
runs in your computer it does mining
when you're not paying attention and it
uploads all that mining can getting back
to nice hash or they can mean Li hold
your keys what could possibly go wrong
so nice yeah and then they pay and then
they hopefully pay you and they
hopefully pay you out yeah you hopefully
pay out so nice hash had all the private
keys those private keys get stolen 4,500
Bitcoin later all those people have no
no way to get back because they have no
way to prove that it was actually done
and they're greater what's funny about
this breach is the first time I read the
headline I'm like whoa fifty million
dollars worth of Bitcoin stolen and the
next day it was 64 million dollars a
Bitcoin stole and I was like whoa like
did they get breached again okay that's
just the price boss that's just the
price fluctuation but the key here is is
that the private key right private keys
are critical if you don't own your
private keys you don't actually have the
money right no matter who's doing mining
I'm gonna what to try and tell you've
don't have your private keys don't have
it now even if you have your private
keys doesn't necessary mean you get to
keep your Bitcoin so a lot of times
today with organized or with individuals
who have their own keys their own laws
they set it up they download a wall and
installed it and hopefully it wasn't
some ransomware scam saying we are now
configure while it was encrypting all
your files we're hoping they did all the
right things and now they've got a
wallet the challenge here is that
historically we have been terrible at
private key management breach after
breach have investigated oh well it's
okay we got encrypted where's the keys
it was on the server that got infected
right we're terrible at this moreover
users
click stuff moreover people don't patch
stuff moreover developers make bad code
choices so there's been a number of
wallis have been stolen through fishing
there's been a number of lots have been
stolen through drive-by downloads
infecting your computer y-you know do
coin hive when I can simply steal your
coins that's been happening and there's
been a number of these wallets
themselves that have been had buffer
overruns or whatnot that allowed people
in that network to still each other's
private keys and hence still the money
so lots of people are using their
wallets
but of course fundamentally back to what
you keep talking about the ups and downs
classic pump and up you know you you you
probably come here thinking you're gonna
hear the the tulip story right back when
I was a lad in Deutschland know Dutch
not Deutsch but forever in a day we've
had this thing where everyone gets
really excited everyone buy stuff and
the people were smart cash out and we're
seeing this again and again so even if
you are able to get your Bitcoin and not
get it stolen put in your wallet and not
get that stolen we sell these crazy flux
fluctuations but of course hopefully
it'll get better right we're still in
the early stages I like your point about
this too volatility that will come out
but we need to start doing some some
fundamentals in the security space right
around protecting these exchanges on
protecting the walls themselves yep so
next we're talking about smart contracts
so smart contracts is a fancy way of
saying a decentralized application so
again it's not a fancy for private area
technology but think of it as a design
pattern the earliest examples we saw
with smart contracts happening is on a
given Bitcoin transaction you have
several fields you have a to address
from address etc you have you have a
notes yield as well what people were
doing is people were actually putting
code in the notes field the notes fields
of Bitcoin transactions and then when
certain transactions of a certain code
would post it would trigger up it would
trigger other code so when specific
events happen the code can automatically
disperse funds from one person to
another as well though as well as a
wealth of other actions because they're
on a blockchain they can run exactly as
intended without inner third party
interface or downtime so some of the
pros around there is you have is in
terms of the CIA triad
have a whole lot of integrity there your
back you're backed by the the full faith
of the blockchain
you have tons of availability there as
these these these networks basically
don't go down a pro is code changes need
a network consensus to implement so no
no one person can go change the code on
you a con is code changes need a network
consensus to implement and what I'm
getting at there is if someone finds a
phoner ability in your code on your
decentralized application you don't have
a good chance of being able to in to
convince everyone - flat - signal to
change that code before an attacker can
exploit it given that you need that
whole network consensus to implement
that code so again that's the whole
centralization versity centralization
you have to be extremely careful in how
you develop these applications the as I
mentioned earlier the etherium and
etherium classic hard fork is a perfect
example of that there was a smart
contract I believe it was called dowels
that was hacked a while ago and that was
a 150 million dollar smart contract hack
the if you were in protocol itself was
not hacked but they hacked the app the
application because they had problems
with it so all the money so aetherium
fort - aetherium fort to have a solution
to that not necessarily a great solution
though as you're you're essentially
changing money just just because of
vulnerability so the today's concerns
around that are if I and what that would
look like today is if I decide with wolf
that I want to bet 50 aetherium that the
Lions won the Super Bowl this year wolf
says 50 theory and that they don't we
put that in in some some type of aid
ideally decentralized escrow account
when the Lions don't win the Super Bowl
not that I'm assuming but when they
don't win the Super Bowl wolf would get
paid out from that escrow account and
that would be a simple example of what
you could use a smart contract for the
problem is is where do we get that flag
to see that the Super Bowl was one did
we get it from ESPN do we get
another news network essential ization
problems right who's controlling that in
who's controlling that information
giving us that flag to determine that
they won because if because if you're
letting if you're letting a you know a
lawyer or something handle it it might
as well be an old system so machines
don't see things as black and white as
we do absolutely again the concern here
is we need to be extremely careful about
how we develop these applications that
I'm messing with the inputs of the AI
write computer yeah yeah yeah yeah so
I'm the classic con side
hey I'm not betting you about the Super
Bowl but be a couple things that were
interesting one was confided anyone here
about confide oh yeah no okay so
conveyed oh was this great stirred up
fantastic startup so what he's talking
about in these smart contracts requires
an espera someone to do the escrow side
and make sure that both sides have it
entered in this agreement and that it
pays out accurately so convite o went
and told everyone hey guess what we're
going to bring us new technology to
place we've got this awesome
smart contract escrow we've solved it
its capital octane and it's magic and
the vessels went great take my money and
they took all the money and right as
they were about to go to IPO the Twitter
counts disappeared the LinkedIn accounts
of the founders disappeared the webpage
disappeared and surprisingly enough the
money disappeared so classic exit scams
that we've seen again and again and
again similarly a plexi coin actually
got a little bit further Plex coin was
the next cryptocurrency much better than
Bitcoin because plaque sounds more
impressive than bit and they were able
to raise fifteen million and trade it
publicly before they closed their
initial offerings and again cashed out
and took it now this was a little more
public this was following the SEC rules
the SEC prosecuted they actually went to
jail but the point remains that the
controls around these
companies either investing the company
or doing live trades in the market are
very very weak and those are the types
of things are making criminals lots and
lots of money as opposed to a 51% attack
sure so the question that's in the back
of a lot of our heads is what about
quantum computing so we'll have button
to press the qubit the black team
so today's concerns are on quantum
computing here is of course flaws in
shot 256 elliptic curve digital
signature algorithm etc would quickly
lead to a compromise of the proof of
work system that we use today so what do
you do in that scenario in case of
emergency you could potentially hard
hard fork to change an algorithm at the
last minute what that would mean is the
entire infrastructure of hardware that
are that is running right now on that
old algorithm essentially becomes
obsolete that's obviously a big problem
Network at the total hash rate of an of
the Bitcoin network or whatever other
network would drop very significantly
that's not necessarily impossible though
as to such leaps and bounds of the made
an ASIC Hardware recently that a lot of
mining companies are refreshing their
hardware every six months anyway because
it's becoming absolutely however in
cryptography these things don't
generally happen overnight I'm thinking
of death md5 sha-1 what happened we were
weaknesses that were found that changed
the effort it would take to do that so
what that would look on like on Bitcoin
is someone would say I think with an
excise warehouse in an X amount of
capital you could break Bitcoin so what
happens there is people begin to talk
just like seg what happened but I see
these problems what can we do about it
the network would implement a code
change to get there through hard fork
our software it's it would definitely be
possible through hard fork may be
possible through software we haven't
seen that yet not for sure there but if
it happened overnight Bitcoin and
everything we know about encryption is
brought is brought to its knees but the
question there is why if you can bring
encryption as we know it to its knees
why are you at all concerned with a
hundred thirty billion dollars III think
people would be using this to keep
enemies from getting nukes not worried
about one hundred thirty billion dollars
worth of magic
money and again Algrim Agri algorithms
can be updated if the market demands
higher security in theory Bitcoin can
scale to meet that well yes
unless you're Elon Musk again I'm
thinking about him on his throne of
share Tesla's and the bones of his enemy
no but if you think jumping back Dez and
b5 shall one we have learned a lot over
the past few years right when you
implement a protocol you don't
necessarily tie the the encryption to it
we separate these right there's layers
of abstraction why because we know as
machines get faster as technology
changes enter quantum computing or
whatever you want Moore's Law is gonna
crush that encryption algorithm so we've
gotten really good at this
decentralization decoupling and many of
our older protocols but in the rush to
implement the Bitcoin and the blockchain
and what I fear that they haven't
learned some of those old lessons sure
you know the fact that you need to
completely do a hard fork and reset it
is very concerning to me because can you
imagine the web sites right we have
broken SSL PCI DSS now says we need to
upgrade great what are we doing we're
gonna hard fork the Internet it's gonna
start on Friday yes I don't like the
switch at the same time right sort of a
craziness it's a little bit craziness
and I fear that we're forgetting some of
the foundational lessons we've learned
and building all this infrastructure as
we rushed forward with Bitcoin and its
relatives so classic coins Casa cons
right so crypt quantum computing this
was actually the conversation that
really sparked this talk that comes into
my office he's like oh my god so quantum
computing has got this thing called
Qbert and cuber obey it okay go ahead
you sure it's on Qbert it's qubit but
okay this hope qubits are gonna change
everything and the speeds gonna come and
it's gonna crush the algorithm and we're
gonna be an attack it and both and I'm
like okay yes yes these things will
probably happen you know probably gonna
happen before then
pyramid schemes right am I wrong so
fundamentally the the interesting thing
we had were we in time
please I'm good okay five minutes
fundamentally as our technology
continues to evolve and adapt we are
cavemen right we still get the same
instincts that survived and thrived very
well we're beating animals over a head
with a stick and dragging a pack and
then we discovered fire nose awesome if
you say it was alive during that time
but my point is we we have these same
instincts and what that means is we have
these same human exploits these are
fundamental human exploits have been
with us for a thousand years and as
technology changes yes that new
technology brings up all sorts of new
things we're in the cloud do you guys
remember when we first moved to the
cloud and all the security talks were
like do you know what's going to happen
now that we're in the cloud they're
going to figure out cloud escapes and
people are gonna come in and they're
gonna salt your cloud and your clouds
going to dissipate and they're gonna do
VM escapes and do multi-tenancy attacks
remember all those sort of things that
we're all concerned about like circa I
don't 2010 to 2015 none of those happen
today not really no what is it we we
fire off exploit at some crappy code
that some developer put up there someone
in the SAS huh someone clicked a link
someone or someone click the link right
we've got the same wetware that we're
running on all this new technology and
therefore we make the same mistakes
because we have the same human exploits
cavemen are running the show and whether
it's Bitcoin or cloud or AI or whatever
it is first we've got to tackle those
cavemen exploits cuz I don't we're in a
very bad spot definitely and one of the
earliest ones from the day when when I
was clubbing animals over the head I'm
like hey I will give you a piece of meat
if you sell piece of meat someone else
pyramid schemes but no-one's honest
right no one's honest about these sort
of things
unfortunately so someone is as a the the
the best and most ethical Ponzi scheme
today is Ponzi coin the world's first
legitimate Ponzi scheme this was a this
was a real project that actually
happened if you want to look it up
you'll have to see it on the wayback
machine because for whatever reason
they're not writing anymore because
money doesn't grow on trees unless
you're bit fin acts so sometimes you can
work
so the this is the whitepaper summary
here's the creator at the top here's you
when you buy in and then here's your
friends college fund at the bottom so
four easy steps four easy steps of
consequence I love this because it was
so truthful those so honest how do you
make money with cryptocurrency well step
one you invest if you're one of the
first few investors in ponzi coin menu
or the top of that pyramid you've got
the full stack invest don't worry about
it just buy it buy it buy it and you'll
get all the fancy cars you want think
about the Lambos next shill it to
everyone tell everyone all about it post
it all over read and make a dedicated
YouTube channel for it everyone's got to
know everyone's gonna buy it call your
dog your teacher your boss everybody I
got a call from a good friend of mine in
Europe he's like I got this great
investment for him like what is this
great investment like well what's your
risk tolerance I said just drop ten
points and you called me hey guys no
seriously what do you because if you
give me ten thousand dollars we're going
to be on the ground floor I'm like only
if you buy one of my ponzi cards and
then he didn't want to continue the
conversation I don't like everyone is
out there shilling right now all the
sort of stuff via mining contracts
whatever so why not show Ponzi coin next
hold on hold on for dear life to it
that's a misspelling in the community
that a drunk guy was complaining about
on reddit it was forever immortalized in
memes and now it's an acronym step 4
so it out buy pizza drugs Lambos you
know whatever you're gonna do with it
and gains will be through the roof and
it must have worked because it was on
top of the world and now you can only
find it in Internet Archive so actually
met me - who should launch Ponzi coin -
Circle City Con edition no but true
story check this out is hilarious it's
one of the only honest ones we've seen
certainly the most ethical or moral most
ethical yeah you get what you're got on
the box absolutely and and fundamentally
the takeaway if nothing else
definitely check out cryptocurrency
definitely check out blockchain it
really is cool stuff but whatever the
technology is we've got to look
not only the cool sexy attacks that we
think might happen in the space but
those fundamental human attacks have
been happening ever since gold mines and
tulip bulbs and my donkey named Lucy
we've got to do that and address these
sort of human issues because otherwise
we're bringing the same human issues in
and focusing in the wrong space and when
I talk to a lot of folks who are very
deep in the cryptocurrency world and are
really deep in building those worlds on
technologies they're not thinking about
you that they're not thinking about any
of that at all which concerns me because
I think we're going to inherent
especially if we do voting off of it
powerhouses off of it everything else
off of it we're going to inherit a lot
of these same problems and by the time
you're my age you're gonna be dealing
with them left and right so address
those key security controls lock them on
in
and then that black team that's I gotta
do thank you thank you so much any
questions yes sir no tell us more that
corn mixers and clean source in the
darkness oh yeah
because bitcoins bitcoins only pseudo
anonymous because it's still it's so
publicly viewable so there's some
techniques to get them into new coins
that's my marrow probably yeah Manero
originally I did recently overtake
Bitcoin on the dark lab so for people
listening on the stream because I know
people go back and do this the question
was cryptocurrency on the dark web
because people are going to dark web and
saying hey how do I clean my currency
because bitcoin is not truly anonymous
other currencies are focusing that way
like Manero which is why Manero is
really hot right now for crypto mining
you also see - using I use the
ransomware that was talked about
yesterday as well - is a privacy coin as
well so yeah great question
there doesn't seem to be so very little
barrier into entry and then we can
create a token anyone can created their
own currency so scams are seen around
that it's all about that subjective
theory of value something there's only
worth something
as much as someone's willing to pay for
it right so it's you people have to be
very careful and evaluate things before
they decide that this is actually worth
my you know the fruits of my labor or
whatever and it's also - back to coin
pump-and-dump
it's a great currency right we can get
you in on the ground floor
just give us ten thousand dollars sure
we'll do that right away
yeah all right we open time yeah we are
right at a couple minutes late so yeah
very good thank you guys officer in the
morning with