to a 6:00 p.m. talk I thanks for coming
to a 6 p.m. talk on a Saturday that's
how crazy we are as security people this
is what we do with our time so thanks
for coming out my talk is deploying
deceptive systems so I'll give you a
little bit on Who I am the premise of
the talk deployment strategies some
demonstrations of some of the free stuff
that's out there and then we'll have
some time for a Q&A and I apologize for
the little bit of blinking we have going
on here we tried many a dongle and had
no success in resolving it so please
bear with us so I'm an advanced
persistent Pittsburgher worked at a
number of companies all around that city
PNC Financial Services sa P Arriba I'm
currently with Dick's Sporting Goods
really have have done my whole InfoSec
career there I'm relocating the Columbus
though just recent development so any
Columbus people if you're here awesome
let's talk all right
I heart mango packets insecure direct
object references long walks on the
beach been doing this for 20 years
and I've done some talking to you I love
me my besides Pittsburgh
besides Cleveland is another great one
and of course Terry Kahn and this is my
first ever Circle City callin both
attending and speaking and it's been a
great conference so thanks to all those
guys for setting this thing up
really good stuff thank you
so the only purpose of this slide is to
say that I've seen some things not all
of them entirely wonderful so let's get
to it
so the premise of deceptive systems it's
honey pots ok nothing new here honey pot
concept has been around forever but
there's kind of been a renewed
I guess maybe rebranded it's not honey
pots anymore it's deception and so the
vendors out there are going to show you
deception technology and it's gonna cost
a lot of money and they're gonna tell
you you know it's that maybe you can't
do it any other way you can but it's
it's certainly not a new concept so if
we consider that we are operating you
know you hear this mantra we'll just
assume that the network is compromised
assume that the bad guys are running
around on your network moving laterally
and this and that so if you think about
that okay so they've already bypassed
our next-gen firewall
they've already bypassed our superduper
endpoint detection you know any ids/ips
stuff that might be there so how are you
really gonna catch a bad guy in that
sort of situation and one way to do that
is is with honey pots so create some
systems on the network that will entice
the bad guys to come to your system
touch it which would be really weird
because nobody should ever touch that
system so that's really the idea and
then maybe get a little attribution as a
part of that and maybe be able to
respond kick the system off maybe do
additional monitoring on the account
that was used to touch the honeypot that
sort of thing the whole thing is you
know these are potentially valuable
systems you want you want them to look
very valuable you don't want them to
look like you know just completely
vulnerable systems you want them to look
like there's there's you know there's
really good stuff here so much so that
the bad guys are gonna come and touch
them so you want these things to get
noticed but you don't want them to be
too noticed you know
this is an example of a good deployment
right it's a choir everybody's singing
the same song they all kind of look the
same you know but what you don't know is
that one person in that crowd is a spy
and she knows the whole story about the
pastor and the secretary okay it's a bad
deployment right sticking out like a
sore thumb not really fitting in saying
maybe the wrong things that's not what
you're what you want your honey pots to
look like
so some deployment do's do set your
traps on sensible subnets so you might
want to have a honeypot the DMZ for
example or if you have one set up to
look like a file server put it where all
the other file servers are same subnets
same naming conventions that sort of
stuff so put them in the places that are
appropriate give them convincing names
and attributes so you know don't just
create a naming convention that makes no
sense for what every other computer and
your organization is named and if you
tend to set attributes on certain
servers in Active Directory you know
things like if you create a new
workstation and you put the user's name
in there we'll do it for this too you
don't want to give any indication that
there's anything different about this
domain joint system than other domain
systems sprinkle enticing honey Docs and
honey credentials all over the network
you don't just have to put them on your
honey pot you can put them all over the
place and have them report back and tell
you when they're being touched places
like the Internet you know I might be a
good place to put a passwords do see X
file continuously improve be creative
think about how best to make these
devices look like they're actually real
and and make it realistic
so some placement don'ts don't make a
subnet just for honey pots because it
will probably never ever get touched
there is one exception maybe to that and
that's if you're creating a honey pot
that looks like a router or a network
device
you know a lot of organizations you know
your network starts with dot one and dot
one's the router but you can never
create a honey pot that is dot one on
the network because well it's always
occupied by a router so maybe get
creative with your network team and
create a subnet that's just for your
honeypot router so that it can be dot
one don't name them things like CEO
never patches or XP legacy pwned me
that is going to be a sure sign that
that is not a legitimate system and it
will never ever get touched by anyone
don't forget to make a whitelist
so you probably have a number of systems
in your environment already that are
scanning doing some automated scanning
maybe vulnerability scanners that might
like light these things up if they come
across them so make sure you understand
you know there's some some tuning to be
done here if you don't know by default
all the different things that are out
there scanning learn create your
whitelist and then deploy so you're not
getting a bunch of false positive errors
don't set it and forget it because
that's not going to help any anyone in
any tool deployment ever ok so now it's
demo time and let's hope everything
works I'll just let you preface this and
tell you that none of this is mine I did
not write any of the honeypot technology
I'm about to show you here
I'm just really showing you how to use
it thank you to John strand and Black
Hills InfoSec for the work that they did
with ADHD which is a really great honey
honeypot distribution that I'll be
demoing and thanks to all the
open-source honeypot devs out there that
are really making this possible so the
first one I'll demo is canary tokens
this is a free service that you can go
to at canary tokens org they give you 15
different types of honey tokens for free
where they can make a callback or they
can alert if they're touched either
either via email or they can call back
on a web hook and then you can pick up
the alert from there so to help
scantiness it's totally safe I mean it
I'll scan it myself so this is an actual
honey token and you can you know imagine
you know you slap this on the bottom of
a corporate asset or something like that
and say password reset instructions and
then somebody comes along and scans it
and so now they've just triggered your
honey token and let's see what that
looks like okay that worked so let's see
oh man I was the only one that scanned
it but that's what the alert kind of
looks like you get back to the source IP
which honey token you actually triggered
you know the user agent and all this
stuff and then you can go in and
actually manage the honey token or get
more information about it here and it's
taking a guess that you know this last
time that I've taught you it was from
the 4140 IP address which is the hotel's
windstream IP that geo locates to here
so pretty cool for just scanning a QR
code this is what the actual generation
page looks like and if you do a drop
down here you'll see all sorts of
different honey tokens that are you can
create anything from cloning the website
to creating a word or PDF document which
I'll demonstrate a little later
AWS keys if somebody picks up and tries
to use I mean that's that's awesome so
all sorts of stuff I believe I had a
there we go
so this is just a DNS query and I get
back a Amazon IP if i refresh here
you'll see that I got a new honey token
it says type DNS so kind of cool gives
you also all sorts of options I'm
guessing that this this source IP is the
resolver it's not going to give actual
source because my IP didn't necessarily
look that up okay that's honey tokens so
next up is ADHD for active defense
harbors your distribution it is a Linux
distro that is just filled up with all
kinds of honey pots and fee tools around
that don't try to get fancy if you stand
a thing up read the manual
I tried to do this first with a 64-bit
image because I knew better and then I
fought with it for four hours and said
really is it and then I got the 32-bit
and we're like a champ so don't do what
I did and we'll cover two tools that are
inside of ADHD but we'll take a look at
all the stuff that's in there as well so
the first thing we'll look at is open
canary open canary is a really slick
little you know set of listeners
I guess that will sit there and listen
and pretend to be a Cisco router or a
Windows file share or a system that's
listening on vns B or a system that's if
it's an open proxy FTP server all kinds
of stuff sequel server gives you all
these options that you configure and say
okay I want this particular system to
look this way there are just some couple
of notes that I wanted to put there that
aren't really in the in the
documentation that I fought with a
little bit just edit that one file and
then
edit the the open canary Kampf to
actually configure what services you
want to turn on and then if you want to
use the file the file share at the samba
capabilities you do have to do a little
bit of editing to the SMB Kampf on your
Linux distribution to get that to work
for all the learning and all the
alerting and all that stuff to work
properly so let's see if we can get
lucky with a second demo so let me just
come back here real quick I'll just do a
quick end map of my Ubuntu VM here to
show you what it looks like right now so
right now only port 81 39 and 4 or 45 is
open so if we come over here actually
I'll show you the config file first so
this is what would be one of those Steve
Buscemi
honey pots this one I intentionally did
turn everything on just to show you the
capabilities in the demo I would not
recommend doing it this way but I just
wanted to show you what's what's out
there so there's essentially lines per
service that you're interested in
turning on this one here is a Synology
as login so it looks just like a
Synology as complete with username and
password box and will actually collect
the credentials that the attacker is
attempting to use same goes for the FTP
server same goes for the Cisco router so
that and then this section is really
about logging so you can log off
a local file you can log off to syslog
the logs are in JSON format
so pretty easy to consume in any sim
hopefully the section sets up the Samba
stuff you know try to make us have a
really secure SMB share sitting out
there that's hosting like some really
awesome documents this is the Cisco
router section where you can actually
configure some anypony creds as well to
generate an extra alarm if somebody
tries to log in with one of those
defined honey creds okay so let's launch
open canary okay a bunch of noise and
then let's see if we're good there we go
we get a lot more ports listening and I
guarantee they're all a bunch of
nonsense so if we just tell that to
ourselves Oh like there's a router
suddenly we're a router and you know
it's just going to do that all day but
if you forget the location make sure I
got this right
RTMP there we go you can see that this
guy is complaining about the fact that
some of the local host just tried to log
in with this username and password and
by the way that was also a honey cred so
maybe you could generate some additional
or something like that when you saw
something along those lines I'll come
over here and there's our Synology nas
you know very very convincing but the
the you can essentially clone any
website you would want here they call it
a skin in open canary so it's just a set
of HTML CSS you know just stuck in a
directory and you can skin this however
you want so if you have the company
internet or anything that that you might
want to present to an attacker or
something that would be very valuable
for them to gain access to you can do it
using this method let's see what else
Oh must have a file Oh share yes so
we're gonna mount the SMB file share
that is available on honeypot now oh
that's called secure so that must be
good and then we have our passwords dot
COCs can't resist it it just looks so
yummy and oh there's nothing in there
that's disappointing
this bad guy come back take a look we
have a new alert and
is source IPE I open the word document
and now you know somebody touched
something that you left out there
intentionally so open canary is pretty
cool free and there's some other
services here it's not not you can't
it's not that it can be completely
defeated and I should show you that I
need to do that so if you do the
aggressive scan which is gonna test for
banner versions and all that sort of
thing it's gonna light up open canary
for sure so if you're interested in
getting that kind of information you're
gonna get all sorts of stuff in the logs
about the fact that this IP is now
enumerated all sorts of things on the
back end so you can even see and map
scripting engine showing up in the in
the logs
okay and now if you take a look here
this does not look like a legit server
really I mean here's Cisco telling that
de but then I'm running Apache and I got
the SSH doesn't make sense and it wants
you and it's everything about it is a
little bit weird so certainly not
perfect but an attacker might roll along
and not do an nmap - a because they
don't wanna make a bunch of noise
because they're smart if they're not
smart and they are making a bunch of
noise you know then then maybe you're
gonna pick this up - because you just
got all those all those log files so
that's pretty much it that's that's what
open canary looks like
I'm blowing through stuff really fast
I'm sorry anybody have any questions
about either canary tokens or open
canary sir yeah I'm not aware of any
vulnerabilities with regards to open
canary now it's your right sometimes it
is using back-end instances Samba for
example it's using whatever Samba is
installed on the box and if you have
some insecure version of Samba and the
bad guy figures that out and pops it now
your your honeypot just became a attack
platform and that's probably not ideal
but as far as the like other things that
it spins up I don't I haven't seen
anything on on you know vulnerabilities
there whether the bad guy could
potentially insert something malicious
in a log and now you know if you're
logged parser isn't parsing properly and
it executes set command that could be
bad I could definitely see some some
ways you could get into trouble there
sure yeah I I will say that the and this
this is not a plug on you come here to
plug commercial solutions but there this
this company who makes open canary they
also have a commercial solution and that
solution has been thoroughly tested and
certified against vulnerabilities within
the hardware platform and the software
as well but that's not to say that
they've retrofitted all that stuff into
the open source solution any other
questions yeah
so what happens is whenever you so when
you hit the QR code with your QR code
scanner the default for most of those is
just go to the website that's in the QR
code when it comes to the word doc same
thing you open the word doc it goes to a
website so all of those triggers are
happening with an HTTP call up to the
cloud where canary stuff's hosted and
then it's their service that sends the
email that's defined or goes to the web
hook it's defined for that particular
token ok we'll go on to our last one
which is honey badger red you know honey
badger doesn't give a so there's not
much additional configure quired for
this guy
the attribution on it is really accurate
and I'll show you that here in a second
it's really the only I guess way of
legally hacking back and it's not really
even hacking back explain when I do the
demo but there are some limitations too
and we'll take a look at all that stuff
so googled echo back here at Firefox and
so imagine this is the best VPN portal
best clone of a VPN portal you've ever
seen I'm not a web developer so I'm not
even gonna attempt to insult you with
that but just for a second humor me and
use your imagination this is a a VMware
horizon login portal or ask OAS a login
portal for VPN something that looks you
know relatively convincing so the first
thing you can ask it to do is to say it
to the person touching hey give me your
location a bad guy probably isn't gonna
do but hey maybe they're just lazy and
they just give you their location ok
well then you'll see that up here we
have this Java plug-in that wants to run
if this is convinced
and if the way to get on the network is
to install this Java plugin may be a bad
guy go for it you know so let's say okay
I'm down let's let's let's allow it for
now
oh my version of Java is out of date
shame then again when isn't it out of
date okay so hey man the publisher is a
verified code certificate seems legit
so I mean if it's verified I'm gonna run
that bad boy yeah and nothing happens
oh well well I guess I guess some other
day maybe some other day I'll be able to
hack into this system so for us we'll
just come over to this neato
administrator page let's OH
well that we got some little pins on a
map there so I'm Pittsburgh guy may have
tested this somewhere in Pittsburgh
let's look at Indianapolis first getting
pretty close
getting pretty close mm-hmm yeah like
that's my hotel room yeah and this is
also where I tested it here let's go now
it's pretty good for location-based and
you might be wondering how how is GPS
you don't have GPS on your computer so
how and so what happens with that
magical Java applet is when you've run
it it sees if you have any Wi-Fi
interfaces available and if you do it
does a Wi-Fi site survey and it looks
all around that the Wi-Fi networks near
you and then sends that up to Google who
has an excellent excellent database of
everybody's Wi-Fi networks and it can
come within feet as accurate as three
feet where you are so does not matter if
the attacker is behind seven proxies it
doesn't matter if they're behind twenty
if they've been dumb enough to do this
not in a VM limitation number one if the
attackers in the VM they might not have
an apparent Wi-Fi interface if you know
assuming they've left their Wi-Fi radio
on it's going to just run that Wi-Fi
site survey and you're going to get back
to location you can see that at our
corporate offices in Pittsburgh
I was demoing this for about five
thousand people all over the building
but each of these locations were
literally someone's office you know or
someone's cubicle or something like that
it's it's that accurate to be able to
put pins that close together so the idea
is is that you you put this stand us up
on the outside of your network you know
sensible placement you stand this up on
the outside make it look very convincing
give it a good DNS name
and hope that somebody that's after you
is now going to trip over it and reveal
themselves and so some of the
information you'll get back is obviously
this is all internal stuff so I'm
getting my internal IP address here but
if this was sitting on the outside in a
real world type deployment that's going
to be external IP latitude and longitude
and an accuracy school out of a hundred
user agent as well so pretty good stuff
and if this isn't your best threat Intel
right here I don't know what is because
now you know that somebody is after you
and so maybe you take those source IPS
and just block them because obviously
they're there or the very least do a lot
more monitoring on them because they're
obviously very interested in you make
sense any questions there are a couple
other just because I have a little extra
time there's a couple other options that
you get here too there's a dot oh yes
sir
yes freezing beer yeah yeah yeah all
good all good so there's a they also
supply a dot do see X that does the same
thing a PowerShell script it does the
same thing a bash script that does the
same thing again this is all open so you
know if you're familiar in any of these
areas and want to try it out or try to
improve you know I think the folks
working on this stuff would appreciate
it
not medical devices I have seen some
that will imitate ICS devices like PLC's
Siemens PLC's that kind of stuff but
medical devices I haven't seen I'm sure
anybody making the commercial solutions
for this would be interested in hearing
about that because they're really
pushing this stuff hard oh thank you
very much so I mentioned that there's
more than a couple honey pots that are
provided with ADHD binary defenses all
artillery is here the browser
exploitation framework is here
a couple versions of honey badger honey
ports this jar combiner is really
helpful if you want to take that jar
file that I showed you the demo one and
smash it together with another jar
that's maybe a little more legit looking
that'll do it for you you know all sorts
of different stuff HTTP tar pit which is
really fun so you know again I would
just recommend going out and checking
out ADHD free download
right right yeah like this is your your
fingerprint for a honey pot and yeah I
think you could with with this
particular solution and open canary I
think you could get around some of that
because you it's so configurable that
you can say you know I only want this
guy to look like this particular type of
system rather than what I did here which
was like lighted up like a Christmas
tree and it looks crazy and because it's
installed on a per VM basis then you
would have you wouldn't have the MAC
address issue unless you deployed them
always like VMware you know instances or
something like that but even still
that's just gonna say it's VMware it's
not gonna say you know it's it's a
honeypot necessarily
okay well if there aren't any other
questions that's pretty much the extent
of it
- yes sir hmm maybe some of the older
ones you know there was one that we used
to use years ago called the la brea tar
pit which was just really a way to slow
down people who were doing recon on your
network so it would just listen on every
possible port on an unused external IP
address and it would accept your inbound
syn packet and respond with a syn ACK
and then just be like and just sit there
and wait and and so and then when the
system on the other end would send
another sin like hey I'm trying to
establish just wait so that one is so
obvious just because a port scan never
gets through and that's not a typical
situation but as far as other well-known
ones I can't really comment on that too
much sir yeah those config files once
it's set it's set and you can put it
down if you want ten new file servers
you know it would be pretty easy to just
stamp them out with with the rights
ahead of config files all right everyone
well thank you very much there's my
information if you're interested in
getting connected and enjoy the rest of
your con
[Applause]