all right try this it's not whiskey's
tea just let you know because I sound
like shit okay first off I'm going to
read off this because when they say they
gave me an hour I was like shit I got an
hour
you know how much am I going to write
well a lot and you know I passed it by
Stephen he was okay with it so please
bear with me for reading off the page
but I'm going to talk about espionage in
the modern age of information warfare
and as you can see from this slide you
know there's a lot of different
countries a lot of different entities
that are doing espionage and now that
we've moved into the digital realm
they're all in on it as well but first
Who am I as Steve said I'm a crabby old
bastard online tweeting about you know
the insanity of it all but I've been
called a security researcher and I guess
that's the thing that's stuck the most
and I end up getting myself in trouble a
lot then it ends up in the news and that
I have to banish reporters because well
except for Steve because usually I tell
them things and then they go yeah right
okay and they write something else that
you know was a little more sexy Steve
tell us is you know tell things as it is
so right now I'm doing Oh send forensics
but in my off hours I do a lot more
interesting things with national
security issues but the real deal here
is that I'm famous in Russia now the
error you see above is a 4-5-1 that's
what you get if you try to go
my domain in Russia I have been marked
either as somebody who's got some
copyright issues or I am a national
threat I'm because this is because this
is all both spy craft and all of us
hacking the things I'm gonna go with
national security threat and the reason
that I'll go with that more so than any
kind of copyright issue is because of
one-to-five some of this stuff here as
you can see Paul Manafort I've found his
spool of his daughter's texts Phil were
hacked by Ukrainians and put out in the
darknet I happened upon them and started
mining them for all kinds of fun things
including his password of double O seven
so yeah I've since the election cycle I
spent a little more time on Russia
looking into what they're doing I'd
already had a good history with them you
know about them but man afford thing
came up I also found in an another email
dump in the darknet a full accounting of
how Russia had set up their own kind of
like an arteaga press group in Ukraine
that was specifically made as a
disinformation and psyops campaign group
and I got all their financial documents
and stuff put it out on the net it was
sometime after one of those two things
and they came pretty close together when
I started writing about him that the
four five fun must have happened because
somebody from Russia who actually reads
my blog sent me a message saying hey
you're blocked in Russia I'm like what
you talking about he sent me the
screenshot so gave me waiting for my
polonium anymore anyway what is
espionage since we're talking about
espionage or that's the theme of the
conference I wanted to kind of go back
and take a broader look at the history
of espionage what it's really about
and how overall we fit into this picture
now as security professionals as a KERS
some some of you mean in the room might
actually work for you know the
government so what is espionage well as
Google puts it it is the use of spies
people to gather or steal information
from others this is for the most of the
time been military recover mental
secrets that has evolved over time just
as the notion of spying for espionage
has since the dawn of civilization
espionage at its heart though is the use
of people and now digital tools or code
to steal information from others for the
benefit of not only nation-states but
private companies or individuals today I
put this keynote together for circle
city con to discuss espionage from the
earliest mentions of its use in warfare
up to today's uses in the digital world
where everything is hyper connected
industrial espionage has become a huge
weapon in the geopolitical and private
space today giving insight and a leg up
on things for corporations individuals
and governments corporations now hire
out their own digital spies and have
used school old-school espionage in the
past but now governments are naked ly
stealing data to give to their home
countries companies as a means to a
financial and political gain governments
and militaries have and are using
espionage digital and other to not only
steal secrets but to manipulate people
to people companies governments and
militaries of their opponents these spy
campaigns now can affect outcomes of
things like elections destroy
infrastructure and manipulate the press
using the digital space as well as the
meatspace to affect these goals but what
I really wanted to do with this keynote
is to give you a bigger picture of
espionage I wanted to disabuse some of
you out there that may think you are spy
some of you might actually be a kind of
spy working for the government or in the
private sector most of you though really
likely aren't spies but instead security
professionals or hackers you aren't
James Bond you're not George smiling
but you may be on the front lines of a
shadow war and some of you might not
even know it
so espionage has been called the second
oldest prevent profession
the first is prostitution and we won't
go into that from Donna civilization we
have reports of espionage espionage use
by Greeks Romans Persians Chinese and
others Herodotus the father of history
has outlined for us an example of spies
in these early times Herodotus on the
Greek spies in the Sardis the Greek
spies arrived in Sardis and found out
all they could about the king's army who
were caught in the process questioned by
the Persian military commanders and
condemned to death but when Xerxes was
told that they were about to be executed
he disapproved of his generals decision
and sent men from his bodyguard with
others to get hold of the three spies if
they are still alive and bring them
before him as the sentence had not had
been carried out this was done the spies
were brought to the king who having
satisfied himself about the reasons for
their presence in the Sardis instructed
his guards to take them round and let
them see the whole army infantry cavalry
and then when they were satisfied that
they had seen everything to let them go
without molestation to whatever country
they pleased
after giving in this order he explained
the purpose of its of it by pointing out
that if the spies had been executed the
Greeks would not have been able to learn
in good time how incalculably great
the Persian strength was and the killing
of three men who would not have done the
enemy much harm but if on the other hand
the spies returned home he was confident
that their report on the magnitude of
the Persian power would induce the
Greeks to surrender their Liberty before
actual invasion took place so that there
would be no need to go to the trouble of
fighting war at all what a write of this
was describing here is that is what we
today would call humans
the spies gathered the intelligence of
Xerxes Army's strength and recorded back
to their commanders of course Cersei
uses overconfident and that would be as
undoing later by the mystic leaves but
that's another Selene so classical
espionage many of you probably know the
imagery here espionage has always had
much of the same goals throughout time
it is to collect or steal information to
give an edge to those parties the spies
work for as you can see it is an old
profession by the passage from Herodotus
and sergeants many of you are probably
more familiar with the more contemporary
ideas of spying from the Cold War
or maybe world war 2 or the OSS was
formed and fought against Germany the
precepts have always been the same and
will remain so in today's spying but it
seems that technology has allowed for
the use of espionage to be a purview not
just of nation-states anymore but also
of the individual as well the new
barrier for entry in espionage today
seems to be to the ability just a point
click download malware and send a
pre-made fish human on the other hand is
a bit different
spies before the digital revolution have
usually been state-sponsored and of the
realm of the secret wars between powers
for instance if you look at the images
on the slide you will see fictionalized
characters from john lecarre a
Tinker Tailor Soldier Spy these
archetypes of spies are closer to the
mark than the ones then one might think
in fact they Caray for David Cornwell
was in fact a spy working for mi5 before
writing his novels as such he writes
about them in a way that is very close
to reality in a world of spies and
espionage before the digital age it was
focused on human human intelligence
gathering from people not just digitally
stealing information from computer human
is all about people working with other
people as sources to get someone to give
up or steal information insert bad
information or other kinds of operations
with a norm that was the for the most
part done in person interacting with
people without an element of Technology
as we do today the technology relied on
then consisted of ways usually to
exfiltrate information securely out of
the enemy territory or to conceal
messages to and from opportunities in
the field from prying eyes this type of
espionage still goes on today but see
but unfortunately it has taken a
backseat to technologies that just carry
out the SBIR is through sicken or Eiland
electronic information gathering and
from my point of view we've lost
something there isn't there's much to be
said about human interaction and
intelligence gathering but since the 90s
we have lost our edge human is hard it
seems and there were many kinds of spies
needed for day-to-day operations
types of spies spies come in different
types there are varying kinds of tasks
that spies carry out some collect
information by observing and passing
along some are out there recruiting to
get information and run agents or assets
and oftentimes these to intercept there
are many names for these kinds of spies
case agents covert agent NOC agent
that's not official cover
handler targeter etc the goal of all of
them though is to gather information to
keep the animal the analysts who then
brief those in charge to help them make
decisions in the government on other
non-governmental spies might do much the
same but pass the information on to
those who are paying for it privately or
one could go the Asian words of sunset
which I'm kind of loath to use sunsets
really overused but and consider the
types of spies in this way this is a
quoting from sunset what types of spies
are there Sun Tzu had the definition of
defender dancer hence the use of spies
of whom there are five classes local
spies inward spies converted spies
doomed spies and surviving spies when
these kinds of arcane descriptions
though you can see what he was talking
about there are spies you recruit from
the local populace that you're attacking
there are inward spies these are the
people inside a government or a military
there are converted spies the spies you
catch and then you make them double
agents you turn them and lastly you have
the doomed and the surviving spies and
and really what that means is just to if
you're going to burn somebody you're
going to burn somebody and you never had
any intention to keep them around the
surviving spies the one you want to keep
so anybody you're running like an asset
in Russia you want to eventually
excellent rate them out because they're
worth something and you're actually
dealing with them today though there has
been an overuse of the word spy and of
the idea of what a spy is with all this
technology people think that if you
penetrate a system you are in fact that
spot this is not necessarily the case
and as hackers or security professionals
you should know the differences between
differences before making the claim it
is also problematic that much of the
security industry as a penchant for
using military jargon espionage terms
and ideas have been added to the mix
like tradecraft
which
me just makes everything we do a little
more word salad II in fact when you call
yourself a ninja you're calling yourself
a spy unless you are from ego or Koga
and several hundred years old you're not
just out of curiosity you all know who
these people are no that's Valerie Plame
she worked for the CIA is a NOC agent
she was burned by george w bush
scooter libby the one on the right is
from the Americans
she's a handler for the Russian agents
in place in America I forget her name
and then show and the bottom is not a
bacos and she's one of the ones that
helped find Osama bin Laden she's a
target er she was a full NOC and she's a
handler so just to give you that context
so on a tradecraft tradecraft is a word
you'll hear today in the information
security circles this is improper
military in the espionage world what
tradecraft means in the spine world has
been practices and technologies by which
spies plied their trade while the
original original tradecraft of
yesterday would mean code making and
concealment how to use a dead drop or
how to lose the surveillance team it has
been adapted to the technological means
to defeat detection of hacking and
infiltrating and controlling systems
keeping persistence much of the
tradecraft and digital as being our
centers on technical understanding of
operating systems and how to manipulate
systems not people a caveat to that
would be the social engineer in the
InfoSec area
but really how many red teams are
actually recruiting insiders as assets
to actively steal secrets from them
knowingly if you want to think about it
in terms of an analogy one could make
the illusion compromising a system
recruiting an asset you find the
weakness and exploit it you interrogate
the system for information you
exfiltrate the data and then you keep
persistence like I said but that is
about the extent of the reality
tradecraft otherwise is a list of
processes and procedures to ensure that
you succeed in compromising a system and
keeping it of course in real espionage
tradecraft you need to use it to protect
yourself and your assets if you don't
you can end up dead or they could end up
dead their term Moscow rules for example
really had possible life-and-death
consequences for the asset person your
running person your recruiting as a spy
because you know if you don't keep your
tradecraft well you could lead the KGB
right to your your asset suddenly they
go bye-bye
the tradecraft of concealment of what
the operative was doing in a hostile
environment like Moscow was paramount to
having a successful operation if you
blew a digital operation hacking a
system in a hostile country it may not
lead to a bullet in the back of the head
of somebody in Lubyanka that's what I'm
saying which brings us to when things
started to change in spying as secrets
became more readily stolen through
technological means like phones and
cables their use fog mented human
intelligence and made agents lives a
little bit easier electronic espionage
of course as technologies came along the
use of them to carry out espionage
allowed for a shift in spy the telephone
and the radio both made seismic changes
and how we can collected information as
well as getting it from human sources
now the pivot was those humans that were
not that were
recruited we're also being listened to
as well surreptitious ly basically we
went from having star chambers opening
mail to engaging telecommunication
companies like Bell into giving us
access to international cable traffic
secrets are being stolen directly from
those who held them without their
knowledge and it was good listening
devices or bugs became an integral part
of espionage augmenting the information
being given by sources and gave us a
bigger picture of what was going on in
the adversaries camp why recruited
everyone when you can just implant a bug
in their office or get their cables
delivered to you from the company
carrying them does this sound familiar
to you today it seems that this is still
the key through much of the espionage
where you carry out we listen in or we
look over the shoulders of those we want
to spy on it became a passive thing in
the sense of in one sense and in another
it became an aggressive means in
creating a way to hack somebody's data
tap them and just steal it
activities that before you had to really
recruit somebody to get you know into a
hard target of course one still needed
human intelligence agents to sometimes
get the bugs into the places where they
were most needed in one case for
instance the Great Seal of the United
States was given to a US ambassador to
the Soviet Union in 1945 by the Young
Pioneers and that's the Cub Scouts in
Russia but much more indoctrinating into
in government this device housed the
theremin listening device made by Leon
theremin a guy from the start wrecking
it successfully bugged the ambassador's
study until this discovery in 1954 and
you know basically we got some people
coming in saying here's a present and
they went great and he put it in his own
study it's that simple but it took
somebody giving it to him to do it
wouldn't like
if you just got an Amazon package today
would you just hang it up in your office
I don't know it was the time when you
had to implant devices to listen in now
you just have to drop code then things
really changed once the computer came to
be and they became networked via phone
connections or networks the paradigm in
spying really shifted what was once
considered to be a secret in a secure
area with a million within a military
base or a think tank was now available
to anyone who not a hack
we went from holding data in a safe in a
room with a guard to a computer
connected to the internet with an IP
stay in essence not secure at all for
some reason we all thought it was secure
because it was digital and it was you
know who can do that who could figure
that out at least in my perspective at
the time this changed for many in 1986
when an astronomer named cliff Stoll
found that the computer in his
university was being hacked to the
charges for time on the system mainframe
via the school's accounting department
with that he became an unwitting sleuth
and that discovered a Russian agent
hacking into the university system to
access military secrets and networks on
connected bases elsewhere via ARPANET
which had just been connected together
it was now possible to cut out the human
altogether safe for the hacker to access
data and steal it for your country this
change the networking of the world was
just the start of all what use of all
you see happening today you all out
there know what is like today anything
networked is susceptible to attack as
well as those in air-gap systems that
someone can physically access or in some
cases you can listen to and you know get
the clicks out of a harddrive things
like that keyboard clips any other
emanations and
was not only out of the box she was
wreaking havoc every time someone
connect to the computer to the network
or save it of files would drive and
network they did from from early
military university networks we have the
Internet today built not to be secure
but redundant in case of a nuclear
attack and a free highway for
adversaries looking to not only steal
information but perhaps now carry out
degrade and deny operations as well
everything went digital in espionage
began a new golden age digital espionage
from all of this connectivity we have
seen the floodgates open to any number
of attacks nation-states are stealing
corporate data to give to their own
companies to get ahead military and
government powers are stealing
information on country's readiness as
well as plans for aircraft and other
hardware for a reverse engineering to
keep them the military parity as well we
have military warfare electronic warfare
economic warfare cyber warfare
information warfare and the list goes on
still other adversaries are using the
digital battle space to have
psychological and kinetic effects as
espionage goals
the line between espionage and war has
been always been a little bit blurred
but it seems today that the line has
been completely erased in the digital
age we're using technology to have
direct effects on people solely using
code and hacking skills the end user is
the target of the Digital Spy as much as
corporate corporations or governments
there may be no need for a person to
meet the target real life all they need
to do now is send them an email or a
LinkedIn invite to gather the initial
access and recruit them unwittingly we
all have become useful idiots in a way
all of this now is handled by people
behind anonymous keyboards but consider
the day when it was augmented it's not
taken over by AI
then there will be no human element
whatsoever the times they are changing
and so are the spies and just for your
edification jsf that's the Chinese
version they stole all the data and they
made their own nothing like going to a
paris air show and seeing your own plane
take off with chinese symbols are types
of digital spies today's digital spies
come in a few different types you have
those who are actively compromising
systems those who are targeting those
systems or footprinting those who are
creating software and those who are
managing the infrastructure is they're
all bare kinship to the designations and
jobs I mentioned earlier but for the
most part the only human interaction
they have is not with the targets but
instead each other in their teams it
takes a team of digital spies to carry
out and SP adopt espionage operation and
these people work in cells inside
agencies like the NSA the GRU the CIA
teams have tact technical people and
logicians work together to compromise
systems and networks to gather
intelligence and pass the data to
linguists and analysts these skills are
not soft skills dealing with social
interactions and methods that a human
specialist would use and as such are
quite different from those in the field
for those borrow a towel operative would
not be in the field as much as behind a
desk in Fort Meade or San Antonio
reaching out across the world to access
networks and data by way of exploiting
them sometimes though there is a melding
of the two kinds of spies with a field
operative that has technical skills
technicians on SSG which is the special
surveillance group at the FBI for one
instance might have agents who are
technically skilled and go out on
assignments in the
see a a Technical Services Group as well
would have these kinds of people able to
go on site and access a system as part
of a team however they would not be out
recruiting human assets and carrying out
tradecraft other than technical
operations of course all of these
examples are from governmental agencies
nations against nation spying which
makes them spies because they are
governmental II sanctioned and work for
the likes of the CIA or the NSA this is
a key difference between our community
and the real world of espionage we may
have some of the same kinds of players
digitally but we aren't actually spies
unless you're I would say working for a
government agency or even a private
agency that's kind of affiliated or off
the radar off the reservation you want
to where you want to call it because you
getting into a legal territory assets
who can be passively listening or
actively exploding things to active and
passive espionage for a long time the
u.s. espionage both digitally and
analogue had been more passive stealing
data from had been the mainstay of many
nations by a hacking lately though that
bit has been flipped by the likes of
Russia to a more forward footing as may
have heard the term active measures are
new the new rage and with that both
sides of the coin are leveraged you
steal data and use it actively to affect
outcomes and the digital space it may be
easier to affect greater change or cause
damage due to asymmetrical asymmetrical
nature of the medium in the case of
Stuxnet the u.s. Israel and Britain
managed to affect the political and
technical landscape of Iran by
sabotaging their ability to refine
radioactive materials with Mellon code
prevented the Iranian regime from
becoming a nuclear power for years and
seven back to or five years I can't
remember the exact measurement that they
gave
Russia has used code to attack the grid
system in Ukraine and disrupt their
election systems on election day other
countries have attacked banking systems
like the Iranians in reprisal for Natanz
- the switch has been easier to flip
from passive intelligence collection to
active measures and kinetic outcomes
from the use of networks encode because
everything connected is Volvo who with
every paradigm change that comes too
late
within a battle space new
countermeasures are creating the
tradecraft of one can spawn the
countermeasure of another and defeat
those attacks the great game of
espionage as it has been referred to in
the past continues on in the digital
realm what you all have to understand
now is that you are a piece on that
playing field whether you're like it or
not if you have access or have a device
that can be leveraged then you are a
combatant anyone now can be a target of
digital espionage whether you work for
the government or a company that makes
something that hostile government wants
how many people that Sony ever thought
that they would be a target of a
nation-state attack over a political
beef you all are now in the middle of
not just your work systems in the middle
and not just in your work systems if you
or your system can be recruited witting
or not to be an asset of an Indian OSH
campaign then you might find yourself in
the middle of an international incident
the targeting also can just be digital
not just it'll digital but human as well
even today human is still very important
even if many are not enamored with
hacking to see it so onto human again in
today's well so human intelligence and
talking about digital espionage I want
to also cover this that sliver of area
where human still plays a role in
espionage in the digital sphere a
premier area that I am acquainted with
are the terrorists on the Internet
many of these players are not digitally
as savvy as most which is changing but
our online trying to hide the real
identities well posting all kinds of
crap these kinds of operations require
using social engineering as well as
other technical and social tradecraft to
insert yourself into their networks
recruit assets wittingly or unwittingly
this can also require the technical
skills of a hacker to attempt to
compromise their system sort attract
them online so we've seen this merging
of abilities the same soft skills are
still used still in use by traditional
espionage that only play out in the
digital realm but into the meet space as
well outside the usual box of pentesting
mail you all may be acquainted with the
acquainted with imagine that you not
only just try to compromise someone's
computer but actively recruit and asset
through the internet to trick others
into carrying out attacks on systems
inside their network kind of like
fishing but a little more active a good
example of this kind of work also would
be the highs and lows of the Russian
troll farm that played a part in the
2016 election active measures campaign
while the depth of the asset management
and soft skills may not have been as
deep there were times when the targets
when the agents of the IRA were actively
recruiting people on Twitter and reddit
as well as an email to actions in the
real world one instance even had an
activist get money from an IRA Ageing
create all kinds of materials and go out
and have a you know a thing on the
street which really didn't pay off but
they tried and this guy actually fell
for it and was unwitting agent for the
GRU over politics as we move forward
post 2016 we should expect to see more
of this kind of activity and not only
that not only reaches out to people on
social media but as that transfer to
local action
as well as making those people who
actively carry out events to the useful
idiots for the GRU or for other spy
organizations human element still is
still very important as we have seen in
recent events of active measures in
hybrid warfare
so hybrid warfare active measures
probably two terms you've heard in the
news the Senate the house reports so
where does that come from
this brings us to the next turning in
the digital warfare and espionage space
as we saw in 2016 Russia used the
Internet to attack the American
electoral process the use of the digital
domain has gone from outright spying to
steal and stealing IP to actively using
it for disinformation and active
measures campaigns to cause chaos and
potentially regime change which it seems
at work here once again the lines of
espionage and warfare have been erased
by the technology of the networked
device and now social media Valery
Gerasimov made the comment on this on
the slide you see here and and though
many would consider him the creator of
the call the Jurassic Tran
of which there is no document you look
for it doesn't exist it's made up by
whoever wrote that up
he made some positives in a different
paper but there's no doctrine he made
the connection of using these espionage
techniques and tools from the
information warfare space as a precursor
to invasion his idea was that you often
you soften the target up cause chaos
debilitate them technically in
kinetically and you may not even have to
send in groups given what has happened
since Trump won you can see how
effective this can be on the world stage
consider now that all of these systems
and assets one one would attack are
things you use every day the grid the
news social media your car phone you
toaster everything that is network today
if
everything that is networks things if
Facebook has made you the product
Jurassic mauve has done the same for you
as a pawn and the greater game of
espionage and warfare so there's no
longer just your phone your computer
your toaster or your car that is the
target of this kind of espionage and
warfare is now your psyche and your
ability to reason if anything we have
seen over the last couple of years
that even without hacking just by
putting out fake story lines one can
cause great damage and while this is all
going on it is all of you out there out
here in the community making new
exploits having conferences giving
ammunition to the spy and the warfare
community too you see hacker started all
this by being inquisitive and breaking
things we do have some culpability to
everything that is happening now as well
screams me to hackers and spotters so
here we are in this conference today
themed on spying and you might be
thinking a bit differently about what
spies are on what technology has done to
espionage you here in this audience are
not average users by any means you are a
harder target for espionage on average
but you are likely more susceptible to
being targeted by a nation-state because
of your skills some of you might be
thinking out there right now I just work
blue team for Staples but the reality is
that if you hold the keys to networks
that have access to information that an
adversary wants they will attempt to
leverage you as well as the average
government functionary given some of the
fish that are out there by adept
adversaries can you even say for sure
that they have not tried to get you have
you detected their attacks have you
stopped them
is this even something that you've
considered
those out there who are doing pen
testing and red teaming you too could be
a target in fact you might be a
high-value target for a nation-state
these spies might not only use technical
measures to attempt to steal from you
though you might have an actual asset
they would like to recruit and you might
not be even know that you're it in fact
if we've been to DEFCON you have likely
come into contact with spies from ours
and other countries that guy you might
be drinking with and going clubbing with
could in fact be a traditional spy
trying to see if you are worth
recruiting and recruitable in another
way what if you work daily on making
exploits are testing for vulnerabilities
on common systems would you not be a
tasty target for a spy plot to steal
your own a or recruit you to make
something new something for a foreign
power it's not inconceivable really in
fact a few years back a bunch of hackers
attended a party in Vegas for DEFCON
what they didn't know was that the party
was hosted by a hostile foreign power
looking to see who they might recruit
hackers hacktivists security richer
researcher all our targets with
espionage activists and spies this is
where it gets fun white hats aren't the
only targets of nation-state might want
an attack or recruiting those out there
who are part of the archeology of
hacktivists are prime targets for
espionage these actors can be used to
gather intelligence used to uses cutouts
or emulated to make an active can make
measure or campaign look like it was
them instead of the nation-state that
actually pulled it off in the case of
anonymous there was a subset that have
taken on the name and the methods of
anonymous to further their own political
agendas such as the jihad ease of the
cyber Caliphate or non-ghosts they have
many names but in some cases their names
are only covers for operations
of the GRU hacking into facing pages for
political giggles could also be used as
disinformation campaigns by the likes of
Russia or anyone else we deems it useful
to scapegoat them and to make a
statement enhance their scare factor
let's say sometimes active groups are
infiltrated digitally as well as
literally by individual spies to gather
intelligence and effect operations
sometimes those spies are actually
double agents like Sabu who took down
Lowell set as a cooperating informant
and actively worked with the FBI to
collect intel on all the players and
help them arrest them all to stop them
from causing more damage it turns out
that in Anonymous you really aren't so
anonymous and that can lead to double
agents putting you in the pokey the same
can bad outcomes can happen when a
nation-state uses you for their own
purposes and you later get out of get
put in prison for hacking something that
someone you thought was on your team
told you to act kind of like what
happened with all set consider this to
WikiLeaks started out as a
self-proclaimed force of good it has
since been co-opted by the KGB
I still call them that but not the FSB
they don't change the spots and Russia
as a tool of propaganda and active
measures against the u.s. in a hybrid
war all you all of you could be used in
the same way so now we have a hybrid
warfare going on previous slides I
talked about active measures and the
pre-suit precepts of the Tarasque mob
doctrine all the actions that took place
online and off in the 2016 in 2016
complement the comprise the doctrine
that jasper has evolved positive of
fighting a war using espionage and
active measures without having to deploy
troops the active measures campaign of
hacking the DNC leaking the information
of WikiLeaks and the use of a cutout
called gucchy for 2.0 our
hybrid warfare they use digital
espionage for its ends the Internet and
any systems connected is now a player in
the digital battlefield and you as the
user of that system are upon within this
kind of war for the use of many
tried-and-true disciplines of old-school
warfare can be used as a force amplifier
due to the nature of the medium
asymmetric nature we saw this up close
and personal in the troll farm operation
and the WikiLeaks dumps in 2016 then
candidate Trump and his minions also
began to use the same tools of leaks
disinformation and psyops to incite
their bases their base and all the while
Russia spun the plate faster and faster
to the outcome of it all of all that you
are all too familiar with today
Jeremiah posited that one could
destabilize a country by using hacking
disinformation propaganda and psyops
Russia then proved them right the twist
with the Russians was that they
mobilized all this data that was stolen
along with current accounts on social
media to carry out disinformation
campaigns or zine formats in the ayah
against the US and our electoral system
at large disinformation that according
to James clapper likely turned the
corner on Trump winning the electoral
college by engaging his base and
inciting the spectrum of people in the
u.s. clappers comment recently not the
government line but he's a private
citizen now so if you're paying
attention to that whole debate it's
easily conceivable that trumps
electrical wind which was very slim in
the sense of you know he a thousand
votes I think it was that all of this
dense information all the active
measures could have turned that tide
everyone seems to be focused on OK will
they hack the election election systems
the websites they had the access to the
voter rolls but there's no proof that
they did anything else
so the disinformation I don't know how
many of you are familiar with the term
and the you know the actual sense of it
being used in a military kind of milieu
but the definition of disinformation is
the use of false information that is
intended to mislead especially
propaganda issued by a government
organization to a rival power or media
what was once a problem for the news
media disinformation in the digital age
has broken out into being mean a means
everyone with a computer a blog a phone
can dis inform the masses with for their
own purposes so you can carry out your
own disinformation campaign if you want
you can buy a bunch of bots do it I
personally have done it small small use
against some people but you can do it
daily now the President of the United
States uses Twitter to dis informants
constituency emulating the narratives of
Fox News credit threads for the likes of
Q and on and others attempt to pass off
bogus stories as reality and inflame
those who are willing to believe them
into action at the polls at the very
least and at the worst of the physical
action some of the attacks we've been
seeing stuff that happened in North
Carolina this information and a new
digital age of espionage entails not
only manipulating social media
narratives but soon enough if not
already inserting fake data into them as
well in hopes that no one would be able
to deny the fault they're false nature
in point of fact of the data dump by
Grucci 42.0 contain contained fake
documents inserted into the dump to dis
inform people about hillary clinton as
well it was only once the metadata was
checked that the fraudulent claims were
deflated all of this is happening online
in your space and is fairly easy to
carry out as an actor with some money
and some time rush
so far has been the preeminent user of
these tactics and methods but soon
enough others will follow suit
of course others may be a bit more
subtle about on it and who knows what
the fallout might be from our greater
campaign carried out by some other
well-funded government actors all of
this made all of this though is made
easier because the digital medium is a
mystery to the general populace who are
unable to or unwilling to dig further
for the truth and that's something we
were discussing at lunch days you got
the internet you got all this
information but first can you trust it
anymore
and second do you know how to find it
and third if you find it can you
delineate between what is truth and what
is fiction you know history is written
by the winners of the battle the war is
it true because it's in a history book
or has it been manipulated per country
you know your history book might say
something different than another
country's history but just saying but
wait it gets darker still when you start
manipulating people's fears and psyches
with psyops
is the good stuff so it's part of those
disinformation operations are psyops
campaigns psyops
psychological operations have been a
mainstay of espionage since the advent
of newspapers leaflets radio and TV
however in the new digital space we have
blogs and all other means of
dissemination via video audio text or
what have you Alex Jones when not
hawking his male vitality herbals is one
of the more prolific users of psyops
whether he is an asset knowingly of a
nation-state like Russia has yet to be
determined however look at what he spins
out there and the way he does it he's
trying to strike terror as well as
incite worship from those weak minded
enough to believe it sting well he yells
about governmental governments carrying
out psyops against
him and his people he's carrying him out
against his people in fact one of the
things well one of the more crazy things
and people believe this ship I don't
know why he says the government is full
of globalist lizard people it's it's not
V it's not the eighties it's not a TV
show you got it in fact one of the
things he has put out there is a direct
Russian black pop agonda operation
concerning the CIA's creating AIDS I kid
you not this lie lineup story came from
Russia
back in the 80s once aids became
prevalent and is still being pimped by
the likes of Jones and others you can
see the CIA guys making aids our t2 is
used not only as an outlet for
disinformation but also plays at the
psyche strings of those believers
feeding them a steady diet of ideas and
stories to cause cognitive dissonance
what about ism is one of their
specialties and you can see it when
Trump uses it all the time - you know
what there was a spy in my my operation
no there wasn't but now he's getting
tension on this it's been recently
reported through polling that more
people believe now there was some sort
of spy in his campaign but not a Russian
spy
the DOJ spy it's nuts were through the
looking-glass a good example of a PSYOP
with a digital implementation was
carried out by Russia and Ukraine in
protesters in Kiev were protesting
Russian interference in their country
when everyone with a cell phone got at
the protest got a text note saying that
they were part of a mass riot this was
an attempt to
all the dissent and a threat to those
with the text that Russia knew who they
were and where they lived in hopes that
they were breaking out that didn't
really work because my don happened
later on that you can see what what
they're getting into
ubiquitous technology has allowed for
the hybrid war to reach a very personal
very personally to anyone on the network
to scare them spy on them or to dis
inform them in a hybrid war that could
become very kinetic kinetic meaning that
you could be targeted by a drone or
disappeared by a government so we've got
this new term I don't know if anyone's
actually coined it hybrid genetic
information warfare I detest the word
cyber trying not to use it I'll think I
used it too much here it means Seth it's
not okay so where is all this going with
the tools and techniques of hacking and
espionage in tandem with disinformation
and kinetic attacks by a digital domain
we have ourselves in an existential
crisis and by existential I'm eating
more philosophically than life-and-death
though it has come to that in certain
circumstances like some Iranian nuclear
scientists being blown up in a car in
Iran or a gcq that GCHQ analysts being
found stuffed in gym bag dead with all
these tools in the hands of those actors
nation state another we could be in a
real we could be a real trouble here the
cumulative efforts effects of Russians
acts on our electoral system did in fact
aid Trump to victory in the US it's my
personal opinion the outcomes of that
election are still being played but in
as much as there they've been seen so
far we have become a weakened power on
the world stage and are still too
fragmented to really effectively
willpower during and after his reign
when one caveat ins this morning
yesterday it was yesterday I was in
between flights and heard that he had
decided to ban all BMWs from being
the United States was huge tariffs or he
just fucking nuts but by doing all this
it places our ability to project power
in the world or to work with other
countries to project power on other
nation states they're like North Korea
it's all being fractured and the chaos
is everywhere he is a chaos monkey what
else might an adversary like Russia do
given that these measures have worked so
well and that the means to counter them
seems to be so non-existent the norms of
over cyber warfare
there's the cyber or information warfare
ourselves are as yet weak and it seems
like in our current state will be unable
to complete them and promulgate them to
the world because of the fractious
nature of today's political landscape
indeed it all can go very kinetic now
from the digital space everything is
connected everything is hackable right
some of these stories out there are true
that you could actually blow up
pressurized tanks of oil or other
flammable liquid liquids by messing with
PLC's you could probably cause deaths
abusing technologies by hacking them and
inserting code just as much as digital
GPS data gathered live from a phone this
actually happened to Junaid Hussain in
Syria he was a few slides back from of
the human slide none of these none of us
you are likely to mourn this jihadi but
consider if the technology were turned
on on you by a hostile government how
would you feel about that
so finally
where do we go from here
let's sum up what we have so far we live
in a world where it is easy that's easy
to dis inform distract and distort and
cause chaos with information alone we
also have a system of networked objects
that can be used to take down other
systems and cause more chaos that
reaches into the real world
it can affect by denying access to
resources like telco and power you'd be
without power so there's a real real
life element that you're starting to see
although I mean Ukraine is probably the
best example of taking a grid down
almost completely here it's a little
more difficult because of so many
different companies but you have to
consider at this time we also have all
our personal information in the hands of
corporations that are selling it to
whoever has the money for that matter
Facebook and Cambridge analytical showed
us that not only would they sell the
data but they would sell it to a company
that actively claimed they carried out
psyops and propaganda campaigns for
dictators sweet plus when the
information isn't being sold for profit
it is being stolen by the likes of
nation-states like China for their own
purposes of espionage from places like
OPM you have an SF 86 it's there's no
where you live they know who who your
relatives are they know all of it we're
also we also seem to have a problem with
persistence of anonymity and privacy as
well that said same information that is
being collected soul and stolen by all
kinds of actors seems to be the standard
now even if we don't want the custodian
of the data to keep or sell it in the
first place even recently the notion of
live GPS tracking of our phones being
sold to whoever paid for it is in the
news as a
company has been doing so without
thought about privacy and patience at
all we are my friends in a digital pan
optic on subject espionage theft misuse
and now active measures by foreign
powers and digital Wars we did not sign
up for these are being actively
leveraged against the general
populations now because of the
technologies we all carry and are all
slaves to we are the product for
corporations while we are the targets
for those actors who want to spy on us
nip you late us and carry out various
kinds of warfare against us welcome to
the great game of digital espionage my
friends maybe it would just be better to
play a nice game of chess that's it
[Applause]
yeah I wrote a lot