things and forensics on the internet of
things and how it affects investigations
and digital forensics a little bit about
me my name is Jessica Hyde my day job
and director of friends accept magnet
forensics don't worry this has nothing
to do specifically with that before that
I worked as a contractor for the US
government for both basis technologies
and American systems doing forensic
things and for Ernst & Young before that
I was in the Marine Corps Rob no Marines
in the room okay I also teach mobile
device forensics adjunct at George Mason
University where I did my MS I am NOT
gonna stand behind the podium because
you wouldn't see me all right so just a
little bit about what we're gonna go
over today we're gonna talk a little bit
about the Internet of Things really
really brief I promise you then we'll
talk about categories then we're gonna
actually start talking about data that
we've parsed and recovered and some
things I've helped on investigations on
and we're gonna it's going to be pretty
cool I'm gonna get pretty down dirty
it'll be nice and fun but why not start
at the end right so if you leave after
this slide that's cool because it's the
conclusion now the the thing I want you
to get out of here is that the Internet
of Things is going to become more
important in digital forensics that
there's a wealth of evidence to be found
and that that evidence is going to
become more of a part of what we do and
why that is and that if we don't start
looking at data off of the Internet of
Things we're going to be missing a lot
of information or investigations because
there's a lot that is there and that
it's going to more often be our suspect
and what I mean by that is any piece of
equipment can play all three roles it
can be the suspect in a crime it can be
a witness to a crime and it can actually
be the victim of a crime and we all know
that our devices can be hacked and taken
over
I'm sure cat told you all about that
earlier today where the devices can
become the victim but in a lot of
instances the device can also be the
suspect so you know start the beginning
we need to define where we are with the
Internet of Things I'm not going to make
you wear a definition read definitions
but the whole point is here is we're
talking about any object with an
embedded system that's capable of
collecting data and it's really
interesting and I actually only included
this because I thought it was fast
meaning that the definition of
internet-of-things first time it's
conning was actually by a gentleman by
the name of Peter Lewis who was part of
the Black Caucus foundation in 1985 so
it's actually a pretty long time ago and
his definition actually I believe is
best he says the Internet of Things or
IOT is the integration of people
processes and technology with
connectible devices and sensors to
enable remote monitoring status
manipulation and evaluation of trends of
such devices and then he said what I am
calling Internet of Things will be far
reaching this man was wise beyond his
years so why do we care about this well
we care about this simply because a
number of devices right we have already
succeeded the point where there are more
connected devices than people and by
2020 it is estimated there's going to be
50 billion connected devices the the
trends as far as what people are
predicting ranges from anywhere to 50
billion in 2020 to one trillion by 2015
no we did not hit that number that was a
really bad estimation by IBM but the
whole thing is people are really all
over the place
78 point 1 million wearables were sold
in 2015 how many of you show of hands
are wearing a wearable device right now
a SmartWatch a Fitbit anything how many
of you only have one piece of on you at
this moment this is part phone all right
put your hands how many of you have two
or more pieces of tech on you right at
this moment yeah that's a 90 percent of
the room so that's why this was
important by 2020 so in two years it's
predicted that each one of us are going
to have 5.1 connected devices if anybody
want to guess how many I have in my home
right now 46 when I ran thing on my
house right before leaving I had 46
things connected I am NOT the average
user 2016 PwC did a survey 45% of people
on a fitness band 57% of SmartWatch and
12% smart clothing before I started
getting into IOT forensics I didn't even
know there was smart clothing I really
hope that smart clothing tells some
people that it's time to wash it but
that's not what it usually does it's
usually more geared towards heart rate
monitors you know when I started getting
into IOT
forensics I'll tell a quick clip my
husband actually was like can you please
pick a hobby that will actually help the
house and I said yes they make smart
washers and I finally won my smart
washer is coming on the 4th of June
which is Monday and I can't tell you how
happy I am
my husband is happier because it means
maybe I'll help with the laundry just to
create data look everything else is done
by robots right I've got the robot
vacuum but there's also issues in for
security right so it's not just your
home use 25 percent of enterprise
attacks are predicted by 2020 to involve
something related to IOT and when we're
looking at the perceived fit of a smart
home it's really really interesting to
think that 40 percent of people think
this is helping them with security would
you agree not really the best use of
security but uh but they do they say
it's mainly convenience right it's a
real reason and there's a lot of
commercial applications with a lot of
times people don't think about people
aren't thinking about the fact that
logistics trucks companies are actually
using IOT to monitor shipments people
aren't thinking about the fact that
factories are using smart
implementations that machines that
you're everybody knows vehicles are and
we know what we're doing in the home but
we need to start thinking about how it's
going to affect us and why does it
matter to us because of the artifacts
and the data that's left behind so we're
going to be looking at a couple things
we're gonna be looking at smartphone
data that's taken off with a paired app
to the IOT device in some instances
we're going to be looking at the devices
themselves in this instance we're going
to focus on three different areas today
we're gonna pick a smart home device
we're gonna pick a wearable and we are
going to pick something I like to call
the category things that go something
into automotive spectrum and of these
the only one of these specific devices
that I tear down the physical device and
we'll give you pin outs for it's the
echo and the echo dot but based on most
of my research across the spectrum most
of the useful data you're going to find
lives in two places it's on the parrot
app in the clouds the devices actually
tend to have less data stored on them
helps with size so smart phone and cloud
are usually typically going to be your
best sources so we're gonna go over some
categories and it's really interesting
where there
sometimes in places you don't think of
so there's actually a lot of bio
information that's being controlled by
IOT everything from heart monitoring
implants which has used in cases to
prove that heart rate isn't there isn't
elevated at time it would to biochip
transformers on farm animals and this is
actually this case where this pacemaker
this gentleman in the UK he set fire to
his house and then claimed and insurance
claim it said you know that his house
had caught on fire well they actually
pulled the data from his pacemaker and
discovered two things one his heart rate
did not elevate at the time that the
fire was set up as if he had been scared
and two his heart condition did not give
him the time to have packed as much
stuff if he got out of his house before
the fire got bad enough for him to
escape and it was questioned in court
and it was allowed to be admitted and he
it was four hundred thousand dollars
worth of damages and the insurance
company wound up not having to pay there
is some weird stuff guys there are
electric lamps that have sensors on them
right so when you're talking about IOT
it gets weird automobiles has multiple
built-in sensors multiple cars involved
here things we're going to talk about
smartwatches and wearable you guys are
used to nanny everything from your
pebble to your Apple watch to your
Fitbit to your Samsung gear but I don't
he's also being used in places it might
be really helpful when there's wrongful
deaths and weird things that happen
there's DNA devices right now that are
monitoring food pathogens
there are IOT devices that are used in
firefighters uniforms to predict heat
and degradation and notify them when
they're in danger and when they have to
leave and monitor smoke there's smart
speakers which we're going to talk about
we're gonna dug into the echo and it'll
be fun and then I bought a home
automation a lot of people are referring
to this as smart home this is everything
like your nest thermostat that's
controlling temperature to your smart
refrigerator to your smart washer to
tells you when it's time to move
everything to the dryer to heating we've
got robotic vacuums and air purifiers
we've got vehicle attainment systems
we're going to talk a bit about and then
we have ovens refrigerators and freezers
that use Wi-Fi for remote monitoring and
think about all the good data washers
and dryers fine
getting mine so what my husband doesn't
realize and I don't know if he's gonna
watch this video he's a pen tester so
it's a good chance
I just bought a $1,200 washer and I'm
gonna take it apart all right so where
do we find the data I might have alluded
to this before but there are really
three main sources of data in general
right on the internet of things you've
got the thing itself which may or may
not store a significant amount of data
you've got the paired application be it
on the computer or a smartphone and you
have the cloud
everybody loves the cloud let's kick it
off and talk about some wearables so I'm
gonna focus on one device at a time
every single device that I'm going to
talk to you about today I have
personally used in an investigation the
reason that I have exploited these
devices was to help in investigations
where I was assisting so first we're
gonna talk about is Fitbit so for those
who don't know if it's actually been
around for over a decade
so it's since 2007 out in California and
in 2016 they bought pebble which means
they bought the good hardware but they
only didn't buy the hardware part they
only kept the software people uh-huh in
2017 they also inquired a SmartWatch
startup vector watch srl so it sounds
like they're trying to keep their
competition in check I don't know that
specifically but this is one of the most
popular apps and it has been used in
several investigations so I'm gonna
mention three so there was a woman who
had claimed that she had been raped
while house-sitting and as it turned out
she said that she had been asleep at the
time wearing her Fitbit of course she
was because she had to you know track
her steps she claimed to be sleeping
when someone broke into the house and
took advantage of her and raped her well
as it turned out her Fitbit proved that
she actually trashed the house to make
the scene and was up about and moving it
and was not asleep at the time and it
actually proved her allegation false
there was also a civil case where a
personal trainer had made a claim about
the inability to continue work
professionally due to a health issue and
that they were no longer that they
needed workmen's comp and the Fitbit was
actually used against the physical
fitness trainer to prove that they were
actually being more active than they
were and then this is a really
interesting new one that I love I mean I
don't love it a woman died sounds
horrible right but there was this murder
that anybody in here from Wisconsin know
ok so there was a murder
this poor woman Nicole Vanderheiden 31
years old in the middle of night is
taken out of her house and she is killed
and she is killed by this man named
George Burke some data from Google
proves George Burgess location is with
the body at the time of the murder
George birch turns around realizing that
he has no defense to say he didn't do it
and he wasn't there and he said that
Nicole's boyfriend who resided with her
actually held him under threat of death
and duress and brought him with him to
kill her luckily for this gentleman who
was erroneously accused he was wearing
his Fitbit and asleep the data was
recovered from the device and from
Fitbit itself and that data we're gonna
talk about a minute the why on this show
that he was sleeping but sleep activity
is kind of questioned by the courts
right now but it also showed that he
only took X number of steps and that he
took those steps at a particular period
of time it's about 20 steps and it was
actually when he got up to pee at about
4:00 between 4:00 a.m. and 4:30 and
because of the shortage of the amount of
steps that actually confirmed that it
wasn't that he didn't have his watch on
him he hadn't taken enough steps to have
committed the murder and it wound up
being his alibi and exonerated him in
the instance let's talk a little bit
about what the data is so the piece of
data Fitbit has is profiles and that's
going to give you the user ID name
birthday profile image URL and the
height what's important to know here
it's a profile URL will bring you to a
picture of course a person is choosing
their picture but it might give you some
information
this is going to give you the name
associated to the user at least what
they want you to as well as their
profile pick the stride lengths here
that it's calculated could be of
importance but note that stride length
is actually calculated based on gender
and height and can be adjusted so
actually in the case I just mentioned
the police actually had the gentleman
because they use the stride length to
determine how many steps he had taken
that's how Fitbit does so they actually
made him put back on his Fitbit and take
X number of steps to see if it actually
matched and it did so good alibi and
good work by the police department in
validating right we got a validate and
verify it tracks your steps everybody
knows it but what you might not know is
that it doesn't in 15-minute intervals
which is why I said he went to the
bathroom between 4:00 and 4:30 because I
actually don't know exactly what minute
he went to the bathroom what's very
fascinating in this case is that Fitbit
actually did provide data based on that
user ID that was recovered they were
able to go to Fitbit get a warrant and
get data Fitbit divided data and that
data actually was to the minute although
I can confirm that on device the data is
stored in 15-minute intervals so this is
actually what you see you see a start
time and an end time and how many steps
were taken in that time so this can
really help show a person's lack of
activity the time of activity or a lack
of inactivity this is what in the false
rape case got that thrown out because
the woman had been up and walking around
so it really shows presence or lack of
movement
it also can actually tell how many
floors you've climbed now as far as
floors climbed this was given on a day
by day break down so it's not minute by
minute or hour by hour but it tells you
day but this can be used to indicate
overall activity for a day as well as
established pattern of life right really
see a trend that people are taking from
day to day now one of the most important
things that many fitbit's not all track
is heart rate the heart rate it actually
gives to you in five minute increments
and it gives you the average heart rate
over that five minute increment so when
you're looking at this periodic heart
rate over that five minutes you can use
this to actually determine the amount of
exertion so kind of similar to what we
were talking about in the pacemaker case
so five minutes segments of time and if
you graph this over time you can
actually determine when somebody's doing
different types of activity and you can
actually say whether or not they've
exerted enough energy to have done
something they said don't claim you were
running a marathon when you were
sleeping Wilmette
and on that side there is sleep capped
now the sleep counter is particularly
controversial the sleep counter is not
designed to measure exactly how many
minutes you are laying in your bed as
opposed to walking around the purpose of
the sleep counter is to measure the
quality' vus of your sleep so it is
looking at other things which is why
this has been pretty much not accepted
in court but used in conjunction with
activity moments it could be used to
exonerate you when somebody falsely
accuses you of your girlfriend right
that's always good so for example here
we see 205 minutes in bed five minutes
awake total amount of sleep 198 so this
might be good if somebody has sleep
apnea for them person from a forensics
perspective the data isn't as
trustworthy and isn't being considered
but it could be a helpful indicator in
something like the false rape case
because there was no sleep time recorded
at that period just active and it can
take place someone at a specific time at
attempting rest but again there's
questions around that a number of
minutes weeks and asleep nothing out
Fitbit interesting enough well learn
something about smart house all right so
this is actually my favorite this is my
baby this is the Alexa echo system get
it come on in full of corny jokes I
actually approached Amazon and asked
them if they wanted to use that and
you'll hear more about me approaching
Amazon in a few minutes they weren't too
keen to it they didn't they didn't think
it was as clever as I did alright so the
actual Amazon Alexa we're going to talk
a little bit about the app has been
around since 2014 but it took them four
years to develop it they spent a lot of
time working on this it's currently
available US UK Germany and I actually
believe they finally got into Canada
Canada was interesting because they
needed it available in French before it
could go into Canada and it's somebody
who's picked the data directly off the
device I know all the future languages
I'm not gonna tell all right so it's a
smart speaker that's voice controlled
when you use awake word right Amazon
Alexa echo computer there's certain
routes you can use those are actually
the four that's your choices and it's
capable of voice interaction playback
music control other smart things yes
anytime I can type one unsecure thing to
another unsecure thing that means more
data for me I'm like the anti security
person in the room right as a forensic
ATAR I completely know that it does run
fire OS on the actual device anybody
who's familiar with Amazon should think
that's pretty cool because that's what
your Kindles run so it makes sense that
they're running that but fire OS is
really just Amazon's version of Android
so here's actually the devices that I
looked at I've looked at the show I've
looked at the dot first and second
generation of the tall echo so one of
the things that makes the Alexa such a
unique device in IOT it's much like your
smartphones Amazon has opened up a store
where developers can create their own
applications for it and as you can see
across 20-17 they went from having under
a thousand to over seven thousand anyone
want to know how they did this really
really smart they went ahead or maybe
not smart figure out in a second they
went ahead and said no what we're gonna
in these hot areas we're gonna start
these classes and we'll teach people how
to build a skill and we'll do a three
hour class class is free if you build
the skill you get a free echo dot $30
piece of equipment people who took this
class have never programmed before in
their life but by the end of it they
write a skill and they put it on the
marketplace and then the marketplace
with morning everybody only wants to go
place with a moiré marketplace now in
your first three hours of coding that
you've ever done how much security were
you interested in very good answer from
the room I mentioned the wake words and
I just love this story so I'm going to
share it real quick which is that when
in the UK there was actually an ad that
ran a morning program where a
girl asked Amazon to buy a dollhouse and
all of these Alexis Amazon echoes across
the UK ordered the dollhouse it was
caught they weren't delivered it's okay
and then speaking of cases they're
actually I love this because this is a
hot tub murder coz hot tub murders are
awesome
no no orders are awesome please don't
take this the wrong way but there were
two people who were found dead in a hot
tub and there was an Alexa in the space
and remember I I Amazon is great I have
reported vulnerabilities based on this
research with my research partner Brian
Moran of Brian Mooar labs to Amazon and
some of the vulnerabilities we reported
were fixed within 24 hours we actually
reported him as Pam they were fixed by
7:00 a.m. tells me how bad they were but
they were fixed other things they fixed
before the first presentation I did a
hour-long presentation with Brian deep
diving into Alexa if you guys want
information that I have it in the deck
they were great so please take with a
portion of thought what I'm about to say
the police department in this instance
went to Amazon to request the data in a
murder investigation right that's the
kind of thing that we should give over
data for Amazon refused Amazon refused
on three occasions to turn over to data
eventually they gave the purchase
history that really isn't helpful all
right let's have enough sources of data
for a brick I took up these devices
apart yes so we're gonna talk a little
bit about the devices we're gonna talk
about the cloud and we're gonna talk
about the app so in my research this is
all echo this has a four gig ultra flash
memory I was able to ISP this device if
you would like to ISP one yourself there
is the pinout
it's published its public on the dot
that that was a little bit more of a
pain in the butt because the EMC
was on there's two different generations
and the emmc on one of them had no
markings on it and there are no data
Shih Tzu before this Gen 1 or Gen 2 so a
lot more testing on my end to figure out
the pinout also it's a much smaller
device no test pads and you got to use
40,000 Swire on this but hey I used as
an excuse to get a brand new JBC a
soldering iron that I love like you guys
JBC makes an awesome one don't ask me
how much it costs oh it's scary so my
hobbies expensive so there's the pin out
for that if you want to pull data off of
that you can ISP either one of these
using a rift 2 or an easy risk JPEG box
and if that's something you're
interested in see me afterwards more
direct directions will be in what do you
find on the device well you can find
some good information you can find the
Wi-Fi address that can be useful but
what's really important it's bit string
right here under user ID right over my
hair it is at this location on the
device and that string is the keys to
the kingdom they'll see in a moment we
can get everything using that URL echo
only stores 60 seconds of data on the
device so if you happen to roll up upon
an echo at a scene that you need to
recover please do not go oh look there's
an echo or hey look Alexa or Amazon
because you're gonna say the freaking
word or even computer because those are
your four key words and turn on the
device and get rid of that last sixty
second recording which is probably the
thing you care about so don't do that
okay thumbs up alright so if you have
done that the data on the device is not
of interest other than that string that
we're going to get back to but let's
talk about what we can get off the
application attached on the computer on
the phone so from the mobile phone we
can get a lot information we can get
user info by the way if you never had
access to the device and just the
application that was paired to an Alexa
guess what we get that same wonderful
string this string is amazing remember
the string there will be a quiz later so
this is the string we care about this
customer ID and you'll see why obviously
not for
chin back to Amazon since they don't
share data that's okay so there's some
basic user info here but that customer
ID might be worth the warrant or
subpoena not really the reason we care
Alexa tasks so I can recover this Alexa
tasks will actually give me different
things that were said as well as similar
tax the created time last updated time
so I can get things that were added for
example to the shopping list I loved
using my Alexa for shopping list by the
way in case you guys are wondering I had
I have several networks in my house I
had an entire Amazon echo system set up
I do not have any Amazon devices live in
my house anymore okay I do currently
have a Google home live but that is for
testing purposes what you're gonna get
for each task is this resource URL this
resource URL is great because if you
just take that resource URL and select
it it will ask you to sign in if you
have the credentials and hint hint
most people use their gmail and Gmail
password for their Amazon account just
happens to work that way usually can get
it off their computer you will actually
get the actual recording will play now
this can be very helpful for time stamps
tasks that have been dissipated by the
user and again if you can get to the
cloud and have those credentials you can
get the voice recording there's also the
Alexa web resource this link here this
is going to give you other types of
audio activity that isn't synced
specifically with tasks and this is
great again it's all time-stamped and
you can actually get access to the
recording from the link in the cloud my
disclaimer I had a note there so I'd
remember to say this disclaimer your
authority to pull data from the cloud
may or may not exist so think about it
before you do it it is where most of the
data is it is where a lot of the data is
in a lot of these instances but there
are specific legal implications please
think about that before you proceed okay
so we actually can find the last audio
is cached sound so just so you guys know
again that's the last recording it is in
wav format
and you can play it again just the last
recording so if you Eve other have the
device or the phone you can get the last
60 seconds but again if you're looking
at the application you can see that ID
number everywhere that's my favorite
number and it's important to recall this
string if you pulled it from the phone
but wait there's more Amazon just added
a new feature recently guys this is them
this is an update I just put in the
slides you can now pull this string
directly what about ever having access
to the device or the attached phone all
you need to do is log into anyone's
Amazon account your own included go to
profiles and go ahead and search
actually if you enter HTTP WWE
amazon.com /gp slash profile it'll ask
you to log in you log in you get a
search bar you can type in anyone's name
when you type in their name guess what
happens you're brought to the profile
page it could be blank if they set it up
link for security reasons but guess what
that URL has that ID and I haven't even
told you what that idea is good for you
well guess what you can take that ID
number and plug it into any one of these
lovely URLs if you use any one of these
URLs you will get back all of the calls
and messaging all of the contacts all of
the devices all of the Wi-Fi contacts
there's more trust me
but basically anything I can pull from
the API as long as I know that string I
can get it you may or may not be asked
for credentials if you happen to pull
this data down hashtag worst vendor rep
ever I worked for a vendor that makes
tools here's a plugin for autopsy which
is open source then mark McKinnon wrote
it'll parts both alexa and casa data so
casa makes tp-link makes a whole bunch
of IOT devices that are integrated i did
briefly mention it's not really part of
this presentation that there were some
vulnerabilities found and alexa during
our research there were also some
vulnerabilities found in tp-link all of
which were reported
things were fixed mark McKinnon Thanks
for writing some plugins based on our
research this is actually how that cloud
data looks if you pull that down and I
just want to provide because if anybody
wants companies slides they can at both
the sands differ summit and then updated
research at OSD f-con last year we did
some presentations on this and we get a
little bit more into the vulnerabilities
and the tp-link stop so if you want to
see that just let me know thanks that go
it's my favorite new category of IOT
because it includes anything from drones
to self-driving cars to OnStar again I'm
speaking about things I've used in
investing I looked at in investigations
before so I'm stars actually been around
for a long time since 1996 so over 20
years headquartered here in the US and
Detroit it's a subsidiaries of GM and
it's basically a subscription-based
service for turn-by-turn directions
calls etc but it's available all over
the world us Argentina Brazil Mexico
Europe in Europe it's known as Chevy
star and I'm sorry Chevy star in Latin
America its Opel in Europe and they
reason that we care about this is over
six million customers so let's see what
we can get off of this there's also
aftermarket so even if you don't have a
Chevy or GMC a clit is possible that it
has OnStar and there's been some pretty
cool hacks right so if any of you heard
of pone start so poem star with an
attack that used man-in-the-middle to
actually be able to unlock vehicles or
start them and GM went ahead and patched
this about 13 days after it came out so
there's been some attacks
alright so OnStar remote link you can
get the account information now the
account information is very valid if you
get a phone that was paired with the
device and now you have a VIN so if you
didn't know what vehicle your particular
nefarious actor was driving you do now
and vinz are very powerful with the MV
records so if I didn't have your ID
before I do now
so this could be really important if
you're going to subpoena or find an
additional scene of course there's
timestamps for doing the registration
but if a vin provides new details about
a data you about a vehicle you didn't
even know was involved that's money all
right
there's also hot spot information about
what hot spot is release from there it
tells you - last time updated and of
course includes then so this can be
extremely valuable because you can get
some location-based information from
that and the passwords there and anytime
I can get a clear text password I'm all
about it because I can use it other
places and again you're going to get
context in terms of having a timestamp
associated with a MAC address any time
we can tie geo in time that's great we
also get the recent places they've
searched so you can actually request an
average via OnStar so send me two boudu
donuts and if I say send me two voodoo
donuts and often it's going to go there
you'll note that these are addresses in
Waterloo Ontario it gives me a timestamp
and it tells me if the route was
successfully sent to the device doesn't
tell me if I drove it but at least I
know it's an area of interest right can
they get that succeeded so this can be
useful because you've got timestamp data
they can put the vehicle or suspect
wanting a desired location as specific
time but what's more important is when
it gives you directions what do
directions to you they tell you the
start point as well as the end points
you don't know if the person took the
trip but you do know where they were
when at the time they requested it right
you can also use this to identify
patterns of life so there are remote
commands chess I can use my OnStar to
tell my device to do things I'm not in
the vehicle and this can include things
like locking the doors to the car or
retrieving the Wi-Fi status now what
you'll notice is some of these are user
initiated and some of them are not so
Diagnostics is sent from the motor
vehicle company we will not discuss the
fact that headquarters that GM is
requesting data from your vehicle that's
a little interesting in and of itself
again gonna get the request ID you're
going to get the VIN
you now know when somebody remotely
requested to lock the door door in the
car again you've got good time related
information and the events themselves
could be useful if you have an instance
where you're trying to prove somebody
was in or not in a vehicle or somebody
else was with them or not with them
knowing if doors were opened or not open
can be helpful there's also places of
interest that are stored and the places
of interest are nice and detailed and
give you Latin long and we love anything
that does that there's also this lovely
address URL so it's going to give you
location information which can tell you
areas that the target might be
interested in going in frequently
because they're saved you can also get
the wireless carrier now this is
important for anybody has anybody here
ever dealt with CDR CDR
these are the actual records you get
from the telco about communication with
the device now what you may not realize
is that if you have OnStar you've got an
extra sim in your vehicle and with this
carrier information so knowing that this
is a tnp I can actually try to get these
records from AT&T now when I get these
records with CDRs guess what CDRs tell
you they tell you exactly which Tower
you were connected to there's lots of
tower mapping and now you've got amazing
geo data thank you so much I love it
with a timestamp so there is some basic
info here but it's possibly two
additional subpoena target for getting
call data records now we've got vehicle
diagnostics now maybe this isn't as sexy
because it's just diagnostic information
like your last trip total distance hmm
that one doesn't seem so diagnostic II
it's me how long you were driving your
car your last trip or how long it was
til you set the odometer but it's
actually the trip itself so not
necessarily a smoking gun but if
somebody went to a lot of lengths here
to establish an alibi or say they
weren't doing something or were doing
something or that they you know drove to
drove to the grocery store but their
last trip was 500 miles they might have
gone a little bit further we've also got
just blank vehicle info but in that
vehicle info we also get the account
number the year and make it
full etc so if you got the vin wasn't
enough to go on before now you have more
than just the vin because now you've got
the make model and the phone number for
that sim card in the vehicle so this is
more ownership information and it's
going to tie a particular person to the
vehicle alright so there are further
things to research here and other
considerations we want to take in terms
of those again I didn't do a lot of data
diving into the data off device for the
op star or the Fitbit I'm sudo like I I
did take data off an OnStar several
years ago but it's not recent enough to
have been part of this information and
to get that data off a lot of times you
may have to JTAG chip off or ISP and
that's going to take a little bit more
extensive training and preparation and
knowledge in order to be doing that so
it might not necessarily be in the same
wheel house if it is even better and in
terms of data on the cloud it's not the
data there it's are you legally and
acceptable able to get to it via your
policies the biggest issue at cloud
cloud is freaking amazing amount of data
man I mean everything from oh three
sixty five to looking at Google Drive
and tasks and like what I can pull off
the cloud is crazy via api's like it is
totally crazy I'll give you a quick
example Google takeouts right you all
know about Google takeout right you can
pull your own data from Google it's like
your own personal retriever you know for
the my activity stuff if I pull that
down via and I'm totally leaving IOT for
a second don't mind me but the Google
home been doing a lot of stuff at Google
home research so I know I'm kind of
leaving here for a moment when you pull
down Google activity from takeout and it
tells you what activity and what time if
I pull it via the API it gives me geo
for it as well so sometimes there's more
value to getting data directly from the
API than just from the resource that you
have so I want to mention that and what
about these non consumer related devices
I don't have a lot of access to devices
inside human beings like insulin pumps I
don't have a lot of access to smart
grids there are things I just
have access to to touch and to test with
and as encryption becomes better and
better on smartphones and computers
since nobody seems to be caring about
our Nile teeth by the way so everyone
knows every single thing I talked about
today was recovered clear text okay
every single thing with clear text at
most I looked at an XML file and most
okay so some sequel like databases wall
and clear text not even basics before
encoded nothing okay so as um and if you
want to ask me about the network traffic
see me privately afterwards this talk is
being recorded so as encryption grows in
computers and phones and IOT
manufacturers are spinning up and not
even having security departments because
some of the vendors that I've contacted
in terms of my research have completely
told me they didn't have a security
department offered to send me more free
devices to beta test I happily took them
but gave them no info but um I gave some
of them info um but the point being that
some of them they'll have security
departments that's important there's
also the hack ability let's realize that
you know your Samsung TV can be watching
you they've been incidences and I'm not
going to get well into this about you
know Samsung is having a hack where they
could actually be used as a monitor into
the room refrigerator is being used as
part of botnets this particular botnet
and you guys are familiar with Mariah
over a hundred thousand devices and I
harped a lot on companies that don't
really give us the best security and
don't think about security when they're
setting up their IOT devices and by the
way if you want to say again Casa and
Amazon were wonderful when I contacted
them and when Bryan contacted them and
they did fix things but I'm always
appreciate it when a company puts
security at the forefront and especially
when it involves children so this
specific forensic bites did some
research into this we reached out to
these guys who make the cognate Ori stem
dinosaur which is an IOT dinosaur that's
used to teach engineering math and they
actually
we took a stance on both forensic and
security so I just wanted to take a
moment to applaud them they said that if
they ever get a request from law
enforcement that they're gonna aid in
the investigation but however and do
whatever they need to to reconstruct the
data however they have made a strong
security path posture and have made sure
that data on the device is encrypted as
well as what's being stored out as well
as the mobile app so I just want to
applaud a company that is still taking
security seriously but also taking their
responsibilities to law enforcement
seriously when a crime is committed
especially when it could be a crime
against a child or security and
vulnerabilities against a child some
conclusion I want you guys to really
know that IOT is important that there's
a lot of good evidence there that this
evidence has been used in court that you
can recover data and it's going to
become more of what we do in forensics I
don't care if you're in the corporate
space in commercial space if you're in
the government if you're in law
enforcement you are going to see more
and more of these devices because
they're in use everywhere right they're
going to be our stuff more often if
you're not thinking about the fact that
a lot of these smart watches have
cameras and the fact that your PII of
your company even if you have a BYOD
policy where you've got an MDM and
you're retracting all their data and
when somebody is wrongfully terminated
you're going through their computer if
you don't think they can't snap pictures
on their watch you're wrong
okay so who's thinking about that so
this point I'd like to open the floor
for questions anybody really no
questions hahaha well thank you so much
if anybody has any questions or wants to
talk about any of the network stuff for
any of the vulnerabilities that I didn't
talk about I'm happy to talk about those
off-camera thank you have a great day
[Applause]