how about that once upon a time
good morning outstanding all right I'm
gonna talk about this idea of an
operator and I want to talk about this
because I think that there's something
going on in security that is a
reflection of something that's going on
in technology and I think it's actually
making us worse at our jobs so just to
make sure that you know we do this
properly and we've include all of the
proper disclaimers and all of that sort
of stuff
the management shall not be held
responsible for anything that I say and
we will not have any subliminal messages
anywhere in this discussion when I use a
term like operator I want to make sure
that you understand I'm not talking
about somebody who is an operator of a
piece of equipment somebody who pushes
the button somebody who connects one
thing to another that's gonna be an idea
that a lot of people think of but I want
to broaden the term a bit and when I say
hacker I'm not talking about somebody
who goes out and buys a hoodie so they
can look like that image that continues
to surface in the media even if it's got
the cool hacker logo one of the things
that we find when we get into this
business of Technology and what a hacker
is a lot of people are concerned they
think about stuff like oh when
somebody's breaking into something that
sort of stuff when I use the term hacker
I'm talking about it in its traditional
sense as it came from MIT where we're
talking about somebody who is going to
code expertly even obsessively
it's unfortunate that it has other
connotations especially insecurity but
they are in fact related and I'm going
to talk a little bit about that one of
the issues that we have for a lot of
people that could be coming into this
field especially those who might be very
good at making systems work and
understand how systems work they have
this idea that to be able to do this to
get a degree in computer science or some
related discipline I am going to be
spending the rest of my life staring
into a screen like this and I don't want
to do that anybody ever heard that you
stare at a screen all day you know it
really cracks me up is that we hear
people talk about how terrible it must
be how it sucks your soul to be staring
into the black death of a computer
screen and then you see a movie and they
talk about or they just they to show a
writer and how romantic it is they're
sitting there you know working on their
novel and it's on the beach or whatever
they're doing their thing and what are
they doing they're staring at a screen
and they're putting English words and
phrases and so on in there instead of
code but they're sitting there staring
at the screen they're typing this is the
same mechanics that we do right so how
is it that this can be very romantic
when we're writing human language but
it's so arcane and horrible and
soul-sucking to be writing code this is
something that we could probably do
ourselves some favors if we'd like to
bring more people into the field the
fact is though when we're looking at a
movie usually what they'll do is show
stuff like this when they want to look
technical and so what do we do we start
screaming at the screen so not only are
we the ones who stare into a screen
for 22 hours a day but when somebody
else has a chance to put something on
our screen we shout at it because really
how much work would it be not to do this
come on all right I'm gonna talk a lot
about potential for those of you who
have seen me or know me you've probably
heard that I'm very critical I don't
like a lot of what's going on in the
industry all right fair enough I don't
but that doesn't mean that I don't like
the people in the industry something
that I deal with a lot is just
disappointment because I get to meet a
lot of really really smart people people
who are very interesting people who are
very interested in a lot of things and
yet they latch on to something and it
works for them so they keep doing it
over and over and over and that's all
they do and they stop trying harder they
just keep doing the same crap that
they've been doing and if you were here
for Jeff's presentation just before this
you'll see that exactly the same issues
that we were dealing with 20 years ago
are the same issues we're dealing with
today we aren't going to get better as a
field if we keep doing the same crap
over and over again to a large degree
we've been listening to recruiters
because we hear things like there's a
shortage of expertise in information
security its job security in information
security and the recruiters say these
are the certifications that you need to
get the recruiters say here's how much
money you should expect to have here's
how long you should stay in a job before
you hop on to the next one and that's
how you advance your career
in order to make that work you need to
make your resume buzz phrase compliant
and you list many many tools on your
resume with the idea of being that when
the recruiter who doesn't know the
difference between a packet and a hard
drive runs a query they're gonna find
that you have experience with super
painter nose man version 11.4 because
that's what the customer needs
but when version 12 comes out and the
clothes box is moved to the other side
of the screen what do you do my skills
are out-of-date and the industry that is
to say we have bought into this way too
hard and I think that it's time for us
to take control of this specialization
to the point that you have focused on
one thing and the application of that
thing over and over again is not a good
idea
can you imagine something that we hear
all the time I'm a programmer okay you
ever hear not just I'm a programmer I'm
a C programmer I'm a c-sharp programmer
I'm a Java programmer you hear that term
[Music]
could you imagine meeting a carpenter
I'm a hammer carpenter I'm a saw
carpenter power tool I'm a drill
carpenter it is absurd we think about it
it's absurd why isn't it absurd to be a
Java programmer that's the only tool you
got your toolbox Skippy
specialization we hear over and over
again you must specialize luring this
particular thing I am the same Matt
Curtin by the way from cypherpunks I'm
the one who published and maintained for
years the firewalls frequently asked
questions my job when I was at Bell Labs
was to run the systems that would
connect internal AT&T networks to the
Internet there were no commercial
firewall products not a one
there was the Cheswick and Delavan book
on internet firewalls there was a code
base that we had from Cheswick and bela
v'n that worked on plan nine that we
would then port to unix and that's how
we made a lot of that stuff work that
was my job and yet once firewall one was
out there people didn't want to talk to
me about how to connect their systems to
the internet because my resume didn't
say that I knew firewall one really I
can't figure out that if I click on the
email icon it's gonna let TCP 25 through
this is the sort of nonsense that comes
from specialization and this is not just
something that I'm floating for the
first time today and I see that I'm not
the only one to know this quote so I'm a
happy man Robert a Heinlein
specialization is for insects this is
the entire quote here the things that a
human being should be able to do change
a diaper plan an invasion butcher a hog
con a ship design a building write a
sonnet balance accounts build a wall set
a bone comfort the dying take
give orders cooperate act alone solve
equations analyze a new problem pitch
manure program a computer cook a tasty
meal fights efficiently die gallantly
specialization is for insects this is
what human beings do and if all we do is
forget about all of that so that we can
do one thing over and over and over then
we're just holding a place until there's
a list program to come along and take
over what we do what's the point what it
means to be human what we do is varied
but how we get there how we learn those
skills how we apply those skills and how
we do those things comes from somewhere
else it comes from our environment it
comes from our DNA Eric Raymond the
editor of the new hackers dictionary
which is the print edition of what used
to be the jargon file had an appendix
that highlighted a couple things that
were common in the hacker personality
things that stood out uniquely or
particularly by comparison to other
people high intelligence consuming
curiosity facility with intellectual
abstractions and that sound familiar
individualistic anti conformist
mentally absorb retain and reference
large amounts of meaningless detail if
you're a programmer and there's a new
programming language that comes out do
you wait for somebody to publish the
book the cookbook on how to or do you go
download the entire language spec inhale
that bad boy and start writing code that
is the difference between somebody who
is merely competent who can get the job
done who will fill the hours of the day
necessary to get a paycheck and somebody
who owns the practice and somebody who
will change the state of the art the
better a hacker is the more likely that
hacker is to have outside interests and
to be more than merely competent one of
the problems that people have and trying
to assess somebody else's skill is that
unless they themselves have that skill
they can't assess it well who knows
about the dunning-kruger effect pretty
awesome isn't it you have to have a
degree of expertise to be able to
determine how good somebody else is in
that same field people who are not funny
think they're funny people who doubt
whether they're really that funny are
probably funny and this applies in many
different fields a hacker
all of these things that go into that
personality it's somebody who was
interested who wants to know how stuff
works and somebody who goes through life
with that intense curiosity that
ravenous intellect is going to pull
things apart and is going to develop a
Bertie's is not going to be satisfied
with the glass of light oh it's red
where does this come from how do you
make it how is this different in this
thing that comes from France from
California from South America what makes
a Beaujolais a Beaujolais a Bordeaux is
that a grape and you find that you can
spend years pursuing those questions and
at some point you start knowing the
answers and you've become quite
competent and you didn't have to give up
your ability to program to get there
some traits that are common among
hackers that I want to focus on for the
purpose of our discussion trying to boil
these things down focus persistence to
the point of indomitable 'ti
intelligence it's necessary but without
creativity doesn't do much good most of
us when we were growing up probably got
into some trouble
did anybody besides me take apart
telephones how many of us pushed a piece
of metal into the outlet that made all
of those things go hey that's
electricity
I wonder how to test whether that's just
like lightning it's not safe to be a
child who's very curious but if you
should survive the ordeal it can set you
up pretty well
that's a way that will reflect itself
putting things back together sometimes
putting it back together differently
from how it was originally done is
really interesting
sometimes disappointing mostly in
disappointing until we start figuring
out and make it work properly we can
start figuring out what these components
actually do but this is the sort of
thing that happens in childhood and then
we get to school boring
but anybody do really well in school
good grades about 1/3 not a surprise
for a while in my senior year of high
school my GPA was 0.9 which was
impressive but not for a reason that my
teachers were especially thrilled with
and I said we don't quit quit making all
of this grade depends so heavily on
homework just let me work off the test
scores right that would be like that's
how real life works you have any friends
that you went to school with and they
now tell you things like I think I was
better at school than real life now
isn't school supposed to prepare you for
real life how curious
the point is that the same personality
is not universally strong the same
personality doesn't necessarily work
well in every instance and the fact is
that we have to figure out a way to work
through the world and we have to figure
out how to start applying things and
it's the application where things start
to get interesting for us because even
those of us who did very poorly in
school probably had a favorite teacher
right and the favorite teacher was the
one that would listen to your question
that annoying question that you always
had what about this why is it just like
that
and they would let me draw you a picture
we weren't uninterested in learning but
the way that something was being
presented was a problem and we were able
once we started to apply something to
get past that problem of something just
being pounded into our heads for no
apparent reason one of the reasons that
I had such a poor grade point average in
high school it was because I went to a
school where tests were basically worth
three homeworks quizzes were worth two
homeworks
I didn't do my homework I know how to do
the stuff so what I did is I taught
myself how to use UNIX better I taught
myself C I programmed an assembler 65
co2 assembler 65 C 816 assembler that
was the stuff that I wasn't being taught
in school so I learned how to do that in
the time that I had but I didn't get
grades for that there's a prize
yes that hackers go through almost 201
this is called larval stage the larval
stage hacker is somebody who's green has
probably just learned to program maybe
just learn to program in some particular
language that just really made a good
connection but this is the point where
that maniacal focus kicks in
he's just continuing to write code over
and over and over building things seeing
how it works trying stuff out and the
sorts of thing that you know for
somebody who's never seen this before
it's just they can't understand it like
what is going on here I remember being
in my high school computer lab and it
was run by somebody who got there very
early in the morning I mean he'd get to
school at like 6:00 in the morning open
the computer lab if you wanted to come
in and get lab time you could get it
awesome so there I was before school
every morning and I got to work on my
programs this is a 1987 1988 and I would
do this every day for months and in 1988
1989 I actually had software that we
uploaded to CompuServe and it wasn't
just that I was writing code in the
mornings anymore I would have to answer
email from people in Australia who were
using my software this is a pretty cool
experience for somebody in 10th grade
but everybody who becomes a hacker
almost to a person goes through this
period just absolute concentration on
coding
making the thing work understanding how
it works why it works and it can go on
for quite a variable period of time for
a lot of people it's about a year and a
half long some people go through it a
lot more quickly
some people take longer to do it my
larval period was probably closer to two
years and you know in that time like
what I one of the things that I did when
after I graduated from high school I
assigned myself a project I thought you
know this UNIX operating system is
pretty cool and I did some stuff with
Protoss and Protoss 16 and I knew a
little bit about the Mac operating
system but I didn't really know how they
worked so I decided if I really wanted
to know how an operating system works I
should probably write one so that's what
I did in the summer after I graduated
high school so I wrote an operating
system for my family's Apple 2 GS I
showed up to my wife a couple years ago
and she couldn't believe it didn't have
a y2k problem well I didn't use Cobalt
I've I've actually had a few protegees
and I've known them just as they started
to learn how to program really well and
they and they would enter into this
larval stage and it's it's really
something if you are a mentor and you
have somebody who's you can see them
going through that same kind of thing
it's not like you've coached them to do
it it's not like you've told them to do
it but they're just naturally drawn to
the problem and they have that same kind
of focus that you do and to see that
kind of passion for them to be able to
harness it to channel it it's really
quite incredible and for somebody who
gets through that larval stage what you
get out of that is that you're not just
a good programmer not even a great
programmer not necessarily a language
lawyer
but someone who is wizardly in that you
can envision a solution that a lot of
other people would not envision because
you understand much more about the
mechanism and you start being able to
see things in context and you can see
not just this individual item but you
start to understand the interplay of
that item with others and you can see
the entire system this big complex
system that is tremendously powerful and
that's where we get into where security
now becomes a good application because
how much of security is not just one
thing that goes wrong in fact for us to
have a weakness that is used by a threat
to make a bad thing happen we've
probably had a bunch of things go wrong
right or in fact it wouldn't be possible
for that bad thing to happen if not for
the fact that we hooked the crap up
together in the first place if we
understood how those pieces fit together
if we understood the mechanism if we
understood the interplay it's entirely
possible that we could have connected
them together in such a way that we
could achieve the objective at hand
without opening up this weakness you
know we really could have made the
cockpit door lock before somebody flew
them into the Twin Towers aimed them at
the Pentagon and probably the Capitol
building in many cases the issues that
we face in security are a failure to
understand mechanism a failure to
understand how it fits into a system
and a failure of imagination
that is what's wrong and that's what we
need to get our heads around when I was
at V Ohio State University this is after
my obligatory dot-com stint the dot-com
tanked in 1997 we were one of the early
ones and we tanked early leading the way
and showing the rest of the industry how
to do this this was not especially good
timing because the week that we got the
news that the dot-com is tanking and
that multi-million dollar exit that you
thought you had was going to turn into a
couple of pennies by the way you're
about eighty thousand dollars behind in
your expense reporting better start
grabbing equipment that was inconvenient
because that same week I was in a cover
story on computer world called super
programmers the basic subtext being you
can't hire these guys no matter what
will make me an offer that was rough I
would a couple of months with no job
that sucked because as a turtle who knew
people read computer world they
remembered me in this article that was
bad anyway so I landed at the Ohio State
University and they gave me this corner
office and they had these sort of
corkboard they weren't quark but they
were like you know where he could put
pushpins in that would just run on the
the height of the door about a foot wide
foot and half wide and the idea was that
you know profs would post grades out
there or whatever you could post
whatever you liked so I would just go
out there and I would start posting
things like research papers but I
thought were interesting or things that
I was working on that I thought would be
kind of cool and somehow or other I got
the idea just never to take anything
down so I just started putting more and
more stuff out there
and it turned out that it started to
attract a lot of attention and students
would come by and it turned into kind of
a thing as they would always look to see
what new crap I had hanging out there
and try and figure out what it meant and
they started hanging around in my office
first of all congregating outside then
they would eventually come in and start
hanging around but while when I first
got there it was kind of an issue
because there were a lot of people that
were trying to figure out how to deal
with me so I come rolling in about 10:30
11 o'clock in the morning I go in there
I'd never turn any lights on I'm staring
at a light source what the hell do I
need lights for and I was at there in
code do whatever I did and so that's the
whole thing about does your senior
software person freak you out you have
to say speak in complete sentences do
you live in a dark cold lonely office in
the corner
does he know every damn line to every
damn movie does he have shit hanging
outside his door you don't understand if
so you might have a hacker the guy that
took this picture I didn't even know he
took the picture he's came into my
office literally took my picture and
walk that I had no idea what's there he
was became my protege who went through
that period of time in himself today is
a wizard Lee programmer gravity check so
there is a point at which you develop
this expertise now remember that larval
stage six months to two years is pretty
typical so yeah you're not doing a whole
lot of other stuff during that time but
after you get through that you sort of
go through this transformation and
you're able to understand things like
mechanism you develop a good intuition
about mechanism so even if the box is
black you can still get a pretty good
idea what's going on inside you know how
to test it and how to give it different
inputs to see what it does to see how it
reacts with other things
and if it turns out that security is
what you are interested in doing and the
way that I typically talk about security
security is making sure that what we say
we are doing is what we are actually
doing and that's it that is a working
definition of security that I like to
use if we decide that that is what we
want to be doing there is this idea now
of a security professional okay we use
these terms a lot we hear these terms
they're thrown around a lot I just want
to take a look at them what do they mean
how do we put them together a profession
a vocation requiring knowledge of some
department of learning or science okay a
vocation what's that a particular
occupation a business or professional
circular here a calling okay well then
what is a professional or something that
is professional and adjective of
relating to or connected with a
profession the fact is if we want to
help on a larger scale we're not going
to be able to do this all by ourselves
I have a CISSP I got it in 2001 I didn't
tell anybody that I'm a security expert
because I've got a CISSP I got a CISSP
because it is a way to demonstrate a
little bit of humility and a little
bit's all you're gonna get from me a
little bit of humility where I am
willing to say that I am a member of a
profession and for whatever criticisms
we can make
of the CISSP we don't have a whole lot
of alternative in terms of being able to
represent ourselves as a member of a
profession something that we are able to
show to somebody who is not already well
versed in the same art that we are a
member of a profession otherwise we're
left with hoodies and the sort of stuff
that we see in the media so I don't hate
it for what it's not it is what it is
it's part of what is related to a
profession and when you're doing the
consulting thing and whatnot you tend to
have to have those kinds of things now
once you've gone through that the
question becomes as a security
professional what is it what is it
you're doing
are you selling stuff selling security
stuff even does that make you a member
of the security profession what if
you're installing stuff installing
security stuff what if you're filling
out forms sitting in meetings teaching
people things influencing them are these
things that you do as a security
professional what is and is not part of
the profession of security something
that I was slow to embrace was the idea
that it's okay to be the grown-up in the
room I'm not used to being adult
supervision but in terms of what the
security professional needs to be able
to do to be able to help we need to
engage with something much bigger we
need to understand business objectives
what is it that the organization is
trying to do we need to know about the
technology so that we're able to see
okay the mechanism by which the organism
Asian is going to get that job done is
to a large degree based on technology
and the policy and process and whatnot
that goes around it it's the automation
that's how we scale so we need to
understand that stuff back to Jeff's
point we need to manage risk we are
helping others to manage risk all of us
one way or another are part of the
process of putting something at risk in
hopes of getting something bigger in
return and that's the reason why we make
the investments that we do whether we
are for-profit or nonprofit that's
fundamentally the reason why we do that
stuff so we go back to this idea of the
operator and there can be a very
romanticized image of the operator the
experience quiet professional daring
it's like man these guys are squared
away the soldiers that are not content
with doing the minimum necessary the
ones who volunteer to be put through
particularly the arduous selection and
assessment so they can be put into
special mission units those are the ones
who have to be able to work and make
things happen when they don't
necessarily have a whole lot of stuff on
their side
and it becomes very easy for us to think
of ourselves in these terms - especially
as now we see in a lot of cases we're
not talking about script key to kitties
being the threat anymore we're talking
about nation-states in some cases
stateless actors the fact of the matter
is that there are plenty of people who
are very well motivated to take the
infrastructure that we run and to point
it back again back at us to try to end
the way that we live our lives this is
not an abstraction
we are not going to be protected by
ships that are able to patrol the oceans
and prevent invaders from landing on our
shores we have connected the entire
world together so the bad guys are just
a few hops away so it becomes very easy
for us to think in these terms and that
can make sense of course the reality
that we deal with is a little more like
this out of nowhere here is the
situation boom quick no time to explain
get in who's getting in whatever is
going down it is serious this is the
idea that I want to introduce to our
field however the idea of the operator
and it is not for everybody and it is
not the only thing that has to happen in
security but for some people it is
exactly the right application for these
skills the hacker who recognizes that
all of that stuff that they've been able
to achieve to get to that wizardly
capability so they see that as a
starting place not an end to itself
there may be much ahead of them somebody
who is able to handle an operation not
the day-to-day sort of what's going on
but there is now something that needs to
get done I need for this to happen being
able to draw from many different
disciplines lots of skills having
experienced that is varied
so when encountering something that you
thought was a DDoS attack for example
you're able to get in there and see oh
actually you've got a problem with the
architecture the software is designed in
such a way that it's making all of these
extra connections and you've configured
the webserver in such a way that it will
allow for only so many connections
fellows that upgrade that you did last
night set the stage free to DDoS
yourselves that is an example of the
kind of thing that I actually run into
in my practice where I have to go in
there and explain to people who wrote
this stuff and have lived it for the
last six months how their system
actually works that's not because I'm
flippin brilliant it's because I have
that focus and I'm part of a team that's
also something very important somebody
was able to integrate skills to get
hands dirty and I'm going to give you an
example of how this comes together I'm
going to use a Red Team example but Red
Team is is just one of the many
different applications where this kind
of stuff can come together when the
operator the red team conducting a
penetration tests but why why is the
mission for us to grab sensitive
information why is always a good thing
to understand the purpose of a pen test
I propose is to help an organization to
understand how well it can detect and
respond to a security event it's not to
find the holes it's not for the purpose
of figuring out whether we're compliance
it is to test the organization's
capability to detect and respond to
security events
a red team is the group of people that
conduct this test they are the ones who
are attacking the system generally
speaking when you have one of these the
target is unaware they don't know if
it's a drill to them everything is real
you may have an executive sponsor you
might have a couple of key people who
have had to be read in but the target is
unaware and very importantly what you
are providing is going to have to feed
back into that organization's security
program how well they detect and respond
to an event has got to go back into
everything from what technology they're
using to the way that they are using it
and also the way that they train people
not just in security but at the
frontline the way that they physically
control their assets all of those things
need to benefit from this exercise it
does not follow that if they repelled
the attack then everything is good what
would happen if you went to DEFCON 5
every time somebody port scanned you you
would go broke you would literally go
broke because you would devote all of
the resources of the organization to
trying to deal with this thing that
happens all the time and so the ability
to respond proportionately is critical
and this is an excellent way to find how
that works so in this particular case we
had a client and it turns out they had a
need their need was to fill a position
that's awesome
so normally I wear a suit so if you like
look on the website you'll see that's
like my normal day thing is I'm always
wearing a suit this is hilarious so I
put on this shirt so I could be like you
know in disguise I've blown my cover so
I'm not gonna show you what other shirts
I have uh I put on glasses shaved up a
little bit
took on a fake name a background made
sure that my cover was deep enough so
that if I ran into somebody who happened
to be from Loveland Colorado I'd be able
to last for more than a couple of
minutes in a conversation and there
wasn't too much to it I applied for the
job that they had that they had a
terrible need to fill somebody who
understands different kinds of
technology so we get in there we get
close because we have some legitimate
business purpose to be there we can see
what's going on during hours and getting
in there and having that kind of
expertise I was able to be a nerd to
wear a pen in my pocket that turns out
to have a video camera in it so as I'm
all wandering around the facility I'm
able to record things and find out where
things like video cameras are and I've
got somebody a colleague playing my
girlfriend who's there to drop me off
who's taking pictures of the outside in
finding other cameras and where they
cover and all that sort of stuff so we
can come back after hours after we've
figured out things like where the
cameras are and all that sort of stuff
we're able to figure out alright here's
how we're coming in and we're gonna have
an insert here we have a rally point
over here here's how we're getting out
of here we work out the timing all that
kind of stuff and for the first time
through we're gonna sneak in get as dark
as we can and go in at night and see can
the cameras see us go back another time
and ultimately
we get into the locked dumpster which we
are able to get because of a matter of
timing we're sitting there watching
what's going on we get the rhythm of
what's going on we get to people when
the time is right to have somebody whose
job is overwatch just seeing what's
going on out there tell them it's time
to go they go in they come in with these
bins big Rubbermaid bins and just open
up trash bags find papers throw the
papers in there they're in and out of
there in under five minutes bring them
back to the office turns out they've
ripped a bunch of stuff up but we put
the pieces back together so we get some
pretty good information one of the other
nice things about being an employee is
that they give me a laptop and an email
account so I know what their email looks
like I know what the help desk will
present to them what it's going to look
like what people are expected to do so
that we are able to have somebody else
whose job back at our lab is to create a
site that looks like they're VPN and is
able to initiate a spear phishing attack
and sure enough it doesn't take more
than about a minute before we get our
first set of credentials and we are in
there's a whole bunch
stuff that happened and because this is
not a Red Team presentation I won't go
into the details but the critical issues
that we get out of this are that we've
done a bunch of different things and we
have to give a meaningful report to the
client of what it is that we did what
worked what didn't work and what it
means how effective are their controls
yeah we got in with that spear phishing
attack but you know what five minutes
after we launched it
somebody had reported it as a phishing
attempt and the account that we were
using had been locked out their window
of exposure was about six minutes before
they were able to get that under control
six minutes that's something that's
important for them to understand because
the issue isn't going to be are we
invulnerable the question is going to be
what bad thing happens when a threat
actually does the thing to us we have a
six minute exposure that's what happens
that's the kind of information that
leadership can use because they can make
decisions like is six minutes too long
is that unreasonable should we spend
more money on it how much information
could you guys get in six minutes we can
quantify all of that stuff for them the
other thing is that's very helpful when
we're talking about how this feeds back
into training is that it's not an
abstraction this is what actually
happened in this organization when an
attack was conducted it's very important
for people to understand that because
they can relate it then to their jobs
and they can make something useful of it
to make all of those things come
together a lot of different skills were
necessary programming was necessary in
this particular case the job that I got
there
this is fantastic it's not one of these
like oh I need somebody who can use
Dreamweaver or you know whatever
somebody's using they had a need for
somebody who knows dotnet and also
understands the IBM midrange somebody
who knows COBOL and c-sharp some poor
bastard out there knows that I'm sorry
report that I am he but that meant that
I could get that job and that's how I
got access to all those things so that I
could download all of the source code
and put it onto my company laptop so
that we could then grab all of the data
off of the laptop the same way we take
forensic images so no timestamps ever
got updated no activity was ever visible
on the system there is the whole thing
about networking that we had to be able
to work with understanding the protocol
stack we had to be able to set up the
phishing site we had to do surveillance
you know finding the best way in the
role-playing thing learning how to
develop and to live the cover I was a
programmer who knows c-sharp and COBOL
and so I made a decision that NIC that
was the guy that I was playing Nick
Nick's
a little bit introverted he's kind of
socially awkward which is to say he's a
Nix Nick was extroverted you know the
way to tell an extroverted programmer
right that's right the extroverted
program looks at the other person's
shoes and so I was that guy so I have
they're going around and introducing me
to all the people you know and I'm kind
of you know bashful and all that then
there was there was a there was a
department in there that had a group of
ladies where they were they were very
interesting and boy I knew I could work
them but Nick could not I would buy them
drinks at a bar and I would find out all
kinds of great stuff but Nick was not
that guy so Nick had to retreat and be a
little bit embarrassed and scared
how to do that is a skill and it's
necessary for it to work in this
particular kind of scenario our red team
was composed of people with lots of
different backgrounds and this is
something very important I talked about
people that come in through the computer
science route a very common route to
come in but it is by far the only way to
come in
we've got people with degrees in
business degrees in criminal justice
degrees in information assurance there
are some computer science expertise
there of course but there's other
backgrounds that are connected here the
guy that we had running our overwatch
was a former scout sniper in the Marine
Corps so he climbed up in a tree set
himself up a hide and we're off on the
radios we got everybody all wired up and
he just sits there and he's looking
around to see what's going on and he's
also got a laser and he put a rifle
scope on it so when there was the point
where the team had to cross in front of
a camera and they just couldn't hide
from it because it had multiple coverage
he took the scope put it onto the camera
and lit it up with the laser whiteout
just long enough for the team to cut in
front of it and turns it off he gave
them cover got in that's the kind of
stuff that you can pick up when you have
somebody who has experience like that
varied experience goes a long way but
the critical thing that ties us all
together are the standards that the firm
has core standards and data acquisition
handling security writing presentation
things that we test for on the way in
and things that we train people on not
because we're going for people who don't
know how to do it we're looking for
people who already do it well so we can
make them great and that is our baseline
and now on top of that you can add your
own particular elements your own
particular flair to that team
so now the question becomes what are you
doing I'm in security are you in the
business you might be in sales you might
be in marketing you might be buying it
are you a practitioner you might be
somebody who's filling out forms you
might be somebody who is going through
the process of seeing that daily
operations actually works the way
they're supposed to you might be the one
who's planning it in deciding how much
this thing is going to cost when we're
gonna start and when it's gonna end or
you might be the operator where
something gets dropped in your lap and
now it's your job to take this thing for
which they don't have a normal
day-to-day playbook for which there
isn't a product to solve the problem all
of these are necessary securing the
organization is about managing risk no
matter what role we have we are all a
part of that process to help the
organization to achieve its mission and
if you don't know what your
organization's mission is what the hell
are you going there for somebody else
will pay you do something with your life
so that you know what it is you're doing
and by all means don't pretend to be
something else there's way too much
charlatan ism in this field
way too many sales guys who don't want
to say that it's their job to sell the
product so they want to pass off like
they're the guy conducting the red team
operations or something that sounds cool
that day so load of crap if you're a
sales guy own it it is your job to make
sure that your product your technology
your service is able to find its place
for people who can put it to work and to
achieve their mission there is no shame
in that
don't pretend that it's something else
and if you're new just say you're new we
were all new and the way that you aren't
new anymore
is by doing stuff and there's a place
for you
operators what makes us different from
some others as the integration of skills
the kinds of skills that we integrate
and this has applications beyond that
operator idea but it's less about how to
use the tool and more about how it works
because once you know how it works you
can make it do other things for you that
maybe the designer didn't even have in
mind understanding things like
programming not just one language but
understanding multiple paradigms
understanding different platforms
networking understanding how the pieces
fit together being able to select a
protocol when should I use UDP when
should I use TCP is not a question of
just what the product is able to do you
might have to design something you might
have to build a protocol a way to pass a
message from one place to another and
understanding those kinds of things will
help you to do so effectively how to
implement these things and it might even
be in the business you know how do you
put all this crap together in such a way
that it achieves an objective and you
can go through this process building one
thing on top of another you learn to
program great you don't know about
networking how about you build a program
that uses networking how about you write
yourself a little server how about you
write an HTTP daemon how about you write
an HTTP client you'll start to learn
about networking that way too now you
will take your HTTP daemon you want to
be able to make this thing work so that
it will automatically answer whenever
somebody hits it you're going to learn
something about operating systems are
you going to have the i net d launch the
thing or are you going to run the daemon
and start it up out of a startup script
that's how you learn about operating
systems you're putting all those pieces
together and there are skills beyond the
technology so here's some fun stuff
things you can do outside of the
technology anybody practice magic you
learn sleight of hand this is fantastic
stuff isn't it the social engineer you
learn about misdirection and all of that
and and you know hey you look over here
you know you do whatever you want this
is great great stuff theater improv
stand-up there are classes you can take
you can go on open mic night you can do
a stand-up work up a routine there's
books for how to do this it's terrifying
but it will get you good at working in
audience working in front of people
understanding how to engage with them
games of strategy different types of
technology like radio for example things
like martial arts and shooting learning
about precise physical movement fitness
actually having stamina so that when you
get into one of those things where
things are moving that fast and you
really can't sleep making sure that your
body is squared away so that it can keep
your mind moving - training is critical
the more you sweat in training the less
you bleed in combat individual skills
exercise them integrated skills exercise
them and then have the team work
together
I'm out of time I'm going to hang around
for questions and I'm happy to talk with
you I'll be here until the conference
closes thank you very much
[Applause]