okay hi everybody
can you hear me okay all right yay
welcome to my talk thank you for coming
I hope you were having a fabulous time
at Circle City everybody having a good
time so far I swear it does it gets
better every year okay so welcome to
patching it's complicated a bit about me
I'm Cheryl Biswas I go by encrypted on
the Twitter's
I work as a strategic threat Intel
analyst at TD Bank in Canada now I'll do
the necessary disclaimer the opinions
expressed here today are my own solely
my own and not those of my employer the
end okay
something I'm really excited to be part
of is the Diana initiative this is a
mini con that promotes diversity and
women in security and this will be our
second year happening during hacker
summer camp in Las Vegas and I encourage
and invite you to make it out and I'd
love to say hi to you there okay morning
it will contain expletives because I can
do that here don't tell my kids okay and
let's get started
oh my god
2017 what a year so we had a turnover we
had want to cry
we had Apache struts not once not twice
but three times yes and oh MFG out of
the gate in 2018 specter and meltdown
now is that dumpster fire hot enough for
you but on a serious note wanna cry
taught us some very hard lessons about
older outdated unpatched systems and the
risks that they pose to us personally
when hospitals got hit by ransomware
they could literally be the death of us
so this is a talk I have wanted to give
for a long time just based on experience
listening to people talk about the same
series of issues and then seeing
evolution of malware it's progressing
but we're not so why patching first of
all it's a common pain point it is a
pain in the ass it is a necessary evil
but it's also this source of contention
and divisive nasaw and there are really
no easy answers I thought that Bruce
Potter gave an excellent eloquent rant
on this point at shmoocon
who here has been dish makan he had this
to say this year just patch your shit
it's not that easy now this is something
that a phrase we like to throw around
because you know we get angry at the
offenders how patching that's a best
practice why the heck wouldn't you do
that and that right there is the big
reason for why I wanted to give this
talk because we have to understand why
it isn't happening why it really isn't
that cut-and-dried it's an issue around
a blame game and a blame game isn't
gonna solve things so for me this is
about the stuff that we don't know it's
about the concerns and considerations of
specialized systems proprietary software
legacy things stuff that we do not have
familiarity with let alone technical
expertise it's also about the costs of
trying to do the right thing and having
it go really really wrong it's about the
business between us technology it's
about the gap actually between us and
business and we've known about that for
a long time
so I like what Alan Friedman has to say
here
yes patches are important and they are
complicated and yes they are largely
misunderstood that is a really good
starting point for our discussions who
here who basically agrees with that show
hands okay who here knows Wendy neither
or follows her on Twitter I absolutely
encourage you to follow her if you don't
already she is a voice of reason in our
community very wise and what she says
here I agree with all right so where
does it hurt
we know that patching is a fundamental
best practice so why aren't we doing it
right or in some cases why aren't we
doing it at all in this talk I hope to
pull in some of those realities and help
all of us understand things better that
we didn't know before just listening to
discussions between people either on
Twitter or over beers at local community
meetups at conferences like this one I'm
seeing the same symptoms of what
essentially is a worsening condition so
I wanted to start with some pain points
it's messy right it's like the
directions for example they're either
missing they're vague or they're just
stupid and useless okay who has had two
who has had issues actually with
patching directions like this you want
misconfigurations
because that's how you get
misconfigurations or this one I think it
doesn't not feel to you like it is the
worst game of hot potato
ever
right everyone's concern is nobody's
responsibility I get talked to talk to
talk to till I'm like out the door which
then leads to issues around
accountability right not my department
not my problem thank you guys so does
this sound familiar yeah no honest to
god though does it not feel like this I
would liken it more to ongoing crisis
management rather than patch management
but when you're patching strategy is so
terribly broken nobody wants to sit down
and do a process reorganization how many
people have had to do process three
organizations you sit down and you do
like the fish top diagram or the
fishbone diagram or whatever the does
your diagram is because honestly change
is hard you'd rather stick with the
devil you know than the devil you don't
you got time constraints you've got
money constraints
you've got resource constraints yes we
have issues is yours by chance the
vendor you want to talk about it I
I brought band-aids anybody you need a
band-aid they'll pass them out I didn't
bring suckers but the band-aids will
make you feel better
all right so survey says
caching sucks right all right let's take
a look and see what these numbers have
to say this was a very recent survey
done by the Ponemah Institute for
service now this is approximately from
from the numbers of people and a good
number of people that they interviewed
how many hours weekly
they guesstimate how many people and how
much cost so just looking at this here
and this is this is how they feel they
did say that by the way in this many
days I'll ask you
quite pointedly how many people think
realistically most organisation it many
organizations really can commit to this
I don't think it's that doable so I have
three words for you prioritize optimize
automate except it's not that easy all
right so let's talk about managing
releases do you remember the good old
days when you know life revolve it
around hatch Tuesday no no no no not
anymore because now we've got
out-of-band releases right and then
we've got staggered releases and then
we've got previews and then we've got
this thing called super students if you
could even spell that let alone try to
live by it and it's a thing and you do
have to live by it so in addition to
that we have to manage down time with
uptime and then you have to get sign-off
and find all the stakeholders and
coordinate that and make sure that
you've got their buy-in and agreement
and sometimes the simplest thing is the
hardest thing like knowing which
releases of what you've got is this or
any of these pain points for you
currently me - don't tell my employer
all right so we are damned if we do
right because yeah stuff breaks and it
goes stuff goes wrong just ask anybody
who's had to live through the recent
joys of applying meltdown inspector
patches on their system and watch
she's tough break however if you follow
swift on security and I will be willing
to bet most of you do they have pointed
out on numerous occasions the necessity
of patching that it has to be a given so
it comes down to this what is the cost
you're willing to pay for the prevention
that ounce of prevention and you live
with it and then we're damned if we
don't and this is true - very true right
because while it may feel like the cure
is worse than the disease after you
watched the wildfire that was one a cry
blow through most of the globe you know
what the risk is you take with outdated
and unpatched systems
it was a huge wake-up call for everyone
but in particular for people who were on
Windows XP who had let hatching
essentially laps for any number of
reasons but this is compounded by some
very dangerous assumptions out there
assumptions about targeting and attacks
there is I'll call it a head in the sand
perception of why would they want to
come after me why would I be a target to
which I would say it isn't like that
you're not actually a target you are a
victim because your systems are
vulnerable so don't be a victim
now last May Wendy Mather neither had a
really interesting tweet thread going on
about enterprise and organizations and
their issues their actual issues around
why they don't patch and if you can dig
it up and look through it I think it
would resonate with you but the fact is
it's an ongoing issue it's not changing
it's going to get worse because
the threats we face the malware we have
to deal with the complexity of exploits
are continuing to evolve so how do we
learn to work with our organizations
based on the past to make this process a
less a bitter pill to swallow
and we know we know from experience the
patches are not perfect which is why you
need to have a process in place okay and
then yeah are those patches that don't
quite get it right they don't hit the
mark exactly case in point
Cisco Cisco has not had a very good
juror and back around the end of January
they issued a patch does anybody
remember that there was a laundry list
of Cisco devices oh my freaking God it
was terrifying yeah and and it was for a
severity 10 I think there was more than
one actually that's kind of
unprecedented that was really serious
fucking shit sorry and a week later
Cisco was issuing another hatch because
they hadn't quite completely patched the
first one now we all know what happens
when you make it public that there is a
special ii-if it's like a zero day or
that critical on like globally used
systems right the attackers are too are
they're waiting in the wings they're
gonna go after this they had a week to
work on that don't think they didn't
take advantage of it yeah that patch got
issued but what happened in the interim
and this has been ongoing through the
year it has not been a good year for
patches there have been more instances
of oops we have to do that again sorry
oh my god oh my god
meltdown inspector I would have brought
a bottle of Tylenol for all of YouTube I
don't think I'm allowed to do that okay
patching is not a silver bullet
particularly in this case and it seems
like every month brings fresh drama
right so it's not about the loss in
terms of processing speed already that
every write-up is about well if you
patch it it's gonna be slower yeah but
if we if we patch it it's patched right
it's not as long as we patch it without
breaking her stuff but the problem is
it's not going well as a process not at
all and my concern is for some other
systems I see us in critical
infrastructure that are also affected by
this because this is like a
planet-killer in terms of almost
everything we use was impacted by these
vulnerabilities right well ICS and SCADA
and critical infrastructure tend to be
proprietary systems legacy software
stuff that when things go wrong it goes
down hard doesn't come back up and then
you have major power outages and worse
oh my god it's the total meltdown who
actually had systems break because of
total meltdown or had to deal with this
so what happened in a nutshell was that
um putting the patch on for meltdown
actually revealed or created a new
vulnerability in Windows 7 systems and
it was bad very bad and again something
for attackers to actively and quickly
exploit and what essentially happened
was because we were looking at reading
from kernel level at a 120 kilobytes a
second go to Reading System
wide at gigabytes per second oh but
better in addition to that there was
right access if it I can't even know oh
that was a big oops
so yes does anybody listen to defensive
security podcast Jerry Bell yes so he is
as you know a connoisseur of dumpster
fires and he sums it up very very well
with this particular statement the one
that's at the top that I didn't circle
the complexity of patching this thing
correctly is going to provide many years
of quality post exploitation privilege
escalation yes and it's true so the
question to us is are we ready for what
we know is coming do we have rollback
points do we have backups and have we
tested those backups it's the same
protocol we say for ransomware but
essentially it should be part of any
change management process in place
certainly for patching so for me the
hard lessons that we are actually
learning because of meltdown inspector
are about the price that we were willing
to pay for speed and performance in what
was essentially a by now hey later
arrangement only at the time we didn't
read the fine print and now we're
getting served the bill but this is
really a constant refrain and what is
like a tug of war between security IT
and business it's about uptime and it's
about innovation and it is about that
damned race to the finish line and
security be damned so just saying but I
think that when well when doing things
the right way gets called into question
we need to question the process
oh my god I would see any more right oh
so many things fly why is it that
everything we make has to connect oh but
it does right everything so there's this
ongoing race for the next connectible
consumable and security gets tossed by
the wayside we've got four lucky default
passwords hard-coded ones if we're not
and if there's a glitch in the firmware
well you can pretty much forget trying
to fix or update that right so from
industrial webcams to Soho hopeless
routers botnets unite right yeah to like
freaking crock pots we are talking I kid
you not legions of Doom sorry but set it
and forget it is not a security best
practice okay so did you does anybody
have the Nintendo switch and you heard
about the the issue the patching issue
did you actually successfully update it
or fix it it's no it's child's play but
we keep building this stuff right that
we can't fix have you ever tried asking
your neighbor to update the default
password that comes with their cable
modem I have it did not go well so how
the heck how the heck are you supposed
to tell somebody to patch the firmware
on their IOT stuff no okay I confess I
I love diehard for and it was really
cool the fire sale part but I'm also a
real follower of ICS SCADA and the
people who work in that area
is there anybody here who is not
familiar with the terms ICS SCADA or
what I'm referring to so that's that's
critical infrastructure it's the stuff
that runs our lives power grids nuclear
plants water filtration big gas gas
pipelines and major power clients
transportation it's in a lot of places
places you don't even consider stuff we
take for granted and like I said before
operational tech is proprietary and it
goes down hard now there's a culture
within this community and it's a rather
grim one that you don't touch it you
don't patch it you just let it die you
run it to failure and this impacts a lot
of us when that thing goes down because
it comes from an era when it didn't
matter but that didn't transition to now
so yes
ot is not the same as IT and 20 years
ago legitimately they didn't see this
coming so security wasn't something to
be baked in at that time because the
systems were pretty much segregated
right it wasn't necessary they didn't
have to do that at the time however
things have changed and stuff has
migrated and things are now getting
connected a lot of things are getting
connected and they never planned for
this and what the problem is is you're
trying to patch these crucial systems
it's much harder so what we need to do
is to understand the differences and
work with those specialized requirements
there are a lot of endpoints in there
and points they never factored in so
let's talk about medical devices did
anybody get to see the talk by Alana
earlier this afternoon okay
I would suggest if you if you have the
chance she's also online but she has
brought to light a lot of really
CodeBlue issues around medical
insecurity it's staggering it's
terrifying and these are critical
infrastructure specialized critical
infrastructure for critical care so
downtime for patching versus downtime
for something that patching broke is a
really serious issue
pacemakers insulin pumps MRI machines
and other because we don't know all of
this stuff but this is very particular
technology that keeps people alive on a
daily basis there are very hard choices
to be made about keeping medical
operational technology running so we
don't know how those decisions are made
they're there within that community the
people running the bees are working with
a bunch of constraints that we have no
familiarity with they are only just
learning now to communicate that out to
us because they're working under the
same kind of constraints that we all do
resources budget cuts
politics bureaucracy so let's factor
that in and try to reach a better
understanding of why they wouldn't be
patching so that we can actually come at
the problem a different way than we've
been doing it
mark nuna Kelvin was at Atlantic
security condom at the end of April when
I was and he had some interesting points
to say about medical device technology
and insecurity one of the examples he
showed was this pacemaker so
it was recently updated I went online
checked it out to see what they had to
say because it was a it's been an
ongoing list of things when it from when
it was first introduced so let's talk
about the vulnerabilities if if this was
a Windows system or particularly in
Active Directory system we'd be all over
it right because what we've got a
dedication
we've got encryption yeah and then how
about the fact that you just have to be
standing in close proximity to exploit
it that's freaking terrifying now I
would love to give a shout out to the
people who have done so much to raise
awareness about insecurities with
medical devices particularly I am the
cavalry Jelena Adi and anybody else
who's been part of that team to champion
this cause and and really raise our
awareness so the prognosis is grim yes
we know that how do we help the people
not get ransomware on the MRI machine
and not have to suffer outages to
essential systems when they don't have
budget or people or time to resolve this
you're looking at vast numbers of
outdated operating systems and unpatched
systems at risk okay it's the
anniversary of wanna cry one year later
so at the time 80 of England's 236
national health services trusts were
infected and there were 600 more general
practitioners offices that were caught
up in this it's it's more than just an
inconvenience I don't know if people die
maybe that information was held back but
you you got to think about how that
would impact somebody
who had not elective surgery and
somebody couldn't take them in at the
time when they needed to be cared for
well it came down to the fact and it
comes down to the fact that it's ongoing
there are still many systems at risk
getting hit today I want to cry even
though everybody in the world my kids
knew about it it was all over the news
so England did a recent cybersecurity
assessment of about 200 of these trusts
every single one of them failed that's
staggering and you have to stop back and
say why when you know what can happen
why and they came back with the reality
that we can't fix them we can't hatch
them we can't change what we have in
place because we can't do the downtime
everything is interconnected
we can't unbundle it take it apart and
fix just that one piece we don't know
how to do this can we figure this out
this is our challenge does anybody work
with mainframes or know much about Maine
France that's a really good question
ah so it's pretty much a given that
mainframes are special hoisted systems
onto their own and and it's true nobody
touches the mainframe it's got a whole
culture around it it's like this this
wonderful little secret world and they
have their own language like Hicks says
- and Rex and all these other acronyms
that mean nothing - outside of servers
but the fact is if you want something
kept uptime that's reliable completely
reliable and powerful you put it on a
mainframe that's why it's at the heart
of global finance 1.1 million
transactions per second
for section and second and these things
really they're practically guaranteed to
stay up that's why they're in place for
those stuff that is the most valuable
however eventually they need to have
maintenance or upgrades so you schedule
outages you have scheduled outages
because if you don't you will have
unscheduled outages and I can tell you
for a fact really bad things happen then
and yes Virginia you can hack a
mainframe and you should now these
behemoths seem like they are
impenetrable but they are vulnerable
like any other system only you never
hear about this and that's because IBM
likes to keep that on the Qt they don't
want you to know in fact when they send
out Muller ability notifications to
their customers there are almost no
details just here hatch this I'm not
kidding
now I know these guys does anybody here
follow soldier a Fortran or big-endian
smalls I have huge respect for them they
are masters of the mainframe and they
have made it their mission to open up
this cloistered secret world to the rest
of us and to reveal what the
insecurities and flaws are of these
massive giants of power they want to
show that these systems are just as
vulnerable as anything else we're
running and how to do it so yeah they
literally hack the Gibson I highly
recommend that you follow them and learn
a little bit more about them plus
they're funny as hell alright so with
all of this how how do we do this better
we know the patching is a best practice
but it is not the only one so
miss configuration it's been at the
heart of some pretty ugly
vulnerabilities and exploits but the
thing is that's a human error it's not a
technical glitch so I would say let's
look at how we're doing network settings
firewall rules what ports were leaving
open and shutting down we can manage all
of this and when it's done right and
regularly revisited it's very powerful
it will stop attacks and then let's talk
about the actual business of patching
for example priorities is it me or have
we had an inordinate number of out of
bounds hatch releases just since January
that throws a wrench into any system for
any level of organization but
particularly for the I would consider
far more vulnerable
small to medium size businesses who
don't have the budget and the resources
and the time to cope with it they barely
have a regular monthly patching system
in place that they can manage trying to
deal with something that's out of been
happening every month or possibly every
two weeks it's gonna throw them right
out of whack boom more low-hanging fruit
right because vulnerabilities get
exploited who here understands what a
sequential patching is and why you need
to understand it you want to give me a
anybody want to be a guinea pig just
give me a quick explanation exactly you
can't just jump ahead you have to do it
in order that's a time constraint that's
a problem you have to make sure that
your systems are capable of taking that
first service pack you have to be able
to have it on hand and available or this
when you do testing
I'm I'm not gonna name I've sat across
from people and had some heated
discussions about why you need to test
your patch in a separate environment
beforehand because if it breaks
something you're gonna really hate
yourself the next morning and it will go
wrong it can go wrong and frickin
guaranteed if you decide to just put it
out on the production system or adjacent
to the production system it is going to
go wrong
Murphy's gonna be right there who here
wishes they had a test environment in
place I I know people who have I done
I've done security assessments and then
yeah you really need to be able to
coordinate that agreement for downtime
and speak to the stakeholders this all
takes a lot of time and negotiation and
patience there are a lot of prematurely
bald people out there this is a wig just
kidding okay yes the proverbial road to
hell okay we need patching yes but we
also need to be ready for what goes
wrong so we need to have roll backs in
place and countermeasures because stuff
is gonna happen and I feel like I can't
say this enough it's that ounce of prep
a preparedness right it's a so much
worth it because you don't want to have
to deal with pound of flesh that is
gonna literally be the cure if you've
lived through a bad patch Tuesday and
really who hasn't when stuff goes wrong
it gets ugly I've been on those triage
calls because with Windows sometimes it
isn't just one month of bad Patch
Tuesday sometimes it's as many as three
successive months and from experience it
isn't as easy as just rolling it back so
you've got customers and their business
takes a hit for business
this becomes the hard argument in terms
of dollars and risk why they are not
going to a
read to your idea of a patching schedule
they're going to insist on their own now
let's talk about visibility which is
crucial I've got five W's here that we
need to ask ourselves and be able to
answer it's really important we're going
to talk about the who the what do you
know what your crown jewels are I'm
talking about people who do not know
what those are or where they are who
can't say what's being used and when and
by whom this is a big one you can't find
what you're looking for when you need to
fix it it's not logged or cataloged
anywhere and of course this which should
just be a standard rule for everybody
least privilege
you don't need everybody having access
to all of the things all of the time ok
so a lot of security professionals see
the problem in terms of visibility that
we can't see from end-to-end across all
of the different sections in IT and we
know that we have a problem in terms of
working with silo mentality and we don't
communicate well well if you can't see
what all of your assets are how do you
secure what you're not aware of
you can't patch what you don't know is
there if you don't see all of the
endpoints you're gonna miss stuff so
from experience and I'm sure some of you
have lived through this as well when you
have to go chase down equipment within
your organization because you've been
notified and now you're see your CES the
c-suite have been notified of a high
level critical 10 vulnerability a
planet-killer
right they're all overdue they're not
paying attention it seems like any other
time but right now they are breathing
down your neck and you have got to find
this and patch it except you can't find
it because it's you don't have
up-to-date records
that there's a catalog system but it is
convoluted at best and you do not even
know where to look and so you you do the
only other thing you've got which is you
you start phoning people and asking them
and they sure as hell don't want to
speak to you because you're interrupting
their day and they're really
short-tempered this is not a solution I
have a two-word solution for you asset
management please all right so what do
you do when you can't patch mitigations
yes yes there is hope and they are
effective one of them I love the idea
how about this virtual patches they
don't buy you time and that's what you
want you want to close that window of
opportunity when a vulnerability is made
public knowledge and the attackers are
building exploits because then you can
actually get to work on putting a real
patch in place and not be the lowest
hanging fruit so I will sit with this
security is not a band-aid solution what
it should be is a process that is in
line with the needs and the objectives
of a specific organization with your
organization so it behooves us to
understand more about where we are
working and what's driving that business
why because hatching needs to be an
integral part of the ongoing business
process and we want to get that c-level
buy-in so we have to work with them
better by understanding more about what
they are trying to do and we're going to
be actually able to broker some
meaningful discussions and achieve I
would like to make a little more
flexibility but definitely create for
them a business case to commit to giving
us time money and resources so that we
can do this better because if we want to
help management hear the message well
then we've got to write a new
prescription for patching it's time for
a second opinion thank you all very very
much for coming
are there any questions all right all
right
go enjoy the rest of the talks and the
con thank you