all right microphone on awesome
we set this clock all right thank you
Circle City thank you for staying
through to the last talk of the day
before you guys have dinner and come
back for the party tonight this is
actually my first time at Circle
sinigang its first time to Indianapolis
so awesome to be here
it's basically some of this talk I want
to talk about this afternoon is some
research that I was in charge of been
doing for carbon black so this is gonna
be mostly research related and nothing
product nothing been doing and all that
fun stuff but to give a little bit of my
background coming into this is that
there we go I worked on this ransomware
project for about 15 16 months straight
to the point where my co-workers
actually made domain names and start
like making memes of me throughout the
company I've become known as just mr.
ransom okay every time it popped up in
there like a help channel or customer it
just went straight to me which I hate it
but I had to take over the role but I'm
a senior researcher with carbon black
and our threat analysis unit we'll call
it tau which is basically focusing on
malware attacks reverse engineering just
writing up things when we see in the
wall then figure out how to protect
against them part as well as my
background has been about 17 or 18 years
now and digital forensics forensics
instant response a whole lot of
different roles now I'm actually a stay
at home no travel research is great I'm
done with you our life but also was a
former and intrusive analyst for DoD as
a contractor focusing solely on apt
investigation so there's a lot of things
that go into my experience to help me do
my analysis if you guys know Jason
Street everyone knows Jason his
co-author on this dissecting hack books
which we have to out and he's working on
third now also a very valid CTF are a
very rapid ETF or so this right here is
the actual lab run CTF from Palo Alto
where they gave you a diecast Szechuan
sauce as a prize so that's actually
framed in my office as one of my prized
possessions this is before Michael
McDonald's brought it back out so I love
that thing so much
so what we talking about the idea of
ransomware that's not real its fake it
doesn't actually exist yet it pretends
to be so one we'd be talking about it
with next hours it's gonna be like very
fast very fast pace talk lot fun stuff
in here some funny stuff some that may
be mildly offensive so I'll just give
you a warning up front I've since heard
out a lot of the content just put blocks
over it but if there's something that's
sensitive to you then feel free you can
close your eyes and just walk out I
won't be offended and kind of started
off is this guy I'll if you guys ever
seen him this is Thomas a train ransom
or sample that really wants to see naked
pictures of yourself to give you a
decryption code that's just to set the
stage what we're going to talk about I
go more than the death of this in a few
more minutes but the idea of
outrageously shocking ransomware or just
really weird stuff it just doesn't make
any sense this is not your wide-scale
Tesla crypt or Betty or whatever this is
kind of off-the-wall stuff and it
attacks certain types of people and
really the stuff works is because we do
have a precedent set in the industry of
early ransomware had to infect how do
you spell encryption have use AES how to
use a proper private public key that was
set off to a CT server because people
knew there was no way I'm getting my
data back I had to make that payment or
I would be losing my data I lose
everything but now that that price has
been set has been a few years what we
learned is they don't even try anymore
adversary just had to provide the
program to say your files be encrypted
right now and you'll still pay even
though they don't do anything so a lot
more just screen lockers they basically
just closed your screen and you can't do
anything crypting your files another not
so that's where a lot of this comes in
from well I talked about 16 months of
research I did it was predominately
because we're really focused on proving
that we had a ransom a protection
knocked down and it was actually working
so it was basically 3,000 samples 300
plus families of ransomware
that we just throw out at me and a
co-worker
and as we're going through them we're
doing a typical research stuff of okay
this sample starts encrypting from sea
route this sample starts the desktop
this sample starts from the sea users
this one uses a as this one uses X or
this one only does JPEGs so that type of
breakdown and then we have this weird
other category whereas like Alice's
doesn't really fit the mold of actual
ransom we're just gonna stick it over
here and as we start going down 3,000
plus samples that other category just
kept getting bigger and bigger and
bigger
they took corners like that actually is
really cool just to dig in by itself and
that's what's leading to this when we
look at those as well they kind of break
down to multiple markets so consumer and
enterprise consumer is actually more fun
one we're gonna talk about here but the
reason why these you get infected is
because sumer relies upon gotcha
ransomware as then you did something bad
and now you're in trouble for it you
went to porn sites you download the game
cheats you did a trainer kings software
somewhere and now you gotta pay for it
so you get it because you downloaded
something you wanted not something you
needed and by getting that you actually
affected yourself and the payment is
pushed through as a risk of exposure
either you do this or we're going to
tell people about you or the FBI is a
note on you right now that you will be
reported if you don't paint make this
payment versus enterprise which is
completely opposite way of doing it
where the infections through social
norms as we know what phishing campaigns
is that an invoice is being sent to a
finance officer a resume is being sent
to an HR representative they open the
attachment because they're supposed to
open attachment and they infect it so
they get infected because that's their
job to get infected it's your job to
stop it but the judge when it comes in
there is urgency as in this is a very
critical payment this is a very critical
document you've got 24 hours open those
up to respond to it you need to do this
right now and there's a whole line of
attacks and actual grants where they
focus on that urgency as well to make
sure that you do get infected quickly
and the reason the payment is due
obviously lack of recovery they expect
you to pay because they don't expect you
have backups which they're actually
always right yeah an almost no one has
backups at least no one has
comprehensive backups to recover from
the attack so that's how they get your
payment and we talk about urgency I love
this guy this is T blocker this is a
sample that says hey you've been blocked
you've got 24 hours left
not just 24 hours but at the expiration
time all your files will be made public
on the internet and your PC would be
primarily locked yeah exactly actually
have all your files ago I'll just go to
pastebin pull them all back down
yeah they don't actually take your files
there's actually no that functionality
is actually in the program itself but
they tell you you've got 24 hours to
make this payment or else this that
won't happen but how much money they've
made a lot because it's just that fear
that could happen to you so at least
back into mr. Thomson train here love
this guy so I've blanked out a lot of
words but the overall message here is
that you are infected your machine is
being encrypted the only way to get to
your access back is to send email to us
and we'll give you an unlock code that
you can type in here and get your
machine back the actual terms of the
agreement are that you must send at
least 10 nude pictures of yourself to
get code back and those pictures will be
sold on to the dark web what they call
the Deep Web and that's how they're
gonna make their money obviously this is
something we're gonna let we see this we
laugh right as people's industry this is
no way this could be true no way people
should be afraid of this however send
news no bitcoins in ransom demands
x-rated photos
Tom's guide Tom's a train wants to see
you naked kaspersky in Reza's ransom
that demands your nudes mother for
grants burn demands nudes instead of
Bitcoin it was inevitable really I
didn't expect that coming
alright I'll roll with it so for
everything that we look at it's like
goddess this is no way this is not
possible there are a lot of public you
know freak out that oh my god this is
real it's gonna be attacking me and then
you're suddenly your parents call you up
or some uncle and says is this real is
this something you focused on because
they think it's actually going to happen
and really when we take a look at that
binary for example these are the falls
that drops and one of these things is
show you this may not be a professional
adversary I don't know you can pick a
pick take your pick
that's actually the Thomas Train theme
song that drops out of that and it plays
as it's you know got your machine locked
so I won't hum along but people know
whether this right yeah
so you look at that it's like okay this
is really a joke this is there's no way
but then you actually start reversing it
and doing analysis of it I'm gonna have
code up here don't need an okay I'll
just walk you through what the stuff
means if you don't have to read it this
is a dark background because of the
program I use it only produces dark
backgrounds until I fix it but the
overall thing here is that when you type
in the code and you press click 2 to
unlock it's taking that text changing it
to a double value an integer and say
does it equal one two three four five
that's it
so that's your encryption right there so
obviously so not something that we saw
prevalent in the wild something that was
probably either targeted or we called
proof of concepts as people show off the
street cred or what they could be doing
however when that stuff does hit the
limelight it just lights up like crazy
you people get really worried about
these things to the point where this was
September of last year
as Kevin menses here that nude
ransomware which is even in the wild has
more press coverage than the CC cleaner
you guys whoa see clear it's like that
was a major apt attack that targeted
hundreds of thousands of downloads of
corporations now you only picked like 20
or so but there's hundreds of thousands
people infected like that
yet that had nowhere near the press
coverage as this stupid ransomware
you think okay it's just a one-off Matt
one of those actually not there's a
whole family of these probably remember
the same guy he keeps cranking them out
every now then about two months ago we
came out with this guy autism blocker
lots of bad words up here so don't read
that loud I'm not gonna be that long
either however there's some few weird
things in here that do tell us hey maybe
it's the same guy
send me 15 years or record yourself
gunning down innocent children Wow okay
send the recordings to that offensive
word and we will make sure you kill that
and that more offensive stuff basically
4chan style
ransomware and when we look at this like
okay is this related yeah you look at
the code it's definitely exact same code
1 2 3 4 1 2 3 2 4 3 5 4 that's like
coffee skate now this is actually real
code now the weird thing about this
actually not weird anymore if you know
programming languages dotnet C C++ so
forth 95 98 percent of all ransomware is
in dotnet which is surprising to me
because most malware is in C or C++ but
ransomware is like almost all done net
which is not prevalent and like apt
stuff that's used like Iran territory
and like one of those countries but here
mostly because it's so easy to write in
there's so much code on the air and
already you just copy-paste it the good
thing about it for us as analyst is that
there's tools out there this is a tool
called en spy that lets you just dump it
like it just displays the code for you
with very little effort so basically I
just load this executable in there click
a few buttons and that's it it just pops
this out at me there's a few obfuscators
I'm going to show you a little bit later
on but that's pretty much all the effort
it takes to really dig into these these
applications so yes this is a weird
family this has some really funny stuff
to it and it's prevalent we still see it
coming out really not in the wall it's
actually affecting people
but then we start seeing things like
Annabelle I mean it's her the Ndebele
the actual ransom or a few people picked
up on this is about four months ago
basically based on a horror movie
this great it actually infects your box
is completely destructive it will
encrypt everyone your files it will
disable the Start menu a disabled task
manager you can't do the start you know
windows are and then it will override
your MBR does everything before it gets
that last step it were actually show the
screen and then start playing music you
can imagine scree P creepy music with a
video or actual an audio of like a
little child laughing very sinner is to
consider is laughing to a point where
this was was a new labor daven world a
house that actually I can't be with my
kids and cabin of the woods and I'm
sitting there working it's a three-day
weekend I'm looking at some ransomware
we go out I've run this off and like
okay usually when I run something I'll
just let it run in the sandbox give
about 60 minutes to marinade and then
come back and look the results so I
kicked this off walk out the door we go
hiking come back again kids as he would
he would come in is like I want to be
the first inside the door he runs up
goes in the cabin comes out crying yeah
that's funny so he did not find a humor
in it I laughed so much but basically
they build this whole you know theme to
it they make an experience out of it
you're not just being affected you're
you're being experienced in this this
thing however this thing again when you
start looking at actual ransom note the
dark sites thought sites are not
existing it's just an example text
alright so proof of concept all right
guys trying to show off his chops see
how good he is we can actually start
building and writing better ransomware
other things we saw when we ran this is
that before you actually as soon as you
click on the executable this is the
pop-up basically saying warning
do you got dotnet four or five if you're
not running it with four or five then
the Trojan won't work
I did try both four and four five and it
got to work both ways so they okay
obviously this is nothing we don't need
to worry about this however no we
apparently we do because article after
article came out of oh my god Annabelle
the scariest mother in crypto ransomware
you should be worried about literally
that's the problem right there in one
article a horror show for users and I
love this newly discovered variant
Annabelle is seemingly designed to wreak
as much havoc as possible yeah in a
sandbox in theory not really like it's
not hitting your box but it left this
like just bad taste of oh my god there's
so many threats on the air net trying to
kill me right now you know so many
families have ransomware that we shall
be fraid not really I think it's more
fun from there let's take a look at hi
buddy hi buddy
because it actually says hi buddy so we
call this hi buddy that's the actual
family most of all are actually Roe
ransomware this one will encrypt your
files as a fun stuff actually loads up
an ie Explorer frame does Bitcoin
websites like hey we're gonna walk you
through how to buy Bitcoin and you know
give it to us actually have all these
buttons what are bitcoins how can I buy
bitcoins search Google for bitcoins
help me will actually you know connects
to the support channel so they're very
nice about this for you very nice people
and even says okay yeah here's your
onion sites you files be encrypted
however we've also seen variants of this
such as this one where it actually they
forgot to put your cryptic code in so
you could just hit all that for
like that's kind of anti-climatic but
you know every now and then we see
people get really freaked out and like
no don't worry try this get all
therefore see what happens
oh my god check your files oh you'll see
encrypted are you good to go don't worry
about that yeah he's a consulting fee
there's a whole lot of things like that
or call screen lockers so screen lockers
are a thing but when they pretend to do
or pretend to say they're encrypting to
put that sense of urgency in you that's
where it starts not playing nice this is
lamda linen your windows has been banned
dear windows user your PC has been
banned we're sorry to say we are now
hijacking legally I don't think that's
how it works and we are now trying to
encrypt lock your files because of fake
windows to know more about this kinds of
banned visit microsoft.com/testlabguides
Ito why very clever I love that actually
when you look at the code of this there
is no deletion code at all there's no
encryption code there's nothing it just
pops up these dialog windows and blocks
your screen and then that's all it does
now this one you can't hold that for all
those but again it gets that fear and
you're like oh my god like I need to do
this quick and it's cheap quick and
cheap I can do this right now I can just
in the quick Pay Pal and get my data
back but it doesn't actually do anything
so that's the whole psychology of this
is if you make it cheap enough and you
really panic people out and you make
them think that okay you're about to
lose everything in 24 hours people pay
and you don't actually have to do
anything like the level of effort to
just make this window for
is actually making code that has to work
you have to test it and QA it and do
support on it now it's too much work so
what do you have
you know obligatory Rick and Morty
reference just like Szechuan sauce what
do you have in ranch somewhere that
actually does work but not so well so we
call being shot with rubber bullets Hey
yeah it hurts but you can just walk it
off
there's not something that actually it's
gonna destroy your business and there
was actually quite a lot of grants more
out there like this either buggy or just
broken in many ways or just so badly
written that you can decrypt it which is
like a junior interns engineer can look
at a code and like I got that you're
right you decrypter this guy Thomas a
train remember this guy right so you
remember you type in a code if this box
you hit unlock in it on wash your box
weapons yeah what's a number one two
three four five what happens if you
don't give it a number rap music in a
word it will crash a box I forgot to
censor out that one word but it will
actually crash not to box it actually
crash the application so it basically
just closed it out by typing in their
word instead of a number because they
didn't have any error handling around
that it just awesome so we do all this
type of work but that idea still set in
the groundwork when people look at
existing grants Mirko in the air net
this is a copy of dumb D you envy us
actually what's called it actually is
pretty dumb so this is a framework you
can download it's open source and you
can use it for your grant somewhere uses
basically simple xor encryption but the
way they hid the actual key that was
used to encrypt your files is by
converting a string to hex values and
putting them here in this weird thing it
actually just says test key but that's
the actual best as far as they wanted to
go and actually office gating their
encryption no aes no private key no
public key just a single word and they
use that to encrypt every file on your
hard drive
once you know that word you can just get
it right back it's practically pretty
easy and we see that exactly a lot so in
this environment you know code don't
worry about this what we see in this one
example is it's actually doing a simple
XOR as well there's actually a routine
that they called XOR give it the text of
the file given the password and it'll
just do it for you this one actually is
pretty nice this one is I can't say the
word extremely offensive but this one
actually does time stopping at the end
after it encrypts your files their time
stop the actual right time so access
times which is actually pretty clever
not many grants wanted to do that
effective maybe less a handful the
actual code like is actually pretty easy
if you're not a co don't worry about it
but I'm looking at this routine here
it's a little carrot that carried equals
x or encryption is not even encryption
in a way it's like lazy man's encryption
if you ever looked in the cryptology
it's it's a requirement for every type
of crips croteau out there but it's like
at the very basic level the idea with
XOR is that it's Lily a binary X or 1 &
0 1 XOR 0 and so forth an XOR works on
or called deltas so you have an equipped
eval you you have a plaintext original
value and you have a key so if you take
your plain text and you XOR it by the
key you get the encrypted value it
actually works into all the other ways
too if you have the encrypted value and
yet sort by that kid you get the regular
value so you can do cool stuff with that
it's actually called X or crib dragging
that's the actual word we don't no one
ever calls it that but it has two
technical word for it where if you don't
know the key but you have the equipted
fall and you have original file that
will tell you the key
just XOR the two of gets each other and
it outputs the key and you can use that
to decrypt all the rest of your files in
hard drive it's actually pretty easy in
this case even if you don't have the key
that's built in and this one's actually
bought on the screen now I'll tell you
what it is this one actually goes out to
the website it generates a URI
sends it to the website and says hey I'm
checking in on a brand new infected box
it'll send back an actual key value to
use for encryption so even though you
don't know that key if you have a copy
of orginal and an encrypted value you
can just you know exilim together and
you get your key and then just apply to
everything else junior developers and
programmers can do that in like half an
hour and as long as they know exactly
what they're looking at and this is
actually again the same routine so code
don't even worry about this but just to
show you if you are a programmer this is
really all it's doing is one one bite at
a time XOR in an output very simple and
very stupid but it works it does just
enough of the job to be effective but
then you have some of them that actually
do real encryption as a new AES they do
private keys that do all that fun stuff
which I love this guy jigsaw jigsaw is
actually a pretty wide family very
prevalent they've been around for years
they actually have lots of different
campaigns now it's based off the Saw
movies you actually have the little guy
here says we're gonna play a game let's
play a game
the idea is like every 24 hours or every
actually every hour I'm gonna delete a
random fall off your hard drive until
you pay the ransom so it encrypts
everything and it just starts randomly
deleting things until you actually pay
and it actually does delete this is
actually real legit they have other
variants of this they've made a very
hardcore pornography version of
ransomware that they put up on fake porn
sites and they try to attack people that
way which was very effective this guy
though it actually uses a encrypt a s
encryption however it puts the actual
password and initially initialization
vector in the code itself so you don't
even have to be a reverse engineer if
you download this free tool and you
throw the binary at it it's gonna just
dump this code out to you and you can
look at it like oh look that's a yes oh
look it's this you can literally copy
paste this into your own program and
just write the reverse of it and get all
your files back we just
what we do when we do IR ever like let
me look at the sample oh yeah we can do
this when you look at like a spur ski
and all these websites that have oh we
have free Decrypter so you can actually
download if we know your family that's
all they're doing they know the code
they know what's built into it and they
just ride the Decrypter based off that
you can actually do the same if you have
some basic programming jobs
something simple no I
again code vision Delos is AES
encryption in this case what we're
seeing this is a sim call crypt console
is basic stuff is making a keys making
an IV it's encrypting data lot of
dollars to stuff we expect and we look
at the main I'm gonna just show a few
things here cuz a lot of text 1 it
generates a key right so generates a
second key so your Christian Keys
together and then save file with key so
it jumps into a file okay and then
starts doing encryption and get to
folder path goes uh network and does all
the fun stuff getting that were
computers and that actually actually
maps out to network shares and crypts
that can't be right
save file Torquay what does that
actually mean take the key take the
vector drop it to your desktop as
program ID - land and just write it so
we're actually creating a random key and
IV for encryption and writing it to a
text file on your desktop seriously like
you actually have everything in front of
you to get your data back without paying
the ransom they they left it there I
don't know at their own convenience
maybe that was the other bug code they
forgot to take out but this was actually
in the wild and you look at oh that's
simple that's actually really funny that
level of ineptitude to developing and
coding is awesome we leverage that we
explode it I hope they keep this up and
we love it hidden taters I love hidden
to hear hidden tier is a open source
ranch somewhere there's put out and get
held about three years ago and everyone
uses it if you have our script Katie
who's actually wants to learn ransomware
they use hidden tears to the point where
this awesome sample came out yesterday
the day before
it's called ops Venezuela and he was
quickly called out on hairnet and give
you example over the left-hand side you
see the get help content this is
actually how the original source code
was I'm just showing you one thing on
here password equals create password 15
so they have a routine says create
password 15 bytes long and it just
returns back a password and do all this
other fun stuffs in the password encrypt
and so forth this is how they wrote this
this weak password equals quote create
password 15 that doesn't work the way
you think it works so instead of being a
randomly generated key the key is
literally create password 15 like that
is awesome I mean a for paper effort
ish this is the stuff that actually goes
along in the WoW they might love this in
fact I think yeah here we go is actually
zoomed in so it's easier to read that
was that's how they should have been
writing it this is how they actually
wrote it in quotes this is the level of
adversary I love they this is what makes
the job fun on a given day oh this guy
we have ransomware attacks documents the
attacks JPEGs they attack your movies
your family backups and they attack your
kids roblox game that's all this thing
does you guys know where roblox is your
kids yes probably 60 million players
it's like one of largest online games so
someone wrote an awesome grant somewhere
about the target specifically roblox
that's set I mean that's really just
mean that's point
and it was real when it runs it drops a
bunch of files and Cooley does batch
file in his batch crawl which is
actually nice cleanly written I'm a good
batch consort does target these
extensions Lua and these roblox files it
drops a foul car runtime and it runs it
against all of them what wrong time is
actually just a command-line AAS
encryption tool you can just download
off the internet so basically they all
they do is sit for everyone these files
AES encrypt - e encrypt - P the password
of apples and once the encrypt that they
start deleting the originals so yes it's
actually in an it melts itself down here
at the bottom it works it actually
encrypts it doesn't damage but like
seriously folks like the tools are right
there in front of you you can just say
okay even if I don't know exactly what
this is someone can look at this like oh
I say yes here I can just you could
download the same tool you can download
anything the password sitting right in
front of you it's inside the file and
that's what we target love it even
better is it when you actually do have
the code you put in so you know it gave
you this box you have to email them and
get your code to put in there if you
actually look at the code
the password is poopoo so very well
usually these cases is somewhat very
targeted like they are actually
targeting an actual person with this
that they know is won't be able to do
this this is not something like and the
email campaign this is uh you know proof
of concept it's targeting actual small
group of people we see this on lot on
hack forms or sites like that where
people want to go in and download games
and so forth and the apps are really say
oh look how bright the cheat for you
I'll write a trainer for you here just
download this and they target kids who
are online downloading cheese so that's
literally how this stuff comes about and
how it gets into systems
but let's talk about the enterprise side
of this can we do the same Sam Sam no I
love Sam Sam smooth my favorites if you
don't know what sam says it's just a
quick briefer up here which is very much
one in more advanced versions of
ransomware out there not just by the
software but how they use it this is an
adversary they actually uses live
hands-on actions to infect your network
they were get in through an open RDP if
they don't have that they will start
doing network scans across all your open
IPs I did an IR LED an hour about year
and half two years ago where they used
wind shock they found a wind shock
vulnerability and is server on a box of
the company forgot they had and use that
to get in and then once they got in
there they were able to pull down me me
cats they pull all the tools in move
around laterally a little bit get around
until they found a box it had a lot of
activity on it and they just sat there
and waited for a domain domain admin to
log in and who was also a point of
contact for the IR so he was not happy
when we told me was his account they did
all the damage and once I had that they
actually use PowerShell to deploy the
ransomware out and executed so they make
XML files on their home machine they
uploaded per box or every single box of
an effect has his own XML file an XML
file has a private key and so forth in
it
public key the idea behind that is you
don't buy a single key to unlock your
environment you buy a key to unlock that
box and yes buy another key to unlock
that box so they get you on a per box
basis that's how they rack up the money
this is what hit the city of Atlanta a
few months ago we hit a lot of major
organizations these guys are good - they
actually target individual industries at
any given time so they were target like
small electrical companies or a target
utilities or Target mmm I'll give too
close to their actual victim if I say
but they do go down these lines of like
over a three-month period going after a
very small specific industries now it is
actual real ransomware
it actually is productive twice we've
been called in doing IR in my former
role
one is where they didn't want to pay
like not too bad you're not getting your
data back sorry we can't undo this
second one is they paid they got the
decryption key they didn't feel like
they could trust it why'd you pay then
they're like well can you just reverse
it and figure out what it does and you
write your own tool like I did there's
like now this tool works just use it I'm
not yeah I think you can build ability
100 hours if you want to buy you a new
tool but this one works the third one
which one bring up the next slide is
they downloaded the tool they paid for
it they got it and it didn't work it
worked to a point but all their major
databases that the entire company relied
upon we're gone we're not being able to
decrypt and so people start going out to
sites like bleeping computer saying oh
my god I bought this downloading tool
and it's not working enough people went
back and forth to a point where someone
was able to fix it with a little bit
help determine what the problem was and
basically it was an issue of files over
300 megabytes the way it did math and
the offsetting of encryption just broke
they just didn't account for surprise
sizes of that big so will decrypt any
size fault under 20 megabytes over that
it didn't decrypt at all so yeah there
was actually a wasted lot of money on
these people however they were able to
reach out and the people from Sam Sam do
actually monitor these forums and do
give tech support and I don't have to
screenshot on me but they made an
updated version of the Decrypter and
provide it back to the customer who was
able to get their files back it took
about six weeks or six eight weeks but
they eventually did get it so a lot of
lessons there
Samson itself has a lot of code issues
we had a great one we looking through
Israel there one awesome box where we
had 500 machines infected this one was
not alright that's weird
we look to the actual forensic history
and reseed encrypted files but then
they're all deleted alright so you guys
you guys recovered the box like now no
we didn't touch it
that's as it was during the attack so
what we knew was that Sansom crisis xml
it puts it into the root directory and
he uses that what we found out was that
somehow as was being read to the hard
drive the xml file got slightly
corrupted like a bite got dropped on how
that happens but that wasn't being read
as actual xml anymore now the bad error
code collection or you know exception
handling allowed stamps him do this
really funny thing where it would
encrypt the file up here before kisses
party code and then after eclipse a
follow check the xml to double-check
values and if the key is not correct ill
basic parse emx xml if it doesn't work
it will delete the encrypted value or
encrypt a file and then they'll go to
the next file so basically what it did
was 30,000 times over took a file
encrypted it check the xml fell deleted
encrypted file left it regional move to
next well know how that can't be that's
that's really bad code actually here is
it i'm if you know code you know this
but basically all it does is run from
xml string Snape ii I call the inside
dotnet so you feed it XML text and it
either passes or fails so you usually as
a programmer wrapped something around
that say oh if it if it fails didn't do
this if it passes to do this no it just
failed and just failed ungracefully so
it wouldn't encrypt any files on that
box just kind of awesome
so again bad coding happens even on the
most legitimate of things I'm gonna
change gears here for a little bit
because I need some more fun topics we
can't just drone all about these really
bad mistakes all day one that we start
where Nicholas Cage
here over mankind and the idea of
Bitcoin and the idea of ransom those
themselves and what that tells us about
adversary and all the fun stuff that
goes along with the samples because we
all know okay the most major versions
out there ransomware use Bitcoin
everyone buys a Bitcoin everyone loves a
special win tips you nose pipe peaks and
spikes up and they ask for one Bitcoin
we're just worth ten bucks
yesterday now two hundred dollars today
and tomorrow be at ten thousand they
after that's five bucks to the point
where as Andrew case calls out companies
that bought Bitcoin last year in case of
ransomware are seeing a Forex increase
the last twelve months
this is actually a thing people are
doing this like okay let's just have it
in our back pocket so that whenever we
get attacked we could just pay it
quickly and get our data back but then
they never got attacked
so that 8,000 or where they were a five
thousand dollar investment something
became 20,000 25,000 dollars and he you
know the admins like mmm I'm just gonna
take a little bit off that no was it we
paid five thousand weeks to about five
thousand there but that was a very
interesting way of doing it especially
with the way Bitcoin was that now
ransomware is moving beyond that gang
crowd came out every January started
using - which is a fairly new one
there's ones out there for aetherium
there's ones out there for Manero then
you got this guy this is actual MBR
Locker variant that overwrites the MBR
and so basically all it does is it
overwrites MBR and puts a ransom note
into the MBR so you can't get back to
your box anymore however this is
literally the whole thing so want to see
QQ which makes you think okay Chinese
that's their major social network
because this is in the MBR it's an ASCII
mode you can't use Unicode characters so
the use was called pinion which is
basically romanized you know Chinese
basically says if you want your data
back send 31 to this QQ you want to how
much you wan is worth
it's five bucks so if you're something
very targeted but really it's just a
funny example of the weird things we saw
going through all this is this guy one
two five bucks and through his Chinese
account however dnbr was overwritten and
they didn't save a backup of it so I
don't know how they can get the data
back and then you think okay with all
these various new Bitcoin variants
coming out with all those new things and
that's what led to this awesome guy here
sprite coin great currency cuz it
doesn't exist this was a brand new
mining software for sprite coin it was
like oh wow there's a new currency you
know get on the ground floor get it Ross
cheap except it doesn't exist you create
your wallet it mixes a little progress
bars and does all that it's actually
encrypting your box it's actually
ransomware pretending to be a wallet in
a minor which is just genius and so many
levels I love it now
that level itself gets into what we call
a variant called black ruby black ruby
came out earlier this year code I'll
explain this really quickly to you the
big parts here mutexes don't even worry
about that this won't come back to the
top rats minecraft a little bit but down
here is going to church itself into the
registry it's gonna then download and
run a crypto minor so what it eventually
gets down to a serious is here at the
very bottom where it installs itself and
encrypts all your files and then runs a
crypto minor so that encrypts your data
as ransom or would and just the pork
salt on that wound it's now using your
box as a crypto mining as well because
what you gonna do you can turn your
machine off no not you leave it going
and it's gonna sit there for at least a
few days while you try to figure out
what I do with this so that's a few days
of uninterrupted crypto mining from your
box and they could just bite the CPU as
much as they want that point like what
you gonna do
they also have some really mean jerk
things they do so I talked about Sam Sam
where over 300 megabytes it wasn't able
to decrypt apparently they ran to some
sort of similar issue because their code
checks ok if it's a file extension if
it's under five lines twelve megabytes
and this and this and this encrypt it if
it's over 512 megabytes and it doesn't
in with bkf which is the encrypted
ransomware
extension delete it Oh jerk move so yeah
they don't even want to deal with
follows that big they just delete it off
your hard drive so even if you paid the
money to get it back you're not getting
it back now that good spell on this is
that we're here for spycraft that's our
overall theme this year right weapons
your iranian this machine before it does
anything this ransomware will actually
do a geoip look up on your IP address if
you're based out of iran it will just
quit anywhere else in the world it will
affect you buddy Ron no there no no you
guys are good base was saying and
they're not the only one to do that this
was a campaign of Kimberly of thought my
head but basically they had a Taiwanese
campaign ransomware and this victim
emailed out and the victim actors shared
this email to Taiwanese news and
basically the victim says my monthly
income is only $400 you really want to
do this dummy legitimate you know most
ransom or do have support they can work
with you negotiate very well fractured
English here of no we don't frankly the
campaign seems to be a total failure
apparently we have largely overestimated
income of the population of your country
Oh back in a compliment here Wow what'd
I say about your country
so okay you don't have to pay now we've
switched on the crip to decryption or
Thunder gratis what it's called so
basically here's your data back
they say that point like me as a poor
college student whatever I can't pay
they'll work with you if you're not
American you know screw America like it
you try this support or try to you know
get the value down no they raise it up
most other countries though there have
some sympathy for you not just Taiwan I
love this guy this is a sick run just
just came out in last two days here of
basically the people who run sig Rana
had some email sent people asking you
like hey how do I get my money how do I
pay this what I need to do one guy asks
how much money does it cost in dollars
and like twenty five hundred this guy
asks how many rubles must I pay that
bomb I notice about the Bob scream but
you do not have to pay I'll just help
you key word rubles Russian soon as you
said that key word thought gotcha bro
really it's a thing and even more so
when you look at the actual code of that
this is actually what looks like in the
reverse engineer code is open up the
registry go to keyboard layout preload
check their value against four one nine
four nine being the Russian keyboard
layout if you have a local keyword in a
Russian layout it will not infect you
it'll just move on what this one victim
got was that he was using a u.s.
computer laptop and so he did get
infected but he's like no I'm really I'm
Russian and guys dated back so when you
get to that point how do you tell the
difference between a real and a not real
threat like if someone sends you like
hey you need to be afraid of this like
yeah that doesn't exist that's not real
think Gears of War though made it they
pulled it off how do you do that
one is the online tools out there got my
timing off a little bit there
one is the ID ransomware bribe malware
onto team is they had this nice little
service here another one is I do
ransomware about on amigo he's a Russian
analyst he puts all the new samples off
on his blog post or in Russian but you
can convert them over the English it
actually works out really well he's got
some really good details on them the
great thing about matter out there team
is that for example this one Agnew you
know ignore the red barb you can go to
the service upload the actual copy the
ransom note and they can look at that
say okay we know exactly what you're
infected with in this version it was
Kirk there's that this is actually Kirk
we're as in Star Trek Captain Kirk so
when you run it it pops up a text box
and actually shows Spock and Captain
Kirk and ASCII alright and then starts
affecting all your files great piece of
art there's no way being that data back
however they now tell you currently
there's no we're getting your data back
but we know in the future eventually
these campaigns run out and adversary's
like yeah okay I've just given given all
the data back we don't want to deal this
anymore
they've moved on to something else so
they will just put the keys out there
publicly it's happening at least five
campaigns I know of so these guys will
track that like hey we actually have the
keys now let's email all these people
who have files encrypted and let them
know they can get their data back which
is why we tell victims don't just give
up and wipe your box just because you
can't get your data back back up the
encrypted files and then why can box
because eventually you may get the key
to get your data back from them again
basic information that we tell you we
don't need to go into this in too much
detail these kind of basics that people
should know about dealing ransomware is
now have backups have the ability to do
root cause analysis which is always the
single lacking point on almost
everything is that we don't know how we
got infected but we got 500 machines
destroying themselves right now how
would you not know that
we think it's email but maybe it could
be someone's download folder how do you
how do you do your job and not be able
to turn that granular level of how did I
get infected in many cases people can't
so it was like okay have something out
there have an email just checklist look
through forensic timelines okay the
first box start encrypting at 8:04 and a
what emails came in maybe just a few
seconds prior to that maybe those were
related typically that's what it is
we also tell people to you can just do a
minimal analysis before you call in I
are calling forensics call in security
teams and pay 400 bucks an hour for
someone to kind of walk through and do
what you can do for free one of it is
just very basically if you can identify
what variant of the ransomware it is
even using one of these sites when these
two websites that would get you a long
way there upload your ransom though
figure out what it is and it really
quickly would tell you okay
either you're screwed or there's hope
for you and based off that you can
determine okay do we need to call an ir
do we need call n security teams and
work us through this but the tools out
there that we use for analysis are
actually pretty basic and open source
and free so if you see ransomware it's
almost always dotnet and so there's a
tool called the inspire which is dotnet
spy then you can just download for free
and just throw software at it and I'll
just just bomb it open code at you
there's actually easy to read and easy
to understand give that to a junior
analyst who's someone who's like just
knows programming went through college
and they can whip out a Decrypter for
you in many cases it's just doing string
analysis this was a version of jf
ransomware where it asks for an unlock
code the code was actually hard-coded
into the binary itself and using a tool
called floss which is from fireEye's
flare team which is an awesome tool if
you use strings a lot stop use floss
instead floss gives you a ski and
Unicode very cleanly and it also does
stack strings which I won't explain here
but they're really awesome
basically office gave strains that can
pull out but in this case that was the
actual password
to decrypt this machine it was just
basically sitting there right there in
the file itself which lead spamming
forensic side we do this a lot if we
have encrypted files we have passwords
we will run strings on entire hard drive
image dump it out to a major file and
then try all of them one after another
until something works because somewhere
on that hard drive is the password
either involve a memory or in the
dislike or something same way here if
you have an unlock code is probably
somewhere in that side executable and in
cases like that that simple string dump
it out throw in the program you get this
nice big unlock button and you get your
machine back and with that thank you
any questions while we're here
yeah like what are the odds of getting
an actual real ransom or vs. okay all
right so did so what's yards of actually
having a real ransomware versus a script
81 predominantly you're gonna see the
real ones more often you can see the
ones like very la Cortes a crypt all
those ones quite often however they're
very targeted and where they attack you
know the either enterprise certain
victims and have very specific email
campaigns whereas these creep kiddie
ones are very prominent on like heck for
arms and websites and forums or you know
people actually using steam to infect
each other in chat rooms which is
actually you know they pretend to be
someone working for steam and like a hey
we're in this program helps us you know
get your stuff back
it's ransomware so you'll see this get
the script PD on that side more often
the commodity side thank you questions
alright thank you
[Applause]