alright man what exactly is this thing
it's a cell phone okay I got that much
but some extra features this thing has
it's a shaver okay anything else you
want tell us about it
I'm sure let me power it on
welcome who makes this shit I don't know
but we can turn on the charger baby
charge a baby opened charge the baby
clothes I'll just look into this phone
that's a very strange phone you can take
a oh fuck
320 by 240 image at the highest quality
we can get shit wow how does this phone
we do if you're watching pornos
I don't know if I can what I don't hope
you can't you got a built-in vibrating
function you want to turn off them he
does not use the razor directly on you
did you sell the razor part right so yes
home again