all right well thank you everybody for
coming in this afternoon fighting off
your food coma listening to us talk
about the scourge of the internet right
now malicious crypto mining as far as
Who I am my name is Nick via Seanie I'm
a threat researcher with Cisco Talos a
little bit of background I've been in
security now got 15 years basically all
of it has been in sauk environments up
until my time doing threat research I
got my start as an analyst in a 24 by 7
sock over the years I was an analyst
lead analyst manage teams of analysts
IPS engineer SIM engineer I am a proud
non coder
I don't code will never code I make
horrible scripts that do things in
adequately and just a little bit about
me my name is Edmund rummaging I'm also
a security researcher with Cisco Talos
so I've spent the past decade in
information security doing mostly
digital forensics Incident Response
malware analysis held pretty much every
position in a sock that you can that you
can have prior to coming to Talos and
starting my role is a security
researcher so just a couple things about
me I love malware so that's that's what
we do we're constantly monitoring threat
landscape ripping apart new threats that
we're seeing in the wild figuring out
how a tag methodologies are changing
over time and then making sure that
customers are protected so I'm also a
huge music fan specifically a punk rock
is kind of my jam so definitely love to
talk to folks about that as well
so over the past six to twelve months or
so we've seen a significant shift across
the the threat landscape so over the
past few years right ransomware has been
the one of the primary payloads of
choice for most commodity malware
distributors right so they'll use spam
botnets for Mouse spam campaigns exploit
kits for web-based attacks active
network exploitation and typically the
the goal is to ransom data stored on
systems but over the past six to twelve
months we've seen a shift in the use of
malware payloads in the wild so all of
those same vectors that have
historically been used form our
distribution have started to be used to
drop a malicious cryptocurrency mining
malware on
systems and we've seen this across the
board we've seen a significant reduction
in other types of distinct different
types of payloads that are being dropped
and at this point it seems like
attackers are starting to shift to kind
of a more passive revenue generation
model through the use of stealing cycles
on other folks systems for the purpose
of generating cryptocurrency so we've
done a lot of research in monitoring and
ripping apart a lot of the different
malware distribution campaigns we've
seen so we're pretty familiar with
Manero at this point if you're not
familiar already Manero is an
alternative cryptocurrency everyone
knows about the Bitcoin it's all over
but we've seen attackers typically try
to mine and generate Manero versus
Bitcoin and what kind of walkthrough why
that is a little bit later in the
presentation there's a couple of
different factors that make Manero much
more attractive to cyber criminals than
Bitcoin so why do we put this talk
together right well we've seen this
shift and organizations need to be aware
of it not just you know reading
headlines that talk about you know
crypto mining worms and stuff like that
but actually walk through what these
attacks look like I look very similar to
what we've seen from commodity malware
for years and years and years except
instead of the resultant payload being a
banking Trojan or click-fraud malware
we're seeing an increase in the use of
cryptocurrency mining malware uh we
wanted to raise awareness and walk
through some things that you can
actually look for within an environment
to very very quickly identify when
systems have been compromised and start
generating revenue for attackers by
mining a mineiro
so what are we going to be covering
today well we're gonna start out by
talking about Manero in general so that
everyone has an understanding of why
attackers are targeting Manero versus
Bitcoin versus other crypto currencies
that are out there we're going to talk
about how mining and mining pools
actually work so this isn't going to be
math heavy we're not going to walk
through specific algorithmic problems
that are being solved by mining clients
to generate cryptocurrency but at a high
level you know how attackers are
leveraging mining and mining pools to
generate revenue we're also as I
mentioned going to talk for things that
defender talk about things that
defenders can do within their
environment to mitigate these sorts of
risks a lot of it is following the same
best practices from a network security
architecture perspective that we've been
preaching for the past several decades
um there are some distinct
characteristics associated with
cryptocurrency mining malware that are
really easy to spot if you are looking
for the right things all right so let's
start out by talking about Manero so
what is material right everyone's
familiar with Bitcoin at this point
there's a ton of different alternative
crypto currencies out there it's just
another form of magic internet money
right you solve complex mathematical
problems and you may result in the
creation of new cryptocurrency in this
case Manero it seems like every week
we're seeing new initial coin offerings
being announced for a lot of different
projects that are attempting to get into
the cryptocurrency market and generate
support Manero is one of the most
successful cryptocurrencies out there
and as a result it's it's attractive for
attackers so just a little background on
Manero it was actually launched in April
of 2014 so one of the unique things
about Manero is that it's specifically
concerned with security and privacy in
and provides different functionality to
users of mineiro that aren't available
with crypto currencies like Bitcoin it
spongeable coin history can't be used to
ban coins or anything like that and
similar to it's a Bitcoin it was
actually created by an unknown person so
let's talk about how the mining actually
works as it pertains to the Monaro
cryptocurrency so it's based on the
Kryptonite proof-of-work
a hashing algorithm it's designed to be
fairer than some of the other crypto
currencies out there specifically when
compared to Bitcoin on the developers
behind this particular cryptocurrency
project have specifically made the
decision that they do not want to price
out standard computers and in terms of
being able to generate revenue through
mining cryptocurrency in there's default
obvious obvious Gatien techniques that
are built-in not selected by the user
and they provide additional benefits to
attackers that are using this thus
cryptocurrency so I mentioned it Mineiro
uses as a proof of work a proof of work
system other cryptocurrencies use proof
of stake and there's some distinct
differences between these two types of
hashing algorithms but it's really
simple so just to like break it down
proof of work
dictates that the resources that you
expend performing the mathematical
calculations when you're mining have a
direct impact on the amount of
cryptocurrency that you can generate
with proof of state systems on the
amount of cryptocurrency you already
control impacts how much cryptocurrency
you can generate so it's pretty pretty
important distinction for the purposes
of this talk at the end of the day when
you're mining Manero the number of
systems and the number of resources that
you have available and under your
control directly directly translates to
the amount of revenue you can generate
through mining Manero all right I'm
gonna jump in and talk a little bit
about CPU GPU mining so if you're mining
Bitcoin and you're not using a SIG's
just stop you're you're not making any
money it's just not worth it anymore the
big thing about Bitcoin is that it is
the hardware specific ASIC just
completely dominates that landscape
which is one of the reasons why we don't
see adversaries going after it
monaro on the other hand is much more
beneficial to this as Edmund just said
it's been specifically designed to be
able to be used and will always work
with commodity CPUs and GPUs and as such
bad guys are much more interested in it
not surprisingly so yes the basics a cig
resistant so what I mean by that is
Asics are specialized hardware that are
designed specifically for a purpose in
this case specifically designed usually
to mine Bitcoin or crypto currencies in
general right the way that Manero is
built is it ensures that CPU and GPU
mining is always going to be profitable
it will always generate money it's a
very very attractive way to get people
to constantly mine and prevent these
huge farms of Asics dominating a massive
amount of the the mining capabilities
for a particular cryptocurrency
and it in at its core it's the same as
any other cryptocurrency right you're
just doing math you're completing
calculations you're solving puzzles
that's how you generate your currency
it's it's all the same it's just how
they
our ties the things you can do it on now
one of the most interesting things about
Manero is they're actually in February
they announced that they're gonna be
continually updating the proof of work
so the whole idea here is to ensure that
that threshold stays low they're gonna
continue to change and alter the
algorithm the things that they're doing
to make sure that average people will
always be able to generate revenue this
actually just happened a month or so ago
so today it's easier and more profitable
to mine Manero than it was a month a
month and a half ago because of these
constant evolutions that they're gonna
do to make sure that the barrier stays
low so that people remain interested and
they'll always be able to use the
commodity CPUs and GPUs to generate
revenue so this is kind of an overview
slide of all the things associated with
Manero and Bitcoin how they're the same
and how they're the how they're
different they are very similar the
biggest differences are the a sig
resistance and the fact that they
they're always altering the
proof-of-work
they're always going to make sure that
they're doing the the commodity devices
are always gonna work and always going
to generate revenue they do also
continually grow that is one big
difference like with Bitcoin there's a
set amount of Bitcoin right there's only
this many Manero is it continues to grow
they'll always be more monaro available
that's one of the limitations of Bitcoin
that we don't see in manera but the big
difference is privacy everybody talks
about the privacy associated with
Bitcoin but the ledger is public so you
can see all transactions right you can
trace transactions until your heart's
content
however with Manero you can't see
anything there is zero visibility into
transactions the wallets are basically
you can't get any of that privacy data
they took it to a much further place
than where Bitcoin ever was and again
the reason adversaries like Manero is
because you can mine it on CPUs and GPUs
that's just how it was designed to be
done
so let's talk a little bit about
malicious script on mining what we're
really here to talk about how is this
being done why is it being done how much
money are they generating how are they
doing it that kind of stuff not
surprisingly the real reason this is
taken off is because crypto currencies
are extremely valuable way more so than
they were a year ago and adversaries no
matter what we think about them are
going to go where the money is that's
what motivates the overwhelming majority
of malicious activity you see on the
Internet right there just following
where the money goes
and why are they going to deliver
something like ransomware that has a lot
of law-enforcement intention it has you
have to maintain communication you have
to do command and control there's a lot
of additional steps whereas with a
crypto minor I can drop it and I don't
care you can take it away doesn't matter
I'll just own another box I don't have
to maintain access I don't have to
communicate with you at all
so one time drop the malware and just
off you go so a little refresher here
how do you get cryptocurrency there's
two ways you can do it
you can buy it from an exchange or you
can mine it now before you go home and
are like oh I saw about this Manero
thing I'm gonna generate all the money
in the world typical computer 125 hashes
a second which calculates to a whopping
25 cents a day in Manero it's not even
worth the electricity it's gonna cost
you however bad guys don't pay for
electricity number one number two they
operate at scale so when you start
multiplying this out you start to see
why it's so attractive with 2,000
systems you're now generating 500
dollars a day in manera we've seen
botnets
with more than 200,000 nodes in them you
do the math that's a lot of money that's
the reason why this is becoming such a
massive epidemic there's just so much
money to be made and it's a much much
simpler process so how do you do this
how does pool based mining work the
whole idea here is you just basically
need two things you need a URL or an
address that is the the pool that you're
mining to and you
a unique identifier in this case a
worker ID and you can see here it can be
like a giant string of random text like
that it could be an email address it
could be a username it really depends on
what pool you're mining to how they're
set up all that kind of stuff now one of
the interesting aspects is we don't
always see this but there is a lot of
capabilities in most miners that allow
you to do some form of stealth right you
can do things like limit the temperature
the CPU
limit the amount of CPU you're using
limit the times when it's running what
else oh yeah how many cores are you use
there's a lot of things that they can do
to try and minimize the identification
that being said we've seen plenty of
crypto mining campaigns that just do not
care they will just push your hardware
till it melts and it doesn't matter to
them I mean there's mobile mining
campaigns that melted phones because
they just don't care they don't care if
your system dies as long as you generate
revenue before the system runs out of
gas so basically what we saw is bad guys
realizing Manero is the future we're
gonna mine all the things and I kid you
not it is literally being delivered in
every single way possibly imaginable
onto end systems so let's talk a little
bit about some of the patterns and
things that we see so this is a very
typical mining pattern right it's a very
clean wave you can see that they're
peaking ebbing and flowing during normal
times a day usually they're trying to
mine in off hours doing simple things to
try and evade the user saying why is my
computer running so slow why can't I do
anything on it anymore however we do
occasionally see patterns that are more
like this and this would be typically
indicative could be indicative of
something like in browser mining
something that's a little more sporadic
where you don't have like this you have
a dedicated system that's mining for
very long periods of time this could be
something that's only mining during
short bursts so you see these huge
spikes and then drops to where it drops
down to basically nothing yeah so as he
mentioned pretty much every vector that
we
use for malware distribution is being
used to push malicious mining clients
out in pretty high quantities the whole
idea being that you push a mining client
and you try to maintain persistence
honor honor persistence on a system as
long as possible right so same ways that
that commodity malware has for years
scheduled tasks registry run key entries
WMI subscriptions
all of those same things are being used
a lot of the reason that the attackers
would leverage those stealth options so
controlling temperature controlling AC
stat power status and stuff like that is
because the whole idea is you infect
enough systems to reach a daily or
monthly revenue generation level and
then you try to maintain persistence on
those systems for as long as possible
because it makes it so you don't have to
go out and reinfect systems every day
because they're being found by
organizations because you know their
server farms are not falling over on the
the idea is if you can infect a specific
set number of systems whatever your
revenue generation goals are you can set
it forget it and hope that you maintain
those cycles as long as possible because
that's that's the whole passive part of
the passive revenue generation model
another thing that I'd like to point out
is you know with ransomware one of the
one of the things that's just a nature
of the the the sort of an approach is
that there's a natural diminishing pool
of available victims right so you know
initially when a user victim gets
infected with ransomware they might be
forced to pay a ransom if they don't
have backups they can't recover their
data there's no weakness in the
encryption implementation that
ransomware but at the end of the day
most people were gonna get burned once
maybe twice and then they'll probably
have a pretty good backup in recovery
strategy which makes them not an ideal
available victim for for attackers but
if these same systems can be infected
with crypto miners that remain under the
radar for an extended period of time
they can continue to generate revenue
for the attackers for a long time
there's no ransom note one of the
characteristics of ransomware and one of
the things that this revenue model
relies on is making the process of
paying a ransom demand as easy as
possible so it requires extensive ransom
notes they have to have
processing portals for processing the
exchange of of the decryption keys if
they choose to even give those back
there's a lot of ongoing care and
feeding that that has to be put into
long-term ransomware campaigns whereas
with this send out a mouse spam campaign
infect a bunch of hosts and then
generate revenue until they get cleaned
up so it's easy to see why this sort of
a business model is attracted to cyber
criminals even in the legitimate
business space people try to generate a
passive revenue whenever possible and
it's no different here so let's talk
about how these these miners are
actually being delivered I wanted to
walk through some specific examples just
to show how how these commodity malware
distribution channels that we've seen
used for years and years and years are
now shifting those sorts of payloads so
here's an email example right emails
nothing new emails been abused by
attackers for years and years and years
but here's a campaign where rather than
pushing ransomware or a banking Trojan
the attackers were pushing malicious
cryptocurrency mining software so in
this particular case it was an email
that was sent to a pool of victims where
it claimed to be from somebody who was
looking for a job and the attacker
basically said hey I'm looking for
employment opportunities here's my CV
please give me feedback and attached to
the email was a malicious Word document
so here's the the word document in this
particular campaign right looks very
similar to decoy documents that we see
all the time in in malicious you know
phishing campaigns in this particular
case the the malicious Word document
actually functioned as a downloader so
in a lot of cases with the sort of
malware distribution the malware is not
actually in the malicious file that's
attached to the email so when you open
the the the file attachment and you
enable macros in the case of word
typically all that's in there is the
code that's responsible for going out to
an attacker control web server pulling
down the actual malware and then kicking
it off to infect the system and that's
exactly what this particular document
did so once you enable content enable
macros a PowerShell would kick off and
it would go ahead and grab this
particular executable so one of the
things that the attacker did was they
changed the file extension to make it
look like it was benign so imagine
you're an analyst and you're in your ear
and your sim you're looking at web-based
events that sort of thing and you see
this sort of a request maybe
the fact that it has dot jpg at the end
makes you think that it's a benign file
but in this case it was definitely a PE
thirty-two executable so once the
malware infects the system right the
attacker has to kick that now we're off
to initiate the mining process and they
have to in a obtain persistence so be
able to kick off the miner again when
the system reboots or things like that
in this particular case the the
command-line syntax that they use to
kick off the malware initially and every
subsequent time had those two same
components that he was talking about
earlier right so you've got the the pool
address so that the mining client knows
where to connect to to communicate the
results of mathematical calculations and
kind of track the the progress of the
mining process and then you've got the
worker ID it's a unique identifier
typically you wouldn't give this out but
since the attacker has to be able to
facilitate receiving them an arrow
that's being mined they have to encode
this into all of the the malware that
they distribute in this particular case
the worker ID has a dot smoke one one at
the end and that's really just a way
that if you're an attacker and you're
pulling resources from two thousand
nodes in a botnet that you've created
and he wants to be able to uniquely
identify them to you know see what sort
of performance you're getting or
identify which victims are finding and
cleaning up the Mauer you can use those
sorts of unique identifiers that way so
here's how this particular campaign
achieved persistence very very similar
to what we see from from Mouse spam
campaigns all the time in this case they
key that appointed to the the mining
client on disk and then any time the
system is rebooted those keys are read
those executables are then kicked off in
the mining process start right up again
so that's an example of an email
campaign I could have walked through
this exact same campaign you know a year
ago and 95 percent of people would have
guessed that this was a ransomware or a
banking Trojan campaign but that's the
shift we're seeing and it's a
significant one we're continuing to see
new campaigns in the wild and it's
continuing to grow in in frequency in
popularity so let's shift gears a little
bit and let's talk web so I wanted to
talk about some of the web-based
campaigns that we've seen in the wild
right so we've seen flat fake flash
player campaigns typically those were
always used for ran
we're banking Trojans we're now starting
to see those used for malicious
cryptocurrency mining distribution also
rigged is an exploit kit I wanted to
walk through how we saw rig distributing
uh malicious cryptocurrency miners in
the wild so just a show of hands who
here is already very familiar with how
exploit kids work okay so if you this oh
this will be kind of a refresher as far
as that goes on so if you're not
familiar with it the online advertising
industry nowadays is extremely
disjointed right from the time you put a
URL into the address bar and hit enter
in your browser to the time a webpage is
displayed there is a ton of activity
that goes on on the back end to
determine you know which advertisements
are actually going to be displayed to
you so Nick could go to a website a
major news website I could go to a major
news website at the exact same time and
be shown completely different ads and
that's because of a lot of the real-time
auctioning and stuff that takes place a
lot of the targeting that advertising
companies are choosing to do but it
makes it very attractive for cyber
criminals because of all of the
different moving parts and coordination
that has to happen in near-real-time
just to facilitate that process so just
to kind of put it in perspective this is
a connection map this is all of the
distinct connections that are made when
you when you load a major news website
nowadays so gone are the days where
you're just pulling down a few different
elements and in displaying the web page
but it's definitely easy to see how this
would be attractive if a cyber criminal
can find the weak spot somewhere in this
advertising stream and insert malicious
code you know they can take advantage of
that to compromise a lot of systems so
just at a high level what it is an
exploit kit so in in most cases when you
browse the the major website you know in
the ads are displayed there's code
that's executing that facilitates the
display of whatever graphical content is
associated with them so the idea with
with a lot of the exploit kit campaigns
that we see is that they'll basically
find a way to insert a code into an
advertisement and it's typically you
know a one pixel iframe so something
that you can't see with the with the
human eye and typically they'll inject
JavaScript and all that javascript is
responsible for is redirecting the
client into the exploit kits
infrastructure though usually bouncing
through a few different servers
but ultimately you'll end up hitting
with what's called a landing page and
that landing page is typically
responsible for querying the system
identifying you know what what version
of Internet Explorer what version
whatever browser is is running what
browser plug-ins are installed what
versions of those are being used
what's the geographic location of the
the potential victim so they find out
all the information that they can from
the client to to try to make a
determination you know is this an ideal
candidate to try to exploit a
vulnerability so if the system hasn't
impassioned there's an exploit that's
been rolled into the exploit kit that
takes advantage of that vulnerability
that might be an ideal client to try to
compromise and they'll typically when
they're successful at compromising the
system they'll typically use that access
to draw malware historically it's been
ransomware banking Trojans click-fraud
malware but we've seen a significant
increase in this sort of activity being
used to distribute malicious
cryptocurrency mining clients as well so
in this particular campaign it starts
with a with a gate so this is that
redirection code that code that's
responsible for the redirection process
that I kind of mentioned before right
it's just an iframe that points to the
exploits infrastructure and begins that
redirection process that ultimately ends
up with a potential compromise attempt
so at the end of the day you hit that
landing page don't worry about the code
it's been obviated by the attacker but
it does that querying process to profile
the system to identify if you know
there's an exploit available that they
can make use of to get an initial
foothold on a system in this particular
case could actually clearly see the the
system attempt to be compromised by the
exploit kit in a controlled environment
but what was interesting about this
campaign is it was actually a multi
payload campaign so the system was
successfully exploited and the attackers
chose to drop a smoke loader as the the
first stage of the infection process so
if you're not familiar with smoke loader
it's essentially a loader that that's
commonly used to load additional malware
onto a system so the attacker will drop
smoke loader smoke loader will register
with the command and control
infrastructure that the attacker
controls it'll send survey information
about the system and then from there the
attackers can determine how they can
best monetize their access right maybe
it's ransomware
maybe it's a banking trojan or maybe
it's cryptocurrency mining software so
here's the actual registration following
the smoke loader infection you can see a
posting information out to the command
and control server and receiving
information back
that's an initial registration process
so in this particular case they dropped
a second payload and it was a
cryptocurrency mining client which was
interesting you know and we've seen
similar types of infection processes
with ransomware in the past right though
they'll drop smoke loader or some other
piece of malware and they'll drop
ransomware and that's important because
in a lot of cases the victim may be able
to clean up the ransomware there may be
a decrypter available if it's not
encoded well but by creating that
diversion the victim may never realize
that there's a secondary piece of
malware on their system and the attacker
can just drop right in and in drop
malware again
so once the malicious cryptocurrency
mining client is on the system and it
kicks off what it what we typically see
from from this sort of mining client is
that it'll go out and register with the
mining pool and then it will
continuously start to communicate with
the mining pool sending updates and
things like that and it uses JSON
communications which aren't encrypted on
the wire it's something that's really
easy to spot if you have rules in place
that look for this sort of
communications so that's an example of a
web-based attack one of the other
attacks I wanted to talk about was
active network exploitation so every
time we see a remote code execution
vulnerability that impacts a service or
platform that's typically externally
exposed in an organization attackers are
very very quick to hop on that it makes
it even easier when exploit
proof-of-concept code is publicly
available it just speeds up the process
it'll eventually happen anyways but it
significantly speed that process up so I
wanted to talk about a specific example
of that that we saw over the the past
year so um so it was the end of last
year beginning of this year details came
out about a remote code execution
vulnerability that affected Oracle
WebLogic but what was interesting is
that you can see on the slide the the
date of January 3rd 2018 we saw a public
proof of exploit code yet
posted to exploit DB on if you're not
familiar exploit DB is essentially a
repository where people can pub publish
public proof of concept exploit code on
that can be used for you know pin
testing or other sorts of testing
activities like that it's publicly
available though so it's also available
to cyber criminals what was interesting
so on the third we saw this proof of
concept code yet uploaded to exploit DB
and then what we saw was around the
ninth there was a sans ISE diary where
they were reporting that across a
honeypot infrastructure they were seeing
a significant spike in traffic around
the internet on port TCP port 3333 and
they even included a map of what they
were seeing from a connection standpoint
and you can see starting around the 3rd
the beginning of January there saw a
significant spike in traffic on that
port and what that port is is that's one
of the ports that the mining clients
communicate to the mining pool over so I
get asked a lot when I talk to people
you know what's you know how quickly do
we need a patch when things like RCEs
are released or disclosed by vendors and
the answer is very very quickly because
attackers will hop on these and what
they were doing was they basically
scanning the internet looking for
vulnerable WebLogic servers and then
exploiting this particular vulnerability
and using that access to drop
cryptocurrency mining software on the
servers that were impacted there's a
significant number of these sorts of
exposed servers on the Internet
which makes it a big problem but it also
allows attackers to very very quickly
hop on exploit a bunch of systems drop
cryptocurrency miners and immediately
start to generate revenue so one of the
cool things about the mining pools is if
you have that unique identifier you can
go straight to the mining pool and you
can plug that worker ID into the mining
pool and they'll give you all sorts of
historical information about the
performance of this particular worker ID
so in this particular case think about
net under the the attackers control and
this is what the actual graph of the
performance that they were getting from
a hash rate perspective look like over
time and at the time when we actually
looked at this we found that they had
already been paid out about 150 thousand
dollars and this is this is pretty quick
revenue generation whenever you had that
worker ID you can
how much has historically been paid out
to that worker ID as a result of mining
and such and so this was at time of
slide creation as most of you are
probably aware of the the price of
cryptocurrency is very very volatile and
so it could be significantly different
week by week but when we put these
slides together it was at about one
hundred and fifty three thousand that
that's this particular botnet had been
generating so the last example I want to
talk about is mining worms because these
are interesting in that they're not
looking at a one-to-one infection when
they're targeting an organization though
in fact patient zero and then through
the use of self propagation additional
resources within the organization may be
impacted and in the case with mining
worms that can be significant because if
they don't choose to be stealthy and
they just crank it up to eleven and
start utilizing 100% CPU resources that
can cause a ton of legitimate services
to start falling over you know if you
have database servers or you know other
sorts of special role servers on if you
get infected and this mind starts to
propagate across your environment and
starts to adversely impact all of those
systems the legitimate services in a lot
of cases will start to fall over and
we've seen this so one example was was
one of mine which was a worm that spread
using eternal blue there's another
example where they were utilizing
android adb and then just a third
example of the use of MRI botnet to
begin generating bitcoins with IOT
devices interesting thing about IOT
there's a ton of them but obviously they
don't have a whole lot of system
resources so you're kind of playing the
the game of you know I can infect more
systems in a lot of cases much easier
but it's gonna take me a lot longer and
a lot more systems to reach that that
revenue generation threshold that I want
to be at so we've talked about all of
these distribution mechanisms right this
is pretty much how ransomware has been
being distributed for the past you know
three or four years and we're seeing
that shift but how much is this actually
generating for the the attackers so
here's just an example of another botnet
that we were we were analyzing when we
were doing this research in this
particular case they had made about
120,000 us
and just another example of a botnet
where they had generated about 200,000
and here's another example where they
had generated about half a million and
so here's just a table of some of the
other botnets that we went through when
we were doing this research but you can
very quickly see how this would be an
attractive business model for for cyber
criminals there's not a lot of care and
feeding there's no c2 infrastructure
necessarily needed for these campaigns
they're not having directly communicate
with with victims to help them buy
Bitcoin and transfer it to pay a ransom
and they can sit back and just let the
revenue generate in a passive manner
once they've reached that a number of
infected systems that they want alright
I'm gonna talk a little bit about how
they evolved but just to put some final
points on that those that table of four
or five there there were hundreds and
hundreds and hundreds of those types of
campaigns going on I mean when that
example of WebLogic happened there was
enough traffic generated to shift the
global traffic profile for that port
think about that I mean the Internet
storm center is looking at stuff at a
very large scale and they noticed a
drastic shift in that that is a lot of
traffic and gives you an idea of how bad
this is
but like any threat as you gain more and
more insight into it the actors are
watching what you're doing they're
watching what you're writing and they're
gonna continue to change and evolve to
try to get better so let's see some of
the stuff that they're doing we've seen
this a lot where they'll just hard-code
an IP instead of a domain they're not
being super clever though because they
just hard-coded the IP to one of the
pools so it's not very sophisticated but
if you're doing things like domain
blacklisting this is gonna get past it
because it's not looking up the domain
anymore we've also seen them rolling
their own meaning they build their own
aggregation point right you they have
their own pool that they set up that all
the bots connect to and then that ends
up connecting out to a pool where
they're generating more Manero revenue
and that a lot of these you'll notice by
the really simplistic users like a work
you're not gonna get a worker ID of one
to three from a reputable pool is just
gonna happen that's not the way that
this works unlike here ZJ that's not
again not a valid pool but this is an
effective way if again all you're doing
is trying to block the IPS and domains
of the pools this will get past that
we've also seen things like this this
one was a little bit interesting
so they registered their own domain and
instead of pointing it to the IP address
they literally just forwarded it to the
pool for mine XMR this is yet another
example of the ways that they go about
doing this some obviously way more
sophisticated than others we do very
rarely occasionally see them
implementing some sort of encryption
around it and trying to obfuscate the
traffic but that is far more often the
exception than the rule it's not
something that we see commonly just
because for from their perspective it's
not worth the overhead if I'm gonna get
shut down I'm just gonna go pop another
box I don't care to take the effort to
make sure it's encrypted so that you
don't see it on the wire so let's talk
about fails this is one of my favorite
sections of this we saw such a rapid
adoption of this that bad guys did
horrible implementations of it my
favorite though this isn't my favorite
but what we commonly saw with stuff like
this where they understand basically how
it works but they don't really
understand that you have to have a
worker ID so they just left it your
wallet your worker ID your email which
doesn't do anything so you have a
massive botnet that doesn't work my
favorite one though by a wide margin is
the open source minor where the author
decided to give you a generic
configuration file that had their worker
ID in it so you could see kind of how
this works normally they didn't realize
that you need your own worker ID to
replace their worker ID so they
distributed a malicious crypto miner
that was mining Manero for the guy who
wrote the open-source miner and
generating absolutely no revenue for
them this is the type of stuff that we
see time and time again one other thing
that we're seeing more and more of you
guys remember back in the days the
Toolbar supported stuff so now we're
seeing more and more what we'll call
freeware that offers things like this
like hey would you mind installing an X
Mr client to help support this awesome
software product and just like back in
the day check the box don't check the
box you still get the XM our client
installed on your system
shocking I know what we're really gonna
end up with is the days like this again
this this is where we're headed with
crypto mining I'm sorry to say but it is
everywhere it is going to remain
everywhere it is going to be delivered
in any way you can possibly imagine
because it generates a massive amount of
money
bad guys took an economics lesson they
realized that what's this is bulk payout
thing I don't want just only 2% or 3% of
the people I compromise to actually pay
me and I get one lump sum payment why
not just move to a recurring revenue
model this way I can slowly make money
over years as opposed to having to
compromise a hundred boxes and maybe get
three people to pay a ransom off of it
so this is one of the biggest questions
that we get our miners malware so a lot
of this goes with the way that these
miners are delivered right you have to
understand how what was the intent I
mean I don't know about you guys but my
typical methodology for installing
software is not to write an obfuscated
macro and pull it off the internet and
install it automatically that's not how
I install my software
I mean teach their own but that's not
really how I roll uh and in an
enterprise environment this isn't even a
question it's malicious if you don't
explicitly allow it it's malicious it's
not supposed to be there it's against
policy
there is no reason unless your company
really wants to make use of those spare
CPU cycles to generate every last bit of
money they possibly can
it's not allowed and I got to tell you
we saw so many examples of people that
were obviously installing miners on
their desktops at work to try and
generate money I mean it it's a trivial
amount of money but people are just like
hey all it takes is one sysadmin that's
like hey I got access to all this
in the data center they're not really
active at night maybe I can run a little
script on the side to generate a little
we've seen that as well that's just kind
of the nature of this yes that's exactly
it it's like the Ronco of threats set it
and forget it this stuff is going to be
around for a very very long time and
there are lots of ways to go about
detecting it
like I've been said the network traffic
is probably one of the best it's just
always there right you're always gonna
have users especially in enterprise
environment that start opening tickets
saying stuff like my system slow or I
can't get to this internal website
anymore or I can't do my job because of
this or that you're gonna see systems
that are running at 100% CPU a hundred
percent of the time which is not normal
typically you'll see all kinds of the
techniques that Edmund bro-up walked
through where you have registry Keys
getting dropped in different scheduled
tasks coming up in ways for them to
establish persistence in general unless
you are at home and you really want to
mine Manero for your own benefit
consider it malicious because you're not
putting it there why would it be
legitimate it's one of the biggest
questions that we have and I love to end
with this this is just kind of a a
snapshot of how horrible and how bad
this is gonna be so they had some
Russian nuclear scientists working on a
top-secret nuclear program that decided
you know you know what we're gonna do
we're gonna take this super top secret
supercomputer and figure out how to
connect it to the internet so we can use
it to mine Bitcoin think about that what
yes because everybody's gonna try and
make Manero because everybody sees
cryptocurrency in the news all day long
and they're how do I get on that how do
I make that money I got to make that
extra dollar it's like their own version
of a side hustle anyway so we're always
doing stuff like this there's always
ways for you to follow the the content
and the things that we're driving we do
webinars and white papers and blogs and
talks at conferences and get newsletters
and videos and everything you can
possibly imagine so if you're interested
in this kind of stuff you like threats
you want to learn what's going on on the
threat landscape feel free to check out
all the content will probably have some
time left anybody have any questions
yeah whatever is worth the most money
that they can make the most money off of
it it's whatever is gonna be the highest
value so if one cryptocurrency starts
taking off that still has the same
privacy
that's a sig resistant you're gonna see
them move to that or for some reason
something happens with the value of
Manero crashing out you could see them
just replace it with something else it's
really around what's private what can I
do anonymously and what can i generate
the most revenue around so it's kind of
hard to say considering we all know that
cryptocurrency values are all over the
place from a day-to-day basis other
questions going once going twice ah yes
yep yep absolutely yeah I mean we've
seen some attackers try to like pop
commodity boxes in mind Bitcoin but
that's just because they didn't
understand math right but in in cases
where they know that there is a ton of
system resources available I could see I
could see that yeah yeah yeah most most
of the time with these attackers they're
going for the largest pool of potential
victims and that's people with desktop
computers laptops stuff like that what
organizations typically use yeah we have
also seen them chaining multiple coins
together where they'll be mining Manero
and they'll also mined - and and and
they'll just drop like a ridiculously
long string of various commands to keep
it running to try and mind as much as
they possibly can from a revenue
perspective anybody have any other
questions yeah
yeah well usually when I talk about this
I bring that up that the way that
enterprises are largely impacted by this
is from employee loss of productivity
hardware failure because your hardware
is not designed to run at 100% CPU 100
percent of the time and the electricity
thing is actually a really big deal I
mean it may not affect you much if
you're just popping a couple of desktops
but if you get one of those worms in
there and it pops every server in your
data center you're gonna be generating a
massive amount of electricity I mean
they say today Bitcoin mining alone is
responsible for using more electricity
than the entire country of Ireland so I
mean it's it's bad and it's getting
worse the power aspect of this is going
to be continue to be a big big part of
the problem eventually yes it depends on
where you live right that's that's why
certain areas are so popular for mining
because electricity is cheap yeah we
gather data through a lot of different
ways I mean there's all kind I mean as
far as like samples are concerned a lot
of it is either active exploitation
they're generally just using open-source
miners so there's no it's just an
open-source miner that's wrapped and
delivered in some malicious manner right
so it you can gather stuff from email
you can gather stuff from honey pots you
can gather stuff from end systems
there's a plethora of different ways you
can gather data around this yeah there's
also a ton of public repositories if
you're just looking for malware like rip
apart so there's no shortage of samples
for this anywhere yeah they're
everywhere yeah
so we this actually brings up an
eight-way crypto currencies in general
or this type of stuff I mean you could
but all that's gonna do is make an
adversary move cuz there's new icos
coming up every single day so as long as
there's currency there they're just
gonna if you shut one down they're just
gonna jump to another one and jump to
another one as far as the actual botnets
though we have seen them get quasi shut
down by some of the pools some of the
times they do it in interesting ways
like hey you know we have this massive
botnet that's generating millions of
hashes per second we're gonna shut it
down by not paying out any more we'll
take the CPU cycles but we're not just
we're just not gonna pay the bad guys
anymore
we have seen that a couple of times some
are better than others other ones
completely shut them off when they get
reported any more questions now all
right good questions thanks a lot guys
thanks everyone
[Applause]