okay hi everybody hi audience oh my god
welcome to Circle City Khan good to see
everybody so I know it's getting late in
the day and people are ready to have
some delicious food later on tonight so
thanks for coming to our talk the
network Night Watch and our talk is
about terry pratchett's discworld in a
relation to InfoSec so who are we this
unit you all know me as mutant on that
guy with the weird avatar that just
doesn't show up on the tweeters who
people talk to when you never actually
see most of the time don't worry about
it she's the one who's cool no he's
really cool it's like a blacksmith and
stuff it's awesome I work at a company
called Drago's I do differ in industrial
control systems
I also punch a lot of things and fight
to voice swords
yeah and we're both giant geeks so
that's why we're here today we're here
to be giant geeks with you so um I'd
love to get a show of hands how many of
you have actually read any Terry project
please please please please please
that's not bad it's not bad alright so
how many of you are here for the
Pratchett but have no idea what InfoSec
is okay because if that was the case you
know that'd be kind of Awesome
but we are not that big of draw yet so
why are we talking about a fantasy
author today at an InfoSec conference
other than the fact that we're giant
nerds
first of all everybody familiar with the
overuse of art of war as a teaching tool
for cybersecurity raise your hand if
you've seen art of war quotes in a
security talk you just saw one like two
hours ago so you should be raising your
hand
we love you kripp dia and honestly not
everybody has actually read art of war
who claims to have or understood it or
really comprehended the lessons that it
teach teaches in relation to information
security and modern technology to be
honest it's usually just used for a
quote mine for whatever people have to
be talking about other than the art of
war that's no fun but as we saw in this
room a lot of people have read Discworld
discs roll is brilliant satire it's
really got a lot of lessons about
security and about modern technology in
of course a fantasy setting it's
wonderful dour British humour and about
as dry as a desert but a lot more fun
it's pretty great
and there's a lot of great lessons in
that in that anthology of books that we
can use to apply and teach InfoSec and
that's what we want to do here today is
take some of those fun quotes in that
fun fantasy environment and show you how
you can relate them to teach about
InfoSec and teach Blue Team and Red Team
security and it will give you some
better sources to mine from pep up your
breath pep up your own presentations a
little bit yeah definitely
so for those of you who have not heard
of Terry Pratchett or Discworld I'm
sorry but I'm not sorry because you're
going to go home and read some good
books you're in for a lot of fun so well
we got the disc to start with it's a
flat earth and it's on top of four
elephants which are on top of the turtle
that flies through space makes sense
right okay most logical thing you've
heard of an information security
conference right okay and there's a lot
of it yeah there's a lot of it so if you
don't understand why we're talking about
this particular intellectual property
today it's really famous I'm sorry if
you haven't heard of it it's it's your
retreat though you might have seen the
movies on PBS lake or on the BBC yeah
for decades 41 novels like dozens of
games video games tabletop games and a
few movies
we've left some out if you disagree with
our choice of which ones to focus on
come find me in the bar later buy me a
drink and then you can tell me what you
think should have been there
definitely sadly the author Sir Terry
Pratchett who was knighted for his
efforts in writing this massive
anthology of satirical fiction books
passed away in 2015 he was a terrific
nerd he was a wonderful computer geek as
well as a D&D geek fantasy and science
fiction geek he wrote other things other
than Discworld including some books
about hacking so just a lot of fun
wonderful person we have a cast of
characters don't worry if you don't
recognize them all the author himself is
making a cameo here points if you can
spot him so there's some characters
there's major groups of characters that
comprise this anthology of books and
each of them is kind of representing
some foibles and modern life it's a
satire again of modern life and
basically there's there's a few major
groups that you can group the books into
we start with of course the witches
witches oh we do we do start with the
witches yes we do oh I'm sorry I'm sorry
right oh yes you need your hat I'm much
better hats are important as we will
find out later on yes
hats are very important but yes we start
with the witches there are wonderful
witches we also have we have the city
watch so of course being a fantasy
environment there is a town there's a
big city and it has thieves and guilds
and everything you'd expect in any kind
of D&D or Lord of the Rings kind of
environment and they have a very
disgruntled City Watch who tries to
guard the city against all kinds of
interesting threats and a very very
let's say world query and then commander
Sir Samuel vanes pharmacist who tries to
handle security in this fantasy city
volumes is the ultimate blue team er but
we'll talk about that later well we also
have the anthropomorphic personification
of death that she didn't hear that Ben
didn't plan to hear that in an into a
sect cost today yeah the Ender
anthropomorphic personification of death
and he always speaks in all Kappa
letters and it's a good thing I've had a
bad allergy this week because otherwise
he's gonna do the dust quotes it's gonna
be great anyway it'll work next we have
the wizards and the wizards live in
ivory tower academia to an extreme yes
they're very talented brilliant wizards
but they mostly care about avoiding
meetings and food and sometimes they get
lost on the way to their own offices and
then there's other people of varying
levels of savoriness yes favor enos most
of them are the nice people and the
people who rob them so so we built our
fantasy world here again flat earth
riding on elephants on the back of a
turtle flying through space producing
they totally makes sense alright so
again let's go back to why we're talking
about this these particular characters
in their foibles the way that they
interact with others they have certain
lessons that we can apply if we choose
to to information security and it's a
little bit more entertaining it gets
people's interest a little bit better
than this digging up old dusty something
through again okay so let's start with
the blue team and lessons for those
various characters in terms of defense
of security the witches the witches are
a great bunch usually the ones that you
run across in the Discworld books are as
me wet wax and nanny aughh they're
intense pragmatists they're very
practical as opposed to the other
outlandish fantasy characters they're
the ones who are making sure that babies
are born that goats are taken care of
when they're ill you know they're the
ones who are going from house to house
clipping toenails of old men so they're
the ultimate pragmatists and the
hard-working defenders and honestly they
have a lot of very solid understanding
of psychology in other terms
she'd long bit long ago been resigned to
the fact that people expected a bottle
of something funny colored and sticky
it wasn't the medicine that did the
trick though it was in a way the spoon
masquerade how many of you have had
people want to buy blinky boxes and
thought that the blinky boxes did
everything for you when really it was
just that the impression of something
impressive something boffo something
fancy and shiny that did most of the
work for you we also have it can't go
around building a better world for
people only people can build a better
world otherwise it's just a cage so we
have an intense desire as security
people especially young security people
to take over everything that happens in
our enterprise and try to build a secure
Enterprise when in fact our job is to
secure a business that is doing business
things with a business model and a
mission statement related to how they
make money
how they produce products how they
function in as an organization we are
serving them we can't create a secure
environment in a box we have to create a
secure environment within all of those
constraints otherwise we have a
maddening situation for our end users
and they'll just find ways to evade it
it ain't about us ultimately but the
reward for lots of work seemed to be
lots more if you dug the biggest hole
they just gave you a biggest bigger
shovel Shepherd's crown yeah you know
the reward for a job well done
is more work there's never an end to it
if you're really good at your job yeah
oh not much more to be said about that
oh yeah no this is garbage
yes she believed in shiny wands and
magical amulets and mystic runes the
power of the stars well grainy weather
acts in cups of teeth dry biscuits
washing every morning in cold water and
well she believed and granny weather
acts so the very very most basic level
of security people we have a temptation
to trust our vendors and as he mentioned
previously those shiny boxes we have
vendors who come in with these beautiful
sales pitches it's a
you plug this into your network you're
going to detect all the apts and we know
with experience that that isn't true it
takes human effort many long hours going
through logs building signatures tuning
our IPS systems and our own training and
our confidence in ourselves to detect
adversaries ultimately it is down to us
it may not be about us but it's what we
did about the human beings absolutely
good old vibes Vimes is without a doubt
my favorite character in the entire
corpus and I do mine you know I bet I
know that one said volumes who watches
the Watchmen me mr. pessimal ah but who
watches you your grace said the
inspector with a brief smile I do that
to all the times of vines thud so when
it comes down to it if you think about
it it's our users trust in us we have to
watch ourselves we have all this
hilarious level of access to the
corporate locks and keys and strong
boxes but if we aren't trusted with that
if we don't keep a close watch on
ourselves to make sure that we are
worthy of that trust well what's the
point we'd hardly be security at that
point we'd just be another group of
users with pretensions what did he think
he was doing the job of course the one
that's in front of you Night Watch so an
infinite response there is a great deal
of triage it's the same with a lot of
different security roles where you're
dealing with incidents and high-pressure
situations with customers with your
fellow employees with your management
there comes a point where you're
exhausted and you're working on things
at 2:00 in the morning when you've been
working on a CTF and you're intensely
frustrated or you've got seven different
things running at work when you're
auditing something where you don't know
how you're going to cope and really what
it comes down to is your training and
your drilling of your activities in
advance so that when it you want
really exhausted and you're stressed out
and you're in a total panic mode you're
able to think about this is step one
this is my playbook this is what I do
first this is what I do second this is
what I do third I do the job I'm not
gonna panic about it I know my tasks and
I'm gonna progress through them in a
logical order because I've trained and
I've trained in a train for this the
worst thing that you can do is nothing
it's not we have a job to do
we can't just shine it on and let it
wait until tomorrow as security is
something that needs to be done and it
needs to be done expeditiously so even
if we aren't sure of the exact correct
course of action to take we should do
something something to make it at least
a little better now we've got the
Wizards which is oh yes bureaucracy
incarnated they are a total mockery of
bureaucracy and of the problems in
academia the good things too but a lot
of it is very strong satire in terms of
the problems in universities how hard it
is to be a researcher how hard it is to
be an educator and the challenges that
come up in that because they are so
caught up in their ivory tower to an
extreme some questions should not be
asked however someone always does how
does it work
I said a chancellor must Ramallah
the master of the unseen University this
was the kind of question that Ponder's
Stephens aided almost as much as how
much will it cost they were to the
hardest questions of researcher ever had
to face that would be from the science
of this world has ever been asked one of
those two questions as part of their job
how much does it cost and how does it
work especially by somebody who's not
particularly technical and keep your
hands up if you like those questions
exactly it's a it's a a challenging part
of our job again to recognize that we're
part of a business and we come to these
conferences and we're surrounded by
security security security technical
works etf's new exploits new research
and then we go back to our business and
we're caught up in what's our budget
this year are we gonna have to hire new
people how are we going to hire them how
are we going to train them how are we
going to implement this project with
which is being resisted by our finance
department and it's just an unfortunate
reality we have to wrap our heads around
I mean we love doing the sexy fun
technical stuff that's part of computer
hacking we love thinking through those
challenges but sometimes we have to
think about the the responses to those
two questions that we're going to have
to give to our management to our
leadership to our customers in a way
that they can comprehend not in just a
way that we can understand as technical
people so that's an innate part of our
job and it's something that well it's
uncomfortable to us sometimes we have to
accept
it's called accountability not the phone
ability writ polly scratched his ear the
man was right of course you had to have
some of the buggers around and there was
no getting away from it personally he
avoided them whenever possible as did
the rest of faculty occasionally running
the other way or hiding behind doors
whenever they saw him soul music in
reference to students originally in
reference to students but I'm pretty
sure all of us have felt that way about
users at least once unfortunately well
you have to have them around otherwise
what is there to secure not much we have
no purpose without our end users and the
businesses that we are supporting and
securing much as we would really prefer
not to deal with them sometimes they are
the job that's our job you get your
death voice ready
maybe you should go ahead and read the
first death quote what in the harvest
hope for if not for the care of the
Reaper man
it's really scary does a good death wait
it's only because I've had this I'm so
glad you're having an Alaric Noah I'm
not feel better so anyway that's kind of
an oddball quote to think about but in
reference to this it's death is a very
misunderstood character in the Discworld
books he is a pretty decent guy who's
just doing a nine-to-five well a 24 by 7
by infinity but same difference and he
has friends he has family and yes he has
a very nice horse but he's very
misunderstood in that he's doing this
job that nobody wants him to do and he's
there and everybody dislikes him because
he's the one who interrupts their fun
who's ever had an experience like that
in InfoSec you've been the person who's
had to interrupt somebody's fun you've
had to block a website you've had to
tell people no you can't install that
program and they're like oh security we
hate you you know like I hope at least a
few of you have been through that
because I certainly have but bringing
things to an end is part of our
necessary function it's the duty it's
what we must do we are there because we
care about them yes and we really need
to express that to our end users to that
yes you think that we're vile and awful
because we're telling you no but please
understand this is why we're doing it we
have a responsibility to secure the
environment and we have the peril of
being totally misunderstood in technical
environments too because we're the ones
who tell people no that's one of the
important reasons for us to network and
connect well with our end users the
auditors flood fluttered anxiously and
as always happens in their species when
something goes radically wrong and needs
fixing instantly they settle down to try
to work out who is to blame hogfather
so the auditors and Discworld are in and
of themselves as sort of supernatural
force and are entirely external to how
everything else works the parallels with
more standard auditors should be fairly
obvious they were very obvious
ratchet I think but this particular
quote is is more about well blame I mean
who hasn't felt at least the urge to
point the finger at someone this is your
fault this is your fault this is your
fault
although not to get to aphoristic but
every time you point a finger you've got
at least three penny pointed back and
that's what's deeply flawed about the
auditors and the Discworld books is they
they their eventual undoing is that they
are deeply flawed and they are so caught
up in whose fault is each problem that
they and trying to make things uh turley
perfect that they're unable to do their
job and they disappear from existence
because they can no longer properly awed
it if you put a large switch in a cave
somewhere with a sign on it saying
end-of-the-world switch please do not
touch the paint wouldn't even have time
to dry it's true that's from the thief
of the time it's very true and in fact
in that book there is a large switch on
the wall that says please do not touch
and yes somebody presses it but anyway
there is a real problem with alert
fatigue in our in our industry we give
users tonnes of prompts we give them UAC
prompts we give them bitna and prompts
we give them antivirus prompts we give
them carbon black prompts we give them
prompts for everything our patch
management systems don't open the
attachment we keep telling them things
like that and we keep giving them yes/no
boxes and eventually to get their jobs
done to go back to that business
functionality they just start hitting
yes to things even when it says do you
want to infect your computer they're
still gonna click yes because they're so
incredibly trained and so frustrated
with our operations in security so
that's something it's a point of caution
we have to be really careful to again
build those good relationships with R&D
and users to try to avoid that the
important thing she decided was to stay
calm there was always a logical
explanation for everything even if you
had to make it up
so an incident response
again we come back to that triage
concept of we're working in very high
pressure long hour situations where
things are stressful and we're exhausted
and full want an answer right now we
need an answer right now or it's your
job or your life and the best thing you
can do is stay calm keep in mind that
there's always an answer even if you
don't see it right away when you're
doing your hunting you're doing your
triage and you're doing it your incident
response and your time lining out and
trying to find that initial point to
pivot off of even if the answer is just
close enough you start somewhere and
there will be a logical answer so stay
calm and keep looking for that initial
point to start and then start looking
for evidence looking for evidence
looking for evidence looking for if
you're on the red team start looking for
you know the next point you're gonna
pivot to the next way you're gonna move
laterally there's always going to be
somewhere to move to stay calm and be
logical algebra said madam proud but
that's far too difficult for
seven-year-olds yes but I didn't tell
them that and so far they haven't found
out said Susan thief of time so how many
people have had someone come up to them
and say I'm just not good with computers
and they've given up this is the
opposite of that if you don't tell
people that something is complicated
something is sophisticated maybe they
won't catch on until they've already
learned it it does work sometimes I've
seen it work I have in fact tricked some
people into learning things in the past
you are smarter than we know and then
sometimes they're smarter than they know
they're almost always smarter than they
now if you keep what they know out of it
good point all right so let's move on to
the other citizens of ankh-morpork and
the Discworld no it's not here shall I
sometimes the truth is arrived at by
adding all the little lies together and
decide deducing them from the totality
of what is known going postal kind of an
inverse of the famous Sherlock Holmes
quote which is so cliche I won't mention
it right now going postal by the way is
one of the books that everyone thinks of
the hacking book in Discworld this is
pretty much going to be the only mention
you see of it if you start with a
Discworld book it's a great one to start
with because it's all about social
engineering and hacking right it's
wonderful but anyway you don't
necessarily have to start out with
completely accurate information if you
put everything you have together
sometimes you can see a common thread
and it may lead you to what the actual
answer genuinely is once you're down to
it headquarters had even started an
Employee of the Month scheme to show how
much they cared that was how much they
didn't care all right so I assume that a
large number of us have worked for
megalithic corporations and large
organizations it can be a hard you know
a hard nut to crack you know working for
one of those companies and having
wonderful technical skills and a
wonderful community here and then moving
into an environment where you feel like
nobody actually cares about what you're
doing and all I can tell you about that
after years of experience is try to find
those small communities and try to make
an effort and make things better for the
people around you you can't necessarily
be the star employee of your company and
it doesn't really matter much or mean
much necessarily if they call you the
star employee what matters is that
you're making a good impact in the
company and you're making more
importantly a good impact on the people
who you interface with on a daily basis
he was a responsible authority and
people could use terms like core values
at him with impunity making money so
whenever you end up in an organization
that you stick with for some time you
become a part of that organization and
people will throw phrases like that at
you at some point and that's when you
know you've become thoroughly ossified
into the business you really have two
choices at that point you can run away
screaming and become a consultant or you
can be screaming and become a consultant
or you can stick with it except that
people are going to throw horrible
phrases like that at you on a regular
basis and learn how to be management of
a sort and learn how to help the people
around you again instead of worrying
about those relatively minor things that
are part of working for a big
organization all right so we're gonna
move on to lessons for the red team
yeah all right so we moved back to the
widgets ah you do have a brain after all
of course it is boffo yes a good name
for Bako indeed the art of expectations
show people what they want to see show
them what they think should be there I
have a reputation to keep up after all
winters mess so a lovely part of the
witch's again is their ability to
socially engineer people and maneuver
people how they need to be maneuvered to
make them better when they're sick or
they're getting themselves injured or to
help them make practical life decisions
and so much of what they do has nothing
to do with magic a lot of it is just
midwifery and care for the elderly and
you know fixing injuries they they are
the pragmatic fixers of and defenders of
society common Society and something
that a lot of them recognize is the need
for something they turn fossil has
anybody who heard the term bothell
before other than the candy how many
have heard pretexting it's the same
thing okay so the concept of boffo is
that if I put a scary-looking skull on
my desk and it's from you know the novel
will be store down the street people are
gonna get a certain impression of me
right if I outfit my whole room in black
and I wear this hat and I put some
spooky music on some theremin stuff and
people are gonna come in there and
they're either gonna be like what's
wrong with you this is hilarious or
they're gonna be like you're kind of
creepy in a hard hat with a clipboard
no one on the jobsite is going to come
anywhere near me exactly so boffo is
not necessary not necessarily functional
props but things that influence people's
perception of you things that actually
perform no practical function but you
use to influence the way people perceive
you so as he says in a social
engineering engagement that could be a
clipboard it could be the way you dress
you know if I'm wearing this dress into
a business people are going to treat me
much differently than if I come in
wearing jeans and a rival et shirt or if
I come in wearing a work uniform if I
show up in a military uniform
people are gonna their impression of me
and how they relate to me is gonna
change drastically and all I'm the same
person all I'm doing is changing my
clothes it's the story they have in
their head for that outfit that they
then apply to you every trade every
craft had its hat
that's why Kings had hats take the crown
off a king and all you had was someone
good having a weak King and waving to
people hats
had power hats were important which is
abroad which is more of an extension of
the previous concept but as a personal
note people don't know me without a hat
it's weird but people won't recognize
without a hat they expect to see the Hat
when they expect to see me it's a
strange concept buy hats and the other
accoutrements of your particular role
play in and of themselves an important
role in establishing who you are to
people and why you're there so again in
social engineering and pentesting and
this can be digital digital and physical
if you present yourself as a you know
marketing person from another company
and you do it well people are gonna
interact with you in a certain way if
you're sending a phishing email they're
gonna interact with you and again
another way if you present yourself as a
CFO of a company and if you send an
email from what's up at gmail that's
going to be received a lot differently
than John Smith at Corp co.com so
understand what your hat is and how its
reflected how its reflected in the way
that you interact with
people for example when an obvious
innocent sits down with three
experienced card sharpers and says how
do you play this game then someone is
about to be shaken down until their
teeth fall out I love this scene it's
probably one of the best social
engineering scenes in Discworld Granny
Weatherwax is a very serious pragmatic
witch but at one point in the money
their total one point in the books
they're totally out of money during
their travels her friends have been
tricked out of all their money by card
sharps and being scammed you know cards
up the sleeve whatever and she goes in
and she plays a game of cards to get all
their stuff back and she wins first of
all because she sees through all the
tricks that they're playing and second
of all because she's a wonderful social
engineer she's incredibly good at making
herself instead of like a regal witch
looked like a old feeble old lady so she
comes in and she acts like a doddering
old lady and she says Oh would you teach
me how to play cards Deary and she
presents herself as incompetent and weak
and feeble and old and she takes them
for everything they're they're worse she
takes all their money and she and her
friends ended up having to flee the
Train because they're they're going to
get chased down by these angry card
sharks but it's a lovely scene and it's
a really terrific example of social
engineering but there's an obvious
lesson here for red teamers don't be
afraid to portray yourself as weaker or
less competent than you are I know from
personal experience doing red team
engagements if I act meek it's
unfortunate and I carry a few coffees
you know I can get pretty much through
any door you know I'm just the shy you
know wearing kind of dumpy frumpy
clothes and I've gotten my coffees in my
hand people let me in anywhere that's
not a gender specific thing you know act
nice acne core inexperienced and people
will be happy to show you around and
show you up because they think they're
better than you if you're weak you're
not a threat exactly
you aren't evaluated as well
an assassin a real assassin had to look
like one black clothes hood boots
and all if they could wear any clothes
any disguise then what could anyone do
but spend all day in a small room with a
loaded crossbow pointed at the door
Night Watch and this is why red team is
always complaining about those scope
things because nobody really wants to
have to deal with what amounts to a
dedicated threat with any arbitrary
surface they want to have at least some
chance of it's going to be along these
lines so if you're going to have a paid
assassin come after you it would be best
that you could recognize that it's going
to happen and perhaps even some of the
circumstances of it happening but as
you're learning as a blue team it's
better to have a scoped engagement
because otherwise you are going to be
cowering in the room at the crossbow
because before you've done any tuning
before you've had any experience in
being a blue team which is arguably not
a great time to have a pen test but
based on your experience level you want
to have a scope that's appropriate for
that experience you actually get
something out of the pen test if you
have somebody come in black box and say
use your best apt simulators to break
into our environment they're gonna break
in you want to do the best you can at
the skill level you are at right now
because we're all on the same team and
we're all trying to secure the
environment but no one thinks anyone is
really going to try to steal the Scone
would you try to tell me that four
guards sitting in that little guardhouse
on a 12-hour shift will be alert all the
time that's enough for a hand of Poker
fifth elephant so this is a point in
time where commander vibes is evaluating
the security around a very precious
royal item and he looks at the security
theater and of course we've all dealt
with security of theater and are in our
daily lives and in our lives and
security and he sees that there's a
bunch of guards sitting around the thing
that's being secured and he's like
there's four guards who have seats there
and they can chill out and they can
probably play cards when nobody's
looking there's just enough people who
they can have a conversation they can
have a meal it's security theater
nobody's actually being secured by this
so something you have to recognize it's
a good offensive security people a
person a good red teamer is to notice
when things are the portrayal of
security rather than effective security
sometimes effective security is a silent
security you don't see it's not the
things that you see overtly right away
and that's a gotcha for a lot of
security people because they look for
the obvious detection and the obvious
sensors and they see that and they
totally miss the more subtle detection
that is in place in environment so be
able to recognize security theater and
it as a deterrent versus actual
detection people who used oh this is the
Wizards were on to the Wizards so we're
back into academia people who use magic
without knowing what they're doing
usually came to a sticky end all over
the entire room sometimes moving
pictures so how many people have heard
of some kid who just goes and grabs Kali
and starts hacking nobody nobody's ever
heard of somebody just like going out
there with Metasploit and screwing
something up oh you guys have a really
talented friends that's a WoW so it does
happen it does happen and you really
need to know what your tools do before
you do them with the tools there's going
to be side effects of various kinds you
might end up ddossing the production
network by accident you might
accidentally nmap some kind of IDs
network and that always turns out well
well there you go
a sticky end all over the room case in
point the bringer of bad news is never
popular especially when it's on an empty
plate yeah we're back to that this
methodology again I always seem to get
thrown so yeah part of working in an or
any organization of any size is
everybody can get breached
everybody's vulnerable to getting
breached no matter how secure you are
how no matter how well prepared and well
trained you are somebody can compromise
your network whether it's due to a
contractor or some vendor device you
would never really spent the time of
scope or even a node a in something like
a more advanced act or nation state or
whatever
everybody's vulnerable to that you're
gonna have a bad day in your career in
security especially if your blue team if
your red team - and you have to go to
your customer and say here's all the
things that I found on your network that
are vulnerable you have to learn how to
present that news because a lot of us
are tempted to especially as red teamers
build this amazing reward of all the
things that we owned like I found XYZ I
found 50 vulnerabilities in this server
and I was able to exploit three of them
and I was able to find vulnerable
firmware on these devices and you build
out this great list and you feel like
you've accomplished so much and you're
gonna present it to the customer and
then the client hates you they hate you
because you've just told them that
they're doing a terrible job
that's terrible PR that's a terrible way
to relate to people yes you need to
provide that information but at the same
time don't serve it on an empty plate
don't be like how I owned your network
it's that's not how you approach that is
it is a professional again everybody's
on the same team red team and blue team
are on the same team you're trying to
secure a network you're not trying to go
look at all the hacking I did in your
network lol you suck that's not the
point
so try to make it palatable I definitely
tell them about everything that you
found but do it in a way that's
constructive say this is how you're
gonna fix this this is good that you
have upgraded all your systems past 2008
server
but you still need a patch for the last
six months we see you're making progress
but we didn't get in over here where we
got in last time yeah that's important
show progress make your feedback
constructive don't bear bad news on an
empty plate don't be like here's all the
things that you did that suck because
it's not going to go over well with for
you it's not gonna over well for them
they're not gonna want to have you back
you're not gonna be able to help them
the gun there are those who say that
sherry should not be drunk early in the
morning they are wrong unseen Academical
it's five o'clock somewhere that's all
there is to be said about that one okay
we'll have to play this one off yes you
can't give her that she screamed it's
not safe it's a sword said the hogfather
they're not meant to be safe she's a
child shouted Crumley it's educational
what if she cuts herself that will be an
important lesson so death is
substituting for the father Christmas
like hogfather in this particular book
and I don't know I kind of look at
educational malware like that there's a
lot of various neutered or less neutered
viruses trojans and stuff wandering
around yes they are dangerous but if you
go and do something foolish with them
and own yourself quite thoroughly that
will teach you quite a few very valuable
lessons and sometimes that is the way to
learn those lessons and on the
educational side when we're dealing with
end users as red team or blue team again
they're not all stupid they can learn
things we want to do it in a safe
environment don't necessarily hand them
a sword but let them learn about
malicious things understand what they
are let them make mistakes and explain
to them reasonably and courteously what
they did wrong try to educate them try
to let them learn a lesson when they
make a mistake instead of going you're
wrong one demerit you're fired
you know that that's not the point we
want to try to educate people and we
live in a dangerous world and InfoSec
people's credit card who said their
credit card stolen in the last couple
years
uh-huh I mean it happens to everybody
and we shouldn't be
again it's not a demerit system we're
not going like you suck we we don't want
you in our in our employment anymore
it's it should be a learning experience
every time and it should be constructive
and it should be polite
am I really a bastard am I just really
good at thinking like one making money
who's ever asked himself that question
as a as a yeah especially red teamers
and it really is important to understand
that distinction you're gonna have some
time in your career when you're doing
red teaming and you're doing offensive
engagements you're gonna have that
moment when you're like hold on a second
I'm getting really gleeful about like
pointing this environment and that's not
the point of this like you do need to
have that introspection every so often
and say okay I am enjoying this and I'm
glad that I enjoy my work boy am I still
being constructive and I'm still doing
something that's useful to security
because a lot of things we do are
robbing people taking their stuff like
that's our job we're doing it under
contract and with disclaimers and we're
simulating a lot of things but we're
still going through the motions of
robbing people taking their money taking
their stuff and you get really caught up
on that he forgotten the ancient wisdom
take care when you are closely observing
that you are not closely observed making
money so this is one of those situations
where if you're breaking in some place
are you sure that what you're doing is
not being observed are your tools
techniques and procedures making their
way out to hands that shouldn't have
them at that particular point in time or
importantly are the back doors that
you're installing in a client system
secured so that some other guy Russia
China Mongolia East
who cares whatever is themselves going
to take advantage of what you've just
put there it's a very important lesson
to keep in mind that people are watching
who's watching and how are they watching
and when you forget to update your
pentesting box and you're sticking it on
people's networks and speaking of which
a weapon you held and didn't know how to
use belong to your enemy and this goes
for blue team with sensors IDS's
vulnerability scanners are a huge one
that at advanced adversaries love to own
because simple ok I have all your
vulnerability scans and now I have a
point to pivot off a bit has permissions
on your computer's SIM boxes yes
external network connections and weak
credentials but it goes for Red Team 2
in terms of offensive computing do you
honestly go in there and patch your VMs
how often are you patching your VMs that
you're doing on-site engagements with
are they vulnerable what can you do with
them what could the blue team or a
adversary who's actually compromising
the network do with your with your point
of presence so you have a risk from the
blue team there and you have a risk from
external adversaries who they're
actually trying to do damage the
wonderful thing about the golden suit
and the hat with wings was that if boys
took them off he wasn't him anymore he
was just a nondescript person and
unmemorable clothes and had a face hoody
vaguely think you've seen before going
postal
so this is on one hand kind of the
corollary of the importance of hats from
earlier but also on the other hand this
is a job this this is not for many folks
a whole lifetime of constant inspection
and cracking things you can have this as
just a job you can take off your hat
when you get home sit down and do
whatever you can be not the apt all the
time there there's other things in the
world try them out
in summary art of war is awesome it's
amazing and I know there's gonna be
people on Twitter like railing on Me
Later like art of war is awesome and yes
art of war is a phenomenal piece of work
and it's a wonderful way to talk about
military and strategic engagements it's
it's useful in a lot of context to
explain things
however it's used overused way overused
cliched corrupted setback words quote
mines dusty as all hell it was written
in like the year what 350 or something
like that
guys there are other books so we are a
lot of geeky intellectual properties out
there and a lot of them are very very
smart another one that comes to mind is
Hitchhiker's Guide I could do this same
talk with with the Douglas Adams books
easily yeah and I bet you can think of
some - there's very smart very sardonic
satirical pieces of intellectual
property out there that have great
lessons for InfoSec and we should be
using them to teach these lessons to
young people and to people who aren't in
our industry they're wonderful tools and
not everything has to be the pinnacle of
ivory tower without at war they're fun
to read they're very fun to read so I
hope that some of you go out and buy a
profit book or listen to it on audible
on your way home or something so that's
all we have
I'm hackster pancakes and I'm you know
if questions comments anybody want to
chat about practice
[Applause]
nope nope they don't have any comments
about practice that's okay we love you
anyway
have fun at the con great to see y'all
[Applause]