and chairs and general chairs they they
don't get any money right so they dude
is very cool for free if they do it for
service to the community and in order to
appreciate and to show the appreciation
for the work they do there used to be a
tradition several years ago that the the
the president of the ICR was handing
over certificates to the certificates of
appreciation to the general chairs and
and and the program chairs then we there
was a certain gap in this tradition so I
would like today with this conference
because I think it's a good starting
point who's to start again with this
tradition so we have the largest chess
conference ever we have a new journal
model that we use if a new publication
model with it let's say a record of
submissions we have a record of accepted
papers so I'd like to use this
opportunity to restore this tradition
and so I would ask Peter and Elena to
come to the stage so Eastern sorry
Selina so so I'm not the president of
icier but I'm the chair of the steering
committee and so I I also feel to be
able to hand over certificates so I'll
do that tonight so on behalf of the ICR
in fact so that certificate of
appreciation reads so the International
Association for Cryptologic research
gratefully acknowledges Elena Bhutan for
her contribution to the world line
community on cryptographic hardware and
embedded systems through her role as
January chair of chess 2018 so thanks so
much
[Applause]
[Music]
so I have another one here so the
International Association for
Cryptologic research and gratefully
acknowledges Peters father for his
contribution to the worldwide community
on cryptographic hardware and embedded
systems through his role as general
chair of chess 2018
[Applause]
[Music]
and as it's not so this is for the war
and we also have something to drink so
this is a : wine so I'm told this is a
local speciality
so I'm handing over this
[Applause]
[Music]
all right so Peter and Elena so they're
responsible for the place the food and
of course we also have a program and so
I'd like to ask the program chairs to
come to the stage
Danielle pH and material Ava
[Applause]
[Music]
so we decided when was it actually one
and a half years ago or something like
that or they almost told me well yeah so
we decided to switch to the terminal
model right so they already accepted to
be PC chert they at the time of
accepting you didn't know that we
changed the model right so they accepted
being program chairs and they thought
that there will be only one deadline and
then afterwards at some point I sent
them an email you know would you also be
willing to do three and to do a
completely new model and then and change
everything and I'm very glad that you
have been the first PC chairs to do this
I think you did a tremendous job so we
have a very successful number of a
playoff of submissions and and accepted
papers so thanks a lot for this
excellent job
[Applause]
[Music]
so it start with Daniel so you meanwhile
know the text probably but there is a
slight change at the end so the
International Association for
Cryptologic research gratefully
acknowledges Daniel page for his
contribution to the worldwide community
on cryptographic Carter and embedded
systems through his role as program
chair of chess 2018 thanks so much
[Music]
and we have yet another one so the
International Association for
Cryptologic research gratefully
acknowledges mature leva for his
contribution to the worldwide community
on cryptographic hardware and embedded
systems through his role as program
chair of chess 2018
[Applause]
[Music]
so in also for the program chairs
something to relax afterwards when the
conference is over so they have a good
glass of wine and with this I'm already
at the end of this introductory part so
I will hand over it actually to the
program chairs too so that they can tell
you what they did as they work so that
the number of submissions that they
received and the effort they had in
getting all the river we saw reviews
from from the PC yeah from the PC and
sub reviewers okay
[Music]
what do they make
as you see the ramp session is
professionally handled and we are happy
to have such a good start I will
continue like that that's a good start
okay so the IAC our guidelines say we
should actually do two things they tell
us what to do the first is that we need
to present entertaining statistics this
is a quote and the second is to present
the best paper Awards and actually we're
not going to do either of those things
it turns out because we decided to
present the best paper award before the
best paper presentation on Wednesday
morning and neither matura I are very
funny I didn't even know what statistics
are actually let alone entertaining
statistics so we just say that's that's
not going to work out so why lie there
probably but maybe that's not such a bad
thing because well Stefan already took
the points here you know in a way but
this is a special year for chess it's
the 20th edition I didn't mention that
actually which is a good landmark
although that's making me feel quite old
now but also a record-breaking edition
in almost every respect the most
important work from our perspective I
guess the most important thing was that
Archie this is the first edition under a
new hybrid publication model and we
wanted to spend maybe a little bit
longer than normal telling you about how
this model looks and how it worked out
in the first year because I think this
is important for everyone really so the
move to the new publication model was a
decision taken by the chair steering
committee I guess in 2017 mid 2017
sometime and essentially this follows
the lead of FSC who transition to the
transactions on a symmetric cryptography
so we now have all of the publications
or the papers accepted and published
Chas appear in the teachers journal
there's a few important differences
there for versus chairs ours was the
first is that this is a gold open access
journal so the publications are
available to everyone almost immediately
in a way as soon as they're ready so
actually if you go to the teachers
website all of the papers are available
now and word before the conference in
actual facts one of the important thing
to point out here is that actually it's
in everyone's collective interest to use
the papers published there as the
definitive source because in certain
like it or not the sort of reputation of
the journal in it essentially depends on
on this somehow so we sort of encourage
you to do that the journal is managed by
BA command in particular Tim who acts as
the managing editor very effectively the
other difference is that teachers
teachers teach as journal operates for
submission deadlines per year so this
means for review processes per year
although in this first year we've only
used three of those because getting it
started there was a sort of leading to
that obviously so if chess happens in
year end actually the teachers
submission process starts in U n minus
one so that the previous in order to do
the work associated with those four
review processes obviously we have
reviewers and in particular the teachers
editorial boards who act as the analogy
to the chairs program committee which is
led by the co editors-in-chief which
again is the analogy of the chess
program chair as was then that the
review processes themselves are
relatively the same as they were there's
just four of them for example they
include a rebuttal phase still but one
major difference is that there's now a
richer set of decisions that the editors
and I guess the reviewers can can arrive
at so rather than just accept and reject
papers for instance we now have the
option to have a major revision which is
essentially saying this is an invited
resubmission so an example of this would
be where the reviewers have identified
something that they want to champion but
it's also they've identified some
deficiencies such as is not ready for
publication quite quite yet overall the
ethos is that were able to take these
papers that may have been rejected
before and hopefully improved them so
that they're subsequently accepted and I
think
the statistics bear out that that's well
okay so now a few words on this year
editor editorial board so which we could
before program committee so while
selecting and sending invitation for
program committee we try to take several
criteria into account of course the most
important criteria is expertise to cover
all the topics in the range of chess but
then we also try to balance and bring
diversity so here are some criteria so
in the end our program committee was
composed of 53 members plus the two of
us and there was so like a majority
coming from Europe but I guess that's
that's a bias which reflects as well the
the audience and probably the
publication as well we have also tried
to balance academia versus industry that
we have some bias toward academia we
also attempted to to balance two other
criteria which are experience and gender
so we try to promote young people and
manage to absorb a third of people who
had no experience in is VR PC before and
I think it worked well and we also try
to balance gender and maybe we did a
poor job toward that but it's still an
improvement over some previous years and
and we think we should try to push that
forward so here is some overview of the
program so we have like for the fourth
edition I think a challenge this year
that started
in few months ago and that so you'll add
some wrap-up of the challenge later in
the during the recession we had two
parallel tutorial session and Sunday and
two invited presentations when from
academia this morning and another one
from industry tomorrow morning
three poster sessions so the first one
was just before the recession and the
two next one will be during the coffee
breaks the morning coffee breaks for the
two next day when Rome session which
will start very soon 15 technical
sessions with 47 paper presentations
which make 25 hours of fun which is a
pretty dense program but hopefully we'll
make it to Thursday okay so now a few
statistics
so first submissions and accepted papers
over the years since the beginning of
chess so as it was already said this
year has new record in terms of number
of submissions and accepted papers so we
can also observe that we have TD
acceptance rate around 25 percent for
now more than 10 years so although we
have a new model we didn't actually try
to constrain the this acceptance rate
and it naturally keeps to around 25
percent so now if you look you wise so
we are fearing not having enough
submission to the first issue but
actually we received a third what is a
good year for chess usually so that was
a good start we got the same number of
submissions more or less to the second
issue and
double to the sole issue in terms of
acceptance rate it was also it remained
around 25% more or less and we also add
about 20% of major revisions or each
issue
okay so regarding region wise statistics
so we also see here strong involvement
of Europe in terms of number of
submissions but even more in terms of
accepted submissions if we look at the
country write submission so most of
those missions are with affiliations
from different countries then we have
[Music]
the leading submitting countries our US
and China and then the leading
publishing countries our European
friends Belgium and Germany so then if
we look at the statistic in terms of
number of authors we see that we have a
kind of Gaussian with a mean a bit
higher than 300 per submission and per
accepted submissions there doesn't seem
to be a bias with the number of authors
per submission and if we look at some
other statistics and possible bias we
see that we had we have about 20% of
submission that code at least 23 members
and which achieve a bit higher
acceptance rate and also long papers
although we just received a few achieve
a better acceptance rate and and what
what is important here is to emphasize
that major revision achieve like very
good acceptance rate so it means it's
it's it's paying to take into account
the remark from the review
to resubmit your walk so when brexit
happens i have to find somewhere new to
live and probably a new job therefore so
I decided to become a data scientist
which in my mind at least means sort of
just writing Python scripts and saying
something interesting about the output
so we tried to fish around for what
datasets we could feed into my Python
scripts and yeah this is kind of the
outcomes I guess the first is we I think
this I've seen this happen a lot so I
guess it's sort of traditional is that
this is a plot of the submissions over
time and what you can see well maybe
maybe this wasn't obvious but the
majority of the submissions come in the
last two days before the deadline so
probably sort of two-thirds of the
submissions in the last two days let's
say so shame shame on you for being so
disorganized perhaps if you look at the
so these three deadlines the middle of
the deadlines fall just after the
Christmas vacation and interestingly the
sort of trajectory the curve there is a
little bit steeper so everyone's
enjoying their Christmas vacation and
then suddenly suddenly they're rushing
to submit the papers perhaps we looked
at the earliest submission which was
twelve days before a deadline that was
an issue too so if that was you
congratulations on being so organized
everyone hates you now the latest
submission was seven seconds before the
deadline
[Applause]
so if that was you congratulations on
being so lucky or so brave I'm not I'm
not sure which we also did a a word
clouds of the titles of the submissions
so I'm not sure there's so much
interesting to say about this but it's
sort of reassuring that hardware and
attacks are popular in in in the
submission title so this is all the
submissions are overall if you look at
the submission titles are accepted
there's not so much change necessarily
but apparently papers about long papers
are popular that the reason for this is
that it's sort of mandated that if you
write a long paper then long paper
should be in the title of your long
paper this is this is where I failed to
get the job as a data scientist I would
say and then the last thing we did was
do a histogram of number of characters
in the reviews and also in the title of
the papers so the reviews I think is
interesting because what you can see
this is the left hand side the right
hand side of that plot shows that
there's a few reviews actually bordering
on sort of 10k of plain text so I mean
those reviewers either really loved or
really hated that paper that they review
but I think this is kind of a good thing
to say about the effort that some
reviewers put into the process and we
should I think be thankful for that the
mean is that yeah around 2k or so what's
interesting about this is that the
minimum review length which was 109
characters is actually less than the
maximum title length of the paper
which was a hundred and forty-two
characters and again with my new data
scientist job hats on I was a bit
panicked about this what was my bug in
my Python script
I mean hundred and forty two characters
title is is impressive I think the next
obvious step is that you put the whole
type whole paper in the title and sort
of avoid the the page limits um somehow
but I looked into this and actually and
actually the reason is that yeah this
very short review wasn't a negative or
bad review in actual fact they were just
so impressed with a major revision they
said this is all fine and everything go
through so in actually fact this this
this this isn't the problem or joke that
it first appears fortunately for
everyone I think so the last thing to
say is that hopefully it's obvious that
a huge amount of effort goes into the
well everything that you see in here at
chess 2018 we wrote a detailed preface
to the teachers 2018 edition that tries
to capture everyone involved most of
whom are listed on the slides here but
we'd like to sort of finish off by
really saying thanks a lot for all their
hard efforts and hopefully you can give
them a round of applause alongside us
[Music]
I didn't think it would be that light so
I can now officially undeath Li declare
the rump session open have fun
[Music]
okay a few words about the ramp session
the wrong session is the first time that
either Danielle and I are sharing a ramp
session and we came to realize that this
is a very long process so we had the
submission up in the submission side for
that and we received 22 submissions
including some that came in unofficial
challenge channels side channels
Danielle says we the committee reviewed
all of the submissions and we had to
decide which one to accept and which to
reject
fortunately for Americans we decide to
accept all American submissions we also
accepted all other submissions so we
have 22 presentations today the
presentations are time limited look at
the ramp session program to know how
long your presentation is if you don't
know you're where you are presenting now
is the time to look if you run over the
time you will have to compete with a
gong so with this we start the first
presentation go ahead all right thanks
everyone I'm honored to have been
selected from Canada I guess we fall in
the Americas
we've made the the cut so I'm gonna talk
to you about embedded hardware
blockchain and concrete security metrics
to help you understand this important
problem I'll give you a quick motivation
some background on Hardware blockchain
and then looking at embedded hardware
blockchain and the differences here so
blockchain solves a lot of problems
primarily if you have money and you need
to give it to IBM they'll take your
money for the IBM blockchain platform if
you have voting booths you can solve
that if you want to go to a thousand
attendee conference like what is Chas
doing here you can go to the blockchain
conference and I'm sure it's great and
you can also do cool stuff like store
cryptocurrency on vaults and you might
have a really great one like this ASIC
vaults are not to be confused with the
you know the more robust vault maybe
that sponsor this conference here let's
say ASIC vault does this great idea it's
a thousand times stronger security and
if you read through it what you see is
they've hardware-accelerated the key
derivation function it's a thousand
times faster to do the key derivation so
there's a thousand times better but you
can also do really innovative things
like if you pay ten euros a month
you only get a million rounds of the key
derivation if you pay 15 years a month
you get three million rounds in the key
derivation so there's a lot of
innovative things blockchain is opening
up for us here the bit Phi another
really great wallet was unhackable which
didn't work out very well so you can
read that that's a John McAfee kind of
sponsored product so it's a little
interesting to read about all right so
that's a quick motivation why we want to
care about blockchain so what is
blockchain so blockchain really has two
aspects to it so the first part is the
block so this is your standard concrete
masonry unit block available in this
case from Canada so we're using Imperial
measurements here you also have your
change so this is your standard number
for straight length chain there's a lot
of variations of chain and blocks that
you can you can go through but there's
your basic setup here how you might use
it so we have a voting system we need to
secure this this is a big problem
someone could steal it so if you had a
very heavy block you could chain it to
the voting machine and it would be very
difficult to steal so these are really
very useful products that you can have
you the interesting thing is although
it's in October you know this is the the
history is very wrong in this because
everyone credits the initial blockchain
release but in fact several months
before that you can go back and check
this out this is legit in May 2008 H
Simpson had an implementation of
blockchain used for defensive purposes
so this is the real motivation behind
blockchain it was sort of stolen
popularized later but this is the real
history of it here alright so this is a
full sized blockchain what about an
embedded blockchain so we're talking I
Oh te automotive all sorts of stuff like
that
we need something smaller something that
we can embed in our product so this is
an example I have one here of like an
embedded blockchain right so this is
what you can
fit in your product itself now we're
very lucky the security aspects of this
actually scale very well so we can use
research from existing threat models on
full-size blockchain so you can attack
the chain or the block as you might
expect and there's quite a bit of
research so you have the concrete
masonry unit the CMU there's a lot of
research around what is the compressive
strength how much you know weight can it
hold there's a problem though and
security people will recognize this it's
done in laboratory conditions so it
doesn't take attackers into
consideration and we have attacks like
attacks during transport so if it's
incorrectly transported unlike in this
diagram here the device is weakened and
when you install it the security level
is much lower than you expected on salt
usage is a huge problem so salt will
corrode both the chain and salt during
the curing process of the concrete or if
mixed in with the water will really
weaken the concrete also there's new and
novel attacks that are rarely considered
so you know hammer drills liquid
nitrogen people have access to home
depot are all new attacks that aren't
really rigorously considered in the
literature so yeah this is just me i I
know people here are really into
hardware security and I thought I'd
bring this kind of feel to your
attention because it builds on a body of
existing work you know started by H
Simpson as I said and it's been scaled
down to the embedded blockchain there's
a lot of work needed on security threats
understanding what these threats are and
how we might move forward in the
embedded blockchain space
[Applause]
[Music]
good evening my talk is the new sick
sick us caller multiplication algorithms
nowadays I received the one question
from my bus
how to obtain a secret key in crypto
systems usually I answered the my burst
we obtain the secret key by Philip
Oxitec were site Aeronautics then my
boss after again what is the size terror
attacks Wow
so I answered I explained the site
general tests through the real world
scenarios because my boss and to not
understand sighs general test scenarios
so sweet Marilyn has a good a special
special a sweet Marilyn have a special
characteristics the first is the
appearance and the next sound this sound
is the size channel information then by
boss is understanding the size general
text in the site owner of this there are
two characteristics categories firstly
is the Singletary subject and the nest
party trace the attacks especially
single traits or texts were pretty cool
and powerful then multi traced attacks
against the scholar multiplications the
oldest and the well-known attack is the
simple power analysis this analysis is
applicable for binary method which is
the origin of a scalar multiplications
the next and you
single trace or texts called the
collagen attack and the beat keep it
dependent attacks also apply applied for
or other scholar multiplications eg TSA
has been used in various protocols
produce and the crypto libraries and
other some solutions such as fiber and
the pro chains our company also have
good solutions the phyto and the
proteins but each EDS they have had some
attack results because the scar emulsion
is the main operations of ECDSA my
company we our team already designed the
new scholar multiplications this column
operation named triple SM GSM this
scalar multiplication already completes
serious serious security honours and the
experimenters equation is DVD come in
University and third-party security
evaluation through the aspect conference
this paper will be present here and two
weeks later in poco our scholar
multiplication has Heather has three
main features first our accommodation
and to not any scholarly coding method
and next our column allocation only and
use the point addition operation even
though all other scholar multiplication
algorithms use both addition and
doubling
operations finally we use only the same
size of a secret parameter
but we did some big public parameters in
the aspect conference our paper only
described the countermeasure for random
scholar multiplication algorithms but
now we prepare the extended paper with
countermeasure for children's color
multiplication and the optimization
message that's all thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
okay well good evening everyone I'm
Helen and Honshu from rhombus I also
happen to be the security standing
committee chair of an organization
called
a risk Life Foundation so this is a very
simple call to action risk five for
those of you who don't know it it's a
Foundation which is a nonprofit
corporation controlled entirely by its
members it has today over 115 member
organizations that includes companies
universities but you can also join as an
individual and the goal here is to drive
forward the adoption and implementation
of the free and open risk 5 instruction
set architecture
I repeat free and open very important
this was authors among others by David
Patterson who you might know as a last
2017 Turing Award winner and so today
there's two documents available for
everybody to look at and to use and to
build processors with an open source
five instruction set architecture as
well as a draft privilege spec so with
the word privilege we're getting a
little bit closer to the theme which is
security and so earlier this year the
foundation had the good idea to create a
dedicated security standing committee
which means to them security is now very
important and they're looking for people
like all of you to join and help us
build something secure on top of this so
it includes today already 30-plus
members and the security committee you
can read the names here they're all
public on the website but please keep in
mind it's not easy to build secure
processors and everything so far has
always been proprietary this is the
first time in history that a foundation
was created and they were trying to do
it openly all right so so far what have
we been able to do well we've started by
creating two subgroups one of them is
gelling with cryptographic extensions to
the instruction set architecture so
looking at things to officially run a
yes or a public-key cryptography what do
we need to add to those instructions to
be able to run faster and the other one
has trusted execution environments
we also collaborate with the privileged
architecture aspect group and we look at
vector extensions and how to achieve
security on top of this so with the
advent of I'm looking at you
specter and meltdown foreshadow etc this
is the perfect time to join it's the
perfect time to try and do it the right
way from the beginning how to build open
source secure processors is the question
the answer I don't know quite yet but
please help find out all the risk right
foundation adopted specs are open and
free again and so this is a call to
action please join us help us make it
the right way from the start and with
that you can read a couple of press
releases and announcement on the risk
live website I've tried to identify the
right color of t-shirt but I couldn't
quite pick between yellow and orange
this time so yeah it doesn't exactly
match the color but it doesn't matter
okay join us thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
yeah hello everybody
Eli and I would like to make a short
announcement you already heard that it's
20th edition of chess and next year will
be the 10th edition of cassette and it
will be in Darmstadt and yeah I think
yeah you also want to say something
about it so it's is anniversary in
Darmstadt the idea of course 8 is to
bring together practitioners and also
people from academia both on the
defensive and on the offensive for
attackers and designers if you want to
say it like this so this event is more
focused on fault attacks and
side-channel attacks so it is nice let's
say focused were more focused compared
with chess event the it will be in
Darmstadt the same place as the first
edition was deadline is December 1st and
yes we will have it we will have your
submissions reviewed and then we
hopefully have a great event thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
good evening today's my presentation
topic is something that is little can
often have great power
subtitles cubed dependent otech
unscalable duplication using a single
trace l decided analysis become more
powerful various countermeasures to
lesstm have been studied for example
count measures to eliminate patterns of
data depend on the conditional branch
statistical characteristic according to
intermediate value or interrelationship
between data have been studied
however the county major have been taken
into account for the secure design of
the kubacheck page although the
prohibits or directly loaded during the
check page since the private key bit
value is extracted and stored in the
variable the private key can be exposed
if the vulnerability is found to exist
to tell the conclusion first I can
extract
private key bits using a single trace
because the power consumption is related
to the DI value we can distinguish
traces of the cubed check pairs into two
groups depend on the qubit value we
refer to this attack as Kiba dependent
or take we consider binary scalable
application algorithms which are less
than two against s PA and DPA in
particular our target algorithms are
based on legal algorithms protected by
intermediate data randomization
therefore we suppose that an attacker is
ability to use a single trace
later the news numerous traces the first
experimental platform is a hardware
implementation on accessibility to a
people at the airport the second one is
a software implementation owner AVR
microcontroller we usually use power
consumption to
an electromagnetic traces we summarize
power consumption properties as follows
electromagnetic analysis is similar to
the power analysis therefore we describe
focusing on the power analysis there in
hardware implementations power
consumption in the qubit check paste is
associated with the Hamming distance
between two consecutive bits di plus 1
and di for example when the private key
bits are 1 0 1 1 power consumption is
associated with the Hamming distance
wonder one gel between two consecutive
bit areas in particular in Hardware
implementation of F's pls tanta regular
algorithms the operations are executed
in parallel so register to be obsessed
and the DI value or determined simulate
simultaneously
hence power consumption when checking
the DI value is also affected by the
Hamming distance between the laser
addresses using two consecutive loops
thus in addition to property 1 property
3 occurs in hardware implementations
this is our experiment result we
attacked the montgomery lopez de letter
algorithm protected by scalar
multiplication experimental results show
that the private key bit can be
recovered with over 96 percent success
rate using only a single power
consumption trace and electromagnetic
trace second experiments on software
implementation our target algorithm are
composed based on the cubic functions of
embarrass and open ssl here we
distinguish traces integrals according
to the Hamming weight of di as a result
see Chris Cobb it can be recovered over
ninety thirty percent success rate
especially if we attack power
consumption trace using the lucky G
associated with reference laser
addresses the success rate
is 100% thus we need to apply
countermeasure in this pace if you have
been questions lever to following
articles thanks for your attention
[Applause]
[Music]
hi some of you might be wondering in the
audience those Friday fit on an embedded
device any fold Elysium doesn t hope
suffer a cold bitter sack those Hardware
designs of code based schemes exist or
why no more may I present PG cz a
website created to store missed post
quantum candidates with regards to micro
controller designs hardware designs and
side channel analysis it's just an
example of the side channel analysis
page where we saw the information where
a reader can like be further pointed
towards so yeah as I said this is the
breakdown at the website so you can just
visit this URL and you can find all the
information about all the schemes that
all the informations that have been done
so far so far we have a lot of
representations of lattice based schemes
and some based on code based schemes and
as you can see there's a really
underrepresented classes here on the
other types of post quantum crypto
schemes and looking at nobody in
particular there are some more research
there's more research here that can be
submitted to the website so please feel
free all you need to do to submit to the
website is have a github account and
essentially do a pull request on the the
data table where whether it's hardware
software side channel analysis I'll be
notified of that and then I can accept
the pull request so if you need any more
information go to the website there's an
About section to follow to actually
submit your your research or you can
catch me here or semi anymore thank you
[Music]
okay so that concludes our first session
let's take a short break and be here at
9:05 so I was supposed to have one more
co-presenter but I don't see a manual
here so I guess I will start unless a
manual will come to the stage
okay so during the dinner this dinner I
was telling people that I'm going to
announce the chess CTF award tonight and
they were asking me okay but what is the
chest CTF so many people were surprised
I'm just gonna briefly remind you what
the chest CTF was about and in fact we
don't we did not have just one challenge
we had two challenges one was the
challenge where we published some traces
and people had to capture the flag and
then the one that captured most flags
world of winners by the other challenge
behind the scenes were actually a battle
between deep learning techniques that we
hear so much about lately and classic
side channel analysis and we wanted to
find out which of the techniques is more
successful in extracting keys so we had
two CTS and not one the first CTF was
sponsored by riskier so the one that is
with challenges and having the price and
we have here the first prize would be a
Nintendo for the winner and the second
competition looking at the state of the
art between the deep learning versus
classic side channel analysis is
actually sponsored by alia sure it's a
horizon 2020 project and we also had the
help of Google who hosted our traces
such that we you could download the tray
set in a timely manner so that being
said some quick stats because we like
stat so there were 58 players that were
registered for the CTF the city have
actually run for 70 days and we put out
there 35 gigabytes of data for you to to
mine there were seven rounds to this
challenge
we looked at key recovery for both
profiles and non profile challenges
there were three types of double three
tre set so Hardware death and G its
software AES engine and an RSA and you
can see how many submission we had
correct how many submission we had and
how many of these submission were
actually correct submissions now here
you see that we have a submissions for
both the classic profiling and deep
learning but in fact we suspect than
many of the submissions many of the
flags that were captured were actually
obtained with one technique and then
were submitted to both sides because I
think the players thought that they will
get double points but that was not the
case
and so we suspect that it is the case
because the the time stamp between the
submissions was very very short not
enough time to run a classic side
channel analysis and then run your
neural network so I'm not sure how
accurate the the distribution between
the two columns is second we also used a
model which for for taking the points
which was winner takes it all that means
that not only you had to solve the
challenges but to get the points you had
to be the first one who submitted the
flag so that was it so let's see who are
the winners to the first competition so
the first the third place goes to the
teams that are known as coder space 2018
I'd affixed zotkin and yeah a name which
is very hard to pronounce at the time I
when I made this slide this morning
because I submitted them on time I did
not know who the teams are so I emailed
them and said if you want to be to have
a public recognition let me know and I
will announce it so I only know about
the identity of one team and that is
either fix who is actually a damia a
security team that won the third place
so
let's give them a big and for the others
if if you contact me then I will make
sure you get something like this
certificate okay now the second place
actually they sold they were very to the
point they solved two challenges out of
the seven challenges they were very
focused and they submitted a flag for
these two challenges the first and this
was the AES challenges so they got a
total of a thousand and five hundred
points and the team that won this is a
GS jws but actually the members of the
team are here with us and mr. Werner
Smith cinder will actually get the
second prize
[Applause]
and now the winner of the challenge
mm-hmm of this Nintendo switch is the
team that solved actually seven of six
of the seven challenges they know they
submitted of the first flag for four out
of the six challenges and they got a
total of 3,000 points and the winner is
the hot eight team and for them the
price will be I will hand the prize over
to mr. Matthias Wagner who will then
hand it over to them
yeah thanks guys so this was my former
team when they were still working in an
XP but they all moved on for some
unfortunate reasons and this is really
huge and I loved the team I wish they
would come back but maybe they will at
some point so I will pass this on at
some point but only when they come back
thanks so much
[Applause]
so this is the the winners board and
then for the second competition we had I
told you that there is a competition
between deep learning versus classic SC
a well at this point in time the jury is
still out on who the winner is we will
publish so that the dataset that was
used for this competition will be public
for you all to try out and it would be
great if you let us know which one of
them works for you
so with this yeah this was the chess
2003 team before
proceed with the program this was found
in the catering room so whoever this
belongs to come find us it's right here
on the podium sorry
they're gone
[Applause]
[Music]
good evening hi i'm song engine studying
in Korea University
this time we talk about simple solution
onerous on plug-and-play continuities
distribution system this suggests that
we did it to consider citation analysis
even in quantum shakur system to
exchange the keys cyclically through an
insecure Channel
we usually exchange protocol such as the
payment or elliptically Pearlman of
course you can snatch in ciphertext in
this channel to prevent evil from snake
hisses matching action action to kdg
ongoing actively sochi area security
oboe qkd
is rising in quantum physics through the
fundamental theory over quantum physics
you can no longer snatchy or reverse
drop that quantum channel between early
symbol
qk d can warranty whether someone is you
it was dropping the channel will not
miss me this may seem on your or to
theoretical or listen to advance made
the qk d to leap out of the lab the
theropod project or to calculate a
network experiment you on qk d has been
problem in distance over 100 kilometer
will essentially china to launch the
mission to create a few additional
between china and austria however also
qk d g quantum secure we originally to
consider other weaker point right side
channel analysis in the qk system
document each main implemented in a
poppy j the time inside the channel
analogous
had already perform on website so the
constant trying acadia proposed a
program program play qk d system image
another provocative implemented
Jean they prevent timing attack edge we
all know we only needed to know one beat
children one in the secret key to
simplify the beats able to kinda bassist
- bitch - bassist means that we need to
know four kinds of state change in the
table to implement it is for kind ruble
0n one week in four kind of proteges to
a patent which depending on different
voltage this means like easy
we had an approach at open Oliver
vulnerability in the qkd system from
Professor Hall in Korea University as
expected we had we were able to obtain
four different trace that director Lee /
240 parent I will give it to someone we
also need to consider such an analysis
even can't even in qkd
[Applause]
it's a short announcement for the hiring
at i/o attacks I owe tax is a very young
palak to in start-up we so-called him
located at Silicon Valley United States
and multiple small task forces currently
distributed globally those small task
forces are being added into the core
team you know append-only and
distributed manner more like how the
auction works way way we are currently
building the next generation blocked him
platform for the IOT applications and to
power large scale and district
decentralized iot applications we're
currently hiring the software engineers
and the cryptography engineers is a
unique opportunity to use the use of you
knowledge in cryptography distributed
system and the game theory to build
something which has significant impact
for people's life please check our
website I owe tax law
for more information if you are
interested in our projects and would
like to take that other entrances please
send your resume to hello at the IO
textile thank you very much
a good evening this a short announcement
of the ECC 2018 ECC 2018 the sick 22nd
raksha from edited cryptography will be
held on November 19th to 21st at Osaka
Japan the second-largest city in Japan
the ECC is an added Rock shop dedicated
to the study of every curve cryptography
and related areas since the first ECC
workshop ECC has broadened is still
scorpioned a little cryptography unknown
covers a wide range of areas within
modern cryptography ECC workshop have
invited visitations only presentations
tend to give an overview of emerging or
established areas of modern cryptography
often combined with new research
findings the ECC workshop is accompanied
by a two-day autumn school on elliptic
curve cryptography postgraduate students
involved in this area the school will
take place on November 19th and 18th
just before the main workshop and here
is the list of the great speakers for
the workshop and a school and a
presentation title that will be
announced and the details of the
workshop is shown at the URL the first
point about generating
ECC workshop and the last one is an ECC
for this year and on the registration is
now open and the only board or registry
to see is applied until the October 9th
thank you
[Applause]
okay so this is also very short one and
Peter submitted it and put me on stage
but okay so I guess what he meant is
like if you're up for even more great
talks good food a nice company and above
all very smooth organization you should
come to our summer school next June
which is not 20 but sixth edition so I
guess we are doing pretty fine and the
challenge here is to click very quickly
on this link and to find out who's
speaking there and what's going on
thanks
[Applause]
okay I'll start with a small disclaimer
I'm going to show some things that are
quite ridiculous but everything is real
so my talk is about Tesla Model S and
specifically the Tesla Model S key fob
as you can see it looks quite simple we
have the entire PCB on left and exhale
pictured on the right it's a simple
microcontroller that communicates with a
transponder that stores a key so what we
found is that they actually are using a
40-bit cipher that accepts a 40-bit
challenge and he turns a 24-bit response
there's also no they also have no mutual
authentication in the authentication
protocol so we built a small 5.4
terabyte lookup table that allows us to
recover the crippling f4 key in two
seconds this is what they approve
concept while so it looks like so it's a
simple power bank I guess we get by
proximity to low frequency stuff and
your stick one to high frequency stuff
so we tested our attack on Tesla Model S
but we also found out that the system
was actually developed by bactrim which
also makes systems for McClellan gamma
and time if you happen to have a
McClellan please let me know
so we first notified Tesla about one
year ago and from June onwards this year
they are actually using new key fobs and
they introduced some software updates
that people that own a Model S can
enable to help stop the attack and your
musk hooves so if you would like some
more information we have a blog post up
on a website I will be doing the post
accessions from now on you can check us
out on Twitter there's an article on
Wyatt and if you happen to have a Tesla
Model S I would be happy to show your
live demo now we have a small video
[Applause]
[Laughter]
[Music]
okay so I'm John Kelsey I'm gonna give
you an update of what we're doing at
NIST so lightweight crypto
standardization you can see we've got a
plan to standardize some lightweight
crypto algorithms we made a call for
proposals that finally came out so you
can go look at our webpage and find the
call for proposals and all sorts of
other information and you can also
subscribe to the mailing list if you're
interested threshold crypto so this is
an area that we've not had standards in
before and we're looking at doing
standards in this so we have a draft mr.
that a nister is basically NIST speak
for a white paper so you know basically
a white paper on threshold schemes for
crypto and we'd like public comments so
if you have thoughts about this is an
area of interest of yours let us know
what you think there's also a comment
there's also a workshop in March and so
you can see all the contact information
here the pqc stuff is continuing a pace
you can see kind of where we are next
year we're going to have a workshop
we're gonna have the the conference
co-located with crypto so it's a good
excuse if you want if you're interested
in either those two come to both this is
already that the comment period has just
closed on this this is our plans to
basically to get rid of Triple DES as
much as possible if you have strong
feelings about this though we will still
read your comments so if you're in an
industry where getting rid of Triple DES
approval for Triple DES is gonna like
utterly screw you then please let us
know so we can take you into account and
you can see with the email address for
that 890 B it's come out as of the
beginning of this year the final version
we're we've seen we've found some bugs
and we're in the process of correcting
them this is something new that we were
able to do now is issue a corrected
version with errata that's not something
where you could revise the whole
document but if you found like a typo in
a formula you can fix it and so I'm also
giving a talk at Ft DC on on Thursday so
if you're interested
come listen to me and you can hear more
about 90 be the NIST beacon has now
switched over to a new format we've got
two organizations and diversity that de
Santiago I think is the not Chile and in
Metro which is the Brazilian sort of
Brazilian version of NIST or maybe if
you're Brazilian you think NIST is the
American version of them so this is you
know these are both organizations that
are have stood up beacons they're
planning to follow our our protocol or
our our format and there's a NIST are
coming soon that will describe the new
format and you can see you can find this
at this URL also v 186 a digital
signature standard this is under
revision soon that will be going out for
public comment so if you're interested
in this you probably are good digital
signatures matter for pretty much
everybody this is a good you know when
this comes out fairly soon it'll be good
to to get your comments in and one of
the interesting things here is moving
the elliptic curves to their own
document rather than having them as part
of the signature standard even though
they get used for other things and
that's it thanks a lot
[Applause]
hi my name is Christophe and this is a
serious talk so I won't be funny at all
and if I'm funny then it's an incident
and I want to apologize for that this
talk is about
sefa which are statistics ineffective
for the techs so suppose you want to
protect simple blocks as a call against
implementation attacks what do we do you
mask this stuff against certain attacks
and then you add some error detection
capabilities like multiple execution of
this stuff and see if the right thing
for it comes out and then you end up
with this piece basically so but it
turns out with the pop sefa you can
attack this beast using single thoughts
per execution of this stuff and what's
also cool about CIFA is that the effort
of the attack typically it does not
increase with the protection order or
the degree of redundancy so what is sefa
it's a union of statistical fault
attacks and ineffective fort attacks and
basically there exists two papers one of
them which contains the basic is
actually the last session of chess
conference and the paper which explains
why this stuff also works on mask
implementation appears at Asia trip so
if you are thinking okay it might be
hard and might be quite special location
to fought in order to mount asifa then I
have good news
so principle for this certain
implementation of mask es in software it
turns out if we can stuck by it zero or
always set a PI to 0 then around 70% of
the instructions susceptible to attack I
also have to point out that
we do not exploit any weakness in this
implementation or that this
implementations not weak the reason why
we have chosen this specific
implementation of masque
AES is that there are not many mask
implementations out there which are
publicly accessible and good and useful
so probably people should change that
and if you think okay always setting app
ID to zero is a quite hard task to do
what you can also do is for instance
flip from patrons having a successful
attack or set one bit to zero or always
randomness one bit or fill a whole pie
or set from PI to 0 or randomize one
part or even skip an instruction so how
does this thing work I do not have time
to tell you so if you want to know this
then you have to read the paper or to
come to the talk thank you very much
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah
so let's go back in time so everybody
knows this kind of computer
yeah that's ATM from 78 so would you use
that till now probably not maybe maybe
for fun but the crypto of that time what
is that
what would you use in 1978 for crypto
des will you use des now
yeah but the banks are still using this
so we want to be in that crowd do you
want to investigate this maybe not so
let's let's go make a jump and time so
we go 298 anybody remembers that kind of
computer I had one like that compact and
98 what would be the crypto down no yeah
we're still des but there was something
new coming up in 98 a yes contest
yeah yes yeah so there's a lot of
evolution but you see it's still yeah
it's not quite modern it's like some old
stuff but we do a lot of investigations
on a yes okay let's make another jump in
time I go to 2008 what happened in 2008
it was the start of the shuttle
competition so a lot of evolution and we
got to also a different model we're not
looking at pcs anymore we're now looking
at all the devices this thing this
blackberry then was really hot and I was
like this thing to have here you know
that was a start of permutation based
capital but would you investigate that
kind of stuff would you do research on
that I'll use that maybe yes maybe no
but that's that's the that's the modern
age do you want to know what this crypto
looks like in that age well then you
come to this workshop that will take
place and I think it's about a month
from now and Milano Italy so it's their
own permutation based crypto and we have
a number of speakers so you will
recognize first off the ball if we just
spoke just before me but there's a lot
of experts speaking about it and I
invite you to visit the website and
subscribe cheap in Israeli education
thank you
[Applause]
hi everyone my name is Jaguar ganya
until recently I lived in Brazil
Naiya work at ojos University in Denmark
so there was like a an upgrade yeah
thank you I have friends in the audience
so I don't want to turn this into
alcoholic anonymous style meeting but I
have to admit that for the past six
years I've been is likely obsessed at
about the insecurity of Brazilian voting
machines so the reason for that is a
hundred and forty million voters use
these machines every two years and they
have been in production for more than
two decades and this is a paperless
voting machine so there are no
meaningful ways to verify that the
results are correct so at chess 2012 I
gave up short a talk at the run session
about how he we hack at this machines
for the first time so we essentially had
to only do this to scan this across the
codebase so we break we actually broke
the vote shuffling mechanism to break
ballot secrecy of course and then after
running this we found this right and the
time stamp there was printed in an
official document that's kept for five
years you know for transparency reasons
so last year we did it again this time
we tried something is slightly more
sophisticated which was this
and then we found a cryptographic key
that allowed us after a few escalation
with other vulnerabilities to manipulate
the voting software so this was the key
we found the key protecting the file
system so we could actually tell to
modify the voting software to tell the
voters to vote for that Raider so which
could be a great present to Brazil I
think so I think the punch line in this
is for all governments and voting system
vendors out there elections are not
really a playground for your crappy
software get your together thank
you
[Applause]
[Music]
hi everyone I'm going to present today a
magical parallel variant of SIDS which
is a post quantum candidate and the idea
is to have a parallel version of it so
we present here a variant of the super
singular isogen e diffie-hellman is
protocol the variant will be run by
three characters instead of alice above
we will have Hermione's instead of alice
and running hairy
instead of mouth they learn the colberto
spell that transform us an elliptic
curve in two magical stones in an earth
into another curve so this is the way
that it works first instead of selecting
prime as usual we will select one prime
that has harmony in one side and hurry
and run in the other side so the way
that the works is is the following we
have three bases instead of two bases
one for her my only one for her you went
for wrong and then her Mahony works as
Alice will compute an ISO journey from
the base elliptic curve is zero and then
Ron will work out the si si th protocol
from his side and we'll carry out the
point of Harry then Harry will take from
the ISO Geneva are computed by Iran and
we will have this the second isogen e
and then they need to exchange oles so
hurry sends an all-too to harmony
Hermione does the same and then Hermione
ends her work in computes this elliptic
curve then Ron works again and then
hurry and finally they met here running
this variant of the SI dish
the H protocol
got mothers but noticeable acceleration
factor of about 10% in the best case and
sometimes we lose but these are variant
is really nice for parallel
implementations so if you happen to have
more than one core let's say two cores
or even better three cores then you get
an acceleration of up to sixty seven
1.67 acceleration factor so this is an
my on working work and we are looking
for new combinations of primes for more
Montgomery friendly primes and to
optimize a single core version of this
proposal thank you hi everyone
so in 2017 we organized this white box
crypto competition I called white box
and we it was actually a tremendous
event because we had like 200
competitors like nearly 100 submissions
so challenge programs were submitted we
are nearly 900 breaks and so it was
co-organized with crypto experts so we
developed the submission server the
server was hostage by tue and i was
sponsored by a equip csa and we thought
it was a tremendous event so let's go
for a second edition so what we'd like
to do would be to run an edition of
white box so again it will be about aes
128 with no external encoding and they
will still be this duo system of points
with strawberry points when you that you
can accumulate as long as you're not
broken and banana points strawberries
being converted into bananas whenever
the the challenge is broken and we still
would like to put some limitations on
the code size and execution time and so
on but there were some kind of feedback
from the community on the
like at some point fifty megabytes for
the C source of a challenge was too
small for some people was too large for
some others one second of execution as
the limit was either too slow or too
fast for some people so there is still
the slack forum so you can go there
voice your own opinions about what the
limitations should be and so the
tentative timeline should be so it
should last for about six months in 2019
so starting beginning of February maybe
and until an end of August but the main
problem is that we're looking for a
volunteer or a group of volunteers who
would like would be willing to actually
host the submission server so the
submission server was developed by crew
experts it's totally open source you can
find it on github and we would like also
to apply a few improvements so that the
second edition runs more smoothly I
would say compared to the first one so
if anyone is willing to do that please
contact me on my email address Thanks
[Applause]
good evening I'm the last one so I guess
I have no time limit so I've did some
work with a lot of cool people which I
will not enumerate because I don't have
so much time but they're very school and
cool in skilful so we've been working on
the cryptanalytic algorithm for her
lattices and we've made some progress so
just the core idea is that sieving was
used to be sort of a as a black box
function you give a lattice basis you
get the short vector and then you insert
it in the vector and then you always
start at the next position the core idea
we have is to view it as a stateful
machine where a lot of information is
kept inside and can be reused from one
ship to the next basically recycling a
lot of information to amortize the cost
where we have been working on
implementation it will be made open
source we have several save inside it's
highly optimized it's parallelized and
so for designing high-level algorithm we
made an interface in Python that make
your life a bit easier and with it we've
been able to break new challenges
we're about 400 times faster than
previous algorithms so stay tuned for
paper and an open source implementation
and maybe more records especially at the
BRE challenges for what why do you care
here our chests will maybe you need to
worry about any status based candidate
because of this the answer is not so
much thank you
[Music]
[Applause]
okay so that concludes the ramp session
let's thank the speakers again I hereby
declare the ramp session over
[Music]
[Applause]