welcome to the first session of the
morning and this session is going to
start with the best paper award yeah
okay so when we were putting together
the program we wanted to do two tweaks
to how the best paper award worked I
guess the first is we wanted to allocate
longer slot to the best paper in
recognition of that so this is sort of
halfway between an invited talk and a
standard talk I guess you could say the
second thing is we put the invited it's
we put the best paper award talk the
morning after the banquet that's kind of
a carrot to encourage people to come
along kind of glad that that's sort of
worked out there's plenty of people here
and the reason for that is that we also
wanted to give out the best paper Awards
to the authors before the presentation
rather than at the rump session partly
because that means they actually be here
so the best paper award for chess 2018
was voted for by the editorial boards as
you heard the other day we had 180 or so
submissions 40 or 50 or so of which were
accepted so this is a fantastic
achievement you could say so I'd like to
invite Martin and Emmet
Kenny's not able to be here on to the
stage to receive the orde
[Applause]
so we we also have a gift we weren't
able to locate any cold boots but we did
get some wooden shoes that's a pretty
bad joke but I'll take it anyway so yeah
we have three of these hopefully you can
take her can you sew myself in okay so
without further ado we'll hand over to
the session chair to start the session
thank you done so Amit is going to give
the talk
okay so yeah hello everyone today I'll
be speaking about cold boot attacks on
ring and module lwe secret keys when the
NTT is used to store the key yeah and
before I start this is based on joint
work by myself and my supervisors Martin
Albrecht and Kenny Patterson okay so
first of all what are these cold boot
attacks well they were originally
investigated in the literature at least
by a Halderman hotel in 2009 and the
attack basically involves an attacker
who has physical access to a victim's
machine and the idea is that there will
be some cryptographic secret key
material stored in this in the in the
victims memory so the attacker can eject
the memory plug it into their own
machine and then essentially taken a
reading of the bits and at this point
the attacker has two challenges of the
first is to locate the key material in
the memory and the second is to use data
remanence effects to actually recover
the secret key okay so clearly these
work on any encrypted graphic primitive
where there's a secret key stored in
memory so the attacks quite a general
one however the attacker we're modeling
here is an extremely powerful one so
it's one that has physical access to a
victim's machine okay so a few more
details on what Halderman
at all showed in 2009 while they showed
that there's this data remanence where
if you cut power to ram eventually the
any information in the ram goes towards
this kind of ground state as shown by
this decaying picture of Mona Lisa okay
what they also showed is that you can
actually slow down this sort of decay by
calling the RAM chips to extreme
temperatures so even if you just use
compressed compressed air for the
cooling you can actually achieve a less
than 1% bit flip rate
towards some ground state and after some
period of time so I'll speak more about
what this ground state is in the next
slide but you can also reduce this bit
flip rate by using more extreme methods
of calling such as using a liquid
nitrogen okay so yeah so all of this is
basically based on the fact that when
you cut power to ram eventually the bits
in the mem
we will decay to either a zero state or
a one state in fact they'll be regions
that decay to zero States and regions
educated to a one state and once again
you call the RAM to extreme temperatures
to slow down this takane yeah and before
I move on
when I say RAM what I really mean is D
Ram here okay so now we move on to in
examples suppose we have a 12 bit secret
key in the victim's memory so this is
the true value of the secret key while
the idea is that the attacker comes
along he they freeze and extract the RAM
and then perhaps they take this kind of
noisy reading of the secret key where
some of the bits have flipped and at
this point the attacker needs to detect
these bit flips correct them and correct
them in order to recover the secret key
okay so eventually if the attacker was
to leave the RAM at say room temperature
or any sort of temperature eventually we
reach the ground state of these regions
of zeros and regions of ones okay so in
addition to these standard bit flips
that go towards the memories ground
state there are also these retrograde
bit flips that actually go away from the
memory ground state
however these occur on much a lower rate
of row one where Row one is roughly 0.1
percent according to the experiments of
Halderman tatar so in addition to this
I'll be using row zero to denote the
standard bit flip rate
okay so whenever we launch a cold boot
attack a standard sort of assumption is
that the number of bit flips we'll see
is the number of bits in the key that
we're attacking times the average of the
two rates and implicitly in order to
make this assumption we're assuming that
half the bits of the secret key are in
the ground state okay so before I move
on whenever I give you a bit flip rate
that contains two sort of numbers the
first one's going to represent row not
and the second one's gonna represent row
one okay so what's kind of known about
these colby attacks on popular
cryptographic primitives well for DES
and AES it's been shown that there are
extremely effective colby attack
even a fairly high bit flip rates of
more than 50% and just to give you some
background I still tell how these
attacks sort of work or what they take
advantage of well four dozen AAS these
attacks assume that not only do you have
the secret key stored in memory but you
also have a number of rounds of the key
scheduled sword in memory so essentially
taking advantage of this kind of
redundant information between the key
schedule and the actual key you can
actually launch very effective cold boot
attacks on DES and AES a similar story
holds for RSA where it's been shown that
you can correct flip rates of roughly
forty percent in the standard direction
in just a few seconds so once again this
attack uses redundancy in what's stored
in the memory
in particular if RSA is implemented
according to the pkcs1 standard you
don't just get the secret key in memory
you also get some other functions of the
secret key in memory and more recently
there's been some work on Colby
attacking entry and it was actually
shown that at fairly low bit flip rates
but still the realistic ones that held
them in a tile showed were feasible you
can actually recover entry keys in a
matter of minutes towers using fairly
straightforward enumeration techniques
okay so next to motivate our work well
as you've already heard throughout this
conference misses running this process
or competition and many of them are
actually based on the lwe problem so a
natural open question in in the cold
boot area is to ask are there effective
cold bit attacks on some of these lwe
contenders and what we actually look at
is attacks on any scheme that uses an
entity to store its secret key in the
memory ok so next we get on to defining
our cold boot problem and in order to
understand the problem we first need to
understand what lwe key looks like or at
least what the LW keys that will be
attacking look like so in actual fact
we'll be focusing on ring and module lwe
which
two of the perhaps main efficient
variations of LW used in nist used in
this proposals and in order to define
their keys we need to fix a polynomial
ring and the polynomial ring we'll be
using is going to be the power of two
cyclamates because this allows you to
use an entity okay so in other words
we're going to be fixing the ring R sub
Q where this ring is essentially the
ring of polynomials whose coefficients
are integers modulo Q quotient it out by
X to the n plus 1 okay so these are
degree at most n minus 1 polynomials
whose coefficients are integers modulo Q
so for ring lwe the secret key is simply
one of these ring elements or
polynomials however for modular lwe the
secret key is a collection of d of these
polynomials however there's an
interesting trade-off between D and n so
what module lwe schemes tend to do is
use a smaller ring dimension n at the
expense of using a non trivial D so for
example Kaiba which is a module lwe
based scheme uses N equals 256 and D
equals 3 whereas the ring LW based New
Hope uses a much larger ring dimension
but we only have one polynomial making
up the secret key okay so how are these
Keys stored in memory for some of these
lwe proposals well it's been kind of
said before that number theoretic
transform or ntt speeds up
multiplication polynomial multiplication
from roughly N squared operations to n
log n operations so in order to take
advantage of this kind of speed up it's
often the case that polynomials in the
secret key will simply be stored in the
MTT domain so that you can perform very
fast multiplication without needing to
apply an entity to the secret key every
time you want to do a polynomial
multiplication ok so next we can
actually define our cold boot problem so
essentially what we want to do is to
decode a noisy entity or recover this s
from STL
where I stole that is the MTT of s plus
some error vector Delta so we're
actually going to be making assumption
throughout this talk and that is going
to be that we have Kappa bit flips where
Kappa is much less than in and of course
you don't want to make this assumption
in general however for the purposes of
our attack we actually require this
assumption okay so next giving more
details on what this error vector Delta
looks like well remember Delta
corresponds to bit flips
however Delta is also represented as an
integer modulo Q vector here so
essentially what this means is that the
components of Delta are not small when
considered as integers modulo Q because
they can they they're associated with
flips however if we assume a low number
of bit flips then Delta's components
should have a low Hamming weight when
written in some binary signed digit
representation or bsd are so briefly
what what is a bsd are well it's
essentially a binding representation
where each bit has a sign attached to it
and we really need the sign digit
representation because there are bit
flips that go from 0 to 1 and bit flips
I go from 1 to 0 okay so an example of a
BSc r7 is 1 0 0 minus 1 since 7 is 1
times I take away 1 and this example
kind of highlights that
bsd ours are not unique because we could
also have the binary representation of 7
so this is kind of something that we'll
be ignoring for the purposes of this
talk but if you want to see more details
on this please read the paper okay so
once again if we assume Kappa bit flips
we would assume that we're essentially
assuming that the bsd are of dulcis
should either a Hamming way of kate a
Kappa sorry and whenever I say the BSD
are Delta what I really mean is the
concatenation of the BSD are of its
individual components okay so the final
thing to be said about this entity
problem is that s has small coefficients
which is essentially a standard design
choice in that all of these ring and
modular lwe
schemes use okay so just to come back to
these these examples of Chi brand-new
hope
in actual fact Khyber consists of three
relatively low dimensional ring elements
so in order to recover a form Chi over
secret key we have to decode three noisy
entities in a relatively low dimension
where it's a new hope we had to decode
one noisy entity in a relatively high
dimension okay so finally we get on to
our attack and our attack splits into
three main components the first is a
divide and conquer
sort of strategy to reduce the dimension
of our problem and essentially what this
this component uses is that we can
compute an entity using fast Fourier
transform techniques okay so the second
component that will describe is how to
work a solution up from one of these low
dimensional instances all the way up to
the solution to our original problem of
decoding the noisy entity and finally
I'll speak about how we actually solve
these low dimensional instances that we
get from dividing dividing and
conquering okay so first of all how do
we divide and conquer well if you recall
the NTT is essentially a Fourier
transform over the integers modulo Q and
the form explicit formula for the NTT
that's used is given on this slide and
you actually see that um there's this
isn't quite analogous to a Fourier
transform because of this factor of
Omega to the half J in the summoned and
yeah so nonetheless even it despite this
difference we can still use fast Fourier
transforms fourth FFT techniques to
quickly compute an entity
so essentially what that means is that
we can write an entity in dimension m in
terms of two entities in dimension and
over two and so on okay so what are the
formally that allow us to do this well
they're given by the two equations in
the box here and the main thing to take
from this take from these formally is
that taking the sum and difference
of the ice and I plus and over tooth
components of an n-dimensional NTT gives
you something in terms of the ice
component of an N over two dimensional
entity okay so yeah
moving on how do we use this to divide
and conquer our instance well recall
that our instance is given by this s
tilde where I stood there is a noisy
entity so in actual fact taking the sum
and difference of the ice and I plus n
over two components of s tilde and using
formally from a previous slide we can
actually get equations 1 and 2 and we
call the the first of these the positive
fold and the second the negative fold
okay so if you look more carefully at
the positive fold you'll see that it
essentially has the same form as our
original instance it's essentially on
the right hand side what we have is two
times yeah and a noisy entity the only
difference is that there's a factor that
a constant factor of two in front of the
entity and this essentially means that
we can divide and conquer
the positive fold once again in using
the same techniques however for the
second of these equations so the
negative fold we have this annoying
factor of Omega to the I plus a half in
front of the MTT which kind of prevents
us from dividing and conquering in any
effective way so essentially we can
repeatedly fold down the positive folded
in sense or repeatedly divide and
conquer down the positive folded in
sense okay so the question is how many
times can we actually do this and can we
actually reach a trivial dimension by
repeatedly dividing and conquering well
in order to understand the answer to
this question we had to look at the the
new error vectors that are introduced
when we divide and conquer so these are
actually given by Delta plus and Delta
minus and if we write Delta L as the
left and over two components of Delta
and Delta R as the right and over two
components of Delta essentially what
Delta plus and Delta minus are are the
sums and differences of Delta L and L
are
okay so yeah what this essentially means
is that if we have that if the bsd r of
Delta is Kappa then we expect that the
BSD R of Delta plus and Delta minus
should have a hemingway of Kappa as well
and this is essentially because we're
making the assumption that Kappa is
extremely small compared to n okay so
essentially Delta plus and Delta minus
have a much less sparse representation
when written in BSD are compared to
Delta because we have the same Hamming
weight but the ones and minus ones are
packed into half the dimension okay so
essentially what this means is that if
we repeatedly fold we we are packing
Kappa ones and minus ones into a smaller
and smaller amount space and if we do
this eventually these sort of noise
terms will approach a uniform
distribution because even packing a
small number of ones and minus ones into
a smaller and smaller amount of space
gives us something that's fairly uniform
looking so if we divide and conquer so
many times that this error term
approaches the uniform distribution then
what we're asking to do to solve the low
dimensional instance is to is to decode
and noisy MTT where the noise is
essentially uniform which is clearly an
ill-defined problem because anything is
a solution to that problem okay so the
final note on this slide says that the s
terms say the same size so whenever we
divide and conquer the s terms or the
thing that the entity is applied to
stays the same size so doesn't cause any
problems
I remember this Delta term or the error
term is what really causes us issues
when dividing concrete okay so to
summarize the divide-and-conquer
component of our attack we start off
with this top level instance which is
our original noisy MTT we can divide and
conquer this once and then we can divide
and conquer down the positive fold
because as the same form as our original
instance
and so on until we reach some bottom
level a pair of instances and it's
important that these bottom level
instances represent well-defined
problems so essentially the number of
times you can divide and conquer depends
on the parameters you're attacking but
for the purposes of this talk I'm gonna
we're gonna assume that we drive in
conquers three times they so the next
component of the attack is how to work a
solution up from the bottom level all
the way up to the top level and in fact
the way our attack works is that we work
the solution up one level at time so
what I'll describe is how to work a
solution up from the n over two
dimensional level to the N dimensional
level so from the second to top level to
the top level and then working the
solution up the other levels is an
entirely analogous process okay so if
you recall the formula for Delta plus
and Delta minus well essentially we're
just adding the left half of Delta and
the right half of Delta and once again
making this assumption that we have
Kappa bit flips where Khafre is much
less than n if we expand Delta plus in
the bsd are then the ones and minus ones
in that either come from Delta L or
Delta R so if we're given a solution to
Delta plus we can expand it in its PSCR
and then guess which ones and minus ones
come from the left half of Delta and
which come from the right half of Delta
and what this ends up meaning is that if
we have Kappa bit flips we require our
most two to the Kappa guesses to work a
solution up one level okay so another
thing is that whenever we make a guess
for for working the the solution up we
can actually verify this guess by
plugging into the sibling instance or
the parent instance so each time you
make a guess we can verify it and what
this means is if we want to work up K
levels then we require at most k times
two to the Kappa guesses okay so of
course there's a small complication when
the bit flips in Delta L and Delta R
collide but
for the purposes of this talk I'm gonna
ignore it but we do take this into
account and paper okay so what we have
so far is that we built this divide and
conquer tree using the structure of the
entity and if we have an Oracle that
solves one of these bottom level
instances we know by guessing how to
work work the solution up one level and
continuing work it up one level at time
until we reach the solution to the top
level instance the question that remains
is how do we actually solve this bottom
level instance and a good starting point
is to compare our instance to an LW
instance so remember we're solving a
bottom level instance here so the
dimension of this NTT is going to be
small and actually in order to compare
our instance in LW instance it's quite
useful to take an inverse NTT on our
bottom level of instance so essentially
we transformed the problem of decoding
and noisy NTT into a problem of decoding
a noisy inverse entity now so in this
section of the talk we're going to be
decoding a noisy inverse entity okay so
here's a table of comparisons between
our instance and standard LW instance so
the main comparison that I wanna
highlight here is that is that the last
one so the fact that Delta does not have
a small Euclidean norm
however the analogous term in in lwe
does have a small you clean Euclidean
norm and this is one of the main
difficulties in trying to solve our
instance using lwe techniques however we
can begin by looking at like how to
solve this using LW techniques and see
how far we get and we'll do that by
looking at the bounded distance decoding
problem
okay so briefly what is this bounded
distance decoding problem or BDD problem
well essentially you're given a lattice
and the input to the problem is a target
vector T along with the radius R and you
promise that the distance from this
target vector to the lattice is that
most are
the answer to the problem or the
solution to the problem is the closest
lattice point to the target vector okay
so how do we embed our instance into
some BDD problem the kind of LW anyway
well the first thing to note is that
we'll be using
we'll be embedding our n prime
dimensional instance where n prime is
you can think of it as being 32 as an
example into a 2 times n prime BDD
instance and the way this is usually
done is that we define the target vector
where the first n prime coordinates are
0 and the second n prime coordinates are
given by are noisy inverse NT T then we
construct this lattice that satisfies
the linear relation that the entity
inverse on the first n prime coordinates
added to the second n prime coordinates
gives you 0 modulo Q and finally use a
BDD solver some BDD solver to find the
closest vector in in the lattice and
hope that the offset vector is Delta s
which is our solution to the bottom
level instance ok so why does this work
well we know that Delta concatenated
with the - NT T inverse of Delta is a
lattice point and the offset from the
target to this lattice point is our
solution Delta s so a perfect BDD solver
will actually return this lattice point
if it's the closest one to the target
and essentially we can guarantee that
this is the case if the norm of Delta s
or the norm of our light target offset
vector is less than half the length of
the shortest vector in lambda in the
lattice ok so to emphasize the point our
main source of success condition that
we're aiming to satisfy is to
essentially given a perfect BDD solver
we want to make sure the our target
offset which happens to be Delta s here
so our solution has a norm that is less
than half the length of the shortest
vector in lambda say 1 Delta s to be
short however there's an immediate
problem here and it's that Delta s is
not sure because if you look at Delta as
an integer vector then the components of
it aren't small
even though it well the main reason for
this is because it corresponds to bit
flips okay so a first step in trying to
like shorten this target offset vector
at Delta s is to consider a base to tell
SDR adulter instead of Delta in the
offset in our target officer and in
order to do this we actually fixed L
equals the log of riku we redefine the
lattice by introducing this tensor
product so I'm not going to go into any
of the details reeling here and we
update the target vector and if you go
through the same analysis using these
updated sort of target vectors and
lattices the offset vector that we're
aiming to be short is now the base to
that LSD are a delta along with this and
the interesting thing is each component
of the base to that LSD art of Delta has
a size at most root Q as an absolute
value of the most root Q because we
fixed this particular L where as the
absolute value of the size of the
original Delta has had norm around Q so
that's a maximal norm of around Q so
essentially this base tooth or LSD our
Delta is a shorter vector than Delta is
even though it's in the high dimension
so there are two main things to note
about this technique the lattice that
were actually running VDD on or try and
solve VDD on is actually higher than it
was before has a high dimension than it
was than it had before so the increase
is from 2 n prime which is the dimension
of the old lattice to 3 n prime which is
the dimension of this lattice and using
this tensor product we actually
introduce a new class of vectors for
example one vector in this class is 2 to
the L minus 1 followed by zeros and this
vector this class of vectors well they
all have a norm of roughly root Q so
essentially our offset vector is now the
base 2 to LSD our Delta along with this
but our lattice now contains shortish
vectors of length from Q so we actually
have an itchy
our aim yet our offset isn't shorter
than all of the latus all of the vectors
in our lattice okay so in order to
shorten this target offset further what
we end up doing is we deploy this kind
of hybrid guessing approach where we
basically want to shorten the offset
vector of base two through alavesa via
the base two to the LSD our delta and in
order to do this we simply guess the
upper bits of this of each symbol in the
base two to LSD our Delta so fixing our
particular L we have that each component
of Delta when written in the base two to
the LSD R has to two integers attached
to it and what we end up doing is we
essentially split these integers into
the upper bits so these are the red
blocks in this diagram and the lower
bits which are the yellow blocks so the
idea is that we guess the Alpha bits so
we just the red blocks we update our
target vector and now our offset vector
is in terms of the yellow bits so
essentially we shortened our offset
vector without changing the lattice or
anything like this okay so it turns out
that this strategy actually does solve
the problem more or less ok so all of
this was kind of described in terms of
having a perfect BDD salt but in
practice the BDD problem is an extremely
hard problem to solve for uniform
lattices our least however our lattices
have some structure attached to them
because they use an entity in the
definition in the definition and as our
experiments showed our lattices stray
far away from what the theory of uniform
lasts is kind of tells us so as evidence
of this we actually obtained well we had
a 96 dimensional lattice and we obtained
that because er 90 reduced basis of this
lattice then what we did was to
investigate this kind of non uniformity
of our lattice we plotted the log length
of
for the gram-schmidt vectors against the
basis vector labels and what you'd
expect for a uniform lattice is this
blue line however for our lattice we
observe the red line and clearly this
well the difference between the red line
and the blue line is quite large and
essentially what this means is that we
can't really rely on the standard
lattice theory to analyze the
performance of our attack so instead we
actually run these BD run or create a
BDD solver in order to understand how
our attack performs and we write them we
use the BDD solver while we build a BDD
solver by using BDD enumeration okay so
yeah that concludes the description of
the attack now what is the overall
complexity of the attack
well the steps of the attack kind of
divide into these natural components so
first of all divide and conquer just
asks us to add a few integers together
so the complexity of this stage is
fairly trivial and we actually had to we
also have to reduce a basis in order to
perform the deed enumeration however the
lattice basis is kind of fixed overall
called bit instances when attacking a
single scheme so this is essentially
done once and for all because if you
notice we kind of solve BDD on the same
lattice multiple times the next thing is
this BDD enumeration phase and this
actually ends up dominating the
complexity of our attack and in
particular this is made worse because if
you remember in order to shorten our
target offset vector we had to make some
guesses of the top bits and essentially
once we make a guess of the top bits we
have to run a BDD enumeration for each
guess so in our attack we don't run one
BDD enumeration we run many many BDD
enumerations
so this is the phase that actually
dominates and finally working with
solution up to tree although it costs 2
to the kappa bit flip 2 to the kafir
of operations roughly speaking this
actually doesn't end up dominating our
attack in terms of what we found in our
experiments at least not for the cappers
that we analyzed okay so here are our
experimental results so we got these
results by producing 200 cold blue
instances for the Khyber and New Hope
parameters we then varied our attack
parameters the various sort of attack
parameters and ran experiments using the
different configurations of attack
parameters and these are essentially are
our best figures in addition to running
experiments on our ntt attack we also
estimated how long we would expect a
naive cold boot attack to work if the
entity was not used to store the secret
key and this is given by the last column
in this table ok so the first thing
you'll notice is that for Kaiba we
actually analyzed much larger row knots
than we did for New Hope so for Kaiba
Rho naught is roughly well we went up to
roughly a few percent whereas for New
Hope all those the row noughts we
analyzed were much less than one person
and this is essentially because New Hope
uses a much larger ring dimension than
Kaiba so this change in parameters
really does seem to affect our attack
the second thing that's interesting here
is that we can compare the costs of our
entity attack compared to the non entity
cost and for Kaiba which is the module
EE based scheme we actually see that
there's a quite a large gap between the
costs of attacking an entity encoding of
a secret versus the cost of attacking a
nonentity encoding
however for New Hope this kind of
comparison is less clear because
sometimes the entity is chief the entity
attack is cheaper and sometimes our
estimates of the nonentity attack is
cheaper ok so to conclude
yeah we've shown that the structure of
entity can actually be exploited by cold
boot attackers for kaiba parameters it
seems that the entity at least for the
bit flips we looked at um seems to allow
for a faster attack than
case where the NTT is not used for new
hope this come this phenomenon was not
really observed in our experiments but
nonetheless our recommendation for the
time being would be that if cold boot
attacks are a concern it's worth not
storing your secrets using an entity
that's not to say you shouldn't use an
entity you can still use the entity but
just don't store the secret in memory
using an entity okay so yeah the idea
behind this recommendation is to sort of
guard off against improvements to our
attack because the NTT really is
introducing them some structure that a
crypt analyst might be able to exploit
ok so future directions the first one
would be to kind of study how to solve
these general LWT like problems with the
strange lohan wait the SDR secrets and
the second would be to try to exploit
the rich algebraic structure of the
entities further so if you saw our
lattice it was highly non-uniform it had
a lot of structure to it so yeah I think
we all kind of think that if we were
able to exploit the structure of entity
further we could certainly speed up our
attack and yeah that's all I've to say
I've got some references and I'll be
able to take any questions you have
Thanks
thank you we have to have four questions
yeah I see that
they're just references I didn't want to
leave or the question or comment no
maybe I have one one one question yeah
what is the cause what is the loss if we
don't represent the secret with entity
what is the loss yeah what is the loss
yeah you you recommend if kolobok
attackers are concerned it is the worst
not storing secrets using entity either
the efficiency loss if we die so usually
whenever you multiply two polynomials is
easier to multiply the entity of a
polynomial with entity of the second
polynomial so essentially whenever we
want to do is like a times s it's faster
if we already have the entity of a and
the entity of s to multiply the two
polynomials however if you have just a
ns you have to first compute entity of a
and then entity of s and then do the
multiplication operation so it does
affect the efficiency of some of these
schemes but only slightly yeah I just
need leave people computer no well I'm
not sure if it's negligible of that yeah
I I don't really know how it effects the
concrete performance of these schemes
actually
question/comment but we thank the
speaker again
[Applause]