and finally the last talk of the session
which is also the last word of the day
is entitled face fast a yes counter mode
encryption techniques based on the reuse
of repetitive data it's a paper by
Jinyoung park and dong hoon Lee is
giving the talk thank you for the
introduction now I will start my
presentation the topic of my
presentation is performance improvement
service continuity in software as you
notice I play yes and counter mode are
used for numerous applications as an
encryption technique because of each
various advantages such as problem
security no randomness requirement
impaired processing and so on yes the
AES counter mode is not only operative
operated on its own or it also
incorporated within authenticated
encryption schemes such as ASG CMAs ECM
so optimizing is counter mode has
numerous benefit beyond the infection
itself there are special characteristics
on ACE algorithm which is used in
counter mode the counter mode encryption
sequentially increase the counter rather
than plaintext sequences the entire
output is operated on using plaintext
sequences and XOR operation so as shown
in the figure that present the initial
whitening pace of AES our processing
multiple blocks the counter increases
but changes in changes only the last
byte in most cases so as as a result we
can find that the output show will
ensure heightening also differ in the
last one byte others are identical to
some of them there are always more
changes in each other in foot block so
this means that the front located rounds
operation menu overlapped I put in a s
counter mode so if these overlap values
are tested and reused properly by its
counter mode can't guarantee the
enhanced
performance if kind of techne was
already known as counter mode caching
however previous continent caching only
reused straight for non changing by it
so they have to recalculate the rest
which is not covered by caching caching
technique in every block artist I will
discuss this limitation in more detail
after a while I'm sure that you already
know well about each transformation of a
strong functional or passive page and
now I remind you about some of the ACE
implementation methods first there is a
terror based implementation this method
really uses the pre-competition table
and the round function is done by
several table lookups and XOR operation
this method was very useful because the
belly useful for efficiently
implementing AES in counter mode however
this method is vulnerable to comfortable
to count
hash time inside channels because the
look of indices are depending on the
round key that is a skew information so
to overcome - timing vulnerabilities on
software implementation this last method
has me introduced it is less the
implementation is a constant time
implementation there is no secret
dependent there is no variable type
instructions and conditional branches or
memory access patterns that depends on
cycle information and finally Intel has
announced a third instruction called a
SNI that support that provides dedicated
hardware support for lace acceleration
and to circumvent
cache leaves by using the AES
instruction set operon came to a full
round in a single instruction this table
shows the fastest result
each implementation method a simple
numerical comparison is not appropriate
because the testing furniture are
different however through this result we
can peripherally rank each method by two
performers in order to record on the
improved performance someone might try
to leverage into existing count
modification technique however such an
attempt can associate easily previous
contemn of caching is not effective on
bitter sliced and a stain I based
implementation it only covered partial
data of round transformation so the rest
which is not covered by caching
technique should be calculated in every
block for example in the case of a sin I
around operation can be done using only
one AAS an instruction so adding some
operations to calculate the rest becomes
a considerable burden our benefit
therefore the previous code mode caching
only applies only has been applied to
table based implementation to show its
efficiency so now we propose on
implementation technique for lays
counter mode in software our method
extend the using ultimate cashing and we
name the face like a previous counter
mode caching technique that deals with
partial Izzard of roundel operation our
nestled phase can cover a round
operation entirely and we showed that
our extended communication technique can
be applied to use to peace last
implementation and even implementation
using a SMI instruction our work is the
first to apply counter mode caching to
be sliced and even Asuna based
implementation and consequently we
record recorded the highest surf forever
odd-shaped
our literature shows that they are
approximately 15 to 20 percent more
faster than those previously reported ok
now I will explain our proposal nestled
techne including previous ones I think
these are probably the end the result of
counter mode caching there are five
types of caching technique and they are
distinguished depending on the round
that applied the figure that figure at
the bottom of this slide shows how the
difference in the counter is spread by
round operation as I mentioned before
the difference in the encounter between
two successive blocks is just last one
byte and at the end of round two this
difference is spread to fully dirt now
let's take a closer look at how to make
the repetitive data useful first base
are the zero targets the initial writing
in this pace were processing multiple
blocks the value of counter increases
but changes only the last byte in most
cases most patch is not changing on most
bite changes until the last by the
counter causes or carry as you can see
after the initial heightening this
characteristic is still maintained in
the result the output is before in the
last one byte so unchanged patch can be
Khurshid and reused to accelerate the
operation base reuses only tell bite out
of often change the 15 byte to minimize
the cache updating so this can use the
same cached information until the levels
elements of counter changes because
interpreting pace is just a so operation
of encounter and round key so while
processing 2 to the power of a 32 -
accessible blocks wasted no need to
update the cached information in face
art 1 and r d1 + Torito
round one Finster out of the ground zero
it means inch of heightening is used as
the input of round one so the so the
last byte of InTouch differ in the last
one byte and this difference of actually
the first column instead of affecting
the first eight so we can stay cash and
reuse the result of round one except for
the first column since the cache data is
change it when the fourteenth element of
round on input is changed so face
updates the test data once for every 256
blocks the previous hungins
implementation is or so caches partial
data the first column of round one
lizard however faced us the live Takeshi
or the first column data can be covered
by face all t1 plus fell down face our
t1 plus generator pre-computation values
for the first column this pre contention
values can be generated during
initialization space or during in
encryption pays most of the first for
most of the result state of round one
are covered by face or the one however
the first column is change it for every
block so as you can see the factors that
determine the first column are zeros if
10th and 15th element of round one input
since the round key remains the same
who are working those fifteen element of
round one input determine divide the
last byte of a counter
and according to the increasing lortab
as one to the previous counter value
this last byte of counter is increased
linearly so those who fight shall never
change the word processing to ^ fully
blocks so this means that the same
values are duplicated for every 256
blocks for example the zeros plug and
256 this block has the same value and
similarly first block and the 257
spurlock has the same value so we can
generate our temporarily lookup table
that uses the last part of counter
lesson index we need an additional 1
kilobyte to create the creature or ruko
table because the first column is a 4
byte and the respite or counter changes
from 0 to 255
if pre-competition tables can be used
for processing 2 ^ fully constructed
blocks without the need for on any of
the additional updating process this is
the caching procedure for face LD 1 plus
at the end of round 1 the first column
sorry at the end of round 1 the first
column is stored in the temporally
lookup table and at this time the last
byte of counter is used as an index so
finally in encryption pays by leveraging
face are the 1 and face are the 1 plus 4
operations up to round 1 can be done
with 2 memory road and one merge
operation
face RT - and face are the tuples target
around - in round two the richer state
of round one is also used as the input
of round two so in this case the
difference in the number of parties of
four which composes the first column and
this difference at the end of the round
- the difference in input effects tofu
lizard so the output of two successive
blocks are completely different
however we can also make a read making
caches in round two the box on the right
side of the figure describes the
calculation from mixcolumns to the end
of round two especially for the first
column as you can see since juice a
lemon tea is different so the data
related to Jerusalem to the change but
the others - not therefore we can catch
the intermediate calculation result for
the first column as shown in the figure
by the red boxes here and similarly the
other columns or Sukesh the intermediate
calculation result for example the
second column can cache it except for
the data relates to this salt element
this can read the disk cache data while
processing 255 cell blocks and the
frequency of update is equal to that of
a hard one because the alteration of the
second column of round the to affect the
test information base RT 2 + or so
target also generate the pre-computation
tables for the remaining intermediate
data which is not covered by face Rd - a
Weber face are the two plus reverse the
similar properties of a facial the one
plus
while the target is different so I would
like to ask you your understanding force
keeping the details of race Rd 2 plus
however in eventually by leveraging
phase are the two and phase hardly two
plus the full operations of Toronto can
be done by two memory Road and one XOR
operation solely at this point of time
there may be concerned about our test
timing vulnerabilities because since our
messily uses the look up additional
lookup table it seems that our method
will reintroduce timing side channels
into protected implementation
however in conclusion our miss the
condom to fish timing size channels
cannot apply to our improve our purpose
method this is because there is no
secret dependent assess patterns
instructions and/or concern branches in
our proposed method and we to evaluate
our proposed implementation the
implemented face by modifying the AAS
source code which contained in the open
source libraries to the best of best of
our knowledge our targets are the
fastest ones and we tested our
implementations in several several
environments as shown in the table
comprehensive comparison research is
summarized in the in this table we
measure the circle using three key
lenses while changing the input of the
input plots in case of the in size over
4000 by 10
128k beat our pitiful eyes face records
6.41 cycles per bite where the previous
fastest one records seven point two five
nine cycles per bite and in case of a
Sen I face records zero point four four
cycles per bite where the previous one
records zero point five four cycles per
bite so we should hear operation on the
structure of counter mode so for AES
that can be leveraged it for gaining a
noticeable performance boost in software
implementation our method phase can
improve the performance of a is counter
mode approximately 15 to 20 percent and
phase can be employed illegally so
implementation method and lastly it will
be interesting to verify whether such
attention techniques can be applied to
other algorithms that had the similar
catalyst to delays counter mode this
concludes my presentation thank you
[Applause]
questions ready then I think we are just
on time to conclude the session thanks
again and I give the floor to Vito again
[Applause]