second talk the title is Hardware
masking revisited and the speaker is
Thomas tokuda from Reuben Kasich he will
name his call 30 seconds thank you
so my co-authors Mike and Amy they're
part of this work of course I want to
thank them for this work so in this talk
we're going to look at some foundational
assumptions of hardware masking and for
that we turn our attention to one of the
seminal papers on this topic as a paper
by shadi and co-authors and in that
paper they take a scientific approach to
counter the problem with DPA so they
create a model so they can reason inside
the model about security of masking in a
first assumption they make the
reasonable assumption that coupling and
other type of these effects can be
ignored and so they start from a linear
model where the total power consumption
of the circuit should be decomposable as
the individual power consumptions of the
shares of the masking scheme now they
are aware of course that that is not
always satisfied there are effects like
temperature voltage coupling that can
violate that assumption and that is
exactly what we investigate in this
paper but why why would you stop there
at these the small list we we can have a
look at our measurement setup which is
based around sakura g fpga and we can
list other parameters that we can
control as well both can control as an
attacker as well as aid designer so we
have the supply voltage that we can
influence we have the shunt resistor
that we can over which we measure that
we can influence we can influence the
distance of a share of the shares as
designers we can increase and decrease
the temperature we can increase the
circuit size as designers
and we can alter the clock frequency
finally we can also alter the masking
scheme itself use higher-order masking
scheme or a lower order masking scheme
and in this talk we're gonna investigate
the effect of these parameters and for
that we first are going to design a
small experimental setup for the toy
example just to investigate this whole
list of parameters that could possibly
influence the leakage afterwards we're
going to look at the main question which
we want to answer in this research is
can we actually use these parameters to
make must implementations leak and
finally we will end with a summary and
some implications of our work but first
our toy example we decided to create a
sets of mixed column instances and
chained them after one another and this
will form one share of our masking
scheme we can activate and deactivate
the last three mix columns here so we
can play around with the lower power
consumption or a higher consumption
within our masking scheme secondly we
routes for of such instances which we
call a generated mix columns we route
them completely separated that is both
in placement and routing on the floor
plan of our FPGA hopefully this
translates to reality we have no reason
to believe why it would and this way we
can not only play around with the order
of the masking scheme of this linear
hydrated mix columns by for example
having only a first order implementation
by only considering the first two shares
having a second order implementation
considering the first three shares or a
third or your implementation considering
all the shares we can also play around
with the distance we can look at a first
order implementation only considering
the first and the second mix columns
closer the wire shares are placed closer
in this masking scheme or we can look at
a first order implementation between mix
columns 1 and mix columns for having our
shares placed further away
with that we look at the parameters so
let's take a fixed junks resistor and we
increase the power supply voltage and I
think the clearest would be the Purple
Line versus the Black Diamond line where
we only increase the power supply the
rule we have there is the higher the
supply voltage the higher the leakage
taking the supply voltage fixed and
lowering the shunt resistor over which
we measure that would be the black line
to the purple line we see that the lower
shunt resistor over which we measure the
higher the leakage as for a distance we
compared these three first-order mask
implementations that is between the
first column and the second one between
the first and the third and the first
and the fourth and we surprisingly see
that distance does not matter much in
the observed leakage as for a
temperature we varied from room
temperature of 21 degrees over 50
degrees up to 70 degrees for the
temperature chamber and we nicely see
that the higher the temperature the
higher the leakage for a circuit size in
the clock frequency let's have a look at
a constant clock frequency so we go from
three mixed columns to six mixed columns
we see that the higher the larger two
circuits or the more mixed columns are
active the higher the leakage and now
with the fixed number of mixed columns
that would be for example the blue
triangles and the brown stars we see
that the higher the clock frequency the
higher the leakage the rule we can
extract from that because both the
circuit size and the clock frequency
there relates to the peak to peak power
consumption we proved them under the
umbrella the higher the peak to peak
power consumption the higher the leakage
as for a number of shares not
surprisingly the lower number of shares
the higher the leakage what is
surprising though is that we see
first-order leakage in all these
implementations the implementation with
only two shares where we expect
first-order security leaks the fastest
in the first order security but later we
also see leakage in
second and third-order implementations
we have to note that there was no second
order and leakage in the second order
secure implementation and there is no
third order leakage in the third order
secure implementation that's it for
those parameters we listed at the start
but we are working on an FPGA and on
FPGA Swire's consume quite a lot of
power
compared to on ASIC so we end the small
experiments on the toy example with some
weighted experiments that will look at
coupling between wiring of the FPGA for
that we look at the structure of an FPGA
that's basically a regular pattern of
some look-up tables that can be wired
together through switch matrices and
while we don't have any specific
concrete idea about how these look
inside how these switch matrixes are
composed of we it's reasonable to assume
that they consist of a bunch of
transistors which can be configured to
be either open switches or closed
switches depending on the bit stream
that is stored in the SRAM now let's say
we have a first order implementation 2
shares are routed on the different red
wires there x1 and x2 it's possible that
open transistors have a leakage currents
and couple V's for that we need to
design an experiment to check whether
this is potentially a threat so we
design a metric and the metric we use is
the number of shared open switches that
means for two given input wires we list
all the possible output connections to
which they can be routed and the higher
that is the more of these units we have
so that would be one units and we
increase we take a couple of switch
matrices in a row and we increasingly
routes wires through them and increase
that that metric so we have three
different experiments one where you have
0 of those shared connections one where
you have 20 of those shared connections
in the middle here and the last one
where we have the highest number of
shared connections as 20 and 16 so we
actually need a lot of these redundant
ones where we cannot really do
just to get the wires on the right track
we take those adjacent switch matrices
we put them right in between two of our
mix columns and then we perform our test
and we see that it the writing does not
really influence the effect much so the
observed leakage does not depend that
much on the writing and I think with
that we have enough parameters to play
around and to play rock effectively to
try to make mask implementations leak
and for that we take established masking
schemes from the literature we have a
threshold implementation of present from
Bushman and co-authors we also have a
domain oriented masking of AES first and
second order by course and co-authors
and we have deepest one threshold
implementations yes by myself and
co-authors and what we get is a three
shared first order presence
implementation that in the regular
conditions where the power supply
voltage of 1 volt and 1 ohm shunt
resistor does not leak but as soon as we
increase that power supply voltage we
get a nice leakage for this AAS
implementations we have that all designs
leak so both the first and second order
implementations of domain oriented
masking as well as the first and second
order domain implementations of the d
plus 1 TI and they leak a lot faster and
stronger than our present implementation
to conclude and we make must
implementation leak that's a clear yes
how can we do that we can alter the
leakage confidence by we can increase it
by hiring the supply voltage by lowering
the shunt resistor over which we measure
by increasing the temperature in which
we measure by increasing the peak to
peak power consumption
either increasing the clock frequency or
if as a designer using larger circuits
by lowering the number of shares which
is not surprisingly if you only have one
share and basically have a unmasked
implementation you leak anyway we also
saw that leakage does not depend depends
much on the distance you have between
the shares nor does it depend on the
number of open transistors or the
leakage currents and those open
transistors between the shares for some
implications the assumptions can be
valid they evaluated that is not
surprising and in masking literature in
Hardware masking has been shown by
amongst others manga and co-authors
which glitches an early signal
propagation more surprisingly is that
correctly masked implementation where we
take real care and making sure we
translate the theory to the practice
correctly it can leak but it's in a lab
environment so what is a real-world
implication and that is where we can
pose the question the main question of
our future work is can this be exploited
by an attacker and if so how
also more relates to practice if we look
at a six what do we expect then we
translate the results from FPGA right
away to ASIC perhaps not the one thing
is sure we likely need more traces due
to higher noise in Asics before we
conclude before I open for questions
some solutions temporal non completeness
would be a solution sadly is very
expensive it would mean that we don't
process on more than these shares at any
given point in time so any clock cycle
to achieve this order security so for a
first order implementation that means we
process the shares sequentially just as
in software basically invalidating all
the strong advantages of hardware we
could embed voltage regulators so an
attacker could not raise the voltage of
the power supply but then again you can
always increase the temperature and make
the design leak or tweak some other
parameters just
the talk of the FPGA hammer yesterday we
could isolate some supply voltages so
basically shared the supply voltage
lines it's not clear how to design
nonlinear must implementations in that
way finally we could deploy the leakage
test in addition to attacks so we could
use the t-test in scenarios where it is
strong to identify leakages of
implementations fast but to validate it
finally I think it's a nice if a masking
scheme is validated in a realistic
environment and for that some authors
have been using the moments correlating
DPA and we'll see a talk about that
tomorrow and with that I'm ready for
your questions thank you
[Music]
it's Thomas questions okay thanks for it
sir I was wondering if you add more
external amplifiers where we like help
you find the leakage more quickly I have
to direct that question to no we do not
add any more amplifiers so I guess we
use a standard setup for for our
measurements so I'm saying if you add
more amplifiers where we help you to
find the leakage more quickly externally
having an internal amplification I felt
I was I was referring do you hear me
okay yeah I was referring to the case
that you have one circuit which is
larger which consumes more energy and it
has more effect on the amount of power
consumption or energy consumption of the
others part of the circuit which
operates on the other share thank you
okay yeah thanks for the talk so what'd
I miss
maybe when you showed the plots in which
orders you found leakage in zone I
missed in which orders did you expect to
find leakage and why did you not expect
like you said I think you said you found
always first order leakage at no second
or third order leakage yes even though
you use four shares so it's always a
surprise if you don't make a hypothesis
right yeah but I think I missed the
point there - do we expect of course we
expect no leakage if we if you have a
first order implementation we don't
expect first sir leakage we have a
second order implementation we don't
expect first and second order okay but
even if you use four shares you find
only first order leakage yes and we did
not find second or third okay but that
may just be that the measurement setup
was not good enough to see that there
will be there will always be noise yeah
there might be of course and I think it
could be but you like to say it's just
too noisy that we cannot see it I would
be surprised if it only is in the first
order but not in the second order so
factor there's noise in the second order
MOSFET thanks we have time for one more
question
yeah all the way better
I mean no yeah I hear not anymore
what of which one of your conquer Asians
hold for a six okay so the question if I
get arises which of our parameters would
affluence conclusions which of the of
the conclusions observations and
conclusions which of these are the
solutions it's very hard to talk to this
observations and conclusions vote for a
six because they have totally different
structures powers especially with
respect to the ratio of leakage and
active dynamic power so I mean some of
these observation I would imagine that
not necessarily hold for a six yes I
agree I think the only way I can answer
that question correctly is by performing
these experiments on an ASIC although I
don't think that it will be that
difference so for sure we need more
traces but the temperature increasing
the temperature on ASIC I would be
surprised that would not lead to higher
leakage whether we can observe that or
not is it stand for the measurement
setup but it's it's fair to assume that
similar problems will be there but that
more leak more traces are required to
see it okay let's thank the speaker
Thanks
you