thank you and welcome everybody to this
session 11 on symmetric cryptography
we'll have two to three talks the first
one is entitled sae be a lightweight
block cipher based authenticated
encryption with authenticated data mode
of operation it's a paper by yusuke NATO
with Soho Matsui Takeshi Sugawara and
those ok Suzuki and he is giving the
talk thank you very much
today I'd like to explain a therapy that
is right at Brookes I hope as a mode of
operation so this is motivation of our
efforts resource constrained devices
such as RFID since Allah knows IOT
devices are widely being used and these
devices have access to in secure
networks so the devices require right
with cryptographic algorithm for secure
communication and authentication right
wait rocks five words that fixed in
ranks primitive have actually actively
designed for example these many right
which block ciphers have been designed
on the other hand these right width
device-width handle by rank data
including including data whose ranks is
wrong as on these blocks of our site
sizes so we need not only a right way to
block cipher but also our right weights
mode of operation that offer the
variable input range cryptographic
primitives and this talk focuses on
right weight model operation so a block
cipher is a habitable plantation in the
x-pyr key so this figure show block
cipher and it accept plaintext block in
this case n bits and secret key after
key and return the ciphertext block of n
bits for fixing secret key it becomes
in with pom patient and Brooks I forgive
random a dome and in rocks fo best model
prism the Kid Rock server is assumed to
be a pseudo-random permutation a block
cipher based mode of operation defined
procedure to rewrite the desired
algorithm in this case a Brooks fr if
you add component so let's consider CBC
encryption mode Capital m is a plaintext
aprox and capture see the ciphertext
block and by iterating the key block
cipher variable ranks plaintext blocks
can be encrypted and like this example
using block cipher these symmetric key
algorithms can be obtained and this talk
focus is on rock cycle based all said
authenticated action with associate
theta
AED for shot so a block cipher best ad
skills books alphabets ad mode operation
defined procedure to ensured jointly
privacy and identity and we consider
ninth-best
ad scheme and not base a skin consists
of entries from our world and efficient
argument and Englishmen are going accept
secret key nonce print X associated ad
for shot and for these inputs enough
capital M is changed for every
encryption procedure print text chapter
M is authenticated and encrypted and
associated chapter is wasn't headed but
not encrypted so the increase our volume
returns a ciphertext
of print X and the authentication tau or
with inputs and the decree to accept
secret key knows psychotics associated
and the authentication tag and if these
inputs are not forged then the decay are
going returns decrypted to
print print text and otherwise that
means the sum of these imports to them
without the reject symbol well regarding
the right weight ad mode of operation
the term right weight usually refers to
primitives that are all compact
implementation target platform so in the
hardware implementation it right laid
mean the small program run good print
and in the hardware implementation
it means the compact socket enriched
areas so in the case of Recife best a
schemes it require memories to keep the
eternal state and plaintext and
ciphertext blocks so these memory size
size its impact on rahman registers
eyelids and when implementing the brook
cipher based aid schemes both block
cipher and the mode of operation are
implemented so this implementation
impact on the program and such try this
so in order to design a right weight
boxer for best a leading most that it's
these sizes are small we considered
these four requirements so the first
requirement is minimal size so this
requires consider our memory to keep our
internal states so let's consider CBC
encryption mode and in this mode the end
with internal state is updated by
iterating the key the block cipher rugby
so CBC requires in which memory to keep
the internal state since our memory to
keep on internal state impact on the
ramen ready society so the transitive
site should be if more out much as
possible when designing a model
oppression and note that using and with
rock cipher
any ad mode requires at least n bit
memory so the minimum state sizes
and width on the second requirement is
online so this recurrent considered
memory to keep a print textbook in this
case there are two types of mode of
operation the first type is alright
steamed where each print o'clock is
processed only once for for example if
it's counter mode Kanta Molly's on right
schemes on each printed textbook capital
M is processed only once
and the second type is offerin schemes
fair or print textbook
processed twice for more so an example
schemes the time T's deterministic led
schemes
SIV and GCM aside plea and these skins
have marks and clip increased structure
our axis figure and so print text is
input to both mark and ng arguing so
these schemes require our memory to keep
all plain text blocks so since the
memory to keep print text block impact
on around unread societies so our writer
880 mode should be on Ryan so the third
requirement is import free so if
requirement consider the block cipher
implementation on regarding the
implementation there are two types of
mode of operation so the first type is
both Brooke safer for the algorithm and
proxy for emboss are used and the second
type is always what's always be used for
since what about what is the industry
both do not require the proxy for
inverse so more compact and former modes
or program and such files since the
implementation side of Roxy impacts on
program on focus IDs so all right wait
most should be in both free
the last requirement if exa only its
only means that mode consists of only
excel operations except for block cipher
so note that acceleration is essential
for encrypting prints Xbox so for
example in the counter mode each spring
text block is encrypted using the extra
operation on since our implementation
sites from our mode operation impact on
program unlocked fighting for all right
waiting mode should be extra only
however previous ad modes do not satisfy
some of the four requirements are also
in this table especially now all
previous schemes do not satisfy the
first requirements so opera program from
the previous box is to design a block
cipher based a ad mode that satisfy the
requirement so in our work are in
addition to the four requirements for
right weight age mode weakens the
efficient hundred of such ad that is a
very important requirement for a lady
schemes static LD means that the same
same ad is used for every and encryption
procedure
well for example pilot headers in
several articles are fixed and efficient
handling of static Eddy means that if
associate data is not changed then the
result of wandering associate data is
also not changed so in this case the
procedure to overhunting associate data
can be skipped
and the this important ad modes were
designed for that easily gravity is such
if re thought we did Valley Brook
fiber-based ad both of operation called
sa B which is designed basing on the
spawn style design methodology so this
is the inclusion of s a B and the the
this part in this part associate data
block and capital a process using the
fast ride this ride alphabets and the
remaining right
destroying c1 bits E is used for the
next person in this pot and then in the
next part
enough is processed using the first Ryan
is it wise are two bits and remaining
the second wine this is little bits it
is also his four domains person and then
in this part each print text block
capital M is process to you using the
first rang all signs are bits and the
remaining right IRA Gardner if I'm right
this the ranks is civets the security of
SAV depends on the side of this right
and this part is used useful domain
space turn on finally the authentication
Tao is defined for for the security of
sa b fa b when the side of the second
rhine CB is a c is equal to the half of
Brooks's outside then sa b is secured a
ad schemes up up - if trail complexity
this means SI b achieve the past about
security and regarding the five this
five requirement let's say the interest
a size of a CD is n bits so si B
satisfies fast kilogram it
and if online scheme and a fairly
consist of only X operation like this
video and say we've inversely and
regarding the roster requirement
associated the blocks are processed
using the first part and this part
accepts only Associated aprox so when
associated data is fixed then the
resulting third result is not changed so
as they will satisfy the requirement and
in the remind talk
I explained the implementation without
this is a hardware implementation of s a
B and this part is the block cipher our
implementation and this part is the
extra Hardware implementation from the
SAV model or present for queries as you
can see the extra cost from the si B
mode is very very small and this is a
poor man Palmas is obvious a B and these
are how the opera's is obviously we are
a see if part and write is a PG and so
the extra five is from the SAV mode
operation is very small compared with
proxy for implementation in case a es on
similary
for software implementation the wrong
side of the extra wrong size from the
SAV mode is very small compared with AES
and finally how the performances of si B
and existing schemes are compared in
this right and this the first table
compares the politics of Si B Kroc silk
on a cotr
and from this rhyme si B is smaller than
these existing schemes and the table
this the Roughnecks table compared to
the
how the power motive of si beyond CoAP
Khan jump and Afghan in FPGA for this
line from this rhyme I say B is smaller
than these existing schemes oh this is
conclusion my talk we define the file
these five requirements for right rate
leading modes of operation
unfortunately previous proxy for best
aid modes not satisfy some of these
requirements so we prevent sa B that is
the right weight Brooks alpha base 80
mode operation and achieve the party
bound security under this consume and
satisfied these five requirements so it
over the compact or they aren't
software implementations oh that's all
thank you very much we have time for one
or two questions okay so you define
these five requirements and there's one
requirement you especially don't mention
which is parallelism in your scheme
doesn't satisfy either so can you
comment on why you don't believe
parallelism is a requirement why it's
not needed so thank you so there's also
schemes like counter where you can run
the block cipher in parallel for for
longer messages you obviously have a
sequential thing and so so why is it
that you don't want parallelism as a
requirement our target is right with
device fees so in fact devices I think
think a parallel implementation if in to
be difficult or in our case because
their own we don't consider part of even
okay
hello I just wanted to ask it seems kind
of surprising hello ah as long as I hide
my face it works okay um so it I was
sort of surprised that you still needed
to keep see over two bits or n over two
bits of capacity given that you have a
keyed permutation I was wondering he do
have an attack that that breaks that if
you don't have if you if you have if you
make see smaller do you know if an
attack or does it just make the security
proof not work or what why did you
choose that you know question we'd fly
me to what why is this the value of see
the capacity why does that have to be n
over two is there a reason that couldn't
be smaller given that you've got a keyed
permutation there where an attacker
doesn't know the key decide them if the
internal state of orbit is rebuilt by
encryption for the ribbon even if the
remaining if bit is rebuilt them a
lottery can control or can know or
interactive or in this case there are
you this forgery you think oh so you're
okay I guess you're concerned about like
trying many different s
many different associated data is until
you get a collision on the capacity bits
or something for point on of the spot on
the see on the bottom part only the
Khoisan on this part is not a program
the program is the encoding on all on
the BB
then it becomes the other proton is
propagated following procedure but only
if called upon this part is not program
the culture is not people the culture is
not propagated Thanks okay let's thank
the speaker again
[Applause]