[Music]
I'm here because I like to learn about
new technologies new toys fun new things
I like to learn about them I like to
talk about them I like to play with them
but I'm not just here because I like to
play with them I also realize that I
want to do more I want to change the
world in some way I guess and I get the
feeling that quite a lot of us want to
do that
but it can be frustrating it can be hard
it can be kind of overwhelming so for
the last couple of years our next
speaker Eric Albus has been working with
a Free Software Foundation Europe to try
and influence policies to try and get
the word out and they have tried a lot
of different ways to do that and he will
now give us an overview of different
ways to get involved to get your message
out there and what's the best use case
for different situations please welcome
our next speaker Eric Eva's thank you
very much for introducing me thank you
very much for joining my talk thanks
also to sharp for organizing this and in
particular for all the angels who make
this possible yeah as announced I like
to present for different campaigns today
that you can use in the forefront of
Elections to get your topic into the
head of politicians into the press and
into a head of society the Estabrook for
the Free Software Foundation Europe so
the examples I give here from the
campaigns are about free software but I
will show you the general methods and
the tools that we use so you can adapt
them to your topic if you care about
data protection or human rights or
animal rights you can use basically the
same campaigns adapt them to your needs
and make lobby for your topic
however because um because all these
examples are about please software I'm
gonna briefly say what is free software
and what is the F is a V doing then I
will show you the four campaigns in
detail and the tools that we use and
afterwards I will compare these
campaigns and tell you about the
advantages and disadvantages of the
campaigns and also analyze and help you
to choose the right one for you to use
so what is free software free software
is all the software that gives users the
four freedoms PI license gives users the
four freedoms to use the software for
any purpose to study the software that
basically means you can see the source
code to share the software that means
you can share the software the neighbor
or you can upload it in Internet and to
improve the software that means you can
change the source code and publish an
improved version this is free software
here are some prominent examples from
Thunderbird to Linux to Libre Office and
the fsfe the Free Software Foundation
Europe we are a non-profit association
that has the mission to brings user and
control of technology by furthering free
software and therefore we help
individuals and organizations to
understand what is free software and
mice free software important for our
society we give legal help with licenses
for developers who like to free their
source code or who like to implement
free software in their in their
development we do consulting and public
relations basically campaigns so we try
to reach out into the society to let
them know about free software
and we think that key point for for
development in our society is to bring
free software into public education and
into public administration so whenever
there is public money involved there's
public funding involved for example for
to develop priests often to develop
software this software should also be
public this software should being under
a free software license now I show you
the campaign's that we use so the first
one is called ask your candidates but
the name is a little bit misleading
because actually it's more about asking
political parties it works much better
with political parties this is negative
simplest campaign I will show you but
still is also one of the most can being
one of the most powerful campaigns so
what you do first is you you send a
letter to the parties that are involved
in the elections and then you ask them
about your topic so in our case it would
be if you are going to win the election
are you planning to further free
software and if you do so do you have
any concrete plans how you would like to
achieve that do you support the use of
free software in schools and similar
questions so you send these questions to
the parties and you give them a deadline
for you to to answer them and you tell
them that the answers they will give you
are going to publish
so once you have the the answers back
you do publish the answers that they are
giving you this is an example from the
Berlin state elections
unfortunately in German I'm sorry um oh
you cannot see my pointer here but you
can see there's on top the question and
below there's the different parties
giving their answers so here's the first
step that you did you asked the
political parties about your topic and
they somehow had to respond to it they
somehow had to think about it they are
aware they I mean they had to think
about the topic and they are aware there
are some people or organizations who are
in favor of your topic however I mean
giving you maybe you have a questions
and then you have eight participate
participating parties this is getting a
huge text this is getting kind of a text
desert and it's not very appealing for
people to read through if they are not
very into it
so it's the next step you should analyze
it comment it and in the best make up
press release make a summary make a
press release tell the people which
parties are in favor of your topic which
party is not or any particular things
that you find in their answers and write
it up as if you would be a journalist
publish the press release of course and
to get more outreach you should also get
in contact with the press and therefore
it's so important that you write it in a
press style that you write it as you
would be a journalist because John is a
really lazy and it will not help if you
will send them a link and say hey look
here I made some questions to the
political parties and here are the
answers please look it up and and write
something they will most probably not do
it
so give them already a text that they
can hopefully copy and paste and then
it's much much more likely they were
really publish it I have just some
examples here that's that we for example
use in our case is free software of
course you have the tech magazines here
on top that you can use there is this
join up which is a portal from the
European Commission with news about free
software netzpolitik.org is a platform
for digital rights a german platform
journalist platform and i also they put
here the sun i mean it's not very likely
maybe that you will appear in the sun
and maybe also don't like to appear in
the sun i just put it here you know to
help you think out of the box don't just
do not just only contact the two three
magazines you are reading daily think
out of the box okay who can i send it to
i mean once you have it written up it's
not much more work to send it to five or
ten journalist more and also very
important here this should be and this
should be the local newspaper here in
particular if you have local elections
and you ask the parties who participate
in local elections and you have a nice
ride up and interesting story to tell
the local newspaper is most probably the
one who will also publish it and you
will also reach to the local people who
are also interested in this local
election so don't forget your local
newspaper so now we have the the first
step was we got our topic into the in
terms of political parties they had to
respond to our answers and the second
step we made some outrage here we made
it into the press so people read about
it people read about our topic and as a
third one that depends a little bit on
how the election final eaves are going
but in case there are some parties
winning the elections that have been in
favor of your topic then this is the
best time to come back on them
and tell them send them a letter again
tell them congratulations for winning
the party we wish you good legislation
period and just to remind you you have
been telling that you like to pay for
free software we are always here for you
to help with it or offer your expertise
give them a good feeling and so they
should further care about your topic in
particular I mean if they have given
very concrete answers I mean it depends
of it of course you will not always get
very concrete answers because
politicians they learn how to say a lot
without saying anything
but in particular if they give them
concrete answers you can the whole
legislation period when there's
happening something where there's
legislation on the table get back on
them
remind them on what they have told you
before the elections and and give them
some help in deciding what is the first
campaign this was I said pretty simple
you don't need any software for it or
something here's the second let them
promise letting promise the idea is that
you write up a charter you write up a
charter and then you ask your candidates
to sign it so this is very candidate
based this campaign that works not so
good with political parties because
political parties then basically they
cannot sign a charter they have a party
program and they stick to their party
program they will not sign a charter
know when maybe he has can be in charge
of signing something like this so this
is candidate paste and write up a
charter with your topic I will promise
when I get elected I will promise that I
will further free software that I will
take care of net neutrality and so on
make some points and then go to the
candidates and let them sign it
the sexiness a little bit is here for
the candidates that they don't have to
write something they don't have to
answer you in a pretext or so they don't
have to think so much they can read
through your charter and they can say
yes or no
basically however a politician I mean
they don't like to promise so much so
the deal that you make you tell them we
make a campaign and we will show
everyone who signs this charter
so you set up a webpage people can see
who signs the Charter and this is the
deal because believe it or not there
will be politicians who are in favor of
your topic and these politicians they
can show their voters see I care I care
about free software
I signed the Charter from the Free
Software Foundation Europe if you're
going to elect me I will be in favor of
free software for example here's the
here's an example made for ICANN annoyed
we made for the for the European
elections in 2014 we aligned with some
other NGOs we call if we promise and
then we came out the Charter about
digital rights and asked basically all
candidates for the European Union
elections to sign it then we made this
web page so voters can see who did sign
the Charter you can see in the
Netherlands they have been 29 candidates
who did sign it and in total it have
been more than 400 candidates who signed
the Charter
so again you have here you have the
politicians they have to think about do
I assign it or not then you also have
the outreach factor you have you have a
campaign you have a webpage so also
people get aware to get aware of your
activity but I also get aware of your
topic and that you care about it finally
this is again very good for lobbying
after the elections because once the
election is done and I mean you have a
database of candidates who did sign a
charter that says they are in favor of
your topic so after the elections when
there is a legislation on the table
these are the people definitely you
should come back on them and say look we
have some concerns about this
legislation because of this and debt or
we are very much in favor of this
legislation
can you please support it you have some
kind of you couldn't put some kind of
pressure on these candidates in favor of
your topic we made this campaign with
some partners together and this is this
is very very helpful and very important
when you do such a campaign try to get
some partners try to get some partners
that are in the same topical field as
you are because having partners helps so
much it helps of course with the efforts
that you have to do like setting up the
webpage and so on you can share the word
but you can also share the fame I mean
in this case there are multiple NGOs in
Europe each NGO has some fame each NGO
has their own press lists have their own
community people so the out retractors
much much higher if you are with
partners also it's much much more likely
that candidates will sign it because if
they see orders multiple NGOs asking me
to sign it
you have more more awareness of it when
candidates wouldn't see it while if you
are alone so this is true for all the
campaigns and I'm explaining here the
third campaign is freedom mode freedom
mode was co-authored by the by this fsfe
team Switzerland and here the idea is
this this campaign reaches out to the
voters what they did is I mean
Switzerland is a very thorough I mean it
has this direct democracy elements and
it's very very candidate based so what
they did is they send all the candidates
a questionnaire to mark there were
having some scales and they could mark
okay I am in favor of net neutrality I
am in favor supporting open educational
resources or supporting free software
and similar questions and then they
filled up the database to to show all
the candidates and how they position
themselves along your questions then
what you could do is I wrote your online
policy politician matching because
voters they could go on that page and
they could answer these questions
themselves and then they can compare the
themselves with the candidates so you
can see here you have some metadata
about the candidates and here you can
see the how are the candidate positioned
herself and how you position yourself
and then you can see okay we are we are
together here on the same side regarding
old medication but regarding net
neutrality she has another opinion that
I have and so this is a help for the
voters to decide whom to vote on
it's maybe not so good for afterwards
lobbying because the I mean scaling
yourself and positioning yourself in
favor or not so much in favor of is not
as concrete as as answering a question
but on the other hand it helps you
hopefully with some morality because I
mean it's something you know people can
use they can go to your page they can
it's kind of interesting they can make
an account and and see how they position
themselves with the candidates and maybe
they can they share some screenshots on
social media it has a graphical
interface so this is appealing to the
voters more than for lobbying but this
is of course also I mean very good if
you can get to the voters and you can
get your message to the people this is
also what we all look for to get our
message out the efforts of e-team
Netherlands they adopted the software
and made a version that is not for the
candidates but for the parties but it's
basically the same sort of parties had
to position himself on these topics and
the voters could go there position
himself and see which party matches best
my own political opinion here's the
meta-information so main author is was
open is it called it's a no GPL license
you can see here the the code and the
API and there's a Swiss so far there's a
Swiss version and in the Dutch version
so be the next two to use it finally
this is the newest campaign that we have
it's called digital nomads which is
based on theirs in Germany there is the
agency for political education and this
agency since several years already they
in the forefront every election they
come up with a volume at which basically
means vote Ahmad where they ask the
political parties questions and these
political parties they can say yes maybe
or no and then they have this web page
where voters can go and watch us can
answer the same questions very very
simple yes maybe no go through the
questions and get a result so we picked
up the whole concept for getting more
attention for our campaign because it's
very very popular in Germany actually
and so we call it the guitar Ahmad we
picked up the same concept we have these
questions you have a very simple
interface yes maybe no and this is so
easy I think even my grandmother can do
it and once you have done then you get a
result and you see which political
parties are in favour of your political
opinion so this is again very vote
orientated it helps voters in deciding
which parties they should vote on if
they care about your topic
and it's at the same time so simple that
the usage is very high I think the usage
the from the official version is very
very high and we run it for the first
time so I hope the federal elections are
in end of September I hope also that we
get a lot of usage here with this after
the results you can also by the way you
can then because the parties have also
the possibility to not only say yes
maybe no they can also answer why they
chose have chosen yes or no or something
so voters who have active more interest
than just clicking a little bit they can
afterwards read through their results
and see what what in particular are the
parties saying here to the questions
again the software meta information here
it's the main author is digital signs
and stories it's an MIT license you see
the code and as it's so new there are
not yet any forest I invite you to be
the first one to fork it and so these
are the four different campaigns and now
I want to show you some I want to give
you some guidance on which campaigns
fits best your needs or your purposes
here's a
no of you with the best feature anti
feature and the target group as the
candidate that was the campaign where
you simply file in questions and publish
the answers of the political parties the
best feature is that you hopefully get
concrete statements because if you get
concrete daintiness is something that
you can work with this is something the
whole legis nation period you can work
with you can get back on them say them
look this is what you said now keep your
word or we could make some bad press I
mean say it maybe a little bit more
nicely but this is actually the the
pressure that you can that you can give
to them the anti feature here was that
this text desert is not very appealing
and users they spend ten seconds on your
page they will not read through the
whole text so we have to do some more
work you have to write it up you have to
summarize it and make it in a way that
it's more appealing to the users and
that's is also that but that goes along
with the target group the main target
group at first hand here is the press
and doing PR about it and later if the
party if there's a promising party
succeeding in the election then you can
also use it for lobbying then it was s
promised the best feature is that it
helps you spread your topic I mean you
send each candidate you send the Charter
each candidate has to think about it
shall I sign it or not reach through
your charter sees maybe how what are the
most important things right now in your
topic and has the thing about it the
anti feature here is that it depends a
lot on the participation because in the
end if you just have a few amount of
candidates who participate in your
Charter then you cannot do so good press
with this so be careful also with the
Charter don't demand too much else it's
very unlikely they sign it make
something political a compromise between
manding and still giving the option for
them to sign it here is the party the
target group are the parties or the
politicians that you work with them
because they have to sign the Charter
freedom mode was the campaign from this
list from the Swiss team who were the
candidates put themselves in a in a
matrix about your topic here's the best
feature the envelope approach because
users they can go there users can make
their own matrix they can compare
themselves with the candidates it's a
little bit like a like gaming and that
helps you hopefully with virality by the
anti picture here is it's very complex
for the press to write it up I mean if
you have imagine you have 500 candidates
like in Swiss then what what other
journalists write about it except that
it exists and how it works but it's not
not you cannot summarize it so that's
why I groups the voters you like here
mainly to get voters on your page read
about the topic and think about your
topic and finally the ticket al-ahmad
here's the best feature it's so simple
to use it you just I mean and and also
the user I mean the user gets the
question and the user has to think about
has to think for him or herself mmm am I
in favor of this or not so you make the
user thing but the rest is just simply
clicking yes no maybe and this works I
mean everyone can understand it I think
the anti feature here is a little bit
roti of state member suspects because we
have the experience we made a test run
in North rhine-westphalia and we made a
little bit the experience that parties
it's not what they normally do and then
they tell you something and you are not
sure if this is yes this is now a
statement or is it just something
written up so it's that's why it's also
maybe not working so good for a lobbying
afterwards and that is why the target
group here again the main target group
is the voters get your message into
society to the voters this is basically
the same overview in a in a graphical
way so when you when you like to get
your topic into the press in through the
election
I mean election times are a really
really good time to do it that's why we
do it for election time because election
times that the weeks before the
elections the all oppressed talks about
the election talks about the political
parties people neighbors talk with each
other about political topics so take the
time use the time before the elections
and then if you'd like to use it then
think before okay what what is what do I
like to achieve do I like to get more
press or make something participatory
and in the best case going viral and on
the other axis you have the do I want to
go to the public and reach out to the
water or do I reach out or do I like to
reach out to politicians and make
lobbying afterwards with my campaign so
you can see here in a graphical way the
different campaigns also you should
consider what what democratic system you
are living in it gets messy mainly I
mean we have in Europe we have a we have
very different political systems running
in the different countries but on one
one big categories if you have more a
proportional representation system or a
majority voting system because a
proportional representation system leads
more to a party pace elections while
majority voting system needs to
candidate based elections and based on
that you should use also these
complaints that I showed you because as
you candidates for example it will not
work with candidates if you have 500
candidates you cannot send them all
multiple questions with free text no one
can read through it not even you
yourself and analyze it and summarize it
so this is for the party based elections
as well as the digital nomad because
this the same again the voters they
cannot for every candidate click through
yes no maybe and compare them afterwards
and but the freedom mode and the let's
promise they have been the campaign's
that are in particular for the
candidates because as promised as I said
parties will not sign a charter for you
and and freedom mode is the the software
where the users can compare themselves
with the candidates also consider if you
are in a parallel state then be aware
sorry then be aware that that as I can
be
in a federal state then be aware that
there are different power levels so on a
state's level or on the national level
don't mix them up don't ask the wrong
questions to the wrong level so don't
ask the the federal parties about topics
that are decided on the state level and
vice-versa here I made an overview about
the woman hours necessary for the
different campaigns this is Justin
estimation it's basically to show you
from my experience how much time is
needed for the different campaigns so
freedom mode and as promised are the
most time-consuming campaigns because
you have the software you adapt the
software and then you write a charter or
a matrix and then you send it to every
candidate then afterwards you fill your
database with all the data so these are
the most time consuming um pains ticket
al-ahmad is somehow the same but as it's
for the party based elections it's just
less amount of work but also you have to
adapt the software here you have to make
your questions and fill your database
but the database of course is much much
smaller and as you can you know it's
initially said it's the simplest one I
mean you do not need any software use
just sending a questions and then you
publish the answers and analyze them and
make press with it so here's the another
version of a schedule this is also
estimation of how much time you should
consider sometimes you for example does
candidates you should begin early to to
send in the questions but then you have
a time spent where you do nothing
because you wait you give them four
weeks to to answer and then you wait
four weeks
but I think three months in general is
is the point three months before
election with every campaign basically
the latest point you should start to
have enough time to do the campaign
right and depending on if you use the
software and freedom mode and so on then
you should first do the preparation
before you start with your campaign also
you can see here that our two candidates
and let's promise depending on the
outcome of the elections these are the
campaigns again that you can hopefully
use for further lobbying during the
legislation period and what you can also
see let's promise is a particular case
here you have no deadline you happen
with all the other campaigns you have
some at some point of time you have a
deadline when you like to start when
you'd like to have your results and then
you like to do your PR with the results
that you got while let's promise this is
the campaign where the candidates are in
the charter I mean why not let them sign
the Charter even one day before the
election it's good for you because the
more people you have I mean you should
have some some amount for making your PR
but afterwards I can still sign it I
mean every every sign e helps you later
after the elections
so here are my final tips if you like to
if you'd like to campaign for your topic
in the forefront of Elections choose
your method wisely and depending on your
democratic system depending on if you
like to reach out to your voters or to
the press just what I told you choose
your method wise do you think about
before what do I like to achieve and
depending on that choose your campaign
be in time this is also very very
important it's really frustrating if you
do a lot of work and then you don't make
it in time so think if you think about
making campaign start thinking about it
half a year before the elections make
yourself a schedule get some partners
which is the next point get some
partners to share your work and then
make a realistic schedule to achieve
your campaign
remember the partners is not just for
sharing your work partners also impulse
is also important to benefit from each
other's fame and to get more outreach to
press and also to the candidates and
depending on the results of the
elections and the paint that you use use
your information after the election for
further lobbying get back to the parties
or the candidates when there's something
and say tell them this is before the
elections but you have told now keep
your word and and do good for free
software in our case and of course the
most important tip in all aspects don't
panic so
thank you very much thank you very much
so we have a couple of minutes for
questions I guess if you have any
questions please line up on the two
microphones in the middle and then we
will just call on you and since you seem
to be shy I'll start off so just
assuming I want to influence something
how's your experience been with getting
actual answers from the press and from
the Canadians
I guess the free software foundation is
recognized is known as an entity do you
think like a small group - three people
have a chance of getting this feedback
sees all these answers I think it works
it should be somehow some kind of an
organization but I don't think it has to
be a really really famous one or
something but I think it works much
better if you for example with your
local Linux user group or another local
Association this could work perfectly
especially also for local elections it
works I think it works perfectly also
with this there's not much fame needed
but maybe it works better if you somehow
some organizations and you are not a
single person that yeah I can imagine
that but yeah don't be shy
take your local Association and and ask
your pal just make them some pressure I
mean yes we have one question
mm-hmm
think about the process behind how it's
been decided what kind of statements are
included in the volume art yeah yeah
the volume art they run they have
volunteers actually you can apply as a
volunteer and then and then they have I
think like 50 people also and they
gather one weekend and then they
together work on it questions that will
end up however its two toward so I think
they make a hundred questions and forty
out of these questions or thirty out of
these questions will finally end up
because we also try to undermine it
actually we had a supporter in there but
yeah it's pretty hard because the its
tutored and mentored and they decide in
the end they the organ the agency of
political education decides okay but
they try to get some input from
volunteers yeah all right just so I
guess if there are no more questions now
people can also come to you at the free
software foundation yeah we have a
village here
I think it's Olson field but I also
think it has no name it's actually
between the two legs on on the map
between the two legs on the right side
you will see it it's very exposed I will
be there all the day you can come and
talk to me
and also I want to announce there's the
there's the lightning talks in in the
are e 10 and there will be today a a
choir singing the free-software song so
if you like to hear this you know please
pass by and please pass by anytime at
the village of the Free Software
Foundation Europe cool then thank you
very much again it was a very
interesting talk thank you
[Applause]
[Music]