[Music]
okay welcome here at cha 2017 this is I
believe the second slot and we will now
have some great information about crypto
who fu has recently been using some kind
of encryption there are people who
didn't I'm surprised
okay who of you has been using RSA in
the up methacel implementation or at
least no steady that or she did some of
them well oh gosh and Praveen will now
tell us how horribly broken it is I
assume they are searchers at risk you
and mostly work on side-channel attacks
for instance or specifically on RSA have
a give them a warm round of applause
please thank you because some problems
there are some problem there are some
problems with turning on this okay so oh
how then let's start with the nice part
how else they come for you up to now
well we got quite light so we just run
here we haven't seen much yet yeah so
well I hope it will be great okay so
maybe let's have a question do you know
guys what is side channel analysis okay
I didn't hear but yeah there are few
hands okay so what we do mostly we work
for a for a lab that that does let's say
hardware evaluation fault injection site
channel analysis there will be some more
people talking about the other topics in
particular here we will show something
on on open SSL on the si implementation
this is of course not the it has some
countermeasures against actual analysis
mainly
against all these Casas parks and maybe
maybe you are aware they were shown
attacks how using timing click each
following from cache or all the other
things to get their key of si from there
we do it using we did it using a.m. and
power here we will present some results
based on power ok
hey go okay
so google talk about how we attack the
RSA implementation from open ssl so as
Lucas already mentioned there are some
countermeasures and even then we could
still attack it so we will explain how
we did that so this was a joint work
with three people that's me and the left
because on the right and then Rafa is
supposed to be here he'll will be back
soon so this is a joint work all of us
ok to give you a very high level
overview of what this is going to be the
attack that we are talking about is
called cross correlation attack and we
will explain how it works in general
without taking RSA are open SSL into
frame and then we will show how the RSA
implementation in open SSL is vulnerable
to this kind of attack you can see the
picture this is actual setup that we
used to break it so there is a
oscilloscope the power supply and then
there's a small here this is where we
had the open SSL running it's a small
bowl 32-bit microcontroller inside or we
will will show the set up bit later but
yeah this is actual setup that we used
so we already saw some hands raised when
we asked do you guys know about side
channels so to give a very brief
overview for those who don't we know
that every embedded device has some
interfaces and some of them are intended
for example keypad to enter let's say
password or any other information or
screen to see things so there all these
kind of
our speakers so these are all intended
ones that means this is these are
provided by this system but there are
also some unintended interfaces for
example power consumption our
electromagnetic radiation
these are byproduct of your system so
they are there you can't do anything
about them and these can actually be
exploited by an attacker to recover
secrets so that is what we are going to
show so these kind of things interfaces
are what we call side showers some of
the widely used side channels I think
you know a few of them already for
example time how much time a particular
operation takes and in terms of RSA for
example as we show bit later but
depending on what is the secret key bit
whether it is 0 or 1 the operation that
it performs is going to be different and
based on that you can recover full
secret key that the implementation is
not protected so that's one of the side
channels and then we have power
consumption so this is what we actually
did so we measure the power while the
device is executing RSA and that could
leak information and even
electromagnetic radiation so you can put
the probe on top of your chip and then
measure the e/m radiation and then that
could be used as well so there are
others like light sound and temperatures
or the many side channels then how do we
exploit this tight channels right again
there are two different ways one is what
we call a passive side channel where we
just observe the operations and we don't
do anything with the normal behavior of
the device so that means we just see
what is the power consumption while it
is computing something or we see the e/m
radiation but we don't do anything with
the normal behave
so those are what we call passive
attacks and this is where our side
channels Falls in and the other kind of
side channels is active so there you can
actually go and change the behavior for
example in inject fault during the
computation and use that to again
recover the secret key for example so
those are called active attacks and
normally they are also called fault
injection attacks because we induce
fault during the execution but in this
talk we are only going to concentrate on
passive attacks which is side channels
and in specific only power consumption
yeah okay to show you how power analysis
can be very powerful let's take an
example for example you have a car and
you need to enter the pin and only when
you enter the correct pin you can login
let's say and you want you're trying to
measure the power while you are doing
this verification right so everybody can
see this figure clearly yeah okay
so this these are the actual power
traces while the verification process is
happening okay so in the first attempt
we we entered a random key a random
password it's four digits and then
nothing happens and we have this trace
and in the second attempt so we try it
for the first let's say this bit this
digit sorry
so they are like 0 to 9 10 options so we
tried all of them and apparently for 8
the power trace looks a bit different
yeah because this is when you enter
wrong well but when you have the first
digit right
then the operation that verification
fails bit later yeah and similarly if
you get the second digit right your
application is failing bit later again
right so this will give you feedback
about okay whether the enter digit is
right or wrong and by measuring the
power you can see okay
at which place the verification goes
right then you can say that okay this is
the corresponding digit and similar way
we can find the third and the fourth so
this is how we can actually measure the
power and figure out what are the four
digits by maximum how many attempts ten
times four right instead of if you want
a brute force you need like almost ten
actually 10,000 attempts but we can do
it in 40 attempts right so that's the
power of side channels so this is the
verification process and what I just
showed you is called a simple power
analysis because we are just trying to
figure out the operations or how the
paths are going in we use modulus we use
the exponents of 1/2 of size which is
going to be more efficient but then we
have a way to combine them so that at
the end we get the correct answer so
that's that's another way of computing
the same either encryption or signature
and to implement RSA the most critical
operation is the exponentiation because
we are talking about numbers of 1024 or
2048 bits or if you if we talk about CRT
then it's half of the size that means we
have to raise the numbers to such large
powers and this is a costly operation
okay so there are
ways to improve the efficiency and if
you talk about the basic implement is
what we call square and multiply yeah so
here what we do is if this if the
exponent bit is zero we just do square
if it is one we do both square and
multiplication so there is a clear
difference let me show you a bit more in
detail how this works
yeah we have the modular exponentiation
and the exponent length is let's say L
and you initialize this to your message
m okay it's quite straightforward
algorithm you you go through bit every
bit from left to right and then see if
the bit is 0 or 1 if it's 0 you just do
the square and then return back if it is
1 then you also do the multiplication so
there there's clear cut difference
between bit 0 and bit 1 this can
actually be used in a straight forward
timing attack because it takes different
amounts of time depending on the secret
key bit so there are several sequences
of operations square multiplication and
square and sometimes you just go from
square to square ok i'll skip this but
this is just the algorithm of what what
i just mentioned but you can see that
you can see that these two the in this
particular operation the multiplication
what we are doing M is going to be same
for every multiplication yeah so because
the message M is constant that is where
we are operating on and if you take the
power trace and then try to take two
places where this M is being manipulated
you can see a definite correlation so
that means if you take any trace and try
to do a correlation on it compute the
correlation on this power values you see
a certain spike when the message M is
being used so that is what we can use to
see if the operation was just square or
multiplication and that can be actually
used to read out the full secret key
this is actually a just a simulation of
what I just explained you have the the
bits both on the rows and columns and
then when your when your bit is 1 that
means the multiplication is happening
you see a certain energy here and by
looking at this figure you can directly
read out the key because this means this
bit is 1 0 1 0 and so on so just if you
compute the correlation on this
particular trace and then you have this
picture and then that's it you can I can
find out what the secret give us this is
actually a power trace that we collected
when RSA is happening and the
exponentiation was basic square and
multiply and you can already see there
is a huge difference between when the
operation was just Square and when the
operation was Square and multiplied so
there is a huge difference and then even
this can be used to find out what is its
particular secret key bit is
okay that was a very straightforward
implementation as I mentioned but there
exists countermeasures and one of them
is multiply always which as you can
guess which as you can guess is going to
do the multiplication irrespective of
the bit is 0 or 1 right so now you can't
really just look at the trace and say oh
this must be 0 this must be 1 yeah so
every time you do the multiplication but
you only take the result into account if
that bit was 1 if the bit is 0 you just
discard the result so that means you do
you follow the same path irrespective of
whether the bit is 0 or 1 but only in
one case you're going to can take the
result in the other case you're going to
discard it so this will make the simple
attacks like like I just showed if not
possible because it takes the same
amount of time and same if you see the
power trace is going to be similar yeah
and this is here it's a bit important
what is the sequence of operation going
to be so here sometimes you have square
multiplication and square and sometimes
you have square multiplication and
discard so you are discarding the result
and then you follow it with the square
ok again what are the operations that
are sharing one particular operand here
earlier it was M right M is same for
every multiplication so that means when
you when you compute the correlation it
will stand out but even here we have a
certain value which is shared and that
is
to the s used here in the next iteration
is same as the s used here if you
discard it right so if you continue this
s is if the bit is 1 this s is going to
be different when you use in the next
iteration but if it's 0 and in which
case with this car this s and this s is
going to be same so again by combining
the power consumption at these two
points you can see a correlation which
can be used to read out the key again so
we do the same attack but now with
multiply always countermeasures enable
the figure now will be slightly
different
but again you can see that there are
places where you can see a square which
is much more like spread across four
blocks at least so in this case that
means the there are two operations
sharing an operand which is s and that
means the bit is 0 so this the same
attack can actually be used even if you
use multiplayer less confirmation that's
what you take ok yeah so to just give a
logical conclusion to what I've been
telling you have a basic exponentiation
which is binary that can be attacked by
using cross correlation but even if you
do a simple current dimension like
multiply always we can still do the
cross correlation attack and read out
the key and then Akash will take over
and talk about how we how the open ssl
RSA implements exponentiation and then
we give
full attack part from measuring and then
how we actually process these traces and
then how we got the secret key out okay
so a so these implementations that were
shown here they are they are not very
commonly used these are things that used
to be used maybe 10 years ago or
something like that it's still possible
to switch to see it sometimes but in
open SSL that they decide to use
different implementation so this is a
kre
exponentiation method so previously as
far as I remember in the open SSL there
was some kind of windowed method
implemented but you do to the timing
cutbacks and cached attacks they decided
to implement a bit more regular method
so forget for our fault injection and
and side channel analysis R&D just to
have fun and discover new techniques it
can run at 168 megahertz and that's
actually the implementation that we will
attack it's possible to clock it with 30
megahertz and yeah did we actually clock
it at 30 or at 168 okay so here in this
case we clocked it at 30 but we also did
the same effect so the the problem is
exactly what's mentioned is that flash
waiting cycles so it may happen that
there will occur jitter when you do to
do some flash caching of instructions
but anyway we did it also for 168 the
misalignment is small difference in time
okay this is this is designed by us as
the realistic training target so we have
source code we can modify it and then we
we know what's happening so essentially
we attacked software implementation
there was no crypto hardware crypto
accelerator or something at all though I
still believe that would be also
breakable even then
actually now and I think about it even
if there was a crypto accelerator
OpenSSL doesn't use it by default maybe
with some flag settings it's possible to
turn it on okay we will use power
consumption so essentially we will
measure it at 3.3 volt pin as far as I
remember it's this one and then ground
are pretty much all these pins so okay
here is no need for amplifier so
essentially there are on the other side
there are some capacitors so we just
removed them removed as many as we could
so the board still works then the signal
using current probe I think there is a
picture okay maybe not anyway there is
we are using current probe we remove
capacitors we will be able to see signal
we will see traces in him in a second we
used picol scope 3 to 0 7 B this is a
relatively nice model with a lot of
memory so we were able to to capture all
the all the all the execution of RSA
excused some relatively stable external
power supply we also since we wrote the
code we just generate a trigger on a
GPIO pin just before just before the
decryption so essentially our
oscilloscope will be able to in real
time to know now there sa is happening a
communication is through FTDI cable then
again current probe that's our in-house
hardware and we use the ddd our our
software risk our inspector for
acquisition and for the analysis ok
let's I will just play the whole setup
when it's ready ok sorry ok so what will
happen here is that ok first of all
there is connected the current probe so
that will collect them the power
consumption will be collected and sent
to oscilloscope so there is just a cable
connected now our
PC first will say to the oscilloscope
now be ready to capture the traces so
then this moment oscilloscope starts
waiting for any signal from them from
from here from the embedded system then
from PC fro FTDI cable we send a comment
that essentially says and performers say
on this ciphertext then the device will
start doing its magic so we'll do the
blind link or anything that that we
mentioned before and then before the the
real operation starts it sends it sends
the information okay now the now please
start measuring then it of course
computer everything sends the response
and the the oscilloscope sends the
signal the digital I signal already to
to our PC and then we can observe our
trace this is by the way not the trace
not ever say but probably does okay what
sampling frequency did you use so there
are there are some details about
acquisition that we again didn't go into
detail but we have to sample at higher
frequency that the target works in this
case it was 30 megahertz there are some
theories but rule of thumb we should go
at least 5 times more so if it was 40
megahertz than we should have should be
capturing at 650 million samples per
second we go a bit higher so go 250
million samples per second why because
we have space on our oscilloscope and
it's always better to over sample than
under sample or that's it is what I
believe number of samples 170 million
for the full operation so that's that's
quite a lot it will result in huge
traces but what's important is it's 80
million for the first exponentiation in
CRT so I'm not sure if you remember but
there was DP and DQ in there sa CRT and
the question is do we need to actually
recover both of them fortunately there
are mathematicians they worked out we
don't we only we need one we only do DP
if we
cover DP or DQ then we are done the
second one can be computed based on the
public key so we will the roughly
speaking need 80 million okay these are
some technical details 150 millivolts so
that's the range for the for the
oscilloscope how much how much variation
there are so this is to avoid some
issues with quantization errors or we've
just set in Costillo scope not correctly
there are only eight bits that the
oscilloscope can measure so we don't
want to waste too many of these bits and
how many traces did we acquire for this
attack ten thousand well that we
acquired as many as we need it
essentially if we need it more we would
have continued we succeed if if ten
thousand we are done we didn't succeed
obviously with thousand because we tried
that first okay so how would how would
the trace look here so this is even even
if I don't know how really RSA even if I
didn't implement it what I would look in
there is a trace is essentially these
two huge patterns because almost
everywhere there is implemented errors a
CRT that standard because it's roughly
speaking three times faster or around
that so almost it is almost always two
huge patterns so this will be the
exponentiation number one this is
exponentiation number two in in RSA in
in open SSL they first use DQ then the
second DP what's happening before we can
just be guessing but maybe the modular
inverse is happening also somewhere we
should expect the pre computations so
probably just before the real
explanation happens there is the there
are some pre computations performed and
what we should expect that the at is
somewhere here probably there may be
despite somewhere around these spikes
there should be this combining of two
messages so of two parts so there is one
exponentiation second and then the
result has to be combined that's that's
what prevention okay
yeah so actually this trace is quite
readable okay so actually everything six
planes here so there again recombination
is here
we didn't mark it but it's there this is
already slightly pre-process traced
essentially it's just low past slightly
so again blinding it's actually my best
guess that this is the inverse that's
what cost time absolute to slope us okay
so here we can find this nice pattern so
the the first step we it's not visible
here because we are only showing one
trace but this is quite a lot of time
okay we don't even give the time but we
are talking about the whole operation is
probably like 500 milliseconds or
something like that
650 okay 650 so how to what will happen
there is supposedly everything is
constant time but not everything is
really constant time so there will be
quite a bit of misalignment the other
thing will be the trigger it's not very
it's never really perfect so first to
start any analysis we should somehow
have these traces that like each value
should be processed exactly at the same
time in our traces so what we need to do
we need to start somehow the alignment
so we first we zoom in somewhere here
let's say and we find this distinctive
pattern here so we have we have the we
have in our software tool there is a
mechanism to essentially align on
patterns it uses some it uses
correlation essentially but roughly
speaking if we if these tools is to
similar patterns somewhere it will just
correct the offset the time offset okay
this this is maybe not the most exciting
part of work but that usually takes
quite a few trial and errors tries and
and and what we did is essentially we
tried manually as many times as we could
to and visually check the trace
are they do they seem aligned and from
these 10,000 traces after after enough
work we got 8,000 traces that that
seemed to be aligned
what happened also here yeah now I now I
see I remember so we got this 8,000
quite well aligned traces but what we
started noticing is that the trace
seemed to be slightly vertically moving
that's usually big that's that sometimes
happens due to the let us imagine that
we run this acquisition it takes we run
it for the night the temperature changes
and then what happens is that the trace
starts moving slowly like for example at
8 o clock in the evening hits it may be
somewhere high because it was maybe
summer warm outside and then it goes
slightly lower this is this is just this
problem of course can be solved in some
kind of controlled environment or really
stable temperature but well we we
applied one of our modules that one of
our software tools let's say that that
that tries to compute the mean compute
the variance so and then correct
everything not the best but again it
worked so we were happy okay another
thing maybe just to give a bit of
feeling this alignment on 10,000 traces
already takes probably an hour or two a
single try but what about the cross
correlation cross correlation requires
is a squared algorithm so we've seen
there were this on the simulations
everything were squares okay so we
cannot really run it on 18 million
samples that would take way way too much
time so first thing is using windows 3
something so essential that's a
compression method that we take like
hundred samples and add them together
and get one it also there is a hope that
it reduces signal-to-noise ratio so let
us see oh how the window or example
output would look like I'm not sure how
visibility is but essentially
there-there started occurring such
patterns essentially the result is a bit
similar to low-pass so what we started
seeing here so this is just the
beginning of the trace so we are looking
here now a bit more carefully so what
what we notice is that there are since
there I think 15 patterns here and then
they are starting being a single for
groups of distinctive patterns so there
are five there are five peaks in this
pattern so we can guess it since there
are five since there are five Peaks
there should be four squares and one
multiplied so that will be processing
four bits
doo-doo-doo-doo and this thing is just
by computation of points how the
pre-computation of points is done is
essentially first we start with M we
multiply M by M we get M squared then we
multiply M Squared by M we have m to the
third and we go on like that so that
matches what we see in the code so what
we did later what happens is that these
patterns here are not perfectly aligned
when we take the traces or when when we
put traces on top of each other so we
used another module that essentially
aligns at this window so the traces are
aligned on top of each other again this
is again one of our tools that we have
there there are other things that we
let's go just further so now we have the
aligned traces this is this is again the
pre-processing and this is our this is
already dddd exponentiation part if
everything is aligned correctly we could
already try to play with cross
correlation and actually that's how we
did it the first time but let's we we
slightly improve the processing so what
did we do we realize that what we really
what we are really interested is the
easy multiply
so we brought our own module that
essentially cuts off everything that
looks like multiplication and everything
that looks different
essentially squares we kick it out so
then we will only do cross correlation
on the on the multiplications so that
was our our result so essentially we
have this these guys that we hope the
leakage will be only here so what can we
do here okay so this is this expertise
these multiplications are coming only
from exponentiation so what do we hope
for we hope that we would be able to
detect what's called a cross correlation
between groups of beads that are the
same so for example if I have 0 0 0 1 1
multiplication and then somewhere later
0 0 0 0 1 again I would like to see
cross correlation they're the same if I
have 0 0 1 0 I should see all the that
correlating with all the other places
where the value corresponding to 0 0 1 0
is being processed and that that value
will be square essentially M squared
because this is 0 0 1 0 so it's 2 so M
Squared ok so we run it
what did we see the picture is maybe not
not completely clear what yeah yeah but
ok I will go slowly because that's
actually how we got here so on the next
picture that we saw everything will be
clear but here essentially this is cross
correlation within a single
multiplication that always happens maybe
it's not very visible but we saw we
started seeing such peaks here at the
beginning I thought that my eyes are
getting crazy but then then then we
started thinking maybe this is a real
leakage so we checked just manually what
is the secret key here and what is the
secret key in the subsequent operation
here and then we discovered it the same
so these 4 bits were the same so then we
knew ok we have the leakage
so later for the same traces we
essentially used we have the same
picture but we used GIMP
with binary threshold and that's just
easier to detect the same the same Chris
Korell very weak cross correlations but
what we discovered it actually worked
so this was these two operations shared
the same the same the same value okay so
when we would work and when it would not
work so that value intuitively should
always work because that's how we just
described algorithm but that's not true
because open SSL treats zero deletes one
differently it doesn't perform
multiplication by one but does something
strange so for once we never see cross
correlation like that we never see these
spots what do we see then we see very
very strange pattern here so we actually
don't recognize recognize multiplication
by one hand by the by the cross
correlation we can only recognize it by
the internal cross correlation here the
pattern is completely different and
actually we didn't analyze why it's like
that we are just happy that we can
recognize it okay okay we are getting
close to the end what we couldn't
recognize here is we know that these two
operands shared the same key and and
then we maybe know that these two share
the same four bits but we don't know
what is that value so what did we do
later that's just exponentiation and
then we went for the pre-computation so
essentially this part here corresponds
to these 15 pre computations and this
part here corresponds to the
exponentiation then here we know the
order so we know that the first
operation will be computing m squared
the second operation will be computing M
to the third M to the fourth M and so on
so if we for example would see here
cross correlation and we know that this
is the tenth operation then we know that
here that point is being processed so
essentially when you compute for example
M to the power of 3 it's essentially M
multiplied by M squared so we see we set
for the cross correlation between M
squared and the actual and the actual
value somewhere somewhere here so for
example let's say this one as far as I
can say based on this picture this is M
to the power of three so if I go here
then I know that in this operation
there will be since this is the third
one then it was M squared multiplied by
M so this the bits here should be 0 0 1
0 that's that's also what is strange on
this picture the strange pink on this
picture is this pink so what what that
would really mean and that that actually
is multiplication by in this case by 0 0
0 1 here the problem is that there is M
multiplied by M so that means that here
there is multiplication by M that cross
correlates with everything because for
each of this part of the loop there is I
multiply M by M then M Squared by M then
so the operation that multiplies by m to
the power of 1 Cross correlates with
everything still good enough because we
can we we know exactly the value again
what will not work here it's it's an M
to the power of of 15 M to the power of
15 is never used because there is no M
to the power of 16 computed here so that
will have to be broad forced but that's
the only thing that will have to be
brute force
so essentially M to the power of 16 will
not cross correlate with anything so no
actually yeah okay okay these are these
are just a few a few examples but it's
exactly it's exactly how I described so
here is three here is 12 so we can
recognize the values here
no conclusion first of all
straightforward binary exponentiations
are insecure against against against SP
a multiply always implementation KP can
be also attacked with cross correlation
messenge blighting class multiply always
is it it's not good enough to stop to
stop the attack so now there is exponent
blind intervention here we didn't
explain it but there of course there are
more counter measures the more counter
measures you had the smaller chance for
the attack that there is for the attack
again it's costly so it's for example
not in open ssl but in may be more
secure implementations in can be there
would cross correlation work in this
case
no it would not work but i would i would
say that way there are attacks also for
this in these cases so you can it's
always possible to pile more counter
measures on top of each other but but
there are always attacks also that that
are therefore for that cases if you well
if you liked the presentation evident if
you would like to see maybe more or even
how we do try to template attacks or
clustering attacks we have some traces
and we will have it in our tenth so then
we can may even show the acquisition
demo or we were initially thinking about
trying to do it now but i think it's it
will be too much hassle so well if
you're interested just come to our tent
and then then then we can talk more so
public key crypto is well i really like
that so i can talk about that a lot if
you are interested yeah
[Applause]
hey questions okay thank you for the
talk we still have a little bit of time
for Q&A if you have questions please
line up at the mic in the middle
we really would ask you to ask questions
that had comments and yeah
please get closer to the mic should
really what will be it for the demo
this is risk our tent it's in the hopper
hopper field it's in the hopper field
yes close to the Spanish village I
believe we just came so yeah so just to
maybe give a bit of a feeling so from
the acquisition to the actual attack the
time of processing the traces it's like
10 hours or more but so probably either
we will show just acquisition and then
already slightly pre-process traces so
just the full attack is way too much
time hello thank you for the talk you
mentioned that used a Pico scope for
doing the acquisition yeah how did you
what do you use for automating the
telling it to start capturing for what
what do you have you mentioned that
there was a tracker coming from the PC
to the Pico scope telling it to ready
itself what did you use for automating
that yeah so we actually so the the
trigger was from the device itself
coming okay so it's just yeah so
essentially that the software was
telling continuously the Deepika's
called arm arm arm arm and then and then
the the trigger was generated by the by
the device itself but it's it's it's
simplicity it's not very hard to make a
trigger from the even from the
communication it would it would imply
that we would have to get more more
sample slightly but the misalignment is
usually since this operation is so huge
even if you in style I'm and he's in two
milliseconds or five we can live with it
yeah okay cool so the the arm the
repeated on signals that being just set
from Pico text and software no we used
to we used our own implementation so so
we have we have this inspector tool but
just to explain there are I am aware of
the open source implementation online oh
I wasn't so okay there are there i i'm
not sure if i can remember from memory
but yeah there are
so you mentioned needing a little lot of
traces about 10,000 yeah what'd you do
this for a real-world attack where
you're not able to get a device to
calculate the same thing that many times
over and over but it's not the same
thing it can calculate whatever a
message it wants okay so if you've got a
real device it might still implement
some kind of limit home yes it does
happen sure so how what do we do then so
then then then essentially we need to
get as clear signal as possible so this
attack we did on another on another
device on another also ARM Cortex but we
used a.m. so this is slightly more
expensive technique so we used two
electromagnetic probe for that and then
we were able to detect a decent decent
cross correlation with hundred traces
okay however we are not showing this
result but because it was in a project
but yeah yeah we we found a crisis it's
possible to do this attack so this
particular attack doesn't require a lot
of traces there are other side channel
attacks that do require a lot of traces
okay on the other hand if text target is
very protected we will just or very
noisy well it's okay to fail then yeah
any further question
then please thank our speakers again and
[Applause]
[Music]