[Music]
so now to our next talk lock-picking has
been connected to hacking for quite a
long time for example I picked my first
lock four years ago at the Oh hm 2013
here in the Netherlands and it was quite
fun there were a huge group of people
interested in lock-picking but
interesting enough I've never really
heard talk about lock picking especially
about the darker side of lock picking
about the attacks that you can do our
next speaker has been a black hat
locksmith for some time in the past in
his life now he changed now he helps
companies figure out where they are the
holes and their systems he claims
there's no locks that can't be picked he
claims there's no sight that is
completely secure so now he's going to
tell us a bit about the darker side of
lock picking please welcome to the stage
Huxley peek
thank you okay welcome to blackhat
locksmithing so before we start everyone
knows the difference between a black hat
and a white hat
don't wait yeah just in case you don't a
black hat is someone who uses their
skills to steal and be generally naughty
and a white hat is someone who uses them
to protect and to help people and this
is the black out variety they're the
obligatory waffle about me first
I'm Matt Smith otherwise known as Huxley
Pig from off of the Internet's my first
love of security subversion came with
social engineering so very often this
involves making things like this
amongst other things and getting into
big sporting events and music festivals
and hacking events that sort of thing
I've never worked for Oxfam just in case
you're wondering then it was more about
IT security when I was a software
developer SCADA systems engineer and
about 13 years ago I got into
lock-picking
which turned into locksmithing which
turned into tool-making and now I make
very specific tools to open very high
security locks the picture we can see
here this is lock for towers this is
where all the magic happens it's
actually Marcela
it is my seller not my parents just in
case
and I like to look for things called
physical Oh dad what I call physical Oh
days at least and that's exactly what it
sounds like
so it's an undisclosed vulnerability in
a physical locking system so that no one
knows about yet so the public or the
vendor that's enough about me to unlock
Smith's the good guys not always I'm
gonna go through some examples are
Thebes and prison breaks and some secret
locks some secret tools I'm gonna show
you some stuff that I've not released
before but this is all my work so I'm
not gonna show you practically how to
steal things
that'd be irresponsible and I'm not
going to be shown anyone else's tools or
techniques anything I show today has
been on the Internet at some time if not
anymore so locks or security devices
they exist to stop people breaking into
your house stealing your car stealing
your bike so if you had nefarious intent
you'd be really really interested in
getting through these things and it
brings us to the age-old adage that
locks only keep honest people out which
by and large is very true if someone
wants to get through your lock badly
enough then they're gonna do it this is
an example of a very old lock this is
4000 BC it's an Egyptian lock now we
changed the design of this lock at some
point we still don't use wooden locks
today so I think it's fair to assume
that this wasn't the most secure lock in
the world and so I think it's also fair
to say that these were picked and
blackout locksmiths have been around
ever since locks have been around
so what motivations might someone have
for picking a lock that doesn't belong
to them any idea is anyone money theft
yeah treasure of course bill free money
other motivations freedom by this I mean
escaped from captivity not overthrowing
your oppressive English overlords of
course these guys their alphabet soup
authorities so they're KGB the CIA you
know the ones these guys have been into
lock-picking
ever since they've existed and these
guys have got lots and lots of public
money to spend very often their tools
are the most amazing intricate and works
of art but because of their very nature
we very rarely get to see them which is
a real shame I think they have enough
money to use the very best manufacturing
techniques the very best materials so
they should be good later I'm gonna be
showing you a couple of the stars is
declassified tools are say declassified
stars you don't exist anymore
of course but it gives you a useful
insight into where the secret worlds of
lock-picking was 30-plus years ago and
it's quite scary so if these guys are
going to want to get through your lock
they're going to want to do it in one of
two different ways
surreptitious or covert so covert is
when the locks been picked but if you
remove the lock and take it to a
forensic locksmith they can look at it
under a microscope and there will be
telltale scratches and signs that tell
the forensic locksmith exactly how that
lock was opened
surreptitious on the other hand this is
like the holy grail of entry for these
guys it leaves no trace at all it's as
if you've used the key no one would ever
know they love tools to do this and it
brings into question what are these guys
anyway that a black hat and whiter gray
hat it depends on your nationality I
guess or your political motivations it's
it's a very hard line to define in this
case
I can attest to this a lot of lock
pickers do it just for the challenge
it's like a mechanical puzzle and there
are always harder locks to try yourself
against so it never gets boring which is
good and somebody's always going to have
some crazy motivation for picking a lock
doesn't belong to them we all know what
one of these is right look at the teeth
are okay so first up to say confession
is good for the soul and a long time ago
in a former life this is my confession
at least I had a pawn shunt for taking
money from vending machines now I saw
this is very low hanging fruit it almost
seemed too good to be true that there
was this big box of money behind this
lock
very often unguarded but my career as a
vending machine bandit didn't last long
it seemed to me became about the
challenge of opening the locks which
turn into locksmith in and so forth so
my hat was changed just like that now
should have to say this standard
disclaimer don't steal from vending
machine
don't steal I'll stop and just to
reinforce this there was a guy in the UK
a couple of years ago he was stealing
from the parking meters we can see how
now he wasn't picking the locks he was
forcing the locks but he was definitely
stealing the money and he got arrested
he got convicted got a 5 year suspended
sentence but in a first-of-its-kind in
the UK he got an injunction banning him
from going anywhere near any
coin-operated machines
this came with strings attached so if
you wanted to go on holiday and he had
to drive his car to an airport then he
could use the parking machine but for a
maximum of 30 seconds and he couldn't
return to the parking machine for a
minimum of 4 hours and this could make
life very difficult ok so don't let it
be you so let's have a look at some
lock-picking thieves lock-picking theft
brings with it a set of unique issues
that you don't really get with other
theft we can say that the vast majority
of thefts are forced entry that's a fact
but the exact number that are done by
lock picking methods it's kind of fuzzy
like this 3 to 6 percent I think I check
maybe 7 or 8 different police forces
certain police forces say snapping for
instance is a locksmithing technique or
they say its destructive entry so this
numbers really hard to pin down and
there are other other reasons why it's
hard to pin down as well which I'm gonna
go into so the very nature of lock
picking means that there's no obvious
sign like I spoke about earlier
you can't find signs if you look at it
under a microscope but ostensibly to the
layman you probably left it unlocked or
they have the key lock picking is gonna
feature a very low down the list of
potential reasons for your house getting
burgled and that's going to keep this
number down the amount of locks that get
forensic Lee examines is tiny tiny it
only happens in the most high-profile of
cases so if your shed gets robbed or
your house chances are the police aren't
going to spend a lot of money
forensically examine in that lock so
it's gonna go unnoticed
there's also insurance issues so if you
come home and you see that your door is
open everything has been stolen you
don't know what's happened and people
always tell you in this case smash your
window or kick the door in
so the insurance company don't try and
worm out of the claim because that's
what they will do they'll say you must
have been negligent with your keys maybe
you left them under the mat or maybe you
just left the locks unlocks your fault
and again that's going to keep this
number down every time that flies out
that's going to
this number down you also get skimming
so let's go for a hypothetical here
let's say there was a thief that could
pick some parking meters near his house
and let's say that instead of emptying
that parking meter at the end of a very
busy day what if that thief just takes
maybe 5% out of every meter and locks it
back up very often this can go unnoticed
for years it can fly completely under
the radar sometimes sometimes it never
gets noticed that I can guarantee you
and again it's a hypothetical it's a
hypothetical and that's going to keep
this number down again if no one notices
and let's say you're the manager of this
parking company you know that the locks
have been picked well no you don't know
that you know that have been opened you
know that they've been locked back up
again and you know the money's been
going missing so your first port of call
is going to be someone with a kid or
maybe someone who had access to the key
and copied it again lock-picking
probably isn't even gonna enter the
heads gonna keep this number down but
I've been want to caveat this by saying
most again most thefts are forced entry
so don't worry too much lock picking is
rare but I don't think it's quite as
rare as it's made out so this is our
first lock picking thief deacon Brodie
this guy was from Edinburgh his florist
was in the late to middle 18th century
apparently Robert Lewis Stevenson based
his character dr. Jekyll and mr. Hyde
off this guy because by day beacon
Brodie was a pillar of the community
this guy used to organize church faiths
he was a town councillor used to bless
babies you know everyone loved this guy
but by night they can Brody changed
completely and he was also a talented
locksmith so his high stakes in society
and the facts he was a locksmith got him
jobs servicing and installing locks on
rich people's houses so Brody's favorite
trick was before he'd install the lock
very simple he'd take ek and make a copy
and then at some convenient point
in the future he'd go and rob the house
if he didn't already have a key he'd use
a method of impression so pretty much
exclusively you'd have been up against
what we call warded locks now this is
old technology now it's not really
employed anymore but he would get
through it he'd take a blank like this
one here or these ones it these are
actually his tools so you take a blank
and he'd put an impressionable material
on the side of it either wax or soot
introduce it into the lock and turn it
Nate wouldn't open because it was a
blank but when it stopped they'd leave
an impression on the suit or the wax and
when he removed the key he'd be able to
see where he needed to file material
away in order to make that key work this
is where we get the term skeleton keys
from so you've removed as much meat as
you can off the key and you've just left
the bare bones skeleton keys another one
of Brody's favorite tricks this is
crafty you'd often carry a blob of put
it in his pocket
and he'd walk around Edinburgh town city
centre he'd go into local merchant shops
make idle chitchat talk about the way
they are nothing important but if an
opportune moment arise arose you'd take
a key and it squish it into his blob of
putty and put it back before he was
noticed and again he'd go home
he'd make a copy and Rob it at a
convenient point in the future he was
quite successful as a criminal in my
opinion one of his highlights was he
stole 800 pound again it was his
favorite trick it was from a bank he
installed the locks so he had a key this
must have been the easiest bank heist of
all time he just let himself in let
himself out with the money he needed a
lot of money because Deakin Brody lost a
lot of money on cock-fightin he had a
wife he had two mistresses six children
so he was a very busy boy and he was
already welfare he's dad had left him a
lot of money and their inheritance
another highlight was he stole the
ceremonial mace from Edinburgh
University this isn't the mace
makes was never recovered this is just
something that it might have looked like
a ceremonial mace
that's not deacon brodie either I like
to think that this mace is right now
sitting in someone's living room in
Edinburgh may be being used as an
ashtray or something it has to be
somewhere now things start to unravel
for Brodie when he's gang start tried to
burgle the revenues of Scotland so what
this means back in those days
money wasn't electronic of course it was
all physical coins and notes and this
was the building where all the tax of
Scotland was kept so this was an obscene
amount of money but it went wrong he
only stole 16 pounds but later on maybe
two months down the line a couple of his
gang got arrested for different things
Brodie didn't know what they'd been
arrested for so he assumes it was for
the bungled heist now as it happens the
two guys never breathed a word to the
police about Brody
but he didn't know and so he fled the
country and that did bring suspicion
upon him so he was eventually found here
in the Netherlands hiding in a cupboard
and he was brought back to Edinburgh and
hanged in front of 40,000 people but
it's not all bad he has a couple of pubs
in a cafe named after him this is his
legacy
I love this guy okay the phone Ranger
James Clark this is the best picture I
could find of him this guy was a tool
and die maker from Ohio in the States at
some point during his career he decided
he was gonna stop making tools instead
he was going to rob from pay phones
specifically he stole from the Western
Electric payphones which were all over
America at the time literally all over
America he often used James Bell as a
pseudonym when he checked into seedy
motels as a way of giving the finger to
the phone company and he was eventually
arrested in 1988 in his Caravan where he
went quietly now these are the payphones
he was robbing from this is where the
money lives the lock is on the side and
this is the lock here we're gonna have a
closer look at this lock this guy was
the only man who ever picked this lock
up to this point in time or the only man
who has ever been publicly acknowledged
with picking the lock now what makes
this lock so secure Ohio Bell has spent
a million dollars in the 70s developing
this lock which by 70 standards was a
lot of money this was the days of the
Six Million Dollar Man so a million
dollars is like his leg his head maybe
it's the peak of Technology it has a
very Peres centric key way what that
means is you see these jagged ET so if
you try to pick this lock you need to
maneuver with your pick around these
wards and that makes it difficult it has
eight levers all of which have false
gates which again makes a lot picking
harder there's a common spring so in
most lever locks each lever has its own
spring this just has one so what this
does if you lift one lever high that
holds the spring up and all the other
levers no longer have any spring tension
on them so they just flap around sort of
uselessly it makes it difficult to pick
the lock that's not what makes this lock
secure or the locks have these features
what makes this lock particularly secure
is the lever grabber so that that's this
big silver thing so on this side we can
see a locked lock and on this side we
can see it's being unlocked and what's
happened is this see
a stump has gone into the hole here but
more than that this lever grabber has
engaged and you can see it's sort of
meshed with the levers and that stops
the levers movement makes them immobile
so normal lock picking theory would tell
us that we push this c-shape thing
against the levers and that creates
friction and then the lock picker moves
the levers and it's that friction that
tells the lock picker what's going on
that can never happen in this lock
because by the time this gets to here
this is engaged and so you can put
pressure on the levers but you can never
move them very difficult lot to pick it
shows you what an achievement it was
that this guy could pick this lock over
seven years he stole from 32 of
America's 50 states he used to travel up
and down Interstate 40 east to west
east-west branching off to different
towns to steal the money he got high
profile he was on America's Most Wanted
twice and there was a $25,000 reward on
his head for capture now like I say this
guy was the only man ever credited with
pickin this lock no we can say this
because the FBI forensic exam and every
single lock that was picked every single
payphone lock that was picked and they
all had very distinctive scratches that
were from his tool but frustratingly we
don't know what his tool looks like the
feds obviously never released pictures
of it and there's no reason to think
Clark isn't taking that secret to the
grave he might be dead or editing I
don't know he'd be 79 now and he's never
told anyone I've heard different reports
saying it was quite sophisticated and
other reports saying it was made from
piano wire and quite simple I think it
was probably quite simple all the best
tools for the simple tools
he earned no one really knows varies
from between $400,000 to over a million
dollars which is 57,000 to 147 thousand
a year which is a pretty good earning
and change so if we say he stole a
generous and say he stole a million
dollars and that the most common coin in
u.s. payphones is the quarter that's
four million quarters which looks like
that's that's where do you keep all that
he eventually got caught tampering with
payphones he got three consecutive
one-year terms so he did three years in
total more amusing than that he was
ordered to repay 802 dollars and fifty
cents don't forget the fifty cents back
to Ohio bail so if we say it costs Ohio
bail a million dollars to develop this
luck and he stole a million then this is
a slap in the face
ironically modern payphone locks in
America are less secure than the lock
I've just shown you now they're not bad
locks by any stretch of the imagination
but they're less secure than that one if
you want it to be a payphone thief in
America now it would be easier than back
then that's just sailing now for years I
didn't make any progress at all with
this lock up for years I've been trying
to emulate this guy and I've got an
example of it here but recently I made a
bit of a breakthrough so this is the
lock in sort of half open position we
can see there at the right height and
this C shape is entering into the gap
so I found that you can over lift one of
the levers higher than it should ever go
so this is one of the levers that's gone
too high and this little pointy bit on
the end of the lever
if you lift it up just a little bit too
high you can see keeps this grabber push
the back which then leaves u7r the
levers to pick unimpeded which is still
no easy task but there's light at the
end of the tunnel this actually led to a
better technique
where I don't have to over lift anything
and as soon as I hit the lock I'll be
the first to let the world know believe
me was this how Clarke was doing either
of the two methods was this class no
Clark was doing it frustratingly we can
never know okay let's have a look at
some prison escapees we like prison
escapes I love this I love the way the
guards are just standing there taking
pictures and this guy looks in quite a
lot of pain look at this so this guy
wasn't a lock picker I guess these are
all tools that have been confiscated
from an American penitentiary I love
this it attests to the ingenuity of man
when times are hard they make the most
creative things we can see lockpicks
here made from knives spoons buttons
wire I don't even know what this stuff
is pretty cool stuff this is the story
of a Finnish borstal break this is the
ABLOY classic lock it's a very very
secure lock it stood the test of time
it's now being around for 110 years so
it's a good luck
but these lads in the Finnish borstal
they managed to escape they went
joyriding they came back they did some
donuts around the car park of the prison
and then they let themselves back in
now the guards assumed that they must
have had a key and they did have a key
but they were never given access to any
of the keys at any time they were never
given time alone with a key to copy one
so how did they copy the keys it's
fantastically simple pencils so this
involves a method that we call sight
reading so if we look at the key again
we can see that instead of up and down
cuts like you get on a normal key this
has 18 degree angles so you can get
quite good at just looking at this key
and going up that's a 2 1 0 5 etc and
that's what they were doing that
visually look at the key as the guard
used it and make a copy from a pencil
very good this is what they use in the
USA so these are called moguls you can
see it's just like a normal lock but
maybe twice the size I heard that the
theory behind making these big locks was
that the inmates would have to therefore
make bigger lock picks and therefore
they'd be more easy to be spotted which
sounds like nonsense
I think being America it was probably
more a case of what's more secure than a
lock a bigger lock of course
can you still pick them of course you
can still pick them they are very
difficult to pick but you can still do
it and these are normal tools by the way
these aren't massive tools they're just
normal lock picks
this is the story of mr. Doody from 1812
this isn't a real picture of him so this
guy he was from Wolverhampton in the
United Kingdom and he invented a lock
that used the secret principle so all
that means is there was a certain secret
to opening the lock either a hidden
keyhole or maybe a hidden button but as
soon as you know the secret you can open
that lock so this is otherwise known as
security through obscurity and it can
work very well on the small scale if you
only have maybe one or two locks in one
or two different towns then no one knows
the secret it becomes a problem when
they're mass-manufactured
using this principle because again as
soon as you know the secret you know the
secrets of all the other locks so this
guy he serviced the locks on staff at
jail which was useful because he got
locked up in the same jail several years
later so of course he picked his way out
but he was worried that his family would
get in trouble or maybe he would get a
longer sentence if he was caught while
on the run which he probably would have
so he picked his way back in the story
goes that he was sitting in his cell
when the guard came around so did the
roll call in the morning like nothing
that happens and we can't talk about
prison escapees without talking about
this guy we're going to come into the
present time after this don't worry it's
not a complete history lesson but Jack
Shephard is responsible for well we can
thank this guy for many subsequent
prison escapes and you'll see why soon
it was only 22 when he was hanged so and
you can see this guy was only a small
month and yet he was renowned for
breaking through stronger indoors for
breaking through solid oak floor but
walls he was good at breaking through
walls he was a lockpick a pickpocket
vagabond ruffian general scoundrel this
guy did
gentlemen Jack as he was known he
escaped from prison four times each time
he was sentenced to death but his first
escape was my favorite so he escapes by
wiggling the iron bar on the window and
he used this iron bar to break through
the floorboard then he broke through two
walls then he found himself at a high
window and he couldn't get down from the
high window without injuring himself so
can anyone guess what he did how did he
get down from the high window this this
is the first example I can find of this
ever happening yeah of course so he went
back to his self he tore strips off his
bedsheets made it into a rope Jack the
lad as he was also known his second
prison escape was dubbed the sexiest
prison escape of all time now this is
because he was locked up with his
mistress Edgeworth Bess she was a local
prostitute and the guards had learned
Begg didn't leave any bedsheets for Jack
to pull the same trick and yet he pulled
the same trick so can anyone guess where
he got the material from to do this yeah
from Bess
this was in a local newspaper it's an
artist depiction this is a lot more
modest than I believed it was she was
pretty much naked in reality now the
idea was he was going to tie the rope to
one of the bars in the window but
unfortunately Bess was a little too big
to get through the gap and so he had to
take all of the bars out and lower the
heifer down himself which he did and
then he climbed down the wall but it
didn't end well for Jack he's got four
times each time from the hangman's noose
before he was executed he was given the
option of giving up his accomplices but
apparently when the judge asked this he
scoffed at him and mocked the judge so
that that confirmed his death sentence
he had two plans to escape the noose the
first one was he was going to use
a lockpick that he had fashioned from a
nail and he was going to pick he
chuckles at a particular time when the
car was going through London and there
was going to be another car waiting for
him but unfortunately one of the other
prisoners noticed his lockpick and told
the guards what an asshole so he was
hanged his second plan to escape was he
was going to wait until he'd been strung
up and then after he'd been hanging for
maybe five or ten seconds a mob was
going to rush onto the stage and cut him
down and take him to a local doctor to
be revived however we can see what
actually happened this is Jack going to
the gallows saying hello to everyone now
here we can see like there's this mob
trying to get to the gallows but they
never made it so Jack was hung and here
we can see his body being given to the
mob now the mob didn't take his body to
a local doctors to be revived it was
more a case of ripping bits off it until
there was nothing left and then that
that was the end for Jack I'm afraid he
was hanged in front of 200,000 people
which was a third of the population of
the whole of London this guy was a
massive celebrity by Jack okay we're
gonna come into newer times now in 1978
Jenkins and Lee these guys were
political prisoners so they were
distributing anti-apartheid leaflets but
they were doing it using high explosives
so maybe the prosecution did have a case
there but these guys escapes they had 14
locked doors between themselves and
freedom and each of these was a
different lock so this was a massive
achievement
they made the keys out of wood and later
on from metal this is Lee or Jenkins
here we can see some examples of the
keys they used this one's quite
complicated
it's about warding and lever cuts so
they weren't simple keys but how do you
get out of your cell door when there is
no keyhole
the inside these guys this was the first
door at 14 so every prison cell had a
broom and these guys took the broom
apart and fashioned like a crankshaft
system I'll show you here so this is
what they have today there was a mirror
in the cell and they'd fish this
broomstick out of the window and using
the mirror they would see what they were
doing and on the end you can see that
they had this key and so that operates
it from the window but this still left
13 locked doors so shows you what an
astonishing achievement and this was
these guys weren't locksmiths before
they got locked up and luckily these
guys are still out there still fine
there they are
today it's a happier ending Barry Marr
Prison Break
Daniel Luther hice this guy got
convicted for murdering someone else him
in another month they wanted this dead
man's guns apparently which is a hell of
a reason to kill someone he escaped
previous to this in 1991 he faked a
peptic ulcer and he got transferred to
the hospital wing of the prison but he
was in a high room so can anyone guess
how this guy got from the whole room
down to the ground
sheets his particular take on it was he
rips some wires out of the war and
intertwine the wires to make it stronger
but thank you Jack Shephard
in 1995 he was transferred to Barry MA
so when he got there he met another
inmate called Baker no Baker was a
long-term inmate and as such had been
given certain privileges which included
jewelry making equipment bizarrely he
was a jeweler on the outside so him and
hi Scott together and thought okay let's
make a cake let's make a key and escape
from prison but the really good bit
about this story is where he got the key
from so when anyone got transferred to
berry ma they were given an induction
booklet telling you how to be a good
inmate what to do what not to do on the
front cover with a master keys to the
prison
[Applause]
isn't that incredible
so they escaped heist left a message in
his cell saying this bird has flown very
cheesy Baker got injured climbing over
the second wall he hurt his leg so he
got recaptured after 24 hours heist was
on the run for 12 days but again he got
recaptured but both of these guys are
now heir to prison hice yeah this guy's
a landscape gardener and an artist this
is an example of his artwork with the
rainbows and the Dragons and the Eagles
I'm sure you can find him if you want to
buy one of these prints okay let's have
a look at some secret locks and secret
tools this is the Chubb custodial 3g2 2
2 so this is a prison lock again the big
thing about this lock is that you can't
do what I spoke about earlier with the
finish guys you can't look at this key
and tell what the combination should be
should boast
that the magnetic key is impossible to
read or duplicate using normal senses
alone or duplicate with standard
workshop equipment now I don't know
about you but that sounds like a
challenge but I've never seen this lock
for sale Chubb are really very good at
keeping their more sensitive locks under
wraps if anyone has one of these for
sale I'd be super interested this is
another Chubb secret lock it's not
secret anymore
the chip manifold mark 4 was used by the
UK Ministry of Defence to secure
whatever you secure in safes documents
and sensitive items it's called the mana
foil which stands for money manipulation
foil so it was designed from the ground
up to stop you from opening it unless
you knew the combination it includes
rumble strips so have you ever seen the
old movies where a guy or have a
stethoscope and they'll be listening to
the safe that's actually a legitimate
technique if you know what you're
listening for but this has these little
rumble strips that deliberately make
noise so you can't use that
it also has lead shielding this circle
here that's the lead shielding and that
was to stop x-ray attacks so if someone
came along with their portable x-ray
device you know the ones and tried to
get the combination that stopped it it
also had crazy strict controls so if you
were a chirp safe engineer and you were
called out to go and work on this lock
you couldn't do it without having
someone supervise you at all times
there was also always a chain of custody
on the parts so if you took a dial or a
disc or anything from Chubb you have to
sign it out so everybody knew at any
given point in time who had what parts
and there are no public successful
manipulations of this that's not say
it's impossible it isn't I've heard
rumors of people picking it but no one's
ever done a YouTube video to sort of
prove it but this has been declassified
for a few years now so it's only a
matter of time and this wasn't the end
for the money foil and we'll leave that
there
Nate oh mercy lock so this was used by
NATO countries again to secure documents
and so forth instantly we can see that
it doesn't look quite the same as most
lever locks you've got this sort of
v-shape to the key now the idea of this
is so you can't just get a blank and
maybe impression the lock
you have to manufacture your own blank
your own key which makes it more
difficult of course it has 14 levers all
the levers have false gates which is a
lot of levers to pick but that's not
what makes it it this makes it secure
but it's not what makes it ultra secure
so this is quite unusual with a lever
lock you can see we have these two
silver parts here
they're the stumps so the idea behind
having two is if you tried to drill a
lock and drill one of these stumps away
the lock is still going to stay locked
you'd have to drill both of them away
which doubles the attack time
and again this is another lock that's
never been publicly picked oh I forgot
to mention the other cool thing about
this luck if you try and tension this
luck so if you try and push these silver
stumps into the levers what happens is
the levers move away so you'll move the
stump and the levers will move away and
so you can't get that friction very
cunning way to stop people picking it
and again I I've heard rumors that maybe
it can be picked but no one's ever come
forward and publicly admitted it this
isn't a secret tool this is a 7 pin
tubular lockpick it's for these locks
I'm sure we've all seen these locks
everywhere on vending machines and cash
boxes now why I like this tool so much
is because of how effective it is so now
it's time to pray to the demo gods I
have one here this is a very common lock
that's used for securing multiple items
of electronic equipment and we're gonna
see how fast this tool can work so we
get it ready I'm gonna reset it just so
you know I'm not cheating okay ready
hold on
Oh demo gods what you done to me
let's try that again obviously it
doesn't always work first time okay
[Applause]
now that was second time that was like
using the key almost so you can see how
frightening ly effective this can be now
not every tubular park lock picks this
easy but the cheap ones do and this is a
cheap on this is a cheap one so don't
use that to secure your laptop is the
moral of this story now this tool uses
an impress self impression ik so what
that means in a nutshell is that this
tool allows the lock to pick itself it
takes very little skill from the user
and it happens very quickly but it
wasn't long before lock companies
realized that this tool was out there so
they started changing their designs
this is battens attempts at foiling this
very tool now I think this is a good
attempt of foiling it so one of the big
things about this lock instantly you'll
see it's got six pins instead of seven
so that tool needs to have its little
arms in different places so instantly
that tool doesn't work another big thing
about this is it's filled free cable so
what that means is you can change the
lock without actually physically
removing the lock so if you were worried
that maybe the key has been compromised
maybe someone's copied it maybe
someone's stolen it you can come along
with the change key and move it to one
of these other numbers and then the
original key won't work anymore they
also put this shroud around it the big
hunk of metal now what this does is it
excludes that pick from fitting in you
need a pick that sort of looks like the
key here so it needs a thin stem you can
single pin pick this lock and you can
self impression it too but that shroud
makes life very difficult
HPC are a tool maker they did make a
tool but open these a long time ago 30
40 years ago maybe I've not seen it for
a long time but this is a good example
of how to stop that tool this is a bad
example this is cam lock systems effort
so can anyone see what camera lock
systems did to stop that tool from
working I've highlighted it in red
just in case it's not immediately
obvious they change the circle to an
octagon and that's it this was the hole
this was the whole model of security for
this lock was changing the circle to an
octagon
that's simple so this does stop the tool
from fitting it won't go in those little
sharp corners stop it working but
luckily it's a very cheap and nasty lock
there's nothing stopping you getting
direct access to the pins and single pin
picking it and it does self impression
to very easily if you had the obvious
tool so how do you think you might
modify this tool to work in this lock do
you think maybe if we change the circle
to an octagon that might work
well obviously yeah and it does but this
tool doesn't exist now I found this
really crazy I thought well if I can see
the obvious tool surely other people can
and other people did I'm gonna this is a
way but lock makers keep tools secret
it's quite an outdated method but this
is how they do it so I was on key
picking which is a really cool lock
picking for him on the Internet
now I put a post up saying at some point
in the future I would like to make tools
for this lock and this lock and this
lock and their lock that one I just
showed you happen to be in that list and
that was all their lawyers saw it didn't
like it they got on to keep eking zhh
owner and threatened him with
prosecution if he didn't give up my IP
address and any other identifying
information and their intention was to
serve a cease and desist order on me in
order to get this prevents potential
future patent breach now that covers
everything doesn't it potential future
patent breach and then I found out
they've done it before
they've done it several well I know
they've done it several times before so
they're probably done it many many times
I've spoken to several tool makers from
the UK and they've all said the same
thing they've said they've either made
the tool or
or put the tool onto the Internet to
sell and every time car lock systems
have jumped on them and said no you're
not doing that and I get why they do it
they do it so you can't get an
off-the-shelf tool that opens their lock
so I understand it but this is security
through obscurity again and the problem
is this lock is everywhere in the UK at
least you'd think if it went to court
but they wouldn't have a leg to stand on
and a lot of the guys I spoke to said
they would have loved to afford it but
nobody wants a long expensive legal
battle with a lock company and then I
noticed the car lock systems have tried
to patent the obvious tool and here it
is you consider change the circle to an
octagon
now the reason they did this is a little
fuzzy I don't know the intentions behind
it maybe they wanted in the future to
make this tool and sell it to locksmiths
but that isn't what happens I think it's
more likely this was a purely defensive
patent they never intended to make the
store they just had the patent ready so
that if anyone did make it then they
could jump on them and say no that's not
happening and now found out it never
actually got granted but whatever reason
the patent for the tool doesn't exist
they tried to patent it and it didn't
work
so maybe they wouldn't have a leg to
stand on after all now like I say this
is an outdated protection method it's
been used many times in the past but now
we have the Internet your secret can be
everywhere in a matter of a day or two
and this wouldn't fly in digital
security if Microsoft make windows 28
and any old fool can look at it and go
oh I couldn't just change an existing
tool and totally subvert their model of
security that I'd have to patch it
extensively or change everything from
the ground up and this is what we want
we want security through design not
obscurity and and this doesn't help
anyone this this type of behavior all it
actually does is keep the
vulnerabilities inherent within the lock
it keeps them there
this is another tool that while secret
once this is the Sputnik or Yugoslavia
you say it was invented by him Aladdin
perchik
this guy was a Yugoslavia who was
stealing things in Germany it's a really
cool tool you can see that you have
these five little wires and each one of
the arms moves one of these wires
independently so it's like having a
movable key inside the lock as you pick
it you can buy these now but they're not
cheap this is a blow classic I said we
were going to look at this lock again so
sometime in the 70s a Finnish sex pest
made the vamp LA which is this thing we
can see in the bottom right corner all
that means is thingamajig or contraption
in Finnish this guy he was picking the
front door locks on young ladies houses
hiding under the bed and then waiting
until the middle of the night before
he'd come out and attack them so wasn't
a nice guy he got caught the finished
police wouldn't believe that he could
pick the locks until he demonstrated it
and this is the first example of a blow
classic being picks in 75 years
beforehand there was a reward our boy
were giving a 1 million fin marks reward
if you could pick this lock which
doesn't exist anymore I could use a
million fin marks right now and this
forced a blow to change the design of
the tool so this tool was using this
front disc to tension the lock our blow
changed it so that front disc just spun
freely and you could no longer use it to
tension the lock and since then it went
to unpicked
allegedly so as soon as I heard about
this it became like a locksmithing
ambition more of a locksmith in
obsession I didn't work on it for 6
years constantly it was off and on
making prototypes realizing it didn't
work
repeat rinse repeat and then I settled
on a design that I thought might work
but I realized I couldn't make it by
hands I needed something more accurate
so I saved up for a year to buy this
milling machine and to cut a long story
short it works there's the tool if we
can say two examples over here I have it
with me if anyone wants to see it
there's the lock open no way but this is
the good
I was really happy but then within three
weeks a friend of mine got in touch and
said oh I see your tool is for sale I'm
that popular locksmith Supply website
and I was like I don't think it is so I
went and had a look and it turns out
when I spoke to the owner of the website
this tool got developed eight years
previously by an unknown government
agency and for eight years it existed
and being used in complete secret and
then once they saw mine on the Internet
they realized the secret was out because
it's almost identical they realized the
secret was out and they Declassified it
to sell it publically so I'm not
interested in reinventing the wheel if
I'd have known that this tool exists did
all those years ago I wouldn't have
bothered spending so much time and
effort and money in making this thing
who would who wants to spend that much
time copying something essentially and
southland it a little vexing is an
understatement it was a little more soul
destroying but this led me to make it
better are used what I'd already learned
to make the tool better so I'm going to
show you the video of that tool I'm not
going to show you the tool itself
because I'm not risking a repeater
before but here is an action
so this is me zeroing the disks so the
tool going into the lock this is the
tool doing its magic day long it takes
is it open 13 seconds
yeah that didn't work did it thank you
PowerPoint okay let's have a quick look
at some of the stars is Declassified
tools
thanks to Arthur my stuff for letting me
show these they're his tools this is
quite an interesting one we have these
six plungers each of which operate one
of these six little arms on the end and
once you pick the lock
you've got the thumb screws that you can
then tighten down and it'll act as okay
the Stars he didn't invent this method
but this was their take on it so this is
a comb pick it's not really a lot
picking device it's more of a bypass
tool so instead of lifting these pins to
the gap here and the pins gap gap gap
gap the key would put them here whereas
this tool it's everything up high high
high so that there's nothing here
stopping the lock from opening it's
actually quite an old technique this is
a picture from a patent from 1934 so
it's older than star Z but this is quite
an interesting take on it this brass box
this is for using this tool one-handed
so the end here sort of slides in an app
and you can slide it out and it's like
it looks anyway like you use in the key
very sneaky this is another tool I
developed maybe three or four years ago
it's for picking lever locks and you can
see there are four little ends here and
each one moves independently now I was
really proud of this and it once again I
soon as I saw the star Z tools I
realized it had been done better 35
years ago this is a five in one is there
anything unique left to build I wonder
can anyone guess who this belonged to
this is a makeup key so what this means
is you can change the little bits on the
ends to form any key that you like can
anyone guess anyone seen this before
no Harry Houdini he was a great lock
picking himself this is one of his tools
and every soften on the internet you get
some mad tools pop up this isn't a
secret tool but I'm not really sure what
it does any ideas
bit of a plug
and from the ridiculous to the sublime
look at this how nice of these so the
story about these was a couple of months
ago on the subreddit lock-picking
subreddit some guy posted this picture
and said does anyone know how these work
or what they're for and within 24 hours
he deleted the post and he deleted his
user account you only have to look at
these to see that these are scream
government tat yeah really
I'd love to know what what how these
work a bit of wire here what's that for
and finally let's just have a quick
comparison between the digital and the
physical world in terms of obscurity so
in the digital world we have volt seven
WikiLeaks Snowden's work that expose
secret government digital tools there's
nothing like that for the physical world
no one's ever released a database of
pictures of physical tools the closest
we ever get is when Locke companies
refused to acknowledge that a
vulnerability exists and so someone
might put a YouTube up shaming the lock
company in the digital world we have
formalized structures for declaring
vulnerabilities like bug bounty programs
again there's nothing like this in the
physical world
in my experience lock makers tend to
want to know the vulnerabilities and
give you nothing more than a pat on the
head as compensation so there's no
incentive to tell them it's not a thing
in the physical world there's a huge
number of researchers looking at digital
problems relatively it's a growing
number in the physical world but it's
tiny in comparison and if you find a
problem nowadays most software can be
patched remotely how do you do that with
a lock if someone finds a vulnerability
in a lock and there are three million of
those locks out there in the world the
lock company isn't gonna be interested
in going and replacing all those locks
that's going to cost money they don't
care about that
so I suppose from that perspective
vulnerability disclosure is a lot more
of a pain in the ass for the physical
world but I hope one day that the
physical world will catch
with the digital world I think they have
to copy the model at some point because
we've got the internet now and
information is so freely available and
hopefully that's where things will go in
the future fingers crossed
that's it we're done thank you for
listening
[Applause]
I kind of feel scared now
don't be scared I mean if a government
wants to get into your house they're
gonna do it whatever
are there any pressing questions we have
about two minutes left for questions I
think you can do you can ask them
directly all right free hugs afterwards
I would say if there are any more
questions there's a lock-picking village
you can always find me in a lock-picking
village I've got a selection of more
tools with me if you want to talk about
them our mind sharing Yin
so please another round of applause for
an awesome talk
[Applause]
[Music]