[Music]
hello everybody welcome back to this a
very nice lecture hall out of the Sun
today or now we are going to talk about
this very intimate and important topic
of cyber crime and we have a very good
expert here he's a criminal defense
attorney and is specialized in
cybercrime so he's going he promised he
will answer a lot of questions about
cybercrime give it up for a natural
hemorrhage
[Applause]
[Music]
okay hear me yeah good so how good
evening I'm mouthful hey Mertz
Colonel defense attorney from Amsterdam
and I'm gonna try to explain something
about the wonderful world of criminal
law and a special cybercrime why am i
hosting this event
oh wow this bright first of all I want
to provide some common knowledge about
computer crime because in my practice I
noticed that a lot of people have
questions about it and there's also some
misconceptions and furthermore I want to
raise some legal questions
societal questions about legal
developments as it comes to for example
hacking powers of the government and
also I want to emphasize the
collaboration between hackers and
lawyers and I think at the end of this
talk you would agree with me at least I
hope so
so my talk has three chapters first one
is common misconceptions about criminal
law and the second one is the war on
encryption and the third one is about
cryptocurrencies and money laundering so
about the misconceptions of criminal law
we often hear law is slow and always one
step behind and I would like to ask you
who agrees with that statement raise
your hand and who says no laws pretty
fast it can adapt disagree with
statement what was something else okay
you're the only one anyway oh wait you
also screw with statement a to you well
in my opinion
law is quite slow you need to go to
legislative powers you need to make the
law of draft it needs to be voted on it
could take one two three four or five
years before a law is adapted but
criminal law is actually pretty adaptive
it can bend in some way and I can show
that with an example about stealing
electricity when the Dutch criminal code
was written he could only steal goods
like stuff and electricity legally
spoken is not stuff it's not good so
then electricity came available for the
average person and there was a man who
actually stole it well he took
electricity without permission and
without paying for it so police arrested
him took him to court and of course his
defense attorney said well the criminal
criminal code in the Netherlands
prohibits stealing stuff but electricity
is not stuff right so what you're gonna
do about it that went all the way to the
Supreme Court in the Netherlands and the
Supreme Court finding the rules yeah
it's true electricity is not stuff and
yeah it's true
you can only legally steal stuff but
we're gonna bend the law in that way
that electricity is now also stuff and
by that from that moment on stealing
electricity was illegal and it shows
that you don't need long legislative
procedures to adapt a law to some new
techniques feuless later that was the
same with a computer game is called
runescape the West's guy had a mask and
a novelette he paid a lot of effort for
gathering it and this other guy the
suspect he broke into his account
and they took he took his ambulance and
his mask and the guy got pretty pissed
about it and he went to the police
and said well this guy stole my digital
goods so the guy got arrested and it
went to court and then the court had to
examine whether an amulet and a mask in
a computer game runescape is eligible
for stealing because it's not a good
it's not it's not stuff it's just ones
and zeroes right so Supreme Court rules
okay now we're going to interpret
stealing and stuff in a broader sense so
that everything you can dominate and
that it's not multipliable and it has
any value you can steal so now from that
moment on you can steal computer
programs as long as you're not allowed
to multiply and it's like three basic
rules of them what the Supreme Court
said it you need to dominate it you need
to control it it has to have value and
you cannot multiply it if it's freely
multiplier volts of course not able to
steal I will later in this talk I will
get to some more examples about it now
let's go to the second statement if
something is not forbidden it's legal
raise your hand if you think that's true
and raise your hand if you think that's
not true
this question is binary in theory it's
actually it's actually true because we
have like most countries the first
article of our criminal code says
something is only illegal if we say it's
illegal you can do basically everything
you want
unless it's written down that it is
prohibited criminally of course that is
the law but then there is politics and
sometimes society thinks that something
should be criminal whilst there is no
law prohibiting that kind of behavior
and we have a really nice example that
in the Netherlands it's the Dutch decoy
minor and it's about grooming and
grouping means it's illegal to go on the
internet start a chat and chat with
somebody underage and trying to get
sexual intercourse it's called grooming
and one of the most severe crimes you
can commit in an ellen's so there was
this guy who went online to a chat
website and he was talking to this other
person which he thought was underage and
he started negotiating and he said ok
let's meet with intent to have sex with
intercourse so the police busted down
his house and he got arrested but then
in the end it appeared that he was not
talking to a young girl but to a pretty
old police officer
it was the the decoyed minor was a
police officer acting acting like he was
a little girl but he wasn't so if you
look at what happened technically
there's this just this guy he's an
adults talking on line to this other guy
who is also an adult that's factual what
happened but still he had the intent to
talk to somebody who is her age
but intent is not criminally liable and
at least in most countries so just this
case when also to the Supreme Court and
the defense attorney obviously said well
basically he talked to a police officer
who is overage so our law doesn't
prohibit that or law prohibits speaking
to this minor but then the Supreme Court
ruled yeah that's true but society
doesn't really like that so we're gonna
configure anyway oh of course I'm
overstressing it a bit it's it's more
legal talk about it but that's where it
comes down to and that also works for
investigative powers and we have most
countries have a sole book for that and
the Netherlands it's called the Code of
Criminal Procedure and it says article 1
says the police can only do things that
were authorized them to do so there must
be a law giving them a power to
investigate otherwise they don't have
any power and there's this interesting
case it's about marijuana farm and there
were police officers that said ok we
think in these houses and marijuana farm
and we want to go inside we want to
break down the door arrest people and
take everything with us now everybody
knows you need an arrest warrant for
that right and you need a warrant for
breaking into the house so they called
an assistant prosecutor who is allowed
to issue those warrants and this
assistant prosecutor said yeah sure I
believe you I think there's marijuana at
a house - here's your warrant go have
fun and police went inside and of course
they found marijuana form they arrested
some people and they went to court but
then they found out that this assistant
prosecutor and he didn't he feel this
exam and he did a retake and he filled
that as well so legally he was not an
assistant prosecutor and he issued a
warrant
so the defense attorney said well if
this this person who is like not an
assistant prosecutor issues a warrant
the world is invalid so all evidence
that has been found must be taken out of
the court case and the district court
agreed and they got acquitted because
all the evidence that has been found
due to the false warrant was excluded
from the case and then it went to the
higher court the higher court found the
same but then it went to the Supreme
Court and the Supreme Court ruled yeah
this assistant prosecutor was not an
assistant prosecutor because he failed
his exams and it's mandatory to pass the
exams in order to be assistant
prosecutor and yeah they went inside and
gathered evidence but the Supreme Court
said the warrant itself is Fallot and if
the assistant prosecutor who was not
were actually an assistant prosecutor
Dan it was a legal warrant and then you
could say well I even my nephew can
issue warrants and if it weren't so Kay
then you just do as you please well that
actually happened that happened in 2013
and me and my colleagues were pretty
surprised by it because the whole rule
that you need a law before something is
prohibited I need a lot to give people
authority is being violated by that in
some way
and the fruit one I heard that when I
was talking to people who are in
encrypted currencies a lot and they say
yeah especially with distribution of
technical programs the globalization is
causing just your jurisdictional
problems for example their de ledger a
ledger of Bitcoin it's everywhere are
you gonna prosecute somebody how are you
going to how does it work if you use and
distributed the OS attack and it's it
comes from everywhere what what happens
for jurisdiction can you prosecute in
the Netherlands even though all the data
comes from other countries what if you
use a VPN or a tor browser so the
question is technical globalization
causes jurisdictional problems and who
thinks that that's true raise your hand
and who thinks all that's that's not
really a problem
oh he's actually right it's not it's
it's not a problem at all it's just
impractical but legally speaking it's
not a problem
because it doesn't matter where someone
someone's computer or someone's program
physically is located and sometimes that
that's that's hard to explain but
jurisdiction legally works in a
different manner and I'll I'll state the
basis of jurisdiction for you now most
countries have three two or three
grounds to base jurisdiction on and one
of the most common uses is the principle
of territoriality the state says well
this is my territory if you commit a
crime here I'm going to prosecute you
that's what basically every country does
that's normal but then again there's
also the nationality of the suspect for
example if you're a German and you're
gonna commit a crime abroad and you come
back Germany can actually say well you
committed a crime and we don't care what
you did it if you did it in the
Netherlands or a Switzerland we can
prosecute you
it's only for more severe crimes though
and there's also something like
nationality of the victim for example if
you murder a Dutch citizen and in
Ecuador and Dutch the Dutch police can
get a hold on you you will be prosecuted
and convicted and there's also some
interesting thing it's called universe
universality that's most for like the
most drivers of crimes like war crimes
and crimes against humanity and for
example like some countries like Belgium
they think that okay we have universal
jurisdiction over some really great
crimes we don't care who you are we
don't care where you come from we don't
care which to whom you committed a crime
we think this is so bad that we're going
to prosecute you anyway
it's some self-proclaimed police power
and the interesting thing it's it's
complimentary it means that jurisdiction
can exist besides each other an
interesting example for is if a Swiss
guy in France takes a sniper and shoots
a German guy in Italy people think okay
you can break your head over to his
diction but it's not really a problem
because which countries have
jurisdiction all of them based on those
principles all of them have jurisdiction
and the whole point is who is gonna
prosecute yeah that's just politics
that's that's legally not really
interesting if you think about that
airplane that was crashed by some
entities in Eastern Europe mh17 the word
Dutch Dutch people hunted in the plane
so the Mellon's can prosecute the brain
crash in Ukraine train can prosecute the
perpetrator might be Russian Russia and
kept prosecute so there's numerous
countries that can actually prosecute
destroying of the plane and who is
actually going to prosecute that's
politics
and with these questions I hope like in
a couple of minutes to show you a bit
that criminal law is not it's not a
science it's not an exact science like
physics for example it's some people a
lot programmers thinking yes or no
there's always a right answer if your
mathematician you're looking for an
answer
Laurie is unfortunately but also
fortunately think more in great skills
it's if there's no yes sir there's no no
sometimes the same question has two
answers depending on the time twenty
years ago the same question would have a
different answer in empirical science
that you cannot imagine that in if it in
law law Benzes law breaks laws adapted
it's it's there's a lot of politics in
it and especially criminal law sometimes
if society wants something to be illegal
it just is and although you need like a
fundamental law says you need to write
it down first in in a criminal code
before it's illegal but if we really
want to and there's really a societal
pressure on it the law can be bent and
you can just use an old article that
just just doesn't cover it really we
just break it open bend it a bit and
then it fits the second part I want to
talk to you about is the war on
encryption and it's not really a war but
I like to state it that way and it's
about what happens in in the Western
world and now that people say okay in
order to be safe we need to we need to
know everything we need to follow we
need to listen to communication we need
to tap phone calls or need to do to
break into encryption and of course
there's a lot to say about our safety
there's like a lot of stories about
terrorist threats and all evil that's
happening to us right now and there are
people working day and night to protect
us from
any harm that we might not know about
the problem is that in order to do so
they want to know everything they want
to look into every detail of people's
lives so we can say yeah it's just a
little bit of your privacy but then you
can be safe the question is when it's
stopped and I think most of you heard
about the zero day exploits it's and
that the government can leave open if
they if they notice about a Filner
ability in a device or in a program for
example in a phone there's there's a
leak and that can be if somebody knows
about that leak it could break into your
phone what some governments do is say
well if we find out about this leak
we're not gonna we're not gonna stop it
we're just gonna keep it secret and used
for itself we're gonna exploit it so
that we can actually still hack into two
phones of people because they really do
not like encryption even now with
whatsapp most people a lot of people
don't know but they are talking now
encrypted with each other on whatsapp
and it's really hard now for the
investigative authorities and
intelligence agencies to to follow
what's being said but if there would be
a firm ability in iphone or in and or in
an Android phone and the government
knows about it they want to keep it
silent so they and they alone can get
into your phone and listen to what you
say anyway the problem is that people
working for the government they'll they
have good hackers and but also the
blackhat hackers have good hackers and
they also can find filner abilities and
you can see it like couple of weeks ago
we had a really big ransomware attack
that used one of these those four
abilities of whom people say that it was
left open by some authorities and also
what to do about encryption there's this
company it's called peach be safe what
they did is they had blackberries they
sold it they adapted it a bit and the
cryptid the blackberries and all the
communications were fire their own
servers so it was impossible for the
police to do tap wired the phone calls
they made and they were in a really good
business they had thousands of phones
they sold so people could actually speak
in private with each other but then one
day there was a raid and the police
stormed inside the office of PGP safe
they took the servers and they arrested
a lot of people and the question is okay
I know some agencies don't like
encryption but you should know that
encrypting communication is not illegal
it's just math right providing an
encryption surface is also not illegal
and selling phones with encryption is
also not illegal so what this company
did is its finest it's like it's not
prohibited but the prosecutors stated
yeah well that is true but you're
facilitating criminal organizations
hurry yeah they say that their money
laundering but they also said like
you're facilitating criminal
organization that's gonna be where they
go to prison
yeah oh there's a guy saying there are
also suspected of money laundering yeah
that's true but they're also going to be
prosecuted for facilitating criminal
organization the whole point is that
this is a company that uses encryption
and now some of them are in jail and I
could raise questions about is that
where we want to go if somebody allows
other people to talk in private
what happens is that is that a problem
because yeah of course criminals use
encrypted phones but also journalists do
also lawyers I have an encrypted phone
to talk with some clients because I know
the government is listening to what I'm
saying to my clients when I have a
normal
panco and the whole point is that we
will see in the end because this case
will come to trial we see if you can
actually convict somebody for just
providing an encryption service because
whatsapp is also encrypted service and
also criminals use whatsapp so what
you're gonna do are you gonna arrest
everybody what's up
also photo phone it's it's it's a normal
phone company but there are also
criminals you use photos oh so now
you're gonna rest like the CEO photo
phone I don't I don't I don't see any
difference in there but we'll see how it
ends up and well in the Netherlands
there's even more we have this new law
and it's already accepted and it said
that the police can soon legally hack
almost everything and they can do that
in order to investigate certain crimes
and the question is yeah almost
everything yes almost everything because
the police can hack into your computer
to computers but the definition of
computer is device or group of mutually
connected or coherent devices of which
one or more automatically stores data
and so basically it's a device that's
connected that stores data I'm not sure
about you but that's pretty much every
device I have in my house even my remote
controlled storage data and so the
police could be able to hack my remote
control and another law that lets passed
is the legalization of exploiting
vulnerabilities their way to debate
legislative powers had a debate about it
like okay should we do that and there
were some political parties that said no
I don't think that's a good idea one of
her parties had pleadings of one hour
and say okay people maybe maybe were
going too far maybe don't
don't like leave open for liability
system if you if you find out about a
film ability close it that's better for
everybody so they wanted to made an
amendment but that amendment was
rejected and now the Netherlands will
have in a few months
legally the power to exploit
vulnerabilities there's one thing that
didn't make it that's I don't know if
you can read it but its decryption
warrants what our government wanted is
the power for the prosecutor to say okay
this is your device it has a password
open it now and if you don't you're
going to jail just for not complying
with my warrant so is you a warrant to
decrypt any information the problem is
that there's also something like human
rights some people tend to forget about
it and one of the most fundamental human
rights is that nobody can be forced to
comply with his own conviction you
cannot force somebody to work with the
police to convict himself so you cannot
you cannot you cannot put somebody in
jail because he's unwilling to unlock
his phone for you so that one didn't
pass but we don't we never know what
might happen in the future of course and
I saw this tweet a couple of days ago
from Edward Snowden figures interesting
to share and it's about Theresa May and
she says I'm clear if human right law
get in the way of tackling extremism and
terrorism we will change those laws to
keep British people safe and Edward
Snowden looked at this this tweet it
said okay well if we take all the
emotional words out she's basically
saying if human rights laws get in the
way we will change them and the more
scared we're getting the more Sheena
phobia is in our society the more human
rights law server like privacy service a
lot but also
the right to not be disturbed by the
police the right did not work with your
own conviction and in the last few years
me my colleague we noticed that a lot of
fundamental rights are being violated
because of safety and I'm not saying
that that that we shouldn't have tried
to have a safer country as possible but
it's always it's a gap between the
safety of your country and also the
fundamental rights of your country
because sometimes they they do not
interact well for example privacy so for
our security our Internet becomes less
safe and our privacy is being restricted
and what if I don't like that what you
do about it
well as I've told you first have the
executive powers they they want more
investigative powers more afford to
research to investigate and so they ask
the legislative powers please please
give us give us more authority and the
legislative powers just did they passed
a bill so now you can do better you can
hack everything you can prosecute people
who are going to encrypt but now it's up
to the judicial power and their goal is
to uphold fundamental rights as well so
is there a universal declaration of
human rights and the European Convention
on Human Rights and all kind of national
laws that protect you me everybody here
and our privacy and I see it as as a
goal of hackers and lawyers to inform
those judges that are going to make the
decisions now this year next year is
gonna be there going to be a lot of
cases about crypto currencies about
encryption that judges need to decide on
they need to decide ok we're going left
or we're going right and in order to
make an informed decision these judges
need to be informed and that's that's
one of my tasks as a lawyer to present
a different viewing point on the case so
that he the judge can make proper
decision but also for hackers because
I'm a lawyer I don't I don't know a lot
about technical stuff right I'm I
specialize in cybercrime but I'm still
I'm not I'm not a programmer I don't
know I don't know a lot about how a US
attack actually works no lawyer knows
but a lot of people if you they do know
but they do not know how to explain for
example to a judge what is the
consequence of his decision and I think
that judges need to understand the
consequences of their decisions because
if they don't if they're not informed
you can say yeah well encryption it
sounds like thing they're only criminals
use let's just make it illegal
it could be oh of course I'm
exaggerating but if it Church is not
informed about importance for example of
encryption you cannot make a proper
judgment so I see it as a goal of
combined no hackers and lawyers to to
inform judges judges about it I'll come
back to that later
because then their first topic I want to
talk about is cryptocurrencies and money
laundering and I basically took two
questions for you and who of you owns
some kind of crypto currency like
Bitcoin or easier or more narrow it's
just basically everybody yeah okay so
who've you are familiar with there are
national anti money laundering
regulations oh there's a lot of work to
do well just just to have a start
extremely short
what are crypto currencies legally and
I'm talking about criminal law private
law what's what's governing between
civilians I don't care about for now
it's criminal law how are they
considered and the best way to to
interpret it is they're like bottle caps
they're just their stuff but our example
from VI T so in Rotterdam a judge
decided that that bitcoins are like
dudes it's stuff it's a thing it's it's
not money but Europe European Union
decided that it would be pretty bad if
you need to pay VD every transaction
because that then you take away the
whole goal of Bitcoin as a trading
currency so for criminal law you can
just like their little stones their
sands their bottle caps don't know how
you what you want to say about it but
it's their things but you don't have to
pay tax they're like it's some kind of
twilight song and there is some problems
with with money laundering laws with
that and money laundering regulations
are fairly difficult and they they
differ a lot from country to country so
I'm going to talk about the
Dutch framework of money laundering and
money laundering is by our law he who
possesses acquires has available
transfers or converts any object while
snowing or should know that the object
in some way derives from any criminal
offense right let's let's break that
down he who possesses acquires has
available transfer comforts
that's this basically everything so the
first part of money laundering check any
objects well the court in the
Netherlands ruled that bitcoins are
objects so check and then there's the
third part it's like so if you possess a
Bitcoin whilst knowing or should know
that the object in some way derives from
any criminal offense any criminal
offense means that you do not need to
know which criminal offense as long as
you know or should know that it's from
something bad happened to it
but the whole problem is that if you see
with cash all money eventually sooner or
later will be used in some way illegal
transaction if you wait a lot if you did
bitcoins change from owner to owner and
eventually somebody is gonna buy drugs
with it and from that moment on it does
that Bitcoin or Eater derives from a
criminal offense
and the problem with with
cryptocurrencies is that in contrast to
cash you can actually see you can follow
the path it has taken everybody can look
up in the blockchain what the history of
transactions is they say okay how would
I know whether my coin derives from a
criminal offense because if I look in
the blockchain I cannot see what it was
a drugs transaction it's just it's just
a lot of numbers well then you have
wallet Explorer calm and this is a tool
or the Dutch prosecutor uses it and it
makes some data analysis with an
algorithm and it shows that where the
coins have been and then it knows about
some public key and with some really
interesting but for me not
understandable algorithm it calculates
that for example this wallet the coins
have been on a braixen market and on
nucleus market I'm not sure if you can
see it's a bit small on that screen but
this is a few of wallet explorer comm
you can type in any public key and it
just shows where it has been and
sometimes it recognizes it this coin has
been on a break stock market so the
prosecutor now he uses world Explorer to
prove that the coin of my clients
derives from a criminal offence you say
yeah you can see it a break so market
that's a dark market and they almost
solely sell illegal goods there so
there's actually a case I'm doing now
and the prosecutor made this statement
and in short the coins derived from a
criminal offense you can see it in what
an exploratory call the he did he did
something shady with it because he
bought the coins with cash and they were
talking encrypted and they were meeting
in the street
which is of course fine it's legal you
can meet in the street and you can
interact you can do what any deal you
like because it's coins it's not drugs
but the prosecutor says the owner knew
or should have known such what's the
case because I can see it and what an
explorer that the coins derived from a
criminal offense so the buyer can also
see it so he should have known and now
he's accepting bitcoins that derives
from a criminal offense does he is a
money launderer yeah I'm gonna raise
some some legal questions about that
this this case is going to be in
December and they arrested quite a few
people that just what did the only thing
they did is buying coins and giving cash
back and it did not investigate where
the coins derive from but that my
questions for the judges are the first
one is is there a duty to investigate
the origin of received coins just
because you can with cash you cannot or
well it's really hard but with bitcoins
it's fairly easy so if you can
investigate it is there a duty to
investigate it so and if you feel that
Judi
do you take the risk of being a money
longer and I think it's gonna be really
interesting to see what the judge is
gonna decide on this because if they
decide yeah there's a duty to
investigate that's that's gonna change
how people interact with bitcoins a lot
and if there is a duty to investigate
how far do you need to look back is that
one per Section two three four or the
beginning of time is a Bitcoin still
tainted if twenty transactions ago it is
used for a drug transport and cannot
cannot I use it then anymore how far
does that duty to investigate reach if
it exists and also does the mere fact
that a coin has been on the dark market
prove that it derives from a criminal
offense because you can upload your some
bitcoins or e term when arrows to a dark
market
just sits there and on dark market you
can buy drugs weapons counterfeit money
but also manuals and manuals for loan
picking for instance that's not illegal
so what if I uploaded my money to a dark
market just to buy manuals of course I
can order it via Amazon but let's just
say I did that
does that make my coin illegal or what
if I uploaded some bitcoins to a dark
market because I was wanting to buy
drugs but later it says maybe just not
do it and I just take it off again then
world X Explorer which show a alert this
coin has been on the dark market and now
you're a money launderer because you
know so I'm I'm interested to see how
the judge is gonna decide about that
part and also that's that's the last
part can a prosecutor legally use wallet
Explorer to prove the origin of a
Bitcoin it's like it's what we'll
explore is made by I think check guy
it's an algorithm and I'm sure the
prosecutor doesn't understand the
algorithm I don't understand the author
in many churches ours or not
understanding the algorithm but the
point is some of you do understand this
algorithm and that's that's to come back
to my story is that hackers and lawyers
should in some way work together because
I'm applying the law I'm providing these
questions to the judge
I also need help of people that explain
to me to the prosecutor and to the judge
how wallet Explorer works
it's it is it's the algorithm is there
are there flaws in it does it work
correctly how how does it work what are
the consequences of accepting it
and that's basically by a question if
there's any anybody of you who is
interested in this topic and you want to
to take a look at this algorithm model
explore use and you're willing to
provide information to the court to you
to our firm about how works you want to
negotiate or talk about what we could do
about it
just email us text us and we can have to
talk about it there's there's no
obligation or duty to anything but I do
I do not have the wisdom of
understanding is algorithm and I think
I'm never gonna have in my life that the
kind of power but some of you do and I'm
a defense lawyer who is in in this case
with with defending bitcoins so if
there's anybody who is willing to
provide us this information and work
together on it it would be happy with
that okay that's that's the end of my
presentation I think I have some few
minutes to answer questions right yes we
do have some time for questions
[Music]
that's off the first microphone is on
the second microphone is not on no no
yes yeah I hear you stated that our
government is now allowed to use zero
day exploits in criminal investigations
one thing the Minister of Justice said
in this discussion was that they still
committed to doing this responsible
disclosure and that they would after
using zero day exploits take a
responsible path on actually making
public the exploits yeah what are your
thoughts about this sorry what are your
thoughts about this my fault is that if
our government is aware of any ferner
ability to shoot immediately close the
gap and not use it first - to hack for
to hack into the privacy of other
citizens I think it's it's best if you
if you know it it's because every day
Efrain ability stays open is it's a
danger to the Internet safety so I think
they should be closed immediately I'm
not sure but from what I understand so
there's this whole long
long-running discussion about
fungibility of Bitcoin the the right to
spend it and from what I understand is
that with cash as if you accept cash you
are exempt from any responsibilities
about where that cash has been because
if that were not the case we would ruin
our economy if as a merchant if you
would accept cash and it would be your
duty to check what its history was then
it would harm business
yeah couldn't you make the case by
analogy that if you accept Bitcoin that
I mean there has been jurisprudence that
considers Bitcoin a good but there's all
also been jurisprudence that considers
Bitcoin a money and that Bitcoin ban and
that by analogy fall some of that regime
as well yeah sure I think you're making
a really good point there but it's with
cash you're not unlimited allowed to
take enormous amounts of cash there's
also some duty to to investigate there's
some anti-monitor anti-money laundering
laws for example for lawyers jewelers
car dealers that actually do have a duty
to investigate but that's that's
regulated and it starts with a certain
amount of transaction the height I think
is 50,000 euros I guess but you make a
fairly good point I think this should be
an analogy between bitcoins in cash yeah
microphone in the back yeah discussion
with prosecutor about the Bitcoin as
when you receive it well you don't know
which wallets coming from or what coins
were going to receive so yeah yeah I
have a lot of clients that that have a
have bitcoins and they bought a couple
years ago now it's worth pretty much and
they say okay I want I want to cash out
I want to do it legally
I want to comply with all the rules so
they come to our office and say okay
tell me what I should do to
comply with all the rules so I can
legally cash my coins and well me my
colleague investigated it a lot and we
have to tell every client that actually
we do not know and it's not because we
don't know the prosecutor's office also
doesn't know and I don't like the tax
agencies they don't know and actually
what we did is we we call them and we
wrote them a letter I called the
functional pockets in the Netherlands
that's the prosecutor's office that is
capable of making rules about it say
okay please provide us rules or
guidelines on how what we can do what we
cannot do but for now they're not
willing to so it's nobody knows and my
advice is always just do as much as you
can do to do to keep a paper trail okay
paper trail if you don't buy coins with
cash buy them online via brokers and
make screenshot of all the transactions
you do and keep an administration so you
can always prove where your coin comes
from and what you did with it but to be
honest for now it's it's it's
interesting it's a grey zone we're not
we're not now was heading microphone in
the back sorry the microphone in the
back Thanks listen to your presentation
and I'm well now more worried than I was
before
Thanks well it's more long wise if you
say that the loss can be well amended
and will apply there's some entity v
what safeguards are there to prevent us
to well becoming and then excuse my
language Banana Republic or something
alike if every gesture every entity can
interpret it in a way they see fit well
that is actually a good question of
course the judges don't have limited
power in bending and in the in the 80s
we had a really strict way of
interpreting law so that you just don't
have room to in to interpret some kind
of writing
like code of conduct but the last years
we see to my opinion unfortunately that
this the room for interpretation is
being broadened for example the examples
I gave you are like are the most extreme
versions of what judges did to to apply
old laws to new facts but it's also a
money-laundering at the time the
Criminal Code for money laundering was
written Bitcoin didn't exist any
cryptocurrency didn't exist so now
applying old laws that are not they
didn't think by then when they were
writing it they didn't think about okay
what happens with cryptocurrencies not
it didn't because there were no
cryptocurrencies but now we're applying
this old wall to new techniques and yeah
that raises questions and I'm I'm
wondering how it will end up that way
but I'm I wouldn't say that we're a
banana republic she say it but I think
we had better times in case of
fundamental rights yeah okay thanks in
addition to the Bitcoin word do you have
any experience with those zero zero
knowledge coins like Zeb cash zero cash
and Moneo because then it's very
difficult if you have these anonymous
young sanctions that's for example more
narrow with with the three keys to be
frank nobody knows what's going to
happen with that and I wouldn't be
surprised if for example more narrow
would in some day be forbidden in the
Netherlands because there is no way or
authorities or intelligence agencies can
look into that for now I've talked to
somebody about it and they said okay
bitcoin that's very easy we're gonna
watch it either as well but when there
was it's just black hole for us and it
depends on where society goes but there
is a chance that that or government will
decide okay well that's too risky that's
that's too perfect for
no that's too perfect for money
laundering maybe just prohibit it but I
don't know it's it's it's it's politics
democracy we can fought about it so
we'll see what happens
microphone in the front well the state
support program programs different
programs to break in the computers of
everyone after of everyone of any user
what if broken computer is used by a bad
boy and what is if bad boys get these
programs I'm sure they won't be in
secret very long sir I didn't stand the
less sentence I'm sure these programs
will not get in bad hands
yeah nobody knows I'm not sure how or or
police is going to to hack our systems
but if they if they develop a program
for it yeah that they shoot make sure
that it doesn't fall into bad hands as
you say but of course there's there's no
guarantee to it at all but of course
there needs to be safeguards for it of
course you cannot guarantee but to be
honest I'm not sure and how they're
gonna do it or if they're gonna develop
their own programs for hacking I'm not
I'm not sure but yeah if they make a
program it can fall in the wrong hands
and also before the next question what I
want to say about money laundering of
bitcoins yeah it's it's a bit scary and
yeah I'm worried but as a normal
hobbyist Bitcoin user you shouldn't be
too afraid for prosecution because the
prosecution is primarily focused on the
notorious cash traders that the trade
cash for ten thousand euros at least and
do it by fine encryption phones in back
alleys in the dark on the street
those are the guys they're trying to get
if you have a Bitcoin wallet or an ether
wallet and some coins derives from a
criminal offense I'm I don't think he
should be too worried though it could be
technically illegal depends on what's
going to happen but if some points of
you are tainted I shouldn't worry too
much as long as you're not going on the
streets buying with cash and hanging out
with shady people with it
okay microphone in the back okay
actually it just replied to my question
which was whether you think there is a
motive for these persecutions other than
money laundering no no now there now of
course their capacity is limited and
they're focusing on some people that
actually everybody knows that they're
buying bitcoins that derives from drugs
and because they're following there's
observations but there's a legal problem
behind it that could affect everybody
but the prosecutors just mainly focused
on drug trafficking drug traffickers and
also regarding loans that are about to
be introduced or that have already been
introduced for example about zero day
vulnerabilities yeah are you aware
whether this is the result of alignment
with EU directives or is this a primary
lawmaking process here in the
Netherlands it's in primary lawmaking
process in the Netherlands I'm not aware
of any European rules about it now
thank you I wanted to hear from you
legal consequences if my computer is
through one of these programs of the
state question it might be if it's a big
business well that could be very costly
so basically if if I get you right
you're asking what if my computer gets
hacked by criminals using the program of
yeah of our government that's the
interesting question about liability
that's not criminal law though it's
simple all you need to sue the
government because you have damages I'm
not sure it's it moved away from the
field of criminal law to private law
which I'm not an expert in but it's a
good maybe you could ask bit for freedom
maybe we have a good answer to that
question but it's an interesting case
though and there I think you already
have some cybercrime court date and I
would like to ask if did the judges
understand when you explain some
technical stuff what they're judging it
if they're like understand it and then
fourth up well what they would to fuck
up if I'd touch the false way did they
like really think about it when you
explained the technical stuff behind it
what it would be if they really have the
false decision for they're all the
people outside well judges can only make
a decision if they feel informed enough
and often they're hired people to to
give that information to them and in the
Netherlands we have for cybercrime
there's in The Hague there's a
cybercrime office of all churches that
they can call or email and they get
information about it and it's also I
think the duty of the prosecutor to if
he builds a case to make sure that the
consequences of a conviction of the case
he brought to the court are known but
also for defense the defense attorneys
there's there's a lot of work to do to
provide this information because of
course I believe the judges and melons
are well informed and are trying to be
as formed as possible but you do not
know what you do not know all right
so if there's somebody discovers
anything like okay hey this this man
this might be really bad implication to
that decision speak up
call a lawyer goes in the newspaper to
try something because I think especially
in this in this new area especially
law cybercrime is relatively new and
there's and in the upcoming years
there's a lot of decisions to make and
we all should make sure that the
decisions that are being made are as
well-informed as possible thank you
okay microphone in front we have time
for one or two questions it's a matter
of time before it comes known that our
police has used an urn up to that moment
unknown
vulnerability to hack into systems of
people that are being trialed in a
criminal criminal court so you asked
earlier in your presentation if we could
help you make a case against this crypto
currency problem I have something I can
ask you to do for us so as early in time
as possible let us know when you find in
a criminal case evidence that our police
has used open vulnerabilities to hack
potential criminals yeah as much data as
possible in technical way about these
zero days so that we can make sure that
those zero days then get patched in the
real world and so that we can start
civil cases against the government for
not having made public the information
about the zero zero day exploits that
could have potentially have done harm to
our computers so that we can actually
try and get money from the government
for not having made public debt which is
their public duty to actually make our
world safer okay I'm gonna
[Applause]
I'm gonna I'm gonna promise you this as
soon as I'm aware of our government
using this vulnerability and I'm allowed
allowed to to make that information
public I will do so I will do so I that
that's a promise I would I would I
wouldn't even just put it on our website
I would go to any newspaper that will
hear it to explain that yeah you have my
word on that we have time for one more
question okay so one of the years ago
German just from one of the highest
courts would not occur about the German
paragraph on money laundering and like
his hypothesis was that this paragraph
being expanded and expanded every year
basically is violating the the law
meanwhile because the it basically
leaves only a very little chance of not
committing that crime because so he made
a calculation based on the annual usage
of drugs in Germany and the usual price
of that and the fact that something is
considered money-laundering if it was
paid by at least 1% of money that
results from a from a crime so you can
like have hundred times the the tainted
amount of money and comparing the the
vast vast amount of money that is
tainted by this fact there's basically
most of the money that flows around the
Germany is tainted and therefore you
even if you don't know whether your
specific money comes from that the the
vast amount of money and shows that by
statistics at least it's it's quite
probable that
you have some money that without a
former crime on your bank account
therefore you basically have no chance
of not committing that crime so you're
making a good case because what's
criminal law if everything you do is
criminal anyway you need to make you
need to split up between actual money
laundering okay what is not actually
what what did somebody did wrong what's
the wrongdoing in it except for just
possessing cash that is tainted or a bit
coins that are tainted yeah maybe you
can adapt that to bitcoins sure that
that's gonna be and also in words but if
you can statistically prove that like
those kind of resources are the
researchers are like because then you
can just show how how idiot it can be
sometimes yeah you make a good point of
that thank you very much let's think on
ours again now it again for a hysto
[Music]