[Music]
our next speaker has been motivating
kids to code for more than 12 years she
has written multiple books and
participated in the world record for
kids programming with more than 11,000
children from all over the Netherlands
please welcome Paulina Maas thank you
[Applause]
I'm honored to speak here in a rainy
evening here in Holland I hope I can
warm you a little bit with my talk if
you have any questions please interrupt
me because I'm happy to answer and help
you with any questions you have yeah
my name is paulina mas I'm originally a
teacher but when I finished my my my
University there was no work for me
so I started off in the computers and
the computers look like that when I
started so that's really a long time ago
I did it for a very long time but then I
thought if I want to have some female
colleagues I have to start in education
because there are no education about
computers and coding and making websites
and apps in schools so I did it for
almost 15 years ago and now a teacher
for 2 days a week that's all my school I
work at a special education needs school
we have we had a we have a makers lab
and we do lots of coding but also make
doing fun things working with the green
screen making stop animation and more
things at this moment I am busy with a
very big project that we are decorating
Christmas tree for instance in Amsterdam
in einem in Rotterdam with 2,000 lights
in there and hum the children they will
coat the Christmas lights on the big
market places if there are any people
from Holland's here and you have some
con
connections with governments your local
governments and you want to do something
coding the Christmas tree would hum the
children please come to me because we
have a nice project doing that my book
my last book was published two years ago
I wrote it with 40 people and it got 40
different kind of tools how you can
start with coding in schools and of
course I'm a mother and we have 4
children they are all studying two of
them are in Delft University and they
are really busy with one of them is well
two of them is starting to be an
engineer so and I'd like to do fun
things here I made the I made a Rubik's
Cube with the Lego Mindstorms and it
Souls it sells it just took me quite a
lot of time to fix it but when it worked
I was so proud because it's almost
always very funny to do some has history
who knows same apart
yes very good he died last year sadly
but he was busy in 1960 already with
coding with children and then he said if
you can engage children if you really
know what you're going to make with them
just don't start you have to learn
coding but first start what do you want
to make and he is very important for all
the coding activities who are now at
this moment everywhere in the world I
think he was one of the starters of it
and two weeks ago I was in Bordeaux
there was the big scratch conference and
one of the colleagues of same upper
parts she is called Cynthia Suleiman she
gave his speech and she showed me some
videos some movies what they made and
they were they are from 1965 and there
you can see the children were coding and
they used a turtle maybe you know
somebody know the total robots where you
can code code yes in the back very good
it's a very old movie a
[Music]
computer-controlled turtle is made to
draw you can see the temple and they
were shooting handsome in the first days
of the court
that's the child acquire the tape format
power that grows and grow that he
projects become more original more
complex and more very so this is a
really this is really old and Cynthia
Solomon she was one of the colleagues of
say Mopar parts he did she showed us
more and more movies what they made when
they was they were busy doing research
with children what they learned from
coding and the funny thing is that this
is the blue but who knows the blue birds
yes this is really a starter usually on
schools to start coding with children
and it looks very much like the turtle
yes even now a newer version and it can
fit a pen so he can do really the same
thing as the as the turtle from same
apart and you can code it with a kind of
a scratch environment so a little more
history there this is John Piaget and he
said children have real understanding
only of if they invented themself and I
think that is really important so they
can make something but only if they make
it themself and change it then they know
what is there so if children really
follow a pattern and make something they
haven't learned anything but only if
they reinvent it of changes then they
have literally learned something and
they will never forget that's really
important because when you then they
start with coding usually they do
something and then they have to change
it and change it and change it I will
give some nice examples from that later
and then there was J Annette's wing
she works at Microsoft at the research
in Microsoft and she came up with a
definition
of computational thinking and there's a
very long definition as you can see but
the most important part is that you
solve a problem by using a computer that
is what it is and of course you can
write papers about it but that is the
main part of it that you solve a
computer use a debt yourself a problem
using a computer and I really like
Simona gertz who knows Simona Gertz she
will be in Hollands
in November yes on the bright day in
attract you can buy some cards a lot
really likes money girls because she is
making silly robots to make this you
really have to know what you're doing
she is really reinventing it because of
course she first tried to make
everything and I really like it that she
it's always like crappy you know with
sticky tapes and it is clear together
order this paper and carton and I think
that is the best way when I start making
things with children that they say it
looks it doesn't doesn't look right and
then I always say well you have to start
somewhere
you know the drone wasn't built it was
made and they came up with the idea
let's put a webcam on there there so we
can make some pictures so that is every
time step ahead yeah so but why teach
coding to children that's always the
questions whether always gets because I
am giving lectures a lot on schools
already but we teach children math but
and they use it
but it doesn't mean that they start
working with math when they finish
school that's the same when you start
teaching children coding it doesn't mean
that they have to find a job in there
it's just a way of thinking that is
important and coding can be really the
locomotive to do new things in school
that is really important you can use it
to get money or to to do to get people
doing it and coding is only a part of
computational thinking because computers
computational thinking is much bigger
than only coding in many in many
countries coding is part of the
curriculum at this moment I know that a
Yuki UK is coding as part of the
curriculum
I know Greece is one Estonia is coding
part of the curriculum in France lots of
coding has is being done also in Finland
in Holland too but in Holland it is not
part of the curriculum because in
Holland you always have that there is a
curriculum but a school is not mandatory
to do it they can choose themselves so
schools who are ahead they can do coding
and you can see that parents have a very
important role in their parents can say
we want the school to do coding or we go
to a school where is some coding or
computational thinking or where as a
makers lab because you see the schools
are setting up makers lab as at least
here in Holland so but then you have to
know why are why am i doing that as a
school not because the parents say it or
because there is suddenly some money or
you get something or you think there is
this teacher who think it's very
important know as as a team you must
know why am I doing this in my school
because else it will be only for one
year or two years and you don't want
so there can be different reasons why
you can start with coding in your school
one of the reasons can be it is only for
high at for gifted children people ask
me a lot to come to schools and do a
special project with gifted children
that can be a part of it one part can be
because there will be jobs if we don't
start coding teaching coding or
computational thinking with children
they needed for jobs we don't know that
we cannot look in the future for 15
years if there are really jobs for the
children if we start teaching them now
when they are 8 or 10 years old so you
don't know that also you can do it
because I want to set up a makerspace in
my school that is important I think that
is much more important than starting
with coding and an other thing is
because it solves with creative creative
thinking we don't know that because they
always say when you start with coding
children know learn how creative
thinking is working what we don't know
that because there is has been research
but it has not been so much reserved
data can really can say because the
children had coding or computational
thinking they know now how creative
thinking is working coding will not be
the only way how to learn that I know
that is working but it is not
scientifically proved that will take
much more time so if you know want to do
it as a school you really have to know a
plan and why and you start very small
you have this big idea you start small
and then you just start and then you see
what's comes along and you get more and
more activities to be done what is
really important you need only one
person in your school who is really good
with some technical things
and I'm usually talking to schools of
primary schools then in primary schools
it's not difficult to start with coding
or computational thinking because there
are so many apps and so many websites
and so many easy things what you can do
with children it doesn't cost a lot of
money only you need one person who
really say I can do this I want to do
this so when I give a lecture on schools
or I'll give a workshop then I always
give them tips what they can do tomorrow
that is important that you take them
only one step ahead so they really can
know ok I want to do this I can do this
I will give you some tips later you
don't need a lot of money that's really
important because scratch for instant is
for free and you don't have to buy a 3d
printer on price in primary school you
can do that but I get a lot of phone
calls for school who bought a 3d printer
and now they say Pauline it's standing
there and it's not working anymore or we
don't know what to do with it because
making a 3d paint 3d making something
for the 3d printer is quite difficult so
that is much more for higher education I
guess 3d printer is fun to see how it's
working but also the kids they get bored
after five minutes looking at a 3d
printer and they say okay now I want and
if you print something it's usually this
small and taking half an hour so I'm not
a fan that primary schools are buying 3d
printers which costs a lot of money also
why you see schools they have the Lego
Mindstorms sets sometimes sometimes they
phone me they say we have 10 Lego
Mindstorm sets and we don't do anything
with it can you come over and teach us
and then I came over to that school and
they put all those 10 my
Lego Mindstorm set in one big box can
you imagine all those 10 sets and then I
had to start a class and we had this big
box with ten Megos mines from set all in
there not so what I did I turned it over
in the classroom and we set it and I
said to the children first we're going
to sort it out and we're going to make
something with it that was really
strange for me to see because the school
said yeah we have those Lego Mindstorm
set what we haven't really used it no
because it was standing there not being
used so you don't need a lot of money
because many things are really for free
to do or there's an easy app or you can
do coding with no computer there are
lots of examples what you can do what is
really important if you don't explain
everything to children if you start use
other starts teaching them with
computational thinking if you explain
everything to them they don't think
themselves and of course all the
software is being changed very rapidly
order is a new app what you want to use
so every time they have to figure out
himself and the only way where you can
do that is you can ask you have to ask
questions to them because they always
say it is not working why and then you
have to ask why isn't it working and
then they say well the little girl is
not walking through my screen I said
have you told the computer that your
little girl has to work no walk no I
forgot so that is important so you have
to ask questions if they ask you it is
not working they all you have always
those children you start explaining and
they hand up their finger before you
have even finished talking they have a
question and they say it's not working
and then you have to ask questions and I
hold I proud try to keep my hands on my
back why is that
why is that what yes because in the
beginning I always did it for them on
the computer I bent over and did it for
them and then three minutes later there
was the same question so I always keep
my hands try to keep my hands on my back
and ask them questions have you lived
here look there and then you really see
they they start looking at the screen
and figured out himself
you haven't told the children though
didn't had any lessons in in Minecraft
because they look it up
and you can do the same with other
things that's really important so keep
your hands on your back and make an
atmosphere that they can make a mistake
that is important too because if you
make a mistake that is the first attempt
in learning the next time you do better
the next time you didn't do better that
is really important sometimes they are
afraid to make a nest mistake but they
have to know that it's okay to make a
mistake because then you learn if you
start doing things in your classroom
with children of you will do it with
your own kids make something which is
really not very complicated and make it
so that children who are not so bright
they can understand it too that you can
go lower and may get it easier so they
will understand it to choose something
but is also wide enough so if your
instance you use scratch if there are
children and they want to do music it is
possible or they want to make an
animation it is possible to don't make
it strict I want you to make this game
or this animation no let them be freely
to do what they want because then they
read
you want to know it and they're really
going to learn it and that is important
make it high enough so the ceiling so
they goat so they go up to the ceiling
so they really know what to do with that
with the program and say and they see
how inventive of scratches or something
else is so that is important so how can
you do that that is really important I
will give you now ten tips what I did
the last year in my schools maybe you
know this yeah this is the jam but that
is you can teach coding to children with
no computer at all he is making a
sandwich and the children have to really
tell him how he's making a slice
[Music]
take out red with white and you might
have open the jam right and jam
[Music]
like what on breadsmith quit not great
butter on bread slice with knife cannot
compute to have not picked up and put it
on plate my time to pick up right and
was its own place
I had
butter and spread well this is a nice
example if you follow Phil Berger on
Twitter he is really one of my examples
what he is doing in closest I went to
see him two years ago and I saw him in
Bordeaux two weeks ago he is really very
good and this is part of unplucked cs
and unplucked CS you see lots of
activities what you can do with children
with no computer and starting with an
algorithm and thinking in code in coding
kind of way
so this is one example we're counting
down sooner one this is scratch who
knows who sees a different here yes yes
it's a new version yes this is the new
version it's on github already the new
version of scratch will be available
next year next summer now you can try it
already it looks kind of the same yes no
no no no no no no and you know what the
good part is you can attach very
different kind of things it looks much
more like snap I used embroidery machine
to make something in scratch and attach
the embroidery machine to it so this is
really a very good example we tested it
two weeks ago in Bordeaux on the scratch
conference so no flesh anymore no so you
can try it you can look it up on github
so scratch
very easy up til around ten years it's
nice to do scratch maybe till twelve it
depending on what they want it's very
creative and they make lots of things
here's a nice example what you can do
with no computers and all the kids like
it here we make a functional design of
designing an app the gets get the kids
get very motivated to do that because
they have to think about a name what is
my app doing how many screens does my
app house and they start drawing it and
there is really an app that you can make
the functional design and put it on a
screen so they really can see it and
they and they have to draw make lots of
drawings and they start thinking about
shall I attach Facebook to it or can I
use that or can I use it so they can use
lots of appease their to to use in their
in their in their app it's a very nice
way to start talking with children about
making an app they are not interested in
making it they designing it so that is
really the process before it and all the
teachers like that too because this is
what they can do and they have to
present all the 21 in Holland you say
that all the 21 skills are in there
always when you do something like this
designing an app here is one thing this
is making a game out of something and
this is an educational game the game has
been made in game maker and it is about
a game about its code from Mumtaz Combs
and this is the month and this issue
comes in dart share and is the the who
say that the digester thank you
[Music]
so this is kind of an advanced game is
made by an eighteen year old girl
but you can think about much more things
what they can do you can make a game
with the game studio which is very easy
with children or also in scratch then
it's get much more attention what you
can do here we make stop animations very
easy to make with an app and even those
children they are only 5 years old they
make something with clay and you teach
them how it is working and the next step
is that you can teach them give them an
assignment make a stop animation about
the Romans or make a stop animation
about something in math or something
else but first you have to teach them
something how it is working because they
don't have that and they don't know it
and with an app it's very easy to do it
you even can use on your phone and app
how to do it so you don't use iPads or
you don't have to use iPads or anything
else it's the same we have a green
screen in school and I always teach the
children how to use the green screen and
my history teacher then he gives an
example that they have to find an image
from ancient time and they have to stand
in the image with something on from this
century there's always a very nice
assignment so my history teacher always
comes to me have you explained them how
the green screen is working already
because I want to do this assignment and
then that's a nice combination that I
teach him something and my history
teacher he can combine it so this is a
stop animation here I have a small video
from the makey makey who knows to make
him a key but have you made with it a
piano very good and I saw some fingers
there what have you made with that
someone else nothing do something with
it because it's really fun
hey what I did it is this a movie is
from two years ago I had the makey makey
and I I figured it out a little bit
myself and then I went to my class on a
Friday morning
before holiday etc here I have a
makeymakey you can make lots of things
from it and we looked at a small video
on the website and we watched it
together and then I said now I go out
for coffee and I come back in 50 minutes
and you have to figure it out what
you're going to do with it
they were busy the whole day I gave them
an iPad and I said okay whatever you
want to do you have to make it in a
small movie and here is the movie I'm a
teacher at a special education need so
they don't like to be on YouTube so you
don't see any heads of it but we know
what kind of children there were or
students that were here it comes now you
can see the makey makey and we they made
a sandwich tears
The Rocketeer
[Music]
it was their mentor yeah first they had
like two stairs and they figured it out
that all the children they were wearing
him peace so that didn't work at all the
minion foil is so they had to make two
layers of aluminium foil a with white
paper in between and make holes in there
then it would attach and then it would
have the sound of the sounds so the only
two stairs what they had finished around
ten in the morning and then this was
this first break so the children from
the school they started using it and
with a lunch break they had all the
stairs and he made arrangements with my
music teacher who they had after me that
they could continue with a lesson and
also they made arrangement with the
sports teacher because they thought they
were really sporty on the stairs doing
that so they were busy with it the whole
day but still if I see that kids now
they always smile because we always
remember that one morning when we did it
and like a half a year later they did
kind of the same on a on a party on
school if you looked at a movie on them
on making Mickey you can see they had
this water and there's dance mat they
made a children's school and they even
attached lights to that so that is fun
to do and something like to make him
ache is really good to use and what I
did we make Holograms with the children
very easy with plastic and then they can
put our own image in there it's a very
simple way in PowerPoint how you do that
even you make a movie and then they see
themselves there in that's really very
nice to do with the children because
then you can stalking about the hologram
isn't it some
what will happen in 10 years time no you
can make it yourself now it is here you
can use it and if you start thinking
about making an app or making a website
you can easily implement with an
hologram or something else in there this
is really nice
it's called sonic PI who knows sonic PI
yes you know is it yes
can you tell me what it is you make
music yes if there is some time and we
can figure it out I have it here on my
computer I can show you because sonic PI
is really nice because they really have
to start coding really making examples
and making variables and functions and
children if the kids really like it
especially the one from 12 14 years old
and if you can see some Aaron doing
there's really like a DJ it's amazing
sonic PI and here we are coding with
Kart you can see the cards on the button
but we have a lot of fun and that is
important the kids have a lot of fun I
don't really know what they have done
but they were a lot they were very happy
and when the kids are really happy also
in your class then they learn a lot that
is important because they never forget
and the last one this is the micro bit I
have it here on me yeah the micro bit if
you start talking about computational
thinking the micro bit has it all it's
not only coding on this small thing what
I have here and I will give workshops
tomorrow morning and on Monday morning
with the micro bit with children but
also you can attach yourself a motor
door to hear LED lights to it and be
making lots and lots of nice projects so
for the micro bit my new book will be
released in January from the micro B to
801 projects what you can really make
with the microbots just not only coding
but really making things with the micro
bit we make like a robotic
a robotic finger which goes up and down
and the micro bed got it all and I can
see here I have here a small video from
a lesson I did last bumped with a micro
bit those are all 10 years old and they
had one and a half hour bits micro bit
and they put a small game on there and
here they are all playing the game and a
person who won the game he would win a
micro bit and you can see how active
they are
[Applause]
[Music]
he won because he hacked the code so
this is the end of my speech I hope you
have questions or other things please
[Applause]
I'm sorry quicker than them so if you
have any questions please come to the
microphones in the top front and the
back I'm very impressed about this but
how do you teach the teachers about this
that's very good question yeah yeah I
always teach to chill the teachers and I
always give them one step like when I
showed them the jam robots they always
say I can do that
so this is the first step and then they
get more interested so I never showed
them really what's a hat like they're
what you can do which is really
difficult now I always show them one
small step and then they know I can do
that and then they want more and more
and more so but that is the difficult
part but on primary school it is I
always say it is not difficult to teach
coding because it's so easy but um on
higher education it is more and more
difficult because then the teachers they
have to know something about coding so
I'm helpful happy that sonic PI is there
a little micro bit is there because
that's very easy also to teach to
teachers thank you for the question
more oh then I show you sonic pile I
promise that's why oh yes you were
talking about teaching to children but
is there any difference between teaching
to children teaching to adults yes oh
there's so much difference yeah because
if I teach to children I usually show
them a small video from two minutes and
then they go ahead and if I teach two to
two teachers it will have to take me
lots of explanation before they even
start touching the micro bit or
stretching things or touching the
computer and really starting off if
sometimes I have like mixed classes with
teachers and which students this is a
huge difference then
because that the the students they are
finished in half an hour and the and the
teachers are still struggling with it
what they have to do yes but that is
that's a big difference in case of the
gem robot what explanations to give you
beforehand how do you describe the tasks
yes with the children I mean with the
weighted gem robot if you if you look
for gem robot and if you look for the
gem robot on on YouTube there is this
this lesson is there completely and also
the the lesson what you can print out
and the the text what the children have
to use because that is a code to like
get up now get knife get butter you know
get a bread
those are coding words to what they
really have to do yes oh I have a forty
years old the child how old four years
old oh yes yes
and I want to like teach him how to look
good so what do you recommend I mean
like what start with there is scratch
jr. for dads so scratch jr. it's an app
so that is very easy or you can use
codable that is online what you can do
or you can start using the b-but or the
blue but that's what you can do but also
you know that's very important just to
start making things yeah that's more
important I guess more questions yes all
right so my question is if you got the
kids really excited yes and then they
first have to learn English after if
they want to do more stuff yes they want
to progress how do you deal with that is
there is there a colliculi curriculums
that you have sort of a shot okay Rick
ulam that they can themselves follow
because the teacher like you explained
yeah it's a hard time enough keeping up
so how do you keep them in front of the
teacher rather than behind well it is as
a teachers you can
not be in front of your students because
they will know it much quicker than you
do so I always say we will figure it out
ourselves or we do it together if they
have a question and you can and they you
can you cannot solve it you start
looking with them on YouTube on the
internet how to figure it out
is it an answer no so imagine you
successfully completed the lesson yes
how they want to go home yes and they
have done all the things that you showed
they made a nice animation and then they
want to move for its forward yes
but the class is done it's it's weekend
okay where should they go okay
there are many websites where you can do
that for Holland I made codec in the dot
NL which have got many different kind of
tools and lessons what I can do
themselves at home and I'm sure that is
in England too if you can see encoded
arrow there are dots a lot of different
kind of activities and then in Holland
English is usually not such a quest not
such not so important because even
younger kids they don't mind so much as
it is in English so that's it doesn't
sit here no but they could Dave if their
children really wants they find their
way and there is curriculum what you can
see first you can do it is and then you
can do that because in England the UK
there is a curriculum exactly what you
have to do when and how and so but I
like more that children are much wider
and if the start of it scratch scratch
is really huge so they can do many many
things and then they can do after that
way they can use snap and do different
things or go ahead with an Arduino or
something like that so that is working
out I hope yes not really
okay more questions
okay
Oh hope did your work yes yeah I cannot
touch it now again
No okay maybe we can hear it
no I'm sorry but this is sonic pie and
if I press rum it will really comes up
with a nice beat and you can change the
beat here by changing the sleep or use
another sample and it's really all you
can see it it's a live loop so he's
changing it right away so they very
quickly know what it is and it is not
really boring what you sometimes hear or
what the music is on the micro bit here
it is that's kind of boring but this is
really very cool and very nice
so yes more questions thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
thank you very much there will be two
workshops with kids with the metalmark
tribute tomorrow morning at 10:00 in the
belgium embassy it's a basic workshop
for children and a Monday morning we
will do in advance so the basic workshop
is only like coding it a little bit get
the name on there get a let light on
there and the next day we're really
going to do something I will take
servomotors with me and other things so
we can make something thank you very
much thank you big round of applause
[Applause]
[Music]