[Music]
next talk is data exploitation will be
presented by privacy international we
will have three speakers leading with
Christopher Weatherhead yeah a big
applause for him then our next speaker
is Aaron Leverett and we will have a
third mystery speaker that will get
introduced we're in the talk so about
privacy international you are famous for
suing GCHQ and winning so your prayer so
I leave you with this wonderful speakers
and a big applause for them afternoon
everyone
no I just lost my mic so welcome yeah
welcome it's from a quick bit of
audience participation how many of you
actually heard of previous international
all right so we're like an eight yeah
that's not too bad so let's like to
introduce this is a the esteemed Aran
deliverance
I'm crystal Weatherhead I've been
working for pi/4 about three years
nearly something like that I'm going to
talk about one of our key programmatic
areas which is data exploitation and
yeah we'll take you through what we're
going to talk about so we could
introduce ourselves a little bit more
too and Chris has been working on
connected cars since I've known him so
part of this talk is going to be as we
said data exploitation part of its gonna
be Internet of Things but we want to
keep it kind of broad so this is Chris's
chance to show off some of his hardware
reverse engineering of the connected
cars but we've also done some stuff on
data privacy with connected cars and I
myself have done industrial systems for
sort of ten years and then recently have
started working with privacy
international so I was a Mozilla web
fellow there they paid for me to work
with privacy
International and do work with them but
not be directly part of the organization
which was great for me because I got to
meet Chris right so anything else you
want to say about yourself I was gonna
say the end we're gonna just talk
through some principles that p.i is
putting together their work in progress
so any feedback very welcome yeah come
on let's get started
so I'm briefly gonna go through who we
are and how we work and a little bit
about PII generally and I'm have just
talked about the data exploitation
program in total totality and a little
bit about cars it's not going to be
particularly deep but there will be
maybe interesting hopefully you find
interesting
yeah nice a little bit about various
bits of a Gmail and rumba and yes I'm at
stern medical devices you have medical
devices then we get to the associative
power of data and then we're going to
talk about the principles for doing I
mean there's a little bit of a cool out
for you guys because we could do a
little bit of help mainly in the tech
side of stuff so one of the things to
say about data exploitation is it's a
brand-new program and we wanted to
capture the way the companies are using
our data theoretically we give our
consent for them to use our data but
then they sell it on to third parties or
they go bankrupt and the data gets sold
to someone else and you have problems
like Cambridge analytical and election
hacking and all these other sorts of
things that start to come about a lot of
these companies are using data in
aggregation so you might be giving up
your data individually but when they
fuse it with everybody else's data you
get a wildly different effect of how
that data can be used and how much money
can be made from it and so we want to
capture some of the issues around that
and some of the advocates who we do
having been more of a hacker and most of
my life I never really worked with
lawyers before I was sort of afraid of
them for the reasons you would imagine
but working at privacy international I
started to see all the ways that legal
advocacy and impact litigation could
change things in this space so that's
part of the data exploitation platform
as well so just on the point of these
three points here space team Gmail and
Roomba space team is a game that I
I doubt many of you have heard of it but
you play it on your phone and you shout
out silly instructions to each other and
you try and perform them at the same
time but we were downloading the app
just the other day it asked for
permissions to the contacts to the
microphone to the to the location and
also to screenshots and this is
ridiculous
like maybe the screenshots is viable but
all the rest is totally unneeded to play
the game so that's a good example of
data exploitation where you're giving up
your data in a simple way over
privileges of apps gmail of course most
of you will already know that they were
scanning for for many years for keywords
inside Gmail to give you better
advertising better for various values of
better in your opinion and of course
Rimbaud was doing the same thing mapping
people's houses by you know selling the
the cleaning robots so we want to
capture that not we're not we don't
wanna pick on those companies we want to
capture that as a general issue and how
the the wider population can fight back
against that yep anything else here now
we're going to connect slide so p.i is
across three major like programmatic
areas the one we're best known for is
our stuff around surveillance where
we've taken GCHQ to court we do
litigation in the european cool we've
done quite a lot of local courts we've
done interventions in the states we did
a amicus brief for Apple vs FBI we've
done quite lightly like it's definitely
where we're best known is mainly around
the proliferation of surveillance
technology yeah its surveillance
generally we all stood on a little bit
of research that falls into the next
category which is building a global
movement so we have 15 partners
worldwide and we try and get the privacy
agenda on the local agenda in those
countries that we're that were our
partners work most of them in the global
south so Latin America South America
Africa Africa and thought the Far East
yeah and that's very important because
trying to be a global international
organization with twenty people is sort
of unachievable in many
waise so by working with local partners
we have a lot better idea of what's
going on on the ground both in terms of
legal changes but political changes as
well and some of those countries don't
yet have laws protecting privacy in any
way shape or form so we're able to work
with them to kind of advocate for those
laws to be in existence at an early
stage yes so when we're talking a little
bit later about data exploitation yes
it's good to be cognizant of the fact
that although in Europe we have quite
good data protection laws in much of the
world there really isn't anything and
even here in Europe we're overly focused
on gdpr and personally identifiable
information kind of approach but we
don't necessarily look at the mapping of
houses as an issue of personal privacy
right so and our final program is a date
exploitation which is broadly fits into
two sort of cat overarching categories
on the one side there's what we call
data in the wings which we'll go into a
little bit about in a minute but it's
the data you can't see the data your
device has which others can access or
it's particularly law enforcement but
you know others others have access to
and can use but you can't see you don't
know it's there necessarily the other
side is data that's interpreted from
data you have given we weren't expecting
to be done like algorithmic learning
machine learning algorithms artificial
intelligence like some stuff around the
data that you've given someone and
they're trying to create new knowledge
from basically and that's also a problem
with data synthesis so it's one thing
when you give up your data to one
company and then again to another
company but you sort of assume that they
will never be associated but of course
there's an entire brokerage around data
that goes on in the world and when
someone starts to associate your phone
data with your car data with your health
data you start to get a much more
invasive picture of an individual or an
organization
next one so how PIAA does its work as
Aaron said with quite a small
organization is only about 20 of us and
so we actually have a matrix structure
so we got our three programming
programmatic areas and across them we've
got a legal team a research and
investigation Stephen do often do
research in places like the global South
on on governments and other people who
are subvert in surveillance then we've
got a a communications team and I've
seen campaigns team who do you know just
generally trying to bring raise the
privacy agenda all around the world and
then we got the tech team which is what
we are indeed the build team obviously
yeah I've learned to respect the other
the legal team and the advocacy team too
but we have a nice internal sort of
rivalry about these things about how we
get things done and I'm and I like the
way that works personally so you know
the tech team will end up supporting the
legal team on these amicus briefs I
personally had never filed an amicus
brief before so we'll get involved in
some of the court cases that are going
on around the world so like Apple versus
FBI or the playpen case so we'll look
into potential ways that tor might have
been not necessarily compromised but how
it was possible to track some of the
users and how that warrant was probably
violated by you know targeting well not
targeting 8,000 different computers
around the world and something like
sixty jurisdictions so we get involved
with the legal team and then they'll
write up the amicus brief and send that
off as advice to the judges in the court
case but I have an organisation
structured like this it means you get a
lot of different viewpoints you get a
lot of different experience across all
the program areas is rather than just
being like oh the the stuff around
algorithms or whatever is entirely a
tech issue it's like it's actually now
it's now it's a issue across multiple
strands of the organization and the
other advocacy team is made up mostly of
human rights activists and researchers
so they'll publish an individual report
on say Tanzania or Kenya or Egypt and
they'll focus for six months on trying
to uncover what's going
including the sale of zero days to
various government agencies around the
world and this kind of stuff so that's a
bit of background so what is their
exploitation well we kind of covered the
outsides but the in our figure come on
to the next slide sorry
didn't I think slow yeah you want to
move on okay sorry so this is an example
of the data in the wings about which I
was mentioning earlier so I'm the on the
top we've got the laptops that had the
Snowden docks on from where the Guardian
I think my colleague did a really good
talk a mess in OCCC 20 2014 2015 one of
those have anyway so be when the laptops
that the Snowden docks were on were at
the Guardian the got the GCHQ turned up
and came around destroyed load of the
chips on the board and loved them were
like pretty benign shit what we thought
were pretty benign shit and I had
keyboard controllers that kind of stuff
and but clearly GCHQ were thinking that
there was some way that classified
information from those laptops that had
handled Snowden's documentation is in
those chips so potentially government
knows something about the stuff we're
using everyday that we don't that
service claim you know else that's just
a like a single example we can always
just ask them there's anyone from GCHQ
in here today want to give us some
feedback
now where's the try and the other side
got the the field test mode over on
iphone which allows you to see the data
around all of the 3G or 4G towers you
know like cellular data the and again if
you know the code you can get the
information but most people don't know
what the code is it's sort of hidden and
there's probably other things inside
your iPhone which if you know the secret
code you can get but you kind of feel
you should probably know some of it and
some of it will like again this this the
cell towers you connect to is
essentially location data and
is kind of personal to you so it's a
little bit worrying now the final one
here is there the room bird you won't
talk about the room for do me mm you're
free I think everybody knows about the
rumor case right you must have seen it
in the press it was only last week that
was a rumor announced that that have
been found out they were that their
little robot that goes around vacuuming
your house is actually mapping your
house why as well as doing that which is
always nice to know that someone is
looking around how how big your house is
and that of course has an effect on you
know people selling properties or
something right so you could buy this
data and then use it to determine
property values are properties getting
larger or smaller in a particular region
over a period of time this kind of stuff
and so that's what we're trying to
capture with data exploitation we view
the hacker community as a particularly
empowered voice in this debate I mean
there are many people in here who can
reverse engineer devices we'll show you
a bit of reverse engineering of a couple
different devices here in just a moment
but the point is that not everyone can
do that so how do we extend that ability
to run Wireshark on a router and see
what data is going out and then
challenge the company legally how do we
extend that to a wider audience to build
an advocacy movement that helps protect
us and our data in the future yeah one
sorry one final point in the Roomba just
while we're at it I've received the
people who bought the Roomba didn't know
their house was going to be mapped they
ruled it because it was a vacuum cleaner
and it's doing something completely
separate to what was they originally
thought it was going to do and we could
challenge that particular issue in
multiple ways it's not just then they
necessarily use the data in a different
way it's all so that they can brick the
devices right so everybody remember the
the nest situation where you buy a nest
and you're able to use it for home
automation and then they threaten to
brick it because the project has been
shut down so it used to be when you
bought a dishwasher it continued to work
and it wouldn't be shut down or altered
or the data wouldn't be used remotely in
some other way that's something that's
changing and we'll talk about some of
our approaches to solving that cool so
I'll give you a little bit of a spiel
about because this is a before you too
into it the this is from the 2017
missing cash guys handbook on there
they're connected after they're
connected car
I just love this one because it'll be
with the surrounding stock imagery like
what is this got to do with cars it's
great but yeah this is so their car is a
really interesting whatever that it has
integrated like Facebook and TripAdvisor
and this is a and I said more and more
common obviously cuz people when I
social network on the go I think I don't
I don't know I'm not a social network
yeah I heard that I heard that from the
car companies I went to a conference
with Daimler and they said that there's
a large block of people on the west
coast of the USA that buy cars and
literally say things like I don't want
to have social death when I get in my
car I want to be able to tweet I want to
be on Facebook I want to be able to
share my location with my partner as I
travel around so they know what time
I'll be home so that that seems to be a
bit of a market force for them and they
now offer a service to delete all the
data from your car from their particular
models of the car but no one uses it
right so when you sell your car you
could delete all of this data but a lot
of people never take advantage of that
service and plenty of companies as far
as I know don't even offer that service
oh yeah we've we've seen cars also like
the deletion is a real issue in cars
because often they just refer to it as
factory reset which doesn't necessarily
delete it just makes it know as you know
there's no you know there was no data
there you know then sometimes the
factory reset reset is functionally a
fact you have to take it to a dealer who
is authorized to reset the car it's not
a it's not just yeah it's a real pain in
the ass
b.o.b you know the side effect of this
is that this car is now having facebook
data or TripAdvisor data or Google data
on it and it's probably not the most
secure environment for that data you can
well yeah we're talking about in just a
minute so true so there's a brief guide
for people who are particularly favored
with the reverse engineering or what it
is it's basically taking stuff apart and
seeing what's inside it
it's not like it's quite indicative
like you can look up all the chips and
have a look at what the chips do if you
happy to do some testing you can do some
testing between the interconnects see
where they connect to and it can show
whether a device is secure or insecure
in some respects so yeah cool I probably
took a lot about reverse engineering so
on my desperate my office I've got loads
of bits of car it's quite it's quite the
entry another one I've been looking at
to BMW telematics units from a one
series and I've got two Range Rover
telematics units once from a 2016 evoke
and the other ones from our 2013
Freelander you know put quite premium
cars all of them and it's they're
fascinating with how much crap they have
on them basically slow yeah let's have a
look quick look at them shall we
so this is the this is the Land Rover
well Jaguar Land Rover they're the same
company so all these when these were
made they were the same company
I think Jaguar is now on void Tata I'm
not sure if Land Rover was also bought
by Tata and a few of you might be like
well you know it looks it looks like a
computer it is a fence entually it is a
computer and it's in your car except
this computer uses a system cool so
there's a shock one here this is this
for an Asus sock and one of the features
of this socket is Fulton motiviation
it's got a a bus on it called the can
bus and the canvas is connected to
everything else and the canvas isn't
encrypted or anything you can send any
arbitrary data across that canvas
including us so this is this count bus
is connected to a 3G modem so that's
nice that's cellular it's also connected
to Sirius own Ethernet control the car
has its own Ethernet network because you
know my my new car yeah why not it's got
a Wi-Fi chip because you know if you
can't get on
hardwired you might as well get on Wi-Fi
I hope the whole unit doesn't turn off
with a car it stays on all the time
because
could be collecting data and it's got
Carlos storage for an embedded system
this has got this one I think has a
about 300 and 400 mega storage on it
which is quite a lot and if you look in
the handbook some of that storage is
used by its emergency recovery system
which is basically about black box in
the same way you have flight recorders
in planes you have a flight recorder in
your car that checks to see why an
airbag was deployed but it also checks
to see maybe whether you are driving
quite aggressively you know heavy
acceleration heavy braking that's all
looked and although this is currently
not connected to an insurer I'm sure
you're sure I would find that
information really interesting there
actually there was a insurer in the
States who wanted to plug USB devices
into cars to keep track of your driving
and then depending on your driving over
the course of a month or two they would
offer you a lower price on your
insurance but then another friend of
mine went and did some reverse
engineering of that USB and found that
he could load it with the exploits so
they were actually changing the attack
surface of the car at the same time that
they're trying to offer you better
insurance which is kind of a crazy crazy
like Renee says chip is that it is also
go it's got USB 3 obviously why wouldn't
you want USB 3 in your car and it's got
a you know full full video out so it is
essentially a computer in your car so
just out of curiosity of you a sent like
1/8 plus plus zero over the can bus just
to see if it disconnects the motor now I
have enough storage
yeah I guess that's a bit old school
yeah anything else you wanted to say
about this yeah does anybody know what
the unknown test points down down at the
bottom are any other car hackers here
any Kohaku's I know there are here at
the camp but alright anyways ok cool
don't go to the next one I think one of
the important points is Chris has been
working on this for like two years
so having each individual person kind of
do this and protect their own data and
try and understand all the stuff is kind
of untenable so what we're hoping to do
is make sure that this kind of research
eventually makes it to the public so
be used for legal advocacy so you can go
to the companies and get back the data
that we know they're gathering because
like I can only do one car every now and
again when I've got well I've got time
too
and there is just thousands and models
of cars and most the systems are
proprietary so it's pretty low hanging
fruit is literally opening the thing up
and having a look inside and just
working out all the chips are hopefully
how they connect but don't know even
that just what they are even is is you
know very helpful we also want to change
the debate a little bit there's nothing
wrong with the stun hacking that's been
going on for safety reasons it's you
know fantastic research shows us what we
should be concerned about but there's
precious few people doing this for
privacy reasons as well and I think that
both of those things need to be done at
the same time cool
just like skips or a couple of the
animations sorry
yeah so this is a this is the BMW's unit
and jokey garden which is a nice my god
this this is a good one because yes he's
the American version of this unit has to
go through FCC regulation so why don't
you get a nice block diagram if you go
forward mother slide which is great and
I wonder if anyone recognizes any of
those chips and that block diagram
anyone that is a my phone for
effectively yeah this is this is in the
Oh BMW and it's essentially it's the
same power chip and same modem is in my
phone for and it's connected the Samsung
memory which is also an iPhone 4 so if
you've basically got an iPhone in your
car without even you know without even
knowing about it yes so this this
extension of all this daughterboard
connects to this is slow in the bottom
corner here and it this one the one the
model of the car I had was probably a
low spec one unfortunately because the
the empty solder contacts are for GPS
but again all of this just aggregated in
one chip you know passed around the calf
up it's great and then yeah it's quite
quite previously low low low on the
privacy scale quick cool
so we took like about looking in cars
hacking cars a little bit maybe yeah
tell them the fun stuff we got to do
last week yeah okay so we've done a
little bit of it we've recently started
having a looker rental cars because
rental cars are a really interesting
example of data exploitation so when you
buy a car and he put date on it it's
kind of your car your data it's you know
you're you have some control over it
when you rent a car you know you're only
on it for a couple of days and you put
you know your location data in there or
you put your foot you know you can't
your phone to the car and you know you
do a cool through or whatever and it's
you know as soon as you give the car
back if you don't wipe that data
no one wipes that data well at least
that's how we think no one wipes that
data so you have you know just personal
information of loads of people driving
around and we're kind of hoping whether
you guys might be able to give us a hand
with this so we're looking for anyone
who is looking to rent cars in Europe
particularly in Europe because we are a
UK charity and although the UK is still
part of Europe it's not seen as being
the European have campuses so if you're
in if you're in the Europe you're
renting a car please can you get in
contact with me because I'd like to talk
to you about it yeah some of the things
we've found is that as soon as you
collect to connect to your phone to the
car all of your missed calls or made
calls or whatever are suddenly available
to people even if you've walked away
from the car a certain distance some of
the places that you've been in the past
are they're stored in the car and of
course theoretically you can delete all
this but the user has to know to delete
all this and we sat down and read
through all of the license agreements on
this particular vehicle that we were
looking at and it took us an hour just
scrolling through the menus to read all
of the license agreements and understand
all of the software that was in the car
that we were renting for a day so it's
kind of an untenable position in the
long run for users all right we're gonna
change gear a little bit upon another
nice but thanks I practiced that so yeah
I want to talk to you a little bit about
IOT a little bit about Mirai and then
we'll move on to medical data and it's
going to go a little bit quickly this is
from a paper
by an academic and his students at the
University of Cambridge and what they
were trying to do is map vulnerabilities
over time and I think it's a great graph
because it's sort of what I had in my
head as a pen tester when I was at
ioactive
you have this is just known
vulnerabilities so this we're not
talking about zero days or you know
something new this is just do we know of
ulnar ability exists or not in this
particular version of this particular
phone on this particular network so
different phone networks send you
updates and patches for your phone or
for the apps at different ratios and
this is basically showing you that at
any given time for Android there's
always some exploits left that we know
about or some vulnerabilities if not
exploits that are available to us as
attackers so the patching rate on the
phones is just not high enough to
maintain a sum assured level of security
and I think it's a fantastic graph that
illustrates that so you can go and see
some of their work on Android and they
have a product called device analyzer
where they gathered this data with
people's consent I also want to talk to
you little bit about Mariah and did you
want to say something about Tesla before
we move on now okay next one so they're
gonna go a little bit quickly lots of
people have heard of Mariah right you
know about the Mirai case I like to use
it as an example of pollution okay so
Mirai was a Mirai was a botnet used
primarily for DDoS as far as we can tell
and essentially it was infecting IP
cameras CCTV cameras digital recorders
set-top boxes these kinds of things
right and then it was using those
devices to perform D doses around the
world
so essentially some vendor comes along
and sells you a product and it does
something that you don't think about
that's poorly configured DNS or SNMP or
something and then that could be used in
turn to perform DDoS attacks on other
people either because it gets exploited
or because it's a reflector of those
protocols right so function wise problem
was that it was default passwords yes so
essentially yet we're talking about
admin admin right so there's some
discussion we can have about
vulnerabilities and liability in a
moment or two but this is accounts of
Mirai infections by country and I know
many of the people who are working these
individual incidents at any given time
this is an ipv4 map which
is actually kind of horribly difficult
to really read my apologies but it shows
roughly the source and destination
addresses not for the DDoS but but in
general for the traffic so we'll move on
this is what a Mirai bloom looks like so
this is what incident responders
essentially have to deal with so here
you have the countries with the counts
at different time over what a six week
period so you can see you know Brazil
wasn't doing too badly and then suddenly
they had a spike in infections and then
they worked very hard to clean them up
and they got a little bit better but
that's what it looks like for incident
responders over the course of a few
weeks constantly trying to deal with
thousands of these things because
companies have plenty of reasons to sell
you default passwords for usability
right so next slide all right so here's
my crazy subversive idea has anyone
heard of the general product liability
directive here in Europe yay thank you
have you read it ok good so these two
are particularly interesting to me we've
been having some discussions inside the
computer security community about
whether or not the product liability
directive could be used if someone is
hacked and the device stops working in a
functional sense so we need to talk
about IOT devices rather than say
everyday general-purpose computing could
someone sue them because the product is
no longer working so it used to be if
you had a dishwasher and it floods your
kitchen you can sue them because it
floods your kitchen right well what
happens if someone Sid floods the
dishwasher and the dishwasher floods
your kitchen can you still sue them so
there's some discussions going on in
Europe about whether or not this is a
good idea and whether or not it's
possible so we looked into the product
liability directive and it says quite
clearly that the EULA does not prevent
liability for an IOT device manufacturer
so the liability of the producer arises
for the directive may not relate in
relation to the injured person be
limited or excluded by a provision
limiting liability and exempting from
liability so the end user License
Agreement would be violating an article
12 essentially is what we're talking
about the other thing that's important
is in one of these two clauses I believe
it's in number one the liability of the
producer shall not be
used when the damage is caused by both a
defect in the product ie of
vulnerability and by the act or omission
of a third party a hacker so we're
exploring whether or not liability could
be divided up between manufacturer and
attackers and whether or not this would
have an effect on the quality of
products in the future so let's move on
this is a modern on an example of
computers in medical rooms right in
hospitals in surgeries in various
devices this slide was produced by a
fantastic researcher called Harold
thimble B he's been doing medical device
research for a number of years and I
think it just gets the point across
right that these computers are
everywhere and they're used in life
critical situations that have a real
world effect right it might be drug
infusion pumps it might be implanted
medical devices such as pacemakers in
you know defibrillators it can also be
for a variety of other reasons right so
yeah just getting the point across
there's quite a lot of computers here so
Harold thimble bees work focuses on user
interface errors this is not just about
vulnerabilities it's also about
accidents so this is a variety of
different ways that you can administer
drugs to patients now what I want you to
want to focus on is look at all of these
user interfaces
some of them signify thousand units with
a comma some with a full stop some of
them place the buttons in different
positions so the the one is at the top
or it's at the bottom so your average
nurse or doctor working with all of
these tools has to switch between one or
another and understand all the different
user interfaces this is what Liability
did for us 100 years ago it standardized
the car so you don't just have a
steering column on this side or this
side or the middle and you don't switch
the brake pedals around with the with
the gas pedal you standardize the user
interface until things become safer we
still haven't done that in medical
devices and Harold Tim will be estimates
that at least in the UK the number of
deaths related to medical device user
interface errors is equivalent to the
number of deaths from car crashes I'm
gonna let that sink in for a minute one
of the points I want to make here is
that one in 1,000 of you in Europe will
end up with an implanted medical device
sometime in your lifetime in Norway for
example that's getting close to about
one in 200 so as we all get older and we
have implanted medical devices or even
wearables this is going to be very
important to us and medical implants
have recently been used for forensics
and led to convictions right the medical
insurance industry wants this data to
keep track of your health over time and
change the pricing of your insurance my
concern is that you won't know why the
price of your insurance changed because
they'll have gotten the data from some
second company or third company and
lastly you shouldn't have to choose
between health and privacy so we have a
special guest speaker here with us that
we've been tweeting about and joking
about for a while I don't know if many
of you know dr. Marie moolah but she's
here with us today and I'd like to
invite her up on the stage to tell you a
little story of her own so would you
please give her a nice round of applause
for joining us thanks so I have a
pacemaker implanted in my body I have a
computer inside of me I got it
five and a half years ago and at the
time I was working at Norwegian Church
doing incidence response already working
on information security and I suddenly
needed this device to stay alive so I'm
depending on a computer inside and I
have data inside of me in this computer
generated by my own body and I can't get
access to it it's all proprietary
information this come this computer also
sends out log information and you can
hook it up to kind of medical internet
of things and there are websites where
the doctors can log in and see my my
patient data but it is not available to
me as the generator of this data so I
started a case maker hacking projects
together with Aaron and to see if I
could get access to some more
information about my pacemaker and my
data and if I could actually trust this
device that is keeping me alive
and I've been doing some talks about it
um a little less than a year ago I was
invited to do a keynote talk for
Hardware dot IO some of you might have
been there it's a great conference on
hardware hacking here in the Netherlands
and I actually ended up in hospital and
in Amsterdam so this is me in the
hospital because my pacemaker failed
while I was up in the air in the
airplane on my way to give that talk and
so this is kind of a personal story
about my own critical infrastructure and
how I accidentally ended up getting hold
of some information due to this
happening so I opened airplane mind my
business just usually I don't feel
anything I don't feel the pacing from
the pacemaker even though it's working
hundred percent of the time and just
keeping my heart beating but suddenly I
just get a strange sensation I could
feel that something was going on I
looked down at my chest I could see my
chest muscle was twitching and so I I
figure out there's something wrong with
the pacemaker I notified the aircrew
when we landed that's people there was
an ambulance waiting for me that took me
directly to the hospital I just spend
the night there because I didn't have a
pacemaker technician in at the time and
this is me the morning after having the
role in the table with the pacemaker
programmers so you can see four
different brands of programmers they
have to use the programmer that is
actually connected to that that is from
the same manufacturer as by device
because all the wireless communication
protocols are proprietary and so they
don't work there's no like in open
standards for this see out other correct
programmers is correct device and but
I'm looking happy in this picture that's
because I've found out that it's not
it's actually something that can be
fixed and by just giving me a software
update our firmware update and so so I
didn't have to have any surgery there
was nothing like physical like there was
no not a hardware issue in my pacemaker
and so this is
and the face of the pacemaker technician
when here took my little programmer I'm
just looking at the dissipate display in
the programmer and he saw this error
message next slide so this was actually
had been going wrong there was a data
error in the pacemaker it was it has
switched up the voltage that's why I
felt the pasting it was constantly
pacing me 70 beats per minute and I'm
really happy that they had the engineer
doing this safety feature because I was
actually keeping me alive it was a bit
uncomfortable but not not a crisis and
but check this out and it's actually a
memory dump and a log file created on
the pacemaker programmer and because of
this crash so I'm sitting there getting
a firmer update and after that I'm good
to go after we have configured the
device of course I happened to have a
memory stick in my bag as usually having
to travel and I also asked if I could
get a copy of this file and that's why I
actually ended up getting hold of some
log data from my pacemaker that we've
been trying to get hold of also in the
hacking project so that was a win and I
also reached out to the manufacturer and
I also got some of that data from them
which made me get access to memory dump
from my device so this is what you have
to do to get all of your patient
information if you're very proprietary
and computers inside yeah you need to
hack it or you need to get a failure
event and get all of the logs you're the
only person I know is willing to have a
heart failure - social engineer a
hospital
okay so you can move on to your
conclusions okay running out of time we
are so hopefully that gives you a sense
of some what we're dealing with
obviously we can talk about safety but
we also want to talk about privacy so
we're trying to formulate these data
exploitation principles one of the
things we want to do is reduce data
monopolies in general of course that's
very very difficult in a corporate world
but there are ways that we can do that
and we would like to work with some
regulators if there's any regulators in
the room to work on some of those issues
we also want to address the imbalance of
power between user and company so you
shouldn't have to spend two years
hanging out at hacker camps just to be
able to access your own medical data I
mean I know you probably would have done
that anyway but the point still stands
right that it takes a lot of time and
effort to do this we also want to
legally contest the non-consensual data
set
sharing that we see a lot of the time
such as Chris tweeting pictures from the
stage yes sorry I'm just joking so we
use a variety of these different
techniques down at the bottom D SARS so
Chris built a nice little router to
collect data from any particular IOT
product that we bring into the office
it's basically just Wireshark on a
router right but every time we buy a new
device we run it in the office and we
bootstrap it and we see which data it's
kind of sending across and this means we
can make legal requests to the companies
and we know in advance what data they
will have so we're in a position to say
we want you to give us this data and
then when they say we don't have it we
can say we know you do because here's
the Wireshark right so a simple approach
but please join us in this kind of thing
we also work on multilateral
international sharing agreements and try
and challenge those Freedom of
Information requests and amicus briefs
as we said previously foi is a great
tool the FOS are a fantastic tool lots
of people have filed an foi in here
right really only a few file more fo is
just ya can use use camp bandwidth for
that all right so we're gonna try and
wrap it up yeah I'll try and keep this
want to show that's okay yeah bill best
so we've talked about the problem so P I
is trying to work on what might be the
solution and what we're trying to do is
bring like a set of
suppose they're like the the you know
the the entry-level of what users should
expect from you know when devices or
services they use and you know like the
you know well you would one like a
baseline effectively so you know and
there's about fourteen of these so I'm
going to try and whiz through them
reasonably quickly I'm looking for
comment on them or we looking for
comment on them to be honest I prefer if
you would send me comment rather than
during the questions at the end that
would be great because I'd like to keep
a note of your comments but I'll try and
go through these as quickly as can so
first thing about this is with the this
boy into two categories there's data and
control and security of information and
so the data control stuff is stuff like
all the data is derived from your
personal data should be treated the same
as your personal data like that seems
fairly sensible really systems should be
designed to minimize data data
generation processing and access that's
very important a lot of people focus on
minimizing the processing but they
gather far more data than they need to
and as you start to look at these
devices you see that yep the data should
not be generated collected analyzed
retained or transmitted aggressively or
excessively although excessively is a
very vague way of putting this is maybe
excess in relates to the user rather
than the you know some arbitrary number
excessive like were you expecting that
to happen basically the general data
protection principle anyway data must be
protected from access by people who
aren't the user that's already mostly in
you European data patient up again we've
talked about places where there is no
data protection law individuals must be
able to ascertain their digital
footprint they must know you must be
able to find out how much data you've
got so you have D SARS but that doesn't
actually really necessarily tell you
much that tells you maybe what you've
told a company but it doesn't a suit old
you that
that's been interpreted from your data
it doesn't tell you you know all sorts
of types of data that your think that
could be used in fact I don't think we
have legal instruments to determine what
can be derived from your data or what a
I could derive from your data or data
fusion could be performed we have legal
instruments for the individual but not
necessarily for society in general so we
see this as kind of a consumer rights
issue individuals must be able to delete
and refresh their data like you must
have the option and it's very like the
the DD field has changed a bit because
previously at least in the UK you could
ask if data to be amended but not
necessarily deleted whereas in the GD P
are you can now a States deletion but we
think it should just be a general
principle anyway and if you're if you
want to you should be able to have a
negotiate of all identity at default you
should be anonymous you shouldn't have
to give data to use a service if that
data is intrinsic to the operation of
that service code only go into the news
pharmacist more relating to the security
and protection side of things and the
first one is devices shouldn't be able
to portray us or device and service you
should not be able to portray us which
is again sort of wrapped in form we've
already gone over but it's you know your
your device
shouldn't be giving out data like
personal information about you without
your knowledge or consent or whatever so
an example of this would be something
like Wi-Fi which broadcasts all the
previous SS IDs you've been on it's
betraying a load about you're free you
know your previous connectivity like it
if your SSID is named whatever you work
the company you work for in your home
SSID is what it means where you live or
whatever it's telling an awful lot about
you by just broadcasting and it sort of
betraying you individual should have
insight into the data is clicked on them
on one why and through and how you know
we've talked about pacemakers we've
talked about cars you need to know what
what's the point why why did someone
take this off me right you buy a set-top
television box and you expect to be able
to download content you don't
necessarily think about the fact that
it's keeping track
of all the content you watch to give you
better content for values of better
security updates should be separate and
distinguishable from our feature updates
that's this is the Microsoft problem I
silent upgrades yes this is where you
get new features you don't necessarily
want because you also want to have the
security features which do one they
should be two separate things
[Music]
manufacturers well we talked about
liability already but manufacturers
maybe should be responsible for security
of their device throughout their
lifecycle yeah yeah absolutely and all
entities the handle the users data
should be joining us every liable for it
so again this is this is in some data
protection law but not all data
protection law and it would be great
that if this were like the the baselines
of yeah so if you're willing to do some
activism around this and you want to do
some legal activism or some technical
activism or just be an empowered user if
you have some ideas about our data
exploitation principles how we can
explain them to everyday people who are
not hackers who are very empowered and
have a voice please get in touch and let
us know Chris won't be here because he's
going to run away back to London as
quickly as possible
Maria and I will both be here but Marie
doesn't work for privacy internationals
so bring the questions about pi2 me of
course you can speak to her about
medical devices and so on and thank you
very much for your time you could have
gone anywhere and seen any talk so thank
you for coming to see our talk thank you
very much that's just a fantastic talk
thank you very much that was the
fantastic talk and now we still have
about 15 minutes for an open discussion
so if anyone of you has a question
please go to the microphones at the
center of the tent you don't have to
answer my question but the Prime
Minister of the United Kingdom Mrs May
has a very peculiar track record closer
to the mic please can you comment on on
the track record of her government and
will it be replaced soon I hope well as
a as a representative of privacy
international I don't think I can
advocate any non democratic process in
any way but the future of the UK's
approach to surveillance I hope will
change and will continue to challenge
that so as we said at the outset our
amazing legal team who I started to work
with challenged the UK's collection of
data data retention laws and also the
sharing of data internationally and won
that court case so that GCHQ had to
acknowledge that they had gathered that
data for 17 years illegally and that's
the sort of work that will continue to
do so I hope that that regardless of any
individual politician whatever party
they might come from we don't like to
see that kind of data retention continue
and we'll try and challenge it anywhere
in the world that we can next question
please
yes a comment and a question
I really like to work about cars just to
give you an idea of how bad security is
with car companies my job is normally
I'm a policy expert I work for the OECD
in Paris I used to work for the Ministry
of Economic Affairs of the Netherlands I
don't code at all i hack law I basically
say I did hack Toyota Toyota the
Netherlands I hacked their website and I
was able to get access to the data of
other Toyota's just by entering the
number plate right and I could see what
people had downloaded for the
what kind of software updates and I
could also send updates to their
navigation system if they actually used
that a function that was completely not
secured whatsoever that I can hack that
is a testament to how bad it is
absolutely I know
Val second Miller who did fantastic work
on car hacking also discovered the same
thing once they got onto the network of
the ISP or the the mobile phone provider
they could see multiple different
vehicles identified by their vehicle and
identification number of the VIN and so
they could see many vehicles at the same
time so I mean maybe Chris wants to say
some more about that I go up two points
there so firstly talking about Toyota
Roenick days it was Toyota he said so me
and my dad and I both are in Toyotas and
we both live in the same well we were
both living in the same address so we
registered our car on whatever is my
Toyota toy you and I could turn that
site and I can see all of his car
details and all the stuff about his car
and I could see all of my car and he
could see what my car it did yes
there wasn't a great system so I
reported it they said thank you they
give me five tickets to dto to a llama
Museum which is brilliant car Museum
here in the Netherlands thank you but I
don't think anything has probably
changed yes I totally agree with you I'm
same thing I also reports to at least we
did our due diligence on that I do have
a common M I'm running around with this
ID on a policy side that notifying and
making people accept end-user license
agreements it's just idiotic and and our
privacy rules want us to register all
the data that we have on a particular
it's privacy sensitive but data is
collected everywhere my standard example
is that even street lights connected
street lights could these days be
privacy sensitive because if you walk
out at night from your home and make a
trip through your neighborhood and the
lights turn on that could be recorded
and then you could see at night who went
out of their house of what
yep so instead of forcing people to
register all the data that they collect
it would be much better if we could get
people to tell you who accessed your
data the same with medical data occurred
through in the Netherlands you need to
give an upfront access to your data to a
particular person before they can access
it but that prohibits doctors when
you're lying half-dead on the ground
to access your medical data which is a
problem for the ambulance stuff so it
would be much better if we had a
register of who access data on you then
that we try to block it upfront what's
your ID on that it sounds like that's
probably a wider conversation we could
have together with PII and yourself
there's lots of regulatory approaches
that we are talking about taking the
main thing is just focusing on the
empowerment of the user but I realized
it's also becoming untenable for
companies to be able to manage all this
data and access in the ways that they're
talking about so it's a problem that
society needs to solve in general and
that's why we'd like to work with
lawmakers and regulators and lawyers and
hackers and human rights researchers we
think it's a really multidisciplinary
approach that changes things over time
it data sharing is a big issue anyway
because it's often non-negotiable like
you agreed like although it will all
give a license agreements and healers
are functioning useless but you're
you're you have to agree to these terms
if you want to use a product or service
and you're having to share data with
people you might not even want to share
data with or you might want to do it now
I'm going to catch you that because
there's other people join the combine me
a little bit later and then also you
still have time no no I just mean we'll
have a chat again later let's go I have
a question - Mary you device was hit by
a stray cosmic particle are you trying
technical countermeasures now when
flying like putting a sheet of metal
over you huh thanks maker it's a really
rare event but I fly alot so I guess
if it's happening to someone then who
would happen to me
so it's possibly or most likely it was
caused by cosmic radiation and that cost
bit flips in the memory of the device I
don't think I want to like I can't live
my life worrying about my device not
working all the time actually I feel
better after having this incident
because of the failsafe mode failure
mode made me stay alive so it actually
worked even though this happened and I
don't want to go around with a Faraday
cage to protect myself against that's
yeah your husband might object right any
more questions well I have one and not
everyone here is a very experienced
hacker that knows how to track their
internet and I was missing in the part
of the tutorial where you tell people
like which is the easy access software
that people can install so they can like
track what their devices are doing all
their connecting devices I think for an
everyday user it's not that there's so
many tools so so there's a reasonably
technical hacker person you use
Wireshark right you download a tool
called Wireshark and it keeps track of
all the connections that are made over
the Internet on a particular interface
and so then you can record that almost
like you would record a phone call and
then you can decode it with various
tools and there's many workshops here on
Wireshark at the camp
some of them delivered by people who
really know the software have been
writing it for years there's also a
little tools like little little Flocker
which keeps track of web browser
interactivity so it doesn't keep track
of all interactivity but at least the
web browser so some of those tools I
would say get people started and then
maybe some of you in the audience will
write some next-gen tools that are
easier to use than Wireshark for
capturing this kind of thing PII is also
working on a nice takeaway here working
on a and I'm the project my my other
colleague in the tech team in their PI
is a writing a bit of software he calls
thorn sack which
is basically compartmentalization for
networks and is about trying to minimize
the amount of cross contamination and
cross communication anyway it's not so
much about the logging so much but it is
trying to minimize what things are
talking to one it's a shout-out to Ed
yeah nice I also work with a team of
lawyers can you get closer to the mic
please
so I also work with a team of lawyers
closer please and the team of lawyers I
work with they said that sudonym icing
the data with the current gdp are it is
suitable sudanese data holds the same
regulations as Natsu demise so really
Naaman eyes data what is your reflection
on that
what do you it's it depends a little bit
on the data itself but in general there
are ways to diiie anonymize data again
using mathematical techniques and as a
broad stroke this isn't true for
everything I think the legal boundary is
not sufficient against a mathematical or
hacker boundary let me say that
differently I think the state of the art
in the mathematical anonymity community
is far beyond what the law is protecting
us from at the moment and if any laws
don't sort of keep up with the offensive
community then we fall behind and it
becomes sort of meaningless legislation
in some way it helps but it's not enough
necessary but insufficient that's my
answer I have two questions for Mary and
the first one is about the other users
of pacemaker do they also have access to
their data or are you the only person in
the whole world
who's got the data from your pacemaker
it depends on what kind of data you're
talking about so the data is related to
the configuration settings of the
pacemaker you can get access to if you
have a programmer and that's typically
when you go into checkups that they
they can set this configuration and I
always ask for a print of a hard copy of
all my configuration settings and that
came in really handy when I had this
incident because I was in hospital
Amsterdam and needed to get my device
reconfigured and since I had access to I
have this print out it was actually in
my office back home so I had to call a
colleague and I get him to scan it for
me and send it to me on email they were
able to configure and tune the device
exactly as it was before this happened
so I could just walk out of there and
mb/s normal again because it was
impossible to get hold of this
information this data from my local
hospital in Norway when I was in in the
Netherlands so really happy that I had
this data and also it's possible to get
hold of these programmers on eBay and so
I bought a programmer for $500 and it
came with a lot of data and that's it I
could get access to you which is kind of
a privacy violation of the patients that
had their data in this programmer that
wasn't really decommissioned properly
before it was sold on eBay and so it's
possible to get all of this data but it
kind of data that we got from from the
crash file that's the kind of data
that's only the manufacturer I will
usually have access to or if you do like
a forensic examination of the device and
then the second question I have for you
is more kind of your creative
imagination of the data you get and have
you got any plan after getting the
memory dump of your heart if I got any
plan have you got any what what are you
going to do with the data we said I'd
like to do with the data yeah I like to
just know more about how my device works
basically and I couldn't get access to
the source code running on the device
with the firmware on the device without
hacking it so I want to you as a
security researcher and have a like a
third party opinion on how secure this
pacemaker is because I know there's a
lot of
pacemakers that have been shown to not
be secured that haven't really
implemented security protocols properly
like really failed with with an
implementation of crypto for instance
and I studied crypto and I get upset
when I heard that some pacemakers have
authentication kind of implemented by
24-bit key so it's kind of silly really
if you know some thing about the crypto
so yeah thank you very much
Christopher you had an announcement oh
no questions were all right then
please join sir what you are saying is
that they use the privacy argument for
not giving you access to your own data
and your own machine right well they're
using their IPR as a kind of I want to
know your own information so why should
they say it's bright its privacy break
yeah that's I think we need to move into
a future with more transparency and
although these devices actually work so
that people can trust them there's any
other questions oh yeah questions paper
well many takeaways are two bits of
homework so if you are renting a car
please do get in contact with me my
details are up there or two to Aaron if
afterwards and the other one is any
comments on the principles we put we put
forward again maybe get in contact with
me or that way they will be up on our
website so you can have a look at them
there if you want to see them in full
and yeah thank you
yeah thanks again thank you very much a
big girl flaws
[Applause]
[Music]