[Music]
good afternoon sha thank you for
attending this talk give yourself a warm
applause because you're in here while
the weather outside is really great come
on it's good to be in here who here is
from outside of Europe
awesome give these people warm warm
applause because they travels very far I
[Music]
[Applause]
hope that we all know that the Internet
expands outside of Europe and most
people here are interested in human
rights but our focus has mainly been on
European issues and now we have a
speaker here who is going to explain
human rights issues and impacts in Latin
America we have Gizella who is a Mexican
lawyer and she's going to talk to us
about the situation in Latin America
give it up for Casilla hi everyone thank
you very much for being here it is
indeed a super warm day which you do not
get a lot of here so I really appreciate
it yes I am Casella I'm a Mexican lawyer
and journalist I specialize in freedom
of speech and gender in Latin America
precisely and what I want to do today is
tell you a bit of what's going on in my
continent what are the protests about
what are our biggest some of our biggest
battles on the upcoming years and more
or less what's the political situation
at stake right now so it's super
interesting because I've seen quite some
several talks about given by women where
they start apologizing pre apologizing
saying oh I do not know a lot about this
topic so if anybody wants to jump in I
am super open about that and I am a
lawyer I am
coding a bit battered it but getting
there but then I was thinking of pre
apologizing and saying hey I am NOT
technical bear with me but then I
thought I am technical I can get really
lawyer in you and be super technical a
doctor can be super technical indigenous
person that works with ancestral
medicines can get super technical and
that led me to think what is being
technical is it working with technology
but then how do you define technology
itself yesterday a very interesting talk
had me thinking if body could be a
technology itself it all depends on how
you define it right so I am technical
just a different type of technical and I
have four points to make so the very
first one or rather the very first two
have to do with all the myths and
mythologies that probably surround
European thinking around Latin Americans
and our use of technology and my very
first example and my favorite one is the
Sabbat estas can I get a raise of hands
if you ever heard talk about the Sabbath
Easter's okay that's a good share of the
crowd so yeah basically the Sabbath
estas in Spanish is EC Ln it stands for
a Pharisee Tosa Bautista de libération
National they are an indigenous rebel
army that started their arising in the
same day that NAFTA came into effect
NAFTA is the North American Free Trade
Agreement it started in 1994 and
essentially there was a clause in NAFTA
that was going to override the
protection of indigenous lands from
privatization by the private sector
which is obviously what happened but
they still they invaded a indigenous a
Batista army rebelled and declared war
on the Mexican government with beautiful
poems so it quickly became the hot spot
for leftist tourists around the world
the wife of
the widow of Francois Mitterrand was
there Oliver Stone
there was even proposal by Benetton to
do a campaign on the Sabbath estas which
is a petition of course being anarchists
said a big no and then here comes the
miss the Western media were just going
crazy about it can you imagine with the
they call them they called it The
Saboteur it was super hot and trendy at
the time I was obviously 5 years old
I've been there in the past years but I
was not there in 1994 so it's actually
this whole narrative started about how
the zapatistas were becoming cyber
Guerrero's they were doing this
informational warfare throwing this
rebellious cries from the lacan Don
jungle using the internet and high-tech
weaponry there's this myth that
Subcomandante Marcos was using a
satellite phone to communicate with
cyber terrorists around the world
whatever that means - that Subcomandante
Marcos wrote in 2013 ha really come on
like we're talking about rural Mexico
here in the 90s they barely had any
electricity support estas most of them
do not even speak Spanish do you really
think su commandante Marcos a super high
powered satellite phone through which he
organized the whole cyber warfare no it
was their Western collaborator
collaborators that took The Saboteur
that were doing that for them he then
said this is a really beautiful poem
actually I will upload it to the talk
description afterwards I think it's
really worth reading it was just super
long I would have pasted it all but he
then explained in 2013 how it was a nerd
from Texas who started uploading all the
communicates and that's how they got
spread into cyberspace right but they
did not have internet it was not them
and when you see the pictures it becomes
really ridiculous this narrative which
is also partly explained because 70% of
the blogs that talk about the Sabbath
East
are either from the US or European so
what kind of narrative one here if
Mexican media and Latin American media
were not even producing enough materials
at the time of course this explains
partly because of governmental
censorship and the control that the
Mexican government has over the press
but still we can understand how some
narratives getting post or others so
just a quick update on how where the
separatists are right now at the time of
the internet of the 90s the Sabbath
estas were very much in tune their
anarchist ideology was very much in tune
with the decentralization collaborating
within the media the internet as an
agreement but then as we have shifted to
social networks walled gardens private
platforms privatized and proprietary
software and algorithms the Sabbath
Easter's have also changed their minds
for them now they believe that social
networks are an instrument of capitalism
and that resistance cannot be
articulated there and they also believe
we should prioritize communitary work
and communitary building in a physical
relationship and I don't mean
infrastructure I mean actually touching
and seeing people and talking to them
and making them and learn things and
teaching each other so that's where the
SEPA theses are now regarding the
internet it's not they have actually
took a step back and rejected the
internet principles as we know it now so
second myth this is really good - this
is Guillermo Gomez Pena he's what we
call a Chicano
not in a bad sense it's not a bad word
he's Mexican but he lived in the United
States for a long time and what he
basically he has this beautiful thing
that I'm gonna quote directly it goes
like this
the mythology goes like this we Latinos
cannot handle high technology we are
caught between pre-modern past and an
imposed modernism that prevents us from
being anything but manual beings already
sense not technician
our understanding of the world is
strictly political political or at best
metaphysical but not scientifical or
technological whatsoever we are highly
emotional passionate creatures meaning
irrational and when we decide to step
out for primitive stone and create high
technology we are pretty much doomed to
copy what others the Anglos and the
europeans have done better so we're
pretty much screwed right this is a
mythology what I think is very
interesting he wrote this at the end of
the 90s it was around 1990 2000 he was
also part of the electronic disturbance
theater we Latinos often feed this
mythology but rings by reinstating a
romantic and humanistic nature and by
portraying ourselves as victims of a
colonialist technology and you will see
why this is relevant in a few slides so
as I was thinking this I was also
thinking how we could do the same with
gender right just change Mexicans or
Latinos for women women are irrational
passionate creatures I cannot handle
high technology how's that first
stereotype we are passionate
metaphysical beings that are made for
cooking but why would you why would you
mesh with software why would you code
why would you and this is also a
stereotype this is also a mythology so
very quickly because gender is going to
cut through my old presentation let's
just agree on what gender is gender is
all the roles spaces behaviors attitudes
clothing colors and topic of
conversation that are deemed appropriate
for men and women this means that I mean
being appropriate if you're born with a
penis or a vagina if you're born with a
penis then it's appropriate for you to
wear pants and like blue and play with
Legos when you're young if you're born
with a vagina then they will put pink
dresses on you give you a doll so you
can fit and tell you that playing soccer
is for boy
so this is essentially the social
programming we get and this construction
is the gender construction which is
different from sex which is rather
biological and it's not non-binary
either but I am NOT getting into that
discussion right now just so we all know
and are on the same page on one gender
is and how it is artificially created
and it's not biologically determined so
countering the myth I really dislike the
digital literacy approach where the
Google creators buzz just strolls in
latinamerica saying come create apps be
a web developer I am not referring to
countering the myth of Latinos not
creating technology in the sense but I
would rather talk about technological
appropriation questioning infrastructure
questioning what technology itself and
how we define technology itself it is
not a neutral matter all the power
relationships that go on in the world
replicate in this infrastructures and
replicate online as well not because we
have a chat it means that everybody can
express themselves equally minorities
will still be oppressed and women will
still be genderized
we cannot talk nowadays online or
Twitter or Facebook about things that
are outside of our gender stereotypical
behavior I will tell you bit more about
that later but this is basically the
concept of appropriating technology so
two really quick examples are in Mexico
the project of resume attica which is
the first indigenous community and
telecommunication service operating with
a license they actually got a license in
Mexico over 50,000 communities do not
have telecommunications services because
it's super expensive it's not profitable
for companies to set an antenna in their
communities because it's sometimes less
than 3,000 people living there so ERISA
matica has managed to create the
technology and to teach the people so
that is the only DeGeneres community
that actually manages it then also in
Argentina we have niqua Chinese who has
been with
minimax networks creating community of
Wi-Fi networks alter Mundi is the name
of the project and then I want to tell
you about this one which is definitely
one of my favorites it's autonomous
feminist infrastructure I know that for
some of us here in this room the mere
word feminist sometimes causes us to
cringe I would ask you to be a bit
tolerant with it because it's also
gendered it's also to say that all
feminists are ugly lesbians hairy angry
ugly lesbians it's also a construction
that has been made about dissident women
so let's just think about the term
feminism once again and how it relates
to infrastructure so this is kefir kefir
what I really like about this project is
that it questions the economy of
autonomous infrastructure itself because
basically it's based on voluntary work
and donations and you know who has time
to volunteer mostly white men because
the free time is a privilege do you
think an indigenous woman that has a job
and then an invisible job that is called
housework taking care of children
cooking and cleaning which is not
recognized it's not paid and you are
expected to do it as a woman anywhere in
the world but even more in certain
communities that have much more said
gender standards do you think an
indigenous woman has time to volunteer
for a note out for the keeping up of the
all-tournament server Oh keeping up any
other administering any other service so
basically their discourse is about how
non-binary it means people that are not
identified as men or women or
non-diverse or diverse people non white
people non C's male people have more
complications getting into autonomous
infrastructure autonomous technologies
I've been thinking that even free
software is a privilege do you know how
much time and knowledge it goes into
making that transition have you ever
wondered that or we just born in an
environment where you could do it you
could get it and then you just assume
everybody else should
is it the most ethical thing so what the
feminist infrastructure is worried about
is actually making the shift and caring
for the way that people are learning to
take care and appropriate their own
technologies I really like this quote we
don't want to scale up we want to skip
and keep it small in the sense of a
neighborhood where everybody knows each
other so the way that capitalism has
shaped the internet nowadays has us
thinking that there's only one way of
providing services and this is massively
because a massive service means more
profit so once again we need to redefine
technology this is high technology even
if it's a small autonomous server that
is only working for a community it is
high technology it doesn't mean that we
have to have Facebook drones to be
considered as high technology and then
this question about digital colonialism
I have to say it's been kind of getting
tracked in the latin-american civil
society environment I question the
concept itself because as I told you
earlier citing go miss Pena the
performance artists I think that if we
assume ourselves as victim of colonial
technology we're also vindicating the
own stereotype so my approach is rather
just question the concept of technology
itself and how are we defining our
relationship to technology and what
power is being invisible eyes their
power and voice is therefore so
basically the premise of the digital
technology we did sorry digital
colonialism which is essentially true is
that most of the world most of the
internet speaks English here's a 2017
statistics it's true English Chinese and
then Spanish and because of this the
content created by the people in the
global South is much less which opens up
a lot of discussions right because then
if say the history of Latin America in
Wikipedia was created well this is the
freebase graph the Wikipedia one is not
that good it's a bit crooked but the
argument is that there are more
Wikipedia articles inside of this circle
than outside of it this is Europe and as
you can see the other all the other
parts of the world are not that the
knowledge is not being as produced in
the global south this one as well this
is the ipv4 utilization and I believe
this is 2016 and this for me is shocking
we have content in English created by
the global north in terms of I Carville
archival processes this is quite
complicated because then it means that
we get historical narratives from the
global North search algorithms I'm super
worried about that proprietary search
algorithms that are also secret we don't
know how they prioritize information and
we don't know how Google for example
decides not to index something why why
would they not index something and we
don't even know about it it's the
biggest and most monopolistic search
engine in the world should there be any
kind of accountability for this and then
of course the bombard a copyright so
basically the fight of Cobra I could
talk for hours about this I will not but
basically we are the flexible is a ssin
of patents and the harsh inning of
copyright norm it's in favor of
multinationals and this is why NASA is
going to be a big issue right now the
free trade agreement the one that the
Sabbath East has rebelled against in 94
is being renegotiated as we speak by at
least two morons my president Enrique
Pena Nieto I cannot even mention three
books that he has read at a Book Fair
and do not yet even get me started about
Trump I cannot talk about that right now
but copyright provisions being lobbied
by big multinationals are going to get
in into NAFTA how are we going to push
back and what are we going to do about
it because that's gonna change the whole
ecosystem of the internet so third let's
take a quick glimpse at Latin America we
have our own problems and we have our
own solutions for them just because you
went backpacking to Latin America for
two months that's not means your
check about our you understand the
reality of the content to the continent
guess what we are not even a continent
with different countries stop calling us
the developing country we're not a
country there's a lot of them there's
not a namajunas reality we cannot even
agree amongst ourselves so let's drop
the Che Guevara fetishization as well
just quick statistics we have around
almost 60% of Internet penetration rate
compare it to Europe and North America
is quite a bit
Mexico is included in the North America
1 by the way so that my shift
percentages a bit as well and one of the
projects that was done who here knows
Facebook free basics do you know what
I'm so basically freebase books is free
basics was about not charging for
Facebook data and it was beautiful
because Global Voices just published
study about how it was a big fail
because it's digital colonialism they do
not take into account the local language
of the population all you get is ads
from the UK and US in the case of Mexico
from one of the most rich men in the
world which is Mexican and well it's not
the Internet it's just Facebook and some
of their crappy services so why would
that be a solution for the lack of
connectivity the answer is it's not
and then hashtags everywhere how despite
these platforms being evil or having
their own rules the world gardens they
have been useful and we have to
acknowledge that for political
organization this is the Eocene terrain
Tytos I am a hundred and thirty two it's
the one of the first and most important
social movements created by a hashtag
and a trending topic in Mexico and that
spread through Latin America in the
coming years it was against who the
moron who is now president he was a
candidate back then and the creation of
trending topics is crucial because in
countries where you have media being
manipulated by the government and
trending topics are a very effective way
of countering our
then take the street against corruption
in Peru yama can say this is so the
state the Mexican state disappeared 43
students 443 anarchists indigenous
students and what the DA's office the
police said oh I'm tired of looking for
them we could use we just cannot find
them I'm tired so we made a hash tag
saying hash tag I am tired
re-appropriating the hash tag it took a
lot of people out on the streets and
this was actually the first regional
movement with a lot of solidarity with a
lot of Casas because we're talking about
for its disappearance and we're talking
about media and not talking about forced
disappearances so then how do you get
past that informational gatekeeping
definitely Twitter was a big tool at the
time pirate webs against the metadata
retention in para ye then what am i la
with quit now they kicked out their
president who was presumably involved in
the Mayan genocide in Guatemala and also
killed one of the opposition leaders and
for @mf Tamir is the now president of
Brazil that made a coop the tag and
still my Rousseff which was one of the
first Latin American female presidents
in the continent she was in Brazil the
downsides of protesting in these
platforms are the tweeter votes the how
they are behaving I'm calling in the
Latin American fake news just because
this term is super trendy right now even
though I do not agree with it and then
of course the private censorship that
goes on in the platform so basically the
government especially in Mexico has been
documented in Ecuador and Venezuela as
well which are three super hot political
spots right now in Mexico with what the
Mexican government does is have a lot of
but accounts to repress hashtags and
prevent political organization how they
do this is that they coordinate spamming
through all these different bot accounts
but through the years they have become
really sophisticated they are not as
hard to catch as they were before so
once
IMing the hashtag the Twitter algorithm
just takes it down from the trending
topics
thus disabling political organization
and impeding us to the actual creation
of counter-narratives
we know what to do with propaganda right
you just burn it or something you know
how to deal with probably it's been
around forever political propaganda but
what do you do when you effectively have
what it looks like a cyber riot police
around your Twitter conversation how are
you going to fight that if we're talking
about private platforms proprietary
algorithms and just a Silicon Valley
company that is not that sensitive to
these kinds of topics because they don't
need to get spam out so these are the
questions that we're facing nowadays
would the answer be all just go and get
organized in your own autonomous
platform how would we teach people to do
that what would be the learning curve
and how could we effectively organize if
we do in such a platform this might be a
matter of life and death it's not it's
not that light Rampal miedo means do not
be afraid the repression of protest was
so much in Mexico at one point that
people stopped protesting it's a
chilling effect you silenced yourself
you self censor yourself so we make this
hashtag where we essentially monitored
where the cops were coming from so we
could effectively run away from them so
we had people monitoring telling us
where the greatest exits were and so
then if the government spends that you
get detained you get taken into the
special you need for crime organic safe
for criminal organizations because of
course protesting is a crime and then
protesting with more than five people
it's organized crime and then well you
just open that door in the Mexican
judicial system right gender has also
been super active through hashtags my
first harassment especially was a very
big hashtag throughout Latin America
women want to be alive and women life's
matter was more or less that we got a
lot of oh all life's matter too
it's like yes dude but you have two
houses one is burning down and the
one is not burning down and you're
putting out the fire in the one that is
not burning down just give the fire hose
to the people that actually need it no
so it was a complicated like that
offline the femicide raid in latin
america is very big at least one
thousand six hundred and seventy eight
women were killed because of
gender-based crimes which means
essentially gender hate it's really hard
for me to talk about this because i've
been close to it in several
investigations and occasions but it's
just bodies that are treated like
nothing in a katha pick one of the most
dangerous sites in mexico to be a woman
we found eight female bodies dumped in a
sewage in a trash bag so when we talk
about online gender violence we have to
know that the internet is not an
isolated reality but that it's also
connected to this offline violence and
machista violence that does exist
abortion a basic reproductive right is
still prohibited in chile salvador
nicaragua on dora site in Suriname and
not only that but if you are a
pro-abortion activists because you're
not supposed to be a pro-abortion
activists you will probably get a lot of
gender hate on your social networks
if you're a feminist if you're a I have
friends that are anchored women force
for Fox Sports and they get so many
death and rape threats because women are
not supposed to talk about sports
because women look better when they shut
up because you are go back to the
kitchen that's the easel that they get
the most go back to the kitchen well
that doesn't is the kitchen my place
should I not be speaking about politics
or sports because it's not gender
appropriate and they online violence
that they get it's part of the social
norm to perpetuate than their standards
so no the Internet is definitely now not
a safe place at least not from where I
see it very quickly what my first
harassment hashtag allowed us to
actually do was visualize and talk about
topics that were not
but that word taboo before it was just
about saying when you were first
harassed you cannot see this graph this
well but this is 18 years old and this
is 10 years old and this is 5 years old
so most women in Mexico and this was
Mexico and Central America get harassed
the first time when they be are between
five and ten years old we're basically
talking about child abuse here this was
a very good campaign because through
hashtags we could actually get all that
information and start making network
analysis and top and connect people more
conscious about this stuff you can also
break the taboo if you're a woman and
you have been harassed it's okay to tell
your story it's not your fault it was
not you you can speak up it's fine it
was a very beautiful very emotive social
network millennial moment then the
downsides of course on the other side is
all these platforms censoring
politically relevant and politically
protected content via their terms and
conditions like this picture we now
Facebook censors nipples they censor
nipples because our female nipples are
connected to a reproductive function and
because they are connected to a
reproductive function they are deemed as
erotic socially because your guys
nipples are not connected to a
reproductive function then they are not
so that's the stupid reason why Facebook
censors nipples it's either algorithmic
or it's their content managers we have
no fucking clue because of course the
algorithm is secret so black women
protesting this is obscene for facebook
they took it down so then the question
about the feminist infrastructure come
back comes back up can we resist on the
same platform as symbols and well
Instagram on shaving bikini lines needs
to be censored somehow because sure
women need to be perfectly well shaved
right we guys can be hairy women have to
be shaved
that's gender again it's definitely not
biological we're all born with hair so
super quickly let me go through this
surveillance scenario which is
also not very good I'm sorry I hope I
don't depress you but this is an
investigation I made in 2015 about
hacking team we all I'm going to assume
we all know the hacking team thing this
Italian malware company that sold
Galileo and they got hugged by Phineas
Fisher in 2015 as you can see in this
map almost all Latin America either
bought malware from hacking team or was
negotiating with hacking team when they
got hacked and they couldn't go through
the purchase which is worrisome for two
reasons first because we have
authoritarian governments buying malware
with no regulation and then we have
regulated we have malware that is being
used in the framework of the laws that
were valid in dictatorships so
dictatorial lost first surveillance now
being used with a super super invasive
malware how would that go wrong well how
can that go wrong can can somebody
please tell me so the biggest client of
hacking team again in the world was
Mexico buying almost 6 million euros
then we have Brazil but quite a bit as
well
and what was concerning here well it was
Brazil Colombia Ecuador on dudas and
Chile what was very concerning here was
that in Mexico it was used to spy
against activists and political
opponents in Ecuador it was used to spy
against political opponents and because
of a hacking team emails we knew that
the DEA effectively intercepted all
energy communications of Colombians
which was quite a scandal by itself it
got lost within all the hacking team
false emails but I think it says a lot
also about US intervention in Latin
America still nowadays then we have a
packrat which is one of the first proven
example of ideologically directed
malware because packrat this study
published by citizen lab showed how it
was targeted against communist countries
except for Brazil the rest of the
countries that we're packrat was
detected where
that communist Allegiance the Bolivarian
allegiance in latin america and then we
get to the bad guys i think of the year
NSO group sold two hundred and fifty
million dollars to the mexican
government
worth of pegasos this malware that it's
also remote-control malware and it was
used against the fiercest critics of the
president the female journalist that
uncovered the biggest corruption scandal
the white house her kid because she was
smart enough not to click on the
phishing links that and as the the
viruses malware sent to her to get
infected it was used against the lawyers
that are litigating the disappearance of
the 43 in the interior american court
and against anti-corruption activist and
then we knew they were used against
government opposition and some more
journalists and some more lawyers and
also there was a special commission that
was investigating the disappearance of
the 43 a special international
commission they got spied on also with
pegasos approximately each piece of
malware costs 1 million dollars so it's
a very expensive piece of malware that
is supposedly being used for national
security reasons but obviously this
shows what the abuses of malware are so
if there's any malware development
developers in the room just think about
how these technology is being used in
other places with the pretext of
preventing crime terrorism or the chapo
guzman escaping from the elegant well
this is just a cool project is
protesters by article 19 encoding rights
which was a response to counter
surveillance protesting surveillance
just like some tips on what you can do
you can cover your face some legal
advice take care with what you post
encrypt etc so essentially
yes we have our own problems but we have
our own solutions as well it does not
necessarily mean that we are idiots or
we cannot do technology ourselves as I
already said I went through the midst of
the Sabbath East as I went through the
myths mythology of how Latinos and us
women cannot create technology and I've
been I take I retake what the latest
poem of the Sabbath estas on the
internet is well first of all there is
not one internet let me just be clear
about that
the Internet's are a lot and they are
connected to geopolitical realities as
well and as I was saying it's not a
neutral space not just because you have
a chat or a platform or a mailing list
it means that everybody can express
themselves equally because power
relationships are being replicated
gender class and race relationships are
being replicated so essentially the
question of the Sabbath estas is is the
internet sphere that still a space of
dispute and struggle or how we
completely lost that battle what can we
do now here from our privilege to keep
feeding a more open and diverse space so
for four-and-a-half things maybe five
first do not appropriate our narratives
now just because you went to an acquaint
Rosa Batista once does not mean that you
know what you're talking about we are
not just emotional and irrational people
it would be super nice to have that
acknowledged every once in a while be
self-conscious about your privilege
having time to volunteer is a privilege
do not judge people that do not have it
take a pause and think about diversity
in your own work environment pause and
think how you can get more women in your
hug spaces pause and think what you are
doing to effectively silence minority
voices online or offline are you
trolling the woman are you the troll
that is trolling the woman are you the
troll that is trolling the Indian guy
Abby
10 next door let's be conscious about
our privilege this is definitely a first
step online or offline recognize that we
might have some solutions for our
community problems it's not only a
one-way street it's not only what it's
done in Europe what should be copied
because a lot of things are not working
here we might have creative solutions
for that and finally ask questions
before telling us what to do or the
famous mansplaining I have to say I've
been getting it quite a lot here at a
child but don't assume that you are
right
just because you are right ask questions
first get to know the other person let's
intersect let's touch each other more
recognize the gender class and race are
a real problem outside of this bubble
let's make this a real conversation we
all want a more diverse equal and open
internet for everyone thank you very
much
[Music]
thank you very much Gizella do we have
any questions we have some time for
questions I won't bite I promise I was a
bit harsh on you at the end
[Laughter]
all right let's thank you shall I again
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]