[Music]
welcome welcome to my talk
my name is yeah you don't wanna home I
work for the National cybersecurity
Center in the Netherlands and I'm also a
guest researcher at TU delft the
Technical University of Delft and there
I also think about ethics in computing
in cybersecurity research in all kinds
of stuff and I want to take you on a
journey on how I I learned that some of
the cases that I've run into and have a
discussion about these cases and think
about how these cases impact the world
and maybe also our work so four years
ago my wife let me go to Oh hm
I'm very grateful and she let me go
again I'm grateful again but at HM there
was I gave a talk about the power of big
words small recap back then there was a
court case in the Netherlands or just a
couple of months before there was a
court case in the Netherlands where the
copyright organization was suing the
ISPs to block access to the Pirate Bay
website
when this court case was going on
everybody knew that this blockade of the
website was at zero effect everybody
knew their way around the blockade
either by using a different DNS server
by using a VPN on it on a different
country by using an IP address by using
Google Translate or any other other kind
of way so everybody knew that this was
ineffective but nobody measured the
effect and I thought hmmm this is this
is measurable I you're using BitTorrent
BitTorrent forms this form you can
monitor the swarm you can monitor swarms
before and blockade goes into effect you
can monitor them after and then you can
detect whether there is a shift in ISPs
present in those forms so that's what I
did I monitor I wrote a small program
that joined the swarm logged IP
addresses and then I looked at the ratio
between the different ISPs before and
after certain IP blocked and there was
almost no difference in in the
distribution which meant that the
blockade actually had no effect so I
just spent a weekend putting a Python
script together scraping all of these
records and I I logged two and a half
million records in two weeks for ten
movies that were mostly Dutch movies
touch spoken movies to make sure that we
had very representative Dutch population
but back then somebody asked me the
question is it actually legal what
you're doing and that got me thinking
because storing IP addresses is actually
not legal in the Netherlands because IP
addresses are considered personal
information and you can only store them
when you have content and there was no
way for me to ask consent to everybody
who was using BitTorrent so this got me
thinking
I approached NSA's ethicist to talk
about this case and we looked at all
kinds of different scopes on how this
this actually works and in the end we we
concluded that because this was research
because this was done in the general
interest of people to make sure that
there was clarity that this was a
scientific result and because informing
them beforehand would influence the
results probably this was this was
probably ethically okay yes so the
got me interested in ethics and I went
down the path of ethics and and figuring
out whether there were more cases that
computer science and ethics collided why
should we look at ethics in computing
well the and I made this this speech
also to a workshop on on internet
measurements and there I said basically
academics and computer scientists are
given a very large space to do their
research and they have a freedom of
teaching freedom to carry out research
freedom to express opinions and freedom
from institutional censorship at least
ideally they have but with great power
comes great responsibility
and what you see is that we're seeing
now that ethics is becoming more of a
part of the discussion in computer
science and also the general public is
discovering that this actually affects
them that the computer that the
decisions that are made in algorithms
really affect our daily lives that we
need to have this discussion but we also
need to think about how we implement
this into academic research an academic
research in in computer science and this
this is typical of how at least internet
measurement researchers think about
research they make a Venn diagram saying
use of privacy laws and then there's a
big circle saying useful internet
research and then there is a huge
overlap where they're breaking the law
but they're doing interesting research
and this is just not okay this approach
is not okay because we need to have a
discussion about all of the useful
Internet research and there's ways of
doing a lot of the useful internet
research that
if you do this naively you would break
the law but there's probably ways that
you can do this without breaking the law
formal ethics in the u.s. at least for
every University there's an
institutional review board that would
look at these kind of ethics questions
in Europe there are ethics committees
and each universities should probably
have them but the ethics committees in
in at least in European universities
they mostly look at plagiarism
Professional Conduct and they don't look
at the kind of experiments that computer
scientists are doing and if you look at
the institutional review boards that we
have in the US they have a very strict
definition of what kind of reviews they
can do and that is human subject
research and if it doesn't contain if a
study doesn't contain actual humans
actually living humans that are directly
affected by the study the IRB won't
bone touch that reverse research and now
well I'll review a case where this is
actually where this comes up what you
see now is that there's increasingly
becoming funding questions in European
research this morning we had a very nice
talk by the Satori project that
mentioned that was built upon the idea
of responsible research and innovation
which has become a very cornerstone of
the idea of European funding so now for
European with funding European research
funding you need to do responsible
research and innovation you need to
demonstrate that you're actually doing
that but it's mostly tick boxes it
mostly checkbox is saying yes I'm doing
this and there's no real check that this
is actually done
so the the formal ethics I think as our
a very good first step
but we need to make the the community
morally aware and we need to discuss
these questionable cases with each other
without blaming people and we need to
discuss whether this can actually be
done without bad consequences and to
help people think about how other well
to think about other ways that their
research could be done without the
ethically questionable methods so one of
the first cases that I did I want to
discuss is the the face book emotional
contagion study this was a study that
was performed by Facebook with the idea
that they wanted to see whether they
could influence the emotions of Facebook
users and they did this by by filtering
the news that that people got they
looked at the posts the the timelines of
english-speaking Facebook users they
analyzed the emotion that was in posts
and they they filtered out if you they
filter out into seventy several
different groups and it checked if you
get only negative emotions what happens
if you get positive emotions or some
kind of mix and the end results was
actually that there was a very small
effect that if you get only negative
emotions and you start using posts with
less words but it was a really small
effect but the the most important part
of this this study of how the study was
performed was actually that they didn't
ask the Facebook users for their
permission they didn't even inform them
after the experiment was done and the
results were done they didn't inform the
users that they were actually part of an
experiment and the University this was
done internally at Facebook but in
cooperation with the University and
University institutional review board
was involved in this study in so far
that the researchers actually told the
IRP saying we're just providing the
methodology Facebook has the data we
don't access the data so there's no
human subjects in in this in the part
that we do so this was actually you
could you could say this this is this
limits the scope of an institutional
review board it becomes an ethical
whitewashing because the the actually
the actual academic review is not
performed of the ethically the ethical
part of the study so then the process
fails a different study that was
actually performed was measuring
censorship this was a study by performed
in the group of Nick flame stir and
others the research was that they used
they tricked computers into trying to
locate to trying to contact a webpage
and then observe the behavior of the
computer from the sidelines and then
from that they could either see whether
connection was successful or not but
what they actually did was that they
tricked the other people's computer to
access a website that was censored so
you're affecting Joe you're doing as if
that computer acts as a sensor website
which could really affect the the people
who own that computer because all of a
sudden they have to explain to their
government to their police or whatever
why they were accessing that censored
website and the defense of the of the
Internet researchers were saying we need
to do this study because we want there's
no other way to measure censorship they
they say they were very careful in the
sites that they selected that should be
addressed and in this case the
conference where this research was
published the reviewers said this is not
okayed what you're doing we really want
your IRB to sign off on the research
that you're doing so the researchers
went back to the university's IRB the
IRB said we don't see any human subjects
don't bother us there's nothing that we
can do about this
the reviewers of the conference they I
heard later that this paper was actually
sent to a numerous different conferences
and and at some point one of the
reviewers they said well being we need
to have discussion about whether this is
acceptable or not and we should probably
publish this in the meantime one of the
researchers was actually actually moved
to a different University so they said
could you please try the the
institutional review board of the other
university and they did and the other
the IRB gave the same result they said
we don't see any human subjects
therefore we can't can't judge this so
go away finally this research was
published with a big comment by the
reviewers saying this is we don't think
that this is OK
we checked with two different IRB and
they said we can't judge this but we
need to have this conversation whether
we accept this kind of research or not
[Music]
so yeah that's the the the big statement
that there was put on top of the of
their paper finally a different way on
how publishing data can actually affect
effective research if you have a big
pile of data and you want to anonymize
the data you really need to be careful
and in this case this this was not an
academic research but there was a sort
of an and attempt to make it to
anonymize the data but it turned out
that the innocent data or the seemingly
innocent data of New York taxi rides was
actually pretty harmful the the story
was that one of the one person in living
in New York found that the city in New
York was publishing a statistic about
the taxi rides in in New York they had
and he wondered well you're basing this
on data about all of the taxi rides in
New York so you probably have data on it
and I would like to have a place in the
city of New York said sure if you buy
USB stick then we'll give it to you and
he got two big tables CSV tables with
which contain data on the pickup
location the drop-off location and GPS
coordinates that were very very accurate
the
well of course the date and the time and
the other table was half sort of
correlated but it contained the the
price that was paid or the affair that
was calculated for that right but it
also included the tip amount that was
given by the client the the data was
correlated back to the taxi driver so
you could see each of the taxis but it
was hashed with the sha-1 hash and the
result with the the taxi was actually
the the number to each of the taxis in
New York has a number and the number is
like five or six digits may contain some
letters but the space of that is not
that big and you probably guess it yes
it was insulted so you place a sha-1
hash to a very small search space and
you can reproduce this and you can
reproduce it so you prove you make a
lookup table and you research this back
what happens then is that you have time
and location of the taxis but you
actually have a lot of pictures of
celebrities getting in and out of cabs
and if you have that then you can
correlate it back to the rides that they
have and from that they concluded that
Jessica Alba is a very bad tipper
[Music]
with the the the lesson in this is that
if you want to publish all kinds of data
you have to be really really careful and
an anonymizing that kind of data and you
should you should really think about
that before you do that
[Music]
one of the things that we talked about
this morning if you are doing research
you have to look at the people that are
affected by your research and it goes a
lot further than you would initially
think you're you yourself are affected
by the research because if your research
is attacked then you're you're blamed
about your research so you have to have
a way of defending yourself which may
mean that you have to have more data
than you would ethically want to have
your your group at the university or
company will isn't is a stakeholder in
in your research
of course the subjects but if you
collect data about enough subjects or a
very small subject a set of data then it
could be that you're affecting subjects
outside of the collected data and
sometimes the research that you do also
affect your colleagues even in your
company or if you do a very bad kind of
research then it may even affect the
whole field that you're in like I mean
like I mentioned before the IRB is only
handled federal grants and human subject
research and the ethics committees that
we have in Europe are really
ill-equipped they don't they don't have
anybody who understands computing and
we've seen how bad this is with
politicians but this goes even further
with ethics committees because they have
no idea what is going on and they don't
understand all of the problems and even
if a computer scientists
if you like me you're starting to wonder
whether is something is acceptable or
not and you go to an ethics committee
and they say we don't know yeah that
doesn't really help me so one of the
things that I've been doing is trying to
start up this discussion in competing
trying to start up the discussion at
least in the Netherlands about having
more ethics committees in computer
science and like I mentioned before with
the censorship study study in the
censorship study that there are no
direct humans and subjects in the
research or even in the taxicab data
there are no direct human subjects in
research but through the research you
are affecting the the you're inferring
things about the taxi drivers but also
about the passengers and other people
that are in this in this research so we
really should be thinking about human
harming research whether instead of
human subjects research I'd like to
close this off with us with a good
example because I implemented an ethical
review in a master education program at
the University of Amsterdam and a very
good example that I presented also at
ECC a couple of years back but it's
still a good a good case study in this
case this was so this was about tinder
and tinder has had and still has a very
bad rap for treating their user data
the very first one of the first versions
of tinder it actually sends the GPS
coordinates of your matches to your
phone
so as you get local you could calculate
the distance to those matches on your
phone and it sent it over HTTP and you
could just intercept it there's an open
API and you can just contact it and get
all kinds of data that means you could
you could basically track somebody I was
using tinder while they were using
tinder you can see where they were when
they were doing it so somebody contacted
tener saying this is not really a good
idea so they thought about it they
thought about it a few minutes they
change the API they change the app and
now they sent they calculated the
distance on the server and they only
sent two they sent the exact distance to
your phone
they still had an open API which means
you could just pick a couple of points
you need three points and you can locate
somebody exactly on where they are so it
took you a little bit more effort to
actually locate people so this was all
done then my student they then dinner
said okay we'll do better we will do
better and they implemented the
threshold of a hundred meters and
everything below one hundred meters that
was rounded to 100 meters and my
students wanted to know whether this was
actually effective and I said okay you
can do this but if you want to do this
then you have to get informed consent of
all of the people that you're messing
this on they said okay we can do this
and they also created some test subjects
on their own and they went out and
started doing some research they found a
way to access the API they found a way
to access all kinds of data and a couple
of days later they came back to me and
said we have a problem we were doing the
research at a university and a very big
population of tinder users or students
so that meant they couldn't find their
own subjects back in the big pile of
data that were they were
back from tinder so they can't
effectively perform their research well
okay we want to do this in an ethically
acceptable way we have to think about
the new way of doing this and eventually
we settled on doing this by hashing the
user ID that they got back from the from
the the tinder API and storing the
distance that they got from from the
server so they could from that they
could infer whether you could locate
somebody back or not but you couldn't
see who it was and what their exact
location was and with that with that
methodology they actually found that it
didn't indeed implement the threshold
but in the API calls you can actually
set a threshold number went from so
their brains that you want to search
within and if you search within ten
meters then you get results that say
that they are actually 100 meters away
from you but the set of results you get
back is a lot smaller than if you ask
for within 100 meters so they they're
only spoofing the number but the number
is actually still there so with that
they found that the tinder didn't
actually implement a good way of hiding
the location and you could still track
tinder users we tried to report this to
tinder they never responded them I don't
actually know whether they fix it or not
but at least we were able to in my idea
we were able to research this in an
ethically acceptable way without
affecting directly the the privacy of
the tinder users
the the takeaways that I have for this
talk in ethics matter matter for
internet research for security research
basically for generally for computer
science research think about the
stakeholders think about think outside
of the box think about people that
aren't indirectly involved in their
research that you do even if it's just a
very small research that you do if
you're at the University the IRB is and
the ethics committees they need help and
they need people to start thinking about
this and helping them start thinking
about this and finally don't be afraid
to reach out to other people to start
thinking about the ethical aspects of
security research or internet
measurement research and it really helps
to talk to others about the kind of
research that you're doing and the risks
that you're seeing and maybe even
missing unfortunately there was a really
good web page ethical research South org
it appears that it went down and it's
not actually available anymore I'm
trying to get it back up or at least
figuring out why it's down but it was a
good way for people to to actually reach
out and discuss this kind of cases if
that page doesn't come back up I'm
always available to talk about research
ideas and help you think about ethical
aspects of it and you can reach me
through that email address or the other
one or in person here and with that I
thank you very much for your attention
[Applause]
questions so let's see
imagine the taxicab research was
performed at your own University what
would you have recommended the
scientists in this case because the the
data set was not his and presumably this
is a data set that anyone can just
obtain so which complicates the matter
even more the the data sets he actually
had to go physically go to the office of
the unit the city of New York to get to
data he didn't really think about it and
he didn't know whether there was a
problem in the data or not and he just
published it online and and said look
this is cool data and you can do cool
stuff with it and it was there was a lot
of people who were doing cool stuff with
it but later somebody looked at it and
said there there was a problem in an
organization I would say that if you're
starting to do this kind of publication
of personal data or even indirectly
personal data you really have to reach
out to somebody who knows anonymization
anonymization is a very difficult field
it's being researched a little I'm
trying to do that and I'm I'm doing it
for a network data and I'm figuring out
that it's basically impossible to
anonymize network data which is a very
sad conclusion but I think that that
it's a valid conclusion still or it's
near impossible but for other kinds of
data it is actually possible to do it in
your anonymization in this case if you
would just have salted the sha-1 hash
then it would have been impossible to
correlate almost impossible to correlate
back
so yeah I would have suggested that that
would be done but after once the data
was out there there's nothing you can do
about it anymore
[Music]
have you looked at the way fringe the
field of like sociology handled this few
decades back because that same problem
that's observing behavior could be
ethically problematic yeah and they also
had I mean I think now they also have
the the medical ethical committee days
to go by all kinds of research yeah but
we all set a problem with it well when
you not have a specific research group
of people in the chamber but you observe
people in the wilds just behavior in the
wild that can be problematic with asking
go sense from people and all kind of
stuff so yeah if you look at that I have
and I've also there's also there's been
a very big study performed by the Dutch
world Royal Academy of Sciences they've
looked at the ethical aspects of of
computer science research and one of the
first things that they did is they
reached out to the medical community to
the social communities to see what they
were doing and actually if you look at
well there's a very funny story there
there was a meeting there was a
professor of medical science it was at
the meeting where we were discussing
ethical aspects of community science
research and he said I don't get it we
have these medical files and it used to
be in a cabinet and now they're on a
computer I don't see a problem but with
with that medical ethics is actually a
really small field and it's very
restricted again there it's it's human
subject research medical research but if
sociology sociology it's different yes
and in sociology used you have the very
big idea of informed consent and you
have to sign a consent form
if you want to participate in a study
and you have to write the consent form
in such a way that people participating
in the study they actually know what
they're signing up for and you can
sometimes be deceitful but what kind of
study you're performing but then you
really really need to tell them
afterwards what you were actually doing
so yes in social sciences they did do
more than in medical sciences but still
the the problem in computer science is
that we have we're doing a lot of
research that really indirectly affects
people and very often like the case I
had with the Pirate Bay words there is
no way at all to actually reach out to
the users and that becomes a problem for
instance for measuring people well in
the wild let's say that when when you
can't also consent from everyone passing
by at a certain point or something they
have some institutions to check that
right and there would be anything to
look at but I can what I can imagine is
that if you do that for one you're doing
it in a public space and people can be
monitored in a public space without
their consent and second most of the
results that they do don't lead back to
an individual and they're mostly about
totals and averages and the discussion
of a public place
you see internet the public place I'm
not going
to answer that but with the the research
that you do for a social science like I
said a lot of the research that you can
do you can do without leading back to
individuals and for internet research
it's a lot harder to make sure that you
that something is not traceable back to
a person Oh back there oh this may be a
naive question but I was wondering why
you consider about the Facebook research
why do you consider the bad thing that
users are not aware that they are being
part of an experiment I mean from a
research perspective you can actually
argue that it's a good thing yes they
are being manipulated but people are
many play with all deference by
billboards as it's set up it goes back
to the it goes back to the slide that I
had in the very beginning if you're
doing academic research you get a lot of
freedom but you also get a lot of
responsibility with that I think with
the Facebook study there's actually an
underlying discussion whether we think
it's acceptable this Facebook is doing
this kind of research in in instead of
universe university researchers doing
this kind of research do we have a
different measure for what Facebook is
doing versus what academics are doing
and there is also the fact that for many
of the stuff that Facebook did in that
study they do it all day anyway
they just don't they just don't publish
about it and that's that's basically the
difference and that in this case there
was actually a public publication about
it and because there was a publication
there was a very big discussion about
whether this was acceptable or not so I
guess for academics there's there's a
higher standard
yeah do you see that has a problem that
hues are not aware they are part of the
experiment I mean what's the problem
with that they are aware they might be
biased yeah that's true
that's true but then like I said for
academics there's a higher standard if
you do want to do a research where it's
problematic to inform people beforehand
then one of the things that has to
happen is that you have to reach out to
an ethics committee you have to tell
them what you're going to do and they
make sure that this doesn't actually
harm anybody and if that you have
measures in place that if it does harm
anybody that you can pull the plug
and that you have ways of supporting the
people that are in the data in the
experiment and finally there's the
expectation that you inform people
afterwards
but in the Facebook study they didn't
even do that how would it compare to for
instance billboards because they also
basically manipulate you into wanting a
certain project your product just warned
for it you or not no we're no committee
involved probably no but for that we
have I mean that's accepted practice and
people know about it and and it's I
guess it's part of your your upbringing
that you were told about that but these
kind of things that you were told that
what kind of effects it has on you yeah
there was a question back there
hi I can see why Facebook's research was
problematic from an ethical point of
view I just cannot see how your research
regarding a part of a Pirate Bay might
raise concerns now I do understand the
legality I understand the fact that
gathering storing IP addresses is we go
in terms of previous law
but I don't see it as an ethical could
you comment on that
was that your I mean he collected those
addresses but you processed this
information in order to produce a
statistical result which approved the
point right
but then I said there's nothing
unethical in that but it's illegal the
way those addresses were stored in your
computer maybe well there's so there's
actually there's a very big overlap
between the Facebook study and the study
that I did is I gathered the data
without telling people without so while
I was deceiving people in giving me the
data because they were they I joined
this forum and they were expecting me to
help them in in voting the BitTorrent
process and I didn't or at least I
didn't do I also collected their data
which is something that I don't get
permission for them to do and for in
fact Facebook at the time of the
contagion study the user License
Agreement didn't contain scientific
research as part of something that you
provide an agreement for and it took
them a couple of months and then they
they did add it so now they have your
permission to do academic research on
that all of the data that you provide to
them
okay thanks any more questions that I
thank you very much oh there's one
question back there I mean so I think
you brought up some good questions and I
would say that we should make sure in
looking at research that we don't
conflate legality and ethics going in
either direction
but I just wanted to kind of so most of
my friends are not technical people and
a lot of them found the Facebook study
really offensive because they felt like
they were being deeply deeply
manipulated and also just with it like
you said that the result for people who
are showing only negative content was
very minor and it only led to a decrease
in the number of words in a post but I
would argue that we don't actually know
what the number of words in the post
means and the number of words in the
post may actually correlate to something
like a significantly higher rating on
like a depression index and so while we
can look at and in something like this
sort of research we can look at the
outcome and go oh well that's minor we
may actually be seeing what looks like a
small result that correlates to a much
much larger actual human impact that's
true yes I think they did try to look at
that and of course Facebook has a lot
more data about people that that they
didn't probably saw that they didn't
take into account in their in the whole
analysis I don't know whether they took
that into account to judge whether
people got depressed or not I mean and I
guess also just like there are a lot of
assumptions built into like the
emotional impact and assuming that the
only measurement of it is Facebook
engagement sorry I I went to grad school
for public health so I think that
there's a lot
really really deeply wrong with the
Facebook study even if it seems people
yeah so I guess the conclusion is that
people are very sensitive when you start
messing with their emotions all right
thank you very much for your attention
I'm here if you want to discuss more and
enjoy a shower
[Applause]
[Music]