[Music]
we're going to talk today about
commanding control centers for malware
and botnets systems and how you can
attack those instead of having to patch
your system all the time this is the
future we are here now yeah exactly the
future is now
welcome senator look for this talk and
have a warm welcome for him please okay
so thanks everyone for coming into today
and this is a free solarium right so too
bright so I'm sorry about this but I
didn't know that I cannot use the white
slide so a little bit about myself so I
born in Macedonia so yeah I still write
three wars so I like everyone else here
I believe so I start hacking and I
published a lot of hacks so far but most
important ones and with a number most of
them are heavily for the commanding
control centers currently I'm living and
working in Amsterdam in Netherlands so
yeah today we're going to I'm going to
speak about four famous botnets even if
there is more than 20 research but we
don't have a time but you can find all
of them in the Shah 2017 webpage so you
can download the wall PDF now you have
more info there and also I'm going to
disclose the Prada for Netherlands the
fiber optic internet router which they
called dry tech hack so basically they
closed the option about the bridge mode
I don't know why so I of course
I report this so they patch it but if
you have a older version of firmware
then you can still trick them and you
can put your router on the bridge club
so yeah first of all family and friends
yeah my son and daughter because
research requires a lot of time and I'm
stealing always from their free time so
without them it's not possible to make
anything because if they are not
forgiving their time then there will be
no research right like everyone else so
my clicker
today I'm going to speak again again
against the soda botnets I'm going to
speak about why we still suck at modern
infections then I'm going to speak about
the crypto lock right the one of the
first round some words in the world
science 2014/15 so where I managed to
breaking inside of this botnet well the
attack was ongoing right so we will a
lot of stuff we share with with
community and stuff like that then I'm
going to rebel also the men in the
browser so I'll we know that to be able
to make a credit card still or malware
you must have a man-in-the-middle props
to attack to bypass the second factor
right so right now in the underground
there is a man in the middle browser
builder right so you can build your own
man in the middle browser attack against
any bank you like in the world it's so
easy then I'm going to speak about the
nice botnet which was very interesting
right full autopilot mode where they
were hacking the nest but nest devices
attached storage devices from the vendor
to net they were hacking them arming
them and then patching them again so to
be sure that no one else was going to
hug them again right so it was a
infinite loop and then I'm going to
speak about the king's family of mobile
right
especially for the banking Trojan
which has a really interesting web let's
say electronic banking application right
which is better than I am using here
like from the ABN AMRO right so they
build better web application for
electronic banking so first of all you
why we are still getting hacked and why
all the transfer is outside right
because what we all are doing is - we
are putting a defense in that right so
we are putting a defense in depth liars
in or come in our companies or in our
homes etc etc so we are trying to
protect our endpoints from the Malvar
attacks right but we are missing
something here the defense in that works
with two fundamental logic first one is
it allows the non good files to pass in
and it blocks the non bad files to
guaran right the biggest problem here is
the unknown files we know what happened
with a wanna cry around somewhere we
know we know what happened with every
single zero-day attack that came in like
a fresh model right
why because this piece of code was
unknown so there was not disposition for
this piece of malware for that reason
all these defense technologies couldn't
stop them right did you guys ever saw a
zero-day attack which is unknown good
which is unknown bad right then it's not
zero they read everything which is zero
there must be unknown and unfortunately
these technologies today if we don't
have a proper sandbox in and if we don't
have a proper good and real time trans
intelligence we cannot find them right
another reason why we are still behind
of the bad guys is that we still believe
that malware on the network is the
mother right
this is a pick up of the mother and this
is the same malware which is active on
the endpoint
so I do think guys which one is the
mother your left one oh right one come
on
left-right perfect yes malicious
activity malicious software right
it must be active to do a malicious
stuff right I don't know what is
happening more yes
so unfortunately yes we are trying to
fight this zero the attacks only from
the network side which will not help us
so we must be on the endpoint that's
what we are seeing on the on the market
last last couple of years so now coming
to the botanist this I don't know why
this is going so fast so in 2013 there
was a cryptolocker right we all know one
of the first let's say publicly run
somewhere right that time when they
start to deliver the malware we receive
some intelligence that time and I had a
CNC server so what we are doing is like
we receive some threat intelligence and
we are building or IP reputation tables
to stop that CNC traffic and then if we
have the malware piece of code we can do
a reverse engineering and stuff like
that to figure out what the model is
doing and based on that we are building
a signatures to block it right so that's
all the cyber security researchers are
doing right some of them like me I'm not
interested too much about the monitor
right I'm interested the C&C server but
he is speaking a lot that's what's my
focus on all my researches right I
really want to be inside their houses
and to see what they are doing that was
my main aim on all my researches right
I wanted to unlock their logic I wanted
to see how how the C&C server looks like
I wanted to see the functionality I
wanted to see what they stole from the
victims and stuff like that so the
infection process we all know about this
specific model especially the ransomware
it was an email right it was coming with
the attachment and attachment had macro
code which was forcing to Mulder to
connect to C&C server etc etc but what's
important
site of the census error right so when I
when I'm doing a botnet research the
first thing that I'm trying to figure
out is where is the C&C server hosted
right mainly they're hosting on the
compromised web server right no one will
not by a legal web server from GoDaddy
and to publish a C&C server right so
they are hacking this shirt host or
dedicated host and they're deploying the
chances are rather right so to be able
to figure out first thing you need to do
is to find a way to find the same way
how they hack the web server to deploy
the mulder right so they figure out some
vulnerability on that server web server
they deploy the C&C server and they're
serving the C&C server right so first
thing is you need to realize how they
hack that web server so you can use the
same techniques to hug their C&C server
right so they're smart right especially
if it's a shirt host what they are doing
is they're going to hack some web server
which is a wordpress or some CMS is that
right but they are going to deploy the
C&C server on another V host which has
only HTML web server right so when you
are going to check use okay there's that
HTML there is nothing variable on this
web server but basically that means that
they didn't hack that virtual host they
hack some another way to host but then
they had a root access so they saw all
hosted web pages on the on that surface
and they put the C&C server on the non
vulnerable right so they're doing this
kind of trust that this kind of tricks
to hide the traces when I penetrate to
this change the server I saw that there
is a two configuration one was the admin
and one was the user right the most
important thing was that they have our
own configuration files right oh this is
good but this is a forum where they can
configure about how much money they're
going to ask from them
right this is a configuration page I'm
logging in I'm going to define my HTML
file
you know the Ransom where they're going
to ask the ransom I'm going to define
define which countries I'm going to
attack I'm going to define how much is
my amount that I'm going to request for
grant so message residue and then I'm
going to click a submit here on the
right page I can see how my attack look
like on the second one I'm going to
configure the decryption right so I'm
going to upload my deck with decryption
application I'm going to define the main
URL the support how they go into login
etcetera etcetera right so this is their
back end real back end from the CNC
servers then of course to deliver the
attack I need to have email accounts
right to make a mess phishing attacks
right so what I figure out inside that
there was a lot of meals a lot and they
had a Mail's from Dutch people they had
a mail from UK citizens they had a mail
from the Germany etc they had all
classified mail folders for every single
country and most important they have
already a lot of SMTP credential stolen
to use on the on the mass spam campaign
so this is a infected users right so
every single user here is a machine in
fact an encrypted right so far that time
there was a two thousand and something
infections right the another thing was
is that the email addresses used for
this phishing campaign for ESS pine
Spain there was two thousand five
hundred eighty email address for Great
Britain there was twelve thousand for
Italian for Netherlands right so they
have a very nice and very narrow
victim target right based on the country
and based on their language etc etcetera
and what also I saw inside is that
they're keeping support right when
you're asking them to unlock your files
when you are telling them that you pay
the ransom SS receptor so they have some
kind of ticket in portal but what I saw
on the ticket in portal it was that a
lot of people paid and they didn't
receive the decryption right this is a
proof from their side from their data
that they are not providing a decryption
case so everything was there so they
built our own system for delivering the
crossover now the second very
interesting and very dangerous C&C
server was the man-in-the-middle browser
builder right so we all know to create
to steal a credit card information and
to transfer our money you really need to
have a very good developer right you
must have a man in the middle brother
attack you must bypass the second factor
right you must have some zero
exploitation you must have a privilege
escalation to be able to steal the money
from the user right and as per today it
was very tough job for a underground
guys to build a man-in-the-middle
browser attack right because they must
know the web application of the bank
they must analyze it very well and based
on that to build many in the middle
browser plugin that they can deliver
through the mother right today is very
easy so this is indication to compromise
the details which I don't I will not
bother you too much because again my
focus is on the C&C server itself right
so we know that this CNC server is used
by Keynes by Zeus and the blocks is
supporting this to exploit it kids let's
say
this was the login page of this CNC
server right so they put a big bill of
the money right so they they're very
they love their job right I mean he lost
that time to find this kind of picture
and to put it on the CNC login page
right I don't know if you guys can see
it I'm really sorry from this white here
but this is a this is their Webster this
is their web application back-end here
you can define the attack campaign you
can you can see how many online
both victims you have you can see how
many offline BOTS Wix victims you have
right so you can build for every
specific bank men in the middle brushed
erotic who going to bypass the second
factor here you can edit the
functionality of the members of the Bob
of the bot of the of the blocks right I
don't know if you guys can see it or not
that's very bad then you need to read my
PDF so the in this blocks here basically
what they can do is that they can define
which victim groups will belong for the
which bank so they can build the men in
the middle block static for that bank
and they can push the configuration to
the the malware itself right so it's
full automatic right I mean so they
deployed the dropper right dropper
checks their bookmarks he checks their
gear location it says the city Sarah hey
Iowa Italian Italian PC here Italian guy
he has a bookmark for I don't know into
the San Paulo Bank and some another Bank
right so give me I mean in the middle
browser attack for these banks and from
here they're pushing this kind of stuff
right so he don't need to go and to do
anything manual it's just everything
here everything is on the portal then
what they are doing right so for every
single block they can generate a
commands right so they have a go comment
is they're allowing the victim to reach
the original banking application they
have a question they can
the question you know they must delay so
they must show the victim that the money
is transferred between the Bob and Alice
but in background is going to Bob the
job right to do this they are tricking
everything so drinking you are you are
asking a question you can push error
questions you can push advanced
JavaScript you can halt the function the
transaction button right they can show
you some error tricks they can kick you
out from the banking right because they
don't want you to log in and to see that
money went somewhere else so they can
keep you on all right and they can
confirm with the fake messages and then
you can forward you to the different
page right so everything is configurable
everything was configurable actually in
this CNC survey you don't need to be a
coder anymore right so just go here pay
them some fee you have a man in the
middle browser build builder go
somewhere else I don't know by the
milkers deploy your mother and you are
ready to go and then what what we have
here it was a custom injections right
because the most biggest problem that
they are facing is the one-time
passwords right
the second factor and to bypass that
they have a special section where they
can trick you to enter your second pass
for all TV pass well you know they're
all one minute right Lent
so for the one minute then you are
decided you are designing here the
system will ask you the OTP you're
putting your TP you don't know why it's
asking you have to pee right and then
they're taking that code and they're
transferring the money so we are not
safe right even without ap we're not
safe with this kind of stuff I can see
very nice faces from the light here so
the another botnet was the cannot mass
right the network attached storage we
all know the shell shock attack right it
was famous but using the shell shock
attack they hacked up I don't know how
many thousand of this cannot mass
service right but they built the attack
in that way that way it was a fully
automatic right
they needed to in fact just one turn up
device and then that cannot device was
infecting other tune up devices right it
was really nice
so what was happening it was that they
were deploying the first of all they are
making a massive shell shock
vulnerability attack right then they are
deploying the payload then they're
patching against the shell shock
they don't want this device to get
hacked by another somebody else so they
are patching them they're putting the
DDoS application inside and they're
deploying the scanner we're going to
scan and who going to hack other botnet
devices that cannot devices sorry this
is the idea Steve I'll alert right when
we saw the cannibalize the capella then
this was the payload hosted on the
compromised web server then from there I
came to the video server except is an
elf script right running running from
Linux is executable actually right doing
DDoS attacks they put up HT HTML
backdoor CGI script right so they can
control the the infection but most
important was it was just automatic
everything was going automatic so of
course we report the tune up and that
time and they patched a stuff like that
but a lot of device is still vulnerable
because they patched the vulnerability
right so they own the device and they're
patching the Venables so last C&C server
if you remember I mentioned better than
the ABN AMRO right it was a kima kin
smaller by the way this is the victims
here this you can see how much money
they have in their accounts here right
and what's the good what was the most
dangerous think of this C&C server was
that you are deciding like okay take
money from this victim sent to my crook
The Dropper
let him to keep 20% and transfer the
money back to my account here we can see
how you can define the drops right so
they have a full management of Crocs how
much money they receive which
drop the reason of of the drop etcetera
etcetera it was a fool I mean it's like
a hippie anna-marie you know when I'm
transferring the money to pay my bills
his same right and it's faster than ABN
AMRO here they can see all the error
locks right they care about their system
they want to know why the transfer is
not done right I'm really sorry that you
guys cannot see this but that's it here
you can define all the transfer pages
and most important here you can add a
new drop and you crook
share putting his name his eben number
he is all his information and you're
defining the split with him how much
you're going to give to him and then you
are ready to go right everything is full
automatic and here is the transfers so
basically you can see from which you can
say for this crook take the amount money
from this victims and then the reason
for the money transfer was like a
payment of rent it was just random words
that I found inside like okay buying
something payment of rent payment of
holiday and stuff like that
but the actual user you know is not
seeing that because of the man in the
middle of Rob's traffic because of the
previous C&C server so that was all for
today for tonight there is more botnet
research articles that I done which more
details and better picture so I
encourage you guys to go and read them
they're really nice and very informative
so last thing for tonight was the
Vodafone hack right so what happened a
little bit very fast
I purchased a Vodafone fiber optic
internet at my home so the device itself
is nothing right he's keeping the net
for me it's rooting for me right
meanwhile by the way I work for Cisco so
meanwhile I got hired by Cisco and they
give me a free gear right at home
and what happened that gear that I had
at home it has a sandboxing capability
and was malware protection all the
gustavus is bad and I wanted to take the
net to my Cisco device
to put this router here on the bridge
mode so I can have a control over my
traffic what happened I went to the
routers configuration page and on under
the nothing page there was nothing about
the bridge I went to do Google a lot of
Google Translate because I don't speak a
Dutch so I end up in a Dutch forum and I
was Google Translate all the time and I
saw that the bridge mode functionality
is active through IP right but bother
for Netherlands disability so they don't
want you to use a net right I don't know
why they claim some security issues but
I don't think so and then of course for
me was start the fast it's time to start
digging in right let's see what is
happening so what happened I log into my
writing I went to the DMZ host right
here as you can see I don't have a place
to define MAC address which will going
to be my net so what I done
it was simple I just figure out the path
get post command by the way so as you
can see here this 7 c0 191 this is my
MAC address and the switch here not 1
what is happening okay it's my true IP
enabled if you just want make a 1 that
and just forward the intercepted post
and you have net which Vodafone
Netherlands don't want you to have it
right for the guys who don't know what
is a burp suite and stuff like that I
have a better option just go if you can
go just go to inspect elements we all
know this this is Safari or anything
else right just figure out as you can
see here this is the CGI script
responsible for the for the for the for
the updating let's say configuration of
the water itself then the strange thing
is here that
you can see the MAC address of the Tri
PD NZ here right but it's not on the GUI
why it's not on the GUI because it's
display:none just delete just delete the
display:none come on right then you will
have a MAC address input but is disabled
so another security check right so they
disabled that you cannot have the input
right but we have a solution for that so
if you search again you're going to see
here that is disabled disabled disabled
right just change the box to enabled and
then you can put your MAC address right
and just click OK and you just bypass
there non-logical wish to not having you
right so I mean yeah this was very easy
beside of the breaking the botanist I
agree but yeah it's my fundamental right
right to have my own connection and
stuff like that so so then of course I
reported to them a couple of males back
and forth I think that they patched but
if you have a older version of the
firmware this will this will still works
yeah this is a disclosure and they sent
me some flowers at home and they give me
some free packages so I have I have more
IPTV packages at home more Dutch
channels which I don't understand how
personally so that was all for tonight
I'm really sorry again for the very
white bright display so if you have any
questions guys feel free to ask me or to
reach me out with any males yes you have
the microphone here for the questions
please go to the microphones
yes yes knowledge so let me tell you
because this is basically what they've
done is they did on power they didn't
filter and they didn't make any kind of
validation of my comment because my
focus was only breach that I didn't have
a time to check but maybe you can change
the DNS maybe you can do more harm right
I didn't I didn't have a time so I'm
living for you guys to beginning right
but I am sure that you can do more but
for my aim was just to have a net just
to have a bridge and to record on that
yes only flowers thank you so if you're
leaving the room please malware
interfaces they all look really
professional these guys definitely know
what they're doing they spent lots of
time in developing that stuff so what do
you think you could still compromise
their service I mean you you expect that
they they spend some time in that as
well because they want to protect their
assets right so that's a good question
let me tell you I try to I try to figure
out how they work let me put this way I
try to research I try to make a research
against maybe mm CNC servers I manage to
figure out only 20 of them right so it's
heavily
heavily research right and sometimes
it's like sometimes they're so you know
what they were doing so they're stealing
the money they're putting on the drop
zone from the drop zone they're pushing
the money they're pushing the Hackett
political numbers with a cool to another
server right when I catch them two times
after that they stop to doing that so
they put a gmail account where they're
using like a drop so they're stopping so
basically every time every single
research that we are publishing is
improving their way of doing the stuff
right so I agree with you they are very
good but I mean come on it's not
possible to breach all of them right so
this is all I got but they are very very
professional
right this is a business model right
this is a model they where you can hire
and you can build your perfect attack
right thank you again if you're leaving
the room early please be quiet
it will show up on the recording and we
don't want that are there any other
questions left because we have time how
much time like 20 minutes 20 minutes
yeah okay you show me ten
okay then I hope that you enjoyed and
sorry again please take the PDF you have
all this information inside more and
reach me out I have more stuff to show
you okay
[Applause]
[Music]