[Music]
all right food and fiber how cool is
that
Dennis was born in nineteen and 1984
so that should be a recipe for disaster
maybe or maybe not
yes please take a seat we're just about
to start
it's about fiber and noodles and things
edible it's going to be awesome really
you should you should sit down and have
a look
maybe we can we can encourage him to
give him a big round of applause Dennis
the bell thank you thank you I'm really
happy to be here I will explain a bit
about how I got there later on but first
of all really nice to be giving this
given this stage to present my work
which I will now continue to do so I
also brought some goodies and since we
don't have a full house here maybe if
you are interested you can hook me up or
catch me after the talk and we can
exchange some some goods which I also
present so first off my name is Dennis
de Bell I'm an artist from Rotterdam the
Netherlands and yeah I mostly work with
technology because I'm yea interested in
how technology shapes our world but also
how to make it your own and to have to
sort of grasp what what's going on just
curiosity I guess and I will show you
some some works that it sort of led up
to but I'm going to present here today
now the fiberglass noodle networking
so in I have to speak a bit so in about
I don't know if you can see it that's
sort of the idea as well so in in 2010 I
did this project together with Jodie
it's a duo of net artists and we had an
exhibition we were checking out the
location to Google Streetview
and yeah we saw all these like these
Google watermarks everywhere in public
space so we thought yeah I mean it's
it's an easy job but it's kind of nice
to sort of reenact this copy writing
over public space for real using and
like a commercial airplane that flew
with this banner that was 25 meters long
and five meters high over the city and
it's also funny that this was in 2010
and we could only find pictures that
were like one year old so from 2009 so
everything you see in Google Streetview
is also already outdated of course so
it's sort of a fake snapshot of reality
and it's copyrighted by Google two years
before I already started sort of
experimenting with with food and
electronics and it was more like sort of
an exercise in in form follows function
so I had this crackers and I used to do
some little bit of soldering just to get
to know electronics yeah I put one and
two together and normally you use like
this breadboard for to quickly prototype
your electronic circuits and then I saw
these crackers and I thought wow this
this is just this is just perfect
so now you have an an edible circuit
board you can eat after you're finished
prototyping so you you you you will
never be hungry while prototyping
in 2014 I participated in the arts hack
day hackathon and transmedia alla
festival this was this 24-hour hackathon
where to make something and yeah I had
this idea to sort of combine like our
everyday technology like this iPhone
with something super basic something
super archaic like the most archaic form
of communication so it I decided to make
it sort of add-on for your iPhone or
some any smartphone which you could use
to send smoke messages so smoke signals
and of course if you would want to
communicate with someone you had to
agree upon sort of a protocol so like
one puff is hello or two puffs is
goodbye
and you could also communicate over very
long distances if you like linked up
together and pass on the message if
everyone would use this and I I made
some other sort of iPhone hacks I took
apart an old iPhone and turn it into
like a spark-gap transmitter using a
short circuit on the on the battery but
yeah I I didn't really like it because
it's it was a sort of dangerously thin
line between sort of critique and
advertising almost so of course Apple is
already sort of a caricature of its own
nowadays I mean come on the wireless
earbuds or laptops with one port so I
mean like the joke is on them III cannot
make it more ridic
then they already do so I wanted I
wanted something else this was the start
of collaboration project with rules come
a being I had made some sort of DIY
smartphones using Raspberry Pi etc then
I met who and yet sort of similar ideas
about technology and networks and
communication we were in the same sort
of whatsapp group where we used to share
like weird pictures from stuff we would
see on the streets but yeah we were
totally dependent on the quirks of
whatsapp and and then Facebook we had to
update our operating system to use the
latest version bla bla bla
we're really tired of this and yeah we
sort of saw also that that's in this
whole sort of app environment that that
the World Wide Web was actually already
dead so we started we wrote a proposal
to the creative fund creative industries
font of Netherlands together with worm
haltered um yeah we wrote a proposal to
create a sort of offline mesh network
communication device which we got a
grant for for one year research and
building prototypes and this is one of
them so the project is called messenger
so as in mesh messenger after one year
of coding we sort of had it working we
had these little portable travel routers
with open wrt on it and they could mesh
together and if two of these devices
would meet in the or would come like
close to each other they would exchange
files
synchronize that content and yeah after
one year we had like a sort of crappy
Python code and was sort of working but
yeah but then I mean then you end up
with sort of look at the nice interface
we have to our app and it works so we we
needed to sort of we wanted to sort of
visualize how this how the system could
be used so we decided to sketch some
scenarios and make like physical
prototypes working prototypes with a
scenario and this is the first one this
is the felling file-sharing Network so
it uses a felling carrier to carry data
to the neighborhood and the idea is that
you send out your cat at night let it
roam the neighborhood and meet up with
other cats and exchange files so the
next morning when your cat gets home
you have to lay this game of Thrones or
whatever you're on your cat so there's a
little little router on this back and
two battery packs the cat they don't
like it so I guess yeah I won't be doing
anything with animals anymore this is
over this is another another prototype
so we built this little open wrt router
in the in the sole of the shoe with the
idea that yeah like the carry of the
device so the human or animal will
become the network infrastructure itself
I guess nowadays you can do it do this
with a ESP that's the size of a postage
stamp but back then we didn't have such
nice goodies there will also be a quiz
by the way after the after the talk so
if you can guess the name of this
prototype you can win some PCBs I used
to make this
so actually this this messenger project
it it it was a sort of parallel network
it made use of it had a hotspot only the
on the open wrt device which you could
visit using any smartphone or laptop any
device with a browser so we also had to
sort of design this interface but yeah
we we sort of never got around this this
whole paradigm of the app because it has
to fit a sort of certain screen etc and
yeah it has to be user friendly somehow
but on the other hand it was so unusual
friendly that none of our friends
actually used the system we made so it
was a nice exercise what excuse me
so that said it was it was more sort of
an exercise in user interface design
using like very high high uh players to
to to send data and to do some nice
stuff but yeah we really wanted to to
sort of grasp the technology where we
were working with so that's when we
decided to get our radio amateur license
and follow this course at the level
which I can highly recommend if you want
to learn electronics or basic radio
stuff take this course you will know
everything within a year it's super
amazing so we got sort of more a bit
more down the stack so from sort of
software layers to more Hardware layers
excuse me
and we started like researching like
obsolete networking technologies such as
packet radio but also like normal FM
radio and how to interface it with like
modern devices to create networks
transmit data etc and this is this is
one of the projects we did we made a
little board and a cheap combined with
the cheap Baofeng radio you could
actually still like recreate 1970s aloha
net computer networks using like only
this cheap radio and a small board that
that triggers radio to transmit or
receive and this is all possible because
back in the day you had like computer or
terminal and you had modem and you had a
terminal node controller that which
switch on and off the radio but nowadays
we just have a computer and we use a
sound modem so this is sort of a piece
of software that acts like a modem that
translates binary data into sound waves
so frequency shift keying which you can
then transmit yeah using any radio and
the software would also take care of the
of the switching of the radio because
funny thing is when making radio
networks they actually don't know where
they are in the network so they are sort
of resilient but there's also quite some
overhead especially when you use like
modern HTTP protocols because they're
constantly this these acknowledgment
these exchanges to check if packet
arrived or not so it's it's a bit slow
and clumsy but it's it's just amazing
that's the protocol we used a x.25 it's
still like standard in the Linux kernel
um so we made a little how-to book I
guess you can download it on my website
not sure actually
then we did some more made some more
jokes
so they started as sort of a reaction on
all the all the free hot spots
yep and wrote to them so every cafe
wants to sell more lattes so they give
you a return they give you a free Wi-Fi
so you can work there and spend some
money there on coffee and we thought
like oh wow it would be nice to like
what with the Wi-Fi logo be if you
instead of wireless you had to use a
cable so we just we made this gif as a
joke so we used the the Wi-Fi sort of
logo and a set of wife I said Ethernet
but then a bar in Rotterdam worm they
were actually really interested in the
in the device so they said yeah here's
some money build it for us so we build
this it's the world's first Ethernet
support and you can you can connect to
it if your Rotterdam it's in worm what's
what's really nice about this is that it
sort of started as a joke but then we
build it and then you start to see what
you have actually done because actually
immediately immediately the press I was
sort of alarmed because it was in the
sort of the news that the Wi-Fi in the
train was unsafe like public high all
spots were dangerous to use so the press
folks count and and the local newspaper
day they came to interview us and said
ah so this is sort of a privacy privacy
act so you cannot be hacked if you
use this so yeah we were like now you
you can't be hacked but I mean at least
you know that the the one who's hacking
is like next to you because the cables
are quite short and another thing is of
course that's most modern devices they
don't even have have an Ethernet port
anymore so it shows you how this
obsolescence or planned of selection
obsolescence manifests itself really
really quickly so this was three years
ago yeah it never gets used of course in
the meantime our collaborative research
project yeah was taking like two years
longer than then actually planned and we
collected like all our prototypes in
this sort of booklet I brought two if
you want one hit me up
so it's a sort of collection of our
prototypes and it contains also sort of
manuals and how to's and schematics to
recreate some of the things yourself and
there's also a nice cd-rom with bonus
material so if you can still read it for
this project we also went to China as
every person who's working with
technology you should do it was super
crazy it's it's a whole nother talk if I
I'm not getting too much into this but
let's say maybe the picture on the right
says enough so we visited some some
factories mainly of like some GI
products so yeah we're we're especially
looking for weird weird stuff weird
combination
of electronics phones with radios in
them etc and we also found these
stickers so if you have trouble with
getting a certification you can just
yeah
get a vital stickers and put it on it so
they had like FCC stickers they're a bit
shiny Cee Lo's looks really dodgy but on
the other hand of course everything gets
made there as well so they actually need
to make these stickers because all the
manufacturers are actually there so what
did we eat while in China can anyone
guess noodles that's correct so we found
these cellophane noodles or mung mung
bean starch noodles or in all of they're
actually called glass noodles I I have
some like wholesale package here you can
buy in any Chinese supermarket yeah what
fascinated me about it that it's like
super flexible and it's actually super
transparent so if you shine a light on
it
I don't yeah I'm not sure if you can see
it demo demo fails so again the fiber
glass connection or the glass noodle
glass fiber noodle joke was sort of yeah
I quickly made of course yeah a joke
without a nice conclusion is not a very
good joke so yeah I bought a packet of
these guys and fired up the old Arduino
made it sort of
light table set up and yeah try to with
a LED on one side and an LDR on the
other side try to transmit some light
truely's through this fiber this noodle
and actually it actually worked like the
first time and I was quite amazed but it
were very unreliable so so I guess it
had has to do with the calibration of
the lights the ambient light but yeah I
never really got it got it working but I
got some Morse Morse code sent through
it but but yeah nothing I could show
here actually so what I need it was a
bigger noodle at least that's what I
thought
so I try to I say experiment but it's
it's more of sort of a tunnel vision in
trying to get this thing to work
experimented with like making my own
making my own noodles Wow okay you see
this should have photographed them on a
black background I guess so I first
started with lag with the main
ingredient of these noodles mung bean
starch and yeah when you cook this it
becomes this sort of custard like like
like liquid so there's non-newtonian
fluid that's fluid but when you like hit
it or compress it it becomes solid but
so yeah I couldn't really work with it
so I mixed in some like wheat wheat
starch and it became like this yellow
like a buck stick I try
some potato starch mixed with some dry
stuff
potato starch becomes this sort of glue
you use for a wallpaper and it would
really work out then I I made this this
jelly this wallpaper glue and put it in
the fridge and then dried it in the oven
and it got close but not yet longer
longer cooking didn't work out then I
who had the genius idea to make a sort
of metal mold and just compress all
these noodles together to form sort of a
super thick super noodle I actually
brought one but I can't find it in here
did it work not really so I used gelatin
as well which was really disgusting
please avoid using this I tried agar
agar which Lutz looked really really
promising it's actually the same stuff I
showed here so this is agar agar it's a
bit it's used for it's like a feeding
ground for bacteria to test bacteria and
also in food so I cook this and sucked
it up in a little silicone tube and then
pressed it out into ice-cold water and
now you have this which looks really
good
[Music]
but did it work
so I spent I think year year and a half
trying these recipes trying out to how
to do this and I I just couldn't manage
to send any light through it they also
got yeah I switched out the LED for a
laser I switched out the LDR the light
dependent resistor for a light
transistor which works yeah a bit like a
solar panel but then like one one cell
but it just didn't work and the problem
was that my talk this dog was already
accepted accepted here but I didn't
really have anything to show you guys so
in in sort of one last resort I applied
for this artist-in-residence at class
institute for molecular biology I
thought yeah I mean these guys must know
how this stuff works right but loss
declines so I found this video this is
actually how it's made so yes this
starch liquid which is like this
non-newtonian fluid that's fluid but if
you hit it you become solid so he has
some sort of funnel and he just make
sure it it stays together when it drips
out and he puts it in boiling water and
chops it off balls it for one minute and
then puts it in cold water yeah I don't
have these skills yet then my house will
become such a mess if I try this it
already is a mess so when I try it with
regular noodles you can buy in the shop
and if you cook them it actually really
works but it for me it was sort of I had
so to take like a water cooker with me
cook some noodles here and hope that it
works because they they also easily
break when they're wet and I didn't want
to bring wet noodles in my back so I was
looking for something that could could
bring like reproducible results so I
found this
I looked into sugar because it's also
edible and translucent I did some tests
with which is cooking sugar and making
sort of like hard candy in which you
have to cook sugar until it's triana
degrees and then quickly stop it but
yeah it just became like brown shit it
was an epic fail but then I found out
these these YouTube videos of super nice
ladies who decorate cakes and they use
these special sugar called isomalt which
is actually an alcohol and it's a sort
of relatively new sugar replacement
which is sort of interpreted as you buy
your body as a as a fiber so your teeth
they won't rot and you don't get fat and
it tastes delicious and it's sort of
nice to work with it becomes like super
transparent so what you do is you buy a
batch of this stuff you put it in a
microwave for like a minute until it
starts to boil then it's like tree
another 300 degrees then you have to
sort of cool it and pull it into noodles
for which you need actually this sort of
rig which is a heat lamp that will keep
the sugar warm enough so it stays
malleable
otherwise it just becomes super hard I
can show you the process so you pour it
and then you fold it until it's cooled
off a bit and then you can yeah you can
pull you can make all nice all kinds of
nice animals for your cakes but you can
also make edible network cables from it
so on the right there like pulling
putting the sugar in sort of the same
way as you could make like like wheat
noodles pasta this was the first test so
this is using a Chinese laser pointer
and it looked so promising and I hope it
is so I can do a live demo for you guys
so the the setup I've now it's actually
yeah one one direction set up I could
make this bi-directional as it is now
but yeah it's a proof of concept and
it's still work in progress so what it
does I use my computer with a sound
modem so a program called mini modem
that will turn like binary data into
audio frequency shift keying so two
tones that represents a 1 and a 0 you
can just pipe any file into the into the
program and it will send out sound then
I I just connect the audio to a laser
just pump the audio into the laser so it
gets
modulated which will send out this
amplitude model modulated laser light
which is received by the photo
transistor on the other side that is
connected to like lm386 audio amplifier
that will amplify the signal generated
by the by the light hitting the
transistor turns it into sounds that I
can put into a sound modem again and
reverse the process so turn it into data
so I have some gifts for in case the
demo doesn't work but I guess we can
just go straight to the demo but here
you can see sort of the process so we
[Music]
have my 90° noodle over here checking
mount in this table I'll just let you
let you hear the audio for a second
maybe it's a bit loud so I will pipe the
manual for mini modem into itself and
transmit it at 10 volts so 10 symbols
second and it sounds like this
so this is the co-founder than
22-hundred killer hurts
so what already works so I just put the
laser in my audio output and a
transistor in my audio input power the
amplifier in the laser there's a lot of
light here I'm not sure it's gonna work
can you see it glow something is working
at this so who wrote this nice sort of
benchmark benchmarking tool so you can
check out how fast you're transmitting
so you can test out different noodles or
lasers so I will just yeah transmit the
manual file into mini modem and run the
benchmark so on the bottom here you can
see the incoming symbols so it will take
10,000 seconds still to transmit the
whole manual it's a bit slower maybe we
can try to do it a bit faster
so 100 on about
no it's too fast ah shame shame shame
okay maybe can do 20
oh yes so the question marks are it's
just gibberish data so yeah this works
I'll just let it run see if it can
finish
I do we have a question
one moment please can you talk into the
mic
polishing the end of CA noodles to be
flat at 90 degrees
nope it's I was so happy it worked that
it is just just as is it's actually not
so not so transparent the end and also
you can this isomalt keeps for for years
and years but it's it's really sub-sect
susceptible to like moisture in the air
yeah I can already see it on these these
older samples they're starting to become
like whitish so you also have always
have to carry this silly Chia bags to
preserve your urine noodles so what did
I sort of learn from this making like
real noodles like this is mega hard but
I'm not giving up I'm going to try it
again modulating a laser on the other
hand is super easy it's it's actually
fun to do actually this this whole setup
works way better without the noodle just
using the air to transmit to the laser
then wait a noodle so yeah I would
suggest you looking into like optical
connections to play with that it's it's
really fun
the only problem is that like laser is
just as radio is a line of sight
communication too so if you want to go
around corners and meet your neighbors
or hook up with your neighbors then yeah
you need something like this because the
noodle it can actually bend the lights
around corners I don't know what what
the maximum angle of normal fiber is but
I I think you can make loopings with
this with this stuff yeah and besides
that it's obviously a nice conversation
piece to talk about technology and food
so as I said before yeah I just I just
had to get this working it started off
as a joke and I know every every joke
has a sort of truth in it so yeah it
must work and it sort of does it's also
also always fun to try something no one
thinks is possible and as you see it's
it's possible I learned a great deal is
sort of yeah bare bones networking and
small electronics and it's a it's the
best of all it's sort of a great tactic
to to speak at festivals like this and
meet super nice people
in the mean time or in the process
obviously yeah in sort of this DIY
offline privacy networking an arms race
pulling fibre is the next big thing so
what is the next big thing I actually
got accepted for artist-in-residence in
China and Beijing for next year so I
will definitely try to learn how to make
proper noodles
I want to make it like full-duplex
like do some some proper make some make
it fit into the networking stack to the
OSI model and of course just make DIY
regular fibre using glass like this guy
on the right only thing is that these
noodles when when making them it's like
300 degrees and glasses a bit hotter so
I need some help with that I guess I see
some questions just one with me could
you wait till the Microsoft or it's
closer to the mic maybe you can turn in
Oh doing 3d printing no please oh that's
super good I was actually thinking of
this because it's it's about the same
temperatures like PLA or nice so yeah
the schematics and benchmark tool and
Gerber files you can find on my website
or this is the direct URL ah then it's
time for the quiz so if you if you know
the name of this messenger prototype
please walk to the mic and I have a
guess you can win a set of transmitter
and receiver PCBs to recreate this
yourself
is it sneakernet
yeah nice let me see
so you want to make sure you have some
more questions yeah okay yeah I think
it's good time for questions there it is
so it's a schematics and bill of
materials any more questions please nope
Wow I have some more boards so you can
also kindly ask if you want one how long
will you be here Dennis and where can we
find you ah yeah a really good question
I will be here all day but not tomorrow
you can catch me around the coffee
attend I guess yes question you have a
question did you look into the different
braking materials no but I shoot similar
technique to make like hard candy that
has dots in it glares yeah yeah actually
this stretching is sort of I'm not sure
if it's positive or negative for the for
the I guess it only sort of diffuses the
light more but it also it seems as if
it's because if you're Bennet and
stretch it you will introduce like
little air bubbles in it and we yeah you
stretch these air bubbles to create sort
of canals through which light can travel
I guess
did you try much sinner noodles to get a
total reflection what kind of noodles
did you try much much sinner noodles
instead of sicker ones to get a nice
total reflection between noodle and air
yeah yeah I tried this one but it's it's
super hard to to line up with with the
laser actually I can pass some around or
maybe you can pass some around for me
yeah so for me it was just using brute
force try to pump as much light through
something a medium as possible but yeah
the next step is definitely just trying
to make my own like glass fiber maybe I
should have started with this and then
move along from there but I mostly most
of the time I work the other way around
and just come up with a crazy idea and
try to make it
I was just wondering do you have any
plans to attempt to develop a
transatlantic fiber optic noodle that
was the question of the day I was sort
of hoping hoping this question would
arise so yeah I already made like a
mock-up so this is sort of how it would
look this is the the dissection of the
multimode undersea fiber cable so it's
also shielded there are multiple strands
in there it would be nice
definitely I think this is the future
okay a few considered using licorice a
shilling for this cable no I guess a bit
of shielding would really help indeed
but then yeah I could just fake it and
use use a normal electrical wire so yeah
I wanted to to show the sort of naked
noodle to you guys but good tip thank
you I write it down I actually also
looked into these media converters that
convert like Ethernet to fiber there are
some some projects by a Hungarian guy I
think who converted these devices for
optical connections but I couldn't get
it to work it's I think it's really
specific like the wavelength and so if
someone can help me with this and please
show me they will show me the light
okay ah so you know actual professional
fiber technicians have really
sophisticated test equipment that will
tell you all the characteristics of your
fiber I have you tried hooking this up
to like a real OTDR or a real
spectrograph does anyone that camp have
one maybe go knock doesn't anyone have
one I should they're only like you know
fifty thousand euros so like no big deal
I should visit the network guys I guess
and I already saw these super nice kits
these boxes that like to fuse the fibers
in the field
Alibaba I should really get one of those
as well well thank you for your splendid
creativity and I really loved your talk
[Applause]
[Music]