[Music]
to present you bill binney on this stage
and he will be telling us the
perspective from the inside of the NSA
because he was a technical director of
the NSA for many years and worked in the
intelligence services for more than 37
years he is a child of the Cold War and
worked throughout the Cold War
decrypting and breaking ciphers from the
adversaries of the US and back then he
used to call himself that a director of
the world in a sense so please give it
away for how the NSA tracks you with
bill Binney thank you
Thank You Ike I'd like to say it's nice
to be back in large with large numbers
of people with character and integrity
which when I worked at NSA not too many
people had and I could get into some of
that story mostly I worked I didn't work
on the programs that Phil Zimmermann was
talking about the commercially available
stuff I was all looking at military and
governmental encryptions and codes and
and activity so but the same techniques
apply to any Crip system I mean it's not
something that and I was on the
offensive side not the defensive side
and I know I knew snow and the defensive
people and I went to talk to them once
about saying here I had all these
solutions on the offensive siding and
can you tell me how you're designing the
defensive side because I thought that
they should be parallel you know we what
what we were doing they were doing and
they wouldn't tell me so that shows you
the same kind of there's that kind of
communications now like for example for
cyber security or all the attacks that
have come out of vault 7 and the NSA
exposures hundreds of millions of lines
of source code on attacks on you know
firewalls switches servers operating
systems all of that that's thousands of
attacks and we've only seen a few of
them so far used to in the world and you
can just be ready for a much rougher
ride because the offensive side knew all
these things were weak and existing the
defensive died didn't and they never
fixed anything so we were all vulnerable
so we all got attacked and so now they
say every time you get attacked we need
more money more people more empire you
know so it's a swindle we're all being
swindled by our governments if they if
they would only fix the things they knew
that were wrong we might have some
security you know so but instead they
don't so at any rate I didn't when I
left NSA I did that in at the end of
October 2001 because they started spying
on individuals and not groups of bad
guys okay so that meant they were
scooping up everything from everybody in
the world
and and it's much more extensive than
anybody thought it's more extensive than
even the slideshow but because and in
order to store all this material they
had to build the Bluffdale 1 1 million
square-foot facility for storing data
and last year they broke ground for a
now a 2.8 million square foot facility
on Fort made it took out a 36 hole golf
course to do it so I mean the point is
if you collect everything as a
ever-increasing amount of data year
after year which means you need
ever-increasing data storage facilities
the store at all
so all you have to do is watch and the
way we the way we found out about this
was to look at the every time the
government wants to build something they
have to file an environmental study so
when they when they wanted to put in
this very large building they had to
also submit an environmental impact
statement and study to do it before they
did so we're looking at those and seeing
what they're building so when they do
that we know well this is on Fort Meade
and it's the it's NSA doing it so you
know everything on virtually everything
on Fort Meade is NSA anyway so that that
game is the knowledge of the scale of
what they're collecting and what they're
assembling for example in Cisco who sold
them to routers to route data to the
Utah facility estimated there was a
small article they wrote years ago that
estimated that by 2015 the amount of
data going into the Utah facility would
be 966 exabytes a year that's about as a
2-byte so that's why originally years
ago I estimated that the capacity of
Utah was about five Zeta bytes I mean
it's my guess you know it's a lot of
bytes anyway so any rate I felt I didn't
have to take anything with me because
everybody in Congress when I left I you
know they all knew me they knew what I
was doing most of what they're doing to
spy on everybody I designed anyway or
had a hand in it so they knew all that
so I felt I didn't have to to to bring
any material out to to validate anything
I was saying because
they all knew I did it so I I naively
thought that I could do that and go
complain through the channels the
intelligence committees and the
Inspector General's and they would all
take some action on it well what it
really meant was when it came time to
actually hearing what I had to say
Congress never invited me and I mean I
testified in the Bundestag I testified
in the House of Lords in the UK but the
Congress would never hear me because
then they lose plausible deniability
that was really their key they needed to
have plausible deniability so they can
continue this massive spying program
because it gave them power over
everybody everybody in the world even
though members of Congress had power
against others they had power on the
judges in the Supreme Court the the
federal judges all of them that's why
they're so afraid everybody's afraid
because all this data they had that's
that about them the central agencies the
intelligence agencies they have it and
that's why senator schumer warmed
President Trump
earlier a few few months ago that he
shouldn't attack the intelligence
community because they've got you know
six ways to Sunday to come at you that's
because it's like J Edgar Hoover on
super steroids they have they have the
same kind of data that raid edgar Hoover
had on everybody
so it's leverage against every member of
parliament and every government of the
world that's that's what I felt was
problem so I I thought I when when
Edward Snowden came out he came out with
material and slides and and and
publications by the government about the
programs they were running that gave me
and that was the stuff I left them so it
gave me all the opportunity to pull it
together and say this is what they're
doing this is how they're doing this
what it means and that's what I've been
trying to do so I assembled some slides
here to give you some idea hopefully a
better idea of what's going on and I
also assembled some slides to show you
what they should be doing I have one
only one case of an unclassified version
of big data analysis which is what they
should be doing and they aren't that's
why people are getting killed that's why
I said in the UK that bulk data kills
people because all the analysts in the
UK and the mi5 and in
GCHQ similarly in the FBI and NSA they
are buried and data and they can't see
what's happening because there's just
too much data and they're using the old
techniques of word searches and stuff
like that that's not the way to do it at
all it's social networking is the key to
solving all of these problems solving
them quickly and making all the data
content problem a manageable thing now
I'll take you into that so here these
are the these are the ways that they
basically collect data first it's they
use the corporations that run the
fiber-optic lines and they get them to
allow them to put taps on them and I'll
show you some of the taps where they are
and and if that doesn't work they use
the foreign government to go at their
own telecommunications companies to do
the similar thing and if that doesn't
work they'll tap the line anywhere they
can get to it and they won't even know
it know the government's know that
communications companies will even know
they're tapped so that's how they get
the into it then they get into fiber
lines and this is this is the prism
program is really where they have the
the the companies involved that's down
there and the lists of them this came
out was one of the first first things
that was published out of the Snowden
material and they were all focused on
prism well prism is really the the minor
program I mean the major program is
upstream that's where they have the
fiber-optic taps on hundreds of places
around the in the world that's where
they're collecting off the fiber line
all the data and storing it but
President was simply there their way of
putting out something where Congress and
the courts could look at it and say well
we're abiding by the law say year we
asked these companies for this data and
we have a warrant for that to do it so
you see we're binding by law when an
upstream they were and they were taking
everything off the line also they're the
muscular program was a parallel one
which basically did the for you know
yahoo and google and a couple others
they unilateral they unilaterally tapped
the lines between their data centers
when they transferred data to back it up
and so on they got everything they had
and they didn't know it okay so that was
their mainly the muscular program from
those companies plus the upstream is
really the main one and prism was only
one small input to the data that NSA was
collecting worldwide these are the kinds
of things they have that I mean it's
satellites all kinds of collection the
real big one it's over there see any
computer network exploitation that's
where they're implanting either with
hardware or software both into switches
and servers around the world and they
can make them do anything they want
because they own them so if you sent
data anywhere through those switches or
servers and there's tens of thousands of
them in the world they basically own the
network they they have access to it they
get it so all of that is feeding another
program that they call treasure map and
this one just says well we want to know
where everything is in the world every
minute of the day so it's not just
collecting what you're saying encrypt it
or not but it's also monitoring where
you are when you do it and that's
basically done by this is a kind of the
geography of the world and there's the
physical layout of the fibers and the
microwaves and the satellite towers and
everything and then that maps to a
physical Network and then logical
networks who's communicating across them
that maps to be equipment which in turn
maps to people and that's how they
follow everybody this is also when you
have cell phones for example how they
take GPS and use the drones market to
target people so I think Jacob Appelbaum
was the one who said CIA or NSA watches
them or tracks them NSA tracks them and
CIA whacks them right at me and the way
they do that and there's 1.2 million
people on the drone list according the
last number I saw I mean that's crazy
I mean you know if they weren't even
they are
making they aren't verifying who they're
hitting they're not dummy they just go
out and kill people all the time this is
insane and I keep telling I call that
program random slaughter because that's
about what it is this is why I get in
their face every time I possibly can in
the u.s. because they're doing stupid
stuff it's hurting a lot of people at
any rate that's that's the treasure map
all the material they collect from all
the sources goes back into these
programs back inside NSA over here on
that rectangle over there where that's
basically a square fundamentally this
was the entire design these programs
mainway and marina are basically that
graphs of social networks that map into
the databases then pin will the internet
and nucleon the voice there are
basically two systems they're following
public switched telephone network which
is all the phones fixed mobile satellite
ok any kind of song and the input of
that into the that all all that content
data then goes into nucleon and it's
indexed up there by the Mirena program
so that when they want to see who did
what they have an index all to
everything they ever said in their
database so this was the whole design I
left them and they haven't changed the
damn thing in 15 years 16 years so
that's real progress for you but any
rate one of the things to look over here
and aside is that both CIA and the FBI
through the FBI Center in Quantico
Virginia have a direct access into these
databases and and the entire graph not
only to that but they also use that for
police around the world so it's a
straight violation of everything all
this data is collected without warrants
so you know it's a basic violation of
the rights of every human and a court of
law and that's what they're using
they're using it to arrest people and
then they post substitution I've got
some slides on that too and these are
other people who have access to it the
the five eyes group over here they had
direct access into the into the NSA
database right here and so do the Drug
Enforcement Administration
Defense Intelligence Agency I CIA all
these people have direct access to all
this data and its children's data as
well as everybody on the line because
they take it all so it's nothing there's
no distinction they don't filter
anything it's just capture everything
this is what a general like sender said
and then with hill-station a few years
ago he said what we have to do is
collect it all and that's what they're
doing the problem is once you collect it
all and and they have the impression or
they give the impression that data is
intelligence right when you collect more
data add more intelligence it's not the
point is you have intelligence when you
understand the meaning of what you've
collected if you can't do that I mean
you have nothing but a bunch of data and
that important unfortunately that's
that's the perspective they have so they
think collecting more is better instead
what happens is it buries their analysts
and buries the both the police and they
and the intelligence people they can't
figure anything out so you know what the
consequences a planned attacks happen
because they don't see them coming and
they can't prevent them and so that's
why I said when I went to the UK to try
to stir them up you know I wanted to get
them upset
I said bulk date because they were
getting ready to pass the investigative
powers bill the bulk acquisition of data
on everybody in the UK as well as
everything everybody they can possibly
get in the world I said bulk data kills
people and the reason I said that is
because of the inability to stop
terrorist attacks for example I mean we
continue to see these things say I mean
nothing has changed they're still going
after more more data more you know more
people more of an empire and they still
can't figure out what they've got but
they're really good after the fact after
the fact once they know who did it
they've got all the data on them they
could go directly at them the other
thing it does give them though is the
power to to manipulate anybody they want
or do industrial espionage or or if
somebody if somebody is getting a
political group together or getting
politically active and they don't want
them they have the ability to target
them are you using this data I mean it's
just it's just they're all they have to
do is go at it so they can target people
and use it against them but they can't
look at all of it the
figure out who out there is planning an
attack on us or is gonna smuggle weapons
or smuggle dope or and if that they
can't do that because they've got too
much data and they're using stupid
searches like word searches well you
know if they use the word bomb you know
if they're looking somebody planning a
bomb or building a bomb we could say if
you say in an email to anybody well you
know the quarterback threw a bomb at the
last to win the game you know what your
your email is gonna be picked up by that
word search and it's absolutely
irrelevant to anything they're looking
for that's the point that's why social
networking of focusing in on those
networks that are involved in terrorism
we're the ones you know with the seats
you have you can focus in on them and
all I would point out that all of the
terrorist attacks that have ever
happened before or after 9/11 have been
by people who were known by either the
intelligence and the police or both so
why weren't they focusing on them if
they were they may have a chance to
prevent the attack instead they're
looking at this bulk stuff I mean it
does it does spend a lot of money it
employs a lot of people so it's a good
what I call a happiness management
program but the point is that to keep it
going sometimes people have to die and
that's that's if that's just on its
unamerican first of all you know no
American would do that no one would
sacrifice the lives of anybody for this
crap but they do and they do it because
there's a big empire behind this I mean
to collect all this data the
intelligence community mostly NSA has
spent somewhere close to 200 billion
dollars since 9/11 just to get the data
I mean they're and they built an empire
worldwide to do it and they've got all
these all these countries come that are
participating in that so and and the big
the closest are of course the easier I
should point out that you see this date
over here down at the bottom right
twenty thirty two zero one eight that's
the eighth day of January of twenty
thirty two that means it's the first
review classification review for this
slide twenty five years so if you
subtract twenty five years from that
it's the eighth the
January of 2007 or 2007 that was the
date the slide was created so this was a
state of things in 2007 right if you
look at all these slides you'll see many
times they'll have a date there and you
could figure out well this is the date
of that of that program you know so any
rate this is where they use the things
for the rule of four the sod that's a
Special Operations Division of the Drug
Enforcement Administration the police
they they have also the FBI CIA NSA the
DHS the IRS all have representatives on
the sod and they all look into the NSA
data the IRS is supposed to be there for
fraud you know and things like that but
they use the data against the Tea Party
and they and the FBI use against the
Occupy group and other political parties
were attacked similarly and of course
they of course people looking to unmask
information about individuals that's
done through these kinds of
organizations you know or they can
request that through directly to NSA so
all that's done by see the problem is as
a human failing here is that the people
given the power over others eventually
they use it you know that's historically
true it's a weakness in humanity you
know that's that's the real problem here
there's no way of checking there's no
checks and balances at all involved in
this at all they Congress says and the
courts say they have oversight that's a
joke okay they don't have any oversight
even and even after the Snowden material
came out at the head judge
Reggie Walton on the FISA Court the
Foreign Intelligence relation court said
he came out said tried to make an excuse
for his court and the judges on it that
they really didn't have a lot of
capability of verifying anything that
NSA CIA or FBI were telling him in fact
he doesn't have very little he has none
he's totally dependent on them telling
the truth and they only tell them what
they want to tell him and his same is
true with the intelligence a committees
in Congress and the same is true in
every country of the world no country in
the world no government of any country
in the world has any control of their
intelligence ages they do not know what
they're doing and they have no control
of really of any of them they can't
stop it they they would say they go to
oversight but then when they go in all
there told us is what the agency wants
them to hear so they get the DES story -
or the story of the day from from that
agency that's the problem I see but so
in order to do this you see they don't
tell any that attorneys the judges or
anything you never have signed anything
never put it in affidavits there's no
documentation that they used NSA data or
NSA collected data from all their
collaborators to do any of this and so
what that means is they have to do a
parallel construction they reconstruct
data or go out and get data that would
they could substitute in a court of law
for for the NSA data because then they
could use that as a justification for
the warrant which they didn't get in the
first place so but so that basically
means they're perjuring themselves in a
court of law now this is not just for us
in the United States anybody who has a
reverend who has any relationship with
the FBI the DEA worldwide they're all
getting insight through these programs
and so whatever actions they take are
based on the unconstitutional collection
of data by the NSA and the CIA but
they're still using they we in fact one
of the one of the federal agents using
this data set commented to a Reuters
reporter this is a Reuters slide he said
you know this is such a great program I
just hope we can keep it secret well
what does that mean that means we have a
secret government right when you marry
when you marry the intelligence agencies
with the police you have a secret police
now in Germany they called that the
Gestapo or the Stasi so I refer to NSA
as the new Stasi Agency
[Applause]
unfortunately that's you know we haven't
been able to do anything I I am
attempting to do everything I possibly
can against these people I have four
times forty supporting four separate
lawsuits against the president at Trump
a previously against President Obama and
the intelligence agencies of the United
States for unconstitutional collection
of data we have to do it for our laws
with our constitution cover its
violation of privacy rights of US
citizens so we're attacking them that
way in a court of law
and I just got my first chance with the
Third Circuit Court of Appeals to
sub-sub submit some of this and NSA data
about their own programs into the court
of law now it's going to be tough for
NSA to deny it because now it's in the
federal courts these this is the court
that's one one level down from the
Supreme Court in the United States and
it's at four separate circuit courts the
one in the second one and the third one
in the ninth one of the eleventh so I'm
coming at them as many from as many
directions as I possibly can and
hopefully one of them will get through
to the Supreme Court and when it does
we'll get to them and if we fix it
I mean and if we fix it why hopefully
that'll spread around the world to the
rest of the countries who've adopted
this from because we started it okay you
know we started it we Americans were the
first one in the bulk collection pit the
rest of you came along a little later
that's only because we were close in and
it was convenient no so we got it first
any rate the point is they're all doing
the wrong thing for two basic reasons
number one it buries their analyst with
a with too much data so it makes them
totally dysfunctional II can't figure
out anything and they're just losing it
and I by the way I provided from Edward
Snowden's material copies of memos
written by internal analysts in NSA and
mi5 and various other places saying that
they are buried and data they just can't
figure out anything they've got too much
data well I gave that to all the to the
House of Lords as documentation of what
I was saying was true and they'd simply
ignored it so but but the main problem I
had from the very beginning was it was a
total invasion of the privacy rights of
everybody on the planet starting with us
in the US but to me that was the I mean
it took me one week to get out of NSA
once I found that out I mean they were
using the programs we you know we're
that were developed in the Sigyn
automation Research Center which I was
founder up and the the people I had
building those things were the ones they
had they depend on to implement them
worldwide on a scale that is still
growing there was no limitation to the
scale I mean we did flat B plus Street
type flat file indexing schemes with
which meant of you if you needed more or
more space you simply add another server
spread out the graph you know and so it
didn't there was no we saw no limit to
anything we could do I mean we'd already
taken in trillions of transactions and
that wasn't a problem at all so once I
found out that they started taking in
everything that they can tell the
telecommunications companies were having
in terms of us communications
principally in the starting with the
public switched telephone network and
then starting very later there very
shortly after that the internet and the
and the basically of the World Wide Web
it took me I found that out in the
second week of October 2001 and it took
me the week and a half to get out of the
place so I got a Holloway Halle
Halloween Day 31st of October 2001 and
since then I've been I've been trying to
advocate internally in the NSA
intelligence committees and the
Inspector General's of the post
department justice and Department of
Defense to have them I mean this is
obviously this is totally
unconstitutional it's a violation of the
pen register law Electronic Privacy Act
like chronic Security Act any of the
laws in place to cover FCC regulations
governing any of the telecoms that's why
the telecommunications companies had to
get retroactive immunity in 2008 because
they had so many laws that they were
violating every day and you know they're
still doing that so so the point was
that they were all in it together and
each one of the committees and the Indic
and the courts had to protect one
another was a cover-up because they were
all involved in this and the White House
was the starter it was actually started
by Darth Cheney I call him Darth Cheney
because he went to the dark side what he
said anyway sorry rate in the meantime
we had been advocating for a targeted
approach where you went after groups of
people that were doing bad things that
you could easily define that by social
networks in the in the world either in
the public switch telephone or even in
the internet we had no difficulty doing
that at line speeds fiber optic rates we
were able to session eyes fiber optic
rates that at stem level transmissions
in 1998 so from there Ron we were able
to do deep packet inspection on all that
stuff and reconstruct everything on the
lines and so we we were we were able to
see networks and we built all these
social networks using the transmitting
the routing data the IPS and and the
addressing schemes of the Internet as
well as the phone network and we had no
difficulty doing a targeted approach
then of using that data to filter out
what was relevant to targets
were interested in or should be
interested in out of the out of the flow
of information around the world at
whatever rate they were doing it we
simply subdivided and conquered it by by
the divide and conquer approach so that
that was our way of doing it then our
targeting approach we even took the
Customs and Border Protection after we
left NSA
and one of the ways we did that I mean
this is the only unclassified version I
could take a big data okay it's the only
thing I have so we went down there and
we had a Bureau of Industrial Security
up there of the Commerce Department
published this alert because some
military in Iraq over ran the bomb
banking factory and they found some some
parts in there and it looked the parts
they saw that part numbers and I think
they traced the part numbers back to
companies in the US selling them to
Iranian companies in Dubai know the
reason they located in Dubai because
it's outside of Iran and south side of
the exclusion for a trade and so they
they operating out of Dubai they could
order these parts you know so the Bureau
of industrial security had to alert
everybody in the world that this was
going on so we took that and used Google
this was some more of the data they had
so but but we used it and went on to the
web and googled all the things and
started looking at at the data this was
also given continued now whoops where
where did it go wait I lost the slide in
the middle perhaps that's what the
screws were that why the screws were
removed okay but this was on our Ian's
computer today rate we found I can't see
it here so it's missing yeah it's
missing okay that's what they were doing
okay we know what they were doing any
rate what we did was we went out we
added all kinds of information to that
looking at we added fax numbers phone
numbers addresses more data on people
involved
and more company names involved and then
in the end of it just before after the
best report came out they once that was
out they took all the names of the
companies they had off the web and then
and then put put other I kept that date
out of the way because then they thought
that business and its customers were
predicting we're still we're still
looking for the old data they didn't
didn't have that confirmed so they
removed it and they changed the names
but in the process of changing it they
they used one of the new numbers phone
numbers with some of the old data so
that gave us the end and we then traced
all to the new data they went and as
they went we followed them but we didn't
lose the thing of course the custom that
border protection and the Pentagon and
various other people intelligent was it
but we used Google and followed them so
we provided all that data to them and
since we didn't trust the US government
to do the right thing we also gave it to
our counterparts in Canada because they
were using losing people from ie D
attacks too so we didn't trust our
government to do the right thing so we
passed it up there too they of course
did the right thing
we didn't of course but the whole idea
was you we we compiled all this list of
information that we got from them and
from those approaches and gave it to
gave it to Colonel woody at the Pentagon
his he was the group that was looking at
the AED you know prevention of ie D
attacks and so on so we passed all this
data down to try to cut the supply of a
parts going into him the reason they
used different multiple company names to
do the construction of the IEDs is
because each company would order a
different part and the idea was that if
the customs of border protection looked
at a given company which is the way they
do it they would only see one part of an
ie D and never deduce that they were
putting together an ie D so unless you
collapse them down by a common attribute
like they're all sharing the same phone
number they're all sharing in the same
address or something like that to put
these multiple companies into one place
where you see the whole activity then
you sum it all together by their names
and you see the IEDs so you can see what
they're doing when you do that and so we
proposed the custom
order protection that we do this for
them they had a small data set of about
a half a billion records over ten years
of imports and exports
that was like one import could be a
thousand cars on a ship you know so it
was like half a billion records that and
they said it was a real mess because the
data was dirty and all that we looked at
there was a goldmine there's all kinds
of information here phone numbers on
addresses so we could lay out the entire
all the entire world's phone numbering
schemes and how they changed as they
change since they put these things out
there so we proposed to them that we
scraped the entire world website and
pull together consolidated list of
however many million companies that were
in the world one at 200 million
something like that and be able to do a
collapse on this and study all those and
find those who were doing was showing
attributes of doing something illegal
which is what this multi addressing
scheme implies so that would define a
set of suspicion zones of suspicion for
companies and involved in the world
trade and we estimated that from our
study if that we scraped the entire
website the pars guide was the website
in Iran in Dubai listing all the Iranian
companies in Dubai there were 5,000 32
of them and when we did that we found
222 different company names that sub
grouped into 55 different groups that
were doing different nefarious things
for the uranium government like
smuggling dope weapons that kind of
thing by getting buying equipment for
IEDs and and looking around for things
like that would help them with triggers
and nuclear stuff and so we needed we
passed all that along too and of course
our government is just too dense to to
really do anything so once we did that
we said we'd estimated that the entire
world would produce perhaps 40,000
targets for you to do targeted selection
of searching of incoming crates and
imports and and don't do exports of
these companies so we thought we could
do that in the first run of our data and
it would take us six months to correct
all the data and make that happen
with Kirk Wiebe myself and two
programmers but that was too cheap
see that was they wanted the letter 1.2
billion dollar contract to IBM to do it
so they fired us brought in IBM so and
they still haven't done this by the way
so anyhow oh here's that this is the
Alton the ultimately thing thing that
came out was they they indicted
everybody it was involved in all this
they arrested a few of them in Florida
but some of them were back in Iran so
they couldn't get to them but they left
the indictment out there but it took him
two years to do the indictment from the
fact from the time that we found all the
data that's a really fast judicial sub
process right so but this was something
they could do worldwide on everything
every possible criminal activity in the
world by looking at that social networks
looking at targeting approach which
would give everybody privacy views that
as a filter right up front
nobody's data gets taken in unless they
are a part of a criminal activity or
falling into a zone of suspicion around
that activity so it would give everybody
in the world privacy and but that's not
what they wanted they didn't want
privacy they first removed our filter
upfront so they could take in everything
and they took away all the encryption we
used to give privacy to people once we
took the data in until we had a warrant
and they removed that and then they
removed the auditing routine in the back
that looked at everybody that came in
and what they did when they came there
and where they went what data they
looked at what they did with the data
and they removed that because they
didn't want anybody to know what they're
gonna do they didn't even want
internally anybody to know so it's not
just that they're keeping secrets from
us they're keeping secrets from Congress
and everybody else even people inside
their agency because the vast majority
don't know I think there's only about
3,000 people now inside NSA that really
are involved in one way or another or
know directly evidence about this this
program so that's the that's the sick
part of it you know this is like a
secret democracy that's not it not a
real democracy I mean the Goethe said it
pretty well he you know he said no one
is more hopelessly enslaved than those
who falsely believe they're free and
that's us
[Applause]
sorry radii for this little thing here I
try to get another way hope you can see
it I can't see if what's this thing
doing here well we have more details
about our startup soon we Kirk and I her
in in Europe because we can't get
anything done in the US so we're gonna
get done we're gonna advise anybody any
organization or government on ways you
can do privacy and security by design
and we're going to help get one of those
capabilities up and running here in the
in the Europe somewhere because
obviously the US and the UK are too
dense to realize it can be done actually
it's their their agenda is the one
that's driving them and that's one that
means money power and control and the
way you get that is to take in data on
everybody in the planet and that gives
you that power then you can swindle
money because you can let things happen
because of the way you're doing business
things happen and that's more
justification to get more money - it's
like a swindle I called the Terrorism
thing of trading privacy for security
live from the beginning and that's just
the way they swindled everybody because
when the way they took in all the data
that made they couldn't stop anything I
mean more people get killed they say
they need more money more people may
bureaucracy to stop it they'd yet that
and more people get killed by another
attack because they get too much data
and they keep dumping more and more on
people just they're perpetuating the
same problem they're not facing the
issue they don't realize what the
problem really is and and people are
dying as a result so we're over here to
try to do something about that and
hopefully we will get there see I have
another slide here right no thank you
[Applause]
yeah
Thanks okay I guess now we can take some
questions anybody have any questions you
want to ask yes if you have questions
please learn about the two microphones
at the front then at this Center there
and now gladly yes please just go ahead
Hey thank you so much
one question comes to mind being the
technical director that you were how did
you end up noticing this rather than
approving that or knowing of all that
from the very beginning well see as a
technical director I was looking at what
is the money what is the biggest problem
that the analysts in the in the NSA had
it to solving problems and predicting
the intentions the capabilities of
people are going to hurt people or
criminal activity and it turned out to
be the digital explosion of
communications cellphones the internet
and so on and so I had to design a way
of getting into it but but I it was
parrot it was pretty clear that in order
to do that we we would be violating
everybody's privacy unless we did
something to eliminate that so that's
why I built in that social targeting and
pulling out only that information
letting everything else go by and that
design was one of the things they didn't
want they wanted to take in everything
so they wanted to get rid of that filter
but you see in order for NSA to put that
into place and get it running they had
to use the same contractors that I did
to have my program built because they're
the only ones who knew how to put it
together and get it up and running
nobody else in NSA did and they had no
other programs that could handle the
massive amounts of data so they had to
use my programs when they did that some
of them came to me and said you know
what they're doing and he said they're
taking in all this data on US citizens
down the hall from us and and building
these graphs and everything and just
doing or analyzing and violating the
privacy of everybody in the United
States then of course after that spread
to everybody in the world but but that
that's how I found out about it and once
I did that that was first time to me I
had to get out of here I knew no one
would do that
in NSA without approval from above and
that came directly out of Darth Cheney's
office yeah question the filtering and
targeting of social networks needs a lot
of data and then you can extract
patterns and then you can throw away the
data because you don't need it anymore
you said well you can you see if you
there's a couple ways to do it you know
one if you have a seed that is you know
a bad guy you could look at his social
network and build from that and then you
could say one degree beyond that as far
as I'll go to pull data in it really
ends up two degrees from the bad guy but
you only pull data in from one degree
from him and so that means that you're
focused all the rest of the world's data
goes right by and that's what you pull
and the metadata is the way you pull it
out because that gives you the ability
to I mean you're looking at the data
that's required for the network to route
data and if you do that then it's easy
to pull all that data out and that's all
you really get and it gives people
privacy and you get a rich environment
for your analysts to succeed that's what
they don't understand I'm still curious
how can you get veterans from things you
have never seen before because
unexpected yeah we we used actually two
approaches out of three but it was
deductive inductive an abductive
approach the deductive approach simply
said it's dealing with the graph if
you're in the graph and you're close to
within proximity of to ops of a known
terrorist then you're gonna be in a zone
of suspicion you'll be looked at it
doesn't mean you're guilty it just means
you're going to be looked at and then a
decision will be made yes or no if yes
then what's the reason you know and if
you didn't include it then the entire
graph will shift if you become a target
at that point you see so it's and that
was done by software the other was the
inductive approach that was the main one
that is if you are looking at sites
advocating pedophilia or sites
advocating jihad or terrorist activities
or violence against the West and you
keep repeatedly
looking at them or look at multiple
sites advocating that then that gives
you the idea that you are a potential
zone of sin the falling the zone of
suspicion and that means you get looked
at so at so at that point you get the
data coming in but you can do it all
having all their attributes encrypted
until you can prove that they are in
fact a part of the illegal activity last
question isn't it handy that they do
have a lot of data about the White House
the people who are now in the White
House yeah they do yeah they have
everything they do including including
the codes to decrypt their
communications thanks a lot for this
question yes please
next question hello
you mentioned the immense capacity to
store all this data from everyone and I
was wondering what companies and did
they incorporate willingly to create
such a capacity to store all the data
and in particular IBM and so can we
still trust our servers and know every
one of them and no because in the United
States if you're a company United States
they can force you by law to give them
their data it's only now coming out I
mean the the business they call it the
business records requisition the first
first thing from Edward Snowden was the
general warrant issued by the FISA Court
to the Verizon company to turn over all
the information about their customers
over 110 million US citizens you know
and that was a violation of the
Constitution a direct violation that's
why the judge Reggie Walton came out
tried to defend the court because of
that but they have the power to do that
with all of the companies and I would
point out that that was BR 13-8 II which
meant it's the 80th order of 2013 two
companies to give business records which
is the second quarter and it's issued
every 90 days so every quarter then
order comes out to each individual
company so and the way I reckoned and
the public switch telephone that way the
first two companies
line in the network providing data were
AT&T and Verizon so Verizon would get 18
t would get order one in quarter one
Verizon gets ordered two in quarter one
and then it gets order eighty in quarter
two that means there's 78 companies
participating so that 78 companies
participating banks you know telecom UK
communications company ISPs on the
internet and so on and in exchange they
received more funding to continue their
efforts could you repeat that please
so did they get anything in exchange for
all the information they passed on to
the NSA yeah money they get all business
they get paid for it yeah there's a
whole schedule on a whole schedule on
the rate of how much they get paid
thanks a lot next question please hello
thank you for being here and everything
you've done for basically all of us and
my question is when you see these
testimonies from for example James
clapper Keith Alexander when they're
being asked directly are you monitoring
you can kind of see in their eyes and
when you read other press that
monitoring means a completely different
thing for people within the NSA so my
question is how do we make questions
more relevant to level the playing
fields to make sure that we're all
talking about the same thing well it's
hard especially when they lie to you I
mean you know yes okay not wittingly but
you know how do we how how do we make
the questions sharper when we say okay
we know oui c'est Mon here's here so
senator Wyden phrased the question
properly I think is what's getting he
asked general Alexander how many how
many US citizens does he have in his
databases that's the right question it's
not you know if you talked about
collection well Alexander you know he
uses a word game collection means
somebody looking at it at NSA so it's
not collected til somebody looks at it
well that's that's worse yet you know if
I collect all your data I've got in my
day-to-day so he asked the right
question how many do you have in the
year
databases well it came back he said he
couldn't answer him so he came back in
writing this is under way but you look
at it's really a joke he says we he we
cannot tell you that because it would be
a violation of the privacy rights of US
citizens this is it's on the web if you
google le NSA answer to widens question
you know you should get it you could
probably get multiple ones but it should
be in there is an American I'd like to
say thank you for your service and I
also wanted to ask as a citizen if
there's anything we can do to make it
easier for agents to blow the whistle or
to encourage them to become
whistleblowers well I I always advocate
to the squeaky wheel gets the oil so
complain bitch my own break groaned if
your if your congressman or senator
comes up for a Town Meeting confront
them with it why are you backing this
this is obviously unconstitutional
you're violating your oath of office to
protect and defend the Constitution and
what are you going to do about it or
should I work for somebody else and if
you aren't going to stop this I'm gonna
work against you give my money to
somebody else and vote to fire you you
know and the other wise sue the bastard
that's what I'm doing
so we do have some more time for
questions so please go ahead and yeah I
was wondering NSA have been several
leaks to the public which helped us a
great deal know more about the inner
workings do you see a cultural change
within the NSA that there may be more
people who stand up and well choose
different paths to choose to reform the
NSA from inside or yeah I think I think
that's probably happening especially
with the younger generation go into NSA
the older generation we did a
myers-briggs study of personal traits of
people at working at NSA in 1992 or
something like that and it turned out
that 85% of them were eight is TJ's so
they're all introverts you know it's
like these are the people who like to
work in their desks you know I mean
mathematicians are that way they're very
quiet people look give me a pencil I'll
figure it out you know going to quarters
the answer you know that's all they do
but they're very easy to threaten those
are the kind of people you can easily
threatened and so that's what really
what's been going on inside NSA I mean
they have a program now called see
something say something about your
fellow workers well I mean that's what
the Stasi did you know that's what I
call Nastase new Stasi you know they're
they're picking up all the techniques
from the Stasi and the KGB and the
Gestapo and the SS they they start
getting violent yet that we know of okay
internally in the u.s. outside is
another story
yeah now we know something about the
u.s. programs but do we know something
about the other nation like Russia we
know that China has some internal spying
program but do they have capabilities of
like external spying yes I had a slide
there I think they deleted that I
couldn't it wasn't there at listing all
of the countries cooperating with NSA
let's see if I can get back to it
there there yeah these are the countries
participating with NSA of course the the
rest of the the five eyes up there and
then everybody else is classified as
third parties except for fourth parties
which we don't talk about because we
don't want anybody know we have
relations with them so you know they're
off the board but these are the
countries and each country has a
different relationship with NSA so I
mean I think eight or nine of these
countries in the third party category
are cooperating in the bulk acquisition
of data and the internet with NSA and
GCHQ in the rest of the five eyes so is
that the answer your question yes but a
big one missing Adar is Russia so we
should suppose that Russia has some
similar secret programs or we don't know
about which one are you talking about
Russia Russia yes
well Russia does the same thing in
Reverse you know they're looking that's
the same way yeah everybody's doing this
it to the to the ability and the
capabilities that they have I guess the
standard spying I mean it's why
diplomacy was created so we could spy on
people you know Thanks yeah
so it looks like no more question yes
there is one more question great please
go ahead would you say that the way that
they are doing the wrong thing is in
capability or not willing to do the
right you mean the other countries no
NSA the u.s. organizations are they not
capable of doing the right thing or are
they purposefully not doing the right
yeah it's they are capable I mean you
could see some of these whistleblowers
still coming out that so they they are
there are people who understand that
doing the wrong thing and they could
create a way to do it like I did
internally the trouble is we have people
managing these agencies who are
fundamentally corrupt
because there's so much money involved
in this you know money corrupts and it's
just I mean the budget for NSA is like
16 billion a year and if you for the
entire intelligence community it's been
close to a trillion dollars since 9/11
so that's a lot of money and and there's
a whole empire intelligence empire
that's built up over there over the
years in the United States and also in
the UK and it's spreading I mean and
some of the testimony from B and D and
what they're doing with NSA the
Bundestag has found out recently about
many of the things they're doing so
they're all doing the wrong thing in
terms of looking to stop things really
they're not taking a targeted approach
that's a professional discipline look at
your at your job and the target you're
supposed to be looking at and watching
instead of looking at everybody's
spreading your effort across the entire
planet you know so they have to they
have to learn how to do the right thing
too so there we have time left for about
two short questions or wait long
question but question I don't know if
the answer is long you just said that
they are able to look at the right
target but like they collect information
on everything everywhere anytime it's
like little kids they were distracted
I'm a little curious all that
information that is not related to the
correct target is related to a lot of
other targets and power is to control
what is outside of your personal space
so mmm question is very big on try to
ask about a specific point of view and
maybe you can elaborate on that how is
it possible that we still have organized
crime on a global scale some of this
outside of the power of the United
States of the direct influence at least
I would imagine organized crime from
foreign countries should be the subject
of this kind of information is it used
and we don't know or is it not used and
why I would say they attempt to use it
but
if you look at the if you google
xkeyscore which is the query routine
going into the databases for most of the
people or I see reach I don't know that
most of that's out there yet but if you
looked at that and you could see the the
way they asked the queries it's about
putting in words and phrases and just
like you do in a Google search so in a
Google search you get tons of material
back so that approach gives you tons of
material which means you've got to go
through all the items try to find it and
where is it in this list of so you get a
hundred thousand items back where is it
is it 90 thousand eighty can you get
there no answer's no that's why they
were failing so you're saying they're
fainting because they're not able to
interpret the daytime that's exactly
right they can't figure out what they've
got because they're taking the wrong
approach so I was wondering someone like
you or someone like you or for example
Thomas Drake who was a version of this
event like came from the inside of the
NSA and now standing here about the NSA
having a lot of data to use as leverage
against people so how come you are able
to be here why why aren't you dead or at
least in jail for something wrong you
said or if they've got so much power
over anyway well as I said in the movie
about me a good American I said you know
if they ever do it if they ever do
anything like that everyone will know
who did it and why so they don't want to
expose themselves to that kind of pull
it political and you know reaction by
the public in the United States because
that and now I'm basically well known
around the world so they I don't think
they I want to get them in court any way
I can if they want to do that that's
that's one of the ways at least if they
don't terminate me I'll be able to do
that
basically by making it obvious dare your
enemy yes a public exposure to a degree
of security you know okay thanks for
this last question please give a warm
round of applause
[Applause]
[Music]