[Music]
and with that I would like to announce
our speaker
Neil Sten ware who is head of at digital
at article 19 and is a PhD candidate at
the data active research group at
Amsterdam University he will talk to us
about human rights in organizations that
create new rules for the internet for
networks and we all have abide by so
great welcome to him thank you hi all I
am super excited that you are all here
and not in the afternoon Sun so thanks
for that I've got way too many slides
for this talk so I am going for a UDP
approach to presenting that means you
might not all get it but I'm happy to
resend at anytime later during the day
but let's keep this real time real time
before we dive into the talk which I
hope will be fun I want to talk about
something serious and that is about the
people that are not with us here today
about people that have given up their
freedom and in some case their lives for
Internet freedom for doing the things
that we are doing here Allie hurrah fee
paid a stipend our director of Amnesty
International in Turkey and these people
are in jail for doing digital activism
bustled got executed by the Syrian
regime
for that Allah is now in jail in Egypt
these brave Vietnamese blockers are in
jail as well
these brave Ethiopian bloggers from the
zone nine group have been in jail has
been tortured the internet is fun but it
can also be a very serious business so
when we talk about the internet and
about securing it let's think about the
people that give away so much for this
I am Niels I am I said a PhD candidate
and head of digital at article 19 head
of digital is a bit of a binary
prosthesis but that was given to me so I
happy to keep it I've been working
before this on digital security and
freedom of expression in a lot of
different countries but I was so
frustrated by teaching people digital
security we have been teaching safer sex
since the 80s and it means you only need
to do one thing to be safe and people
still don't do it when we work on
digital security we tell you a thousand
things that you need to do and we're
still not really sure that you're safe
and in the best case scenario nothing
happens
that is such a bad incentive for
behavior change so and especially asking
this of the people who are in extremely
stressful situations where they're just
trying to do work asking them to
validate keys and do all these extra
things just to be productive it's not
gonna work we should be able to do
better so that is what I got interested
more in Internet infrastructure and try
to make things more human rights
respecting by defaults and I'm going to
take you a bit on that trip that that
I've taken which has been very much an
exploratory trip so we start with a bit
of history where I can show you that
almost of a bit of an academic so buy
some quotes to lay the theoretical
groundwork we shape our tools and
thereafter they shape us when we create
technology we consciously and
unconsciously and bet our own thoughts
values and worldview in them that's not
special for technology we also do that
in architecture if we make broad roads
with no sidewalks only for cars what's
going to happen more cars
if we're going to recreate large spaces
with benches trees people are going to
be outside so the way we shape our
infrastructure is shaping our societies
there's no rule number
now I hear you're thinking well but
technology it might be just neutral
because it's not technology that kills
people it's people that kill people so
here I'm going to try to introduce the
term affordances another academic thing
you bear with me it means that it's the
character characteristic of a technology
to enable or disable certain use and
behavior that makes it easier or harder
to do things or even to have specific
rights and the question is then of
course who is creating that technology
what we also need to think of is that
technology so we talked about
affordances Neil postman took that to
the far end and said the way technology
is built is determining largely how you
can use it well I feel some of you
getting really anxious about it because
it's exactly the hacker way of breaking
technology and using it in different
ways right but it's still showing and
growing the path there is also some
pretty good criticism on Neil postman
because he's saying you're putting way
too much importance on the technology
that's why they also called him a techno
determinist technology cannot solve all
our problems
having said that technology is a very
human activity
so it's intertwined the technology and
in human social behaviors so let's try
to trace that history of technology and
the history of enabling of our rights so
your your Europe you you've gone through
the academic part it will be much better
now so what I what I what I forgot to
ask who of you here self identifies as a
lawyer or policy person yes and how many
of you are are technologists nerds very
good so I'll going to be hard on the
lawyer aside the lawyers please help me
so let's have a short look at the
history of technology and it's important
to see that
during the Second World War the first
programmers were actually women working
on the ENIAC machine and the ENIAC
machine computer was designed to
calculate the trajectory of artillery
and a lot of resources went into this at
the same time the radiation lab was set
up where for the first time
interdisciplinary researchers got
together to work on systems one of the
people working there was book Minster
Fuller who stood at the beginning of the
development of of what we now know as a
Silicon Valley culture pretty much but
at the end of the Second World War
something said something else happened
as well and that was the universal
declaration for Human Rights was written
it was drafted under the lead of a
drafting team by Eleanor Roosevelt and
what is important to know about the
Universal Declaration of Human Rights is
that there is no other international
norms a document that has been accepted
by more countries so it's the biggest
agreement on norms that we have but it
is not a hard agreement and there I'm
not alone in this frustration also if
you reread the anecdotes from the the UK
delegation they really wanted to make it
international law but they couldn't get
through it that only happens later on
when we got the International Covenant
on Civil and Political Rights and that
was in 1966
so with these treaties the Universal
Declaration became international law in
parts and not only in 1966 the
International Covenant on Civil and
Political Rights happens but also the
International Covenant on economic
Social and Cultural Rights
why do same two treaties at the same
time why not fold them into one it's
because of the politics stupid the civil
and political rights were the wishes of
America and the Western Europe law
an international governor economic
social and cultural rights where the
wishes from the from the Soviet and g77
bloc later we also had so there was a
lot of contention between the two given
forth and these two were seen together
with the Universal Declaration as the
International Bill of Rights there are
also other conventions that codify human
rights such as the International
Convention on the elimination of all
forms of racial discrimination mm-hmm
and the convention of the rights of
persons with disabilities and the
Convention on the elimination of all
forms of discrimination against women
this is international law and
governments should do everything to
protect these these international laws
and enshrine them in their own national
laws once you've done that you've
ratified the treaty then fast forward in
history Berlin Wall fell
so the contention between the Soviet and
the Western bloc kind of dissipated and
this was enough for Francis Fukuyama to
say this is the end of history
liberalism has won welcome to the future
this is going to be freedom for everyone
the middle class will rise and with the
growth of privatization everything will
be good and liberal democracies will
flourish under capitalism that was the
promise that was made to me and it was
not true at the same time after the fall
of the Berlin Wall we also seen the rise
of internet hosts so this huge wave of
privatization went together with the
building of the Internet infrastructure
oh so if we think back about the
previous world communication network
which was the Telegraph and the
Telegraph was completely regulated
nationally by governments and
internationally by the oldest UN body
that's even older than the UN itself is
the UN Telegraph Union which nowadays is
called the International
Telecommunications Union only
governments have a say there
but the internet was not built on
government standards it was build
another form of governance we'll talk
about that more but let's go back to the
human rights story because then in the
2000s people realized if it's only
governments going to protect human
rights then we're not going to get far
because some companies are actually
getting quite on par with with
governmental power so how are we going
to keep the government's to accounts
well first in the early 2000s we had the
UN Global Compact and UN Global Compact
said you need to have a corporate social
responsibility strategy CSR how many of
you have heard of that good that I'm
telling you them so and corporate social
responsibility was pretty much you can
have an oil leak here you can build a
school there you're good so that's and
everyone after a while so mmm-hmm this
is not really good but or this is not
good enough but it created the awareness
that companies had a responsibility to
do something about human rights and then
in 2011 under a committee drafted by
John Ruggie the UN guiding principles
for business and human rights were
thought up and they are actually quite
simple there are three pillars their
responsibility to protect the
responsibility to respect and the right
to remedy so it reaffirms the the role
of governments to protect human rights
they should go out and do everything
with their ability within their ability
to protect human rights that are
universal inalienable and interdependent
then the corporations and non-state
actors have the responsibility to
respect human rights that means that
they have the responsibility to look
within their own policies and operations
and do a human rights impact assessment
to understand how they impact and here
comes the important part directly or
indirectly human rights so with that is
also the introduction of the concept of
chain responsibility
so and you've heard about this you've
heard about this in the garment industry
where Nike and Adidas had sweatshops in
Bangladesh India etc with the push of
the UN guiding principles for Human
Rights it was much easier to hold them
to account and many of these have now
assigned it and got it into place same
with the mining industry same with the
banking industry not in the IT industry
we think of ourselves as being
completely ahead but actually we're
pretty much behind the curve and the
Forgotten pillar the right to remedy
that's the possibility that if your
rights have been violated you have a way
to access to that be set right that can
be via national law but corporations
should also provide that possibility to
to set that right so now let's go back
to the internet and let's see where
those two worlds merge so let's
differentiate three different layers
yeah we can go always I about it but
we're going three layers the physical
layer the logical layer and the social
order application layer and where we're
talking increasingly about human rights
and in this schematic give provided by
ICANN everyone puts human rights on the
application layer because that's what
people can see that's what people
understand but somehow these layers are
forgotten layers whereas if we think
back about affordances these lower
layers actually make possible everything
that is on top so perhaps we should try
understanding what the impact is of the
logical and the physical layer and how
that is done so let's have a look at
that and then we get into this weird
beast of the multi-stakeholder model no
one really knows what it is because
there are many different forms of
multistakeholderism some more formalized
some
formalised some more accessible some are
less accessible so I'll give you a few
examples where we can where we can have
a look at so let's start with the World
Summit on information societies in 2005
which was still a UN meeting but a lot
of people were invited to come and to
work on a joint outcome documents which
was the Tunis agenda and there in the
42nd point which was not on top of their
priority list they reaffirmed the
commitment to freedom to seek receive
any part and use information so the
connoisseurs among you might know that
this is exactly the language of article
19 of the Universal Declaration of Human
Rights so the right to freedom of
expression but here coined the law URI
weasel words like we also we also must
protect and respect the provisions for
privacy and freedom of expression is
contained in the relevant parts of the
UDHR and the Geneva declaration which
means if you put in the relevant parts
you can always argue that it's not
relevant for that for that place but
still it was the first place where human
rights got um anchored and then jump
forward you see we're going forward to
history you and Human Human Rights
Council in 2012 said the same rights
that people have offline must also be
protected online a bit of a no-brainer
right because it's not an another
dimension and it's still people but it
was at understanding that we needed to
think that the old UN frameworks the old
laws did not really cover that and that
thinking was really pretty much right as
Edward Snowden has showed us and then
everything got kicked into a higher gear
because the UN General Assembly agreed
on the right to privacy in the digital
age where it called upon all states to
respect and protect the right to privacy
including in the content of digital
communications to take measures and to
review their procedures practices and
legislation so they should do stuff
normally when the UN says people need to
do things
Oh quite a lot must happen and this was
because Dilma roussef did then president
of Brazil was part of the eavesdropping
program that was uncovered by Edward
Snowden and so the Brazilians together
with the Germans led this resolution and
it also led to the establishment of a
Special Rapporteur on privacy then
Brazil organized the netmundial
conference in Sao Paulo in 2014 and that
was actually quite interesting because
it was the first time that in the front
there were for my clients and the my
clients were for civil society academia
or there there were five miles of my
clients civil society academia business
technical community and governments and
people could queue up and it would go
round robin and this confused everyone
because it was diplomats used to be
speaking on behalf of their country
after some Hecker
after it was really weird but we managed
to get an outcome documents and some
found it more strong stronger some have
found less representation in that with
civil society for once we were the best
organized stakeholder group we had one
text on which most people agreed in the
end we got a bit snaked by the by the
lawyers of the private sector but you
live you learn but what was there is
that there is the declaration to the
UDHR but also boom ICCPR ICS CR and the
Convention on the Rights of persons with
disabilities so there is this increasing
body of human rights language but this
is all theory right they can say
everything in Geneva they're not running
the internet so let's see where the
rubber hits the road let's have a look
at ICANN who view knows what icon is of
so good so icon is is administering
policies and operations for the root
zone of the DNS right oh I'm so happy I
don't have to explain I can but
I can is also an example of the multi of
a highly formalized form of the
multi-stakeholder model it means that
the policies for the different top-level
domains the country code top-level
domains and the generic top-level
domains dot banana Amazon etc are
managed in different spaces as well as
the addressing supporting community so
they're handing out of the IP blocks and
then there are also other groups that
can have that can have an impact and a
review of the policies that are made by
these bodies and within these bodies
there is then a sub categorization of
civil society of intellectual property
lawyers so it's highly structured and
then what happened then you think that's
a lot of structure then within all these
bodies there is also a process on how
the policies gets developed so you can
notice that I can is pretty much
colonizers maybe not the right words but
there are a lot of lawyers and so
everything is put down into processes
this helps in to transparency but it
also takes you one and a half year to
actually understand the processes so
almost all meetings of ICANN or mailing
lists and all video calls are
transcribed but before you understand
what is actually being said and how it
works it takes you about one and a half
year so that is where transparency is
not the same as having easy access in
those policy discussions right so you
need a lot of resources knowledge
networks and understanding and also
money to be able to participate in the
meetings then something interesting
happens after the Snowden revelations
because I can was astir so originally
the DNS was managed by Jon Postel when
the the root zone was managed by Jon
Postel
when the internet got more important the
US government the
the NTIA the Department of Commerce said
okay we need to institutionalize this
and they contracted ICANN to do that
which means that the u.s. still had
contracting power over ICANN and this
was something that after the Snowden
revelations the u.s. said were happy to
give this up we're happy to give this up
but not to anyone
we're not giving this to another
government we want to give this to the
international internet community this
was a new thing and this is I think I
think why multistakeholderism is
important not only because we love the
Internet but it's also an innovation in
governance so a sovereign state was able
to give up give out something so so so
important such an important asset as
control over the DNS so they said we
need to develop two plans one technical
plan and one plan to improve ICANN's
accountability and we succeeded you can
ask yourself was this really an
internationalization because if you look
at the language that the NTIA in the
Department of Commerce itself put out it
might also be a privatization and
actually there were two press releases
one for internal use in the US where
where the NTIA said we're going to have
the private sector take the leadership
for DNS management and in the
International statement they said we're
going to internationalize the DNS
management so that's other thing to be
to be cognizant about but the good thing
part of the the accountability work was
an inclusion of ICANN to respect
internationally recognized human rights
so we were able to put that in before
the before the transition happens but we
weren't able to negotiate all the
details so in workstream 2 which was the
part that would happen after the
after the transition we were to supposed
to develop a framework of interpretation
for the human rights bylaw and a lot of
people were very afraid that workstream
2 would be the graveyard of ideas that's
okay if we push it through for a
transition and then after that nothing
will pass but hurray we almost have
consensus on the framework of
interpretation the last public comment
period ended and we're now reworking
that which means that by the end of the
year I can will respect human rights at
least according to its bylaws this is a
slide that you cannot read this you can
find this graphic as well on ICANN Human
Rights dotnet and I also put the slides
in the description of the talk
afterwards so this is a simple mapping
of all different rights only the G and s
o which was the the part that makes
policies for the generic TLDs it's
touching upon ranging from freedom of
expression freedom of association due
process participation the right of
security so we tend to think that the
internet stops at freedom of expression
and the right to privacy but there are
way more things mediated by the internet
nowadays it's a right to political
participation the right to due process
right to education right to science
so all these things we also need to take
into account when we think about
infrastructure does this mean we're now
protected from evil takeovers an icon no
but we definitely have an easier in
easier tool to have a look at ICANN
because this means that I can will do
human rights impact assessments of all
its policies and at the moment when
they're doing that civil society or
anyone for that matter can drop in and
see we've missed this or you should
think about this which means that you
don't need to be entrenched in the
trenches of ICANN all the time to be
able to keep them to accounts so
hopefully this is a good thing
so let's now have a look at a bit more
of the nitty-gritty technical
it's because you're nerds really stuck a
long time with the lawyer II stuff and
I'm thankful for that so what is
interesting is that the primacy of the
Internet is that it's a network of
networks and in debt it's a bit in
congruence with human rights because
human rights always argues from the
basis of the rights holder the user but
on the Internet users cannot simply
claim their rights every time you want
to connect you need to ask can you
please give me an IP address will you
please route my packets pretty please
will you not drop them
can I please connect without accepting
your horrible policies that I do not
even know about this is an inherent part
of how the Internet is designed and that
means that the people running the
networks are always in control I'm not
saying this was intentional I can
actually actually pretty okay to say
that this wasn't intentional but it
isn't affordance a characteristic of
what we've built so in some senses we
may have it made it harder to protect
human rights online because of the
infrastructure we have again that
doesn't mean think of Crohn's barracks
law that the Internet is totally bad now
it has good parts and it has bad parts
but we need to think about that when
building it so don't leave the rights to
the to the lawyers or they'll take care
of it because the rights are being part
of the internet that we build
consciously or unconsciously we're
programming in what we think and who we
are and if we want to make the internet
a real global network we need to think
with people that are not only from the
global north because half of the world
is still not connected to the Internet
which means that we're also reproducing
a network on which many people might not
feel at home and that paints me because
the internet is always for me field like
a place of freedom for many others it
might not a friend of mine an equal it's
engineering performance art made a
programming language in Arabic and he
said why do you call it information
for engineering performance arts he said
because it's not gonna work
github fails parsers fail nothing works
like utf-8 isn't even the norm for
non-latin characters so what we're
saying to people who are not using the
non-latin scripts and often to people
not speaking English not only on the
content layer but also on the
development layer like this is not your
network you do not belong here you need
to adapt to us and that is a problem but
there are many ways to go in there are
also many cool developments and it is of
us to be aware of that and work on it so
let's have another look at another body
that is important in the development of
the internet the internet engineering
task force who of you knows what the
IETF is I love this audience so good so
something really cool what we're now
doing to take care of the steps and a
colleague of mine said it's so greatly
like why was God able to create the
world in six days because there was no
pre installed user base so what we need
to do now is that we need to work with
all those horrible legacy stuff and just
build tunnels or pop tunnels and of
tunnels and tunnels but that also
creates a lot of latency right so TCP
you want to establish a connection syn
arcs in Ock you want to do a TLS
handshake on top of that Network getting
convoluted shit so some folks at Google
largely have developed a new
implementation which is called quick
which is pretty much TCP plus TLS over
UDP and it has encrypted almost all the
headers so the descent IP receive I see
it's encrypted it's awesome and it's by
default it's good and here the market
powers of Google are quite interesting
because they can roll it really out
really quickly between the Chrome
and the Google servers boom then we have
a lot of uptake so then these big
companies can actually do something good
which is great at the same time there
are also some other actors in the IETF
so for instance in the discussion on TLS
1.3 there is a strong draft that we
should include forward secrecy then the
banks or other large financial
institutions came in and said no no no
no no no no no no no forward secrecy
because we have so many boxes and I'm
this they said this we have so many
boxes and last we hadn't we had a
problem and we had 60 people on a call
we couldn't fix it it was a problem in a
database so and network traffic that we
cannot encrypt is a DDoS attack on our
system like oh my god it's like you
don't even have a panel to check the
performance of your databases so just
because they do not want to adapt to an
environment in which they have forward
secrecy it doesn't mean they cannot
decrypt they can decrypt at the
endpoints right but they want to decrypt
in-flight and he said we only want to do
it in the data centers but why only do
it in the data say if you only want to
do it in the data center why make it a
standard in whole TLS so that everyone
can do it and what is really problematic
is that the American Standards Institute
NIST is supporting this and NIST has
already been found one times by the NSA
with weakening crypto protocols and this
is shamelessly happening again so what
we need to be strong and that's why we
need your voice in the IETF but these
are the problems that we know about
security privacy issues we can make them
better we have quick and what the quick
people said that was so much fun is that
they said ok if you're going to if
you're going to get forward secrecy out
of TLS 1.3 we'll implement it with
forward secrecy in quick fuck you pretty
nice
so can internet protocols further impact
Human Rights so within the IETF and the
internet research task force we set up a
research group to to start thinking
about this and for that we needed to try
to translate technical concepts into
rights so then you got crazy shit like
this and there were so many discussions
to be had about all these different
definitions and also what does equals
mean right because if you have this will
you're automatically a freedom of
expression no it creates an enabling
environment and this is part why it's
important to have the UN globe
to implement the UN GPS the ruggy
principles because then we get to make
better policies because no part of the
internet rules the whole internet but we
need to understand which part of the
internet impacts what else it's also
impossible for policymakers to make same
decisions and they're gonna make stupid
broad hand policies because they sense
hey if you cannot make it clear where we
should act
we'll use a hammer because we make laws
that's what we do so there were a lot of
other rights that we've been trying to
think of and two years of thinking and
discussing in the human rights protocols
considerations research group in the IRT
F resulted in the draft on the research
into human rights protocol
considerations and that actually gives
you a guideline for protocol developers
to think about their human rights impact
and this is going to be an RFC by the
end of the month so we'll have an RFC on
Human Rights yes
but that means that we now need to
leverage those tools so we have made the
steps from saying in general this is
important now we're enshrining it slowly
but surely but now we need people to use
this because else it'll be dead letters
so what is good stuff in the ietf while
researching for the human rights work we
found a lot of good RFC your who knows
what an RFC is okay very good
I love you so these are a lot of good
RSC's with very interesting rights
knowledge but a lot of them it did not
get very it was not made very explicit
so we had to do a lot of anthropology
and exploring and to understand doing a
lot of interviews but increasingly
language is becoming more explicit and
there is more space for a civil society
in the IETF
and there is a lot of interesting stuff
going on on TLS 1.3 DTLS UTA which is
finally making pinning for smtp
necessary curdled cool stuff you like it
come to the IETF what is not so good and
why we need you to be there these are
the amount of RFC is published and this
is by which organization and I can tell
you the first eight ones are companies
the universities that are in there is
because the early RFC's were produced by
universities so because of different
reasons academics and let alone civil
society is completely underrepresented
I'm not saying people Eric that work at
companies are evil no not whatsoever I'm
saying that they are inhaling the fumes
they need to get something done they're
not getting paid to think about human
rights so we should remind them while
working on that and actually they are
quite susceptible engineers like to
solve problems so let's help them make
clear what the problems are and what net
we actually want
so what is really ugly and what is also
a problem for the IETF and that's what
you hear over and over is that the IETF
is not the protocol police these are
open standards everyone can implement on
the internet whatever you want
permissionless innovation but what we
see is an increased in increasing in
centralization we see this on the
physical layer with ISPs taking over but
it's going to be far fucking words with
5g where which is decided on what 5g is
and this is really crazy in a closed
industry body the 3gpp - it should not
get access if you're not a company or
not affiliated with a company and China
the European Union and the US are all
battling to be the first to implement 5g
whereas we have no idea what is in the
spec so we're just giving them the keys
to our spectrum and our stuff it is so
frustrating and then there were some
good parts potentially in it about open
spectrum but then with LTE why a Wi-Fi
uh LTE over Wi-Fi
they are gonna squat the open spectrum
directly and then the doneto end effect
will be we do not have access to the
frequencies and they do not need to pay
frequency auctions anymore really
frustrating then in the IETF we had the
thing that the Internet is end-to-end
the Tula's ITR IP and the objective is
connectivity and to end the dead man
it's really sad if you look at how much
content is going through content
distribution networks and how much of
these content distribution networks are
breaking SSL and TLS it is really a mess
and we do not have clear transparency
about what they're doing let alone that
we know how it's routed right because
BGP is not transparent BGP nice hobby as
well we should clean it up once then on
hardware we also see the dominant a few
dominant organizations and well the
application layer is all the hype you
know about that so what does that mean
what are we looking at
well it can take different forms there
is some good some bad and a lot of
opportunities and the Internet is still
a very exciting place and we need to
remember that rights are like muscles
you need to train them else they go away
and if you do not and if you train a lot
then you know sometimes you might break
a bone that's not so bad
so know about internet governance and
know about the infrastructure because
the infrastructure is what determines
what's happening on top so we need to
think about the breaking the
centralization of knowledge which means
getting it out of the patterns and out
of the trademarks and getting out of the
companies to understand how they are
running the networks we need to fight
for our right to science which is also a
human rights we need to be able to find
out how then for how the networks work
because it is now a days our public
sphere that is mediated by the Internet
it's about voting it's about your
primary contact to to your government to
your representatives but it's also your
freedom of association that's largely
mediated by the internet so we need to
ensure that we know how it works that we
can also ensure that we can keep our
rights then then we need to ensure they
will building a real global network for
the people not for the networks not for
the operators but for the people and
that is something that a lot of the
people in the IETF do not necessarily
have in mind they're having a hard
problem they're working on really hard
problems for operators but we need to
ensure that the end user is better
represented and that we as end-users
also understand the system's better so
we need to take power and rights into
account in the design of all
technologies because we shape our tools
and thereafter they shape us thanks very
much
[Applause]
[Music]
right we do have quite some time for
questions hello hello hello hello hello
hello the tae ik hello which are the tie
between patents and protocol okay so a
lot of protocols that are implemented
are actually not be are not open
protocol such as I such as in the IETF
and especially on the lower layers on
the when it comes to physical connection
and what is implemented in in
proprietary systems they are trademarked
so we do not know what they are and we
cannot access them the IETF actually was
formally set up and set up for that the
Internet Society to protect the
engineers in the internet engineering
text task force for patent claims
because a lot of times companies want to
want to standardize the technology so
they'll be able to sell the middleboxes
and the funny thing is that a lot of
people were working in the IETF
have trademarks on technology for which
they want it to be compatible that's why
probably the bank's really do not want
to change the technology because they do
they need to win then they need to
change and because they haven't used
open-source they have a vendor lock-in
and then they need to pay the vendor a
lot to change that so we need to explain
to the bank's you shouldn't have vendor
lock-in and you should definitely not
put the costs for you having a shitty
system on the whole of society
[Applause]
[Music]
hello yeah so you talked about ETF and
everything that's still not going yet
and this almost sounds like a
recruitment speech rather than just some
information so are you rooting for
somebody are you forming teams yes I
recruit barbarians so know what tell me
so
both we're both active in icon the ietf
the I Triple E we're now also working in
the ITU to make work more transparent
and we always need people that end the
way you can interact is help us simply
do in the IETF for instance do human
rights impact assessments of working
group drafts just help us analyze how
these new standards can impact human
rights and earlier we do it in the
process of the development of the
internet drafts the easier we can change
things because if you do it very late in
the process it's much harder to shift so
there and we're also having a small
public interest group in which we try to
coordinate to do reviews of internet
drafts and something very similar we
have an icon as well so please come talk
to me or send me an email and I'm very
happy to work with you on this Hey yeah
first of all thank you for a very
sobering and an interesting talk I I
know that I can has profited massively
from their monopolistic position and I
was wondering if that's going to be
solved with this new governance model
[Music]
well the problem is DNS right is that we
need to coordinate or ensure that there
are no way to put my contacts on and
there now can think again the problem is
with the design of DNS that there is a
single root zone and that needs to be
coordinated and that's done in a
multi-stakeholder way so actually we
have not had many problems with the US
government intervening in I can so it's
also a bit of a theoretical exercise I
think it's good because we're trying to
understand better how does
multi-stakeholder thing can work whether
it will work and whether whether it will
make things better that remains to be
seen it's really too quick because it's
only been October last year that it's
gotten independence but we're trying to
do some analysis of automated analysis
of mailing lists and off discussions to
see how the balance shifts but what we
do see and that is quite interesting is
that there is a huge influx of
governments in in ICANN to join the
conversation which is kind of
legitimizing the multi-stakeholder model
so but on the other hand the government
are only advising and not in the
policy-making trenches so it is such a
weird beast it still remains to be seen
how this works which could radically be
disrupted if we come up with something
as a surname coin had this
implementation of DNS in the blockchain
right yeah yeah blockchain is going to
change everything but you could imagine
DNS done differently and that would come
with other affordances so it's
yeah
Harry Halpin yes X w3c so I do want to
mention quick quitting on the patent
issue so one thing that would be awesome
if the IETF did and one thing that the
w3c the web standards body did correctly
is they essentially have royalty-free
licensing so we have to remember even
free and open-source software can have
patents there you are not immunized from
patents unfortunately by using the GPL
so therefore I would like standards
bodies like the IETF to have better
patent policy so I've definitely been on
some crypto mailing lists in IETF where
the people just like literally emailing
their mailing lists and being like I
can't read that last email because the
ITF says you have to disclose all known
patents so there is a patent but you
don't know about it's okay so that's a
bit dangerous it's better that the Hat
the companies explicitly declare all
patents and promise to license them
royalty-free forever
that being said w3c is obviously really
fucked up because they're pushing DRM
digital rights management into html5 and
soon in the ebooks being pushed by
Netflix and then with ebooks Springer
Elsevier everyone else who's trying to
close down knowledge
would you please computer and my
question is why hasn't article 19 I can
the IETF
all these standards bodies which are
doing some at human rights why don't
they tell their fucked up younger
brother w3c to get their act together or
do these organizations think that the
DMCA and DRM is compatible with human
rights so at my ETF 101 in London in
March next year we're organizing a
hackathon on privacy and human rights
considerations for the w3c to address
exactly DET exactly this and work for
two days on seeing how we can integrate
these concepts also in the w3c people
from a w3c will be there and I really
hope that some of you will join us there
too I'll I'll go I'm gonna tweet it is
it good I'm at Nielsen over so it's the
two days I had
of the ietf 101 meeting so we had a
really good hackathon big before the
last IETF on HTTP status code 451 which
makes a legal censorship more visible
but we now also really want a hack on
web standards so that's going to be for
IETF 101 and I would love you to be
there Harry and thanks for fighting the
DRM fight we're not done yet
hi you said that we should join IETF
probably to help you in in in you in
doing your fights but it's my
understanding that IETF is completely
split in half over this topic if it's
even their concern you know they say we
are technical people at least one half
and the other half says maybe we can
take this into consideration but it's
still unclear if they are the right
people to address with that topic so I
think actually that it the situation in
the IETF is a bit better because we had
a plenary talk at the not the last but
the IETF before that where Dave Clark
one of one of these early internet
inventors and us talked about human
rights and affected the internet
architecture board organized a plenary
talk about that and there was large
agreement that this is important and
that the IETF should engage on it that's
a good thing how that's going to be done
remains to be seen and in indeed in the
TLS discussion it was about half half
but I also had a strong feeling that the
deck was a bit stacked there so it's
also for us to get engaged and help us
also influence on the other side it
doesn't mean you can't in and you all
know when you get into the IETF you
can't just do a hand wave you need to
come with arguments but that's will also
help us to understanding because no one
understands what the internet will be we
get to shape it
right there appear to be no more
questions could I have a warm round of
applause for our great speaker
[Applause]
[Music]