[Music]
over the last years we've been uploading
more and more of a photo and video data
to the internet either voluntarily
through YouTube and Facebook and
Instagram I guess and also without our
knowledge through security cameras
coupled with increase in machine
learning a high research and all of that
I think we are all quite concerned about
applications but it's getting farther
than that and our next speaker is
looking at what the implications are for
our society as a whole for culture so
he's an activist
he's a digital rights advocate and he's
a tech ethicist please welcome to the
stage Matthew stander just will let you
know if you want to move up be awesome
if you want to leave it any time no
worries like I know it's late in the
lated camp everybody's probably in a nap
for some party tonight but excuse me
while we're here let's talk about the
future my name is Matthew cinder I call
myself a tech ethicist I'm really
interested in the both the cultural and
ethical implications of emerging
technology kind of this question what
does it mean to be human in the 21st
century other things like what is the
social contract that humans and the
machines we've built but that are
becoming more and more than just tools
what is the what is the social contract
that we can expect what is it what is a
reasonable expectation of privacy when
we live in an age of ubiquitous
surveillance
so my talk today I am gonna run through
it in some ways they're the kind of
first half is going to be a updates on
what is going on as far as facial
recognition technology how it's being
deployed in countries around the world
how it is become how our faces are now
becoming an access control vector and
what does it mean then image once it's
taken in a digital format can
continuously be processed and added new
and have new layers of information added
to it alright so I first really got
interested in the idea of ubiquitous
surveillance and particularly facial
recognition technology because I feel
it's an interesting Nexus that combines
sociological psychological but also
technological forces what I mean by that
is when we are walking down the street
oh let's say 50 years ago 60 years ago
walking down the street you could in
some ways be anonymous
maybe somebody could see you but there
was very little record of you being
there
now with twenty four-hour-a-day CCTV
cameras those that have the access to
these two databases in which that
collects visual information can rewind
they can also see where their other eyes
are around town and actually map out our
trajectory throughout the real space in
which that we occupy so with that um
this is gonna be this is a six things
from a talk that I'm giving in an hour
and a half but I wanted to start with
this I have been working on a theory and
called hash tag mimics but when it comes
down to proprietary algorithms
proprietary platforms I'm very concerned
that there are a lot of a lot of forces
that can be exerted on our information
flow that create a increase the signal
to static ratio between information
sources and us so this is a theory that
I've been I'm continuing to develop I
call it mimics and a stands for monitor
index manipulate
intercept sensor and silo so these are
these are six forces in which that the
proprietary nature the black box nature
of proprietary algorithms can can
interact with our information and
eventually nudge us into consumption
decisions or other decisions in which we
not we may not have even known that
there were they were acting on us
mmm-hmm
so let's let's take a look at this when
it comes to the mass proliferation of
image and video technology that is
surrounds us it is pretty mind-blowing
that a hundred thousand people nearly a
hundred thousand really sorry I'm not
nearly a million people log into
Facebook every day that 1.8 million
snaps are created in internet minutes I
mean snapshots new yeah I mean there's
so I mean I think that snapchat has been
very impressive in the way that it's
been able to be outside is they've been
able to resist been able to resist
purchases by Facebook and now has had
its IPO we'll see how that goes I don't
personally use snapchat but y'all
probably all seen at least a snapchat
interface in which an augmented reality
layer use vector mapping on a face in
order to create filters this is actually
a pretty sophisticated piece of
technology vector mapping I think is a
pretty exciting thing it talked a little
bit about that later but it just goes to
show that now as commercial products are
being put out that we use as fun
there also is technology that's being
developed and that goes into it goes
into something like a snapchat so I
mentioned this a little earlier this is
a this is some bullet points paraphrase
from a piece and a new inquiry by turf
Allen called invisible images and this
this was an when I wrote this piece it
got me interested in this in this
dichotomy of the idea of how we see an
image is always static but the systems
that we put it into can continual return
and be able to draw out information that
may not have been a
parent when the first kind of cycling
through of this image how so totally
concerns about that a photograph shot on
a phone creates a machine-readable file
and I think this is a really interesting
first point that we are not creating
images that are human first readable we
are now creating machine readable first
and we actually need a subsidiary or
another a photo viewing app in order to
see visually what the what our phone is
captured the and secondly that images do
not need to be turned on turn into human
readable forms in order for machines to
do something with it that we that there
may never be a human readable file but
information that's captured is still
being AB is still being processed and
the implications of this are that the
the automation of vision at the scale
which would forgotten of the first slide
1.8 million snaps per minute this sort
of enormous scale and it says is is
something we've never seen before
right the computing power that it used
to take to I don't know even put you
know images into a system for CCTV
cameras manage the the information flow
especially an analog since people needed
tapes and tapes and pH s's and maybe
DVDs whatever it may be but now on on
such a small device we're able to of
with solid-state memories and other
things we're able to put so much
information in one small space so I
wanted to talk a little about the kind
of ecosystem that's going on and this is
that's what we're seeing now is a mode
of development a mode of technology
development that is diverging in two
ways at least in my opinion and this is
the corporatization of of services but
this is also nation-states
developing technology to further their
interests so this so at carnegie mellon
who had at the time the most advanced
had the world's experts in facial
recognition and vision technology and
neural net
works these people were all based at
Carnegie Mellon what it over do they
poached 40 of the top researchers in
this field and now they're working for
what I would consider a pretty shitty
you know a pretty shitty company it's an
interesting interplay in which that now
there's commercial or economic motives
for the brightest minds in the world to
not in not to put use their talents for
the betterment of humanity but for
individual corporations on the other
side of this is nation states that Baidu
and other companies in China are now are
now doing some amazing things I mean
Facebook and Google as well but but
China right now is has some of the the
not only the top supercomputers but
they're also doing they're also
pioneering machine learning neural
networks and other things on their own
accord why I find this interesting is
because if we're talking about modes of
technological development what what are
what do we expect what are the motives
that drive the the entities that create
this technology if we look at China even
though the Chinese computer scientists
and others that are programming this I
find it quite interesting and that the
boxes the linguistic boxes in which that
code is entered into isn't written to do
programming languages also has what I
consider a cultural DNA that a character
that each character representing a
syllable in Chinese is different from a
string of characters in a Latin alphabet
and so I think that's really interesting
is for me to think about though the ways
in which that different entities are
pioneering different technologies but
they all bring something different they
all bring their own motives into the mix
so these are three things that I believe
that are going to be important effectors
in what I consider a next epoch um this
is an epoch of the road change
relationship between humans and
technology so I'm going to talk about
the I'm gonna talk about these three
things and some other things but talk
about how machines see us
how we see each other through the lens
of machines and how we view what we now
consider machines all right so let's
delve into this into this a little bit
so personally I like the agency I don't
have the ability to control how a CCTV
camera or Facebook or Instagram running
neural networks on the uploaded digital
content is sees me what kind of
sovereignty gives me as an individual or
how I'm packaged together with groups of
similar people
and this really does I believe impact to
our identity I'll get into this little
more lightly as I as I as AI is
incorporated into new platforms this
will become increasingly pronounced we
see this all the time ai is gonna do
this let's let let's outsource decisions
to that so what about you so I'm appear
you're down there we can all see each
other in this room but if we think about
unmet worked humans well I caught the
next billion the next billion people
that have never touched a networked
device right but soon more and more
people every day more and more people
are have a phone in their hands when it
comes to a place like India and
Bangladesh that have a high rate of
digital adoption half just by the scale
of their populations but there's still a
lot of unmet worked humans so how is
somebody that is not even on Facebook or
snapchat or these other systems how
would it what is their identity what
does their sovereignty of self look like
in the context when they're still being
passively captured whether in the
background of selfies or on CCTV or soon
with self-driving cars that have both
lidar and cameras around it what are
what are what is the ability for people
that are not inside of these corporate
silos to actually control the way that
they're seen and ultimately when I'm
thinking about technology you know what
are the communication strategies that we
need to develop and with the the body of
epistemic reality there's new the way
that we learn things
how will this inform humans when we're
dealing with not just one type of AI but
many different types of AI that all have
these optical nerves that are
essentially digital eyes so machine
learning neural network so mega face is
a database instead of by a university in
California and it is like one of the
most important test dataset so it's a
training set with over 4.5 4.0 toes with
yeah nearly a million unique identities
and there's no other so there's some
overlap so people are able to have
different motors of themselves and this
right over train things but it I find it
quite interesting that one database is
kind of the standard for machine
learning let's talk about how this is
problematic and even the idea of why we
need to further interrogate test data
and training data but I just wanted to
set this up here because this is kind of
deep for mere a lot of the a lot of the
contests that are that are that are run
use this this database the mega face
database so as I said like we are
getting more and like every day it seems
that there are new developments inside a
facial recognition recognition
technology and a lot of these are done
for corporate capitalists means so
Google is now linking offline online
habits and offline buying habits facial
recognition technology is being used
there's being rolled out across the UK
to to track consumers and I mentioned
this Instagram has rolled out a neural
network which now looks at the
background of photos and see where
brands are and other things and they're
able to match up advertising ID with
particular photos but again it's kind of
weird I upload something and all of a
sudden it exists outside of my control
and can be crawled by by multiple
processes
I'm not gonna talk to so much about
emotional measurement measurement but
there's a number of factors so emotional
measurement at least with this example
uses at least 10 data points for frame
and we have the the vectors on the face
this is able to where there's emotional
measurement that's able to work in real
time walking through a train station and
with a twith with that with at least 8
frames per second we're able to get tell
that the mood that people are in until
this exists but how is it being used
well here's two things in the last
couple of weeks that have come out and
so we have we have a new technology that
is now being employed for CCTV CCTV
cameras but I think most interesting is
this example now Disney has a new patent
that they're gonna put an infrared
camera behind the screen to be able to
look out at you and see if you're
smiling or not so there's real time real
time analysis being done on you even
though you are paying to engage in an
entertainment product and I think this
is really interesting what are the
assumptions of once we paid for
something once a week and have been in a
consenting economic actor have we given
away our rights are we okay with buying
excusing buying a concert ticket paying
50 euros for a concert tickets but at
the same time there's drones and cameras
and watching us and tracking us and
we're using our wristbands to check in
so I think that like the agency in which
that we are able to to employ to be able
to freely exist inside of space is
actually perhaps hopefully not but maybe
diminishing so I think I'm so sorry
auntie over our identity as we move
through place in space will be more
important right now a lot of things are
fixed they're stationary we have
androids and apples that are
increasingly running more sophisticated
technology on device GPUs that then ping
back to servers but at the same time
once self-driving cars automated
vehicles come online we're going to see
more than his lidar which is the
satellite was a radar
positioning that she's were kind of the
cartography and the movement of space
but also see more images that are passed
up once Tesla or lyft or uber
incorporates more images on their their
vehicles when we're now on a street
we may get passed by four cars that all
have a photo record of us being there so
now I'm gonna talk about ten different
cities to say like to show like we we
are now in the future so New York City
is adding facial recognition and license
plate readers to its river crossings you
go from one baro baro to the next
they're gonna know who you are this is
not just street-level surveillance this
is more than that license plate readers
are are quite interesting in the sense
that you can be parked and they can know
something about it but you we cannot
maybe draw a lot of conclusions from one
particular license plate in one
particular location but through being
placed at crossroads that nexuses at
bridges we're nail now those that have
the power are able to now link up and
see how often we go where they're able
to create maps of our of our daily
commutes these sort of things
I don't know Alpert Collins here which
is the Peter teals like big data company
actually we just got into a fight with a
New York PD and so New York PD is
actually not using them as a as a
service provider anymore but let's just
say that this this is articles from to
October 7 2016 but the Palantir was
still a client of a new of New York City
so we don't know maybe if you were in
New York in the last six months Palantir
may have a record of your face but you
we don't know that another time another
bone this is an example of a vulnerable
population that is being used as a petri
dish for this technology New York City
is going to use homeless or use facial
recognition to to track homeless people
so if you don't have a home somehow
your ability to not have your image
taken is somehow decreased again back to
a social contract we don't have a
reasonable expectation of privacy
when it comes to facial recognition
technology Berlin where I live in suits
is train station there has now been a
patriarchy tension technology rolled out
on a pilot program highly controversial
but controversy and public backlash did
not stop them from doing this and Berlin
Germany is being actually a quite pricey
centric country this goes to show that
this is this is happening everywhere
Milan the Milan central train station
like has a very interesting new facial
recognition technology program but this
is not for surveillance it's actually a
new ad platform I so appetizing totems
in Milan's train station have facial
recognition in order to collect
passenger data without authorization
again going back to the different modes
of development of these technologies is
it commercial is it a commercial
development is it a national security
development is it an economic advantage
development is it something like
emergency disaster response and so
there's different ways in which this
technology is being used but as it gets
more more sophisticated it is easier for
large datasets or underlining code to be
transportable a few more Japan grants
aid to install face recognition systems
worth 3.4 million dollars and Pakistan's
airports Amsterdam not far from here
testing facial recognition and boarding
gates Australia say yo what if we didn't
have passports anymore what if your face
was your ticket again British Airways ba
is using biometric scanners for pasture
Airport check-in and the US
administration has also fast-tracked
facial recognition in airports China
China is now incorporating 600 million
CCTV cameras
it's a shit-ton of CCTV cameras there
and there's some quite interesting I
know this this story here is one of my
favorites mmm somebody's stealing the
toilet paper we could buy more toilet
paper or we can install a draconian
facial recognition system to stop these
people so for me this is one of those
things that is about how do we how our
policymakers and corporate entities
constructive constructively working to
solve problems and I feel too often the
answer is let's let technology take care
of it let's slap some AI and video
cameras on it this will do this will do
the job and it doesn't stop there
China's down testing us is using
predictive ATIS AI to stop crimes before
they happen this is literally out of
Minority Report right Ireland where a
lot of the large headquarters for for
companies are our based now driver's
license to vehicle so now faces get
automatically inputted a whole registry
can be and put it in and matched India
the the $1 program which is the new
biometric ID has anybody been following
the the case of India's new IDs right so
I find this really interesting this as
well as the currency swap when the five
ten rupee notes were were changed
overnight the Modi administration did
the largest currency swap in the history
of the world without anybody even know
it was coming
it was actually an impressive feat of
logistics and and Quran and macro micro
economic and the country didn't collapse
I mean there was it was I was blown away
when I saw the scale and size of this
currency exchange of we're taking all
these notes out of circulation tonight
and these are the new notes going in and
within a course of a few weeks those
smaller notes were no longer accepted
well I think it's interesting is because
no technologies no technology
technological advancement exists in a
vacuum it doesn't exist in a bubble
there's other factors going on around it
and so when everyone now in India 1.2
1.3 billion people now
biometric card that is essential for
them to access public services that we
that now these things become become more
pressing that the ability for those and
power to oppress those that don't agree
with them becomes more worrying so as we
hear there's a couple of case studies
from the US Oakland has all this
information from its street-level
surveillance programs and it doesn't
really know what to do with it
right before the the most recent
inauguration in January police for
surveillance cameras or we're owned
don't really know why and there's
actually been some pushback from DC
Metropolitan Police and the FBI about
actually not saying so much about this
as far as I know nobody is quite sure
who did it or hasn't publicized but we
talked about the bridges in New York
City but think about the information one
day of having being able to move
laterally through a CCTV network for a
city the size of Washington DC we're now
able to track diplomats heads of state
that are visiting other important
figures and with this sort of
information the ability of even one-day
snapshot maybe it can't tell you
everything but you're still able to
understand movements of people you're
still able to to do mapping of social
mapping and network out any of these
things and so I I think that when it
comes to the massive vast amount of
information when of still and moving
images of people there is a lot to be
done around privacy controls I call a
theory I'm working on drone buds Minh
right and um buds Minh is someone who's
responsible for a publication that's
it's the person we can think of them a
public editor right now that cities may
have data protection officers but with
drone data with CCTV camera a lot of
times these slip through the cracks and
policy becomes about information and
retention how to dispose of it but it's
not actually interrogating why all this
information is coming into a centralized
database so now let us talk about like
some other things going on
tazer which probably know from pop
culture of a non-lethal weapon they're
traditionally I guess they come in two
forms one a handheld that really gives
out an electrical charge the other have
these nodes that go out and electrocute
someone who is being shot by them but
Taser is now getting into the AI machine
learning and to visual analysis so this
really concerns me because if a police
officer is wearing a body camera and
they walk by me I broke it if a police
officer walks by me who who could what
like why I am at least in the in the
u.s. the assumption is innocent until
proven guilty um but I really feel that
we are entering this new era of a change
in this sort of and sort of this
relationship in which you are not guilty
yet no but we still want to know where
you are where you were and eventually
will get so good that we can map out
where you're going to be so they are not
the only one a lot of companies whether
it's on social media geofeedia another
or in other companies and varitone
another companies are bringing our
bringing new frameworks of processing
power of neural networks and another
machine learning to to the the tools in
which that like have what traditionally
been rolled out but have been static and
now they're we're creating a dynamic
data collection framework so talk a
little bit about this relationship right
I mean so see here that yeah that more
and more our faces are being recognized
CERN so I really found this a startling
statistic that 68 major city city
departments in the US that two-thirds of
them have body cameras worn and but a
lot of them don't we don't really know
much about them there's no transparency
around these around the way that these
tools are being used and as well what
happens to the data after the fact is
there a is there a shelf life on this
data does it get expunged overwritten at
a certain point in time are people to
sitting on what hours and two days in
two months in two years of information
that they can retroactively lis be
analyzed again the idea of like no image
is static anymore that all the images
that are captured by police video
cameras can eventually even if not yet
we don't have the technology now can at
a later date be repurposed to draw
conclusions that were technologically
available at the time so right now how
big of a problem is this it's 117
million Americans have their face in
some sort of database most don't know
there's something like 20 states I
believe in which that are now have not
put up a that have willingly put their
driver's data driver's license databases
into the federal level very little
oversight and as we've seen sometimes
democracy is pretty fucking stupid and
or at least populations in which they
vote on things are not in a position to
make an informed decision because of
propaganda or because of whatever may be
but we are holding we are putting the
fate of our faces in we put in the fate
of our faces in two institutions in
which when not may not always have our
back so again are we really still
innocent until proven guilty or are the
system's being created now really making
us guilty until proven innocent okay I
mean right now there's active
research being done in order to identify
who's guilty again some minority report
said this is even further complicated by
a few things that now seated Apple and
other companies are working on 3d
modeling on three on taking 2d images
and creating a third dimension vector to
be able to like see things project
things that might not even be captured
by the original frames we have drones
all over the world we're now now people
are working on real-time targets and
typing manifold algorithms for the
united states air force i wouldnt take
this moment to say did a lot of times
the datasets that are being used on for
these trainings are not neutral datasets
i don't even know if there is something
as an unbiased data set but that's a
different conversation 9:30 this evening
if we I think I'm gonna be talking about
proprietary algorithms I'll get into
that more then but I'm really interested
in the idea of this scalability of the
the proliferation of once this
technology is available whether it's due
for an espionage or through private
partner private public partnerships that
this technology will eventually find its
way into into ways into uncover noble
untransparent
unaccountable on a system for that
oversight right now we may be able to we
may be feel comfortable that there's a
chain of command and the US military and
if they're going to use a drone based on
some sort of image recognition
technology that there's a high enough
confidence in which these are bad people
are you know the words of the president
bad hombres right and so but we have
really very little assurance a lot has
been written around around the mass
civilian casualties at Reagan by
especially drone strikes trying to get
one high-value target but certainly blew
up 50 people at a wedding so this is
these are things that are not just no
longer science fiction they're actively
being deployed in battlefields but they
won't stop there so as I mentioned
earlier this is one of the things that I
think that I
that I think we need more and more
discussion more of a broader
conversation about and this is the
ability of a single device with very
little with very little connection to a
central server to you know server farm
to be able to perform a more and more
advanced sophisticated technology on the
device itself there are GPUs that are
now rolled out that are able to perform
some degree of neural network that
really takes the burden away from the
processing on at home base at
headquarters of the server so as more
and more work can be done on our devices
themselves it actually decreases the
processing load on the server side and I
think that this is also quite
interesting in the sense that the
miniaturization of these technology is
also a threat vector in and of itself
that no longer you need massive teraflop
to run all these things if you can in
front load this computing on the on the
device itself and by the time it gets to
to server to the database that like it
there's already inferences drawn a cafe
to from Facebook is is yeah they've open
sourced that recently so this is out
there yeah Google is doing it as well so
what is a little remix now and say that
right now seeing is believing in some
ways I'd say that's right now we see an
image and we don't necessarily were not
necessarily skeptical of it but very
soon very very soon I believe that we
are going to have to question more and
more about the images that we see this
double asian ship between us and our
technology and what does it look like to
trust an image soon our eyes may lie to
us The Economist wrote a really
interesting piece about this a couple of
weeks ago well I guess last month July
first was published but kind of went
into the actually
was ticking uh kiss me julian assange
and saying that you know how do we know
that one person is who they say they are
what are the what are the resolution
what is the pixel resolution that we
need in order to ensure that what we're
seeing has not been manufactured has not
been doctored doesn't have a vector
layer on top of it that is looks like
somebody saying something but is in fact
not this goes hand in hand with the idea
of like after one image as we get more
precise about tagging and indexing and
even creating metadata around images
machines don't no longer or needing less
and less training data in order to
quantify characteristics if not state in
a human readable form what something is
this is interesting and there's some
interesting work being done on satellite
images and comparing a comparative
analysis between time frames so maybe
before of flood and after a flood but
more and more automated systems are
going on to match up and see where to
see what has changed and so we're
getting we're doing this from you know
from low-earth orbits but at the same
time these same technologies are able to
be will probably eventually be able to
rolled out and things like CCTV cameras
I mentioned this like now we don't
actually have to see how they're a whole
face seen via system maybe just a
profile of you now the yeah that the
iPhone is now working and I think that
iPhone 8 will even have more
sophisticated technology to be able to
render and re-render people's faces
based on a incomplete sample so I think
this kind of gets to to what I really
want to kind of get it crosses the
emergence Ocracoke the emergent social
contract that has been forged between us
and our technology is under is operating
under asymmetric pretenses that my
relationship to technology is not the
same as technology's relationship to me
that our physical bodies have a contract
attack
even if we don't know it and this is the
this comes in the form of captured
images the services rendered locations
but we're never really able to peer
inside and see the technology that sees
us so quickly who is developing a lot of
this out on the private side
Marvel in China face plus plus flipper
which is a which is augmented reality
but it's also using facial yeah also
facial recognition technology and fine
face which is creepy as fuck fine face
uses the VK the large Facebook clone in
Russia and it has been used to basically
identify so the the two male cofounders
basically said in their part of their
marketing scheme you can take a photo of
anybody run it through our system and
then you can find the profile of that
cute girl that you saw at the bar and
discover what she didn't do it's really
creepy and if we look at two if we look
at these how these how these facial
recognition the real-time face
recognition is being marketed people are
smiling and it's it's women like here
ooo this is something like this is
interesting but there's very much a what
I feel is a a phenomenon which is
unhealthy that there are males there are
tech bros if you will designing
technology rolling out marketing
strategies and but it's not getting
people the chance to say hey maybe I
don't want to be in this system just
because I have a VK profile or maybe
just because I have a Facebook profile
does not mean that I've consented to be
discoverable in public but this
technology rolls on there's some really
interesting stuff going on with facial
recognition when it cut image
recognition in the human body automated
dermatologists superhuman vision these
sort of things this was going to the
points I was saying that like
there is real-world replication bias or
that that the the bias that occurs in
real life also has a knock-on effect and
has a replication a bias inside of our
technologies if we have no black people
if we have no people from of we have no
women inside of a database that it is
going to be less and less precise
without less training data but who's
investigating who who are our data
interrogators who are our data
ethnographers currently I I exist that
we don't have we have not built these
these roles into a technological
development cycle that we have to do
more as as activists and as I understood
think about like how do we inject a
stronger stronger safeguards into into
these systems but as well how do we make
sure that the data that we're using -
for testing and for training is as
objective as it can be so there are some
things that we really as more and more
glasses and patterns come online there
are some really interesting ways to
resist Silicon Valley has been a little
more open to the idea of of of bringing
philosophers into into the loop but that
the consequences of failure so the
replication of historical inequalities
the undermining of democratic and
judicial institutions profit
maximization as the basis of future
technological developments amplification
of agloe jewel global technological
hegemony that is able to rival
nation-states the removal of humans as
the primary decision-making force and
the proliferation of lethal autonomous
weapon systems laws so I just have a
couple slides left and open them for a
couple minutes a quick Q&A but if
anybody has any questions and start
thinking about them now so some things
around just these are I would not say
these are like my thesis do to combat
these sort of things but more more food
for thoughts that we have to do more in
the due diligence of diversity we need
to bring more people and more
backgrounds into the decision-making
to turn a critical eye onto the systems
that are being created
do we want technology to follow
something like the Hippocratic oath
that's using medicine to do no harm
do we want to still do distill into the
technological DNA of machines to not to
not kill to not do harm what about the
Magna Carta as a defining character as a
defining as something to build the
theoretical technology on do we want the
idea of that you in order to be found
guilty that somebody that a judge has to
find you guilty and what about the new
valuation system how do we put a value
on this technology when advertising and
surveillance have their own revenue
streams what does it mean how do we put
humans back at the center of the
equation so if we're gonna if humans are
going to be out of the loop which I hope
they will not be but the introduction of
digital imaging into AI has brought
about a new type of a relationship it
the proprietary nature which I'm most
scared about but even when it comes to
open source is very difficult to
sometimes audit code but even taking
proprietary AI that uses our images to
formulate opinions about us to drive
that tries to nudge and drive our habits
and define our identity if a state did
this if in a state structure we will
probably be up in arms but because this
has happened under the surface because
we don't see this now it's not this is
not front page headlines this is not
protests in the street and so unless we
can create a new way to give humans the
capacity to have sovereign power over
their image the social contract of the
future will not be negotiated with a
unified entity but with a multiplicity
of for-profit technology that are
oftentimes non-state actors so in a few
years if we have Amazon drunk drones
flying overhead and we have Tesla's
lifts and ubers all driving by and we're
in the backgrounds of selfies both on
iPhones Androids being uploaded to
Facebook and Instagram these are what I
all is up it is what I call a private
distributed privatized governance
framework which for me to have to try to
get any one record a sponge to
arbitrates that I saying I don't want
this image in your database I can't just
I can't negotiate with technology in
general I have to initiate if I can and
even now there's not any solid way to do
this negotiate with each of these
different corporate actors and I find
that very problematic and something that
I think that we have to elevate as far
as our calls to a more open and
transparent technological future we have
to reevaluate what we feel comfortable
with when it comes to this social
contract all right well that's all I
have if anybody has any questions I
think we have a couple of minutes still
questions comments thoughts no first of
all thank you scary but quite
interesting well let me say that I do I
do believe that we can make a better
future I am not jaded I think that
although the powers of the world that
companies with half a trillion dollar
market capitalizations and nation states
that have the capacity to end all human
life
these are big challenges but I'm not
resigned to the fact that this is going
to be the 21st century and I think
together working on philosophical and
ethical frameworks the idea about what
did what level are we comfortable with
enforcement being able to mandate
transparency inside of proprietary
algorithms is going to be a large
conversation but it's something we have
to start now please line up let them
please line up at the microphones
hey thank you great talk miss beginning
of it but then again I'm also in this
field and I know a lot of things you
talked about and it's funny to see
someone usually I'm on stage saying this
and now it's someone else that's really
interesting but about what that'll dead
to me was to give some feedback which
was you say that the human is out of the
loop but what I found is that the
Scrabble is it's math washing is that
the human is not really gone it's just
hidden right is these algorithms are
designed by people who are to a degree
self learning but also to a degree
designed by which data goes in so these
they're not really gone they're just
hidden so if in that sense we are still
accountable humans can still be held
accountable to that and we could still
yeah so they're they're still agreed I'd
say like two things on that one I think
it's interesting if we're looking at the
causal really at technology on a on a
corne illogical a time axis there are
humans that are intermediary dispersed
so we have the coders and the
programmers those who deploy these
systems people that are used checking in
to like see what information they wants
whether it's police you know body
cameras or whatever but I think that
once this technology gets out into the
wild that the human capacity decreases
because of the automated dashboards now
now I mean these geofeedia and these
other social monitors or social media
monitoring platforms are kind of that
pretty much very limited training is
required now to use these very
sophisticated platforms so I am NOT
saying that humans are completely out of
the loop but at the same time we're
making more and more user-friendly tools
that decrease the amount of
technological know-how to use them and
they're able to also exports I mean we
talk about the Wassenaar and like
malware you know like cyber weapon
malware research and and export licenses
but that's mostly kind of on though the
digital munitions sort of side of things
but what's to stop a company in the u.s.
or China from exporting a very powerful
a facial recognition platform that
requires that already is there in a
dashboard and you just click
our target and whatever so I I think
that I absolutely agree but I think that
as technology were actually it's with
these systems are being designed for
people that are not technologically
advanced secondly I I worry that if we
have not built in kind of benchmarks in
which that data has to be erased that
information has to be reviewed that the
mass accumulation of information inside
of inside of servers has a couple of
drawbacks one it's vulnerable to being
compromised what happens if I with the
OPM hack in the u.s. what happens if a
massive New York City database gets gets
hacked and now state an apt like now is
able to do their own mapping and so I
think that while there's still room for
humans in the loop humans have been
deprioritized and now Israel China and
Russia are all developing autonomous
weapons platforms that need no human
interaction and if this is based on
facial recognition targeting systems I
find this that next level of problematic
in which that you don't even have to
push nobody has to push a button anymore
and I hope that you didn't get mixed up
is somebody else at least in the US
military chain of command there's quite
robust I mean it's not perfect and they
they're really bad at what they do but
with the civilian casualties that are
caused around its but there's now
actively by nation-states working to
create systems that further bring humans
out of the loop I I definitely agree but
I think that we are able to
institutionalize we can kind of in a
social contract way what we expect
technology to how would we expect it to
be accountable not just to those who
make it or deploy it but to the people
that it inadvertently captures along the
way I think we're just talking about
different levels of the the question
where I'm talking about the design phase
or where there's a lot of possibility
for accountability and I understand also
that in the user face that it becomes
more opaque well I think the you the the
development phase is where really
problem we can make the largest amount
of impact once it's in the wild it's
very hard to recall these things but if
we think more about something idea of a
ethnography whywhy does Facebook not you
know when they're you think their role I
know maybe things are dictated by the
policy teams or the global standards
teams but what about yeah the data
investigator to what like how and as
we're combining these databases or
building them on top of each other we're
maybe the columns fits ok well that's
that but what does it mean if for
example New York City stop and frisk if
you were to take this data and pull add
in I have King Crawford and because they
know I've talked to a bit about this if
you were just rely on something like New
York City crime statistics you might see
oh wow
actually young men of color are
exponentially more likely to have a
weapon or drugs on them but if you don't
wait for the idea of stop and frisk this
law that give the gave police officers
the ability to go up to anybody
suspicious and Pat them down then we're
not properly waiting for the truth at
the way that though that the cultural
biases have replicated into the digital
form so I think that it's important that
we start thinking okay well what does it
mean to be a data philosopher or a data
ethnographer a data an interrogator and
and to me this is like where we need
more diversity of humanities and other
fields into STEM fields in order to make
it a much more rounded yeah Bible knows
ones s course I've got a second one if
the second question is our nuance would
be that a lot of these things are very
based on the American examples right but
in the Europe there are currently
stronger protections as to for example
what counts as a private piece of data
and what counts as a identifiable
information information so perhaps
that's a good or hopeful part of it is
that in Italy in Europe there seems to
be some degree of in the first like a
fine phase could not happen in Europe
that would not be okay and so that might
be I mean I think will be interesting to
see the final form of the GDP are the
idea even with the right to be right to
an explanation I think the way that this
comes out in case law and
court rulings is gonna be quite
interesting and consequential a union
like Europe that has that is a major
economic market for for these companies
really I think has to be a leader the US
has no political capital there's this
revolving door between the Washington
and Silicon Valley and the corporate
capture is really quite startling other
places but China and India are now
becoming a surveillance state so I think
that Europe is kind of you know help us
EU you're our only hope but I think that
things like the right to explanation and
once we get into the the Devils in the
details
to what degree do our there is is as a
judge or a panel or you know European
Court of Human Rights or just as what is
the case what is the test case and so I
think this is actually a I mean I guess
I'm now advocating for strategic
litigation that now we need to start
thinking about the ways that we're going
to use the impending especially GTR but
other but other things and and taking
cases from other case law and things how
are we going to as activists and as
anchors how are we going to frame these
issues I think the e FF and access and
there's some organizations that are
working on these things in the larger
level and their respective fields but
for me though I think that we now need
to be thinking about senior expanding
the next two to three to five years of
strategic litigation strategic
litigation targeted advocacy strategic
lobbing how are we going to like push
this over to make sure that the right to
explanation which I think is
particularly practical or applicable
here
because if if decisions are made about
you using only your face and an
automated you know way that this gives
maybe there's somebody that's standing
in order to bring a case and there's
other things in it but I find that it is
now the time that we need to start
talking about how do we use the
progressive policies that Europe is
rolling out in a way that ensures and
it's actually in kind of corners
technology companies too if they're
gonna roll this out in Europe maybe it's
easier it gives them cover to roll it
out with protections globally
very hopeful about is that if I hope
about is that I'm starting to see that
this field this market is well they have
to have to use what occur for example
there was a two weeks ago there was some
news about people who got a physical
mail like you know through the letterbox
about the skin condition they had and
they'd only looked it up on the Internet
so the connection was that there was are
now companies that will connect your the
online anonymous browser with the real
person who is near where they live and
then and they are now sending those
mails so at the point there is that
people will start to see this invisible
thing because they will start to get
targeted quite rigorously and then they
will hopefully awake get awakened and my
personal hope is that as the market for
as people of gamma Karev this there will
be a growing market for privacy
enhancing technologies that you know
protect them in any way or that this
debate will come in next ten years the
the first example died a similar that
was target the supermarket kind of a
household goods store in the US was one
of the first companies to run like a
pretty comprehensive data analysis on
his customers trying to find patterns
and and they found that and their large
case around this was when somebody got
coupons for baby diapers they did not
even know they were pregnant but they
had run the Diagnostics on a big data
scale to be able to like identify who
was shopping who is in these trends and
so it's only when it kind of into excuse
me when only when it kind of enters into
our world we get like wait how do they
know something I don't know and I think
that this is again part of this social
contract
we have our original instance that were
captured we have who we are now and a
lot of times we're throughout two right
now I think we've been seeing these two
points me now and me then as there's
relationship but the ability to
extrapolate and forecast information
about these relationships and to be able
to predict what we're gonna do tomorrow
this is something that I hope there will
be some sensational stories because
otherwise I think for enough people that
we'll be able to pass under the radar
but it's a very but I think this really
does what it comes down to with this all
this information
not just about what we're doing but
gives them the power to predict or we're
going to do tomorrow and not just
predict but by quantifying our identity
as a user nani user subscriber non user
it puts us in a box which ultimately
enables them to put hindrances and
burdens in our path to influence our
agency and this is really I think for me
one of the things that we are slowly
ceding our individual agency our
personal sovereignty to corporations and
other interests when we don't even know
that they were involved in our
decision-making process thank you thank
you very much as you said you have
another talk later on that goes I think
a bit more into the algorithm side of
those things so if you are interested
it's in 925 @re
or PA the other not up here look it up
look up so speed up car so please one
more thanks for speaker
Matthew stand down
[Applause]
[Music]