[Music]
there's also quite a few nerdy sports
like real-life Quidditch or Segway polo
but it's also really cool sport that's
kind of nerdy but also quite educational
and quite a lot of fun I've been told
so now you know Oliviero will tell us
all about this capture the flag please
give a big applause for him
[Applause]
hello folks first thank you for so much
for joining me in this talk so as I was
introduced it we're gonna talk about CTF
and the main reason why we're talking
about CTF so this is this is the
motivation behind this this talk is
about how why play city herbs so just a
little bit about me
my name is Bruno Gonsalves Oliveira I'm
Brazilian if that matters I have
master's degree in software engineering
I'm a computer engineer I'm a sinner
Security Council - at first waves of
spider labs I have some certs I have
done some talks in some places and it
may be the most important here I'm the
goony CTF player so you must think about
well I'm not
I'll it X or hacker or whatever you can
call I'm not that guy so we'll see here
just a motivation behind what brought me
to this area let's say that but a lot of
you can talk but you know there are some
discussions related to the penetration
tester - CTF players - white hat guys
black cap guys and
one thing that they will say that the
CTF player think they think himself
about being an ultra hacker or just
because he got a hundred points on the
CTL the DEFCON CTF or something like
that so though that's not the case you
know what I want to show you it's much
more than these as much more than points
is much more then of course technical
stuff is the base of everything that
we're going to say here but I don't I
don't want to show you some cutting-edge
technique or anything like that it's
just why I got to this area and I got so
excited so when you're talking about my
motivations so you know after ten years
doing penetration test things starts to
get boring let's put this word well it's
always saying it's not like all the same
it's a cool job I love my job but you
know after ten years you got limited
time for doing stuff you usually got the
same thing well if you think about we
got lame passwords we got some usual
unpaid stuff we got I don't know we got
poisoning in the past we got our
poisoning now we got the LA I mean our
poisoning and stuff so you know it's all
basically the same and if you think
about we got some as I said that there
are those certifications like OSCE or
SCP front of a sip security it's it's
good from what we have nowadays you know
but it's not even close from water CTF
can teach you so that's why I got this
excitement you know so that's why I I
wanted to you know to explain this
should talk about this because I think a
lot of people got some you know maybe
borings not all the same even on
offensive security
in mostly on penetration test because on
penetration test is all not always but
it's very superficial you know you don't
go much deeper on their own software
exploitation on finding vulnerabilities
on by your hand so when you got a chance
for example to try a new a new technique
I I will show you this later but for
example a new venerable each that came
out or a new type of exploitation that
somebody just published it on somewhere
else and you've got the opportunity to
test that that's that's really good
really great because you can you can
take these new technologies new
knowledge in in apply because well I
always say that I sting says said that
the the only knowledge comes from the
experience in I totally agree so if you
take a book and start reading about
overflows reading about you know
assembly or whatever it's not the same
you know everybody knows here I think so
so it's not the same so when you have
the opportunity to test whatever you are
learning in a real-life environment that
will change you
that's my bad so now one thing very
interesting that I would like to say
about this it's like when I was maybe
fifteen years ago or seventeen years ago
when I was a teenager very excited about
learning buying books etc this kind of
you know I use I use this word a lot
today that's because I don't I don't
know any other word that works perfectly
in this case but excitement you know to
learn and this is the good thing about
it so you get all these new stuff we got
back and I'm and now I can say that I
I'm back like I'm 17 years old
I'm buying books I'm learning I'm
talking to people I'm trying to figure
it out stuffs so this is the cool thing
about this so that's the real cool
that's the real motivation behind this
talk it's all that I said now so I hope
you get something and enjoy so what do
you see here what is the city F why but
why right why you're gonna play this why
you're going to spend so a lot of times
doing this where how cool is it how can
I start and of course I'm going to show
you some stuff for example what I'm
gonna show you in the technical stuff
about it
it's not as I said it's not a
cutting-edge technique but it's not very
common so this is the world it's not
common to see so in an environment that
for example as as me doing a penetration
test a lot of stuff to check out before
doing something that's new because I
have 60 hours for doing the job so I
have to chew hack the network before
that so if I gonna try I always say that
I take a lot of time doing this and my
wife is here to chew to make me not lie
I spend a lot of times doing a lot of
time so I try to learn and all this
excitement comes back so what is it
through the flag well our hacking games
involving a lot of stuff so it's
basically in the end you have to find
some plane test test a flag in something
well or in a system or in an application
or hidden in a in a file so it's
basically like that we are they are
running some CTF right now so it's
probably like this so what are what is
what are they say I've heard about so
it's most forensics crypto web
exploitation reverse engineering and
low-level exploitation so how we get it
started
so these are some CTF that it's started
very easy but do you see the cool thing
about this that maybe when you want to
take a look at and try some the first
web application that were seeing you see
that's not it's not very usual because
it's the cool thing about staff is not
very straight Oh everything's not very
straight so you always have to take a
look out of the box think about are the
dogs to have an idea on what's going on
this is probably the main site that you
have all information about CTF so you
have all the CTF organizers the CTF
teams the write-ups and the scale going
so if you want to know anything about
CTF
it's there so you can take a look on CTF
time dot org you can see the team you
can see the score so the cool thing you
can see all the score and this score is
an anvil so you can see who-who is I had
you who is behind and which staff they
are playing etc it's a very organized
site
so what you can expect in a in a CTF as
I just but you can expect new
vulnerabilities as I said so something
that just happened you see there so in a
well we are we are we are talking about
good cities right so just to make clear
so maybe something that's just published
and you see there's a there's a
challenge there that are that is talking
about it so that's the cool thing
however there are
all the techniques - I will talk about
this later
so as I said before there are new
techniques so maybe a new hip
exploitation on Chrome or whatever they
apply on the on somewhere on someone
else and you have to to use it there or
there is a new protection of memory for
example I think I'll put on inside but
for example the Intel put or when I put
the shadow stack so it happened out like
I don't know maybe last year or
something
I like the shadow stack and you can
apply this technique and what the people
are doing - should bypass this and
applying the real life so but old - and
all the school and I I said why why all
the school well in our area it's very
easy to to see people trying or running
joining this offensive security stuff
you know it's very popular
it's very hype to be a hacker a hacker
so they won't do that so but now well
when I started 17 years ago we don't
have we didn't have so much information
we have in what information we had in
the past it was usually good normally it
was good but now you have a lot of
people talking about a lot of you know
so you see a lot of information that
maybe bypass the basics for example they
don't know they three went way handshake
in TCP but when a hacker I don't know
web browser
they are fuzzing stuff you know so when
you learn the basics on low-level
exploitation for example there are paper
for there a paper about the hip
exploitation that's very famous a house
of God house of everything I forgot the
name of the paper just because I'm
nervous
not because I
don't know exactly so this paper was
published and then in the next one
someone this guy published this this guy
never came up to see to suppose to say
that he did this this paper
his nickname is Fantasma phantasmal
phantasmagoria maybe he's here so and
the next one they publish it someone he
didn't put any proof of concept of his
techniques just the techniques in the
next Freck someone published the malleus
Maleficarum right so in this paper there
are parks and etcetera this it's a very
nice paper to read so if you wanna join
their low levitation it's the basics you
know so that's why old things are cool
too because we need to we need to
understand the basics before anything so
as I said before new vulnerabilities
less last year was really some fun
ability double you get and one month
later or in the same week I don't know
there was the second inside 2016 and
there was this one ability to exploit so
you know you can try that's that's the
thing that's the cool thing about it
yeah
you just saw the pub the paper and you
can apply your knowledge or try to
exploit which losing this knowledge
that's cool I was talking about the
shadow stack so in Tokyo westerns MMH
2016 there was a challenge about this
and what's very nice it's just you know
so you have all this information that
you can get from these challenges and
apply in any learn you know well I put
some let's say tips here and how to get
started on this area on games so
forgetting styling exploitation you
mostly need a web server to monitor
requests and burp well you can crawl you
can brute force you can check it the
requests and responses live right so
this is a cool thing headers it set for
a cookies so you when you were talk I'm
not as I said before I'm not an expert
in nothing Soho but if you wanna when
you're talking about web we have a lot
of stuff to do and as we see on web
exploitation challenge we must see some
restrictions for example this is some
few challenge during the web
exploitation so we have histories of
space so and you can use that for
example you have removed a common
execution but you can use this way CH
bypass the space filter you have precise
scripting cross-site scripting is
probably the most fun because there are
a lot of stuffs that you can do if
cross-site scripting and is not just for
the alert so when you're doing a
penetration test maybe I just I'm just
take the proof of concept on alert and
it's good to go you know but there if
you wanna work if you wanna see the flag
you have to go ahead ask a SQL injection
well this is not work sorry
so you need something else and there are
a lot of restrictions shoe I didn't put
here but if you if you take a look on
SQL injections challenge that really
isn't in the past you have some idea
file uploads well this is well I see I
saw some people in like I know last week
about the PayPal compromising in the bug
bug about stuff did you read that so
basically the guy said that when you see
a file upload a penetration tester
always shakes you know because
something's there you know if it's not
well configured something's there in and
something's direct you and look at file
include when they talk about local file
including you may be checking dot dot
slash dot dot slash but the most
commonly thing that you can do with a
local file include in a challenge is
using PHP wrappers so this is just for
example for this will convert the source
code of upload dot PHP and you show
encoded in base64 and then you have all
the source code so this is very common
to seeing in a penetrating a penetration
test but in in a challenge from city
apps so what I can say about exploit a
web exploitations about this but of
course there are a lot of stores a lot
of stuff going on and if you were
involved in if you like web exploitation
and you never played simplify at CTF
before you love it because there are a
lot of ways and things should do and
things that you learn and that's the
important thing here that you learn and
even if you know this is stuff I say I'd
say share so someone said before share
is scaring share is scare so this is the
stuff so why not just publish now I'll
write up telling how you did it and any
sheriff the community you know somebody
else can take this information and learn
something from there
so it's not just about learn but it's
about teach chew and I have to say I got
a start on this area really raw
on the low-level exploitation and I have
good friends behind me on the team that
I didn't know but I was invited to the
team I started playing and you guys were
like really rock stars on a little heavy
exploitation and I really sing me it you
know they helped me a lot and when you
if you join a team for example just for
playing or for learning teaching
whatever you have it's good to have
somebody else for take you in this
journey you know it's really hard to
learn by by ourselves because as I said
before the information now we have so
much information about a lot of stuff
and this makes everything harder because
we don't know what information we can
trust and how is reading etc ever
everything involves that so about
reverse engineering some essential tools
well it's the same ler Ida Pro basic I
really like binary ninja harder issues
just for elite people I'm not very usage
we've had there and but it of course is
a really powerful tool and really
necessary for if you understand that
that to you you be good and of course
the bugger etc I put there already BG
windbg gdb just to make examples but one
thing that I you say in the final it's
that we don't have so many linux windows
exploitation or reverse so that's a
shame we know I forgot the the CTF that
I was playing before and someone put
Windows challenge with really high
points and in the description said don't
be afraid of this we
those environment we put a lot of points
just because it's our windows you know
and if you take a looking who solve it
this challenge just few teams just
because well we have to normally have to
put an environment like you know install
new windows or whatever so maybe this is
the an issue for doing the the challenge
in not now but now is is being very used
it's being used it a lot it's symbolic
execution well if you take a look about
symbol a symbolic execution it's about
running the application with symbolic
inputs so what what does it mean it
means that you don't know whatever you
are inputting you are trying to solve
constraints in the execution flow in our
case here this this symbolic execution
it's a term that is use it it's very
it's highly used in the soft engineering
but it's now being applied a lot on the
on the security and it's about it so I
it's not here well but it's simple it's
you have to go in a way you have two
ways for going or maybe ten or maybe a
hundred ways for an execution so if you
open an Ida Pro in an open an
application you see a lot of jumps and
this jumps go to different places so
what happens if you go there and you can
imagine an application that there is I
don't know maybe for a menu and there's
something hitting there and you have to
put a big number or a special world to
go into this jump so this will help you
to solve this constraints on the
software we have a lot of framework
going on and in these two is really
awesome so I'm gonna show you real fast
but if you wanna take a look at this
later
so of course reverse engineer is all
about family you have to take a look on
data functions and jumps so no no
mystery here so this is just a sample
right here we have this function that
creates a key and there we have
something else and you never go there in
this case so here the the challenge was
solved just patching the binary from jab
not equal to jump so a little simple
stuff but there's in the past was a lot
of using in the crack is that when
you're cracking some software this is
highly using just patching a jump or one
or two and you're good to go so this
this is one challenge this was one
challenge so I I wanted to put some
sample here so we're talking about this
this challenge from Google CTF from last
year unbreakable so it's it's a tool
that you have to put the key the right
key there to generate a valid product
key so you have to put a password or
whatever and then you generate a key for
you so if you put there something like
that you have the you have some failure
message etc however if you go here and
take a look on the code so here it's
open with the binary ninja and if go
ahead you see the function let's call it
when the products the the activation
failures and then so not here we have
the function in the end 50 and we have
the when the when these functions
colleges because the project was
activated Sousa fully so we have two
functions that you can easily see when
you disable the this software so here
are just a simple code using angry and
this is all it's pretty much all the
code that you can you'll have to use so
you put find where you want to to be so
where is your thank you or your keys
here which function you you want to
avoid and this is the author I didn't do
this one so this is the author so it's
pretty much that you have to execute you
say that's an argument and after it is
you run the code and you got the day
King so you can see that it's a it's a
it's very cool because it just made some
twist on the reverse engineering stuff
because you can just put whatever you
want and where you want choose acute and
try to find a way should be there this
is there's no verbose message here but
when you put that into your code you see
a lot of a things what they're what it's
attempting in whatever just to get to
the message so this is it about the I
just wanted to put about some sample
from using symbolic execution because
it's being used it a lot actually a
plugging that one that's like plugging
of the year from NIDA Pro last year was
a very cool plug-in using symbolic
execution and it's all click it I want
to hear
I wanna hear make it for me so it's
ridiculous so if you if you are
interested own reverse engineer just
take a look on this - I just forgot the
name as well pom pom same let's go
that's that's true so it's bouncy so
take a look if you are curious about it
so if you want to get it started on
low-level exploitation some essential
tools gdb of course I always say that
gdb it's the the first time that I saw
gdb in my life said how people do it
it's like it's disgusting
you don't have anything it's very very
hard to see stuff but now we got some
better interface that you can use as gif
and by the way this guy that made gaff
it's in our team he's really awesome so
and this tool is really really awesome
really really awesome you can you can
monitor requests for example it just
understands if he can be a user after
free it's very cool take a look and of
course I'd assembler as well in this
case binary ninja hidari - if you're not
familiar with bound tools and you when I
join and I'm gonna start with this thing
you should take it
it's a Excel II before Python that you
have a lot of handy stuffs for doing
exploitation so after exploitation so
it's in numerous you have a lot of
stuffs there so if you are doing if
you're when I joined a little
exploitation take a look at this and
you'll be happy so when you're getting
started what you should see well first
thing check for which architecture is
compiling the binary feeds there
- Oh 64 bits secured check if has PI a
relocation with only SLR it's always its
defu so you always have the the
libraries being handle mizen in the
memory it's by the foo so I didn't see
any any any challenge that you didn't
have SLR enabled so then you have PI you
have real location with only you have
Canaries and you have NX and no is
equitable so no is equitable it's pretty
much you know but it may be you see in
some in some challenge that are not a
now a it's not enable when it's not
enabled it's probably because you have
to create some special shell code for
that you have to being smart you have to
be creative with you to create your
alphanumeric e with 50 50 bytes or 40
bytes or 30 bytes I don't know and
that's good stuff so when you're
checking that you you you have an idea
on what you're dealing and maybe so
enabled and maybe it's not maybe it's
just 1 or 2 etc so what are the inputs
this is a very important stuff so you
should locate where you can put some
data maybe you have to jump around to
get something executed maybe you have to
combine two inputs should get an
overflow enough by one for example so
where you can put the data it's very
important you of course check the
problematic functions before anything
check that if you have if you have a
string copy or if F gets or something
like that
probably the they starter the start
problem is there
so you have to take a look and of course
for dealing with heap check the memory
allocations and see if you are writing
data in the same memory allocation or
[Music]
whatever check what is doing now we have
the stack lash are you are you are you
familiar with this tech class technique
that was launched at one month ago so
basically it's when you get the stack
overridden by the the heap or the other
way around so a very cool paper by the
way and keys of course this is well not
common maybe in some entry-level stuff
maybe you have to trick sploit x3 copy
you have to do a summer reverse
engineering see that there is a key that
you need to put in the first input for
getting to the second put etc so about
the memory allocation so when you see
mostly all the the heap challenge you
have to define some length how many
words you put there or how many sub
allocation will you be there so this is
very important when you're talking about
memory allocations so this is another
another sample that I want to put here
it's a file extreme point overflow
that's found on the cedar file
challenge on pound Abel so this this is
spawn about this spawn able stuff is not
it's like it's open every day so if you
want to enjoin there now you you can
create you have a lot of cool challenge
they're really related to little heavy
exploitation none was preview none even
the first one is not not that trivial so
that's cool so you see that so if you're
familiar with this technique this is not
it's not a very common technique you
if you if you look for this information
if you look like this finally spring
point or overflow you see something like
you you see something there you know but
if you don't know what you're looking
for so for example in this case well
I'll show you
so in this case we have only the noise a
quotable enable in the hell location
read-only was just special so if you're
able to overwrite the god the global of
set tables you were able to do it
because they are real location with only
it's just partial but it's not the case
as well so here is the software it's a
very simple software you can open read
write to the screen and close and then
you go out so the first time that I saw
that I saw well you can open a file in
the system so if you are familiar with a
low-level citation in modern computers
or anything like that you see that the
first thing when you don't have you're
not able to write a shellcode or you
don't have any space that is as a
cutable memory you have to use Rob
payloads so when you use Rob payloads
you need well this is not what I would
say but the thing here is that you can
open read any file and you need a leak
from the system to use the library see
for example when you're talking about
the unique stuff so you need a leak you
need you need somewhere that's leaking
an address from library C then you take
the base and then you find whatever
function you want a cow and then exploit
so in this case a file in the system
when I when I there's a file in the
system when the software is running that
it's proc self or proc the number of the
PID maps and this file
leaks the addresses including the
library in this case you wouldn't be
able to see in the first time they
address they base the address just
because there's a limited number of
bytes that's being shown
however they the file is never closed
when you open that you have to close so
if you read one more time you get the
second the second part of this byte so
the file will be the files will be split
in for example I don't know if have I
don't remember maybe it's 40 bytes you
have like 40 bytes each time that you
are reading so think about that I always
say that when you solve a challenge it's
very easy after all after solvent
everything is easy when you're doing
it's very hard so keep that in mind
because sometimes you want to show that
stuff and you show very straight for
example in a penetration test when
you're showing in your report you don't
really show your attempts you really you
just show your way for doing it and
somebody may be somebody that's not
related to the to the area Kim take a
look see that was easy you know he found
a Microsoft SQL with a CA with no pass
well you found that but you find after
scanning I don't know may 2000 computers
and in a port in a very different part
so that's one thing that you keep in
mind after you saw the after you see the
the write-up so whatever you're you're
you're doing it's very easy trust me
I spend a lot of times on this one then
well you've got that so if you
I read one more - one time I read one
more time and then I put on the screen
and then I get the lips eBay's you know
you can see there so this is very
important normally they will provide you
the lip see that they are using because
they offset from the functions are
different or in the other way they want
one day when they want you certainly
will know that an address of puts an
address of another function and the
difference between these functions King
led you to discover the the library see
so this is one thing so then we have the
leak so now we have to find Devon
ability because in this in this
challenge the leaking was not really the
problem but in the most of challenge it
is the leaking is part of the problem so
not in this one so here we have F scam I
scan F and a half close there so we know
that can have its dangerous in this time
I I can overwrite the F closed argument
in this section in this in this software
so what I can do from there so that's
the point this was very easy you should
take a look you go ahead and open a file
try a billion bytes and then you go to
really try a billion bytes you know
every space that you have to put bytes
put it and and and try it so in this
case was in the asset menu when you put
along a long input you overwrite the F
close so from there after spending some
few days I mean I think so I don't know
I discovered that so when you're closing
a file
you have a file a file structure in the
in the memory that contains mostly where
the date on the file is and some headers
and some stuff from this trans file and
a lot of stuff in one of these stuff
it's called IO file jumps if you take a
look in a file structure in a memory you
see all these extra Chur and it's
calling in the end they structural IO IO
file jumps
these this file jumps it's a functioning
in library C so what you can do from
there if we overwrite this function what
we get it so what we should do well we
leak at the library so we're good we
know where the library is
so we find the system this is the way
that you find so this is the offset so
this is the library seat provided by the
challenge and I try to find system and
this is the number of bikes more that
you need to it should do the math after
the the base library C so when you got
this so in this case I don't know you
can just do the math just that address
plus this address and you got the system
function so I create a file structure in
memory and I put a system as IO file
jumps so here as I we don't have PI
enable so sorry I keep I can be here so
there it's where the data is so after
after you're debugging you see that this
data there will be allocating memory our
own zone desire is that this address
then we got in the end instead of the IO
file jumps we have a system
so we have we are calling the system
function instead they file jumps and in
this in this in this place normally is
the header of the file structure that
starts with F bad or something so in
this case this this data will be
allocated exactly on SP plus four bytes
and when you check that you see so what
we did here we create we we trigger the
overflow and then we can overwrite the
address that we are that we will be
using the nav close so this address is
this address just just below the 30g
ways then we got the a file structure so
this is the phallic structure that
you're dealing they did realize lines
and our file structure sets that our iio
file jumps it's a system and our and the
argument for the for this is the slash
bin slash bash so in the end you get is
a cuted and you got a shout so this is
what I was talking about well we need to
this information was very helpful to me
to understand a lot of stuff it may be
just giving a talk fast like this you
don't don't get the point it's not it's
not getting the flag for me it's not
just getting the flag which is it's
trying to understand what I don't know
and this was a case like this I didn't
know about this kind of overflow I
didn't know how to to exploit this stuff
and I learned some cons about the CTF
guessing so in a lot of city FC you have
some gas
seeing stuff so something that's not
technical you have to guess
well it's not my thing and most affirmed
the most of the CTF players - so that's
not the thing I like in nobody likes
actual as I said before a 99% of the
it's Linux for exploitation so you don't
have a chance to should deal with this
Windows star for new text is new
techniques involving Windows so that's a
shame well I'll put yourself
disappointment because when you last 40
hours of your life doing trying to do
something that you can get it man it's
hard to swallow you know but in the end
of the day you see that you could learn
you saw a lot of stuff but this is
something that you you have you know to
wait and sometimes they're very hard so
having two hours will not be enough for
a common guy like me you know so that's
it
lessons learn it from here to me it's
about learn learn learn learn share
scare so take a look in what you're
doing
try to spread your word and share what
you learn into what you're doing that
will be helpful for someone this is
pretty geek but having fun in knowledge
well you know I'm not this kind as a
very geek guy you know this guy I drink
I smoke I do a lot of stuff you know but
I have a lot of fun with CTF
it's really good and as I said before
well I don't know if I put well I put
here in conclusion of that I could go
back to my roots you know where I came
from where why
in this area why I'm doing this because
in the in the beginning was like I was
very excited I want to learn I want to
do stuff and then I get a job you know
you have a family two kids do your job
you know in jobs always job you know you
can have the most fun job in the world
if you have a boss and it ever or you
have a client it's a job you know in the
end of the day maybe you're not that
happy with what you're doing so when you
got this free time in God some space for
doing whatever you want to do it's cool
and in my case I got back to my roots I
got back to to learn to read to exploit
to power so that's the best that's the
thing no it's really fun again and
polish is pure excitement again so you
know we are in the inner penetration
test you got like you know domain
administrator you got everything power
and you know in this got me back that
now when I see a pound asian you know
you really well it's beautiful you have
to to understand and it you see how how
cool it is and that made me better on
job as well so sometimes I was you know
I have 40 hours
I found these I found that and now I had
seen in the last in the last years that
I was not playing in after 10 years
doing the same thing I was like you know
doing the job but now the things change
and you know I mean I'm another person
ability to that and that's in that
school so some resource staff time again
you can check that all that later this
this is a
videocast which you can say from captain
dragon sector captain he shows a lot of
good stuff there so if you want to take
a look on mostly on a low-level
exploitation this guy's really awesome
we have level flow level flow it's a
little bit superficial but you can start
it with it so so this is it you have any
questions thank you
yeah thank you for this very exciting
talk I guess I know what I'll be doing
the next few weekends thank you so now
we have about ten minutes left for some
Q&A time are there any questions if they
are yes already if it's okay a technical
question so when doing binaries how do
you deal with the GDP offsets being
different than when running the binary
normally because like let's say I have
the address of a variable let somewhere
but when I load it in gdb locally it's
always different it's with the name with
the environment variables and so on
with environment yeah when you cannot
attach to a running process per se to
get the variables real offsets it can be
problematic when you develop the actual
oh yeah so if I understand right your
question to talk about variables in the
in the environment for example there XI
equal no no let me rephrase so when you
run a binary normally everything is that
some addresses okay but when you run it
in debugger in the debugger the
addresses are different the offsets okay
so there are there are a few protections
inch debugging for example the main
protection that you can attach before
the debugging so or you can using a LED
preload for example and using another
another library to to start your
software for example if we're talking
about Linux and you start you can you
can create a binary that will be loaded
before they disorder we sell they bury
load exactly that will bypass the
protection it's one of our example it's
a this is a very old protection but they
are very old bypass by the way so
nowadays
I don't really know which which another
protection in Windows we have a lot of
stuff going on and I'm not very familiar
but in UNIX I'm not I'm not very
familiar with others protections but one
way to do it is using LED preload so you
compile with a binary if you take a look
at LD preload bypass debugging stuff you
see a lot of miners that do this job
again is the K to do one more so for a
student who cannot afford an Ida Pro or
Community Edition could work or binary
ninja play games is like doing just gdb
with red re or pita or I don't know pon
DVD or what you showed all right you
think for let's say higher level CTF
yeah so capped extreme so well because
the licenses can get quite yeah well I
use either a lot but you can use you're
talking about Windows stuff no but when
you want to do like static analysis on
something so you're talking about P part
was a quotable well through or whatever
like any binary that you need to reverse
I'm not sure like about Linux we have
the binary ninja that's a cool that's
awesome - I talked just a little bit
about this but there's a lot of plugins
in it's in Python and if you're right
you're on and now you can use simple
execution but it's just for PE elf so
when you're talking about PE you were
you're right the community edition it's
it's very well it's not that bad I don't
use a many many things from the
community edition but yeah you're right
the plugins that are very cool you you
won't be able to use it but if you're
dealing with another the cool thing
about the Ida Pro that they'd supports a
lot of access to right support our sport
SNS
yeah unfortunately there's no water way
around now that I can say here as
expected pull any more questions please
line up at the microphone okay maybe in
the meantime I have one question for you
so do you think maybe it's already the
case that CTFs will be as popular as
exciting as other eSports so if there's
a new one published is there like a rush
and people refreshing the leaderboard
yeah in Brazil we are having it's it's
that's a very very very entry level but
they're trying to do some cool stuff for
example for the public
you know brickers what's the deal the
abouts part because as a CTF player I
just want to play I don't I don't care
but the the excitement for the public is
the key for the games going very popular
right so for example they they the guy
showed me a CTF in I don't know
somewhere in Asia that you know they
have a lot of explosions ever player was
Bill it was being recorded his face his
scream so it was like you knows like
Rockstar women the guy was there playing
and everybody was watching and every
time that somebody got a flag some
explosions came out was like very well
if they if they could do that maybe not
as popular as a soccer my baby as
popular as legend off something legal
that I don't know yeah another YouTube
video for me to check out when I get
back home yeah somebody else so thank
you guys
yeah and thank you again very much
[Applause]
[Music]