[Music]
so we have a few lightning talks for you
we have one very exciting ending
hopefully very voiceless though they'll
come along in a little bit I'm pretty
excited about lightning talks because I
love seeing things that are dazzling and
brilliant and over in a flash
I can't usually do the first so I can
try and do the last two and be brief and
I'll do that now and introduce our first
speaker who also is helping coordinate
the Lightning talks so if Hackman wants
to come on up and give us a talk about
identifying phishing domains please give
him a warm round of applause as our
first speaker I mean so I'm chief System
Architect of sight ground and we host a
lot of shit so millions of hosts and
sometimes of some of those hosts get
compromised not because of us but the
users have now on their computers they
don't update their websites and stuff
like this so on local machines we cannot
help but lead we're thus white to local
machines we cannot help but on our
servers we can actually check what's
going on and since we have a lot of
sites that we are hosting we get a lot
of complaints for hosting fishing which
I don't like at all usually this is
handled by our abuse department but it's
manual work every time so I decided to
use a little bit of AI to help these
guys and actually stop them doing any
fishing so usually have also complaints
for spam
four botnets but those who we have fixed
in the past so we don't have issues with
that check wait wait wait wait when you
turn it off it disconnects here you
didn't missed anything from the slides
don't worry the important stuff is now
so phishing is a bit problematic because
you actually don't know that you're
hosting this and actually you don't know
when it happened and usually it's not
directly from the user but from someone
that is impersonating the user or
uploading the application that we don't
know that can upload something usually
the attackers upload the phishing page
and leave it there or create a separate
host only for this page or even
sometimes orders specific domain name
only for this phishing site so for the
last two we have already deployed
something on our infrastructure that we
can automate this when they're creating
a hostname that should enter the web
server configuration we actually put it
through our AI and it checks if this
host actually looks like a fishing can
tell explain why how so we decided to
use a little bit of AI only a little bit
but first before we start with AI what
we found is that a lot of domains and
hosts that have Amazon hotmail eBay and
stuff like this words that are obviously
not hosted on our infrastructure
shouldn't be there unfortunately there
is a problem if you start with the words
approach because they're there things
like the fruit Bank eBay checkout Amazon
checkout and stuff like this that are
normal for web developers to create
subdomains and use those for their
shopping carts so these are valid things
Wow
Amazon code dot u K dot something dot
something obviously is something that is
a phishing so we decided to start with
worked avec worked avec is representing
like a sentence creating a number from
each word and creating a vector from
these words so we can actually check if
this domain is similar to something that
we consider bad unfortunately we were
not very successful with that it was
only sixty six sixty to seventy six
percent accuracy so we decided to switch
to something else
and to improve that we decided to look a
little bit more on the fishing coast
that are created usually stuff like
Amazon where the always represented by
zero some misspellings here a lot of
dashes or underscores used and
verification that this host actually has
web facing interface because a lot of
the underscores are used in DNS legally
but in the web usually you don't see
something with underscore so we switched
from work to back to support vector
machines and there we actually achieved
95 to 97 percent accuracy of the
technique of fishing host so what we did
was we started with engrams two to four
characters depending on what your
dataset is we actually had to tune this
like a week in order to make it work
dictionaries with bad good words that we
really want to know that there in the
domain the hostname and other checks
like how many - is how many underscores
how many numbers and how many how long
is the hostname actually helped a lot to
achieve this 95 97
accuracy so once we had this we actually
filtered all of the hosts that we are
hosting right now and found out four
thousand phishing pages on our
infrastructure and called the owners of
the hosting accounts to remove those
things I'm going to use the same
infrastructure for directories and files
that are used for fishing so thank you
fantastic thank you very much and so we
have another speaker coming up while
he's getting set up I'm always curious
to see how far people have come
obviously there are some people here
from from Holland yeah raise your hands
good anyone from Eastern Europe
excellent fantastic Central Europe
Africa South America okay interesting of
course yeah so who reckons they've come
the farthest yeah wherever you come from
all right anyone from further away than
San Francisco Pacific Islands maybe yeah
what do we got China fantastic yeah all
right well our next talk is about open
hardware and just go ahead take it away
thank you my name is Alexander ball
truck and I would like to briefly talk
to you about open hardware
reconfigurable network cameras built by
hackers for hackers so I will not read
the specs but you can see that it's a
quite powerful seeing CPU running Linux
openembedded Yocto build and it had a
lot of extensions such as SATA USB sync
ports etc so you can really run on port
a lot of application to the camera like
OpenCV was really easily portable to the
camera
and you can adopt any hardware supported
by linux and connected to the camera
directly this is the PCB design and
since it's open Hardware on our wiki you
will find all the information about the
PCB layouts
BOM etc you can also virtually
disassemble our assemblies our camera
assemblies you can see any model in this
kind of 3d X freedom models and
virtually disassemble them if you click
on the right on the parts it will show
that part on the wiki with all the
documentation so the weekly address the
blog you can subscribe to our blog to
receive some information time to time
and on the licensing we exclusively use
free software licenses and certain open
hardware for the hardware part few years
ago we started with calibrated cameras
so we do sub-pixel resolution
calibration for individual sensor but
also for camera rigs containing multiple
sensors such as this one for example so
you will find more information about the
cameras on those these two links Thanks
and recently we also started with 3d
printed cases so that you can experiment
different sensor arrangement and do
panoramic cameras or stereo but zero for
the grama cameras or different multi
sensor camera arrangements so why multi
sensors the easy answer would be just
because we can we have enough power on
the FPGA on the camera to process up to
even twelve sensor per motherboard you
can connect up to four sensor directly
to the camera or 12 with a multiplexer
board and we can have many fancy
application of
Manti multi-sensor we've calibrated
cameras so this is an example of
panoramic cameras alpha build the the
street view cameras that was used for
Google Street View and then we have
built this new camera for stereo stereo
photographic panoramas so this camera is
capable of 3d reconstruction this is
another example of radial construction
with a four lens camera doing a single
shot 3d reconstruction and the software
is currently available already in
Ameche and now we are starting porting
it to the FPGA so it will run real time
in inside the camera itself and this is
another example of multi sensor camera
application
it's a freelance camera but you can also
do this with the 21 lens I showed before
and it provide you a dynamic therefore
field in post-processing so you can
choose the depth of field of your camera
and make all the rest blurry so we also
provide cameras for developers you can
apply for sponsored cameras you can
contact me for this during shot I'm
present at the open digital radio and
that way for village you can find me
there and test the camera if you are
interested to do so thank you very much
perfect fantastic off to a great start
outdoor living bit of fishing some
camera work outdoor cameras in
particular and our next speaker is
continuing with the theme of outdoor
living PC whiz here is going to talk to
us about the pirate life which I think
epitomizes outdoor living so once you're
set up I'll stop making up this rubbish
trying to tie together this disparate
muppet show of themes instead we'll just
enjoy the presentations yeah
good looking good we've got a mouse
that's outdoor living right okay cool
pirates in practice here's a talk from
PC Wiz about pirate life yeah this isn't
going to be a technical talk I've got
transitions and everything oh well I
copied about me doesn't taste remade
clearly it's about my details and it's
changing automatically stop stop
oh well it's going for the slide so
here's basically the I'm going to talk
about I ran in a general election in the
UK that just happened which was fun and
I learned some things so I'm going to
share some of those the first thing I'm
going to kind of go through is the story
of why I ran in a general election and
that was basically because I made a kind
of joke at a pub a couple of years
earlier with my friends sitting around a
table feeling a bit sad about a Tiffani
of the current government and going you
know what if a significant election have
run for the pirate party and lo and
behold after weeks of saying there will
not be a general election there was a
general election so I that's why ran so
basically the process is because UK
pirate parties quite small it was
basically to send an email to a
nominations officer couple of days later
you've a candidate okay having not
really been involved with the pollak
party that much before I'd been a member
for a while but not really participating
in anything
I had no idea where to go so the first
thing I did was go onto the discord
server because I had been avoiding
discord because I don't like it but
apparently we use it and there was lots
of friendly people there to help me do
election things so yay and there's
plenty of election paperwork to do which
is also fun and has to be done on time
but it's really not that hard so kind of
but the thing I want to really pass on
to people is that it's all about
confidence and about just being able to
force yourself to go and do something
talking to a press is about nagging the
fess they don't come to you they're not
interested they're lazy they don't even
spell check for things you send them so
the most important thing to do is use
all of the spell checking and grammar
checking people you can - when you're
dealing with the press that's that's the
top tip and the sec the second tip is to
put yourself in situations where you
can't really do anything other than
continue in the situation because that
way you're not gonna wuss out and go oh
I'm not doing this I'm just gonna hide
away in the corner than not cause the
first you just have to get on and do it
and that's and that's basically how my
campaign worked and I guess the last
thing well one of the things to touch on
with with the whole election thing is
that obviously I wasn't going to win a
seat in the UK Parliament that just
simply wasn't going to happen I wasn't
even going to get a large number of
votes in the UK Parliament so when
you're running for a small party in the
UK you've got to measure success
differently so the way I was measuring
success was by engagement and causing
conversation in the local area whoever I
was learning and that happened so that's
what I call success I've got back two
minutes left so I shall import some more
knowledge on you so one other thing I
learned is that pirate policies can be
applied to where these four aren't just
about copyright and software patents and
the digital world you have to try and
find a way of applying those to everyday
issues like school funding or
health care for vision and the way to do
that is to go and actually talk to
people so you have to turn up at school
halls and things which believe candidate
didn't actually do but oh well that so
you have to turn up and talk to people
and that's basically the point and
getting the exposure and I think I've
run out of stuff so I'll hand it back
over that antastic thank you I have to
admit that largely describes my life as
well turn up and talk to people
sometimes it's good sometimes it's bad
sometimes it's endless this is Genesis
sorry he was here yesterday he came to
speak to us about the history of legal
cannabis and running cannabis farms
today is gonna speak to us about
something else I have no idea what it'll
be mushrooms you think it could be I
don't think so I've seen him speak about
a lot of other outdoor things he was
gonna speak to us about hacker yoga I
don't know how hacker yoga works I guess
that's some sort of stretching exercise
where you reach out and grab shelves in
the morning praying to the shell gods
but that was the previous talk what's
the new talk two years ago and two years
ago I had the three lightning talks
back-to-back right now I just have a
five minutes I would like to have some
assistance with the slides can you move
it to the correct screen I'm not okay
okay take your time we won't start yet
let's get it okay I didn't get any sleep
I was I was presenting at an online
summit community and I was presenting
for an for an hour and then I had
another hour very powerful conversation
so my energy was just so high and I was
so much it I couldn't fall asleep right
now I had a two hours nap and my body
is fully recharged I treat my body as
the technology I treat my brain as
technology and I've purchased this
domain hacker.com two years ago at the
car of communication camp so these are
my different yoga postures it it helps
it helps me with different back pains
and and other you know occupational
hazards but today the main subject of
the talk is actually another project I'm
making which is called astral ship
Genesis and previously it took me an
hour to go through this slide so right
now I'll just give you a very very quick
overview this is my bio don't read it I
will send you the link two slides this
is me my evolution throughout the years
I called myself a shape-shifter
Alchemist wizard magician I am yet to
explore my true calling on this planet I
am originally from Poland that's where
my accent is coming from in Poland
communism times lines to get any food
not nothing in the shops a communism it
was not cool I was to Burning Man I was
to Rainbow Gathering I was - boom
Festival I was to many international
communities this is my profile on Stack
Overflow I was working for a bank for a
very good money now I am no longer
employed by a bank which is a very
relief these are my two kids I love them
so much they are very cosmic they know
everything this is my little yoga
website that helps me with the back pain
and when when you are a good-looking man
and you go to a yoga class full full of
girls it's just incredible it is
completely out of the world how many
girls I meet through your goddesses
ridiculous yoga needs more men and
hackery festivals need more women the
gender is rather imbalance so we
actually have this Chapel we have this
large building the amount of work that
is put here is completely ridiculous it
is out of this planet but we have a
building in North Wales it is when you
fly fly to Liverpool or Manchester
because
it's much much easier Liverpool and
Manchester fly to Manchester or
Liverpool this is the Google arif this
is the Street View this is the our
building this is our Instagram profile
we actually have the building and we
have a video links links resources blah
blah everything go visit our wiki and
you know what now we are flying to Mars
Elon Musk is flying to Mars the in the
popular culture it is normal we are
flying to Mars it is done it is
happening we are also travelling through
time through gravity waves the concept
of virtual reality consciousness it is
happening like we are already
approaching singularity and in a mask
what is the chance we live in the base
reality of course we live in a
simulation one in a billion chance so in
the 10 years Facebook iPhone blockchain
all these technologies are so or
revolutionizing the world we have
everything to live prosperous life we do
not have to work majority of the work is
bullshit middle management passing
papers we do not have to work universal
basic income is getting introduced on a
global scale and I'm just jumping
jumping jumping yesterday it was an hour
I just want to go to this you know clue
essence these guys are buying city for
50 thousand pounds these guys are doing
a hard based on the desert these guys
are opening a new country this country
has been around for like 50 years
we are opening a new country we will is
send an official invitation to every
single country on the planet hey we are
recognizing you as a country please
allow us to open official ambassador at
your land and will also send the
invitation to car to countries like
Google Google is already more powerful
than many islands on Pacific we will
recognize Google Apple Facebook
Microsoft as the actual countries
because they have a much bigger
influence than all this you know three
islands of the Pacific so this is
happening and I am inviting you to our
project we are building thousands of
dollars life support capsule food water
oxygen waste treatment energy because
you can look at the human body consists
of cells and planet
earth consists of humans we treat one
human as a cell of humanity and as was
as we will travel throughout outer space
as humanity will expand to other planets
which is already happening the Mars the
Elon Musk the space X it is already
happening and we believe that by solving
this problem how to sustain a life we
will solve many other interesting
problems and I invite you to the party
once you see you can't unsee
I'm thank you so much for staying with
me I love you so much thank you thank
you thank you thank you too many
hyperlinks fantastic don't forget your
laptop
don't forget your laptop this is yours
okay
all right very well so that's like
compressing ideas and audio on-the-fly I
feel like I just went through 3000
hyperlinks and too many ideas to
compress into a single five-minute
space-time continuum but our next talk
is going to be about open digital radio
matthias has just signed up to do a
lightning talk are there anybody else is
there anyone else in here who would like
to do lightning talks we have a lot of
space tomorrow we probably have 18 slots
for lightning talks so sign up for a
lightning talk bring your friends I see
some of my friends in the back of the
room they don't want to be associated
with me which is why they said all the
way at the back with my agent and I know
that they promised to come and speak
tomorrow too so you better be signing up
alright anybody do the public speaking
technology public speaking workshop the
other day yes and have you done a
lightning talk what what is your excuse
for that
please join us we need more likely talks
tomorrow so I'm gonna leave Matthias
with the stage to do an open digital
radio thank you very much
after this presentation talking about
all these things we will have in the far
future I'm going to talk to you about a
radio broadcasting standard from the
early 90s and more concretely more
concrete the open digital radio
Association maintains and develops a
piece of software that
be used to set up a fully open source
digital audio broadcasting transmission
chain so in a few words digital audio
broadcasting is a European standard as
said from the from the early 90s that is
to radio what dvb-t
is to television so it's the step from
analog modulation analog transmission of
radio broadcasts to a digital
transmission of of this content this has
a benefits in terms of audio quality in
terms of a number of programs you can
transmit in a given region and has all
all sorts of advantages because it's a
digital a digital medium so our tools
that allow everybody to to generate
these signals are comprised of an audio
encoder so that you can prepare the
content you can encode the content
properly there is a multiplexer that can
gathers many different sources together
and there is a piece called the
modulator that can create the the signal
that you really have to transmit them
over an antenna to reach your audience
and we're using generic devices these
devices from company called ethos but it
also works with your badge from the last
CCC camp or equivalently with the hack
RF and other software-defined radio
devices like these so the tools
themselves they're not a full solution
it's not just something you can buy it's
not the Box you buy and then you set up
somewhere on your transmission site and
it works what is the set of tools you
can assemble you it's flexible it's
interconnected using IP so you can
create your own your own system and all
of this is on our website on digital
radio dot org and also on all the
sources are on github and it's GPL
licensed in addition to these tools
necessary for the broadcast themselves
we also have additional things around
there's a lot of effort also active in
the reception part because of course you
need to be able to receive this div
signal and you can use the RTL
the are sticks this is very cheap as
they are tunnels or other as they are
devices to receive your signal and
listen to to radio this thing is in use
in several countries in 24/7 broadcasts
in Europe among them Switzerland the
United Kingdom there is somebody in
Denmark who operates a transmitter using
these tools and there is also somebody
in in Germany and I've learned this very
recently a first test transmission that
is that has started what are we doing
more or less currently so I mean what
are we doing at the camp we have a small
village we have a an ongoing project the
goal is to make power amplifiers more
energy efficient or the goal is to use
more of the potential of a given power
amplifier and make it more efficient in
terms of electricity usage so here you
see a small setup the most important
thing in the picture of course the the
Mata bottle we are looking for codec
experts who could help us improve the
audio quality of the encoder so if
anybody is or wants to become an expert
in audio coding you're welcome to get in
touch with us and there's also activity
regarding monitoring tools and all the
things you need if you operate these
tools in a in a production broadcast so
to conclude we have a village I hope you
can see the arrow so we're in the
northwest of the the Lamarr field it's
just over there near the near the large
Tower we're sharing our tent with the
ZigBee the the z-wave crowd the dead
wife gran and to conclude many thanks to
everybody who's involved in this camp
organizing it and helping out many
thanks
[Applause]
microphone there we go all right thank
you very much so Peter is our next
speaker he just rocked up earlier I'm
getting the impression that he may or
may not have slides or diagrams but he
looks like a professional thank you so
much there you go enjoy so my name is
Peter Van Dyck and I would like to talk
to you about cloud security so who has
never heard about cloud you're a cheat
right so I assume that you are this talk
is this this presentation is for people
who are in some way shape or form
involved into like deploying online
services so who's deploying online
services for a month who is using online
services that's the rest of you right
now this is still a few people in the
black box and if you are really involved
in securing online services ok fair
amount so I'm gonna give you a couple of
research resources to help you out on
that to start with I think that it's my
it's my personal opinion that cloud is
not so much technology although it's
technology driven it's basically a new
way of delivering IT it's a supply chain
of IT thinking and I have a larger
youtube movie on that that explains it
in a bit more detail all those links
will be on the wiki that comes with the
lightning talks so I'm write that up
after just I've finished so that's the
first thing to understand and it's it is
unavoidable in a way and if you want to
talk about how unavoidable it is meet me
at the bar later right now I want to
give you some resources that that are
let's say really helpful in your work
potentially who's ever heard of the
cloud security alliance ok a few people
in the back great so I'm I'm pretty much
involved in the cloud security Alliance
I'm actually a board member of the Dutch
chapter and to ask you the Alliance is
doing a lot of great work so this is it
like a nonprofit organization supported
by basically
large relevant companies a hundred
thousand individual members doing
summits and events across the world but
most importantly producing a lot of free
content free accessible content and the
flagship piece of content just got
updated and that's the security guidance
for cloud computing and that is just in
its fourth edition it was released one
or two weeks ago that's a body of
knowledge that explains how to secure
cloud computing it has a lot of
technical stuff but it also had a lot of
governance stuff now you may or may not
like that
but that's just a new reality and this
is one way of catching up on that that
body of knowledge is actually testable
with an individual certification pull
disclosure I do a course on that but you
can study for that yourself based on
that same body of knowledge there's also
something that's called the cloud
controls metrics so if you're involved
in securing cloud services that's a
really helpful tool beyond that if
you're actually delivering an online
service you may want to look into the de
star certification scheme that is for a
security trust insurance registry which
is also a product of the cloud security
Alliance and it's also freely available
no big bucks involved then what else was
there in terms of important resources
that I wanted to give you so beyond that
there are like another 160 research
projects ranging from big data security
IOT security crypto and quantum safe
crypto and a ton more that I won't go
into right now my call to action to you
is have a look at that material it's
really worthwhile doing that you may
want to consider going to an event or we
do some kind events in the Netherlands I
think in the UK is event Germany not so
sure the US a lot I also run a cloud and
container security meetup in the
Netherlands so you may want to be
visiting that as well and basically
that's my message you know there's this
stuff that you can use comes the events
and if you want to talk there's even
more fun come over well I'll actually
I'll actually coach you into giving a
good presentation if you want to
so with that said I have one minute left
but I'll give it I'll hand it back to
you to think it is over thank you so
much thank you did you see that you
stood right at the front of the stage
very professional very projecting that
was pretty awesome we have another
speaker who hopefully will come up to
the stage she's just turned up so it
might be a bit of a surprise that she
was coming up right at this moment she's
going to speak to us about fashion
technology and I think that's pretty
cool I bought it Becca if years ago from
a company called bata brand and it
basically is called a flash bomber
hoodie and if someone takes a picture of
you at nighttime and the hood is up
it reflects the flash camera with tiny
beads of glass and therefore your face
is blacked out so people can't take
pictures of you so I think fashion
technology is super cool and I'm glad
that you're going to speak to us about
it so hi everyone so my name is Amina
and I have a startup company called 360
fashion network and I've been doing
fashion technology for the last ten
years and as technology has evolved I
have always taken it and applied it to
the fashion industry fashion is often
separated from the technology side
because they are more hands-on and also
because of the technical nature they
often don't understand what's actually
possible on the engineering side most
engineers could care less really about
elegance and style when they're coding
and soldering and putting together a
prototype but I think we really need to
merge these two worlds together and I'll
tell you why yesterday a gentleman gave
a speech where I asked him as far as
tracking cameras if there were any
technologies available that would enable
me to scramble the cameras that I could
embed in my clothing for example and he
said yeah there's some like high-powered
infrared lights that you know I've seen
that confused the camera but you know
that's not a long-term solution he said
because only a few people would actually
be able to
where those and he said legislation is
really the long-term solution and I said
yeah but by the time legislation goes
around we're all tracked because you
know the cameras are everywhere
but fashion on the other hand is
actually a very fast way to react to
technology and I'll tell you why because
when something is in fashion it's in
everything when polka dots are in there
in your curtains they're in your shoes
they're in your clothes they're in your
laptop case they're in your bag they're
in your car they're in everything the
way the fashion industry works down is
that as a trend emerges it goes
throughout the entire lifestyle of the
human being so in in effect I do believe
that if there was a cap with high
powered LED infrared LEDs on it and it
was communicated properly to people then
all of a sudden boom very quickly you
could roll out clothing with those LEDs
inside and people would understand them
and they would purchase them and in a
matter of a week or two everyone could
have this clothing which would confuse
the cameras and another thing is is that
in the engineering environment when I'm
working together with large scale
companies they come to me and they're
like we need to do something for women
or we need to do something with fashion
and we don't know what to do and a lot
of times that's because I don't know
engineers think we're all naked but I
don't see nobody with like all their
parts hanging out in this room so they
often forget that clothing textiles and
accessories that what we are wearing are
actually part of the IOT environment
I built a hundred and sixty-two gloves
that were all controlled using the
gestures of the dancers which controlled
the entire lighting of the performance
and it was on CCTV and the director
Jiang Gong he absolutely refused to let
me use any high-tech solutions
he wanted a button so I put a button on
there but you know what happens the
humans they go ooh a button I want to
touch it and then backstage two minutes
before your performance you've got 50
girls running up to you going my glove
doesn't work right so disaster scenario
and you're like did you push the button
and they're like oh yeah I did you know
so instead what I did is I soldered off
all the fucking buttons and I was like
fuck that that didn't work and I used
gesture recognition because in the
performance I watched that every time
they wanted the lighting to go off
synchronized they all made this one
gesture so that's a situation where a
high-tech solution actually could solve
elegantly a solution for the performance
and so I think that we really need to
start thinking more of the lifestyle so
me and my company I'm like often trying
to bridge this divide between the two
sets excuse me it's two sides because
they don't even speak the same language
so you have to work with the clothing
people on the garment construction side
and be like I need channels coming out
here I need a zipper here I need to be
remove an inner layer here because if
that's all not working I need access to
it for the engineers to fix it on the
engineering side you have to think about
the size and the flexibility so all in
all I'd like to say that I think these
two worlds need to come together and I'm
seeing that over at our tent at the
hacking space if you want to come at 11
I've got engineers showing up and
pimping up their style and also lots of
women thank you fantastic
actually
I like that idea I have to admit I think
hackers could be the cutting edge of
fashion the bleeding edge of fashion
right geek chic baby I'd like to see
more of that so I was told earlier that
I shouldn't stand in between the camera
and the pole otherwise it sort of looks
like I'm pole dancing and nobody wants
to see that right Wow
saucy crowd saucy crowd but I don't want
to get in the way of the next
presentation which is a deeply deeply
exciting we try and save some really
amazing things for the end so we've got
a bunch of people that I think are ready
to come up here and maybe do a sound
check before they do our final talk for
the day come on table yeah so you
thought you'd seen it all but now it
really begins and while they get set up
I'll keep things going a little bit can
we have a round of applause for all the
angels who've been helping out with the
sound helping out with the event yeah
cool does anybody here know what this is
gonna be are you ready do you know
what's coming do you know what this is
can you guess it's a choir yeah I'm
excited about this it's up to you yeah
are you all set all right
just a moment microphones coming on all
right we just thanked them they were
busy bowing so they didn't notice really
hello okay so so this all started with
that at the last cares Communication
Congress I noticed that people always
met at the table of the Free Software
Foundation Europe to sing the free
software song and I thought I'll make a
choir arrangement and and so now you can
hear the choir
[Applause]
[Laughter]
[Music]
- now and jealous of Fred you'll be free
hackers you'll be free
join us now and share the software
you'll be free I guess you'll be me
Warners can get money through a curse
that is true but they cannot tell the
neighbors
a curse that's not food when we have
been a free software will become those
30 licenses
[Music]
[Applause]
joining us now and share the software
you'll be freed occur to be free join us
now and share the software you will be
free occurs you be free
[Applause]
[Music]
fantastic it's always worth staying till
the end I'm really pleased that Benjamin
yes
okay thanks miss thanks again to the
choir for coming up to sing that song it
was filled with a little bit of mild
peril there at the end and reaching down
into the toes I think that was a
reference to to something anyways I'm
gonna wrap it up now I'm gonna repeat a
few things once again thanks to the
angels and the sound people give them
another round of applause for the entire
conference
and I'm certainly pleased as well that
when the lightning talks started there
were less of you in the room and more
came in I like to pretend that's just me
I know it's not I think it's all the
fantastic speakers that we just had so
thanks for listening to all of them and
make sure you go and get your t-shirts
from the online website or go and visit
the shop because we're running out of
them but they will ship to Benelux in
Germany and enjoy the rest of the
conference we need more lightning talk
speakers tomorrow so sign up and come
back in CS tomorrow thank you
[Music]