[Music]
welcome to shower 2017 just a quick
summary of what is happening here there
are 300 talks and workshops 100
self-organized sessions and this is
growing like with 50 every day now one
megawatt of power huge trek tens
thousands and thousands of badges 100
Gigabit Ethernet so it's very fast so
someone just came up to me and said like
I just downloaded 300 megabytes in one
second so it's 2 seconds per tf-x movie
so there's an awesome music lounge
there's a silent lounge great decoration
throughout the sites everywhere several
bars dozens of showers toilets great
food there's a family village
there's awesome logistics making
everything happen here
hundreds of waste bins that are being
managed
also there's Network everywhere there's
DECT coverage everywhere thank you
there's over a thousand pages of
regulations and permits went to went to
in where we are right now it is
ridiculous how much legal stuff we've
done
there's recording so for everything like
this there will be streams there's first
aid I could go on for a while so it's it
is just insane the amount of stuff going
on here currently right now what's
happening here
is insane and that's only for one reason
and that reason is you you are making
these events thank you
[Applause]
so it's it's impossible to put into
words the amount of Awesomeness that's
going on right now like hundreds of
people have worked for the last two
years to put together this event
especially in the last month's and last
days some people worked really really
insanely hard to be where we are right
now so many of the things at share if
not all are built or managed or
maintained by volunteers many teams have
done impossible to make sure that we can
be here and distant with power right now
especially I would like to give a big
round of applause to the power team and
network team they have been going crazy
because this site is one by one
kilometer
it's insane so
[Applause]
this is the eighth iteration of this
event
it started in 1989 and its billing held
every four years because it's just an
insane amount of work that in between
there are events in Germany as you all
know if not also go there and in the UK
which is also awesome
and as with software like games are like
software and we try to make every
version better and better and better and
more impressive so the massive there are
massive amounts of time being put into
this and well still even still then it
might be possible that some things are
just not perfect yet and remember that
this event is run by volunteers entirely
so if you see something that doesn't
work please help and improve it that
will be the best solution
nothing happens automatically everything
from the smallest things that you see at
this camp have has been built by
volunteers
so please do help out the bottom line is
really shy as what you make of it and
currently it's fucking awesome
so the goal is to get as close to heaven
as we can
might not be perfect but we're trying
those who help out like for a number of
shifts you might have heard already you
get this awesome
t-shirt you will see you will see a lot
of people running around with this
beautiful t-shirt
it has a nice checklist on the back
filled with nice jokes you will read I
don't have slides so yeah you'll figure
it out it it's it's it's awesome so
currently there there are thirty-six
hundred and fifty people on site so
that's that's it that's an that's that's
a very very large large number of people
and a show of hands we just had so I'll
skip that so who is visiting this camp
for a camp like this for the first time
oh well welcome so welcome
[Applause]
so we figured out like with thirty six
hundred fifty people and four hundred
workshops we started calculating a
little thing like if you would like want
to attend all sessions that are being
organized if an average session takes
about one hour and you will do want to
follow all sessions in a like and still
stay sane
you will need clones of yourself you
will need a lot of clones of yourself at
least twenty so but there's a problem
with this reasoning because if there are
clones of you there will be more
sessions and in the end we couldn't
figure out how where this where it is
ends so it is really impossible to see
everything here everything on a scam but
please try otherwise we have to figure
out a cloning device and a brain working
device and there will be so much
knowledge that your head will hurt in
the end so good luck with the impossible
challenge also welcome to beautiful
zeevala we're currently in say Boulder
which is the most Dutch part of the
Netherlands as you can get fined for
this it has a dike it's on an artificial
island it has very complex land usage
regulations it lies well belies below
sea level the ground is mostly clay and
on this artificial isle with this which
is the biggest in the world we also have
another artificial aisle so many things
to scouting long hoods
save all the the scouting Netherlands
and the municipality of say Boulder for
having us here they please give them a
applause
[Applause]
okay secret messages so this is the most
Dutch place in the world a few if you're
allergic to the Netherlands you would
have died right now
so don't worry it's contagious and you
will carry it with you for the rest of
your life but even then there's a
there's two things that this event
should really that you could should
really take home from this event and
carry it with the rest of your life and
the first thing is the meaning of share
that is still hacking anyway and like
that's that's the goal that's the point
whatever happens please keep on hacking
just do that and and if you don't well
what are you doing here I think that
that will just happen always like with
all decisions made all the events that
have been organised all good all bad
choices we're still hacking anyway like
there's many events before it is and
also regardless of anything that happens
at any place at any time for any reason
you can count on us you can count on us
we are all still hacking anyway and
that's why we're here
[Applause]
so so yeah hacking pushes boundaries
it moves society forward it is very
awesome to do as you will see if you are
new here at this camp otherwise you will
notice by hearts and we also believe
that everyone here at this event should
be completely themselves and that's very
important the more yourself you are the
better creativity you will have the more
awesome things you will make so that's
very very important and if you might
feel impeded by this mission there's a
cohesion team that can that knows the
entire Oregon everybody and that can
figure out stuff for you all day 24/7 so
they're in the silent lounge outside the
Dyke so I welcome everybody to be
themselves as much as possible
shall I restart the clip right here we
go
you of course will find differing
opinion at opinions at this camp please
have an open mind try to learn there's
most I think always reasoning behind why
something is happening why something is
happening right or wrong so take your
time and the other important rule next
to still hacking anyway is be excellent
to each other for this event there are a
few things few websites that are
maintained by the sysadmin team and I
will want to I would like to go over
them shortly and then go to a Q&A and
they are so I have to make this a little
bit smaller it's really fast this screen
it's very nice so the first one these
pixels over there if this is the angel
system if you want to do if you want to
help out in a structured manner you can
therefore there is an angel system the
URL is angel dot shat 2017 dot org and
there you can register and you can mark
yourself as being arrived all right you
should do that at the info tent they can
mark you as being arrived and you can
help out with one of the many many
shifts that we have you can also do this
in an unstructured way and you will also
get if you do this please tell that suit
to somebody with a nice high face so you
can get food vouchers and also go get
the t-shirt in the end but the angel
system is very important it's the
backbone of of the event please register
please help out with the many shifts
that we
we have there in the night over day so
this this it starts here there's
something else that's really important
it's the wiki oh wow if you have if you
have Oh
does anybody have shades so the wiki
contains a lot a lot of knowledge can I
increase the font size yeah there's a
lot of knowledge on the wiki tiki torch
a 20-17 dot o-r-g org and you will find
a lot of interesting information such as
the most important announcements like if
you want to have more web wasps how you
do this also you will find the villages
you'll find a list of interests and of
course I wanted to show the list of
interests and there are two things turn
Wi-Fi on waiting
this is a demo effect this doesn't do
justice at what what the amount of work
that the knot has put into this so now I
should enable the proxy so like this and
I should do this so there's a new thing
on the wiki that's a list of interests
and for every village there is and every
cluster their interests you can you can
add interests and tags and you can find
other people or other villages with the
same interest so you can connect each
other
because that might spur new ideas and
more awesomeness so how to bring
everybody together this is one approach
and the interests are sold are ordered
by by by the amount of villages and and
clusters that have entered that so
they're over well I think let me let me
see join the I for every interest Aires
you can join the channel so if you do
join V there's like 308 interests and
well I am NOT asking you to join 308 RC
channels I think you already have that
so like soul ring and fun and hacking
well it's good that these things are at
the top right privacy Arduinos at the
list goes on and on so you can find each
other based on interests fear this way
there's much more in the wiki if you
have a question how does something work
it's probably on the wiki so that's one
there's also another really important
thing and that's the schedule that's a
program that shot when you substitute
org or zoom in a little can i zoom in
yes excellent so we can click and we see
we see that's currently there's an
opening talk cool and next Oh Phil
Zimmerman the beanie and a lot of a lot
like like lot a lot
but a lot of content this is one of what
I've been warning about so there's so
much to do I want to you need at least
six other clones for this right and
another thing that's really handy during
the camp is the map there's this
interactive map map touch' 2072 org
where you can zoom in I hope I can zoom
in at this this here we go so you can
see all the fields which are arranged
alphabetically from north to south so
here at Wozniacki you will find the
badge bar for the awesome batch that we
have and if you click on it you'll see d
wiki page so talking about batches have
you all received your badges
the batch team is sitting over here
sparkly
happy it's really awesome that this this
is the first Dutch hacker camp with a
badge so the amount of work that went
into this is ridiculous and they're
still running around and they're still
happy I don't know how they do it but
they do it so please give them a round
of applause
[Applause]
there will be a badge contest also at
the fifth day of the camp there will be
a batch dog that will have the most
awesome apps showed and displayed so you
have 5 days to make something beautiful
on this badge the feature set of the
badge it's an ESP 32 it's a special
edition with more RAM right more storage
so we have this is a very special
edition also this is the black one I
don't know this is just one apparently I
will steal this right now
and what's more well yeah I'm a bit
speechless that you also get some let's
please sort of them on and they give the
nice char design colours to six colours
if you program a program it like that
that way
alright alright there's a massive
multiplayer game on the barrage already
it's called 2-shot 2017 game install it
I don't know how it works but I'm gonna
do that so that that's clear some other
things on the map that I would like to
show here is the alt power network at
camp 2015 in Germany there was the wish
that we should move away from generators
and start with an alternative power
Network so technically we could have
done that but we had a lot of work to do
that with the power companies so we
still had to rent a power generator but
luckily Piznarski I started the alt
power can I click on this I hope so No
start at the old power Network it's a 42
DC 42 volt direct current grid it's
located here at the top of Lamarr field
there are it's four times 42 folds
forced to amperes
max there are over 42 connections that
the amount of work went into is is 42
times 42 hours this is information so
there's there's been a lot of work
there's a lot of solar panels laying out
there if you value the transition from
generators to a better or cleaner power
source please join the village
join the cluster out power and work on
it so we can move to a better way of
power please
alright also the last one the the the
network guys knock they have a 1 or 100
gigabit ethernet connection I'm sorry ah
man I'm tired
a 100 gigabit internet connection and
they have actually two hundred two
gigabit bearing so it's real you can
actually use it to full capacity I don't
know what on what but you figure that
out there's there's they said like
there's 402 quintillion IP addresses in
our range and if you want to store it at
all for whatever reason you will need 6
million petabytes just to store all the
unique IP addresses good luck yeah
that's another new thing at this camp is
to harbor the safe harbor well where
shoot the harbor B hmm well here there
are so a lot of boats already it's next
to the silent lounge it's really cool
also if you want to take a swim just
walking over here there's a nice beach
here where you can lay down and relax so
that I think that concludes this opening
and thank you very much I think well
there's one thing welcome to sha 2017
[Applause]
[Music]