[Music]
I'm a privacy designer and I wrote a
little book about that called design my
privacy that's used in a lot of schools
and that lends to teach privacy design
but more importantly I'm a technology
critic which means that I try to not
believe everything that Silicon Valley
tells us face value and I also work for
the Ministry of Technology and
innovation in the Netherlands which
doesn't exist but the website does okay
and the main question I I work with in
technology is how do I get a wider
audience to understand what's going on
and to care about it and one of the
places I do that is is set up which is a
I'm a co-founder of this Media Lab this
cultural organization in Utrecht here in
the Netherlands and we do funding
projects and we're nonprofit and what we
do a lot we use humour to explain things
use humor to reach a wider audience to
help them understand what's going on so
we do a lot of crazy projects and but I
won't really go into those I'm afraid
but what this talk is going about going
to be about is what does it mean to be
free when surveillance is a dominant
business model of the Internet and I
think it starts with this button that a
lot of us click all the time
and we agree button we don't really know
what we're agreeing to and what I'm
interested in is what is the long term
you know what happens in a long term if
we keep clicking all these buttons all
the time and I believe in the long term
we could see the rise of something that
I call social cooling which is a
purposeful connection to global warming
and I'll get to that later and the core
idea is that we change our behavior a
lot and that we start to yet
apply more self-censorship but I'll get
into that all that this is you know
we're going to talk about so what I
worry about is when I want to explain
you know new forms of surveillance to my
mom you know how do I do that and that's
why I think
we need words like this so this is my
hack in a way you know what metaphoric
and politicians understands so that's
why I tried to come up with this word
like I said I think as oil leads to the
global warming I think we could make the
narrative that data could lead to social
cooling and I started with by building a
website it was his pet project I made
social cooling calm and it went viral so
that was really nice and and then well
then I said things exploded and I'm
gonna talk to you about three things the
first I'm gonna talk about the rise of
the reputation economy because that's
the core foundation of this idea then
we're going to talk to you about what
social cooling exactly is so what is
happening in the long term in this
answer this reputation economy comes up
and third they're gonna talk to you
about what to do about it because I
don't want to leave you all depressed
but starts off with this but this is
this idea that a lot of us think more
and more feel which is idiot maybe I
shouldn't click on that little link you
know you're on Facebook you're browsing
and you're you come across this link you
think I could click on it but someone
might remember that and that might look
bad
who here recognizes that as feeling see
but the more I give this talk the more I
find people feel this and it's really
growing and I think this is in the core
the smallest version of what I'm talking
about no I call it click fear or in
touch click phrase and this is no
scientific studies point out that this
is happening more and more that a lot of
people are feeling this and that we see
these chilling effects pop up these
effects where people stop clicking on
things or stop doing this because they
think it might harm them or it might
hurt their chances and of course this
idea is is not that strange I mean we
all understand that if you feel you're
being watched you change your behavior
and even even earlier like architects
like Jeremy Bentham created this idea
for the panopticon that you the concept
you probably know this prison where the
core idea was that the prisoners could
be washed by the that the prison masters
but they couldn't see the other way
around so
you couldn't see the jailers you
couldn't see if they were looking at you
and this meant that if you were in this
prison you constantly had this idea
am I being watched right now am i doing
something that's illegal or not right
and even if you wouldn't you might not
have been watched at the moment but you
started internalizing this idea is what
I'm doing right now is that illegal and
that was the whole idea by Bentham he
said these prisoners even after they
leave the prison they will still have
ingrained this idea of this jailer who's
constantly you know watching them is
will keep thinking even when out of jail
is what I'm doing right now is that okay
is this acceptable and of course all
these prisons were closed because they
turn out to be quite inhuman but in a
way this is exactly what we're building
now on a societal scale and that's
because of the rise of big behavioral
data and I was gathering all this data
about our behavior um and we do this
because big data has the promise of
behavioral change right and the most
basic version that you all know is of
course advertisement you know vert eyes
errs gather data to give better ads we
all know this story but it goes a lot
further than that and I think what most
people miss in this story about why our
data is gathered and why advertising is
important it's also about risk
management right that's where actually
if you look at the numbers the bulk of
the money that is made through data is
not made by advertising but it's made by
risk management people who want to
manage you or citizens or consumers as a
risk and if you want to see what the
extreme version of this is all you have
to do is you have to go to China in
China to building something called the
social credit system and this is
basically a score that well says if
you're a good sister or not it's a
rating that says it's a citizen well
behaved or not and this is what they say
they say when people's behavior isn't
bound by their morality a system must be
used to restrict their actions
all right so China fundamentally doesn't
really trust their citizens to make the
right choice than themselves they say
well we'll nudge you will help you to
make the right decisions the system will
be based on various criteria ranging
from financial credibility and criminal
record to social media behavior and from
2020 onwards each adult citizens should
besides its identity card
such a credit coat so they're making
this mandatory and they're wasting no
time because already you have the first
version and that's called sesame credit
since we created this a commercial
variety made together with a Alibaba
Group that you might know from
Aliexpress and websites like like like
that and already you see that that
students are in bars are like you know
comparing scores like how's your score
if a good score is more impressive
already this system is connected to the
larger largest dating website in China
so if you want to date someone you can
actually look up their score and see you
know are they paying their bills on time
or they're buying good things and this
already it's already made I'm gonna skip
this one so what you see is that are you
buying and say are you buying a saying
the right things becomes very important
right in China because getting a
government job or a loan or a visa will
be a lot easier if you have a good score
but the Chinese government doesn't want
citizens with a low score to leave China
because that might be you know a bad
representative mmm but this is the thing
that gets me most because until until
now you could say well you know that's
your own fault if you if you're a bad
citizen then you get a bad score and you
got less chances that's fair but the
thing is it it's this is also a factor
so if your friends score is bad that you
know that influences your score and vice
versa if you have a bad score you might
drag your friends down and that's where
it gets really you know insidious and
where you restarts thinking who are my
friends and that's where you see the
rise of things like like data
discrimination you can talk about data
stratification where certain people will
cluster together and this is one of my
new hobbies is to take these really bad
stock photos and then to to do this I'm
gonna do something to it and this is
this before and now I'm gonna give you
to after and just see how it changes
alright that went from a nice couple to
this kind of sassy romantic love story
where she wants to be with him but he's
five star and she's only a three star
right and in a way this is what we're
building in or they're building in China
okay so like I'm saying and then you
could be thinking that only happens in
China
oh those Chinese they're so crazy but
the thing is we're also building that
we're building
the exact same thing over here only
we're calling it the reputation economy
which means we let the market build it
if you give an example that this is a
Danish startup called deem Li and I
quickly want to give you a small piece
of video from yeah they're promotional
video basically is there any sound by
any chance
no if I turned sounds turned on here
what the video says is this is Cheryl
and she has in a really good score on
her ride-sharing app but she doesn't
have it on another website so what if we
could connect those so then you could
have one score that represents you as a
person wouldn't that be great and then
the video goes on to explain that with
this score you know wouldn't be great if
you connect it and show the score on
things like there we go on using your
dimly score on your resume to get a
better job like in China use it to get a
bank loan like in China use it on your
dating profile to get you know better
dates like in China right so we see the
exact same thing happening here except
the market is building it and most of
this whole ecosystem of all these
ratings is actually invisible to us
because we know our uber scores and our
Airbnb scores we know we have those but
those are the tip of the iceberg
most of these scores are now invisible
to the first example tinder has you know
ratings on how attractive you are you
don't know about those but they are
there and that's just an example um more
and more you see that these data brokers
which are companies specialize in
gathering your gathering your data and
making these scores are taking your data
basically and then combining it into
this course sometimes up to 8,000 scores
a d'italia so after right right now
so all your data that the thing that
people don't understand that's your data
up there but they those scores are their
data
yeah so they're up to already a thousand
decides are out of date and they're
gathering scores about things like you
know your IQ but also your psychological
profile sexual orientation economic
stability these things you might not
have explicitly
shares but that their algorithms are
able to deduce from the patterns they
see in society right because someone
else might have a similar profile like
you and they know that they are or they
have had no this I'm not gonna go into
that but their algorithms are able to
deduce this about you up to 8,000 things
about you and okay another video which
we don't have the audio for but this is
about a famous study where your Facebook
Likes
could be correlated to your personality
now you're you're aspects as well and
that's just from Facebook like they were
able to deduce really was really
shockingly high accuracy your gender and
all these things yes like the important
thing to understand is that these what
especially in American and European
you're a little different but in America
you understand that these scores they
will always say these are our opinions
about these people they are not facts if
you'd say there are facts in the United
States you can get suit if it's not true
so then you get a libel case but what
they all say is our opinion of course
their clients will take these things as
facts so it doesn't really matter but
that's that's their how they do it and
so we have to understand it's people say
often well I don't want them to you know
use my data or share my data that your
data is really quite safe in a way at
Facebook is they won't share your raw
data that that's really not valuable
what's valuable are the deduced derived
and scores from that right the Distilled
project those are valuable and that's no
longer your data that's their data so
that's really important to understand
the really important distinction to make
a lot of projects currently say and
we're gonna make ways to so you can have
your own data it's kind of missing the
point um so in United States these
opinions are protected as corporate free
speech so there's really nothing you can
do about them in a way so what you see
is that people are becoming aware of
this of that this is going on that these
ratings are being made you see this more
and more and what you also see that
people start to optimize their behavior
so like for example you know if you find
that Facebook is now starting to give
advice on loans but
on your Facebook friends you've gotta
start thinking like in China about who
are my Facebook friends and you also see
that these algorithms of course are
rarely fair but I'm gonna go into also
March but yeah this started really a big
effect on us um oh yeah these are some
examples of what is he having now so
Spotify a couple weeks ago said what
you're listening to will now be sold as
a life as a rating about your mood so
your mood is now available to
advertisers and of course you go further
than that and this is an interesting
case where people got physical letters
in the mail about a skin condition they
had and they'd never told them that
although he had done is go online look
up information about the skin condition
and these data brokers were able to
connect these people who were searching
online through their physical home
address and then solve this data and
this connected data and people got
physical mail so this already you can
forget about being anonymous online
already there are companies now that
offer you know to give the real identity
of people who were surfing um this is
not a mind-bending video that I
recommend you watch
it's about psychographics it's via a
company in the you know in the UK called
Cambridge and Latika and they have been
very influential in getting both Trump
to win and getting the Brits it's to to
break apart this video is mind-blowing
this his honesty in saying how he uses
these these data these scores about you
these subjective you know your
psychological profile basically they've
gathered from you from your on your
online data to influence messages to
better reach you as a folder right so
they know that if you are a new highly
neurotic and isn't that they will give
you a message about gun rights and if
you're a highly this and that they will
give you another message so they've very
focused targeting you micro targeting
you based on your psychological profile
to get you to vote a certain way
um and of course a week after after a
week afterwards we saw that this dataset
was actually leaked and again here so
you see this you know what I was talking
about this is the model data right
well as data described as modeled voter
behavior ethnicities and religions was
leaked so this is about 200 million
Americans this data set got leaked
including all the psychological profile
stuff that's scary now when I give this
talk at a tech conference I always get
the thing that's not new we've been
rating people for forever you know your
bank always had with ratings and no it's
not new but this is deeper and it's
everywhere right so now your green
grocer has not just scores about your
creditworthiness
but about your psychological profile
that's a whole new ballpark and this
market is huge all right some estimates
said in 2015 in the US alone it was
worth 150 billion that's including you
know things like Facebook and all that
but that's just to give you an example
to scale and ok and let's get this so at
the short-term and you could say that
the DC systems in the short-term do have
some advantages right they could create
trust you might rent your room to
someone on Airbnb through the trust the
system has created through these ratings
as valuable they might be able to reduce
crime there are long-term advantages and
those are being extolled a lot people
are talking about that was a lot but um
I want to talk to you about the
long-term negative effects of living in
a reputation economy because I think
those are rarely talked about I think in
general which you could say if you want
to have a summarized in a ways that all
these companies are interested in risk
manager you as a risk and when you see
that this this pressure to manage risk
is kind of put on the shoulders of the
consumer of the citizens who themselves
will start to manage themselves as a
risk all right I don't want to be a risk
I've once a good loan I want to go this
and that so I will be less of a risk so
the company will accept me and that
brings us to social cooling right the
the the long-term effects I'm going to
talk to you about three aspects that I
think are we will see in the long term
and I've kind of already talked about
the first one which is that we'll see a
rise of a culture of self-censorship
right we've already seen these things
happening with people not clicking on
links that much anymore and loads of
studies are pointing this out
now especially the one about spring
break was the one that really started
this for me this exploration into this
the subject and where people you know
the students don't go as wild as they
used to on spring break because they're
being watched the videos will go online
the next day so yeah that's fascinating
this is what the girl says from Spring
Breaks is we are very very reserved you
don't want to have to defend yourself
later so you don't do it right that's
one of the quotes from these students
who just don't party as hard anymore and
in scientific circles this has this
effect has been long for known for a
long time it's called the spiral of
silence where you don't want to say
something weird or fall out of the
mainstream ideology so what you see here
basically is this first point is the
idea of self-censorship is that what I
find so horrifying about it is that you
do have freedoms right you do have the
freedom of expression for example but
you don't use it all right because
you're feel the social pressure to not
to not do it right so that's really
insidious in a way right that's really
weird
the second thing is if you look at the
first part of part was about how if
individuals reacts to this reputation
economy but the second thing is what
this does to a society in the long term
and that you will see societal rigidity
society will be less able to change and
that's very much where we see the
societal value of privacy because I
think what privacy allows is for
minority values to in the long run
become majority values heat is time and
time again in society so let's give an
example let's look at weed here in the
Netherlands right in the Netherlands
weed was illegal but then of course you
know some people try it at home and then
hey Janeen you should try as a bit of
weed it's and then she was like wow
that's not so bad and slowly but surely
society's opinion about these things
changes you know in the background
beneath the surface then after a while
people are like you know what are we
still worried about and then society's
opinion changed changes that's because
privacy allows us to do things outside
of the view of the controlling eyes you
know just explore
and you see that a weed is interesting
but the more important thing is of
course what Martin Luther King points
out that this is also how society
changed his values about things like
discrimination about gay rights etc so
Martha King has a great video where he
talks about how proud he is to be
maladjusted he doesn't want to adjust to
you know the pressures of society to
accept the discrimination and all that
so this is a pretty you know important
thing about privacy about feeling free
to to fight against the justices that's
related to this idea the third thing
that in a long term could happen if we
live in a society like this that will
create a culture of risk avoidance and
this more of our economic arguments you
could say and I'll give you an example
so there was an experiment in New York
in 1995 where they started giving
doctors already scores on how they were
doing and of course if patients died
under their knife that was a negative
effect negative influence on their score
so what you found was that these doctors
started to the doctors who operated on
you know high level cancer patients
cancer patients with advanced stage
cancer the doctors who tried to help
these people they got low scores because
these people relatively often died let's
say like one and two of them died so
these doctors had low scores
because they had the guts to help people
how the doctors who didn't do anything
who said you know sorry I'm can't help
you those had high scores because people
didn't die under the knife these people
died prematurely so you see that these
systems create these perverse incentives
to to not take risks to avoid risk and
of course with you know people like
doctors and other professionals in our
society we would like them to take risks
right risk taking risk is important and
if we care to set strong incentives to
not take risks that's a problem if you
cease very much you're a paradox of the
creative industry that I'm sure we're
all you know part of which that um
Sarris didn't touch but if being having
the guts to be different it was one of
the things that research point now is
really important for children to become
creative
this is about a project by Taino about
measuring surprise how children can
become more creative that's very
important now they have to be different
they have to be feel that it can be
different of course you can wonder in a
system where you know it's all about
writing you and scoring you all the time
to what extent you can still feel that
you can be different
I want to give you a short example of a
company that really freaks me out let a
comp that points to all these things and
it's called red owl and this is a trend
in the security business that really
worries me there about securing the
human layer of the enterprise you know
about insider risk and what they do is
they they really they gather all kinds
of data about the people and about their
employees in a company including you
know third party feeds social social
media data email all kinds of things
they create these you know it ingests
all the data sources and then they put
the pieces together and basically create
these risk scores for for citizens for
employees including you know who is most
likely to leak for example I think
that's kind of freaky of course it is
this is one that really blows my mind
which that they say it's about people
yes it's about people but not in a good
way you know this is really crazy but
this is what the market is going towards
so you see again this pressure this risk
is a risk aversion that's really
dominant okay so those were the three
things about social cooling the aspects
the you know the rise of self-censorship
the long-term ability of society to
change my lesson and we see you know
less ability to take risks which is
important as well for the economy now we
get to the final part of this talk which
is you know to not leave you all the
press is how do we deal with this and I
think there's a couple of areas that we
should quickly talk about which is
politics the wider audience the economy
and finally you and me and of course
first thing we do with to wake up
politics so inertia politicians like
Reserve said well we all have to be a
little bit a little bit more normal
no that's something that we don't need
right so the problem here is we are
becoming too transparent and some some
stories and does it slide again but you
could say the least with the Democratic
that deficits right it's a some of that
we don't want and I think God
politicians has to understand that
better yes really have to understands
how in the long run these systems could
damage democracy it's about a balance of
power right often these algorithms that
rate us are completely on transparent we
have no idea how they work but we are as
citizens very transparent
I think that's there's a power imbalance
there that politicians really have to
understand better luckily there are
things like the GD P R which is the new
European data protection regulation that
are really starting to fix this so
politicians are waking up on a European
level which is really great the second
thing that we have to do we have to
educate the public and that's one of the
things that I try to do a lot so I'll
give you a short example of one of the
things that we get it set up which was a
an exhibit last year we made called TVs
devices and one of the things that we
had there was a coffee machine called
taste your status and this was a coffee
machine that basically gave you coffee
based on your area code so if you lived
in a good area you code you've got
really nice normal coffee but if you
lived in a progressively worse
neighborhood you got progressively worse
watering watered-down coffee was just a
small arduino to pump the extra water
and it depending on the data and I'll
give you a short video about how that
works but this induction and there's no
sound so that won't really work but um
yeah there were lines for this thing and
people really got it there really it was
really it for us the best way to take a
shortcut the shortest way to explain
that your data is increasingly
influenced in your life right that's the
thing that people don't get like the
other things you do that data is coming
back to you and so yeah that's always
found these people to scores and how
many was rating do you think these
people have any idea I'll give this four
these are four-star people they got
first our coffee all right I guess the
core thing that I try to do here towards
you know getting the public to
understand is that for me is framing it
as an environmental issue I mean that's
the thing that I think could be very
useful that's course where Sochi
cooling comes in so I try to explain
people that data is not a new gold I
think that's a pretty bad metaphor I
think it because gold is so great I
think we need you know there's nothing
wrong with cool people like gold with
oil we better understand that there are
you know downsides to it right we really
understand that now we're in the middle
of you know going away from oil we see
the downsides I think we need to
understand the same thing with data and
look at it like we're looking at oil now
and at least who you know not that's
environmental nature damage but damage
of our social environment you could say
so that's again why I believe this this
metaphor is useful to say if oil is a
global warming data could lead to social
cooling so I create a little map and I
think if we look at where we are now you
know we're not you know which is we're
only just starting with this awareness
it's early days I mean there's no the
leaks were start of that but you know
people almost nobody understands the
disconnection in my experience again the
I already explained this I think what do
we understand is a long-term this could
be damaging trust like if you know oil
damages the environment you could say
that the trust is also something that's
being destroyed I think the third thing
we have to do after the the politicians
have to understand it and the citizens
have to understand that is that ways to
create markets for privacy friendly
products so I think again we could use
metaphors there like you know biological
food could turn into I ecological data
or something like that right it we have
to get some kind this part not a
metaphor or if I have to find again
metaphors to get people to understand
they need to have good data good
services just like you know we started
to eat biological food we need to have
that for data so yeah otherwise you
could end up with things like this or or
you know this data severe effects on
your chances on the labor market and
finally the the thing that I think we
have to stop doing individually is where
to stop saying that we have nothing to
hide I think that's that's most you
probably understand this as a problem
and we're gonna skip the big picture
which I'm because I don't have any time
right to do that
okay um very briefly to say is that this
loss for who explains that when people
say you have enough to hide they mean
against the old system of control like
police a crime you please pitch
you go in front of Judge you go to
prison we understand that system of
control that's what people mean when
they say I've nothing to hide that mean
that towards that system I understand
that but there's a new subtle system up
on top of that about you know you
perform the wrong behavior that gets
noticed and then you get subtly
influence to perform for more preferably
hey behavior that's what the loads are
points to and I think that's what's
going on here so when people say I have
enough to hide the mean from the old
system from the police you do have
something to hide right so if anything
I've learned in the past couple of years
I've been able to explain in one
sentence what privacy is privacy is the
right to be imperfect and this is really
important your right to have right
because we're all human so we're all
important all the time and after here
nerds say well privacy was just a phase
we're going away from that like it's
some kind of evidence drug thing I think
that's ridiculous I mean if you compare
to other the rights that we have you see
that right if you say women's rights
were just a phase was there for a while
it's gonna go away now you see how silly
this is to say and of course Edward
Snowden does it even better when he says
arguing that you don't care about the
right to privacy because you have
nothing to hide
it's no different than saying you don't
care about free speech because you have
nothing to say right so privacy is a
fundamental human rights and there's a
reason for that
in conclusion we really have to
understand develop new ones underspend
understanding of these privacy issues
new data issues especially all of us
politicians my mom we've done this
anticipate these long-term side effects
that I've been talking about with
anticipate social cooling and I hope
that's optimistic view for me I hope
that's a way by comparing it to global
warming it also says that we can fix
this right we are fixing dorming we can
fix data if we don't we might end up
with a society that's more well behaved
but also perhaps a little bit less human
thank you
Thanks any questions thank you very much
guys for for being here attempting
someone who was willing to stand in
going straight from heaven no problem
talking about cooling of society
Evans gift okay we still have 14 minutes
for the next lecture but I have someone
someone who found the microphone are you
willing to answer one question I
couldn't agree more than it was
fantastic what you said yeah but my
question is don't they realize that we
need creative people we need people who
do unexpected things we need people who
are out of the yeah are across any
border or or because they are the future
and they have to create wealth so if we
suppress any innovation because it was
not seen before I have worked in
research and it was very curious that
they said how this is totally new I said
yes that's why I'm here yeah okay my
whole point is yes that we don't most
people don't realize that you know I
think fear is a short-term emotion and
and creativity long-term emotion you
could say it's about long-term
understanding of Technology and that's
really something that we're don't we
don't excel at currently and that we
have to improve and of course this is
not really a story that you know a lot
of tech people really want to hear right
because they want to hear the story
where they're blockchain is fixing the
worlds and everything's gonna be amazing
Desa Silicon Valley story of course it
sells technology and if you're gonna say
well let's be nuanced let's also look at
the negative sound effects in a long
term it's always going to be an uphill
battle
yeah I'm afraid so no gig guys welcome
to the semi-automated society of today
that's what it is thank you see you for
the next lecture in 30 minutes bye-bye
[Applause]
[Music]