[Music]
so what we're going to talk to that day
about is how to structure activism right
we all know this feeling that we're
frustrated with the way things are right
now everyone will change it but it's a
grind against the machinery that are the
corpse of this world and we want to
defeat time and we want to win this
fight but in order to do that we might
need a little more structure than we
have right now it works for camps
because those are smooth short time
investments but maybe for longer-term
projects and longer-term interests we
need some other structures so today dr.
Reebok is going to tell us about these
kinds of ideas that they are using
she's CEO at radically offensive
security rediculous offensive radically
open security are the open security yeah
and so take it away a big round of
applause for her please so good evening
so today's talk is I think a little bit
different than some of the talks that I
give I often times give technical talks
sometimes I give business model talks
but today what I actually really want to
do is give a little bit of a personal
talk I'm busy with a social enterprise
that also happens to be a security
consultancy company and I'm hoping today
that by explaining what I'm doing that I
can perhaps inspire some of you to want
to attempt some similar things so let's
start with a question it's a bit cliched
but what would you do if you knew that
you could not fail so a lot of us in the
IT industry we
get sucked into these very comfortable
living patterns and employment patterns
and you know many of us are of course
are quite lucky you know we can get
pretty good paychecks you know doing the
stuff that we love and but at the end of
the day is what we're actually spending
our time on what we really want it to be
spending our time on you know I mean if
you could really choose anything like
what was your dream from when you were
young you know what it what is your
dream now if there's one thing that you
could change about the world you know
what would it be and what would you do
if time wasn't an issue if money wasn't
an issue what would you do well for me
you know for me I mean part of the
reason right now why I think for me
activism is really important is because
of the current political climate you
know like many of the people here in the
room of course some of the political
events in the United States are somewhat
alarming of course the trend that's also
spreading to the rest of the world
including Europe you know it's it's
undeniable and at least for me
personally I feel a calling you know in
the changing political climate to try
and at least do something to the best of
my abilities to try and make some
positive change but I think that for me
personally the call to really want to
make things better started actually
quite a while ago so this is a picture
of me back in high school basically at
the time you know sort of teenager
growing up in in the south of the United
States you know now we're basically
talking about probably the mid to late
90s okay and just as a little bit of
contextual information not that I think
it makes a whole huge amount of
difference but I for example myself
happened to be a lesbian now growing up
in the late 90s you know again this is
25 years ago in the
south of the United States it was not
the most amicable political climate Hill
I say you know and I got a bunch of
pushback from a lot of places you can
react to that in several different ways
but for me the way that I reacted to
that was kind of wanting to push back so
I did you know after a while decide that
part of the way to kind of harness that
energy was to try and put it into
activism so for example for a while
again these are stories I don't usually
tell but for example I was a member of a
group called the lesbian Avengers for a
while anyway big big trouble a bunch of
troublemakers we ate fire and like
caused all kinds of problems but you
know basically it was me sort of at the
time trying to take something you know
that directly influenced me and really
to try and mobilize it and you know turn
it into something impactful so I could
ultimately make the world better also at
the time when I was in the United States
you know again at that political climate
it was basically very it was still pre
9/11 and the country was very much
looking inwards and there were so many
things about the American dream that I
just didn't think we're right you know
things like you know I grew up in an
upper middle-class suburb you know all
the students you know had sort of larger
cars than their teachers you know I
thought it was incredibly irritating and
obnoxious but what I discovered of
course at that time is sort of you know
that you know though the house the big
house with a white picket fence that
actually doesn't make people happy you
know to the point that you know these
people who sort of have everything
they're not politically engaged you know
they just are trying to you know live
that American Dream you know to the
point that you know one neighbor around
the corner at some point actually
committed suicide you know and it kind
of starts to make you evaluate and sort
of ask the questions of you know what
are we spending our time on you know we
come from these places of opportunity we
come from these places of economic
opportunity of Education you know for me
personally also I mean I'm white which
also confers any number of you know
undeserved advantages but then the
questions start
to become how do you take these
privileges how do you take these
advantages and how can you actually turn
it into something where you can attempt
to have this positive impact instead of
just getting caught in the rat race and
just doing everything because you think
you're supposed to be doing it so you
know for me my first real foray into
probably what I would call tech activism
because of course me also another thing
about me that's undeniable is I'm an
incredibly huge geek and I love it and
I'm proud of it
and you know for me also technology was
also one of those things you know I'm
just like many people of the people in
the audience here I have been using
computers since I was 7 I started on a
8086 you know and gw-basic you know with
the with a 300 baud modem you know I'm
one of those so you know tech always has
been also you know a hobby of mine you
know if if I were you know an artist
tech is my clay but I don't have to
explain it to the people here in this
room you guys know you know I'm
preaching to the choir and this kind of
stuff but the first time I think I did
something really what I would call tech
activism was when I was working as a PhD
student and then later as an assistant
professor at the Free University of
Amsterdam so some of you if you go back
a little while might know me from back
in the days when I was working on RFID
security research back in 2006 I have
the notoriety that I was the first
person to publish a proof of concept of
malware for radio frequency
identification tags the so called RFID
virus this basically went viral
back in 2006 again this is ten years ago
I'm starting to feel old but you know
but it really you know went viral in a
period before viral was even a thing it
was all over the papers it caused a
whole lot of reactions and ultimately
you know to the point that like after
the research was published I got 200
emails in the first day you know I mean
everything ranging from people who loved
the research people who hated the
research you know people almost who
threatened me people who
marriage proposals I mean you know no
but it's the kind of weird stuff that
you get you know when occasionally when
things get in the news after that I also
did another project called the RFID
Guardian which was basically building an
embedded device which was sort of like a
firewall man-in-the-middle device for
RFID tags it actually was my intention
at the time to attempt to commercialize
the RFID guardian I had some subsidy
which I had at the time but sort of due
to circumstances the subsidy dried up
before I was expecting it to and
ultimately well the problem with
hardware is if it's half-finished
it's a doorstop so basically we never
finished our analog front-end and then
that basically caused the project to die
well it happens I mean I basically
consider it I can I consider myself to
be an entrepreneur and I sort of look at
the RFID Guardian and how I wanted to
realize it sort of as my first failed
startup but that's okay you know you
have to sort of have failures before you
can move on and have your successes and
of course I learned a whole lot from
that process one thing I learned was
that hardware is hard yeah but you know
I also learned quite a bit sort of you
know my initial leaning is sort of into
being interested in in business but what
really struck me from the time though
was sort of the impact and the dialogue
that it caused I mean at one point
people got mad at me at one point I was
at a conference and the chief privacy
officer at the time of Philips looked me
straight in the eyes and said your
research is bad for my company and this
is the chief privacy officer right
anyway but look I'm not saying this
depicted on Philips but you know the
point is that you know sometimes your
research is going to ruffle some
feathers also at the time also with the
RFID virus stuff
f-secure antivirus had actually
published a full-page ad saying how
among other things they debunked the
RFID virus you know so people were
debunking my research this is when you
know you've made it when like people
take out full-page advertisements
attacking your
[Laughter]
but you know not that I was unique in
that because of course some of the other
great RFID security researchers at the
time I mean heaven knows the team at the
Rob Bowden university I'd got more than
their own share of problems so you know
your research is good man you start
getting problems but you know at the end
of the day though I mean for me it was
never really just about you know
research it was about RFID and it was
about the ubiquitousness of computing
and it was about privacy and it was
about the security implications and the
fact that you know the companies
wouldn't own up to the problems and what
I really learned from that period of
time is that you can say to a company
you're insecure and then the reaction is
going to be no I'm not you know and the
thing is you can't really tell them you
know that they have problems you you
have to show them and this is sort of
what I learned being an academic you
know you can try sometimes and have a
dialogue a dialogue can help but I think
at a certain point it actually only gets
you so far but then the question is you
know if it only gets you so far
what else can you do you know what else
is next so you know so the problems then
you know if you do want to change the
world and answering the questions of
what's next you know people might ask
the questions of ok so what do we do if
we want to build a change making
organization you know do we create a
charity do we create an NGO do we create
a foundation you know but the problems
with a lot of these forms of well
building social organizations is that
they're dependent so for example
dependence upon subsidies and as an
academic researcher that was one of the
problems personally that I had you know
again due to the economic climate at the
time the subsidy dried up and then once
the subsidy was gone it's game over you
know and most of the not-for-profit
entities out there are either dependent
on subsidies or they're dependent on
donations you know
well I'm gonna get a little bit more
into things like social enterprises but
you know part of the reason why I think
it's actually important is because
sometimes if you want to build a change
making organization if you can create
something that can actually operate
independently that actually gives it a
far a lot more freedom to move and it
also gives it a lot greater chance to
actually survive so and of course coming
back to the whole political climate now
and Trump I mean a lot of the problems
of course is that if you are running
some kind of an ideal organization you
know this is not the most stable climate
right now for getting those subsidies
they're starting to reroute them you
know to other places so I think you know
unlike any other period in time I think
that creating self sustainable you know
positive change making organizations is
going to be more important now than it
ever has been before you know because
the generosity you know from some
governments that we've had and you know
might be a thing of the past and I
wouldn't necessarily rely on it
so you know another thing is that and
coming back to the issue of trying to
tell companies to change their behavior
so I'm a member of this thing called the
spindle in inspiration council there's
this organization called partisan
Amsterdam which is this sort of group of
NGOs that that work together and one
time I was speaking with a lot of these
people from the NGO and they were
talking about for example companies like
like Shell and they were saying you know
they're doing all of these really
horrible things in Nigeria you know in
other places what can we do you know can
we talk to them you know we've tried
talking to them but what do we do and
this is the problem I mean you can Lobby
you can protest again you can publish
research but it doesn't necessarily mean
that they're gonna listen and one of the
things I think that I've discovered
about social entrepreneurship is that
the one way that I think you can get the
companies to listen is to hit them where
it hurts and you know where it hurts
in their wallet that's the way it is the
only way I think that these big
companies will listen is if you hurt
them financially and how do you hurt
them financially build something better
so business activists consider it to be
a dirty word you know business big
business business is always the problem
but the question is can business if we
repurpose it in just the right way can
that business actually be part of the
solution now one of the things about
business that I think makes it a really
ideal form of well vehicle for activism
is that it is set up in such a
ridiculously independent way I mean the
whole concept of corporate personhood
you know I mean obviously corporations
are not people but you know they've done
enough lobbying to sort of set up in the
legislation as if they are oh yeah
companies they have rights you know I
mean oftentimes companies have more
rights than than individuals do but the
point is as activists we can exploit
that you know precisely because of this
corporate personhood it means you have a
lot of freedom to be able to act and it
has only means you have a lot of freedom
to be able to set things up in the way
that you want to set things up one of
the problems again with with charities
and foundations and NGOs is that you can
only perform a certain small amount of
commercial activity before you start
getting restrictions from the government
I mean if for example you're a
foundation that's registered as
charitable with the government there's
usually only a certain amount of
financial transactions that you can do
before you start coming into a grey zone
where you might lose your charitable
designation from government you know if
you're a company you don't have any of
these issues and if you're a company
there's really only two requirements
that you have to fulfill one you have to
stay within the law
and two you have to be able to cover
your own expenses that's it and for the
rest you can do whatever the heck you
want you know and again it's big
business that set it up this way but we
can repurpose it we can reclaim it you
know and we can use this for our own
purposes one entrepreneur that I mean
look good or bad agree or disagree but I
think he sort of exemplifies what you
can do with social entrepreneurship is
Elon Musk I mean talk about disappearing
subsidies of course you know the three
things that he's working on you know
that the space race solar energy and
electric cars I mean those are three
things that absolutely can no longer
count on being funded by anything
government related you know and and
research grants and things like that I
mean all of that is probably pretty much
guaranteed to dry up
but people like Elon Musk are doing more
for things like you know that like
electric cars that any academic
researcher has ever done you know what
he's also doing now with with solar city
for for solar panels he is harnessing
the vehicle of a company to essentially
try and change not just technology but
the political climate that is influenced
by that entire ecosystem if he can
actually accomplish what he's attempting
to do between solar city and Tesla you
know it could eliminate our dependence
on oil for example imagine how that
would change you know the climate of the
political climate over the world you
know not that everything Elon Musk has
done has been perfect because of course
you know he's also human he's also made
mistakes you know he's also got
personality quirks but but for me
personally I see him as a really
inspirational example you know and he's
also faced a lot of hurdles had some
problems managed to get over them and
you know has managed to build in
impressive but what's most impressive is
that self-sustaining organizations
self-sustaining you know and that for me
I think somewhat exemplifies what we can
do but I think I can get even more
idealistic than that but but I do take
him as a good case study and a good
example of what you can accomplish with
social enterprises another example that
I really really love this is a more
local one for folks here in the
Netherlands is an organization called
Butte Sora
so Burt Sora is a home health care
organization in the Netherlands and the
problem with health care is that health
care oftentimes has been structured in a
bit of a pyramid fashion so you know
you've got sort of the the bureaucrats
at the top you know and then they might
be running you know the hospitals or the
hell at home health care thing and that
there's you know then the layers of
management and then eventually you have
the the nurses that are absolutely at
the bottom and basically they go as far
as calculating how many minutes it takes
to apply a bandage you know how many
minutes that nurse is actually allowed
to spend you know and then calculating
into their route okay and then it takes
20 minutes to get to the next patient
and then in fact they're not even
patients they're customers here they're
you know that's sort of how they're
treated in traditional healthcare and
nobody likes it the nurses didn't like
it because you know they don't want to
be treated like you know like like
machines and they also don't want to
treat their patients like numbers you
know in a system so this guy his name is
just the bloke he basically figured out
that you know what we could do is we can
actually take that whole healthcare
structure and we could try
decentralizing it so instead of having
this really huge top-down structure
instead we can create these little
localized circles and then we can ensure
that they are completely decentralized
they can operate completely uniquely you
know independently of one another you
know they're all sort of brute Zurich so
they all operate with a similar set of
principles and operating procedures
if they need help they can sort of phone
in to the headquarters to get advice and
tips and to help resolve disputes and
things like that but except for that
they actually all work in the pit
completely independently and what wound
up happening was because they were
smaller and decentralized it eliminated
the overhead so what wound up happening
was not only were the nurses able to
stop treating their patients like you
know like like numbers but they actually
were allowed in fact we're encouraged to
actually sit down and drink a cup of
coffee you know with and to get with
their patients and to actually get to
know their patients and the nurses were
happy because they were actually allowed
to start treating their patients like
people you know and because you know the
work that they do I mean it's God's work
you know and it's their calling and you
know finally they were had the freedom
again to be able to spend the time doing
it in the way that they wanted to do it
you know and the patient's of course
also loved it because now again they
were no longer treated like numbers they
would now they were actually being
treated like people you know the only
people perhaps maybe who didn't like it
you know or some of the bureaucrats you
know who were losing some of their their
margin and some of their overhead off of
this but the truth of the matter was
buttes aura became so financially
efficient because they had stripped off
all of that overhead that they were
starting to actually become more
profitable than the the money you know
the previous market leaders that they
were actually trying to replace so at a
certain point what wound up happening
was the other health care providers went
to you'll stab look and said the way
that you are structuring buttes or we
want to do that too and what he did and
this to me is really the sign of a great
leader he helped them he went to his
competitors and he helped them to
restructure themselves so they also
could be more decentralized and so that
they also could could change the way in
which they were operating yes to become
more cost-efficient but of course it
also made them more social and in such a
way it wasn't about market share for him
you know it was about having a positive
impact on the world of home health care
you know and regardless of whether you
know Bruce Oreck had the percentage of
market share or his competitors did that
was actually irrelevant because he
changed his competitors and thus he
raised the bar you know with the with
home health care in the entire and other
ones you know this to me is really
inspirational so so for me personally
you know I've also attempted to build a
similar kind of kind of social
enterprise so for those of you who are
not already familiar with radically open
security but that basically is my own
social enterprise and it I set it up
actually as a not-for-profit computer
security consultancy company I started
at about three and a quarter years ago
and when I first started it everybody
was like you're doing what but you know
and people looked at it and they were
like well not for profit that's kind of
weird I don't know you know is this
gonna work
but you know three three and a quarter
years later and well look I'm up here
telling this story to you you know on
the big stage in this nice hacker camp
so we've done a few things right but I
mean what I think actually we have
managed to do is change a lot of the
things about the dialog about computer
security and the industry and openness
and transparency you know and sharing
and I think slowly but surely we also
are starting to influence also our
competitors and causing them to start
reanalyzing their own behavior so really
quickly I guess before I go on to the
next slide but just the core principles
of radically open security are basically
just ethics again open source we
everything we develop we release into
the open source and openness and
transparency so openness and
transparency what that means in practice
we invite our customers to join us in
chat rooms and they see and hear
absolutely everything that we're doing
while we work you know but we also
release all these tools to every
so we work using this principle called
chat ups I'm not gonna spend a lot of
time talking about that right now
in fact I have a whole separate talk on
that that I give but I'm not going to be
giving that today but the idea is that
we work in these chat rooms with a
globally distributed team and we have a
chat robot that actually facilitates our
operations and the chat robot is
actually quite interesting because it
assists us with everything from
penetration testing to documentation and
reporting to project management you know
to you know uh you know billing and
scheduling and all these different kinds
of things so it's super important to us
and we've open sourced everything you
know again with the hopes that at some
point our competitors can take these
tools and run with them why not you know
but a lot of people if I tell them about
what we're doing they're a bit hesitant
to want to take similar steps to do
similar things themselves another thing
I really like about radically open
security is I really consider us to be a
bit of a lifestyle business you know I
work we are based essentially a
collective of freelancers and small
businesses so they're you know I am the
only internal employee in radically open
security still after three and a quarter
years but we have about 35 freelancers
that are walking that are working
together you know and again the
organization is is the people so ya know
they're contractually bound occasionally
customers look at us a little bit funny
and say yeah but you have contracts you
have NDA is yes of course we do you know
but ultimately what it means is that
people are location independent so we
have people working all over the place
because it's essentially
business-to-business contracts with our
freelancers I don't have to deal with
immigration or work permits which makes
hiring really easy you know and yeah
ultimately it's just a construction
that's really scalable and that's really
worked really well for us that's why I
haven't been inclined to change it but a
lot about how we operate is actually
really quite weird but at a certain
point I just figured out that weird is
actually a benefit weird is actually an
advantage the other thing also is when
people know that you're we
they actually will accept that weirdness
from you and they will actually come to
relish it so we get away with a lot of
things I think that some other companies
can't because we have the reputation of
being weird so people kind of accept it
but it works well for us so you know
again I started at three and a quarter
years ago and I was optimistic when I
started it but I don't think I really
understood you know how far perhaps that
this all would go you know I mean we
have won a ton of awards for how we've
set up our organization
you know both for our operations but
also for our business model the Dutch
Chamber of Commerce called radically
open security the fiftieth most
innovative SME in the Netherlands you
know I'm really proud of that
you know we've also won a whole bunch of
other awards you know things like I was
inspiring 50 twice our hackers have won
some awards at blackhat in some other
places we've done this awesome net aid
kit project I don't know if you guys
know the Free Press unlimited but net
aid kit is a not-for-profit project that
we've done to help build them up
completely open-source Wi-Fi tour and
open VPN router so that's also a great
project of ours that I'm super proud of
you know and also yeah a sprout magazine
put us in their challenge or 50 which
yeah it was just an entrepreneurship
magazine so like 50 most challenging
startups in the Netherlands so and also
just sort of to peak it off like - two
months ago about CIO magazine in the
Netherlands actually called me the most
innovative IT leader in 2017
so look I'm not saying this to toot my
own horn I'm saying this because if you
take a chance and try and build
something different you never know where
it's gonna go you know when I first told
people that I was gonna start radically
open security they thought I was either
crazy or stupid or or you know or maybe
just deluded but they they didn't
understand how this could work
and now three and a quarter years later
people are seeing it work and I think in
another five years from now I think you
know as far as we've come you know I I
think we're gonna have a whole lot more
impact and I think we're gonna make a
whole lot more waves right now than we
already have
so but you know but people are hesitant
to want to think differently and people
are hesitant to want to create something
that's unique that really fits them and
fits their passion and that fits their
drives and there's a number of really
common excuses that I hear you know for
the reasons why you know they need to
stick with traditional business models
or why they need to stick with their
usual jobs you know or or why they need
to keep doing things the way that
everybody else has been doing it but we
need to pay our bills right well we pay
our bills too you know I mean look with
radically open security we charge market
conform rates to our our customers and
we pay market conform rates roughly to
our personnel you know so everybody is
able to pay their bills but what's
different about us though is that again
it's the manner in which we operate so
it's again the openness and transparency
the open source also you know set up as
being a not-for-profit company we
actually I forgot to mention this
earlier but we give 90 percent of our
profits to the NL net foundation 90
percent we literally have a contract
which set up with them we've already
made our first donation to them you know
at some point when we're more profitable
we'll wind up giving them more but of
course right now we're still a scale up
so we're still reinvesting on
to sort of build that sustainable
vehicle but it's starting to roll you
know a three and a quarter years later
and I'm also super proud of this that we
actually already have been able to start
giving a Nelnet some money and they're
actually right now in the process of
creating basically the radically open
security fund within a Nelnet so they
can actually start funding community
projects with that within the next few
months and they'll net will start making
some noise and announcements about this
so this is sort of your first little
preview of that but I'm so freaking
proud of that seriously I mean this was
like the vision that I had you know of
trying to take security consultancy try
and reclaim it from these huge
commercial black box corporate security
companies you know and look I mean we
obviously haven't you know completely
taken over everything you know they're
they're still there but what we are
doing is we their customers are starting
to walk away and their staff is starting
to walk away and at this point I've
heard for sure you know that they are
starting to actually have internal
strategy meetings trying to figure out
how they can combat the up-and-coming
threat that radically open security is
think about that it's a it's a David and
Goliath story you know why would
something like for example a big for
consultancy firm be afraid of us well
think about it
I think actually they do have really
good reasons to be afraid another thing
also is that the common well I'm
actually going to skip both since I'm on
the topic too - not scalable you know a
lot of people just sort of think yeah
but the open source business model
that's that means you have to give away
your products and sell services but
selling services in scalable well I'm
gonna tell you that it is but not in the
way that people usually think about so
with radically open security the way
that I see it yes we're a services
company but we're also a platform
there's a really good well you guys are
familiar now with for example uber and
airbnb I'm not saying they're great
companies you know we all have
differences with how uber and Airbnb
sometimes operates but the one thing
about uber and Airbnb is they are a
platform that essentially matches
producers with consumers and they have
an IT automation layer in between that
facilitates those operations and because
it's icy ICT facilitated ultimately it's
it's almost you know completely scalable
right because as long as they have in
the case of like let's say uber you know
the producers are the drivers so they're
people with a car who want some extra
money the consumers are the people who
want to ride you know and they have some
pay if they have money and they want to
go somewhere all over does is it matches
the two of them together right so think
about it now with radically open
security we have producers and we have
consumers so we have producers those are
the pen testers you know they have pen
testing skills they want a good job a
nice comfortable job and they want money
we also have consumers the consumers are
the are the companies our customers it
could be huge corporations it could be
governments it could be little tiny NGOs
whatever so but ultimately what
radically open security is doing because
we're a platform because we only work
with freelancers and SMEs is we are
matching the producers with the
consumers and we are building a platform
to provide a stable process and user
experience for both sides the
penetration testers have a certain way
in which they work so we provide them
with automated templates so for example
we have this a suite that we build built
called a pen text it is essentially the
core of our dock our documentation
workflow and reporting process we not
only open sourced it but we made it an
OS project so oh wasp pen text and butt
facilitates on the you know sort of on
the on the on the pen testing side
consistency you know and process and
making sure that the customers get a
reliable experience you know that's
consistent every time you know with the
pen testers it's sort of like a
competitive marketplace of you know of
pen testing jobs they log in and then
there's basically announcements and then
they basically say you know we've got
you know a job and it's going from this
state to this state we need you know
it's with these technologies you know
these tools and frameworks who wants it
and then basically based upon skills
availability and the price as number
three we then make a match between the
job and then groups of pen testers now
what we're doing is a bit more
complicated than ruber and Airbnb
because with uber and Airbnb the
matching is one-to-one whereas with
radically open security the matching is
many-to-many because you will have
several pen testers working together on
a job and you will also have multiple
pen testers in the chat or sorry
multiple customers in the chat room that
are interacting with us so I mean it's a
more complicated process to facilitate
but fundamentally it's the same thing we
are building a platform company and we
are automating almost everything
radically open security is a security
consultancy company but I also see us
actually is turning into a DevOps
company that's actually what we've what
we've become lately because our
increased use of things like a
containerization continuous integration
you know justjust I have been hiring
less and less administrative stuff and
more and more coders and sis admins and
DevOps people because we are building
this platform we are building this you
know automated open-source layer and by
the way I'm open sourcing it right but
but that's the point we've got this
platform which essentially means that
yes we are a services company but what
happens when we finally get this
platform right how could we scale look I
mean I'm not doing this because I want
route radically open security to grow
big that's not the point
that's missing the point I'm doing it
because I want to change how the
industry works
and I'm perfectly happy to give away
this platform so everyone else can use
it but ultimately what I believe is that
how we're working with openness and
transparency and with the chat room so
the customers can actually interact with
us as equal partners rather than you
know as being traditional you know
vendors and customers you know I I just
think it's a better way of working you
know and if I can give away these tools
and then enable everyone to do it this
way then why wouldn't I want to do that
the other question is hard to get
funding so yes being a nun for-profit
not-for-profit company makes it harder
to get investments you look 8 at the
very beginning an angel investor had
offered me a half a million euros in
funding and I turned it down because I
did not want to give up one iota of
control of what I was building because
the second you accept venture capital
you've already lost you've already lost
and if you're trying to build any kind
of organization with any amount of
integrity you know having to constantly
explain yourself to some investor of
some kind it's gonna shackle you you
know but I think actually especially for
the kind of thing that we're building
you don't actually need much funding to
get it started we bootstrapped radically
open security using my savings account
okay and it's not that I'm not rich or
anything I'm really not but the way that
we did it is we again started as a
services company you need investment to
create products but you don't really
need much investment to do services and
what we did is we actually used services
to bootstrap our products and to
bootstrap our Rd you know because once
you actually have turnover then you can
actually start to reinvest some of that
into sort of building that vehicle that
you're building and and you know it's
not going to grow as fast as if you have
some kind of an investor but it is going
to maintain your integrity and it allows
for slow organic growth the other nice
thing actually about not having venture
funding is because when you don't have
very much of a buffer when you don't
have very
much of a margin it means when you make
incorrect decisions you feel the pain
quickly I've had moments you know in
radically open securities history where
I have made incorrect decisions you know
in running the company and incorrect
decisions and trying to decide what to
sink money into and what I shouldn't
I've had months I had one month where I
literally had to take a 30,000 euro loan
from a friend of mine under my own
personal title to be able to make
payroll that month you know cuz I made
the wrong guess you know fortunately it
worked out you know I mean we basically
wind up getting the money back I paid my
friend back it's all good
you know these are stressful moments
when you're the director of such a
company you know but you know but but at
the same time though the other thing
also is that if you don't have
investments and if you're a charitable
organisation if you're a social
enterprise you will have a lot of
friends so we don't have investors but
we have had a number of partners that
were willing to give us interest-free
loans and guess what
that's even better throughout the
history of radically open security we've
had about 25 thousand euros in
interest-free loans from friends of ours
why am I telling you this
well openness and transparency right
okay why not but the point is we've paid
all of that back now you know and it did
enable me to be able to bootstrap the
company without giving up any of that
control and too many people go to
investors because it's easy too many
people go to investors because it's sort
of that sexy Silicon Valley ethos of you
know do it fast you know make it big
have your exit you know but you don't
have to do it that way you know and
that's one of the great things I think
about being an Amsterdam and not being
in the Bay Area because I have spoken
with people in Silicon Valley before
about what I'm building
and one particular CEO of a company in
Silicon Valley she could not wrap her
head around why I would go to so much
trouble to build an organization that
I'm not gonna get rich from
you know whereas in the Netherlands I
think radically open security is the
kind of company that perhaps could have
only started in the Netherlands you know
because this is a country that is social
this is a country that gets it to the
highest levels of the government we get
support and I've appreciated that and
that has helped us countless times the
other thing also is things like for
example customers won't accept it you
know but but really huge bureaucratic
organizations yeah but you're weird and
non-commercial why would they want to
work with you well I'll tell you why
they want to work with us it's because
the way that radically open security
works and the way that we succeed is we
find one geek you know like a tech geek
like the kind of person who is in a
conference like this we find one geek
that gets it and then that geek fights
to get us into their company you know
and that geek navigates the bureaucracy
within their own organization for us
because they know why we're doing this
and they want us there you know and this
is the kind of stuff that like money
can't buy this is the kind of stuff that
the only way you can buy it is by
believing in something and fighting for
something and letting other people know
what you're doing so that they want us
to help you and support you and in such
a way you know radically open security
and in the first you know against three
and a quarter years we already have had
between 50 and 60 customers you know
across sectors from government to law
enforcement to banks insurance companies
media companies telcos hosting providers
IT companies software SMEs little law
firms you know NGOs you know it's just
university is hopeless whole everything
in between you know and how did we get
into so many places it's it's because of
those geeks they get it it also doesn't
hurt that sometimes those geeks happen
to be the CEO
but you know but this is something
that's you know our competitors can't do
and this is why they're starting to get
afraid again for good reasons
well competitors steal our IP now that's
one that I hear a whole lot you know
sometimes I talk to other people who are
running startups and you know I'll say
to them you know what your building is
awesome if you just open sourced it you
guys would kill the market and then they
say yeah yeah but but if we open source
it then our competitors are gonna take
it and run with it
yeah I think I think that what line of
thinking is really a fallacy because if
your competitors first of all your
competitors are not going to adopt it
that easily partly a because pride you
know many of them have you know don't
not developed here look I mean I'm
giving away my tools already as open
source you know as radically open
security have all of my competitors
adopted it yet no are they going to I
don't know we'll have to see but the
moment they do it's gonna be admitting
that the way that we're doing it is
better so I mean I think they're
probably not going to adopt it until the
point where they realize that they have
to you know but you know that's cool
another thing also like from my days
with the RFID Guardian I also made
open-source hardware and software stuff
and I know again firsthand from
experience just because you put stuff
out there as an open source doesn't
necessarily mean that other people are
going to use it because then it would
mean that they have to learn it they
have to troubleshoot it they have to be
able to debug it and maintain it up
stream upstream things you know if you
know if you want to to be able to keep
you going well being able to benefit
from additional developments you know
that kind of stuff so it's actually
complicated for other people to steal
your stuff but what other people don't
realize though is that if you do give
that stuff away what you're gonna get
back is goodwill what you're gonna get
back is reciprocity when you give you
get you know I mean you don't want to do
it with those intentions you know I mean
you don't want to just give
you can get but if you give it makes
people want to give back and that's the
thing you know and as soon as that when
you give it lowers the barrier to entry
for people to actually use your stuff
you know and ultimately you know one of
the rules of business is once you have
users you can sort of monetize the whole
thing but until you have users if you
know there's nothing to monetize and the
point is that if you keep this stuff
proprietary and then sell it or have
licensing fees you are creating a
barrier to entry for people adopting
your stuff isn't that silly
you know but people don't think about it
that way you know but business is
changing the world of business is
changing how it's being done is changing
and the people who don't change you know
our dinosaurs and you know those
dinosaurs are gonna become obsolete
until they figure it out and learn how
to also change in similar ways you know
but again this is the kind of stuff now
that is going from the IT field to you
know to MBA programs you know but yeah
so so these are again some of some of
the common objections but I have to say
that you know radically open security
has managed to do what we have been
doing not just despite these things but
because of them you know and that's why
I'm out here telling the story if you do
things differently and you do things
that are unique sometimes it will evolve
in ways you didn't expect and it will
also pay you back in ways that you don't
expect so the sky's the limit
I don't think what we're doing as
radically open security is necessarily
unique you know there are other social
enterprises that are out there I mean I
do think we're somewhat unique in the
computer security space you know of
course an IT in general there's a lot of
other organizations out there doing good
you know like the Mozilla Foundation and
you know others but but I mean take the
whole concept of a not-for-profit
business so you know basically taking a
commercial front-end for a
not-for-profit back-end how many other
industries could we take that concept
and use it with you know I mean
buurtzorg has already sort of doing that
with health care and with home nursing
but could we also use it for education
could we also use it for transport for
agriculture
you know perhaps for banking
you know also with banking we've seen
other examples like Grameen Bank and you
know the world is changing you know and
if you can take in the area that you're
you're good at I mean for me it happens
to be computer security you know that
again I'm an artist and computer
security is my clay you know other
people are gonna have different clay and
you know I'm an artist of computer
security and other people can perhaps be
artists of banking maybe they can be
artists of agriculture artists of
healthcare why not you know and you
don't just have to do art to be an
artist you know so that leads me then
back to begin I think to end where we
started so let me ask again
what would you do if you knew that you
could not fail thank you
if you have any questions please line up
at the microphones in the middle and
then you can ask them there yeah we have
a question here aren't you scared
in your task of not becoming a corporate
bastard that you become a corporate
bastard yes all the time yeah yeah I
mean I think that from time to time it's
really important to reevaluate where
we're at and to reevaluate where we're
going and you know sometimes I also make
incorrect decisions about things you
know I think it's good to have the
people in your company thinking along
with you and also to make sure that
they're sort of imbued with the same
values you're right the open and yeah
and like for example when we have
customers I have sometimes staff members
that will actually question whether or
not we want to be working with a
particular customer
you know police defense you know those
are the kinds of things that tend to
raise discussions internally and
sometimes I'll make decisions about
things and sometimes my staff members
will call me on it and whenever they
call me on it I thank them so yes you're
completely right at some point
yeah at periodic intervals we do need to
re-evaluate what we're doing to make
sure that the direction that we're in
remains consistent but I also think that
because I'm so open and public about
what I'm doing I'm pretty sure that if I
were to change it I would get a hell of
a lot of criticism for it
so I think that's also a whole lot of
you know a little bit of insurance also
to make sure that the that we also stand
on the right path and on the good and
narrow you know I'm trying to almost be
a caricature of myself and I'm trying to
make the company a caricature of itself
and sort of how you know pure I'm trying
to make it take that path and I think if
we were to stray from it I think I would
hear that from several places at least
that's what I'm hoping
Thanks
hi there when you talk about creating a
company it's always the question is how
you prevail sorry how did the legal kind
of what is it's called the LLC or what
what did you do found yeah so we are
something so we're a Dutch company so a
Beibei but we have this designation with
the Dutch tax authorities that's
something called a fiscal fundraising
institution so a fist coliforms ver from
the instilling so that basically is a
construction we stole from the Dutch
churches so churches sometimes want to
do a commercial spinoff okay and then
the the church does this commercial
activity and they want to get the money
tax-free back to the church again so
there's a Dutch language institute
called regina coeli that those of you in
the netherlands might know them
otherwise as being called the Nolan fund
v so basically the nuns from a little
village called v and what it is is it is
the language institute is an
independently operating language
institute i mean it's it's a commercial
enterprise but ninety percent of the
profits from that go back to the to the
nuns so we essentially stole that
construction from the churches and we
just made our spin-off our commercial
spin off a security consultancy company
and we made our church the NL net
foundation so it's a bit of business
model hacking but that's how we set it
up yes hi my name is Casey thanks for
the talk I like this a lot I have a very
similar business called the hive it's
about 40 people um difference is I
actually have employees so you know but
probably doesn't matter much because I
find that the hardest thing is getting
loyalty and the only way you can do that
is by providing training and learning
options yeah right so I was wondering
how you do that yeah with us I mean it's
training is a bit difficult because we
work with this whole peek over our
shoulder concept which basically means
again customers are in the chat rooms
with my pen testers the problem is if I
use junior
people it becomes evident to the
customer incredibly quickly that their
junior so I have to admit I have a bias
towards hiring senior staff because
they're less likely to screw up in a way
that my customers are gonna see it I
mean I will sometimes hire mid-level
stuff and then kind of attempt to train
them up but people fresh out of school
as things are right now they tend to not
be a very good fit for my company I feel
bad about that I wish I had a better
training budget maybe when we're larger
we'll have more of a margin for that
kind of stuff but as of right now that I
sort of avoid the problem by not hiring
juniors maybe that's not a good solution
for your senior people they will only
stick with you if you keep them
continuous chances to learn and also you
know improve yeah this is the way
especially in Millennials are and
nothing I have to do about it so you
have to do it is yeah well I think that
they do learn a whole lot I mean I'm
providing them a stimulating environment
with a lot of freedom where they have a
lot of smart colleagues so I mean if
they have questions about like I'm
working I'm hacking some system and I'm
stuck you know can you guys help I mean
we've got a lot of really smart people
together and I think that we tend to
keep the smart people because you know
smart people like being with other smart
people someone's there there they don't
want to leave the community you know so
at least the good fits don't want to
leave so that is one way of retaining
people yeah the other thing also is just
that I think we have the reputation that
we've built up that we are very
competent in pentesting and and a lot of
customers tend to come to us with sort
of their specials you know so if they
have something that's particularly hard
or you know this weird embedded system
they want tested or a cryptographic
audit or sort of a mix of different
things in a single pen test they will
tend to choose for us and that's
actually really nice because when they
give us the harder jobs it actually also
tends to keep our staff really sharp so
you know I guess just by having the
seniors we've been able to provide
better quality and because we have the
better quality it means the customers
give us the more challenging assignments
and that turns into a virtuous cycle
cool yeah one heck I also uses having
them give a training to their peers they
love to do it and it's good for everyone
yeah
thank you for the questions another one
yeah when you I come from Germany and
when you look there there was kind of
trendy to do social entrepreneurship so
and when you look at the companies in
the end you would still seeing
investments of venture capital so how do
you experience the kind of social
washing that's going on when you in in
this sphere so how do I experience them
did I call my term would be social
washing like green washing the social
washing in the end when you look at them
they have venture capital and they and
they will do stuff that it's not from my
point of view and yeah I mean to me I
mean if anybody's accepted any kind of
venture capital I I don't think they can
really call themselves social I mean
maybe me but again this is kind of dogma
this is like my religion this is my
belief I mean maybe there's good
investors out there but I've never seen
them you know and and look it's easy to
call yourself a social enterprise but I
mean you need to walk the talk
you know and ultimately the the
community will see what you're doing a
judge so I'm sure to speak as around
afterwards some some minutes our time is
over now so I really enjoyed this talk
and I hope you did too
let's give or speak another round of
applause
[Applause]
[Music]