we have a new topic that's encryption so
I want to ask y'all who things
encryption are encrypting your emails
and stuff is a really good idea raise
your hand please
now that sort of people and who has ever
done it
encrypted email or something yeah
Oh what's the same amount and who is
doing it like on a regular basis like
say for but 50% of your online
communication your email who has like
50% encrypted Wow okay not much
happening in the audience I have to say
and that's a well-known problem I guess
you have nice encryption but people are
not really using it and not really at
all outside of this community I guess so
our next speaker is working with an
organization or project that's trying to
do something on this front the pretty
easy privacy project so I would like to
welcome to the stage here an Arnie
marques who is yeah head of the on the
main board of the pretty easy piracy
predation and is also separately from
that on the board of the Swiss case
Computer Club so that's why he might be
also familiar to you so you can start
now please give a warm round of applause
to Ronnie
thanks
taste-test can you hear me now yeah okay
so it works so this talk is about a
pretty easy privacy project that we
already had different talks and
different conference about it and here
we just want to prevent to present the
state where we are and not not just on
the technical level but also on the
social level collaborations we are
having with other organizations to go
faster in what we are doing here so it's
about automatic encryption for the
masters as you know that's a classical
slider nowadays in most in lots of talks
you know NSA but not just NSA all the
Chinese the Russians even the Swiss are
doing mass surveillance so even in
countries which we consider it safe
until now things are changing into the
wrong direction so even in Switzerland
we have now two laws which allow for
mass surveillance with selector searches
a word based stuff and everything I had
to talk about this topic yesterday if
you want to look it up what's possible
there and what we need is we need the
contrary so mass encryption and mass
Animas ation in the second step just to
stop this because politically things
seem a little bit as seem a little bit
difficult to change at the moment at
least
however the pep foundation where I am
member at in the council it's a Swiss
foundation we also have a political
standing the the foundation is
controlled by political activists by
people like Volker Burke and me from the
CCC and also Reina tangents and pata
loon from Germany they are also known
for their activism inside ticket all
garage so we are serious about this kind
of stuff and of course if possible and
if it makes sense we also support
political projects which have impact so
for example we supported this referendum
here stop it that's a lawful
interception law we failed with it but
however
which ride it at least well philosophy
of pep so we fully subscribe to the
cyberpunk manifesto and I hear some key
sentences so privacy is necessary for an
open society in the electronic age a
private matter is something one doesn't
want the whole world to know privacy is
the power to selectively reveal oneself
to the world so this project is about
fulfilling these propositions here and
of course we need to act we cannot just
make politics and wait that tools get
better we just we just have to take
action and so cypherpunks write code we
know that someone has the right software
to defend privacy and since we can't get
privacy unless we all do we are going to
write it and of course the pet project
itself as we will see later is not
really a crypto project because we are
not doing own crib that we are just
using crypto already there however
that's also quite a lot of work we need
to be cross platforms running and
everything must be ultimate eyes what
that we'll see later so another
important point is that we published the
code so that other peoples can take it
up and help us in that and we don't care
if someone is against it because mass
surveillance is also being done without
any consent in Switzerland you can
probably say that the people said yes to
mass surveillance law but at the general
level with Russians Chinese and
Americans and other countries doing
doing all of these kind of things I mean
there is no content at least also not
from countries which are outside of
their legislation because they are most
massively they are spying on foreigners
so they are just doing it and so we can
also do the same on just on the other
side however for this to work we also
need cooperation so this is kind of here
it's written for privacy to be
widespread it must be part of a social
contract people must come in to end
together deployed systems for the common
good privacy only extend so far is the
cooperation of one's fellows in society
so well why do we need this project
after the Snowden revelations I mean
already before in at the CCC for example
in Switzerland we did like self-defense
courses or I mean today they are known
as crypto parties and of course the
numbers of people increased after the
Snowden revelations but we we had to
learn that the people are not really
able to use these tools in the end I
mean you explained them public key
cryptography what is a private key well
is a public key what is revocation
certificate what is a passphrase and for
normal people I would say like my mother
that's just too much that's completely
not feasible
she she's able to install an app for
example and then probably she needs a
little bit help for the mail address or
something and then and then it should
just work so no further steps needed and
that's exactly the the idea we have with
this project here and now coming to
email which you want to protect first
that's the the first channel want to
protect there are two important things
here the first thing is that email usage
is still growing so almost everyone who
use the internet must have an email
address either even if you are just
using Facebook or Twitter usually you
need to set it up with an email address
and also the notifications by the way
which receive could be encrypted if for
example Twitter would allow to to safe a
public key up there at our system that's
not that all of this is not done
Facebook does it to some extent but well
Facebook is compete another story
because they do lots of surveillance
just inside the system anyhow and email
is also one of the you're still best
functioning federated identity systems
so as said everyone needs an email
address to identify themself to have an
account so we need to protect this
channel because flight tickets are far
going around like in clear text or
probably even even medical documents at
least in Switzerland there are lots of
people just sending things around like
this and this this must be protected
messages should be encrypted and signed
so scientists signed emails would also
be a nice thing Peppa toss is of course
automatically because if if you do that
and you can check that the signature is
correct you can also mitigate against
phishing attacks of course I mean if you
can detect that the message was sent by
a key you already verified then yeah
they should be away and I mean today you
know with with things like wanna cryin
not petty and stuff that could have been
helpful in lots of places like hospitals
or something where these things started
somehow so as said new PG is one of the
best known implementations of the open
PGP standard so there is the last one is
RFC for 880 explaining how it works and
about on the console you cannot expect
people to use it and with graphical
tools you have like n ik mail or
plug-ins for Outlook and stuff which are
already around usually you still need to
carry out some manual steps you need to
invoke the key generation and then they
ask you about passphrase perhaps so
these are things which are not feasible
for normal users so privacy needs to be
easy and not just good so we have
already good a privacy where the tools
are there but disability must be
enhanced so we need privacy by default
as we as we say it so that we changed
the standard behavior so every time when
it's possible messages should go out
encrypted
so what is the approach of pep
organizationally that's probably also
interesting and also important because
we saw in the cyberpunk manifesto that
you also need to spread these systems
and how how do you want to do that if
you don't have a concept how to how to
bring that into companies for example so
the first thing the pet project did
indeed was creating an Outlook blocking
because if you like it or not
outlook is one of the most used that may
looser agents on desktops and for that
purpose because the foundation which I
am representing is not doing business or
selling stuff for that purpose the
pepper in the pet project also there
also exists companies which are instance
which landed Luxembourg serving
different kinds of entities the
foundation itself is in Switzerland and
tax free and as I said in the beginning
controlled by by activists of privacy
and freedom of information and so forth
what's also important to know is that
the foundation owns the core code of pet
so you will see it later there is a an
architecture with with an engine and
with bindings or adapters around it such
that you can easily use the pet
functionalities or the automatisation
steps we do and all of this core code is
is in the ownership of the foundation
and belongs to the foundation itself so
you cannot just buy the pipe foundation
and dissolve anything everything because
it just it belongs to itself it's just
not possible you can perhaps exchange
the people and this will also happen at
some point of course but the things are
locked in the into the foundation okay
how is now this privacy by default
principles achieved well instead of
writing manuals how to use new PG we
just ultimate eyes the step so that
means concretely when you install a pep
for each email account you have used
aside we start with email but you can
also have author identities like XMPP or
whatever later on but for email of
course you might have different email
accounts one for business one for
private purposes and then for each of
these a key pair is generated RSA 4096
it's just default setting we have and
and and when you send out an email then
the the public key is attached such that
author PAP clients can automatically
import the key so this is the easiest
way we we we see to do it so because
it's also compatible if you for example
receive an email with an attachment and
the public key there you can just right
click import and then you can
communicate out with PAP people using
pad if you for some reason need to
deactivate this there is also passive
mode we call it you can click on this
and then the keys are not attached
anymore by default
despite if you received from the contact
you are writing to already an email that
was that in the header has some
information about PAP so there is an
expert version information and if if the
PAP client sees that and it says ok the
other one has PAP anyway so I can I can
attach the key but it might be a problem
in some cases to always have these
attachments so you can also deactivate
it if necessary we don't rely on key
servers or or any other centralized
platform so we don't have a platform
which would need to subscribe to like
authors have so it's just software for
the end-user devices and that thing with
the key servers I mean you can use them
you can opt in to you two
look up the keys on the kisser but as
you know everyone can just upload key to
the key server and that happens in in
some cases so this is probably not so a
good idea to do it by default so because
otherwise people might receive messages
they cannot decrypt because someone just
put the key up there and you can also
easily verify the contact using trust
words what our trust words trust words
are just representations of fingerprints
with words in natural language so we
just map a Ford DG text block to a word
so you can you can now you can have up
to up to 65,536 words the lists we have
are from libreoffice usually they're a
little bit smaller so you lose some
entropy but not much so usually it's 50
so each block is 15 point something bit
still so it should be enough entropy
there and yes as I said pep also wants
to stay compatible to things already
around so to just fit into the ecosystem
which is already to some extent there
are not so many people encrypting emails
but if someone is that it should be
possible to have interoperability here
whenever there is a decision privacy
versus security that's not the same it's
a privacy project privacy will be chosen
so that's the reason why the web of
trust by default is not used
episodes designed for multiple
communication channels so we will add
for through communication transports
into the engine that we were the next
thing which will happen quite soon will
be a XMPP so that you can also reach
your friends if they are using chat or
other things which are used so this goes
up to noon as we in the end we want to
have canoe net that's a peer-to-peer
thing to have also metadata protected so
but we'll just look what people are
using and the head and add more and more
stuff and also other crypto standards
and what we will never do the trip to
ourselves you just use the libraries
already there and also help in also help
in out auditing them if not already done
a special thing with purpose that also
private keys can be synchronized so that
you can read your emails across
different devices
I will explains a little bit later
because that's of course something which
will interest some of you how this works
and it's without a cloud or something
which where you need to put the key up
there okay oh it's already here so ok it
works like this if you if you if you
have an email address which you want to
use on different devices let's say your
iPhone and your Thunderbird installation
on Windows then you just configure this
email address on on both devices and
then both devices independently of each
other will of course because they have
PAP generate keys so they have
completely independent from each other
key pairs but then these devices start
to send we call them beacon messages or
just like technical emails to the
mailbox such that all want one of these
let's say starts and says I am here the
other one sees that and says oh cool you
are there other is Republic he I take it
and then the same thing which you can do
with outside communication parts you can
also do with your own devices so just
show the fingerprints in form of trust
words and then then you have your both
devices like here you will see it
desktop in the end and another system
and then the system asks you all of a
sudden do you want to build a device
group and you say yes trust words
confirmed and then you have a secure
channel I mean you trusted the this
thing manually with with the
fingerprints in form of trust words and
then the private keys of both device
will be transferred to both devices so
you can read all your past
communications of course if you don't
want to have specific email addresses on
your cell phone because you say this
thing is hacked anyway
I mean Android phones and stuff might be
a little bit difficult if you don't get
updates you can still say these email
address I just used on on the on the on
the desktop and another one which is not
so important whatever that means you you
just use everywhere and of course the
key sync is not done for all mail
addresses automatically but just for the
ones where a connection is possible by
the same email address and these we can
also - with other protocols then even in
then even in a synced form I mean if you
have online communication where you can
synchronize things directly and you can
do that email is assessing kind of stuff
so you need some matches some messages
going around such that you can they can
communicate and then you can build up
this device group and these messages of
course are not shown to the user so
these messages it just written pepp
synchronization message so if you would
have a device using that mail address
not with pepp you would see some
messages and then it's written just
deleted or ignore it and it will also be
deleted automatically when when the
process was done so it's just you just
use the mailbox to do this process
that's the easiest way to do it and by
design it's a peer-to-peer approach
because you don't you don't need to put
the key on a server and protect it with
a pass phrase or something like otters
are doing in the email or post email
area
so no net is the other vision we have we
also work with the new net project so
specifically with Christian growth of
and authors office project together we
want to route all the traffic through
yeah a completely crazy project here
which more or less replaces the whole
internet stack the glue net even has a
No Name system called can you name
System DNS which is completely
decentralized and you have I think 40
subsystems and one is called cadet and
this one you can use then to make
messaging and why not use that to send
emails in the end without relying on the
email infrastructure if it's possible we
will do that and this projects already
very old but it never achieved a state
where you can actually use it on a daily
basis and so yeah that's the reason why
working together here so probably we can
make a new net to some extent even
usable PAP itself is free software
because we like more like this
decentralized certificate authorities
thing there is also see assert domain
here just installed a root certificate
then you can look at then you can use
this site in fact otherwise let's
encrypt and yeah we also do a code out
it or we are in the in the process of it
it's a little bit mess to be honest
because we have other things else too
but we want to out it everything we are
doing at least at the latest when when
is released so that you know okay this
can this piece of software I'm using was
outed and we will also make sure that we
provide instructions to achieve
reproducible builds there are also tools
for that so we will try to do everything
let's say right as far as we can so
there is already an out date for the
engine that's more or less a year old
now so we will we'll have to do another
one and all kinds of errors were found
buffer overflows memory leaks the usual
thing because
the pep engine down here this thing here
is written in c99
so that so that it runs on on all all
kinds of platforms even on such without
mm use because we also envision to help
in encrypting IOT stuff or whatever else
might be possible so why not if it works
and then there are adapters we call them
adapters well technically they are
bindings but we call them adapters
because we try to adapt to the to the
language style which is typical so
things in Python should be pythonic and
not just some hack that you can just use
the functions but it should really feel
like Python so so we call them adapters
because we try to adapt to the
environment of the of the programmer and
the the functions you have in the end
are things like encrypt encrypt decrypt
get trust word so it's really easy in a
way that you cannot do anything wrong as
an application programmer who has no
clue of cryptography so that's the idea
here so we try to abstract and so it
should it should not be easy just for
use as follows for programmers to to
implement cryptography well here is an
example of the architecture for desktops
so for example if you have found the
bird then there is the enigmail plugin
we have a cooperation with an email next
version we already postponed the
deadline I don't know how many times so
we just say it's finished when it's
finished now the next ending male
version 2.0 will have pepped inside or
it will provide a way to install pepp
silently such that uses without any clue
can just engage in encrypted
communications and yeah for any male
here it's silver eaten that's a service
I mean there is such a JavaScript
adapter then which can be because an
email is written in JavaScript so there
is a JavaScript adapter which is a JSON
server
where you can just send communicate
through it
to access the engine functionality and
do everything which PAP can and also for
the outlook area here then there is a
comma DAP tur so for for you to use PAP
functionality with c-sharp and yeah for
Carmel by the way there is a student
project a student handed in a pep
implementation for Carmela's bachelor
thesis but we somehow lost contact we
should probably have a look at that
because it would be interesting to have
it yeah so what is currently really
available for outlook there is a release
which is usable for Android you can on
Google Play Store and then on them F
through it you can try a pep out how it
feels there is a better release for that
so you just write pretty easy privacy
then you find it because entering this
symbol might be not so easy yeah and for
a macmail there is this cooperation it's
almost feature complete we have more
like packaging issues how should we
distribute that should we prep should we
provide probably also bundle we are
thinking on providing kind of a bundle
like the tor browser bundle where
everything is just inside you can just
go on or should it be more like having
packages everywhere or should it be it
just everything so there's a lot of
stuff to do here and we also need people
so if someone is interested in working
on these areas just contact us we might
even find financing for that and for iOS
that's a little bit a sad story in the
iOS project should have been the first
one which exists because I was a little
bit as a sad story in two ways because
there is no open-source PGP client for
iOS that is just i p gmail i think is
the name is a commercial application
where there is no source code and PAP
will provide the first iOS app where you
also have the source code
and and also jailbreak instructions if
possible so that's not always guaranteed
but if possible often the foundation
side will also show you how you can
install it on a jailbreak device and
this the first sad story here is that we
we had an agreement with a company in
Canada that was doing an email client
inbox cube and and that idea was that
they put pep inside it was everything
was written an objective-c and they
somehow in the end because the
architecture was a little bit difficult
didn't manage it with properly so we we
started with ourselves and then also our
developers said that it's just not
feasible to continue like this the
refactoring for this bigger than just
rewriting it and then we stopped the
project and in the mid of July 2016 we
started an own iOS project which is this
new pipe for iOS and that's completely
written in Swift and we think with a
clean architecture and pap is
automatically inside so that's the
reason why I think things are also
taking longer than we planned
but it's not yet future complete it's
still in alpha phase it works already to
some extent but there is still another
version now for the public we trying out
but if you want to try it out directly
using Xcode and stuff and folding into
device you cannot just contact us we can
help you with that
so what other adapters are available has
already said that there is this comm
server tab for Outlook for example so
and for Android devices usually the Java
native interface is used but you can
also have probably server-side
applications which need Java interfaces
so there is also a solution for that for
enigmail JavaScript but also for browser
add-ons by the way I mean we have also
the idea that we provide add-ons for
browsers such that you can
encrypt and decrypt your messages for
the different web mailers which are
around but always in a way that your
keys are strictly on your device and the
browser plugin would then connect with
the json adapter and adjacent activate
the engine the engine would do the the
cryptographic work through new PG and
back and forth so that's a little bit
idea here cutie adapter that's relevant
for car mail or author QT applications
in the in the in the KDE area also
collab systems wanted to do something
here but somehow they didn't because
they have a group there with also with
client-side installations where they
were they were interested in that then
there's also Python adapter that's handy
for almost everything also for ticketing
systems by instance why not you can also
encrypt your notification so the users
if somehow the ticketing system got the
public key so that's a fully
opportunistic approach just sent the
public key there and then you receive
all the notifications encrypted
objective-c adapter of course needed for
iOS so for apps written and objective-c
or Swift and these both languages are
compatible so how does this look like so
that you have an impression a little bit
so first of all one thing which we I
mean this is the Android story must also
be told I mean this is a car not a car
nine fork we try to cooperate with the
car 9 car 9 project and proposed to to
make a pull request but they said they
have no interest in our approach here
they want to continue with open keychain
so they have an own approach and they
are not interested in things besides
email because our client will Austin be
able to to reach contacts on XMPP and
other things so that's a little bit the
idea here and we also changed of course
the interface a lot in in Conine you
have just like I think random colors or
no idea for the users
here when you see colors this is like a
trusted contact here this is a contact
where you have a public key at least so
you can write him encrypted and if you
would have a contact you miss trust
because you think his key is rocket or
something then it would appear as a red
square about something which PAP never
does is to stop you to communicate so if
you want still if you want if you if you
prefer to still write encrypted even if
it's proud of it even if the NSA can
read it or whatever then you can still
do it I mean it just will appear right
then so how does this look like
concretely now when you have a message
so if you don't have a public key you
are in the in the in the mode that you
can just write an email an email like
nowadays mostly just like unencrypted
that will go out unencrypted but the
public key will be attached so if the
other one has pepp you can already
receive an email back which is then
encrypted if that happens you see it
here then it gets yellow or if you are
writing a message and and you have a
public key the message will have this
yellow coloring so this is traffic light
semantics because there is also green
you can achieve that we think it's it
might also be a little bit like a
gamification concept people probably
want to come green so they will probably
try this handshake process which we
provide here and then these trust words
are shown and then you can use a
separate side channel and ask you the
partner if they see the same words on
the screen and if that happens you can
just say yes yes on both sides then it
the channel turns you have the
appearance turns green here of the
window you see that you can also use p2p
fingerprints you can also use long trust
words as some of you surely will know
usually to have
complete fingerprints you need 24 digit
extra blocks because anyway
each of these fingerprints is is has ten
four digit blocks so but because we
think that's probably a little bit too
much we just have them so that you lose
lots of entropy of course but if you
want to have more entropy you can just
say show long transits and if then you
have twenty words and you can also
compare them of course directly when you
meet someone looking at the screens why
not
so just words you can just look at it
and if they're if these are the same you
can go ahead of course because we have
different people talking different
languages you also need different
language for the trust words total
fallbacks of course English but we have
also Catalan German Spanish French
Turkish and more will be added so that's
an example now here in in you know
Spanish if your partner doesn't have PAP
you can also just compare fingerprints
so here you also see that if each word
is a fingerprint and you want to have
the full trust words you need 20 words
because we just concatenate them for now
probably there will be another approach
hashing them and stuff but that still
work in progress and so here you see the
three basic collars so if you have a
contact which you also trust because you
manually did the trust process the
handshake process then it will appear
green and also if you are about to write
an email and you have a public key from
someone you already trust that then it
will show green and and also you have a
you have a signaling at the pair message
level and and in that a pair user level
so at your contact list as I showed
before you also see the people with
different colors and you know how to
private you can communicate with them
so the same applies of course with a
little bit not design for the author the
software we have so this would be
Outlook so there's also text here if you
are color blind for example you need of
course a concept here so we just have
text here now in other cases we also
have symbols unsecured if it's about to
go out or if it went out unencrypted
secure for it was at least encrypted and
secure and trusted if you also put trust
on it by manual that's the only manual
process usually need to do if you want
to have trusted communication so that
that's a handshaking process for Outlook
so somehow the same and for any mail I I
wanted to show life how this looks like
and now how fast you can enter in
encrypted and also a verified
communications about the the macbook
where i have this stuff running doesn't
work here so I can just show it at the
Swiss village if you want or just like
individually if you want to see it live
so benefits of pep so it's it is yeah
model proof let's say or further proof
with others also unable to use such
stuff in this case it's a general
problem so it uses you shouldn't need to
do anything particular so the decisions
at Pape that pet makes should just be
good yeah and then and then I mean the
same which we are the same at the same
things which we are teaching at crypto
parties we can also just put into code
and then you have kind of a protocol
because that's what you have in the end
if you just write steps down in s code
and people can just engage in increase
into an encrypted communications like
this and also very important that we if
there is no specific provider so you can
just use pep
for email now with any email account
there is no restriction and we don't
know as PAP what you are doing with PAP
probably okay we can see that you
downloaded it but that's that's it and
then this breaching function because
usually you have a little bit of problem
that you install a new app and then you
don't have friends there vendor lock-in
so with PAP we have the very general
approach to just add more communication
channels and more cryptography methods
that you can use here or which are
typical in these errors a minor for XMPP
it would be OTR Oro MIMO we can just use
libraries to engage in such
communications too we also want that
Pepe's is standardized so we are we
didn't we didn't do that much yet but we
have to plan to write Internet drafts
and we're also engaged in internet
engineering task force meetings and
command and communications already to
have this process going it's of course a
thing which takes years and you have no
guarantee that you will get an error FC
number but that doesn't matter most
important thing is that is that we will
we get our stuff documented and that we
have running code which can be used and
if someone doesn't like the engine the
adapters whatever you can also stay
compatible by just doing the same or
discussing with us and let me change it
so that's a little bit ideally we want
we interoperability is the goal of this
project which we just want to to fit
into the into the ecosystem so it's
talking of visions here you see what
what we envision I mean that's that just
a made-up example that doesn't exist in
practice yet so but why not I mean you
could have one app where you can just
say okay I have Gmail Yahoo Outlook
iCloud whatsapp Facebook Twitter here
and I just want to reach my friends in
the most in the in the most private in
the most private way possible and then
you would also see here the different
identities I mean this is now
user that you have called Rick I think
you know the movie behind this kind of
stuff and this user might have T for
that entity might be on Twitter on you
might have a very key mail address a
private email address you might have an
alias for some of these addresses here
and also a phone number which indeed is
also an identifier an identifier for for
signal or for whatsapp which is used
there so we will also need some yarn our
registrations I think for certain
communication channels such that you
such that you can say okay I am about to
contact the signal user a whatsapp user
or a ring user or a tox user or whatever
so there are lots of you is missing here
so you see the project is completely
crazy and we are at the email level now
so just to say so okay that probably I
already said of course are one of the
biggest problems that we have nowadays
with the tools bits which are already
easy to use like whatsapp signal
protonmail whatever is that they are
just I mean you need to use their
platform that's the first thing for some
of this in in some cases this is a real
problem I mean for example in the case
of whatsapp they have all your metadata
when you locked in locked out whom to
commit to whom to to you communicated to
how long and everything so there are FBI
records showing that in the case of
signal it's much better in that area but
that's of course a little bit a problem
if you have like a platform which can be
shot down censored and or which can even
collect metadata because in lots of in
lots of the mass surveillance situations
we have there are more interests in the
metadata so if you use whatsapp even if
the crypto is fine and not backdoored
and stuff they still have the metadata
that's quite an issue then there are
also better tools I think like ring or
talks that they they are a little bit in
the spirit like new net so fully
decentralized peer-to-peer everything
like this so they have a DHT a
distributed hash table 2 to 4 dressing
the dressing is done decentralized but
if you install ring for example which
was released some days ago then you you
see that you have no friends so you need
to start to find the user base first and
other thing is that my impression is it
still eats a little bit too much battery
because for the DHT to to to have to DHT
working you need everyone participating
and they also do that with the cell
phones that something in new net is a
little bit envisioned in the in the
sense that if Gounod realize it's it's
it's running on on a mobile device that
you don't use it that much for such
purposes or you just switch can you net
stuff I mean you can still send the
machines receive them but you don't
participate in this in this in the in
the in the DHT kind of in the intent
intensive stuff there so we also have
this rating system with the colours
that's probably all something which is
for normal people let's say helpful just
that they can directly see how private
they are of course if their device is
not backdoored or malware was installed
of course in that case you have you have
lost anyways but if the device is fine
then these privacy status with the
colors might be helpful and we have also
this interesting construction with
community on one side commercial things
on the other side so that we can really
separate this and and in in that
commercial interests cannot destroy the
community interests and that we also can
as foundation support projects which
from a commercial point of view are not
interesting I mean there are lots of
tools around which we where you can put
encryption but you cannot sell this kind
of stuff so not even in support area and
not even with red head models nothing
we want to support all of these projects
possible and that's something which is
of course bedded on by not a
non-commercial entity which is around by
activists which understand that so then
the the I already said that you can
synchronize keys but if you can use that
system for keys you can also use it to
sync rise to trust I mean such that you
you if you already trusted someone with
the iPhone that does that the same trust
is also transferred to the other device
so you can you have the same you are on
the same page on all of your devices
that something easy to add is will be
added it's not yet in and also you can
synchronize calendar and the dress data
not by supporting all address books
locally but just by mapping from one
book from one address book to the other
I mean it will of course happen that not
all fields can be mapped
deterministically but things like names
addresses email addresses phone numbers
they're usually you find the mapping
from Outlook to some Thunderbird thing
why not and and that then you can of
course do that and then you have like
synchronization of addresses and
calendars without a cloud so you don't
need Google or or iCloud or something
like this then that's a little bit a
very new thing I mean it depends if you
know what I'm talking now but I mean
there is this web of trusting where
where everyone signs each author in the
the social graph is put on on the key
servers usually so everyone can see whom
you trusted and Christian got off from
the newer projects like new telluric no
net and so forth as an author idea here
he calls it folk of trust the idea is
that that if two persons don't trust
each other but both of them have people
which they trust then it proposes a
method which a method which will be
mathematically also checked by Indian
friends to to to make an intersection of
the contacts they both trust and if a
certain cardinality that means a certain
number of people is achieved you can
automatically say it's green of course
this can be attacked by mating up
contacts and stuff like this but there
is at least an approach here to have
like web of trust without exposing the
social graph so privacy preserving and
and you don't even know then why you got
green so it's just that there are enough
contacts which you both trust so that's
a little bit idea it's probably also a
question of the threshold you use how
many people you need to trust together I
think I should hurry up a little bit we
have also other ideas probably you you
saw the new taller talk that's a payment
system where we have a wallet in your
browser or on your devices and then you
can just go around and and thinks in a
very easy way and and with cash
properties so that you are anonymous
when buying something but if you sell
something you are transparent to the
state such that you are still taxable
but you can also just send money to your
friends that's supported by no taller so
that anonymity is preserved and so you
can so there's the idea to have a pay by
mail feature and also pay to spam
feature that's a little bit more
complicated thing I mean in the canoe
night system there is the parasol stick
the canoe included there's also new name
system and there you can of course then
define zones like companies or
corporations which you trust which are
which don't send spam out and by
defining policies on your devices that
you you want to receive from all of
these trusted bodies people in the zones
emails that's possible without payment
otherwise you can say that you that they
should be charged if they are not in a
trusted zone also the support of yeah of
also support for Hardware tokens such as
you can store your private key on HSMs
is the thing we are working on with with
neutral key so we are applying for a new
project here where we try to put all
these pieces together here such that
yeah we have like bigger system where
privacy is restored again if if you want
to know details here I think best person
would be Christian but you can also ask
me then we can make up a contact just to
show what we are doing here and then we
are also an increasing number of
interesting corporations now one thing
is that we have a shared ownership
agreement with the new net project why
do we do that I mean we have a multi
licensing strategy towards the companies
so they are allowed to also provide
closed source software if they want or
if it's necessary for a certain customer
as long as they don't change the engine
and adapt as long as I don't put
backdoors and so will enforce them to
have out it's there and this
disagreement is very important for the
iOS area because in in the App Store you
are not allowed to have GPL GPL software
so you need an exception there and we
got this exception already now from fork
new net for the pep code page we don't
need that because now it's our own code
of course
Patera solves another issue with new PG
their group which is GPL GPL licensed
and
yeah they're the decision until now was
that it stays like this so we are not
not able to use new PG for iOS so we are
we are using net PGP there that this one
is an open PGP implementation once
started by the net bsd project and you
know I think we have we have we did a
rewrite of most of the parts I think
already and are just doing that to have
a solution for IO but of course it's not
so good as picnic which is better has
more mitigates against different kinds
of attacks but it's just what we we have
now so then we also have a cooperation
with Isaac Switzerland where we apply
together to Isaac's be on the net
program to get funding to make these
internet drafts so to have pep
standardize and we already were in
Prague some weeks ago discussing and
showing a little bit what we are trying
to do and as far as I can say directions
were like it's needed just let's just
look at it and we need to split up all
the things we are doing because it's a
real big thing so there will be a bunch
of internet drafts here any any Gmail
was already said then you may know the
river and David Logan Foundation they
are known for for running in
investigative journalism events in
Berlin and London they were already some
and they also gave us money to make
tools in that in that sense PAP so that
investigative journalists can engage
more easily in secure communications and
with the valhallen foundation which is I
think best known to support WikiLeaks
they will also help us in in in
donations from the U because we are in
Switzerland so if people want to donate
to the project to the foundation part
then this is possible
soon via the violence tapetum and for
the new night thing because I said we
want to route email traffic and author
messaging truck new net we
we'll be doing I think as of October a
new net simulation for 10,000 100,000
and 1 million peers first assuming some
I mean user behavior we need to find out
how how people how people communicate
how many emails they send how many chat
message is more or less like this there
will be some sociological studies I
think about that and then we will run
create a model and and and create new
net peers doing that kind of stuff and
and then we can see if there are
scalability problems to roll this out
massively because that's the plan so we
want to see if it works
so they the Nelnet foundation which is
based here in in the netherlands gave us
30,000 euros for that we still need some
more funding for because the project is
one hundred thousand euro project we
estimate yeah and that's it so it's more
like broad overview a little bit what
I've quite shoot her might be some
questions so first thank you for the
talk please give some applause
if you have questions please come to the
microphone we don't have too much time
for questions but might be something
nothing really
do you really believe all of this anyone
would yes someone hi thanks for the talk
so you mentioned what means right what
you mentioned what means that yes yeah
but I think that there it's very
difficult I mean everything is below the
address bar can be faked and so the the
webmail provider can always if there is
clear text below it let's say the
address bar the the one sending you the
webpage you will always be able to read
the content of your email so you still
have to trust him right you know I mean
we do the work before that I mean there
is already a project called mail velop
doing that to some extent but it's not
that easy to use and it doesn't have
this trust rating system and stuff but
you can just put ciphertext into Google
Mail or orgy mix and get them and
there's even an API for that and when
you get ciphertext back you can get it
out then you are the browser add-on
level and from there you go on to the
engine so there's no way the the mail
provider can do anything there they kind
of course just make the work more
difficult incompatible whatever stuff
like this can be can be done of course
but it should it should still work it's
it's just lots of work because you have
different browsers and you have lots of
mail providers but in fact you don't
have that many which are dominant so
there are lots of small ones but yeah
you know which which ones are the bigger
ones no okay so you don't type the email
directly in the web browser but we do it
before yeah yeah yeah if it's about
encrypting at one yeah
of the web folk of trusting yes oh
because let's say you're using some
social network stuff like I don't know
indeed sing or something like that yes
you know this person maybe you know this
in this in this person's and then you
can also find by this function that you
can do some intelligence of the term of
only other persons because so let's say
you add somebody then you see are
there's a person and this is another
company and so you get some information
about the other person because he gets
successive suggestions to you and so if
you have this folk of trusting you could
maybe have let's say 20 sock puppets
yeah that know that that know people for
some extent yeah because they get a
little bit known to the people and then
you can get gather intelligence on this
thing like you have a lot of sock
puppets how you know that's clear I mean
that's first of all it's a threshold
question I mean how many people must it
be and then and the end they can of
course send people out and create lots
of yeah puppets
it has to call them to to just achieve
this this green mode and of course it's
difficult because this is ultimate izing
trust which is not possible usually it
would just be an idea to probably we
need to signal some trust level but not
showing it directly green that's that's
usability question so it's just it's not
that we will put it in bunch for sure
it's just that we will implement it
together with christian and then try it
out of it so let's projects like CAS
cert but you have to bring your your
passport and then somebody gives you
trust because this is all the passport
but the trust the trust you give
directly with with with trust words okay
so people are just trusting there are
just putting their direct trust on each
other I mean if you now know notice
these people here and I also know these
people here and we all trust them in the
but we are we never trusted us then the
idea would be okay there are enough
people here which we both trust show it
somehow if it's now green or not it's
not a question but let's let's assume
I'm an employee of maybe five secret
edges you know of course yes I first and
so I first saw so of course but these
discussed something if you want to do
that on a really big scale still I mean
that's absolutely clear that if you
require two less people you can do that
but that's that's that's there we have
costs involved because you need to
create these puppets that's right yeah
and then I mean this is a cost
optimization project anyhow because if
you really manage to have more
encryption then in the for excuse core
some lights will get darker and that's
right ahead the idea we have here yeah
okay so we have like one minute left if
it's a really quick question we can
start what about the encryption of group
messages your well I mean for email if
you if you just have different contacts
I mean what do you mean something
specific or let's say the email case now
or what yeah I mean if you talk into the
microphone okay yeah
is that an implementation for the
mailman or something not yet about that
that's envisioned that you can create a
private key which you then can share
between the people who should be able to
enter the list and if the key changes
you can signal that and then a new key
can be defined so that's that's
envisioned yes oh now we really have to
end thank you very much for this talk
and also you and your team for putting
all this energy in this really hard
field so give him a big round of
applause please