[Music]
our next speaker tonight is Matthew
Stender Matthew is a technology ethicist
currently project strategist with online
censorship to dog and tonight he's going
to be talking to us about some of the
different ways in which social networks
and other proprietary platforms used
data they've collected about us in
intrusive ways so please give a welcome
to Matthew stander hello everybody
hello everybody thank you so much for
joining mean everyone here this evening
I know it's getting to that kind of
twilight of camp I hear there's a grappa
flowing at the Italian embassy later so
you'll probably find me there after this
my name is matthew stander i am somewhat
self-proclaimed
technology a tech at assist the last
year and a half I've been researching
around a central theme and that is what
are the cultural and ethical
implications of emerging technology and
also what does it mean to be human in
the 21st century I'm really interested
in examining the social contract between
us and the technology us as humans and
the technology that we make and how it
has become more than as tools and is now
becoming part of the way that we create
an epistemic reality that is the
information that we have the knowledge
that paints the picture of the world
around us is now being very much
influenced nudged and activated by
systems tonight I would be talking about
proprietary platforms but also
proprietary algorithms as opposed to
open-source technology which we think
most people this camp are well-versed in
but I think sometimes we forget about
what's going on in the proprietary world
what is exactly that we're fighting what
is it exactly that corporations and and
governments are doing that we should not
just be be wary of but can actually take
stances against so I'm gonna examine on
I guess we can call tonight a hashtag
but it's more than that it's a theory
which I've been working on for a while
and I call it mimics and this is an
acronym initialism stands for monitor
index manipulate intercept censor and
silo I'm gonna walk through these these
letters and and talk a little bit about
some what's why I think it's important
that we that we put some sort of
communication strategy behind
proprietary Ness and and be able to
relate it to people that are not so
technically versed and have other people
understand what it is that these systems
are able to do in a none transparent
process that affect the way that we live
our lives so once again my name is
Matthew stander and I'm going to talk
about how beyond this minis concept how
platforms have really geared themselves
up to be against humanity so there's a
so saying then art imitates life but I
think more and more that technology is
mimicking reality so let's start with
I'm gonna start this talk with some kind
of on a sociological slant philosophical
if you will I'm gonna talk about just
some basic thing this is kind of how I
have come to see the world
and try to also build strategies around
how to communicate these things so I
think we all know we're surrounded by so
much technology and we have everything
at our fingertips but the problem is
that this technology is not neutral that
a lot of it has is capitalist driven we
have manufactured a man that gets us to
voluntarily give away our information
but it's used for profit maximization
all the algorithms the information that
is more more tailored and curated for
who for the US that these platforms
think we are is in a constant state of
evolution
earlier today I gave a talk on facial
recognition technology and one of the
things that interests me about facial
recognition technology is one image that
we snap that may go to our iCloud or
Google or Facebook that we needed advice
to see it we need battery in our phone
in order to access this photo it's not a
human readable image first only secondly
first is a machine readable image and
what I find particularly disturbing
about this concept is that these images
can continuously be churned that new
information new data new of presumption
x' new information can be accumulated on
a single image each time that it's
scanned inside of a large of a large
database and so we're now dealing with
this with this world that is we have so
many we have somebody dynamic
information points that have been taken
from us or that we've given to
technology companies and this really
does I believe changed the social
relationship that we are able to
experience with others and changes the
way that we ourselves are able to
self-identify so this is both an active
and a passive influence on both our
psychological and or sociological
decision making the things that I do if
I want to get those likes on that
Instagram picture I may pose in a way I
may go to the place in which that other
people go
this is for me to be able to put out a
digital image to the world but also get
validation and gratification from others
in responses of likes and comments so de
carp as if a witness sang but I want to
interrogate if this is still true in the
21st century just because we think are
we there for so let's talk about with
some of sociological philosophical
concepts I'm really interested in agency
and I'm this idea for the capacity for
individuals to act independently and
make their own free choices this is what
I'm most concerned about with
proprietary technology that forces are
being exerted onto us and in a way that
we don't realize that our free will that
our free choice that our agency is being
outsourced or nudged upon confirmation
bias this is something that I also find
interesting that the more and more that
we are exposed to proprietary platforms
we can think about it as social
platforms now the more that were exposed
to Facebook or to Instagram that we this
does impact our epistemic reality these
are the things in which that we see that
other people live their lives the way
the other people live their lives but it
also been influences the things that we
hold to be true so we're we're searching
we're trying to interpret information
but a lot of times as when chose as been
shown in studies going back to the 70s
that the things that confirm our
pre-existing beliefs are the easiest
things for us to understand or choose to
be what we consider fact or truth or
objective reality and so this idea of
the illusion of control that we
overestimate our ability to control
events that we think that we may
actually you know this is a languor is
well-known for this concept dating back
to the the early days of the internet
and I think that even now it's important
for us to to think about what degree do
we have the ability to shape our world
and how much are we just a factor of the
world pushing against us
and I mean finally I think less concept
here technological determinism you know
does society technology drive
development of its social structure and
cultural values and if so what degree of
influence does the proprietary
technology have when we don't have
transparency when we can't see inside
source codes when there are black boxes
when the systems that go through that
each each part of a machine learning
algorithm a neural network a GA and
whatever it is all these processes going
on we are not able to see what's inside
and track back the outcome to the origin
with a clear and meaningful causal
roadmap and surveillance capitalism I
probably most of you are familiar with
us some of the buffs from Harvard theory
of surveillance capitalism it's a book
about it but I think I hope this was
interesting I forget if I learn ins the
former or current chief economists but
this idea which the chief economist for
Google would say the ability to take
data to be able to understand it to
process it to extract value from it to
visualize it to communicate it that it's
gonna be a hugely important skill in the
next decades so this we can see now that
did somebody in charge of the
monetization that the finance the
revenue the the long-term economic
prosperity of a company like Google that
is more powerful than then certain
countries if they're still looking
mapping out the next couple of decades
to mine data to under to make their
money off of our information I think
that we have to step back and say ok
this is not an isolated phenomenon we
need to dig into this and also find ways
to communicate to people that may have
never thought that Facebook or or
somebody or your search feed your search
results in Google may
change how you see the world like Oscar
Wilde said it's very sad nowadays that
there's so little useless information I
think this is particularly true in the
digital error so as I'm saying when
we're surrounded by these things that
buy that confirm our confirmation bias
when we're exposed to things that do not
create cognitive dissonance when
everyday a feed in which we check
consistently gives a similar information
it's sometimes hard to know what lies
outside of these bubbles so MIT
Technology Review is talking about these
things we see other world publications
talking about how Google is the is the
future also see how technology companies
have been captured by state institutions
and how these companies smaller
companies that aren't that are not these
global players but still have have found
their way into working with governments
to amass a massive amounts of
information using proprietary systems
that then they then rent due to
governments this is more and more
there's more more of an extraction
industry around data so this is what I'm
going to talk about today this evening I
think that I don't know up to up to this
point this is six six examples of things
which I feel have captured a bare
minimum of the things that I that I am
trying to to speak about and have people
more aware of so I'm going to quickly go
through cases of this this is I don't
know if everybody here may know all
these cases but also to hopefully
inspire that there is kind of a wait
around this
this acronym so we are constantly being
monitored our phones are like spies our
cars have become tracking beacons right
and so we now find ourselves interacting
with many proprietary systems we find
ourselves in Uber's on facebook well
enough momentarily checking to see if
our Amazon package has arrived but we
were monitored all the time and by
different forces so I talked about
facial recognition and my last talk but
I think that we're gonna see more and
more of the phenomenon that's here in
the lower right hand corner that now
Google and Facebook are matching online
data with offline shopping habits so
going into stores but also using
location services on your phone being
able to to see if there's correlation
between the ads they served you and your
real IRL spending habits we also are
used to people listening we haven't
really thought about it we're being
monitored Facebook Messenger is now
going to try to do some using keywords
we've had anybody that's used Gmail for
a while I actually just stopped but for
a long time our emails have been scanned
to service targeted ads now the US
military wants to get up in Twitter kind
of these firehose api's at the FBI
couldn't get it for a while but or the
CIA couldn't get it but the FBI was able
to get a firehose API that now the world
around us there's a real-time social
monitor social media monitoring tools I
don't know if anybody over at the the
share labs reports on the hacking team
metadata it is an awesome read it is
really an it's an impressive report it
was really one of my favorite reports
from last year at lis they were able to
go through and so this is this is a
graph of
the CEO of hacking team his email
frequency throughout the day just a
small data set but you could really get
a picture of people's lives when
something as simple as email metadata
even is just like it is the headers
right you're able to see okay well then
who are they contacting what does this
look like on a weekly and hourly or
weekly and so the sophisticated photos
are these sophisticated images of our
lives can really can really tell a large
amount about us with not a lot of data
with indexing our information is is is
stored and then analysis are served and
we're served not what we want but what
they think we want and I think this is
interesting once we're talking about
these large data sets how similar do we
have to be to someone else in order to
get served a similar ad and I think that
the lack of transparency and the nature
of proprietary systems and we're not
able to look inside we can't answer
these questions I don't what is it that
makes me a liberal or a moderate or a
conservative am i more the some of my
clicks before just because I think
therefore I am
is this still applicable or is it
therefore I click I click
therefore I am and this is the
relationship this is the lack of a
social contract between people and our
technology that I think we have to
continue to interrogate some of y'all
probably heard that uh Rumbo was
thinking about selling maps of people's
homes this is a Google from last week
from April like break the story it's
this to me is this nexus in which that
we are no longer just online beings that
we're now online even if we're offline
there are some interesting uses to some
of these things that looking for spikes
in search data for malaria are you first
symptoms so Google is not doing it
actually is not is not just using data
of do I have malaria
it's
isolating the search terms that from
that appear around malaria and then
using them as indicators to look for
outbreaks nifty but also a bit invasive
manipulation
Claudio Becker who give a talk yesterday
and I believe tomorrow as launching a
new project Facebook dot tracking dot
expose and what that project is doing is
it's a browser plugin and it's looking
at post IDs on Facebook and saying how
often does this one post show up when
you log on to Facebook this is a sort of
data data collection that I think that
we can really help transparency efforts
we don't really know we just see a feed
and we we don't know if we've seen it
before I never really look at ads and I
really don't know if an ad as it
appeared there before if that ad is is
as as they're every day but when with
tools were able to now see more and more
about the ways in which that's
algorithms prioritize content and
manipulate our feeds in a way that is
not chronological but what they think we
want so there was a really interesting
case I've seen Ryan Robertson and they
wrote a number of pieces about this I'm
and they've coined his term search
engine manipulation effect seem and they
were able to around the around they they
first did it in a controlled environment
and then they also did this study at
during the Indian elections the
elections in India and 2014 I believe
and were able to look at the ways in
which that small differences in search
engine feeds were able to change
outcomes of Elections I was looking into
around the around the u.s. election I
was looking into writing a piece around
the ways in which technology companies
could influence our influence our
democratic agency let's say
ability to feel that we are exercising
our ability to vote for the person who
we think we will do the best job and I
think this really stood out to me is one
of those persuasive cases maybe it's
it's less than a point in some cases uh
yeah less than one percent but the the
science exists now and so this is able
to be replicated and actually when I
find it interesting that as these
surveys are these these research
projects are being done in academia
there's probably the same research being
done at the campuses in Silicon Valley
to see exactly what the what the effects
are of things like a search feed so
reports of manipulates what's trending
who how the information that gets to us
not so I guess ago a year ago Facebook
changed the way that they sorted things
friends and family now advertisers
aren't happy and there's also a
Melissa's militarization going on around
around the influence of beliefs we see
recently YouTube announced that using AI
was more effective than humans when it
comes to having people leading people
away from terrorist content so
interception interception granted is
maybe the the weakest letter but I think
is an in my mimics framework but I think
it's interesting because it shows that
above any one system are higher powers
that things like prism is now been
showed to to be able to have massive
amounts of upstream collection that we
are now that I mean and this any of you
think about it prism cost twenty million
dollars a year which sounds kind of like
a lot but to be a spy on the whole world
that is if you if you got the tap if
you're able to do this like why would
you
knew not yeah and I mean consistently
owning large platforms although I have
to say that I like that AOL was one of
the last to be owned so yeah there's
really I felt it like with his
interception and the way in which that
the pictures that's especially which is
made a metadata being collected
especially on u.s. citizens that falls
outside of 702 that there's a lot of
that a lot of this is maybe not even
direct information but metadata that
yeah email headers are collected but as
Michael Hayden said the former NSA
director we kill people based on
metadata so this is deadly serious that
not these are not just like you do not
just throw away parts of our of our
emails these are not just a casual
conversation on Facebook if you were a
have you matched the description of
somebody on a kill list or a high tech
or high value target list there may be a
drone coming at your face
based on your metadata wireless song and
people are finding people are finding
vulnerabilities in in systems constantly
in in places whether it's cell site
simulator stingrays or orders out of
dates unpatched telecommunications
infrastructure there's more and more
ability for the information that's
collected proprietary to proprietarily
to leak out and even and I think it's
also very problematic when IOT devices
that exist on a proprietary yet
unsecured platform are susceptible to
external attacks then there's also the
state apparatus then Shandong Province
in western China where the ethnic
minority Weger group is there's a very
restive area and there's been a lot of
resettlement by Han Chinese and so
slowly
the ethnic majority has been has been
kind of pushed to the edges of society
but they were actually a couple of weeks
ago and having checkpoints stopping
people on the road and making sure if
they had state spyware on their phone
again what happens at the edge of the
earth in the most marginalized
communities eventually finds its way
back into us that have privilege and
then the courts are another like threat
vector when when we have one warrant
giving the authorization to hack many
accounts when Y when warrantless
requests are ere are signed without
looking all all these things it's it's
another ways in which that that we can
be intercepted in the traffic even
though we're communicating in what seems
to be a secure in proprietary way
censorship is an issue that I work on
quite a bit
I work as a products trader just for
online censorship org
it's a project to be good by uh by a
colleague my colleagues three years ago
I suppose feel free to follow us on
Twitter what we do is we have a survey
that's been it's been online for about a
year-and-a-half now and if your social
media post has been taken down or if
your account has been suspended you can
go onto our website fill out a short
survey and we take this these surveys
and then come a granade it with other
information that we track we do a weekly
takedown which every week we put four
stories up that made news around content
moderation policies abuse content
moderation policies and so we then well
every six months or so we write a
reports the last ones available on on
online censorship org and what we're
trying to do is in some ways a
crowdsource transparency around
platforms if your play if you we don't
really know the cake take down the
transparency reports are really slim
they provide they give only a handful of
indicators and it's very difficult to
make to draw any stories from these from
their transparency
so because they're not giving us the
information we designed a way to have
people report their information to us
and censorship is both direct and
indirect sometimes it can be there can
be abuse around censorship so flagging
if a platform hasn't built in that
hundred people flagging the same peoples
of content at the same time they've been
built in for this then maybe this
content goes down until it's reviewed
but this can also be used in abusive
ways Facebook we've seen many cases in
which that content that did not violate
Facebook's Terms of Service was still
taken down again we work on on reports
and work with other organizations but
it's very difficult for us to to be
completely thorough because this is
still unscientific data it's what's
getting pushed to us and so we try to
make recommendations these companies
transparency is always at the top of the
list but not just transparency but
enhanced transparency reporting because
without and without training without
solid transparency reporting it's very
difficult to know what's going on on a
platform that like two billion people
are using every month so that's what I
was talking about earlier so rules like
hey and don't worry about it humans
we're gonna let our AI take on the
terrorists well who's reviewing right is
there any external review is there a
public editor an open buds man that's
able to step into this proprietary AI
process and say oh actually a human
would not find this offensive only a
machine and the final letter siloing so
there's been quite a bit of talk this
week I've been multiple conversations
about the idea of data portability but I
think one of the issues right now is I
well I work on is around community
archives but also long-term archives how
do we create original rosetta stone that
can last 20 years or 200 years is it
possible to build anything digital that
can last 2,000 years
well as long as the information that we
have that we have a map that we
accumulate on a massive scale every day
all our Facebook Likes our Facebook
content all our search results all this
ephemeral media that exists only inside
the proprietary platform that is not
exportable if this only exists there
if tomorrow Facebook goes down what
happens to this shared digital cultural
record of us what if you're not on
Facebook the inability for
interoperability is also concerning if
you get kicked off a Facebook you can't
comment on certain websites if you get
kicked off YouTube and aren't able to
our Twitter Twitter people have had been
hard banned there's a few people that
most of them were pretty shitty people
but it also goes to show if companies
are able to target individuals then they
are able to eliminate them from a
process and especially if these
platforms say to be representative of
democratic values and norms Facebook has
a live town halls for the u.s. election
Twitter also live streaming debates and
so well these companies are saying that
they are participating in the enabling
democracy they're also
institutionalizing walls walled gardens
which keep people some some people out
so as so as we see more of an app in app
browsing from Facebook and things like
amp as more and more as we as URLs are
decreased this is also changing the way
in which that we can revisit the same
webpage twice if something doesn't have
a URL how can how can we you send it to
the Internet Archive if it just exists
inside of a browsing space a browsing
ecosystem inside a Facebook again
there's plans personalized Google's
from my colleague join New York who's
written about this extensively that both
professionally and personally a ban can
can impact our lives so I'm not gonna
say that I completely agree with this
but I think it's an interesting it's
different an interesting angle to look
at this it's not that computers are too
smart about to take over the world but
they're too stupid and they're here and
so I think that this is to me this is
one of the the philosophical questions
that we need to ask ourselves our
computer smart is artificial intelligent
really is artificial intelligence really
intelligent or are the motives of those
who control these proprietary systems
actually the things that are creating
this change
I'm gonna talk so much about biases but
it's a really big topic and what do give
some examples about the ways in which
that more and more of these technologies
proprietary systems and platforms are
going to impede on our lives so Yahoo
was just which was just acquired by a
large ISP in the u.s. it could be that
there's now there's now some smart
billboards so this is actually from a
year and a half ago a couple of years
ago but I think it's also important to
remember when we're talking about
massive amounts of data or patents for
this matter that this data can pass
through a chain of custody then if we
Yahoo gets bought by Time Warner that
what we're there is not a social
contract or even our privacy protections
in place in order to ensure that our
data still falls within the original
data terms and conditions I don't know
what to say about digital assistance I
don't really get them but evidently I
don't know there was a 300,000 of them
sold or something on prime day through
Amazon so they're here and every many
people have a yeah straight up a spy in
their living room now the IOT space not
really something that I fuck with but
suffice to say it's a clusterfuck
I think a big part of finding solutions
to this I believe is examining who is
making the technology why are they
making the technology who was it for and
how long is it meant to last Kate
Crawford was a friend didn't like
colleague working in the same space as
written extensively about this but I
think that if we look at if we look at
who is creating technology who is build
who's creating technology and who is
affected by technology it's it's it's
difficult why is it that a court that
one in four black Americans have faced
race-based harassment online I'm not
saying this correlation but I think it's
interesting that if you look at the
policy teams and the engineering teams
of these companies especially Silicon
Valley companies you're not going to
find a lot of black Americans on these
teams so what on whose life experience
whose background are we taking into
account when we're designing these
proprietary systems cars are
self-driving cars more and more are
going to be around but I'm gonna close
with a few last points and then
everybody has any questions so I think
it's important for us to realize that
even though many people here at this
camp and in our communities are open
source until they die the floss is king
that these sort of things that many
people and a critical mass of people are
still going to exist inside of these
proprietary technologies a second point
is due to trade secret laws and speeches
code or code is speech in the US that
there are already judicial protections
granted to technology companies to keep
their proprietary algorithms and
platforms can classified as trade
secrets it's thought by accidents I
believe that these that there is such
Transparency if we were to pull back
behind the curtain and somehow be able
to see inside the decision-making
processes of the the newest technology
rolling out it would probably be a
wake-up call but because we can't see
inside we only see the influence that
were the epistemic reality that we get
from using these platforms and that in
some way is kind of like blinders that
we are not able to see left to right but
just straight ahead into the screen that
every day these messages that are being
reinforced whether it's politics or
music or fashion that all of these
things slowly influence and nudge our
agency and create a perception of what
we are expected to do the data of data
is the future I don't think for us but
like companies now the the valuation of
startups in in Silicon Valley is really
wild I there's tens of millions of
dollars floating around to potential
startups and so many of them have data
and invasive data intimate data
collection as a revenue model
finally we I believe we need to demand
more from our machines by the people
that make our machines the people that
sell our machines and finding new ways
to encourage algorithm transparency I
think the transparency is such a big
part of this but also user control also
things like forward consents things like
differential privacy settings but
finally we need to also find ways to
rethink really to rethink the financial
evaluation of these companies how is
Google
worth a quarter or half a trillion
dollars yes it's a service and it makes
our lives easier but this is wrath of
God money so I believe we have to do
something or the future will be written
for us but failure to change the course
of current technology and trends could
make could create a system in which sits
as more and more people come online as
the next billion people come online and
are into instantly connected to these
information vacuums masquerading as
phone apps that we can see more and more
replication of historical and equalities
of bias that socioeconomic status will
continue or what the technology will not
help us gain an increased quality of
life and more prosperity but will keep
us in a bubble based on who they think
we are these were probably targeted
technologies are very capable of
undermining democratic institutions who
saw brexit coming who saw the election
of the current American president some
people did but nobody on my facebook
wall it's really interesting to think
that this is when thing very that we're
able to see these processes and in such
a powerful way how could it be that even
though I've never seen a pro brexit
Facebook post and seeing hundreds and
hundreds of anti brags the pace with
posts that there's these these people
out there that I am so insulated from
but still exists what does that mean
what is do i or do we live do I live in
the same society as somebody else in my
same country if my Facebook feed tells a
complete opposite picture of the world
as there's the amplification of a global
technology technological hegemony that
now the rise of the technology
corporation to rival the nation-state
said who do you want on your side in a
war Google or Canada not talking shit
about Canada but I think it's important
that we either we say okay what how
powerful all these technology companies
really I'm also concerned about removal
of humans at the primary primary
decision-making force let's just say
that human out of the loop society out
of the loop we're already seeing Israel
Russia and China work on lethal
autonomous weapons systems that are
truly anonymous a truly truly autonomous
Dick's without any human input there's a
kill list input into this system maybe
and something maybe gather in in part
from Facebook posts check-ins or Google
GPS data so what can we do I think we
have to work in a way to communicate
things to make people realize that they
do not have confidentiality of movements
or association or communication how can
we create privacy as a default I think
in this community is well that we've
seen one of the places which privacy is
truly appreciated but we have to do more
we have to create more robust strategies
to let people outside of our communities
know that this is not just a a risk of
data falling into the wrong hands but a
we run the risk of creating a society
not built on individual agency but by
technological determinism do more build
systems tools and processes that enable
users to reference personal data
collected by platforms how can i yeah
how can we
how can we advocate to enable Facebook
in Google's and the other platforms out
there to let us know what they know
about us we need to increase algorithm
transparency and increase control over
the portability of data Confederated
federated systems or networks that allow
us to traverse our platforms so much to
do to prove support platform to provide
information free of censorship I watched
a tenth lead to the kind of the jump
from Twitter to Macedon not long ago and
III the conversations going around that
of why Twitter was no longer the place
for many people was quite fascinating
and I think that this kind of gets to
this of a censorship at the freedom to
instance and and work in a decentralized
fashion and I think we need to do more
to increase the competence and the
integrity and security of data as it's
stored stay saved and transmitted so the
whole life cycle of data not just
thinking about data as something that
exists when I take a selfie not thinking
about data just is something that exists
when I'm searching results but thinking
about data as something that is a
continuum that even though it was like
this and had this meaning to us when we
put it in the cloud the cloud may have
also been creating its own thoughts
about the same a same image as long as
it's been there so one more time
mimics hashtag monitor index manipulate
intercept censor and silo I'm not saying
it's the best catch-all or it's the most
catchy thing but it's been a pleasure to
present this concepts to y'all tonight
and this is the end of my talk I would
you have anybody has any questions love
to answer in my name is Matthew Stender
Twitter's and I'll keep this screen up
here
thank you very much please come to the
stage for questions hi my name is Barry
and this mimics it's disturbing but
there's one more thing that I would like
your view about which is shields on
Twitter like it's not trolls who are
engaging in a conversation but more
people who are you know they are trying
to manipulate the conversation but not
in the fairway they're doing it in the
system ethical way they're kind of
altering the topics you know it's just
not it's not sometimes they appear to be
BOTS sometimes they appear to be human
or you just don't know of course what's
your view on that shields I would save
anything I would put this into the
manipulation category that the idea of a
platform being manipulated not by state
actors or the platform itself but by a
subset of user base I I think that
Twitter is I don't know sometimes I read
below and I'm like oh yeah I can't tell
if these are people or BOTS or what I
think is more I think is more and more
countries engage in psychological
operations as psyops become more of a
comma as a protected warfare technique
again routine this rise with no
Macedonian but nets and these sort of
things that we have to we have to do a
few things one we have to be get better
at spotting or discarding or being able
to have better tools to block certain
users perhaps think about if enough
people block something or lock one user
can they get reviewed and then be you
know is there is there a a process
involved for a more of a temper like a
temporary or block if they're engaging
in malicious behavior but when it comes
to actually the changing of the
conversation
i-i-i think on one hand there are people
that are being employed to do this
Samantha bee is American comedian has a
Canadian comedian who has a show in the
u.s. actually interviewed some Russian
trolls and they were talking about why
they did it it was kind of for the lulz
and I think there's a South Park episode
as well I don't know if you've seen that
where there's a character that basically
is a troll but do but I think it's the
it's what are what are what is the
motive behind inaction and I think
sometimes it's very hard to tell
sometimes we just need gibberish and so
I think if there is it D railing is it
to create static in this conversation is
it to divert topics and so I feel with
something where some ways we need to
look at them the motive I think it's to
distract other users who are not you
know if it's a controversial subject and
like you me talk about and then he's
overhearing that and they probably would
know that the chill is no just trying to
make that conversation less interesting
yeah in some ways I think that it is
also up to us engaging in conversations
to have a well enough thought through or
it it helps if we have a well thought
through if what we post that we stand
behind and if it's robust enough to not
be able to be derailed I I think that we
should strive to that I don't know if
we're ever going to be able to get
thrills or trolls off because where do
you draw the line what is what is the
difference between me on a snarky day or
I'm whisky drunk and is like does you
know and then somebody that is you know
sitting in in Belarus so for me as far
as advocating for transparency and free
and open platforms free of censorship I
I find the troll problem it's not the
shield problem like the chill problem
very interesting because we're who gets
to call it a troll and I think the same
way with with that I would just say that
if we're able to create
new platforms that are decentralized and
we have more micro granular control over
who is allowed into these sub more
curated communities that's an
alternative but on an open platform like
Twitter I I don't really have a solution
[Music]
practically sure absolutely
practically speaking we're how do you
see the solution in policy in us
demanding more openness especially if
you consider the conflict of interest
that both you know commercial companies
have but also States and in some cases
those states are not even in our control
so how do you see that well I'm right
now the the geopolitical landscape
I see Europe as a leader I think that
the GDP are if we're able to use even
strategic litigation and Saida under
that framework that the European courts
have shown to be much more sympathetic
to people not corporations so I think
that's on the policy slide that now is
actually a very interested in to lobby
Brussels I think they are already
gearing up for strategic litigation once
it passes and particularly things like
the right to explanation I think this is
a very interesting a policy framework in
which there has not really been included
in any other governing data you have
information regulations that that I'm
aware of and to me this idea at which
that a policy mandating the trackback
coolness of a decision to its component
parts is actually a very powerful
mechanism to ensure at least a chain of
custody that we're comfortable with to
be able to somehow not just have
arbitrary artifacts and a machine
learning process or an algorithmic
process but to really be able to look
back and see where at what chain it was
broken or what chain where what at what
but argumentative
you know network things were going on I
so policy strategic litigation I do
think it's more more data stories around
really painting a picture the intercept
had a really interesting piece a couple
of years ago about the revolving door
between Silicon Valley and Washington DC
and so I think that more projects that
visually map out the number of former
Googlers in the White House or the
number of the State Department folks now
you know running your policy directors
at at Facebook is also an interesting
way to do network mapping and help us
understand how intertwined are these
things that's part of it we don't
actually know where all the the the
motivations and interests that the the
both the state and corporations have
some of them are playing the long game
they have not even meant they're not
even mature in their plans that and so I
think that the more we can do to make
people aware about who are running the
companies we know cabinet members and
yeah in government's but beyond Mark
Zuckerberg how many people's names do we
know at Facebook or Byung Smits and you
know people how many in-page like how
many people do we know it at Google and
so I think it's also about elevating the
profiles and putting a little more heat
on on people that are in these companies
to let them know that they're not just
making these decisions in darkness but
that the world is watching them sure but
I think in general that addresses
results right things that we we actually
get to know on it's it's all the stuff
that we don't know that all the the huge
amount of data that they're collecting
and they're making decisions on that is
either in our benefit or not whether you
know they're there there is benefits for
them to be to have it done in our
benefits as well but there's no way to
control that and I think it's gonna be
extremely hard to either through policy
or you know except when we do
journalistic infiltration or something
like that to actually get that type of
information outside I would say I would
have said maybe two years ago if we were
here that advertisers and lobbying of
boards of directors but advertisers in
particular might be a strategic way in
order to influence the course of the
the company but now Facebook and Google
together have like 90% of the digital
advertising market captured between
their duopoly and so I think that we're
actually losing a little way to actually
use economic or traditional market-based
solutions to nudge these companies I
think they're actually with content
collapse in the West like they're
actually now the emerging markets are
really where they're focusing so I think
it's also important for us to get ahead
and work in advocacy and information
training in India Bangladesh and Central
Africa and places like this in which
there's large populations and through
free basics the free Xero rated Facebook
internet and other things where these
things are gonna roll out that we need
to be ahead of the curve and already
have strategies in place to roll a toe
be working with local organizations on
the ground to at least have people be
aware of what does it mean when you log
into Facebook because I think the
transparency around the Terms of Service
and actually whatever this legalese of
what they what it sounds like they're
collecting and actually how much
informations they have is is frightening
so I were the online censorship org
project that I'm involved with we are
our platforms available in English
Spanish Arabic and Portuguese maybe I
don't know so we're even in that we've
create a multilingual framework to
capture as many people and as we as we
go on to translate more languages so I
think it's also about it as activists if
we create tools to make sure that they
are available not just to our
communities but to the world at large
next question please from Mike in the
back perfectly thank you first very much
for an interesting presentation
basically you give already answer to my
question but I try it another way it is
interesting to see that even for a
person a QR which is aware of the
mechanism on the platforms that a stream
of text in front of your eyes makes you
still questioning your perception of
reality in both two ways like what's
created content versus real persons of
and your perception of experiencing
opinions versus opinions you can't
verify but being confronted with in your
stream and you answered already where do
you see some interesting activities you
would like to rise awareness on
practically for us where we can join and
amplify them well I can encourage
everybody to check out the new project
that I mentioned earlier Facebook
tracking exposed it's a browser plug-in
and that information is able to be used
to analyze patterns of how which it
creates in a record of the post ID and
then every time you're on Facebook it
collects them and so one of the
interesting applications of that is to
figure out are there any interesting
data stories that we can extrapolate
from the number of posts even though
every other on a daily basis on Sundays
do we get more ads or around election
time do we you know are a few key people
and are in our feed getting pushed to us
on a you know hourly basis so I think
that transparency around the the
algorithmic sorting is quite interesting
online censorship org is again to plug
blog my project but we have this we are
a survey that people can fill in so if
you ever see anybody on Facebook saying
their post has been taken down
especially erroneously it would be great
if you could you know send them the link
and we're really trying to capture as
many stories and then turn those into
reports and policy policy proposals or
policy recommendations yeah I think like
new platforms like mastodons and other
places which is it like if we're able to
create a critical mass on on open source
platforms or we're open on proprietary
platforms then it gives them more
legitimacy and if we're able to create
platforms that are not reliant on
traditional advertising models or on
proprietary closed platforms that people
can instant
in create Newtons and instances for
themself and it doesn't have to be a
top-down then this idea is legitimize
more in the eyes of Silicon Valley that
people say oh wow we Macedon got this
big without really any VC funding how
could that happen and so I think that we
also need to show that there is a bit us
as as people that are thinking
progressively about these issues that we
do not adhere to the traditional value
in which of these platforms think that
they give us that our value is actually
in privacy but this is something we
probably we value that the lack of
censorship on platforms is something
that we value that we're going to have
our voice hurt there and so I think that
also while raising up alternative
platforms and engaging and working to to
create or be a part of the system so
that the platforms that we want gives
them increase legitimacy and visibility
that's hopefully well sink into the
minds of those that are funding
platforms and and the places that
they're forum funded I myself never had
and Facebook account never used it but
thank you very much for raising
awareness because that's passing in my
argument to people once you would know
what's really going going on on there or
what's the purpose you would not use it
anymore and that's basically your
expression you supported that very well
thank you very much welcome any more
questions from the audience we still
enjoy a minute for question no thank you
very much I was
[Applause]
[Music]