[Music]
good morning everyone thanks for making
it up I barely did
welcome to the brief history of CTF talk
I do have a challenge in the sea I can't
have a CTF talk without a CTF challenge
but it might be broken so I just want to
preface this with I couldn't get my
payload working but it was like 5:00
a.m. when I finally got to set up so my
excuse is that I was tired but you guys
hopefully can can solve this if you want
to get your phones out and take a
picture of that one the password to the
account is just insomniac I think I got
the permission set up where you probably
can't screw with each other but there's
probably still away so so be nice and
see if you can solve the challenge
there's a slash flag file that's only
readable in a suid binary with source I
mean come on I'm really making it easy
on you because I know you only have a
few minutes so if you can you can solve
that challenge during the talk that way
at least if I'm boring you have you have
something else to do so this is my
unbias not my UN bio I know we are in
Geneva but this is the things that I am
not so I want to be very clear I am NOT
the best CTF player by a large margin
I'd say low key into youhad have pretty
good claims on that I'm not the
winningest DEFCON CTF player PPP has
beaten me more times I'm not even the
organizer the longest-running CTF shell
fish has done that the same kind of
organizers and I'm not the longest
continuous CTF Clarissa seagulls been
playing for way longer than that I'm not
even a current CTF player because I have
retired I'm too old and slow and and I
my hobbies are different and this is
very sad I wistfully look at CTF these
days but I haven't played in at least a
year and a half now this is very sad
board I am though is somebody who has
played a lot of Def Con in the past it's
late a lot of CTF won a couple times I
helped build Cyber Grand Challenge which
is a really fun massive CTF probably the
biggest in terms of infrastructure and
overall investment of time and money
CTF that's ever happened that was put on
by DARPA I was captain to the team
behind ghost in the shell code which has
some memorable challenges
I run cap TF comm which is a collection
of CTF challenges and one time I ran a
CTF awards ceremony just for one year
but but hopefully we can we can kick
start that again later and I'm one of
the developers of binary
as well a quick survey who here has
heard of capture the flag I mean you're
in the talks oh right yeah you have to
do that okay who has play to capture the
flag keep your hands ups excellent now
who has knows the current team CTF time
rank who could tell me yeah okay a
couple of you were like yeah I we know
of plus or minus where we're at who has
organized two CTF has run their own CTF
excellent that's a good chunk there
hidden who is retired from CTF like me
and your retires yes good retirees we
can join together afterwards maybe
tonight at the CTF we can form a new one
okay so I'm gonna skip this because you
don't need to know what types of CTF are
in the beginning at least for me it
wasn't quite my very first CTF but one
of my first CTFs was the DEFCON CTF
where we submitted via DTMF I don't know
if anybody were here I know though I
think it was talking to one of the
pandas who was there for that year you
actually were given a telephone cable to
submit your keys so you actually had to
deed dial tone DTMF into this asterisk
employed server so that's the the
beginning of sort of my CTF experience
I'm gonna reference DEFCON CTF a lot
because I've got the most experience
probably with that but clearly there are
a lot of other worldwide CTF my stories
my experiences are certainly biased
towards what I know and so I would love
to have you guys tell me more about what
I don't know of other cts
in different areas but I don't expect
you to read this this is not meant to be
readable for reference this is a Google
sheets document that is open and I would
love to have contributions and comments
and fixes if there's things I'm missing
but this is kind of a detailed look at
the history in terms of what
architectures were you is whether the
kind of notable key events I want to
cover two of them now and one is badger
badger was really really cool this was
one of the legit BS Def Con CTF games
where they built a custom Wi-Fi badge
whatsit there was actually Wi-Fi they
bought their own custom RF protocol and
it was spread spread spectrum
frequency-hopping written by hand they
wrote everything by hand
oh also it was running to msp430 cores
virtualized on top of his eye links fpga
they had to have two cores so they could
have their out of man command control
and like the flash in the emulation for
like their game infrastructure as well
as the one that you could
flash this is a really really impressive
piece of design and this predated the
sort of current trend of badge explosion
if you're a Def Con this year you there
was like 50 badges and some really
really cool stuff that people are
designing I'm but this was a completely
like you know ground-up hand done piece
of love it was really really impressive
unfortunately there was a minor bug in
it then off-by-one so that team zero
couldn't score and team zero happen to
be PPP that year and they happen to have
an exploit before anyone and struggled
to land it never got it working during
the game but thankfully root ARS is any
of the root ARS players here this the
French CTF team no one will admit to it
if they are they were they were one of
my favorite teams to compete with the
Def Con because they always got second I
always felt so bad for them they were
second more than anyone else in the
history of Def Con CTF I believe but
they were great sports they were the
only team to successfully land an
exploit on this badge during the game
they have a very nice write-up in the
slide notes you can read kind of more
the details of what the exploit was I
hate actually worked on him one of the
next place for our team I think they may
have even held true tars land theirs
because ours we were throwing it and it
was failing and they pulled her off the
wire and I think it might have might
have helped them but clemency is an
awful piece of work if you if you play
DEFCON this last year it was a terrible
terrible thing that was done to you I
I'm sorry for that but I think many of
you may have enjoyed that pain clemency
was a custom architecture you might have
heard about this where it was Middle
Indian it wasn't big endian it wasn't
little endian
it was Middle Indian and this is just
because lightning is evil there is no
other explanation it was oh also nine
bits because why would you want a power
of two for your number of bits which
made year translations from networked in
memory byte encoding super awful it was
it was really really terrible and the
worst part about clemency was they gave
everyone the design doc for it the day
before the event and I had actually been
arguing I'm good friends with the legit
yes organisers and I had known about it
for a while they had talked to us and
said hey would you make a binary ninja
plugin for this and we looked at it said
no that's way too much work there's no
way we're gonna make a plug-in to
support this awful architecture although
several people did
hack together some plugins during the
event but I was really impressed a lot
of the teams at the finals were able to
to adapt and take this crazy
architecture weirder than many other
architectures you've ever seen build
working tooling in less than 24 hours
and then play a CTF and write exploits
on that on that architecture so that was
really really neat that challenge now in
terms of the overall total CTF and
thanks to CTF time for their kind of
archival data you can go back and look
and see where we're at in terms of total
CTF
I just in 2017 we had about a hundred
and forty so we're not quite at every
other day but we're closing in there
right where you could literally play a
CTF every other day and if we assume
that CTS run for you know two days
apiece often times then we're looking at
every day of the year you could
essentially be playing a CTF if you
spread them out so there are an insane
number of these capsule flag
competitions that are going on and that
means there's something for everyone
right there's different styles there's
different challenges I'm gonna not spend
a lot of time on scoring mechanisms
suffice to say that that they exist and
for attack-defense competitions in
particular they're very fraught with
with risks right to try to make sure
that your teams are playing legit or at
least the way you want them to play
you're getting the right behavior out
requires a lot of incentivization so you
really have to think about when you're
organizing a CTF how do you score do you
let team how do you prevent teams from
replaying services from replaying
attacks do you want them to for some
services but not all you need to have
some sort of pulling mechanism you want
to make sure that they don't just turn
their services off because it turns out
an unplugged server is a very secure
server it's just not very useful one and
so you have to sort of incentivize the
proper behavior jeopardy style of course
CTF so this sort of more scoreboard
based they tend to have sort of
different scoring mechanisms I really
like the self adjusting scores where the
the scoreboard automatically balances
itself based on the number of solves
it's really hard anyone who has ever run
a CTF can tell you it's really hard to
properly score a challenge to come up
with this is clearly 100 points 50
points 500 points whatever your scale is
you will get it wrong because someone
else will think of something easier than
you thought of that you didn't find or
what you think is an easy answer because
you know it and you made it is actually
much harder to other people without that
that tainted knowledge so one
recommendation is that when you were
building a CTF have your teammates test
your challenges teammates with no
foreknowledge of what the challenge is
to make sure you you've gauged it
appropriately now there are a lot of fun
Superman defenses as I'd call them
especially in attack-defence CTF where
you're engaged heavily with other people
some of them are really stupid and some
of them are really interesting service
redirection is really stupid
for example if you want to make sure
that my service is running I can just
netcat to someone else's service and say
look at my service is still running tada
I'm still providing services it
interacts is very functional but you're
not stealing my flags that is not an
interesting defense it's not a
technically legitimate one and so as an
organizer your job is to sort of prevent
this and minimize this now but there are
some other ones that are more
interesting and you may or may not want
to allow depending on the type of event
you're in syscall filtering virtualized
services people have have wrapped
services in Khemu they'll actually
instrument it so that all that that
everything is passed on through it
except for the opens this call right and
they'll go ahead and trap that and is it
opening the flag then disallow it right
and so you'll see a lot of generic
defenses like that that mean the team
doesn't have to actually figure out
where the vulnerability is but they can
just tune Eric Lee patch them all over
the place I talk very fast and I know
this so I actually have slide notes to
make myself slow down and stop so I'm
gonna take a breath for a second and I'm
gonna show you if you're working on a
CTF what prize you're working for it's
too early for audience participation
okay it's a mug it's a you know
insulated cup it's got the binary ninja
logo on it and some stickers and if
anyone else wants stickers afterwards I
have a whole bunch of stickers up here
as well there's a lot of fun Network
shenanigans too
all right real-world impact one of my
favorite things about CTF is that a lot
of people look at
these crazy challenges and they say like
that's that's not very realistic right
that's the most outlandish ridiculous
thing that doesn't relate to real-world
exploitability the weirder the challenge
is that I have ever made
the more likely it is to represent
something I worked on my day job as a
vulnerability researcher you would be
very surprised at how often real-world
problems inspire CTF challenges and
vice-versa
back and forth there they're very very
often related and so the skills you
develop playing a CTF can be very very
helpful when you're actually doing a
reverse engineering and vulnerability
research I have a whole list of things
of challenges that have developed
real-world exploits and vice-versa and I
don't even have time for them so I'm
gonna skip them and tell you to go watch
my infiltrate talk that I gave a few
years ago where I listed a bunch of them
and the slides are online so you'll
actually have to listen to me jabber and
you can you can see there's been a large
number of these these challenges that
were really had actual impact so this is
not just a game that we're playing but
actually has inspired a lot of real
tools and real exploits one of the
aspects of CTF that is very near and
dear to my heart is gamification in fact
I actually quit my job at my last
company three years ago and founded
vector 35 we make binary ninja so that
we could actually build hackable video
games our long-term goal is to build
like a real MMO with hacking as a as a
real game mechanic now and not like you
know click-click hacking but actually
real reverse engineering real
programming actual virtual architecture
those magic spells are actually code
running in a virtual machine inside the
world and so the players will like CTF
players you all be wizards in this world
it's going to be an amazing place once
we end up building it but we thought we
should make money first so that's why we
we made a real product and tried to sell
that so you know eventually we'll get
there we hope if we do well I will be
able to build this but I think that
there's tremendous potential I think a
lot of us got our start in security
hacking video games cracking software
doing these kind of like I said I saw
some nods yes it's okay
I like cracking software I buy it and
then I crack it usually but this is how
a lot of us kind of starts this
challenge in this fund
this drive to solve things and so doing
that inside of a game environment where
there's other people were competing
against where there's sort of fun
interactive visuals makes it a lot more
interesting one of the earlier examples
of this was choose your pony adventure
my team loves puns and so choose your
own adventure games were inspired by my
Zork and the text adventures of your
choose your own adventure was started
for the pop on the p20 an adventure was
a very simple game again it was just a
text-based game you could follow through
a little series of challenges where you
had to get past rooms and once you made
it to the end you had a different
exploit and depending on the route you
had taken there were different
characteristics and they exploit that
made it easier or harder it was it was a
lot of fun but actually a few years
later PPP in their plat CTF released a
really cool game like interface their
scoreboard was actually like this world
you walked around in the web browser and
two of their main main exploiters
actually spent more time building this
web interface than they did challenges
that year because it was really
cool-looking it was fun but there wasn't
actually any challenges like in the
interface right the web interface was
really just there just you know look
cool and to walk around interact with
people and so the following year after
that at ghost Michelle Kobe released
pony adventure 2 and pony adventure 2
was was complete overkill
it was a unity based MMO with we had I
think two hundred something users a
hundred something users simultaneous at
one point running around shooting each
other
hacking the game client because you were
supposed to hack it to solve challenges
you had to cheat and this was literally
the point of it
rusty Wagner how the co-founder of my
company was was the the primary
architect of this whole series of pony
adventure challenges he spent about six
months a ton of time just building the
CTF building these challenges into it
and it was because it was in unity it
was dotnet reverse engineering which
made it a great introductory challenge
for reverse engineering now you didn't
have to know any native assembly but the
net D compilers are pretty good so the
next year we came up with Pony Adventure
and pony vector3 was based on the Unreal
Engine and so it was C++ much harder
reverse-engineer in fact we actually use
it in a training course that we just did
a few days ago I see a few students in
the audience where we teach reverse
engineering inside of this game because
it's a lot of fun too like you know when
you get stressed with the reverse
engineering you're doing to go shoot
some stuff for a little while and so the
the the source to this game that you
don't have to take the course we've
actually published the binaries for both
opponent venture to in point of extra
three online so if you grab the the
slide URL at the end you can get the the
links to that but there was all sorts of
teleport hacks of flying hacks there was
some game glitches in the game but most
of the the exploits in Poona venture to
input image were three were exploits of
the client you patched your client you
exploit the server
you were you were hacking the game
infrastructure itself one way the other
right the server trusted client input
and would let it automatically you know
tell aware as position was when it
should have verified that it was
physically possible to move that fast
between two points for example and so we
we kind of wanted to to change this and
again our long-term vision for for a
hakama video game as one in which the
hacking occurs inside of the game
because when you break the game client
too much it sort of becomes not fun at a
certain point right because it's totally
unconstrained and so we wanted to build
a world where we were using the game
client more directly and not just like
patching your game client cheating and
so pone Adventures Z is a little a
little dark in the background was a
zombie survival game scrt actually has a
couple of copies and so if you go out
and see the TV you may have wandered
past it there's it's it was written for
NTSC and the NES is pal so the audio is
a little distorted and it's a little bit
slower but it still plays fine so you
can go check out you can you can try
this this game Pony Adventure Z is
modeled very much like a Zelda you'll
see people like did you copy Zelda
sprites no all of our sprites were
hand-drawn we didn't in fact our trees
have shadows much in finer detail than
Zelda one ever ever had
so so you know we're very proud of of
our little little game
it's hand coded 6502 but my favorite
part about this is that pony vet rosie
takes its inspiration from the
speedrunning community and the game
tazón community if you haven't seen the
work being done by speedrunners it's
mind blowing
all right so people who just started
playing these video games to go faster
and faster and try to like optimize
their routes I started doing what we're
called Tazz's tool assisted speedruns
where they would frame-by-frame do
perfect input into the game and so they
could come up with the most optimal
solution to beating Mario or whatever
the game that they're running was and
somewhere along the line they decided
well hey that's weird
if we do this specific sequence of
things the game crashes I wonder why
that is when the answer is they're
exploiting it they're exploiting it with
up-down left-right and just using the
controller inputs they were able to
create exploits to these games they
called them total control speedruns they
were exploiting the game they were
coming up with with advanced
exploitation technologies almost some of
them didn't even know like security and
software exploitation was a thing they
were just like how do I make my game
faster and they come up with these
fantastic exploits a pokemon yellow on
the Gameboy has classically been in a
lot Super Mario World has been owned so
thoroughly that they they can jump to
the credits by hands now doing raw code
execution in 41 seconds I think is the
current record they can they they just
do some bizarre series of manipulations
many of which are pixel perfect and
frame perfect frame perfect meaning once
every 60 ticks you know so one sixtieth
of a second our one fiftieth of a second
they have to get an exact perfect timing
on their button presses for some of
their moves so the fact that humans can
do this on an NES controller and it can
be pixel perfect on the screen is is
mind-blowing right this is really really
cool so Google sethbling or
tool-assisted speedrun Super Mario you
can watch agdq there's a whole series of
these fantastic runs where people are
doing this so opponent venture Z was
sort of our homage to that that we
released as a CTF challenge to kind of
bridge the gap
between the CTF community and the
speedrunning community thanks watch I
appreciate that and heard something
alright and we actually released it as
well on the 30th anniversary of Mario
and the NES and 2015 so oh yeah I should
have pulled this up earlier this is
actually the current I think world
record speedrun
I have no idea how this speedrun works
by the way so we built point adventure Z
to be exploited we designed several
flaws into it actually has code
execution bugs where you can use your
inventory to write shellcode and you can
move your items around and change your
accounts by selling and buying things
and you can specifically build shellcode
payloads this speedrun I have no clue
how it works like absolutely none they
just kind of glitched between screens
and they're off in different pieces of
memory so we should probably actually
pull up the the the replay file and
figure out how he jumps straight to the
boss there because that boss does not
appear in that configuration on that
level we have I've we have no idea like
he's literally treating some random
piece of data like map data that happens
to have a boss on it and then he defeats
it which triggers the game over screen
so he beats the game in about a minute
and thirty seconds in this speedrun and
the fastest we ever did was about eight
or nine minutes when we were testing it
so even an intentionally vulnerable one
was you know more vulnerable than we and
we realized okay one of my favorite
topics of CTFs are visualizations and
yes I'm being intentionally ironic that
the only slide without an image of my
talk is the one that says the word
visualizations cuz that's my sense of
humor so I apologize visualizations have
been around for a long time as CTFs
usually for scoreboards so back in
DEFCON this was I've gotten 2004 or 2005
I believe the scoreboard was actually
broadcast on like the hotel's TV so
there'd be like CRT screens you know at
the time with like this the school board
it was meant to look kind of like a
stock ticker and they were showing the
live live stats of the game so you could
watch you know who was winning many of
you see I'm sure cts with with great
visualizations and great scoreboards but
I think we've we've come a long way
since then
for example I think the flashiest is
probably ni CT out of Japan has a tool
they call Daedalus that's actually been
around for about four years now
it's they've been using it and code blue
and second enough a number of other ones
if this doesn't look like anime come to
life or a Minority Report then I don't
know what does and they've actually I
think tried to market it at various
times it's like an actual tool to
companies to visualize attacks I don't
know if your sock I mean other than
impressing your your c-level folks at a
large company I'm not certain that this
would be super useful for actively
running at an Operations Center but it's
really really cool-looking
it is it is Bar None the best looking
interface to a CTF I've ever seen and
like I said I think they actually built
it for not even for CTS but then they
just decided maybe no one's buying it we
should actually just make it a CT F
visualization when it's awesome I wish
mine looked that good so one of the ones
that I mentioned earlier that I worked
on was cyber Grand Challenge hey I'm
curious how many people have heard of
cyber Grand Challenge before more than I
expected so thank you it's that's good
to hear
the visualization of cyber Grand
Challenge were not nearly as flashy as
Daedalus
but like Daedalus they're very very
data-driven
right and so these were not just like
fancy things in fact the the the the
phrase we were we were using internally
with this was no cyber the idea
is that we wanted to have well it should
look good and be accessible to to a
layman it should actually communicate
something it should tell you something
about the game in a way that was
actually more useful than just staring
it like raw numbers this view may not do
that as much but there's actually a
whole series of videos online and visi
one of the team captain of Ken shadow
which ran Def Con for many years was
sort of our celebrity announcer for the
event so here he is explaining the
visualizations and these visualizations
were a collaboration between myself and
rusty and a video game company so we had
an actual video game company worked for
about a year and a half building these
visualizations and taking a bunch of
binary instrumentation and throwing them
all together so that we could show what
was happening inside of the game and so
this is like really data dense you can
see which team was exploiting which
other team on which services you can see
the total number of services in play you
can see where teams were getting their
points from their availability their
security of their evaluation if you if
watched the event live there was some
glitches it was painful to be behind the
scenes because the announcers were sort
of like strained in at several points
with nothing to talk about and I had to
kind of cover and we had a whole like TV
production crew it was a fantastic
experience like I was on headsets you
know I had like this push button thing
just to talk to the cameraman and the
producer and the guy on the stage and I
would tell him okay we're sending you
information on this service where this
team did this but unfortunately like we
had some trouble with getting the
getting the all the information up to
them in time so there's actually a a
recap video that I highly recommend that
talks about some were kind of behind the
scenes things that that happened this is
my favorite visualization of all time
though this one here is technically very
useful and I would love to see somebody
actually take this and do something else
with it the source code has been open
sourced it's it's based on the key mu
with dataflow and so we generate
execution traces well run a binary and
we'll trace it will monitor all the
registers that reads the writes but more
importantly we log the instruction
pointer and so just by logging the
instruction pointer and then what we do
is we map that over and do a Hilbert
curve so a 2d plane where you know
Hilbert curve I was the exact phrase
it's a space-filling mechanism that
maintains locality so the idea just
being if you take a number line and you
squiggle it up into a piece of paper in
such a way then any two points that were
close on the number line are now closed
on the piece of paper it just means that
if two things were close in memory and a
linear address space they'll be closed
in this 2d plane and then we extrude
this plane over time as the execution
progresses right so we run the the
program we execute it and we can see
pictures I'm going to restarted here we
can see pictures of a program running
okay well that's neat but so what right
what does it actually tell you well one
of my favorite things is that when we
were developing this tool internally
after the qualification round for CGC we
were testing it an inputs from that from
the teams and we would take one one
binary from one team or and we compare
it against the reference binary so we
take the original unpatched but binary
had a vulnerability in it and then we
would take a
version from one of the teams and we
want to see how do they differ what are
the ways in which they're the same or
they're different and we could actually
tell oh well they have the same shape
they have the same structure you can see
the same loops the same calls to other
functions and then like so the same
overall flow and parsing of data would
be very visible but this was three times
longer well why is that it's because in
this case they had lifted two two LLVM
IR readmitted re down to native
execution so it was a completely
different set of instructions so if I
gave you the two binaries you could do
things like well maybe we can count the
functions but the function size would be
very different the opcodes would be very
different so they'd have certain
characteristics of they're the same
certain that are very different but by
feeding this an input generating this
trace we could tell these are doing the
same thing they process the data in the
same way very quickly and visually but
you could actually even see oh there's
their memory safety check they
instrumented all memory reads to make
sure that they weren't crashing and you
could see this one function being called
a lot they jumped down to it a whole
bunch right so you could just see this
visually you've got a lot of information
about it they were very useful when
comparing two pieces of software so
anyways Seibert gonna challenge was a
huge event the data is all line the
corpus of challenges of vulnerabilities
is all available for research and so if
you're actually doing any kind of binary
analysis research it makes for a really
nice test corpus because among other
things they they actually if deft
out all the vulnerabilities in the
source code one of the requirements for
the authors was that you had to know
exactly where the bug was to patch it
now of course they didn't know all of
their own bugs there were absolutely
Vollmer abilities that were explored in
the game that were not intended but
those that were intended to have to have
if deaths and have documentation which
makes this a very useful test corpus for
for research so I highly recommend you
check that out and there's also a recap
video that summarizes a lot of the
individual events that happens inside it
all right so now the real reason I'm
giving this talk isn't as an excuse to
talk about just my favorite crazy things
that have happened and capture-the-flag
over the years right there the the best
part about CTF are all of the the fun
stories the unintended flaws the hacking
the organizers the organizers hacking
you so I'm gonna start with one that I
call antenna fun at DEFCON CTF teams
will often have two separate groups
because if you're limited in the number
of people on the team floor
you had more than a people you'd have
like a separate group of people up in a
hotel room or maybe even you only had
one or two people at the game floor and
the rest of your team hides because you
can't concentrate you can't think in the
game floor where it's videos and noise
and there's people coming by and
bothering you another team spying on you
and so we thought oh this is great
our team had a lot of people this year
we're gonna get a giant antenna and some
like military-grade like RF equipment
and set up a point-to-point link between
the game room and our hotel room and
this was in the other Rio that where Def
Con was held at the time which which is
a giant Tower of course in the middle of
the Vegas and they have this foil
plating in all the windows which is word
that like the Penn & Teller's face are
you know it reflects the Sun it reflects
a lot of ambient heat it reflects a lot
of RF - it turns out and so we never got
our link going although we did discover
later that one of our one of our teams
of people was out like positioning the
antenna pointing at the tower hotel
security thought that was really weird
for some reason they didn't appreciate
that and they came out and escorted them
away from the parking garage where they
were and one of the other CTF teams at
DEFCON took a picture of this out that
window and tweeted it and we're like oh
there's our guys I guess they didn't
they didn't make it so we were really
bummed that we didn't we didn't have
this like working point-to-point link
between between our room but we thought
well we have this giant antenna I mean
what what else could we do with it and
like well we could you know psyops
psychological operations on our
opponents and so we took it down to the
game floor and we set it up we ran the
cables like over where it looked like it
was plugged into a computer and then we
would just be working never done that we
did just it and pointed at a different
team we'd work some more and then we so
you know we wanted them to think we were
van Eck phreaking them and pulling off
their images from their monitors were
pulling off their keystrokes and so we
got these really nervous looks and you
know we would intentionally aim at the
different team and oh yeah we call
people over and pointed stuff I did fess
up to them we didn't want them thinking
they were gonna get cancer afterwards
from whatever we may have been doing
most conferences have these have these
nice air walls right so that they can
rearrange the rooms some of these air
walls come in these have these little
hidden closets so as I mentioned that
the the noise in the environment at Def
Con is not very pleasant and so one year
we happen to be situated right by the
edge of the wall
and we know there's a handle on the wall
we thought that's weird wiser a handle
on this this wall and you open it and
there's this like little closet space
but which was actually like you know 15
feet by 10 feet it's a whole room back
there right next to our CTF table so
half our team went and hid in the closet
now for the rest of the CTF it was very
quiet we got a lot of work done we ran a
network cable into the wall and we had
until the the staff member from the
hotel came in and looked at us and goes
there's people in here
we're like yep hi he left and let us go
too so we were able to keep playing the
whole CTF in the closet but we didn't
get down tools get broken a lot in CTF
right one of the best parts about a CTF
is you know the techniques that people
are going to use and you can screw with
them right this is what makes it
entertaining you can intentionally break
them and this makes our tools better to
the sort of adversarial model of
intentionally attacking our tools and
then fixing the tools to handle those
things makes them better for the real
world because security is an inherently
adversarial environment it's the one
thing that makes makes security
different from many other aspects of
computer science and research is that we
are actively combating foes right
viruses are being not written by
computers but written by intelligent
people although maybe someday soon then
maybe the computers will be entirely
writing their own but right now we're
combating smart humans that are
attempting to hack us that are
attempting to write viruses and smart
humans are defending it so this
adversarial relationship is fairly
unique I think to a lot of avenues of
research
laso you see a lot of tools being broken
in CTFs a lippy cap and Wireshark always
have bugs if you go and run Wireshark at
any any Def Con in the last decade or
any other attack/defense competition
it's gonna crash and you might even be
giving code execution on your box to
your opponents like depending on how
good their bug is how much time they
wanted to put into it because it turns
out Wireshark is nothing but a protocol
parser lots and lots of protocols which
it will happily decode for you without
even asking by default and protocol
parsing turns out to be one of the
harder problems and one of the more
error-prone security Pro amount of
problems so there's always lots of bugs
in Wireshark so it
the detectors you'll still have bugs so
run it in sandbox to run it VM or write
your own write like actually I know at
least a half dozen teams who've written
their own stream reassembly a stream
extraction tools specifically because
it's too easy to exploit Wireshark
flooding listeners is less technically
interesting but still entertaining and
requires a little bit of work most teams
that build their own command and control
infrastructure an attack defense CTF
right where there are actively getting
back their payloads you might want to
encrypt the flag so that it can't be
trivially taken off the network when it
comes back to you and so when you do
this it's a phoning home or it's
connecting back to you and if you do
this poorly I your opponents might be
able to just flood your interface with
fake keys making it hard for you to know
which ones were real and making you not
able to submit them as quickly to the
infrastructure and if several occassions
this is this has happened to real teams
this one happened to me and it wasn't my
fault I swear it was a teammate of mine
and it's actually I've done several
different events but when you submit
your flags to a score server
don't use curl or a command line tool
and if you do really don't make don't
just pass into flag as a command line
argument because that's going to end
poorly for you in particular with an RM
dash RF back ticks around it right and
so this actually happened in my virtual
machine I had led a friend of mine use
during one of the one of the CTF and
nine 4:47 in Australian CTF team I was
like lols we put back tech RM RF and our
flags did anybody get owned and and I
went in looked and I had gotten they had
gotten code execution on my box but I
was running a bunt to which thankfully
if you've ever tried RM dash RF on a
bunt to at least you used to do this I
hope it still does so test it on a VM
before you take my word for it but it
used to require a separate parameter
right so you couldn't just type it and
it wouldn't nuclear a whole hard drive
because it was so commonly used to troll
people that a bunt to actually modified
RM so that you couldn't do that right
so thankfully I was that was the only
reason I was save like they absolutely
had command injection on my box and I
said no samurai did this as well I guess
apt eight and another one Chris Eagle
has been around CTF forever he literally
wrote the book on
and he was been owned a schoolmaster see
a seagull he has been playing CTFs
longer than there are CCF players who
have been alive right that's how long
he's been playing CTF one year at Def
Con the last time he won it before he
became an organizer of it they were so
far ahead the last day they just played
guitar here or the whole day and the
reason they they got ahead is because
they had a really really beautiful
payload what their exploit would do the
the infrastructure for cts have changed
over the years sometimes they would use
X inot D and they would launch a process
and then for a while they would fork the
process they would have a route own
process to listen on whatever port and
then and then fork so that you you don't
want to let the child overwrite the
parent well if you do the order wrong
and how you do the forking the child can
still over at the memory of the parent
and this allowed Eagle to build a
payload so that when he exploited a
service on your box he was able to
process inject into the parent process
that was the one forking children to
answer all the requests and he was able
to patch the bug so thanks that was nice
he fixed the bug no one else could
exploit you and put his own backdoor
into it right and so he not only denied
all your flags to other teams but then
he had all the flights he wanted kind of
coming forward without throwing his
exploit so it made his his payload very
stealthy you couldn't replay his attack
because it was specific to it you know
private key infrastructure which he had
set up in memory and you're in your box
so you couldn't reuse it you couldn't
learn anything about the exploit was a
beautiful payload you destroy the
competition that year there's been a
bunch of what I'm gonna call a nearly
epic hacks against infrastructure these
were things that almost worked but
didn't the telephone infrastructure I
mentioned earlier we had to submit your
flags via DTMF which by the way there
was a run on modems us at Fry's that
year in Vegas because my team bought
them all thinking we would deny them to
our teammates to make it harder because
if this was like right with it before
the transition were very few people
still had modems in their laptops
anymore but the Astra server that they
were running the VoIP infrastructure on
had a default credentials on it and one
of the teams was able to figure this out
and get into a debug menu and there was
try
to reconfigure the VoIP server so that
they would be able to have flags
redirected to them first
instead they broke it and so they didn't
get any flags and they just took the
server down for a little bit well I can
show to fix it but it was really close
to owning the infrastructure one team
actually had a breakout of the clemency
emulator that they never quite landed
but that would have been in stone edge
on all the services because you had been
able to own a team's infrastructure and
then from there potentially do more or
do some sort of like permanent payload
the way eagle did earlier one of my
favorites is the crypto backdoor one of
the ways that teams verified you were
actually running your service in an
attack defense type CTF is they would
build a backdoor and do it so that they
had a public private key infrastructure
and they could request the flag at any
time this way if you had a generic like
I just removed the flag or I made the
flag not writable or I modified syscalls
they would be able to verify that by
getting code execution in your in your
your process with assigned payload from
their their private key and they would
able to be able to replay it on your
machine to verify they can still read
the flags the problem with their crypto
was it didn't have a nonce or a
timestamp and so you could replay
attacks you could actually proxy their
attack to somebody else and be and
because their payload verified they
could read the flag you would get the
flag back if you wrote the mandala
middle out properly and so the problem
is by the time my team noticed this DD
Tech had changed how they use the crypto
backdoor and they sent the the data on a
separate interface there was two virtual
interfaces on our machines that year and
we didn't notice that the crypto
verifiers were coming in on a different
interface if we had we could have
redirected to the other teams we already
had the working payload and would have
been able to get every flag from any
other team using the organizers own
infrastructure but we didn't so it was
nearly epic actually epic was the year
that Lola skaters dropped FreeBSD O'Day
and started popping out of jails this
annoyed the organizers to no end
DD Tech was not happy that year but the
rest of the teams thought it was
hilarious because I mean who wouldn't
like a real O'Day in the middle of a CTF
causing chaos and ruckus it was it was
quite entertaining that same year there
was some
tcp/ip shenanigans one of the techniques
that my team had was the ability to
monitor monitor tcp/ip timestamp fields
right and so pehlivan at AT&T Labs it
actually proves to paper some years
earlier about using the TCP timestamp
field to count the number of hosts
behind in a NAT so you could use this if
you were sniffing to be able to make
estimates about the number you could
sort of get estimates of the number of
hosts well in a relatively small network
like the size of Def Con and with good
data you could not just count hosts you
could perfectly D anonymize right you
could actually even though the data was
being source routed and so every
connection came from the same ip address
you could actually uniquely identify
every speaker with this with this
technique the cool part about this is
this wasn't discovered by one team but
at least two teams independently
developed this technique for the same
kind of problem using some sort of some
original research you would take that
the the timestamp start you take the
skew of it which is based in the
operating system and those two facts
together would give you a sort of unique
fingerprint to let you separate out the
hosts we tried to use it to only allow
access to the the score server
infrastructure so that we would pass all
the polls and firewall off everyone else
but we had some glitch where we weren't
identifying some fields and so we are
some hosts and so we couldn't deploy it
generically that year but what we did do
was block the wrong one we did do was
block of all our skaters from throwing
their exploit at us anymore so after a
while we just disappeared from the
network and they couldn't hit us which
actually helped their score a little bit
that year I really really like troll
challenges so I called troll challenges
when the organizers get the hack two
contestants back right so it's no fun
when you're just getting beat up all day
and everyone's writing explicit for your
services it's always entertaining when
the organizers get to exploit the
participants back trust me is an
entertaining one that started at Def Con
it's been fielded variants of it and
many other CTFs where you were given a
binary and it was called trust me and
and you're supposed to run it it's
heavily off you skated with all sorts of
packing and anti analysis that you're
not meant to like undo by hand you could
try to spend the whole time doing it or
you could just trust it and you could
run it and it would turn on your
microphone and record audio
and complaint if it couldn't and quit
and it would take a webcam capture and
complaint if it couldn't acquit it would
make sure it wasn't running in a VM it
would make sure it was running his route
it would enumerate the number of USB
keys disliked it would do all sorts of
invasive awful things but if you just
let it do it at the end of which would
give you a flag right so if you trust in
it you got the flag and it would send
all this data back to a
command-and-control host I want to point
out - so if you like had a spare machine
on you didn't care on or you just were
super Yolo you would just run the binary
I love these challenges because you have
this trade-off like in your head do you
run it do you really trust the CTF
organizer these are hilarious
hacker book was a challenge that we
field of the ghost in the shell code it
was like a PHP awful interface it's kind
of like Facebook where you just had a
bunch of different pictures of people
but you were told you had to identify a
certain percentage of these hackers and
we got a bunch of random pictures of
people from other CTF
many of whom we didn't know and our
database didn't actually have answers
for who all these people were we didn't
tell the organizer was that we pretended
like we had the names of everybody who
was in it and there were several
different exploits actually there's
several ways you could actually reuse
one correct answer several times there
was another PHP bug so you didn't
actually have to know the names of all
these people but some people didn't find
the bugs and so they were just trying to
enter the names for all the people
including one person who said listen I'm
typing the right name for this person
he's a friend of mine I know for certain
it's him it's not working and we're like
well you know I don't know like what's
the what's the image and he tells us the
imagine it's we have no idea who this
person is either we just pull it off
some like CTF web page and we're like oh
that's that you know I don't know that's
weird
keep trying I guess he's like no I've
got his I've got his passport I'm typing
his name exactly from his passport it's
not working like thanks for that we
didn't really need to daeun on Amaya's
him but I guess we did so it was a fun
challenge their experiments was a
challenge that Redford actually
mentioned to me that was a Python or
that was easily solved in Python you
were meant to write an emulator that
would solve a bunch of ellebra
algebraic equations and the
the answer was just a Python eval the
code and thought you could solve these
math problems fairly quickly you would
go through different stages one you know
was 1+1 and it would build up to it like
level 100 but level 99 was a Python
injection attack that if you just ran
this evaluator they'd be running Python
code on your box instead hit cons
perfection was a category of challenges
that actually abused flaws and tools
every one was specifically meant to
break a tool because again there's
always these flaws in tools and they
were able to use it to force you to
either fix the tool write your own tool
or find some other tool to kind of work
around it these are these are super
interesting at CGC we actually had
someone really really test our
infrastructure well by tripping over a
power cord and this is kind of like the
sequence of events that like it just
only happens we're like multiple things
had to fail right so first of all the
ups on the rack kept it damaged during
shipping
we're told oh no that's fine it's no big
deal Vegas power is very reliable
because they make all their money
gambling machines and so the power never
goes out in the casinos I thought okay
well then we're probably okay without a
UPS and then the the the stagehand who
was plugging it in on the infrastructure
I didn't twist down the 220 volt power
connector for this particular rack so it
was unscrewed and could pop out and then
somebody had to trip over the cable so
all of these these failures had to come
to play and and we we had our whole
whole infrastructure for the
visualization scoreboard analysis go
down and right in the middle of the
event and this included the ability to
get data from the air gap because this
air gap robot was picking up CDs and
dropping them on the outside of the air
gap every time there was a round of data
and so I missed a round of data while my
servers were rebooting and we had to go
to our backup plan which involves
someone inside the air gap plugging in a
USB thumb drive throwing it over the air
graph to somebody else who rein it back
into me but thankfully we were able to
recover with that so the moral of that
story is when you're running a CTF you
need several layers of redundancy
because if you have for three of them
will fail right there's always going to
be problems one of the things that I
hope I can convince you to do is to
contribute there's a lot of ways the CTF
community is benefited and so I'm asking
hopefully for volunteer
and people that will help out with some
of these some of these ways I run cap TF
comm which is a website that archives
off challenges because we want to make
sure that we don't lose them these days
CTF SAR better about putting them on
github or saving them in a place where
they can be archived but these are a
fantastic resource for new people to be
able to play old challenges and I would
love your help in gathering challenges
from CTF so I don't know about or I'm
too lazy to say or I didn't didn't play
and if you send them to me there's
contact information on the website that
would be helpful right tools and even if
you write tools and you don't release
them binary ninja was actually a private
CTF tool written a Python for my team
for many years before we rewrote it in
C++ and I've been making into a
commercial product and many other CTF
tools are written and privately but then
when you retire like me then you can
release them and still benefit the whole
community mentor other people there's a
lot of opportunities to help out others
in the community we've all been helped
there's always somebody ahead and
there's always somebody behind so let's
let's work together run a CTF I have a
huge amount of respect for people that
organize CTF it's a lot of work you
should definitely try it you will learn
as much or more than playing finally if
someone could take over golden flags and
actually run that again that would be a
great thing and this was a award
ceremony for sort of highlighting some
of the best challenges best techniques
best solutions in the CTF industry I did
it in 2014 just once
I don't have time to organise this so I
would love if somebody else would would
take that on I'll give you the domain
name and all whatever art and help kind
of promote it finally CTF time is a
fantastic resource but here's a bunch of
ideas of things I'd love to see improved
on it come and chat with me up over over
drinks and what else could be done I
want to give some credits for the photos
from wiki how the slides anybody who
runs the CTF these fine folks who all
gave feedback suggested stories and all
the teammates have played with in
particular I mentioned earlier rusty who
wrote most opponent venture has been
just done a ton of a work for the CTF
community the slides are already live on
that URL including the solution that I
had that broke by the way to my
challenge that nobody nobody sought my
challenge yet I guess isn't
man I may really be broken so I
apologize if so it's working oh they did
solve it okay they did so the flag said
stand up and shout I'm the greatest
hacker alive
oh is that okay yeah you want to do it
let's see what it says now is the server
even still up I mean I gave them root on
my bow on my box all right so now it
says yeah let's see if I can do this
here let's do what the flag says now
there we go yes you're welcome dragon
sector is the best CTF team ever make
sure you come up and get your prize
thank you for salt everyone give them a
round of applause for solving the
challenge and any any questions come up
and if there's no questions make sure
you get a sticker I have a bunch of
stickers up here thanks thanks very much
[Applause]