[Music]
okay so yeah my name is Abram North I'm
also known as pond tester in Twitter and
github and social networks
I work as a principal security
researcher with 45 basically in the
static code analyzer team I don't
consider myself a speaker but I happen
to present that different conference
conferences that I like black hat and
DEF CON and so on and I have a special
interest in remote code execution
vulnerabilities through our web in web
applications so I basically successfully
exploited products and vendors like
Microsoft what I call workday a
Salesforce and so on actually the
Microsoft one one of the Microsoft ones
I'm going to present today so apart from
that I have some experience around
serialization back in 2012 I was looking
different REST API implementation
libraries like Restylane and Andres DC
and I was able to find some remote code
execution vulnerabilities by abuse in
Access dream and XML decoder and then in
2013 I started looking at Java binary
visualization right at that time and to
my knowledge this was the first public
remote restitution gadget available for
Java digitization but unfortunately no
one was paying attention to javadi's
realization at those days so it was not
until 2015 when Gabriel Lawrence
presented the gadget in Apache Commons
collection that people started looking
Java visualization vulnerabilities I
started fixing them and finding them and
so on so that's why I'm saying
unfortunately because we got we could
have saved ourselves a couple of years
by starting looking at that in 2012 at
least so at that time when they released
discard yet I started looking in
judicialization again I was able to find
multiple remote code execution cages was
able to bypass the standard mitigation
technique which is called as look-ahead
object visualization and I was able to
find the cut yet in the Java Runtime
which means that you don't require a
third-party libraries to be present
in the classpath in order to exploit
these vulnerabilities so then I moved to
J so this visualization which I
presented last year at black hat and DEF
CON but most of these is is Java right
so at some point I changed my interest
and I started looking at dotnet and this
is what this talk is about um we're
going to see a brief introduction into
serialization formats and then we will
see what are the most popular and used
dotnet serialize are both by Microsoft
and third-party libraries like JSON
dotnet if we have time we will see some
some demos including this Microsoft
promote Constitution in nature and then
we will move to see how we can detect
find these vulnerabilities and then fix
them so serialization 101 so I don't
know why but in English the Americans I
guess and British people use pickle for
serialization to me pickle is just this
green vegetable but it's actually very
famous like the Python libraries called
pickle this talk up by crisp Rahab was
called Marceline pickles but well to me
it make a great excuse to use a Rick and
Morty drawing see me in my slides and
well this is Rick obviously and if what
you have an instance of Rick that is
living in your VM and at some point you
want to put this this object into a
different representation so you can
store it in the file system for example
or maybe put it into a database or send
it across the network or whatever so you
put it through the magic portal and then
you get pickle Rick right and this is
the sterilization format of Rick at a
later stage you want you may want to
recover this instance of Rick in your VM
so you basically reconstruct the object
based on the information on the
sterilized format so the the thing that
is key for visualization attacks here is
that we are not sending just the pickle
but we are sending also this pickle Rick
right and this is called the type
discriminator the type discriminator is
nothing else that the class name or the
type name that you are sending along
with their data and so if you are
familiar with Java visualization for
examples you are probably
familiar with well this is the binary
format and this is basically the ASCII
representation of the class name and
basically the server is going to use
these class names to actually
instantiate and reconstruct the objects
at the server side so that's Java
serialization in dough in dotnet for
example in JSON dotnet you have
something similar but this is JSON
format right so you have type attribute
here that contains something that looks
like toad net assembly dotnet type name
so if the attackers are able to change
those type discriminators then they will
be able to force an instantiation of an
arbitrary class in during the
initialization process and that will
basically allow the attacker to
instantiate a multi instant instance
instead of the require so there is
nothing really dangerous on getting the
server to instantiate or call the
default constructor for a different or
arbitrary type because the four
constructors are just parameter lists
and they don't do anything paths
normally but normally in order to fully
reconstruct the object there are some
callbacks and some methods that may get
invoke right so for example if you are
familiar with Java visualization you
have the read object and read resolve
callbacks that are invoked in order for
I mean this allow the developers to
fully reconstruct the object so maybe
you need to initiate initialize
something or register the object in a
jndi context or I don't know notify
someone about the initialization or
something like that
so in dotnet we also have this kind of
callbacks we have the visualization
constructor we have some visualization
callbacks like on on visualization for
example and we also have some
annotations that we can use to let the
framework know which method should be
invoke within the visualization process
apart from the binary format normally in
JSON and XML and the setters are also
invoked right so basically we invoke the
default constructor we reconstruct the
object and then we invoke the setters in
order to populate the values to the
different properties of the of the
object so with that we fully reconstruct
the object but there is
some code that is executed so gadgets
gadgets are basically different types
that are sitting in the classpath of the
application that is this aerial icing
you can provide a type name but you
cannot provide a type byte code so these
types are special because if they are
provided with some malicious values they
can lead to arbitrary code execution or
to something bad like removing files or
doing something bad so this is a simple
example that is a gadget a setter gadget
so it starts with I'm poking some
setters it's in dotnet in the class
system windows data object data provider
and I like to use these for explaining
what our gadget is because it's very
simple right so you have three different
setters that when you invoke them with
attacker control data they will
basically initiate a chain of calls that
will end up invoking the invoke method
on instance write this one down here so
basically there we are we are using
reflection to invoke an arbitrary method
on an arbitrary object instance passing
some arbitrary method parameters and
those arbitrary values all come from the
different setters right like the value
that you pass to the setter so this is
an example of a payload for JSON
Dannette basically what we are saying
here is ok we are going to deserialize
an object data provider so the server is
going to instantiate the object that are
provided by calling the default
constructor and then it's going to
invoke the setters for the object
instance the method parameters and the
method name and because we saw that
these setters will eventually call their
reflection code to invoke the method
then we will be able to get a rhetorical
execution if we can provide this piece
of JSON to a vulnerable JSON the net
endpoint so with that I think that's
enough about gadgets I wrote this
application called why so silly adore
net there is a Java version that will
basically generate payloads for you the
Java one is just for binary format sorry
for them Java binary format this one
supports different federalizes
so you have to pass the format there
that you want your data to be your
payload to be serialized so for example
you have to specify what cut you do do
you want to use what format a do you
want to use and what command do you want
to invoke okay so with that let's move
to the dotnet CLI service part basically
this is nothing new
back in the days when I was playing with
the rest endpoints in 2012 at Jane's
four so from the Google project zero was
presenting at blackhat that some
malicious code could be executed as the
result of dotnet visualization so at
that time he found that binary formatter
and net data contract serializer both
could lead to some dangerous execution
but at that point there was no remote
code execution gadgets right so it
happened like in Java the Java
visualization vector it was a very well
known vector since at least 2007 or
something like that but until 2015 when
the Apache Commons collection gardius
remote code execution gadget was
published no one was actually paying
attention and actually started fixing
things so same thing here it was known
that by 94 matter was dangerous but it
was not until last year when a colleague
of mine Alex Miller Alex Mills and James
Forester and myself published three
different gadgets for remote execution
when people started looking at fixing
the dead civilization so we extended the
list by James 4 so by looking at other
side Eliezer's so James already said
that binary format that is realized is
vulnerable in the default configuration
but binary format there is also used by
all therefore matters right so for
example the binary message for matter is
used by the Microsoft message queue the
equivalent to activemq for example in
Java so if you are capable of sending
arbitrary message to a message system
and they will be using binary message
format that is as vulnerable as the
binary formatter one also object the
state formatter that is the one that is
used to sterilize the viewstate
data in the in asp.net it's using an
object state for matter so because of
that we will be able to get arbitrary
code execution in view estates if we
know how to modify the view estate
without breaking the signature that we
will see that later so James already
told no told us about that data
contracts analyzer but also shop for
Mattel using web services fast Jason and
sweet Jason third-party libraries they
are also vulnerable in the default
configuration so this is what I think is
the most popular and use vulnerable
pattern in dotnet that is basically take
some objects and then sterilize them
using Bey binary formatter and then
basics before encoding that I'm putting
that into a cookie right that means that
when the cookie get backs to the server
the application is going to the
satellites that data and there is no H
Mac here there is no nothing that
prevents the attacker to from modifying
that and injecting the payload so I
first find this vulnerability in a site
or a company called app harbor that is
basically like a Roku for donate
applications and if you browse the
application you will find that at some
point we're assigning some cookie with
some values that it starts with a a a a
a D which is the magic number for dotnet
serialization which made them basically
vulnerable so we reported the issue they
fix it and then we found that they even
have a blog post explaining how to do
that in your own applications like you
can use the cookie temp data provider
with binary format there and then make
your application vulnerable in that way
so now this blog post is deleted but I
found that this same advice was
everywhere is like really and tens of
blog post is in India trapping different
lists and also it was used by Microsoft
in an old version of the asp.net MVC
framework so at some point in 2013
probably after the James foresaw talk
they remove this cookie temp data
provided from the asp.net MVC framework
but I think that the damage was already
done many frameworks and many developers
were already using this pattern in their
applications as we will see
so simple example well this is a
vulnerability that I found in Microsoft
Asia Network basically you can expose
your intranet right this box here is
your intranet and then expose your web
applications to the remote workers right
here by using what is known as the
application proxy service and that means
that you will install a connector in
your network and then your employees
will basically access a URL that is
provided by Microsoft and then they will
be ready dicted to the Active Directory
login that will basically set your
credentials in your own Active Directory
and if everything is correct you will be
given a token that you will provide to
the application proxy server and then
you will finally authenticate to the web
application right so I'm pretty sure
that you're familiar with this login
page so basically I don't know if you
can read anything from them so I can I
can't stop it apparently okay
well you can't read anything but this is
the URL provided by Microsoft you can
change it and put your any domain you
want and then I do access your remote
application you are ready ducted to
Microsoft login right you don't actually
have to login into Microsoft and this is
a pre authentication remote code
execution vulnerability what I'm doing
here is basically I'm just deleting the
cookies for this page before sending the
request to burb so I'm going to do that
right now
and basically what I will do is send
this request to the repeater and the
response is basically the resurrection
to the Microsoft login page and then a
cookie there Adam I don't think that you
can read it but it's basically starting
with this magic number again this aad so
I basically just well if we take this
value and we take it to the decoder to
see what is inside of this basic stiff
or blob we will see that there are some
type discriminators and type names so
this is basically using dotnet
serialization specifically it's using
binary formatter so at that time I was I
haven't written the why so she got net
so I used my own gut yet generator at
this point I'm basically what I'm going
to execute is the nslookup to my own DNS
server and basically I'm going to
accelerate the name of the of the
computer name the computer name variable
to verify and to prove Microsoft that I
was executed in that in there servers
are not in the Internet servers so that
takes a while because the VM was very
slow that day if I try that locally I
will get a connection from from my own
servers what you can't read anything but
there is a moon of a that is my own
computer name and now if I copy paste
the payload that is generated and that
you can generate now with white Sociedad
net if you copied out to the request and
send it to the application proxy
remember we are not even authenticating
so this is pre authentication remote
code execution in AC or network we just
copy that
we change to our DNS server and as soon
as we send a request we will see that
it's been executed in the Microsoft
servers so we get like four different
resolutions right there and well you
cannot read it but this is not moon Ave
that is my computer name this is
Microsoft come
and those are Microsoft APM IPS so with
that I will if you send a request again
you get the connection from different
servers which means that these
application proxies are working like in
a load balancer way which means that if
you compromise the application proxies
you can now get access to all the
Internet's that are being proxied by the
server so with that those those were the
four matters that were vulnerable in the
default configuration right like binary
format you should never use that with
untrusted data there are a different set
of four matters that are vulnerable if
you configure them in a special way or
if you let the users provide not just
the data to be this realized by but
something else that is called the
specter type so for example if you use
data contract serializer or XML
serialize this are sterilizers that are
okay to handle and untrusted input and
trusted data but you should never use or
never let the users to control the
expected type so that's exactly what
DotNetNuke that is a content management
system or actually the most popular
content management system in in.net was
actually doing so basically again I
don't know if you can read anything but
there is a cookie that contains this XML
item that comes from an unsigned cookie
that the attacker can control and then
this XML we get the type name extracted
from the XML and then we initialize the
XML serialization a m-- so now the
attacker can control the expected type
and by expected type I mean that for
example they are going they're only
going to work with that expected type
right so for example if you are sending
or expecting a shopping cart you cannot
send an object data provider like the
cat yet that I saw you beforehand you
can only send and deserialize a shopping
cart and then at a different point they
they sterilized the rest of the cookie
and then this CMS was been able to
remote code execution I don't have time
to show you the video but is in the DEF
CON talk if you want to check it and
then there is a different set of
visualizers that are vulnerable
depending on the configuration of the VC
réaliser
so for example JavaScript serialize er
that is the native solution for JSON
serialization in dotnet the one that is
used for example by asp.net you should
never use that with her type resolver if
you initialize this JavaScript
sterilizer with a type resolver that
basically means that it is going to
include the type discriminators the type
information with the json data and then
it's going to process that and that is
going to allow the attackers to control
which types are going to be
reconstructed and then that will lead to
an arbitrary code execution
so that's JavaScript steriliser json
dotnet is the most popular json library
for.net has the same problem in the
default configuration is secure but if
the Velo pairs enable this type name
handling setting and they put anything
older than than the known value so for
example type name handling objects or
out or arrays that means that the type
information will be included in the json
data and that will allow the attackers
to actually get arbitrary code execution
so that's actually what a framework that
is called breeze was actually doing so
breeze is a framework for entity
management database entity management so
that what they do is basically the
expose your database entities through a
REST API right right so for example they
expose a rest endpoint to add a new
record or to delete a record to modify a
record and so on and they do that
automatically
so they have this demo application for
developers to learn about the framework
and well this is a very simple
application that allows you to handle on
manage a different car models so for
example you can change the name of a
model and submit it and it will be
persisted in your database if we send
that to a through burp we can actually
change for example they in the name of
the car model and if you can change that
and send it to repeater you will see or
I don't know if you will see but there
is an empty dictionary in here that is
called say
option and an empty object or an empty
dictionary because this is using JSON
dotnet with the type name handling what
I'm doing here is basically using the
object that I provided gadget that I
showed you at the beginning of the talk
remember the one that was using the
three setters to call any method and I
was basically using that to invoke the
process dot start and invoke the
calculator so you copy/paste these
directly into your request and now if we
go back to the server now we can check
that there is no calculator running as
soon as we send a request it will be dis
a realized the object that I provided
will be instance here that the setters
will be invoked and the calculator will
be executed so that was about a brief
introduction to some of the NC realizers
now how can we find them right how can
we find wearable endpoints so one simple
way is by inspecting the traffic as I
said this is the magic number for binary
formatter and this is probably the most
used one if you search in Solem for it
you will find like five or six hundred
instances is still alive then what I
wrote a very simple plugin for purp that
I released today is very simple it
doesn't I doesn't mean to be very
accurate so it has some false positives
because this magic number can appear in
images for example or it may report a
view state that contains serialize data
but then is assign it so you cannot
change that without a server
realizing but it detects different by a
magic numbers not just a binary for
matter 1 and different encodings not
just by 64 so it's kind of useful to
detect probabilities like the azure one
or any some others you can also use an
active approach like black box approach
sending a payload that if gets the
serialize will make the server to sleep
for some seconds or to initiate a DNS
resolution that you can detect in your
server or you can use is like instrument
your application instrument your VM and
see if some untrusted data reaches some
of the this visualization endpoints if
you have access to the source code like
I did for example for DNA
or for breeze frameworks you can
actually run a static analysis and look
for untrusted data flowing into one of
these things like for example single
data flows are very simple to identify
for binary for matter or for example for
XML serialization twill required one
flowing into the data to be the
serialize and another one flowing into
the expected type so again it's simple
most of the static analysis tools should
support that and now at the third part
of the talk is how to fix vulnerable
endpoints or how to verify if the
vendors are actually applying good fixes
so the first way is to stop using
civilization I mean this seems like
rather stupid but I've found many cases
some of them I cannot disclose yet but
that they are using civilization to
cellulite strings right one case that I
can talk about because it's already
fixed is in the Nancy framework which is
a web application framework and instead
what they have these instances are
cookie for CSR protection but instead of
putting the token directly into the
cookie value they were sterilizing the
string into an object and then basically
for encoding that data into the cookie
which may basically make them vulnerable
to remote code execution
instead of CSR so I don't know also if
you don't really need type
discriminators don't enable them right
so that was the case for example for the
breeze framework that I showed you
once that I reported the issue they it
took them like 12 hours to fix the issue
because they realized that they were not
actually using the type information
right when they wrote the framework for
the first time the clients were meant to
be done F doesn't have clients so they
were exchanging some types and some
dotnet civilization but at some point
they added a JavaScript client and
because of that they stopped using the
type information internet because it was
useless but no one disabled that and
then they leave their different work
vulnerable so this is the way of
protecting Jason dotnet for example like
JSON dotnet sorry like a bridge
framework did basically just explicitly
called
time name handling and them past and
non-value to make sure that the data is
not the type information is not included
in the data so the first approach was to
stop using it the second approach is to
verify that no one is tampering with
your cookies for example so if you do
that always you use H Mac never use
something like md5 or sha-1 with the
secret and the data because that's gonna
able to house extension attacks and this
is the way that for example app Harbor
or AC or fix the issue right they just
included a signature an h-back so they
were able to verify that the client was
not actually verified changing or
tampering with the data so that should
be the case like for example if you
cannot stop using this allocation and
you have to put something into the
client-side because maybe I don't know
for performance reasons or whatever you
have to sign it and make sure that no
one is touching that as I said at the
beginning and that's what Microsoft did
with the asp.net implementation of the
cookie temp data provider in the first
version of the framework it was
vulnerable but then they fix it using
the data protection API and then they
also fix the asp.net view state that we
will see later so it's very simple I
just use the data protector API protect
the bytes and that will basically sign
and encrypt the data using the
web.config encryption on validation keys
so view state is an interesting case at
the beginning like many years ago they
were not signing or encrypting the view
state so the view state is basically a
representation of the state of a given
page so instead of keeping that
server-side they send it to you and then
when you request or send a and their
request back to the server they take
that data and reconstruct the previous
state of the page so as I said they are
using object state for matter with which
is vulnerable to remote code execution
attacks so if you allow the client to
change the view state that will lead to
remote code execution so at some point
they included the option to enable an H
mark and encryption to the view state
because well at that point there were at
that point in time there were no remotes
and gadgets but if you could change the
viewer state you could change the
application logic and lead to different
bugs
so in 4.5.2 they even ignored the enable
view estate max so even if you put that
into false the asp.net is going to
ignore that and it's always going to
encrypt and validate and include the H
Mac for the view state they even back
ported that to 1.1 so if you are not
ignoring the patches you should be
protected so when I was writing this
slide I was curious about how many pad
set servers were in the net in the
network and basically I checked with
southern and out of the 10,000 results
that they gave me 200 were born apples
so this made like a big interesting I
don't know probably Bitcoin miners
botnet anyway so at some point they
improve the cryptographic posture of the
viewstate right because if you are able
to leak the crypto at the encryption and
validation keys you can actually use
that to change the view state and then
it will lead to remote code execution so
Microsoft decided to add some additional
protection by using a key derivation
function and something that they call
the purpose and the purpose is nothing
else that some strings right so I don't
know if you can read it but there is a
primary purpose and some specific
purposes so when you visit a URL and
they generate four different strings and
these four strings will be used to
actually derive a new set of keys so
instead of using the encryption and
validation keys that you have in your
web config file they will derive some
keys that are unique for the specific
URL that you are visiting so for example
if you visit the account register URL
the first purpose is always going to be
the same is just describing the purpose
of the encryption that is going to be
client state meaning that is going to be
used for the view state and that's not
going to change but now the second
string is something that is called a
slash account right this seems like
rather predictable given the URL that
you are visiting
the third one is account underscore
register underscore aspx which again is
rather
predictable and also easy to guess and
the fourth one is this abuse state user
key which contains something that looks
like an arbitrary unique token like
seven seven something but now if you go
and check the cookies for this page that
you are visiting you will see the anti
cross-site request forgery token it's
actually using the same value as the
viewstate so now you have all the
different pieces that you need to derive
the new keys so and get arbitrary code
execution still you need to be able to
leak the encryption and validation key
this is the key point here so the whole
idea of these slides is to remark that
you need to be very careful with not
leaking the keys
how can you lick the keys well if you
have our neck sexy moon ability for
example or maybe if you haven't patched
these very old CVS like 2010 2015 that
allowed users to actually lick the
web.config file from Troy's hand I found
that apparently I haven't seen that
myself but apparently there are some
error pages that can leak the encryption
and validation keys and last but not
least in github you will find hundreds
of keys so if you are lucky enough that
someone is deploying the application
with the very same keys then you may be
lucky and get arbitrary code execution
so the final recommendation here is to
use encryption to you to get a is to
encrypt your web config file at least
some sections of the web config file so
even if you get like an X X availability
in your application the attackers won't
be able to get the encryption
invalidation key and be able to actually
escalate from xxe to remote code
execution so we talked about the stop
using it signing it and then binding it
is the third approach so this is a very
dangerous approach but is well it should
work but you have to be very careful at
implementing it basically the idea is to
constrain which types are going to be
allowed you did indeed during the
serialization right so you can basically
implement a Silurian binder implement
the bind to type method and then you are
provided the assembly type the assembly
name and the
typename so you can check them right
before this type get instantiated and
then decide if you want to continue with
the visualization or just discard it
so if you go and use this way I don't
know if you can read that in red but
never use black lists they are very easy
to bypass I will show you now the bypass
code yet and never use a very broad
white list approach I will show you an
example now so this is an example of a
good security allowed list serialization
binder which basically is implementing
the serialization binder interface and
basically is checking for a specific
strict list of allowed classes and if
you have the classes that are allowed
are not found it's throwing an exception
right you should never return null
because if you're returning null then it
will default to the default binder and
then it will allow the exploit to go on
so once you have your civilization
binder you have to assign it to the
binder property and then DC allies and
trusted data that's the other way of
using a serialization binder so as I
said never use a broad whitelist
approach this is actually save the code
from a Microsoft very popular Microsoft
product I'm in the process of this
closing this vulnerability so I cannot
tell the name of the product but the
code looks very similar to this right
and at some point they are checking if
the type starts with Microsoft dot put
the name of a very popular Microsoft
Word here and if that's the case then
they will allow you to continue with the
serialization because they think or they
trust that they don't have remote code
execution gadgets in their name in their
namespace in in their own classes and
maybe that's true and they don't have
this client this kind of cut yet in
their namespace but what is probably
sure is that they contain bypass gadgets
so what is our bypass cut yet basically
it's a type that initiates and nested
this realization from additional ization
constructor right so you are protecting
the outer visualization and maybe you
are binding that and checking that these
malicious claw
are not used are not digitalized but
then you are allowing the visualization
of this class that it's going to
initiate an inner or nested isseul
ization
which basically won't be using any
binders so it will allow the
visualization of untrusted malicious
remote code execution gadgets so again
in your DC allocation binders never use
or if you are checking for the
protections maybe doing some bug hunting
if you see that they are using is a
signal for from or if you see for
example that they are returning new that
means that this binder can be bypassed
also if they are using reflection in
their binder it's very easy to get at
the OS and us the application so that
was the third approach binding it the
fourth approach is replacing it right so
maybe you don't really need to send all
these type information along with the
data so maybe if the client and the
server can agree that they are going to
exchange I don't know I use her instance
maybe just send in the name the address
the last name and so on it's enough and
you don't have to send that they are
using combed acme dot user or any any
type name so that's the approach that
Google protocol buffers use that's a
good approach if you want to DC lies and
trusted data last but not least JSON and
XML are also secure but as long as you
don't include type information like we
saw for example in JSON Dannette so
that's all I have for you so if you have
any questions
any question someone
thank you for talk um I was wondering
did you try to report all those machine
keys because you can do quite a few
things with those machine keys from
github or did you find any issues in
modern or in popular software so I
haven't reported any of them there are
literally hundreds of them in github and
I guess that for example if these are
open source projects or open source
frameworks that the people that are
going to use those frameworks are going
to change those those keys otherwise if
you know that a specific framework is
using those keys and you can look for it
websites using those frameworks and try
to exploit that but yeah I don't know we
try we probably for the most popular one
we should try to find if they are using
those hard-coded keys and report that
that actually makes a very good CTF task
right so being able to lick the keys
then use the key derivation purposes and
all the stuff so maybe for the next year
okay so no more questions so okay thank
you for being there and thank you for
your talk thank you
[Applause]