[Music]
hello everyone so thank you for hosting
me and for thank you for attending to
the session my name is Garrett Zachary
I'm a security specialist within VMware
occurring EMEA and we're gonna talk
today how we build our lease privilege
security architecture for virtualization
and cloud environment
let's start by statement made by Gartner
this year will be a transformational
year for enterprises from a networking
perspective and this is conclusion
basically from a study that garnered
that on high class and big enterprises
in the market and the reason is mainly
because we start we start facing a new
type of technology a new type of
information system and we are mainly
living in hyper connected word so the
behavior of the users change it the the
way how we build application changes the
way how we consume infrastructure is
changing and mainly the we move it from
the situation where we have data center
hosting applications hosting data to the
data is the the center of the IT where
we consume services in the cloud in
public cloud or manage cloud or in even
in private cloud where companies and
enterprises are restructuring their IT
in order to consume services like in a
cloud way and then we're moving to the
IOT the inclusion of IOT is disrupting
the whole way how the the IT
infrastructure should be built so in
that case we can see here that the
security is mainly the component that
need to transform we need to transform
in order to adjust and keep the pace
with the digital transformation and the
move of the the application and
the data from the data center to outside
so one thing never changes is the the
purpose of security is mainly we need to
to protect our critical application and
critical data in an increasingly
changing world of mobile of cloud of IOT
and also increasingly changing word in
the threat landscape in the way how
application or attack it and this is
mainly based on how the user is
consuming the application and the data
and how enterprises are structuring
their network and compute in order to
deliver these applications so if we take
a look on what we are facing today is
mainly move and move from an attack or a
threat landscape that move it from
targeting infrastructures to more
targeting application and targeting the
data and the recent announcement about
the last attacks and the big
announcement of yeah who are other
companies bring more information about
what are what kind of attacks these
companies are facing so they are
sophisticated they are targeted and they
are more hard to detect so on the other
side that this is a this is not VMware
since this is a study made every years
about the security environment or a
security market and you can see how much
company how much security vendors exist
in only security market and we can
classify them on different type of
security vendors so some of them are
mainly targeting the security of the
infrastructure so going from the user
the the device to the network to the
storage to the application itself
others are more focusing on governance
risk management compliance or it's more
analytic solutions to provide more
visibility insight and correlation
mitigation between different information
we collect and mainly we would like to
provide here more control on the compute
on the data and on the network and all
of that is mainly to preserve what we
call the cyber hygiene the cyber hygiene
is the main focus today for incisal for
a CSO and how to drive their security
strategy and how to secure the
application and the business is to build
mainly these five pillars around their
cyber hygiene strategy these pillars are
mainly the least privileged how to
implement the least privileged and make
sure that every workload or every
application or every user stick with the
privilege that were dedicated to him in
order to do his job no trust zero trust
what we call zero trust model or micro
segmentation is make sure we control and
we we check every exchange every
communication every traffic going from
and to any process or any workloads
encryption make sure if in case of data
leakage that the data is encrypted and
not usable by hackers or by the the the
attacker multi-factor authentication
without compromising user experience so
we enforce the authentication to get
access to service and we make sure that
the Royall identification provide the
right access to the right resources and
then patching so we keep the pace with
the vulnerabilities discovered
vulnerabilities or existing
vulnerabilities in providing patches and
applying patches and workloads and
applications so this is the five pillars
for cyber hygiene
policy or cyber hygiene for enterprises
you can notice the these pillars are not
dependent on the infrastructure are more
related to principle and they are not
tied to physical barrier or perimeter
and as you said in the second slide our
IT is not anymore sitting in specific
physical locations and data now is
flowing from and to the cloud to the
data center and sometimes the security
team itself is responsible for
protecting data that never crossed their
infrastructure so user is in Starbuck
cafe going to a service in the SAS mode
in the cloud and security guys is
responsible for protecting the data
coming from the the application and
going to the user or vice versa
so let's start with the how to drill
down these five pillars on the
infrastructure and how to make it
consistent and integrate it to the
infrastructure itself so from a VMware
perspective we we are intending to
provide what we called intrinsic
security solution in transit because we
need it and to end we need it integrated
to the infrastructure not built on top
of the infrastructure so for users we
have a workspace one that is the the
experience of the users of the end-users
AirWatch to control and manage devices
different type of devices from laptop to
mobile devices tabs and even iot devices
for the network we have the capabilities
security capabilities of nsx network and
security embedded in the virtualization
environment and that expand across
multiple data center and even the cloud
and on the storage side we enforce it
capabilities of encryption on the
storage devices so in storage in
Hardware physical devices
compute side we enforce it by AB defense
and AB defense is doing enforcing the
least privileged principle on the
compute side where it's complementing
the nsx security capabilities that
enforce the control the the traffic and
the network so we talked about least
privilege and this is the the topic of
today so lease privilege and this is the
definition from Jerome's letters from
the MIT it's mainly every program and
every privilege users of the system
should operate using the least amount of
privilege necessary to complete his job
nothing else and if what does it mean if
we compare this the IT infrastructure
through the time so the last time where
application are sitting on the same host
was the time of mainframe so the
mainframe we have every component or
every application is built in a way that
sitting on the mainframe and if you
compare it to real world is like a
company hosted on the same building so
for security of this company it's quite
easy to put a bodyguard in the hole at
the entry of the building and then he's
checking everyone is accessing to the
building our exiting from the building
and make sure that there is no one is no
unknown people are someone who need to
go inside without authorizations moving
forward during the time we saw that
these applications are now distributed
and they are distributed because we need
to build in the application in different
way and that makes absolutely sense when
we talk about DevOps where we talk about
agile business business agility and
agile methodologies and so on the
problem is if we apply the same
principle of the body
on that we put in play in the whole of
the entry of the building now we are in
a situation where this guy is not able
anymore to control everything that goes
to every component of this application
and the problem is we still now this is
how we implemented security so we build
security policy to protect and to
implement the least privileged mechanism
but how we enforce it in the
infrastructure is mainly dependent and
really tied it to a control and
enforcement point position it at the
perimeter specific parameters so we may
compromise compromise of saying all
component having the same trust level
sets together in same zone and we'll
call DMZ and from this dmz if I need to
go another trust level another DMZ I'm
crossing a security device or a security
feature and then what happened here is
it's not a problem of Technology or
security vendor or wherever or
skill-less a lack of skill it's just
because from a network perspective if I
am attacking or targeting the weakness
point in a specific zone
I can freely move laterally and spread
my infection in the same trust zone and
then by using legitimate traffic I can
go from zone to another and then
exfiltrate data and I'm doing
sophisticated attack so it's a mix
between vulnerability architecture and
the way how we implement security on the
compute side we are facing the same
issue so we build application we host
them in workloads it could be a VM it
could be container it could be physical
bare metal server but these VM has an
operating system with process
and once we install a component of
application on this VM or in this
machine we expect that this machine we
have only with what we expect from the
application so if it's a web server is
just delivering web server and
connecting to app the front-end
application server and so on once we get
a compromised machine what happened is
that we compromised the weakest process
or we exploit a vulnerability and then
we go through the operating system to
escalate privilege and then from
escalating privileges we get access to
other process and we initiate different
actions and different tasks that we from
we expect from this VM so back to the
principle of least privilege security
architecture what we need is more for
the lease privilege we need to shrink
the exposure surface or the attack
surface around the app from the network
perspective and from the compute
perspective so that means we need to
close the security controls make them
the closest to the app from the compute
and from the network and then we can
implement the controls that tied with
the application wherever the application
is sitting and by the way that make us
more comfortable to address any new kind
of implementation or or technology if
the enterprise is adopting public cloud
or if it's the enterprise's going for a
private cloud if they are going for
containers if they are going for micro
service development and enter one and
then the idea is to align these control
from the network engine and from the
compute side to what the application is
expected to do
and based on that we can provide more
insight to governance risk management
and compliance and then we have data
control network control and compute
control so the alignment between the
infrastructure and the control could be
done through a unique property for the
cloud and virtualization which is what
we call the hypervisor the hypervisor is
called
what we call the Goldilocks zone why
because we are the closest in the
closest position to the application to
the workloads without being inside the
same trust domain of a compromising or
attacking workloads so we have the same
or closet visibility that an endpoint
control installed inside the host
without having the the the the the fact
that we are not isolated from the attack
surface and we have the same isolation
as a dedicated network device but
without having the negative point as we
don't have we don't we have a lack of
visibility on the application so the
hypervisor is if we compare it to our
solar systems is like the earth is
exactly where we can put controls and we
can make them the closest through the
app without the dependency on the
physical infrastructure so this is how
we do it on the network side so what we
did is if we look at the infrastructure
today we have servers and we have a data
center build with storage compute and
network and then on top of this we build
our virtualization layer so we host the
hypervisor on bare metal server and then
we enrich the hypervisor with network
capabilities
extend the security capabilities inside
the hypervisor and provide these
services on Prem or even more in the
cloud so wherever the the application
will be if it's a a VM hosted on Prem or
inside the data center or it moves from
a data center to another or we move it
even more to public cloud or magic cloud
we provide the same level of protection
across the whole infrastructure so we
create this abstraction layer to make
the application having the same service
level wherever they are and completely
agnostic from the infrastructure so that
make man that make us able to build a
virtual boundary around the application
and tied to control for every component
on the application in case of
compromising another server in the same
domain in the same physical boundary we
can easily stop the lateral movement or
the lateral propagation at the boundary
of the application so completely
agnostic from the physical world and
then we can provide this to all our
security partner to enforce the controls
with advanced security services I layer
seven inspection manual inspection IPS a
next-generation firewall and so on with
that we while implementing these
services the closer to the VM we can
easily adapt the security level even if
a host or a workload get compromised for
the same application so we can react on
that immediately and put it in
quarantine in order to protect the other
component of the application as well
on the compute side we bill the same
principle but from the compute
perspective so if we look to the the
virtual machine and workloads we're
going to see mainly processes and
operating system in case of confirmation
as we said then of one process the the
attack get to the operating system and
spread across different processes the
difference between what we provide in
terms of security solution is instead of
going and try to chase the bad behavior
or the bad signature or the malware to
detect which kind of malware is
attacking my compute we we focus more on
how the application should behave and
how the application should work and any
deviation from this expected behavior is
detected as an abnormal behavior and
rise it as an alarm and then we can take
action on it without being inside the
the compromised environment so how we do
it so we do it by first knowing what we
need to protect which kind of privilege
have every process and every component
in the application so we first need to
know the application we start by
capturing how the application should
behave and how every process in the
application should behave from compute
and network perspective and that leads
to a situation where I need to have 360
degree on every component how interact
with other components in other workloads
so I don't need only to look at my
workload but also need to know how my
process and my component works together
so I need to have the whole view not a
part of it and then once I have this
intended state of behavior
I'm gonna detect any deviation so I
detect the deviation even if it's inside
the compute or something it's outside
the compute and I'm detecting it from
the hypervisor level so I know exactly
what happened inside the the compute
side and take action at the hypervisor
level and then when I detect any
deviation I can build my response and
these response will be mainly to alert
block or take action on the workload
like snapshot or whatever so capturing
the application behavior means for us to
build what we call the intended State so
this is how the application guys think
of the application and think of every
component and how every component should
work with others and then we build what
we call the running state so think about
the application guy build a blueprint
this blueprint will be used by a
different business unit and this
blueprint will be replicated for every
business unit and the data or the the
behavior of the application could be a
little bit different from one business
unit to another like three-tier
application with a web server from an
and data base this is the blueprint and
then when we deliver this to business to
marketing it's going to be using this
way to engineering this way and so on so
we calculate what we call the running
state and from the running State we're
gonna detect any deviation from what we
expect so to go deep in how we bullet we
have this capability to know the
structure of the application because we
integrate with the hypervisor and the
vCenter that managed the the virtual
infrastructure and the cloud
infrastructure and then we can also
integrate with other provisioning tools
these provision tools could be ve
realized automation could be Papa could
be all the DevOps tools that provide to
application guy the ability to automate
deployment of new applications on my
infrastructure and from that point I'm
building what we call the application
scope so application scope I have my
infrastructure I have three four five
ten VMs working together they are
sitting in different paths in the
network I know the name and the
operating system I know which which kind
of network traffic could go from and to
every VM and every process and then by
integrating with the application
automation framework I specifically know
which version for every process and how
this process should work inside the VM
and how this process should communicate
to with other process in other vietze
and from that point I can complete with
what we call the machine learning
because that cover like between 80 and
90% and what the application should
behave that the machine learning
complete the 10 the rest of 10 or 20%
that's what we call the running state
and then we build what we called
manifest manifest is the birth
certificate for every component of the
application wherever they is sitting on
the same workload or different workloads
like micro services and so on we push
this manifest to every hypervisor every
ESXi host wherever the application will
land wherever the workloads will land
they're gonna get these manifest already
provisioned on the hypervisor itself and
then from that point when we start
enforcing the protection we start
detecting any behavior and compare it to
this manifest so as we said we have
these workloads sitting on hosts and
then we have these manifests provisioned
on what we call protected zone which is
mainly the kernel of the heart visor and
every behavior on the work
outside process running calls between
process memory tampering whatever so we
detect it and we send it to the
hypervisor
and we compare it to the manifest if
it's in the manifest as a known behavior
or a known application and then part of
the intended state or running state
that's good if it's a deviation we can
arise these to the management or we can
we're gonna apply the response that have
been configured as response to this
abnormal behavior
so think about anyone who is trying to
hook a process and then make it behaving
differently like issuing SSH connection
to the database this process for example
is not intended to ask you a SSH
communication to the database but from
the same VM I can have other process can
issue SSH to the to the to the database
for management perspective for example
so in this case from a network
perspective I can see only IP addresses
connecting from host a to has B or
workload a to work with B so this
traffic is a load because I have SSH
alone but from the process perspective
this process is not allowed to do SSH so
I'm gonna rise it as an alarm or take an
action on it and what what kind of
action I can take it's mainly manual or
automated actions and it could be
integrated on the hard visor like
snapshotting the vm blocking connection
blocking the outbound connections or in
inbound connection and alarm and I can
integrate with NSX so from the micro
segmentation perspective and then
quarantine the workloads because
something is going wrong with this
application so by building these
lease privilege based on what we know as
a good behavior from the application we
can easily link between two teams that
are working in digital transformation
for the enterprise these two teams are
mainly the security team and the
application team
the main problem today in operations
operating security for the enterprise is
to know how these application are build
the legacy old traditional way how these
teams can was working together it was
mainly to okay I'm developing an
application and bringing it to the
security team now it's your stuff so my
problem is your problem and your problem
is your problem that's the security
issue is not my style
but on the other side I'm the only one
who knows exactly how this application
work so with the solution we provide
here with our defense is linking between
the tools that application guy are using
to develop and deploy applications like
puppet chef v-ray and so on and the
security team that now have the
visibility on the intended set of the
application and then have the ability to
build the controls and the enforce the
security on the the hypervisor and the
cloud environments so it's like having a
security team that knows about potential
threats and what response we have to
build on that and then the application
team that understand the application and
both together are working in order to
build the least privileged and then we
can do that by capturing and embedding
the application knowledge and enabling
collaboration put to transform security
so that's for mainly for the lease
privilege the other component for cyber
hygiene are micros
imitation we talking about with NSX
encryption so we embed the encryption as
well in in the compute side so it's a
part of hypervisor security capabilities
today or even on the storage side and
then we have these capabilities to
provide application control based on AB
defense on the other side on the user
side we talked about the lease privilege
on the user side so we have these three
pillars that we can build to calculate
the security pasture and user pasture in
term of privileged so we validate and
verify continuously the right of the
users the right of the app use it on the
device and the right of the device
itself if there is any deviation so we
can immediately react on that and
exclude the user from the access and
propagate these information to the
application enforcement side on the NSX
side so with these capabilities
integrated to the infrastructure and
that's what we call the intrinsic
security capabilities we can easily
bring these capabilities to partners so
they have more insight and more
visibility on what's happening on the
application side so we can build better
governance better risk management and we
can streamline the compliance as any
deviation will be reported and then we
can build the basis for better cyber
hygiene that cover the three five
pillars we talked about so we try as a
VMware as a company to play a role in a
security market in order to go beyond
the fact that we need to security the
cloud and the mobility but they take
this advantage of cloud and mobility to
seeker applications and users so with
that I'm adding to my presentation any
question yeah
thanks for the presentation so that the
concept of knowing good is not you and I
think we all agree that most people need
to make a lot more effort to measure
good and you're doing this with your
ability to in this in this capture phase
and then measuring it with with app
defense what's your view on integrating
the knowledge which is captured there
into other enterprise tools such as
cmdbs
and enterprise architecture tools things
like ServiceNow our way and how does how
does that knowledge fit in with those
tools yeah so we are in we develop
security capabilities through a defense
or NSX with in mind to have an open
platform and an open solutions so like
we did with the NSX if you are already
used to NSX which is the network and
security layer on the virtualization
environment and we integrate with
multiple partners to enforce the
security with advanced security services
or even more to provide insights to CMDB
solutions or to the GRC solutions we are
doing the same with a defense so we
start collaborating for the first phase
with vendors like a cabin black for
providing insights and collecting
information for off reputation on
process and we are we start working with
other vendors like qr4 for the
integration with CM solutions and this
is the first step but we have already
open API that could be used by our
partner to integrate with AB defense and
consume these services from information
perspective so like feeds to build their
own analytics of of the application or
of the infrastructure or even more we
can get some insight from their side to
build reputations or to build the
protection level that we need and as I
said we already integrate with
provisioning tools so some of them are
also connected to
tools like puppet chef and so on so we
can by using these provisioning tools
collect information about the
application itself like data
classification for example we need to
know which kind of data is running on
these applications so or will be running
on this blueprint so we can consume
these informations to the open LPI okay
thank you you're welcome
other question
okay so thank you very much for the
presentation
[Applause]