all right well I uh well I get my Slayer
set up hope you are obligatory sound
check to make sure that our video guys
can hear me and you can hear me so good
morning ladies and gentlemen I wanted to
push the slide sorter button this is the
filler by the way in case you're missing
that wrong application you can't do
slide presentation and word it doesn't
work hot dog he can be thought so the
first thing I have to tell you is anyway
my talk today is going to security
operations the sin and the security
architecture use case development
process I actually use this in work
every day I'm the director of the
security operations team for slate
consulting were at MSSP based in
Virginia Beach and we actually destroy
soo on our platform as a non negative
tool because the commercial said that we
used us doesn't do it the onion business
this talk was originally put together I
just finished my graduate program with
the same technology instituted this was
like one of my
presentations I've got all the alphabet
soup you could possibly want to go along
with that but as Phil mentioned the blue
team handbook is not on this page
because contributor so I'm going to talk
about building a security operations use
case and making that stand the test of
time so I want to tell you a story of
why I actually thought this was a useful
talk for a professional development
conference group of professionals many
years ago back in 2007 I was working for
a Medicare provider and we bought our
first sim we spent one point four
million dollars one point four million
dollars four years later we could
implemented maybe thirty five custom use
cases and we had maybe thirty data
sources coming in 28 of which were
commercial data sources and we had a
falling out with the vendors and we
replaced it at that time I had 497 pages
of actual use case documentation okay
yes I like to write as you know but I
didn't write for the sake of writing I
wrote because it has a lot of a huge
amount of value if you actually take the
time to write now of what your problem
is what your need is what your
requirement is what kind of tooling and
you need to make it work and what you're
going to do with the output of the
security platform okay I was audited out
my nose being a Medicaid payer provider
we had on average well
audits at a time and when you're in a
this kind of an environment and you're
dealing with federal funds state funds
in general public and you have 5.7 lives
under your under your purview that's
actually how the insurance industry's
measure it they measure it with lives
under their care they don't measure it
any other way
the auditors like to know how you
monitor the environment so we spent a
lot of time with that the specific use
case that I'm going to kind of dig into
and I'm actually going to show you some
content from the next book where this
use case is pretty much fully developed
so you can see what one of these things
looks like for real
there's on account looks like a lot of
they're going to account lifecycle
management
that may sound mundane but it is by far
the most positive topic that we've ever
had when I was working so I don't do
that to tell you this when we replaced
our one point four million dollars in
with a next generation phenomenal
platform really liked it we named our
the guy from Canada and the lady from
Chicago a ream of paper and we said this
is what we want me to do they were
actually incapable in their Esso w of
implementing 33 135 news cases and after
one year because we had such a good set
of use cases we had 130 discrete data
sources reporting into the sim all
generating an appropriate level of alarm
conditions meaning since we had taken
the time to write out what made a
difference for us in monitor McHale
and we could most importantly
emphatically and with passion explain to
every administrator of every one of the
268 information systems that we had 143
of which had their own account
management some of functions why we
needed this it was a whole lot easier
the vendor liked my use case model so
much they now use it internally with all
the clients and I find brand into them
at Gartner conferences still using that
template like oh yeah so that's kind of
nice so when you think about where these
things come from
you've got systems analysis and design
is ITA complex system yes or no yes how
many the information systems do your
does your business depend on I don't
know but I do know this there was a
study done recently probably about three
or four years ago I was actually the
source but the study talked about in the
Fortune 1000 your typical user has 17
account username and passwords to
memorize that's pretty cute how many do
you have and how many of you have bought
invested in and made a personal
commitment to one password or something
like that because if not you're just
going to go now
the same password everywhere we all know
cater to that so as we go through this a
number of books actually influenced this
talk and I do want to call your
attention to a book I've really fond of
it's called page of thing it's a
business book and one of the things and
be paid to think we talk about if
there's a chapter on being a learning
organization so that chapter was
actually kind of influential because it
really helped me to kind of put some of
these thoughts together so they use case
embodies or brings or in a requirement
and I do like this feature of a Mac I
can show you my personal favorite on
this chart is that one of the wheel
chair
but as you look at this yeah this is a
funny picture and yes it is very true my
actual a statistics on how many projects
fail you know and you really have to be
aware that you have to separate the need
from the feature and when you're working
in the business of producing a use case
and providing some instrumentation and
assisting someone and doing and
implementing a technical control that
supports an administrative control which
means you're turning the wrench in the
system so it tells you a lot of
condition because you want to know if
that condition is supporting and
conforming to policy that's what that
sentence actually means you really have
to know what the need is not the feature
the need is what you actually must do so
when we build lose cases and when we
build information systems and when we
design a security process and when we
create a dashboard and when we go to
turn on auditing it in a system and when
we're gonna go do something with the
data every single auditors asked me what
do you do with the alert I never met an
author that didn't ask that question
what we want to do is realize that we
are building little me software things
we are if you look at the India going to
dashboard you may say oh that's cool
cool I'll just look on Randy Franklin's
site and I'll see the account life cycle
events and I'll make a dashboard of that
three weeks later okay it will drive me
nuts because when you really get right
down to it it's not just Windows it's
every other system you have that manages
an account or a privilege
or something like that so requirements
is the name of the game and the use
cases embody or bring forward and
embolden those requirements so I gave
you a couple ideas of here of how
projects fail you can do research on
your own 1.4 million dollars that was I
had five other things to implement I
couldn't implement this in 37 really use
cases later 130 data sources later one
year one vendor $400,000 we had four
people monitoring the sent six five
twelve
okay that's pretty huge when you look at
the fact that you articulated what you
need you understand the mission of the
business you understand the components
of the value chain instrumentation
coming in from the things that make up
the value chain and you can actually
bring them forward into monitoring
consoles before we have this technology
in place we on an average quarter we
were to reimage
you know thirty to forty systems and
have any work for hundreds of hundreds
of hours of downtime because we actually
unlimited better than madre we got down
to a quarter you know
you these things you compare one quarter
for one year to one quarter for the next
year we went from in the 40s we went
down to like five or seven three imaging
systems because we can detect better we
can respond better we have better
instrumentation so that actually
translates to FTE hours saved FTEs out
hours saved relates to who in the
business the wrench turner or the
executive it's not the register
so often these things into being little
mini projects when you're building
something
that system you're building some kind of
really cool thing about you whenever
you're building in your security
platform your NSN platform your sin
what-have-you many moons ago we used to
talk in terms of the Iron Triangle from
a project management perspective that's
changing and approving as things adapt
and get better so our Iron Triangle
today is more looking at the value that
we're receiving the quality and the
constraints as opposed to just the
traditional triangle so this is an
example as you design and you make
decisions when you implement something
when you build an architecture for
something think about how to get to of
something that is valuable in small
incremental steps I personally really
believe the agile software development
process is a great thing today if you
can release a component and you have
nine features and you have nine
capabilities
that's better than releasing and you
could really set it save one month if
you can release that in one month and
those nine things are solid
that's better off than releasing 18
things in three months
because you'll get immediate feedback
people will be able to use the system
and you'll get a chance to
course-correct
so that's an example power industry is
improved use case is defined right our
use case itself from a kind of a formal
sense is you know the actions and steps
that define what somehow someone
interacts with a system we call that
someone an actor they are external they
take data in they provide data to they
receive data back they're not actually
turning the wrench they're kind of your
consumer your input your output things
like that so it's our actor and then our
system is what's actually processing the
data how it's going through its various
components the gentleman who talked
earlier what he mentioned is that he had
bro scripts that actually made decisions
for him and provided data to him but the
actors were the system's connecting that
he never actually got attacked the poor
guy right that we're trying to feed had
systems attacking his environment
those would have been the actors for
security operations again we want to
tune this formal computer science
software architecture concept we want to
tune it to us as security people so we
want to look in that we want to look
about how we're achieving an objective
usually that objective is to find the
bad guy find evil find policy and
procedure violation and find human
mistakes on track corporation guys
anybody here old enough to remember an
EM FM or an RL L five and a quarter inch
drive does anybody want to admit that I
actually threw away the receipt for my
first hard drive about a year ago it was
a thirty megabyte full-height five and a
quarter and it cost five hundred and
eleven dollars in 2000 excuse me in 1988
dollars so it's like and my wife was
like why are you still hung onto that
I'm like you know this beat anyway in in
that in that package you got a blue
diskette from a company called Ontrack
they're still around they've actually
stopped producing that as far as I can
tell their annual state of the nation on
why you lose data because for for like
the past 20 years more than half of the
data loss has caused from human error
people make mistakes they do my favorite
mistake that I caught because we had a
great sim was I'm and probably none of
you have had this story as I tell you
the story we had a gentleman who stood
up a new age 323 server that's some VoIP
telephony thingy
technical term thing he made that up for
you guys in the DMZ for video and voice
conferencing and he had the bright idea
that since he already had an IP address
assignment firewall rules that he should
reuse that
what he did not realize is that his
secure shell port was exposed and you
know since it was a requirement as
because we had built a use case and a
logging policy that if you deployed a
system in production you could not
actually get your address and get it
connected to the network until you'd set
it up to log to our sim because we
actually had that in place within four
hours
we got three hundred eighty three
thousand password guessing attempts and
one success and I went to his office and
I said dude what are you doing I'm
staying up to three twenty three box I
said no you're giving it away to China
it's like no I'm not I said yes you are
you know and and and the evil of that is
the guy didn't know what he made a
mistake okay so these can these fancy
cool capabilities we're talking about
and the idea of actually developing
these things will catch human error and
you know the science tells us that it's
not just the bad guy it's the good
meaning intended person who made a
boo-boo we have another great use case
we had where we had a software
development project that went awry and
since we actually had monitoring for our
file systems came in from a package
called morones to let you know the
number of changes and such
somebody had deployed code in production
but not change the name of the reference
system that was dev that ever happened
anybody okay not as big a laugh as the
last one but you know so he gets rid of
a hundred and seventy two gigabytes of
production data we knew about it within
ten minutes because we came in and the
monitoring program says such and such as
way out of spec for the number of file
system changes they had hey Joey
that's not his name you were way out of
spec yesterday what's going on and then
they figured it out but they you know to
recover the data brought it back but we
had a monitoring control so you know you
have to have a cool complex picture I
chose to have
something easier in the room what's your
business need
what is the security question that must
be answered when you build in these days
if you're not answering the security
question you're not building a security
our particular use case you're doing
something else so there may be some
other use case rules that can apply to
help you you develop your requirement
list and remember we want to articulate
a need which is different than a lot
actually
because if you instrument something and
you can identify the need you can
satisfy that need you can actually say
we got it done you know I'm a big fan of
closure I think it's one of the most
important things in a project how many
of you worked on project and never
gotten a closure oh yeah that's means
there's one honest person in the room
there's a lot of guidance to help you
hear a plethora that's the second
definition looked up the word the first
definition is a second so if you look at
you see their common internet security
controls the CIF top-20 you've got
Australian signals Directorate which I
worked about from Ismail was here the
last ball really interesting so
different standards you got this day 153
which is a program you conform to you by
the pound
it is a 494 page but influence influence
your data stream and your system and
your end capability so when you actually
construct one of these things you need
to follow a template I'll actually show
you one in a few minutes my template
it's about three pages along with all
the text and the things to prompt me
word document big fan of that doesn't
have to be super complex the name the
purpose what are the requirements
right-hand side things that are germane
or that relate to the security
monitoring function so again we're
taking a true
approach and we're applying it to our
knowledge domain we also have something
you need as security people we do want
to try to see if the use case and the
monitoring and how it relates to the
kill chain because if we can understand
at what point we're instrumenting
something in the kill chain and if
you're at the point where you're acting
on objectives in the kill chain that's
kind of like game over they've already
gotten in and they've owned the house
the better off you can push something or
do something earlier in the kill chain
the better off you are so that is
actually a very helpful thing for our
our cathartic thought process these
cases have a place in the library use
cases need to be scoped appropriately
you do not want to build a use case that
says monitor account life cycle that is
an epic failure you want to build an
individual use case that says monitor
changes to elevated groups that's a lot
more achievable a use case that says
monitor accounts not used and created or
not used for five days and they've been
created you want to build a use case
that says monitor for this accounts
being disabled within one hour of the
termination notice that was the second
most audited thing we ever dealt with in
our environment not only did the
auditors want to know how we managed our
accounts and all of our systems they
wanted to see concrete proof where we
knew that accounts had been disabled
correctly and because we could
articulate it and explain it and we had
instrumentation and we had the most
important thing the time of the request
and the time of the action we actually
could build this nice chart and what we
found because we put some thought
process in it it was ninety seven point
two percent of all accounts were
terminated within 83 minutes of the
notice I just did you
two very important parts of a security
conversation a measurable metric we're
taking this concept of monitoring
account management etc and what is our
metric what percentage of success do you
have and what is the duration and is the
duration within the acceptable time
limit so if you can actually derive
derive not drive that during your
requirements analysis process and your
requirement development process and you
know the purpose of the use case that
you're gonna instrument and what you
actually want to get out of it you will
actually solve a problem which gets back
to probably everything that I just you
know that lets me actually be successful
because I can articulate problem build a
monitoring functionality to what that
does for me is that actually gives me a
mechanism by which I can test these
things in my environment design of
experiments is actually pretty huge when
you deal with complex systems the better
off you design and experiment the better
off you can find things we use it all
the time make sure that as you're going
through this process you want to be
smart about what you do specific the
more specific you are the better chance
you actually have of arriving at the
other side and getting it done if you
make it broad in general you kind of go
all over the map determine what the
measurements are I will also tell you
that one of the challenges I faced in
the 25 years that I've been in IT
actually I think it's more than that I
had a birthday last month
it's probably 26 years now is metrics
and who loves metrics is there a metric
fan in the room I got I got two
volunteers I didn't I'm legally blind so
if some of you waved I didn't see that
so you know I got all I saw was two guys
were Fonz how many people in this room
140 so that means 138 are not metric
happy well I'm telling you they take a
little longer right but if we can
actually produce metrics guess what we
actually have measurements for our
security program the better we can
measure ourselves as to how well we are
protecting the business the better we
can articulate to who begins with the
executives with tip about what we're
doing to protect their business the
better off we are and the more funding
we get you're good yeah money I mean
really you know realistic time based I
think these things are self-evident
right so we have a very particular actor
in this in the security architecture
news escape model our actor is the stock
our actor is the person at the other end
of the notification and what they're
going to do with the data we want to be
able to put information in the hands of
the sock so that they can actually do
something with it and provide them with
guidance do you create a ticket do you
reach out you talk to the manager
probably not at what point do you
actually involve a jar a person is
affirmed on if they're feeding at the
termination notice all these various
things they lead to conversations but
ultimately when you build a use case you
want to think about the end consumer of
that use case and along the way figure
out how you're going to instrument them
to do their job effectively we have
components when we build use cases I am
a big fan of actually articulating in a
usage every
of the 37 I mentioned earlier at how
many pages follow 497 because I spent
four years developing them by the way I
didn't just do this overnight actually
names all of the components in the
platform the McAfee Antivirus EPO system
is that IP address so-and-so and user
account so-and-so and this is the table
because when I need to go change it when
someone broke it and when someone at the
other end of my sin platform room I
secure my NSM platform changed something
and they didn't tell me how do I go talk
to them about what they will use a
polite term broke how many of you have
lived that lesson where you build
something in year one somebody changed
it at the beginning of year two and your
stuff doesn't work there's anybody
experience that pain in the room I saw
once like one one courageous soul waving
their hand in the back right but that's
why we take the time to write this stuff
down you know it does make a difference
because you want to know how these
things work you also really want to know
if you're monitoring isn't working where
did it break these things are very
complex you know building these things
in descend platforms and NSM platforms
and all the sensors you need and the
rule sets and and in a disk space you
know everybody anybody ever run out of
disk space that's kind of important to
write also a lot of these platforms tell
us things that are not inherently
obvious it's anybody in the room owned a
Palo Alto next-generation firewall again
one two brave souls now if you're
instrumenting your Palo Alto firewall
and you want to provide that to your sim
or your socket or an SM platform how
many times have you had to explain to
people what the word alert means in a
rule it does not mean the Palo Alto is
giving you an alert
it means the administer firewall admin
hold the ng FW you must
this feature on to write it to out so we
actually get a result
so reference data makes a difference
when you look at use cases for account
lifecycle events you look at the data
process what occurs in what order you
actually draw a picture there are a lot
of moving parts and for the since on
security architecture NSM world it is
well worth that you write out the moving
parts in the draw picture there's
actually a very very nice illustration
on the second insight if you have a look
you should somebody created a nice
architecture diagram and it tells you
where all the stuff flow should be so
very very nice tool for us for account
management account lifecycle management
you actually have to turn on the policy
you actually have to get the windows log
you actually have to go get the data
from windows how many ways can you
actually get data from windows there's
at least five that I can think of right
now you have to send it in you got some
TCP communications you got some latency
you're gonna have to fight with your
windows admins who don't want you to be
pulling data every two minutes they want
you to pull it once a day that does not
meet an objective if you pull security
data from a platform once a day because
what is affected your time to detect and
your time to respond you know that
because as you write out the use case
and you write out the requirement and
you come up with a measurable target and
that gives you as the security
professional the ability to engage with
a particular system administrator on
paper to explain this is why we need
your help to implement this function for
our security programs so we can do
effective monitoring so what does it
look like I've put in a couple of
screenshots in here so we could see what
some of this stuff actually looks like
we actually have auditing turned on you
can actually see this data for every
system you have to make sure that the
system is in fact instrumented you have
to turn on various policies in one
commercial sim platform I just grabbed
this as an example
yeah the name of the rule of a spell
behavior do that some various thresholds
the unique pieces of information they're
looking for in their platform a panel to
bring things to your attention there's
enough information here in an alert
panel or a dashboard something
suspicious happened failure to log on to
a disabled account and it's red it's red
good never it's bad once you have the
basics implemented you can do something
more sophisticated this is a more
sophisticated example where you have and
then is this deleted account created and
deleted right yeah
created and deleted within a very short
amount of time is that suspicious oh
yeah do you want to know about that oh
yeah what kind of you know what happens
with that I don't know for the onion
right we've got all the data it may not
be lock mechanism to get it into the
onion we can actually go get it or
methods by the agent but I you know just
kind of drove me nuts
but it worked and I could get it and
from there you know are you actually
getting data we mentioned earlier you
want to know if your system is working
as part of the tooling for your sock
function or your sim function tell them
look at the dashboard once a day make
sure you're getting data at some volume
so that you know you're monitoring
control works and then you look at it
and you say hey we've got dashboards -
these happen to be for event IDs that
you can't read them I'm sorry there's so
yes you can actually see the account
lifecycle event so you know even here we
can actually go
these types of things based on the
numbers and you know what that looks
like so you can find these things
there's dozens and dozens of other use
cases you can actually create what I
wanted to do was to show you a bit on
what these things actually look like you
know if you're gonna go you're gonna go
talk about these things and build this
stuff out this is in the next book by
the way so this is kind of like a an
author preview this is the the template
a purpose statement a problem statement
I have prompts in here describe the
business objective problem that the use
case will address that's happens to be
in my in my square brackets and then I
have guidance on what you want to do in
actually developing one of these use
cases so as you go and do this in your
environment you take a template you put
prompts in yourself so inner for
yourself so that you actually build this
kind of stuff out correctly and you are
building things and you're being
consistent what are the discrete
objectives I personally in my template I
have the smart acronym I put it in my
template so I can pick the things out
that I want to do and give myself a
self-check
I look at what am I actually going to
communicate to my Security Operations
Center on the other end what's the rule
how do they go look for it what are they
going to do with it that's very
important all of the various component
names if you've ever been in a business
where you've managed a sim platform over
time or an NSF platform over time how
many of you only have like one or two
thing reporting to the platform is that
common no how many of you have more than
25 things reporting to your platform
that's under your care anybody want to
see many many hands up more than a
hundred my personal height was a hundred
and thirty and I you know which is
amazing to me but it was and I think we
did actually see some hands at more than
a hundred for those of you just not
turning around so you've got you know
your kill chain components where does
this actually work so well I'll actually
show you what
but some of this stuff looks like and
you know there's a lot of value in this
deliverable profile section we actually
for every single business document that
i.t produced where I work and we do this
today where I work now we have this
profile name requirement sign-off date
what it relates to what its revision
number is what its effective date is
because when an auditor comes in and
they want to evaluate what you're doing
to manage security or monitor security
on behalf of your organization they're
looking for the idea that you've done
some risk analysis you've done you've
produced an instrumentation or to
support dealing with risk in your
environment and that you have a way of
knowing how these things work we're
actually going through a sock too right
now and they're asking us these types of
questions it's very interesting so I
have an example for you here I realized
of course this is a lot a lot of a lot
of words but what we're saying is we
really want to know elevated access in
Windows has to do with group management
and group membership what's actually
going on so I have my fact that I want
to know the answer to this specific
point we want to be able to achieve
monitoring for 100% of all changes to
elevated groups in our environment
how many elevated in groups are there in
a Windows Active Directory domain by
default do you actually know does anyone
know correct there are 14 which means I
have to find a data owner for up to 14
groups usually it's going to be two or
three data owners because it's the
domain but there in fact are 14 elevated
groups and all those groups provide very
specific rights and profit in the
capability my requirements I have to
make sure that I get a success
notification to a group owner
okay so think about this if you have
grooves that are used in the file system
or an application and those groups grant
elevated rights in a system who is the
person in your business that needs to
know if someone has been granted access
or had access removed from their
application it's the data owner you have
a hundred applications in your
environment how many of you think you
could actually go find - is it easy is
it an easy problem there's not easy
problems in explaining to a potential
data owner that this is part of our
monitoring control program because we've
written a good use case that explains it
and ties it to company policy and then
we know that we're going to be audited
and we can articulate that to someone it
makes that conversation easier so I
actually created a nice little picture
here I don't think I have all 14 groups
I've only got like eleven of them is
there something missing
is there a convention our users who
change these groups known and when you
start decomposing this what you really
get down to is you find lots of things
when you're monitoring account
management you find in this idea that
people will create accounts in their
constituent system or their application
that do not conform to the directory
standard is that a problem yes that is a
problem by actually instrumenting this
use case you will detect that problem
and now what what did you got you have
another thing to solve it's outside the
scope of this use case you have a new
use case you're going to develop you'd
be the secondary use case you we did you
would build is monitor for account
creation and deletion
that is not in the reference directory
we actually did that because we would
import the list of active accounts in
the platform once an hour
very easy Active Directory query there's
about probably if there's more than a
hundred people in this room there's at
least fifty ways of doing it to get the
answer to that question but in the
directory an account activity occurs
check the account activity against the
reference list you have an exception I
mean it's it's a natural outgrowth of
creating one use case you have another
one and you have a lot of the source
material that you need to actually
create this process you also find that
you may have naming convention issues
certain accounts are permitted to and
not permitted to make changes certain
accounts are permitted and not permitted
to be added to elevated groups if you
had a process in your organization where
you separate out users who have elevated
access and you give them a specific
account and you find someone who's
adding accounts that don't conform to
that naming convention to the elevated
access group what have you found a
serious problem
how many of you have ever dealt with
users who have to be in the
administrators group on their local
workstation okay I can tell
instructor cam says lots of faces says
oh my god I can't believe you brought
that up have to be yeah well guess what
we actually did this we had
forty-five unemployment we found 1168
employees who had their accounts in the
administrators group that's 22 percent
guess what I just gave you
begins with metric and then begins with
measurable it also means I can Institute
change which I can track and show value
it also means I can go find out what
that problem caused in appropriate
software installation not conform to
policy and a huge amount of risk my
favorite case was the was the business
director in Georgia I'm sorry she was in
Georgia she generated 83 antivirus
alerts in one minute because she read
soccer mail I don't know what soccer
mail is but she compromised her entire
section because rich she was reading
home email on the company network and
whole office is just kaputski that's a
technical term kaputsky little
multiculturalism for you they're going
on that made this this administrative
account business very nice and monitored
so we could actually do all that and
long story short we got down to less
than six hundred people who had a
secondary account and we got down to a
very very low rate of people who had
their login account in the admin group
but because we actually have these
models and these capabilities and these
ability to pull this data in and do
something with it and tie it to a
program and an audit control in most
importantly we knew why the user needed
this and we gave them a nine page
document with seventeen compensation
mechanisms of how they can get software
to work with their standard account
modify this don't do this and we taught
our service desks but actually made that
problem pretty much almost go away we
ended up with eight tax people and if
your birth interacted with tax people
they're very conservative so we thought
our risk was pretty low ladies and
gentlemen I'd like to thank you for your
time that's my talk on the security
operation
[Music]
[Applause]