hello everybody first of all I apologize
they make these slides so so I'm
actually borrowing somebody else's lives
totally I didn't make these five
specifically for this because Phil
contacted me today okay
since you're coming down do you mind
talking that so I did at one point go to
work for a little company called source
fire and you know for some reason I sort
and so source fire be I started working
with the fiddle at the art store down
here important and first I heard what I
had dealt the army probably because they
couldn't sell any kind of sales but so
they decided I'd hire and so I can't
work at source my arm attitude that was
apply and I've been ever since even
through the acquisition Cisco so the
what I've been able to do since I've
been there as I've worked in
professional this is for about two years
then I worked
to show him their way anybody ever heard
of the afternoon DRT right so I moved up
into BRT about five years later in 2002
arted rocked by the school rules and
then following the acquisition of
Sourcefire in the Cisco we formed a
group called caliphs and I wanted to see
a manager so all the while I've been the
community manager for short and since
during I get over the history to kind of
build up to where I'd be like the latter
at latter end of source fires run before
the acquisition was we were starting to
think about how we wanted to involve
local sources and wonders to start so
sort of I was starting to love story
right
we've kind of been you know marketing of
the marketing intensive store and
branding and storage and the web team
over the websites to them you know this
team of that and then I was a community
editor so we decided when we require so
now
I also run everything clear maybe if you
guys have heard of that I gotta stay
within the camera I paste a lot so how's
the run except maybe project if you've
ever really maybe and some various other
small projects but now that we're
required my Cisco kind of by my job
since I've come on board as they've
actually figured out that we at source
fire do something about open source
because how many throw that and so I've
kind of been charged with doing the same
thing within Cisco was growing Cisco's
open source presents and things like
that so that's a little bit of
background about who I am but the title
of this talk is snort and kind of
history and where we're going so I
figured so when I joined source fire
back in 2005 my first weekend work was
that like suppose the last night explore
the conference or otherwise I'd like to
say that you know I shut down but maybe
the work don't know
so last Linux roller coaster was and you
know we went there and is my first day
at work I didn't know what to expect you
know I'm here at a story booth and I
know a little bit about story I don't
work for the company but you know I know
I can figure this that nothing but
but somehow I wound up my first week
weren't being in the San Francisco
California at the Moscone Center at
Lenox world so and I'm sitting there and
those of you have never heard of Martin
rash she was the founder of source fire
and we started the story I was like a
total family it's like meeting Steve
Jobs sitting there at Starbucks right
and I see him walking across the that
you do every minute it was just a garden
it was just funny because they're like
you know we're sitting there and we go
[Music]
looking over a shorter you sit there
owns macbook cranked it away that's 2005
so so that's where I first saw story
thank God was asking questions unless
you know the story you know what's what
do you want to do whatever want to
change things like that we're going to
make it multi-threaded one we could
learn before we want to be able to you
know farm things are most different
boxes we want to have a configuration
that we don't have to change we can
change the real time not the stop sort
and restart i wanna do something right
you want to insert a new rule we want to
shut it down and restart it does not
where she goes we fix it well how do you
do the configuration let's all ooh all
right
so you know it's kind of beginning the
origin story of star three and then
several years later probably two or
three years later we got to the point
where it was code stable and we wanted
to start performance testing and so we
started a performer's testing it and we
actually found out it was slower than
regular short because the way that
you're doing right you know that's where
we kind of came across the perception of
the misconception that multi-core is not
necessarily faster just because you say
well forward so we kind of came across
that perception when we proved it over
and over again rolling okay well how do
we do this with the vision of you know
processors aren't giving any faster
Pentium went to a certain point that
maybe never even animated ship smaller
sequel or chips you know says you know
put more chips on one guy and things
like that so it was more about being
able to utilize all those processes at
one time and so what we found out is
when you're analyzing the single thread
you want to packet processing and packet
processing across the single thread if
you have to exit a core to go to their
four different core or if you have to go
you know I don't like more into a
different cloth frontside bus or god
forbid you should go in between two
processes right that process was
incredibly insane and then somebody had
already it was like oh let's let's
borrow things out to the GPU does that
mean no that's even longer and we do the
motherboard like what are you thinking
so we're talking about like real time we
have to do stuff in some microsecond
right
so the ipsi has to be operate in real
time so after the performance tested was
actually and the same time for sortie
fires in republic we decided to write
you know we came out with our day we
came out we're gonna make it next
generation firewall we acquired immune
ette right so there's like all these
things that kind of compounded well
about five six years ago it was well
after certain time came out and as well
after there was something else that came
out around that same time but as well
after all these things came out and we
decided we we didn't hit we were with
our with a source fire harvest before
were Department Cisco searched fire
higher apart where we were hitting a
theoretical limit and it was around a
hundred eighty gauges there right and
while that seems like incredibly fast
when you're talking about selling into
the service provider market you know you
have to be able to go much much faster
than that so you know we were we were
and that we
we knew that we needed to prepare for
the future so there was a meeting
between you know the BP Development
Director development myself we said well
never start three we need to start all
over again start from scratch we write
everything that you thought of and do it
right the first time using all the
knowledge that we've learned over the
years so that's what we did as we sat
down we completely rewrote it there's
actually no copy code anything in that
in the new story there's notice or -
there's no - or three but we brought all
that code over or we didn't we started
running again we carved off like two or
three people from where the available
organization which by the way at the
time was only six people this is a true
story
so aspire to develop an organization
that worked on the IPS before we
requirement Cisco was six people so we
carve off like three of those six we're
like look you know these three are going
to maintain the storm 2x country these
are going to work on the future and so
now that were required by Cisco we were
somewhat ear add all that to say the
reasons that we wanted to build North
right speed obviously initiative right
you have to you have to get beyond the
limits of where we're at we wanted to
preserve memory because in order for you
to multi core store you have to run of
the essence of store whenever the core
anybody who's ever done this but it's a
pain in the butt to configure and keep
up running right so you have to have
separate store that call for each
district or you have to have a separate
set of rules for each board you want to
do it correctly right so that is better
it's all brands you know preserve that
so we wanted to have one start that
company one copy we wanted to make and
we kind of sat in bringing store when we
came up with you know 30 ideas what we
wanted to do one of the primary undies
we wanted to do is hey hey we're
rewriting the whole thing from scratch
anyway let's rewrite the rule language
over here
everyone does separate store rules right
we're running out of that but we knew we
could make things so that's what so much
slides are about so a little back story
about the I can drove from the airport
to here I've been up since 4 o'clock
this morning so let's let's try this
let's see if this works
oh my god I love it when it works the
first time store 3 is an alpha 4 we're
going to go this year
okay my I have dictated the requirement
for store 3 go beta and we have a store
3 compelled rule set it doesn't make any
sense to give you an engine that you
can't use the rule set right it's good
to be miss so I said so we released the
we released a stork 3 compatible
community rule set and those of you that
are familiar with the rules our to
convert we convert them down from start
to to start 3 there's also a tool within
the store 3 tarball that allows you to
convert we have to convert 40,000 rolls
right so it's exhausting and we have to
make sure that come Adam we don't want
to give you anything that's not
compatible right so one of the things
that we sat down we thought about like
hey when we rewrite the rules so let's
make it simpler for us to do our jobs
while we're at it this is the way a roll
looks like today which is an HP uri
you've got something malicious that's
within 20 with it also within the HTTP
URI what is the redundant thing that you
see here
the word content so we distort three we
started rolling out this concept of what
we call sticky buffers so those of you
because I still don't think that's well
enough explain to the world about what
violated us we decided to make all
buffer sticky instead of select ones you
know and the reason that the the way
that you're able to tell sticky buffers
different from non sticky buffers is the
sticky buffer generally come before a
match or a section within the world
right so file data and then you do all
your content matches or sip sip header
right and you can write all your content
matches after that you know everything
takes place within the set better so we
decided to kind of fix this and the way
that we did this is is basically this
you write HTTP URI one time okay so
makes things a lot lot simpler to write
and then there's there's obviously
there's ways to you know once you're in
a buffer how to get back out of the
buffer there's ways to do that but the
way the reason we did was make hopefully
make your life simpler and is there a
learning curve I don't think so then
again I do this for a living but we
started to do this internally in
experiments and and it's working pretty
well another thing we wanted to do so is
we we still I think was old sin
but in snorkels today if you go into
metadata and you type service HTTP if
you have a network map defined in the
story it will you know the auto census
dozen the doesn't the product it doesn't
do it no cool story then we'll all go
figure out what port is HTTP and we'll
apply those rules to that port right so
we kind of wanted to bring that logic
from the product land over into open
source land same sericata did and do the
same thing so we have alert HTTP and we
did this for a ton of different
protocols as well you know alert HTTP
alert FTP it operates basically the same
if it figures out what store it is it
applies the rules to that nothing
nothing too terribly difficult there but
we went a step further so we don't we
decided we're like hey do we need the
kind of sat down we asked ourselves hard
questions like do we need that what does
that do for us right other than indicate
direction right what does it do and do
we need it so that's one of the things
we actually it's optional you can write
it if you want but you don't have to
write it anymore so now you can just
write a rule that looks like that a
little bit more so keep breaking this
rule down a little bit right you got
you're looking for this is the way that
you would generally look for a rule or
something malicious and this is the way
that you would look for something
malicious within the user agent field
well we also have something that we
wanted to make other than sticky buffers
is what we call dynamic buffers and
these are buffers that are set at read
time when the packets coming across we
make it we make the buffer up
he's a crate on demand Wow I love this
Batman this is great
simplified met these are not my slides
simplifies many HTTP rules so what we
did pay attention because I'm gonna you
know click is this section right here
you see HTTP header right there's your
sticky buffer so we know the age of the
rest of that stuff has to take place
within the HTTP header buffer we don't
need this so let's just do this is the
packets coming across there's a rule so
this is this is that same rule
it's just simplified and now I have a
unicorn
this is the greatest M&A of presenting
other people's life this is where we
actually really want to concentrate on
most attacks nowadays our
file-based right and when we kind of sat
down we asked ourselves you know today
like I said you know if you ever went to
the store whole set you know that
anytime a file is transferred across the
network we generally have to write two
rules one for inbound and one for
outbound what so why why did we need to
do that so let's just regardless of
protocol even if it's encoded you know
if it's inside of a stream if it's
inside of an FTP stream and I have a
download HTTP if it's attached to an
email doesn't matter why should we have
to think about how to do this as we can
where this is code and I'll be just
typing right we don't need to maintain
multiple roles we don't need to create a
modifier rules
so here is a current role okay you've
got sets the buffer of saying hey filed
imports as a variable that included as
FTP and includes pop out one for coming
inbound one for going outbound things I
want you to pay attention to we don't
need the two client we don't need the to
serve these is all redundant stuff let's
get rid of it
say Alert file we don't need flow
because we all care which direction it's
going just to learn on the file and we
don't need to a whole second rule that's
what a new rule looks like and we can
even get an even more specific and say
file type we have a keyword called file
hundreds more type you can say file type
CD yeah blah right so the only examines
PDFs instead of all we can even get even
really technical if we wanted to we can
actually give it a specific version file
version 6 so when it opens up a PDF and
it says PDF is one point six you guys
have ever looked at inside of a PDF the
versions right in the first several
bites right we only have to look at PDFs
that are version 1.6 will you do that
for browsers we can do it for a lot of
different things so things again simpler
Paul's triplet great the I I don't know
if any of this is converted over to the
New START three version will also
convert your existing rules see you
mainly retype all of them and just take
a file went up through the converter and
spit out start three rolls there is a
there's there's a ton of new buffers
there's a ton new language there's a ton
of protocols there's like I said if you
could if we could we sat down with Marty
and one of the questions that we asked
him was like if you had to write snort
all over again from scratch how would
you do it
and so it's actually not even so I mean
what we need is y'all we need testers
okay there's a bunch of them which is
pretty good for an alpha I think there's
about downloads about thousand downloads
to start three a week but we need people
to grab it music configure it use the
rule set and tell us what we've also
something different that we did again
you can blame this guy is all of our
development is open which is if you
history gonna start to you know that all
of our code repository first or two is
actually inside of Cisco it's not a
little public again or anything smart
three is the opposite it's completely
open it doesn't have any weird licensing
restrictions around it it's GPL v2 the
same as story but if you guys remember
the original start 3 came out there was
a whole bunch of drama or kerfuffle
around there was we we had added a
digital licensing to the
which basically said if you can use sort
for free but if you're going to use
snort and you're going to charge for it
you need to you know give us so now it's
just basic gplv2 why did we not go gplv3
there's a whole bunch of really good
reasons but you go down the hall and you
talk to some of our open source lawyers
and they really don't like gplv3 it's
like the Richard Stallman system as a
whole they don't allow anything it's
just going to be licensed gplv3 so again
legal issues um try think where I would
go from here I mean it's you know we
want you to use it we want you to we
want you to download it we want you to
use it we want you to you know check it
out give it a give it a go it'll wreck
it it's supposed to I'm pretty sure but
it's supposed to figure out how they on
the box right it's supposed to be smart
like that like so it give you a for
instance anybody that's ever configured
like your memory settings and sort of
your been cat all of that nonsense you
don't have to do any network it figures
it all out for you based upon the size
of the box that it's wrong you know
other than that you know I can talk
about snoring all day but
Oh what questions can I answer for you
guys
sir you mentioned in the first version
there are three performances terrible
I'm sorry I repeat the question
then he said they quit the first word is
ghost or three because the way we were
multi-threading at the time the
performance was terrible and he said how
is this version it's much better I don't
have numbers like a new studio we have
engineering testing but I don't really
see good job suffice to say so I
wouldn't be 110% when we purposely do
not look assert ours we don't prepare it
we don't look at their code we don't
look at any other configurations
anything like that the only reason that
we use in alert HTTP is because a lot of
our developers and this would be a smart
way of doing it and I said hey I think
that's sort of but we have a standing
policy within sort within Cisco is that
we do not look at Cercado because we do
not want to accuse of copying we do not
want to be accused of in with that right
so we don't know anybody constantly when
you copy that
it's the same question he is this is the
we're doing very well the numbers are
very very good they are way past what we
expected so we basically internalize how
sort to does it today okay so how start
to doesn't say is that you have to have
something that's a front of start to
like the up ring the divine flows out
across the multi course right okay so
you have a flow that's performed so we
just did that on steroids right it's
basically you start snoring off it takes
the traffic coming in and it divides it
itself so it's and it keeps the flow is
pin for a poor right and that's how it
analyzes so that you're never swapping
in between cores because that's where
you lose that's where you lose so if you
have a beefy box nice amount of RAM it
actually takes less than when you start
to does but it has a nice amount of RAM
and you have you can just throw them
processors with the problem because
processors do large-scale things are
relatively cheap right you could have a
hundred cord die it's about that big
right
I mean cisco makes its own processors
and they're pretty good you all you have
one back here sir you don't ask
questions anyway
yes question was you guys do better
documentation could your documentation
suspect so good news is the
documentation that's built into the
engine so anytime we update the engine
when we write the engine we have the
right documentation again engine
actually generates the documentation
itself so it's only today again we
wanted to eliminate it we wanted to
eliminate pain points right store cops
our pain point documentation czar paying
place rules their pain points we wanted
to eliminate pain points so there's
actually a command in surgery where you
own the command line that will dump out
the documentation for anything and you
can specify what part of documentation
you want it'll generate HTML it has all
kinds of really nifty thing
the phrase you jump into the sea drive
normal languages you saw right it's
basic it's text it's English its unless
think it's fairly intuitive but again I
do this for a living so I mean I'm
biased but this is a white glove and I
give a lot of talks about different
things and stored and opals were some
things like that look one of the
feedbacks that I hear is well the storm
rule language is very confusing and it's
funny because like we it's not the
intention we try to make it simple but
you know but the 80-degree fantastic
there there are storm / wedding classes
that you can take if you don't want to
do that there's plenty of tutorials
online we have plenty of blog posts will
start to the work and but yeah I mean
you don't need to go take a class I
certainly have never taken a class but
again I've been doing this for 12 years
- so 15 but yeah you don't need that so
quick pull on the road for those of you
that are in so close before nice almost
our tools
- and then you stole store three is that
better so there's he it's not compatible
with the current unified - so I don't
know who's intelligent decision that was
but now that you reminded me I'll go fix
it no there's no doubt put unified there
because it's kind of a standardized
format we had dumping tools and we'll
dump it out and you can dump it out of
JSON you can dump down whatever it's
just the reason that we didn't even find
- is cuz this buyer is very small it's
storage is the is the key that that's
the reason that unified - is structured
the way it is because of storage so we
can store lots of it right you know if
you want to store it and offload it to
separate desks you can always come back
to it later and dump it out and whatever
format you want because it's a
standardized format right yes I'm sorry
yeah you can dump out unified - into
JSON but no it's not natively in JSON a
second thing is that requirement do you
guys want that yes JSON out
so if I understood you correctly earlier
you mentioned that there's an organic
capability within snore 3 where where I
don't need something like gif brains
awesome will that capability allow me to
also output other tools
so if I wanted to run that those blows
across like I would today right would be
Africa right on the same box I don't
know the answer your question
it'll be honestly I don't know I'll find
out you didn't give me your email
I'll shoot you an email where you shoot
me an email yeah thanks
no problem I'll find that word and back
your question is international teaching
all right
so how many people have ever written a
threshold on the rule and to get the
alertness or some something since hey
this is being deprecated right obviously
it's being deprecated rule 8 on it
totally thinking over ten years so it's
cool you know we received we were going
to remove it honestly and the reason
that you're going to remove it is
because we split dress holding with two
pieces right is rate limiting and you
know because basically threshold was a
keyword that that operated on not making
rules alert as much right and so we
thought that there was two parcels
there's front there's this front of it
there's the back of it there's prevent
rules from a learning until something
happens right until it's seen it seen
the same thing 10 times right and then
there's now that it's happened how many
times do you allow the alert to happen
over a period of time so it's two
separate things which is why we kind of
made a decision accidentally saying
threshold was now two different things
it's rate luminance so we separated
those out and we just we never we never
remove the keyword probably because we
received a lot of negative feedback
about it to be quite honest with you I
will tell you well I will tell you one
thing if you guys are happy with
something in store it if you guys are
unhappy with something in storage
unhappy with something that where you
think we're
changing direction about if you have
questions the store users mailing list
is the best place to do this
so our developers settle there I sit on
there I can I have the direct channel
right into that development pipeline I
can go over to the next you know not the
next bit used to be the next building
down Sephora walk up to the next floor
and I can say hey people don't like this
don't do it and then they ignore me but
no it's it's no I be I take that
feedback to development meetings and we
take that all that stuff into account
and we say hey you know if there's a
good reason we're picking something out
there's no reason to change that
changing something we're gonna do a much
better job mission for 2018 that's kind
of communicate better to the community
because I feel like for a while we've
kind of kept everybody in the dark but
again we just we spoke the functional
threshold when the two different things
so the functionality is there it's just
different keywords sir
FLOTUS thank you
so yes polar bears are very integral to
how we work we are hoping the the large
majority of the way that we being
callous right fools we write it was the
way that we use flow bits is to pin one
side of a flow to a separate side of the
flow right you asked for this
I'm returning this so I saw them this
question was asked and here's the answer
coming back to a server right that's how
we generally use four bits we try really
hard not to use flow bits because it's a
it's a configuration because if you
don't have all this rules all but that
rules down or decimals are but that
one's not set if not check checked it
off set you guys have seen these
warnings I'm sure right that's
complicated and we wanted to stop doing
that so that's one of the reasons that
we rewrote the rule language like we did
right if you look at the learner file we
don't have to set up a little bit that
we saw an extension on the rule or a
back of the file magical more and then
check that final match later to see if
that files coming in about we just say
alert file matter right so we're trying
to eliminate the use of little bits as
much as we can but the functionalities
do it yeah we just don't want it's
another step that you have to do as a
rule liner to look for bad things like
we need to get the engine out of the way
and make it easier for you to do your
job
yeah yeah like for instance you say look
fire you don't need to say flow to
server establish right so the current
rule if you guys are gonna look at the
file eight years ago writing that entire
category which was basically look for
the extension of those files and so our
our rule writers don't have a
requirement that if we are going to
write detection than inside of a file
it requires six rules to do this four
rules are just the tracking of the fire
two are now looking for the
maliciousness e during the round out as
we look to the final attachment an email
outbound we look for a file attachment
email web have to be inbound we look for
lose the other thing something else it's
only different protocol I can't remember
because then we write a rule for the
magic of the room so if somebody changes
the file extension trying bypass you
will still get the file medic and then
there's two orbitals that you know check
the presence of if that fluid is set
it's a management nightmare for us
because then we have to write six rules
from one of our ability this we can only
six of one seems also half a lot of time
and it's smart and it's staple and it's
you know
yeah
[Laughter]
[Applause]
I'm joking and they know I'm joking but
it's we know we know it's in shape
unfortunately I'm kind of like in
between a rock and a hard place and do I
go back and fix the snort tools manual
or to manual or do I focus on the future
and and I keep telling our guys they're
like oh we run we released or three and
no we're deprecated - and with a three
is the future and three is doing
fantastic I'm like if you released or
three today we would support snort - for
the next five years there's absolutely
no way we can drop support like that
well yeah we can't we know unfortunately
my attempts to go over to that building
my attempts go over to go upstairs and
kick them in the teeth have not worked
because I'm like oh well you know you
know we'll get to the main of ramp when
we write these functions and so I'm
actually kind of I've done this I'm
doing this for clarity right now because
clearly these like endeavor of is you
think this start to use think store
community's bad you should committed
clamavi world because this Clementi
world's way worse so I just hired a guy
into my team and I've made him I'm
basically to make him the community
manager for Clementi and fix that so I
want to do the same thing for stores I
want to basically hiring three manager
just for short and one fourth I made me
and oh man
a lot of time to do wings but somebody's
gotta do it
yeah anymore
if not I'm gonna have to go you know we
we designs two or three to take
advantage of hardware accelerator cards
you know from I mean there's lots of
hardware accelerator cards are out there
we need to design three take advantage
of those we use them in our product some
we want to make sure that we you know
code for ourselves as well but no we
don't have any published recommendations
yet
I imagine that something we'll get to
when we get more into like a solid 30
stage but I think we're a little still
too early to start again it's an alpha
right we need we need to get the beta my
my my hurdles beta once we get there
I'll feel better anyway I'm gonna be
around for a little bit
and then I have to run and go record a
podcast that'll be back so I got
everybody check into my hotel record a
podcast come back but I'm around yeah
good talk
[Applause]