oh oh very much I do want to say yes
again thank you thank you thank you to
everybody who made today a success thank
you again to Phil for arranging all of
the nitty gritty details of today he's
done an excellent job so give it up for
Phil also our sponsors I do want to make
sure to recognize our sponsors again
Augusta University for providing this
amazing facility Leo cybersecurity for
sponsoring lunch Proofpoint rural
Technology Fund know starts press dual
comm and mid bit please make sure that
if you are on the Twitter's that you
tweet out to the sponsors and say thank
you because without them today would not
have been a success so thank you again
to our sponsors have you had a good time
today
have you learned something new excellent
alright so one thing before we get
started mr. Chris Sanders could I ask
you to come up front yes right now so as
many of you are well aware Chris started
this little thing called the rural
Technology Fund which donates equipment
to classrooms and this is something
that's very near and dear to my heart
because I grew up on a little mini dirt
road my address was a rural route I
didn't have a real
some folks do so we are very
appreciative of everything that you do
during and with the rural tech fund and
we want to recognize you for that so on
behalf of secure dating solutions and
the entire security and community we
would like to present this check for
$3,000
[Applause]
okay so are you ready here we go
so we've heard a lot of great stuff
today and some of that great stuff came
from Chris's talk and he talked a lot
about pivoting we're gonna continue to
talk about pivoting but we're going to
right now pivot into the elastic stack a
lot of folks know this as ELQ and when
we did our very first technology preview
of the elastic stack of elasticsearch
logstash and Cabana back in February ish
I very quickly was reached out to by the
marketing manager of elastic Co saying
if you wouldn't mind please use the term
elastic stack instead of ELQ
so from here on out you'll hear me use
the term elastic stack so you see this
picture here release early and release
often this is a this is a strategy that
we are firm believers in and you see
this throughout the entire lifecycle of
security onion and you certainly see
this throughout this last few months of
this elastic stack integration we
started off back in this was in March
March the 16th we released the very
first technology preview of the elastic
stack on security onion very basic very
simple integration just to show folks
hey this is where we're heading
we'd love to get your feedback release
early release often incorporating that
feedback being agile and trying to make
sure that we're meeting the needs and
desires of the community our second
technology preview was released June the
second see bite remember the big change
in technology preview - ok well we had
elasticsearch in the first technology
preview the second technology preview is
when we switched to docker so the very
first technology preview we use kind of
these standard Ubuntu packages for the
elastic stack in technology preview 2 we
moved to
her images now there's a very important
reason for this and that was that with
those kind of standard abouttwo packages
we were really kind of limited to the
elastic stack version two because that
was what we could run using open JDK
seven which is what we have on a boot to
1404 now the current version of the
elastic stack is version five but that
requires open JDK eight so therefore in
order to run the stack on a boot to 1404
we integrated using docker images and
we'll talk more about that in just a few
minutes technology preview 3 came out
July 28 and it had some some nice
improvements there not a whole lot of
earth-shattering stuff from technology
preview 2 but that's kind of a brief
history of where we've been this year
and what we've been up to as far as
integrating the elastic stack into
security onion a couple of metrics here
this has been over seven months of work
we really kind of started in February
thousands of hours put into this project
and over 700 github commits we've been
working quite feverishly trying to get
this done as quickly as possible and you
know this is one of those things where I
knew at the beginning once I made the
decision that we were going to go with
the elastic stack it was going to be a
lot of work I wasn't quite sure how much
work it was going to be and I wasn't
sure that it was going to be this much
work but it's a lot of work I do want to
say thank you because we are very
appreciative first of all for the fine
folks at elastic Co for releasing the
entire OpenStack is free and open source
software so that we can take advantage
of it I want to make a special thank you
to Justin Henderson so for those of you
who don't know Justin Henderson at one
time ran the world's largest security
onion deployment anybody want to guess
how many sensors he had it's on its way
to 800 it's currently over 600 possibly
over 700 with hopes of getting to 800 so
world's largest security on the
unemployment and years ago he started
moving
to the elastic stack and based on that
he started kind of building his own log
stash configurations and kind of
releasing those on his github repo and
that has been kind of the basis of our
elastic integration that we've been
working on so huge thanks to Justin for
the work that he did there he also built
some of our docker images which we'll
talk about in just a minute
one of those dr. images is based on a
couple of Python scripts by my good
friend Mark Baggett marker you're still
here did Mark mark left see I was going
to give him a shout-out and he runs out
on me what's up with that
so mark Baggett wrote some Python
scripts freq server dot Pi and domain
stats dot pi we'll talk about more about
those in a minute but those are gonna be
gonna give us some amazing hunting
capabilities so I'm very excited to demo
those for you
Wes Lambert who is now an official
employee of security onion solutions as
of a few months ago he has been doing
some yes he's back there waving he's
been doing some amazing work on our
visualizations and dashboards so I'd say
about 99.9% of the visualizations and
dashboards that you see is blood sweat
and tears from West Lambert he's been
working tirelessly on that if phil
planner mira so phil has given crazy
amounts of feedback and so when we first
started talking about this way back in
late last year leading into january and
starting into february we had a lot of
discussions Phil and I did about okay if
we're gonna do this we got to do it
right and we want to make sure that
we're doing this by analysts for
analysts and we're not just building
dashboards just for the sake of building
dashboards it's got to be real it's got
to be actionable and you've got to be
able to find bad guys with it so I do
want to thank Phil for all of his
feedback there and everybody else in our
entire community who has played with
technology previous one through three
and has provided feedback we certainly
take that feedback very seriously and we
try to incorporate that as much as
possible so let's talk a little bit
about some goals I said that Phil and I
had a lot of discussions about what do
we want this thing to look like what
does it have to do you know Don this
morning talked about
goals and needs and features and how do
you differentiate those things and how
do you make sure that you've defined
your use cases and that you're
satisfying those use cases so a couple
of goals that we had number one require
no prior knowledge of elastic right
because we have a lot of folks that have
been using elsif for a long long time
and we want to try to make that
migration from else' to elastic as easy
as possible and kind of abstract away
all of the nuts and bolts so that you
don't have to be an expert in logstash
configurations just to be able to get
this thing up and running but at the
same time we want to make sure that the
hood of the car is not welded shut we
want you to be able to change your own
oil and change your own spark plugs so
we want to make sure that we're exposing
all of those knobs for tweaking and
tuning to making sure that experienced
users can customize the system to
whatever extent they want to so Chris
talked about pivoting quite a bit so I
told you we were gonna talk some more
about that
so integrations are very important to us
we're very much focused on making sure
that folks can start in Segel and pivot
over to Cabana to say hey I've got an
idea lurk here and I want to pivot and
cast a wider net into Kabana
and say hey show me all of my bro logs
show me all of my sis logs show me all
of my sis Mon logs for this particular
IP address so pivoting whether that's
seagull or squeal or squirt or whatever
the case may be
and then once you're in Cabana as your
web interface for slicing and dicing
your elasticsearch logs we want to be
able to obviously pivot to full packet
capture when the time comes to be able
to do that dashboards I've seen a lot of
folks over the years building dashboards
and they make some nice pretty pictures
and that's great but at the same time if
we could make those nice pretty pictures
actionable and actually usable by
analysts to ask questions and get
answers
those questions that would be ideal so
we want to make it by analysts for
analysts just like squeal was designed
by Bam Fischer and an incident responder
from way back when we want to make sure
that we're taking all of our years of
experience of hunting down bad guys and
kind of exposing that in these
visualizations and dashboards that we're
building we want to make them
interactive so it's not just a dashboard
that you're putting up on the big screen
in your sock and it's just showing off
for your dog and pony shows we want to
make it a dashboard that you as the
analyst are actually interacting with
you're slicing and dicing within the
dashboard and you're getting the data
out to make it actionable and that's
really the key at the end of the day so
requirements to do that when I build a
dashboard I want to make sure that every
single dashboard that I build in cabana
has a search panel at the very bottom
that search panel is going to expose the
raw log entries because if I build a
dashboard and it's just pretty pictures
well that's pretty but it's not
necessarily actionable but if I include
a search panel at the bottom and I'll
show you this in the demo in a few
minutes then I can actually see the the
nitty gritty detail of all those logs
and I can sort of slice and dice among
different fields and I can pivot over to
full packet capture and to do that I'm
going to expose in that search panel
source IP and source port destination IP
and destination port and the elastic ID
and this is going to come in very
important in a minute when we talk about
pivoting from cabana over to cap need to
go and get our full packet capture let's
talk a little bit about workflow we want
to be able to be in cabana looking at
our visualizations looking at our
dashboards and we run across an IP of
interest we think maybe this is a victim
IP address maybe it was some kind of a
drive-by exploit maybe whatever the case
may be we want to then pivot on that IP
address and go and get as much
information
as we can casting a wider net and saying
hey Cubana show me everything you know
about this so one of the things you'll
notice is that we've taken fields of
interest within cabana and we've
hyperlink them so for IP addresses for
host names domain names things like that
those kind of typical indicators they're
all hyperlinked and anytime you see that
hyperlink you click on it that takes you
to a very special dashboard that we've
built to do that kind of investigative
work that is going to be our indicator
dashboard and that's really going to
expose what we consider to be the most
important kinds of data that you would
need to investigate a particular
indicator now once I'm kind of in that
workflow of if I'm hot on the trail of a
bad guy and I'm chasing them down in my
network and I've constructed all of
these different filters to really kind
of narrow down my search well I've got
some different dashboards and I might
want to kind of keep my collection of
filters and I might want to kind of
switch over to another dashboard now
this kind of tripped me up when I
started playing with Kabana but what I
realized pretty quickly was that hey you
know what a dashboard is really kind of
like a lens that we look at look through
at the data and so what I might want to
do is kind of change my lens and kind of
pivot from just looking at maybe my DNS
lens I might want to pivot over to my
HTTP lens just like Chris was talking
about just a few minutes ago so the idea
here is that if I if I've already kind
of created all these filters in Kabana I
can pin those filters down I can switch
to another dashboard and that's going to
hold my filters in place constraining
that data set that's in the dashboard to
just those filters and that's gonna be a
key part of my workflow so keep in mind
that whole concept of pinning those
filters down but wait there's a problem
this is going to be a recurring theme
throughout this presentation I'm gonna
kind of talk about some of the problems
that we've addressed and how we try to
overcome those problems as
we integrated all of this elastic
goodness
so I see your problem there's a dude
passed out in your engine also your
mechanic is a pony so if your mechanic
is a pony you might have an
authentication problem and that's kind
of what we have here because if you
think about the pure open-source elastic
stack there is no authentication
whatsoever if you go in if you go with
the elastic xpac plug-in then you can
get some authentication but that's not
open-source we have to have open source
there are some open source plugins out
there that provide some sort of
authentication for Kabana but it's kind
of an unknown quantity and really it
truly who wants yet another username and
password right ideally we'd like to
leverage our existing credentials to be
able to then authenticate to Kabana so
there are solutions you know if you mess
up your Rubik's Cube just repaint the
nerd thing so in this case we repainted
our rubik's cube by writing our own
apache authentication proxy right so
this way what we then wind up with is
this nice single sign-on web page hosted
by apache which then becomes the
front-end not only for Kabana but also
for squirt and also for cat me right so
if you remember back a couple of years
ago it used to be the case that you
would have to like log in to Elsa and
then you would have to like log in to
cap me and if you remember back long
before that you would have to like
authenticate the Academy every single
time right so we've made tremendous
strides
you
right so you've already got a squeal
username and password let's leverage
that right so anytime you try to log
into squirt or cap me or cabana now it's
gonna prompt you for username and
password that first time you put in your
squeal credentials and you're good to go
but wait there's another problem you're
gonna hear this over and over and over
again and you're going to sing it along
with me as we go so get ready so if
you're an astronaut and you got this big
honking helmet on your head and your
nose starts itching you can't get there
from here you know what I'm saying we
had the same kind of problem because we
just talked about a minute ago the fact
that we'd love to be able to go from
Kabana and find an arbitrary log and be
able to pivot over to cap me now in the
abstract that seems relatively simple
right because we've been doing that from
Elsa in the past the way that works in
Elsa is the get pcap plugin it scrapes
off the source IP source port
destination IP and destination port it
then constructs a URL to pass that
information over to Kat me and it then
goes behind the scenes and gets the pec
pcap for you and renders it now the
problem here is that when we first
started this whole technology preview
process back in February and we were
running the elastic stack version two
there was not an easy way to then scrape
source IP source port destination IP
destination port and construct a URL to
get over to cap me you can do that with
scripted fields and elastic five but we
didn't have that at the time plus we
came up with a better way anyway so the
solution here it is if the math teacher
tells you to find X you just circle it
right there on the page so in our case
finding X solving the equation really
had to do with a little bit of a rewrite
of cat me so in this case instead of
having to feed all of these little
pieces
information in Academy's source IP
source port destination IP destination
port let's let cat me instead do the
heavy lifting so instead of passing four
pieces of data to cabby let's just pass
one piece of data and that's gonna be
the elastic ID that's unique identifier
inside of the elastic search database
that says this is the unique identifier
for this particular log entry so now if
we do that if we pass that over to cat
meat cat me can then go in query elastic
search and say hey elastic elastic
search give me all of the information
for this particular log entry now the
cool thing here is that if elastic
search comes back and says hey this is a
con log a broke on log and it's got
destination IP destination port all of
that information and guess what our con
locks have the sensor name on the very
tail end of the log file cat me just
scrapes the information off and it goes
and gets the full full pcap all is right
with the world
now it's not a con log let's say it's an
HTTP log chris talked before about how
burrow has these unique identifiers the
bro connection ID and that's how bro
logs can be correlated amongst each
other cap me uses that and leverages
that and says okay if this is bro HTTP
let's just strip out the connection ID
then go back to elastic search hey
elastic search I need the con log for
this connection once I've got the con
log then I can figure out what sensor I
need to go and request the full packet
capture from all that to say write a few
hundred lines of code and cap me is now
much more intelligent and can do all of
this automatically without you having to
think about it right and that's gonna
open up a whole nother window of
possibilities there so we're excited
about that but wait
there's another problem hey Larry stop
cranking it I think the engines flooded
so if you're I talked about this before
you know we started off with a Buchi
1404 the original elastic version too
because that was the only thing that
could run an open JDK 7 now elastic 5
has lots of new features obviously we
want to use the latest and greatest
hotness that required open JDK 8 so when
people tell me you're gonna regret that
in the morning I sleep in till noon cuz
I'm a problem solver so in this case
docker was our problem solver docker
solve a whole lot of problems for us so
by packaging the elastic stack and
docker images that kind of gets us
around that whole sticky OpenJDK issue
because we can build these little docker
images that are just a very minimal sin
os install just enough to get open JDK 8
bootstrapped
and now we've got this nice abstraction
layer so we can push these doctor images
into place and we can run the latest
version of elastic stack on our current
version of a boot to 1404 plus we get
some nice security features out of it
like process isolation and sandboxing
and things like that pretty cool but
wait there's another problem so if you
got one of these fancy new cars that has
like it's driven by a computer and it
like updates firmware over-the-air
across the internet and like some bad
guy like man in the middle is your car's
LTE connection like forces down bad
firmware that says if his GPS
coordinates are at his house and he puts
it in the park just go ahead and shove
the foot on the gas and run through the
garage door right that's a problem so
our problem here is docker hub security
right if we're going to use docker
images if you think about what we've
done with a boot
ditches in the past all of our abouttwo
packages are GPG signed to prevent
tampering right so if somebody ever
tries to man-in-the-middle your
downloads or you know is able to
compromise one of the abuti repos your
machine is not going to install those
packages because they don't match the
GPG signature now we want to make sure
that we have that same level of security
for our docker images so our solution
here is the docker notary now this is
something that is kind of optional it's
not really turned on by default but what
we do with all of our our scripts
whenever they do a docker pull we make
sure that we enforce this flag that's
kind of counterintuitive disable content
trust equals false it's kind of a double
negative it's not really good form but
that's our way of explicitly enabling
this whole concept of number one when we
create a docker image I sign it with my
GPG key that's done through the docker a
notary service and then when we do a
docker pull it's going to check and
verify those signatures and make sure
that they're correct but wait there's
another problem we need more power right
just like Tim Allen and that great old
show we want more power so I want to be
able to send automated emails I wanted
to find arbitrary criteria because maybe
I'm not a 24 by 7 shop maybe I want my
systems to be monitoring for certain
things and letting me know what it sees
that I want to look for baby domains a
lot of times bad guys are registering
brand-new domain so I want to look for
domain names that maybe we're registered
in the last month the last week I want
to look for host names or domain names
that have high entropy right when those
bad guys are doing domain generation
algorithms and they're doing totally
random looking domain names that look
like a cat loft across the keyboard all
right I can measure that I can look for
entropy but I want to do that on an
automated basis also I want in endpoint
visibility in addition to my network
visibility so I got your power right
here so here's how we do those things
a last alert is a great project which
allows you to define arbitrary criteria
and have that run on a scheduled basis
doing searches for whatever the heck you
want and then alerting via whatever
service you want there's like 21
different plugins you can do email and
you can do slack and all of the hipster
chat channels these days these kids in
there
whatever's domain stats I mentioned
before mark bagging wrote this great
Python script called domain stats and so
this is going to essentially go into a
Whois query on a domain name look at
that registration date and then we can
measure that and we can write rules
against that to say hey I want to look
for any domains that maybe were
registered in the last month the last
week whatever like why is freaked
stirred up by another Python script
written by Mark Baggett that does
frequency analysis so you take a DNS
name or a host name you run it through
Freak server and it's going to give you
a score that score is going to indicate
how random that name looks and so we can
now take every single DNS log every
single log that has any kind of a host
name we can run it through Freak server
and we can very quickly very easily get
a score in every single one of our logs
as they come in they're automatically
ingested with this frequency analysis
score that's pretty cool finally
endpoint visibility we've heard a couple
of folks talked today about system on I
love system on I hope you do too it's a
great free tool from mark russinovich of
Microsoft Fame and it gives you great
endpoint visibility so we want to make
sure that we are supporting folks
deploying system on collecting those
system on logs so we've got the parsers
we've got the the log stash config the
visualization the dashboard and auto
runs as well it's a great endpoint
visibility there but wait there's
another problem
here's where things get interesting
you know we really don't want just a
single standalone box we'd really like
to do distributed deployments we've been
doing with this with security onion for
a while right you think about we've been
doing else' distributed deployments you
have a master server you have sensors
down here and that's in Elsa that's a
distributed database because each of
your sensors had its own local Elsa
instance the Elsa web interface could
then query all of those Elsa databases
in parallel and return you the aggregate
results from all of that we'd like to do
the same thing with the elastic stack so
let's talk about well you've kind of got
the traditional elastic search
clustering which is very powerful it's
very cool but it's really kind of chatty
right and if you think about the way
that that traditional clustering works
and if you were to try to overlay that
on our kind of distributed our
traditional distributed deployment model
well then you may have a master server
in your data center and you may have a
remote office on the other side of the
world and a slow win link between the
two and if you try to do a traditional
elasticsearch cluster across that slow
and link you're probably gonna have a
bad day right because it's so chatty and
requires so much back-and-forth now
elastic came up with this thing called
the tribe node which is a little bit
more lightweight it's not doing the full
replication across that way in link but
it's still fairly chatty it still does a
lot of communication between nodes very
much unlike our traditional else'
deployment where nodes were very much
independent aha elastic recently came
out with this brand new thing called
cross cluster search that's their
replacement for the tribe node cross
cluster search enables you to do a much
more lightweight and less chatty
connection to remote nodes pretty cool
but wait there's another problem okay so
if we go with this whole cross search
cluster thing we're going to have a
master server here we're going to have
sensors down here we want our master
server to query our sensors
here but remember before I said that the
open-source elastic stack by default has
no authentication and there's no
encryption so if a master server just
goes in queries across the network
by default that's unencrypted we we
really don't want to be sending that
stuff unencrypted across the network we
really kind of need some encryption so
let's think about the way we did it in
Elsa with Elsa we used SSH tunnels to
encrypt all of that communication
all right so Elsa master server says
okay I need to connect to this sensor
down here so I'm going to connect to
local host port 50,000 that's my first
sensor and that's a port that gets
forwarded across the SSH tunnel down to
the sensor down here so now master
server sends a request sensor responds
master server gets the data okay well
let's just do the same thing with
elastic search but wait there's another
problem all right this is where things
get complicated okay because local host
is not necessarily local host wait what
did you just say yeah when docker comes
into play you don't just have one local
host anymore right because local host
from the perspective of the docker
container is different than local host
of the host OS itself right so if
elasticsearch tries to connect to local
host port 50,000 that's local host port
50,000 inside of the little docker image
the docker container
alright so my SSH tunnel that is doing
that port 50,000 port forward those
things just aren't even talking to each
other okay so I was wracking my head
with this how are we going to make these
things make the connection how are we
gonna make this work so as it turns out
there's this internal docker interface
and by default at least on my machines
it's 170 218 not 0.1 so when we
configure our SSH tunnel we'll just add
some extra syntax to say okay instead of
connecting that SSH tunnel to port
50,000 on
host will connect it to 172 18 not 0.1
that's that doctor interface that
elasticsearch inside the doctor
container can connect to and ultimately
get across the SSH tunnel but wait
there's another problem the problem is
if we want to do that extra syntax SSH
doesn't want to let us do that so we
have to reconfigure SSH to allow that
but we don't want to do it globally
across the board we don't want to open
up huge security holes so we have to
make sure that we very granular ly limit
that to just the SSH tunnel and the user
account associated with that autum SSH
tunnel okay cool
got it but wait there's another problem
all right so we got a master sir we got
a sensor got an SSH tunnel connecting
the two and in terms of tcp/ip we have a
connection port 50,000 is flowing across
the SSH tunnel all should be good with
the world however the second that
elasticsearch up here tries to talk to
elastic search down here elastic search
down here says you know you actually
should be talking to this IP address and
this port so it's kind of a redirect
that goes the wrong direction so okay
fine let's just reconfigure elastic
search on the sensor to give it the
proper IP address and port using the
transport publish host and transport
publish port syntax are you exhausted as
I am all right so now we've got the
plumbing in place we have tcp/ip in
place we can do the whole three-way
handshake thing and we can actually do
an elastic query now we just need to
have the sensor tell the master server
hi I'm a new sensor I want to I want you
to add me to your list of sensors to
query so if you are familiar with
elastic search you know you can do a get
you can do a put to change settings so
we have the sense
to a put to underscore cluster slash
settings to add the new hostname IP
address in Port and all is right with
the world now that's your first sensor
you probably want to add more the plot
thickens
okay so now your second sensor is going
to say hi I'm sensor number two I'd like
to join your cross cluster search so it
doesn't get to cluster settings it says
here's the list of existing sensors it
finds the highest number port which at
this point is 50,000 so we increment
that since there number two is then
going to be pork 50,000 one additional
sensors then continue incrementing so
each sensor has its own port that's the
same basic methodology that we had in
place for Elsa we just had to fix all of
that plumbing stuff that I explained on
the last 27 or so slides all of that was
undocumented it was it was me just
running into stuff with trial and error
right
okay questions or comments so far would
you like to see a demo well the yeah I'm
pushing my luck here because and that's
why you see the flames down here right
so oh so you're the sacrifice okay okay
well I appreciate that I do let me give
some caveats here
okay so we've already had one fail we
had a projector and podium fail this is
a relatively new laptop and this is only
my second time doing a public demo I
have three virtual machines running each
with eight gigs of RAM and this is all
brand new stuff the cross cluster search
stuff is considered beta by the elastic
folks and all of our integration stuff
is still considered pre-alpha at this
point so that's all my excuses
[Applause]
we could go down in a blaze of glory
are you ready buckle up
I need some liquid courage all right Oh
in addition to getting a new laptop I
switched from Mac OS to Windows C with
with Mac only offering 16 gigs of RAM on
a laptop I had to leave I'm sorry
Joel I'm sorry I know I did Joel gives
me the thumbs down I know I know
16 gigs of ram is just not sufficient
all right excuse me so here we go we've
got a master server here 530,000 logs
that's kind of visible let's see so let
me show you this first so I've got these
two sensors here I'll just very quickly
show you this guy's got 8 gigs of RAM
it's got our whole standard security
stack plus the elastic stack running you
can see there it's got its own
elasticsearch instance and then of
course since r2 is going to basically be
identical same thing there standard
sniffing stuff standard elasticsearch
stuff so master server has its own
elasticsearch database sensor one has
its own elasticsearch sensor to has its
own elastic search they're all
independent but yeah they're joined via
across clusters search which allows us
to query all of them in parallel and get
results aggregated across the entire
sensor population all right so just to
prove that to you let me go down here to
stats
so let me see if I can do a little zoom
egde here so if you can see there we've
got master eighth one and it's got
21,000 logs we've got sensor one eighth
one that's 21,000 locks and sensor to
21,000 logs so cross cluster all of that
plumbing stuff I just talked about it's
working it's amazing all right so let's
see what else can we do here let's kind
of talk about number one if I can zoom
back out and then go here so just a
little bit of kind of workflow
navigation type stuff if you've played
with our previous technology previews
one of the things that's changing as of
today is that the link to squirt and the
link for logout those are now located on
the sidebar here right and you'll you'll
be able to see here that when I go over
to squirt I don't have to authenticate
the squirt because of single sign-on
right so if I'm already authenticated to
kibana I can instantly and easily pivot
to squirt I do what I need to do there
now while I'm in squirt let me actually
do this so I'll just do a search here
and I'll just rewind this back to say
2016 just to get a whole bunch of data
and then maybe I start doing an
investigation here Chris Sanders style
maybe I look into an alert maybe I find
an interesting IP address maybe I want
to pivot on that IP address and so maybe
I go down to this list and I look for
cabana that's going to pivot over to our
indicator dashboard notice I didn't have
to authenticate all right and so here
I'm on my indicator dashboard and here
we kind of expose what we consider to be
the most important kinds of data for
that particular indicator so we've got
kind of the overview of the different
kinds of logs from snort alerts to HTTP
logs to connection logs we've got our
IDs alerts listed here we can scroll
down the page we get like source IP
destination IP HTTP sites sites hosting
exe so we can tell instantly this is
actually a Windows exe coming from
Windows Update
right so in your triage process this
makes it very easily to go from an IDs
alert and say was this malicious or was
this legitimate well this is probably
legitimate depending on your view of
Microsoft's legitimacy so now this is
what I was talking about before and that
all of our dashboards include a search
panel at the bottom you can see the
search panel listed here and we expose
the most interesting fields in that
search panel so source IP source port
destination IP destination port UID and
underscore ID now so let's talk about
Chris is Chris's idea of pivoting right
and data expansion data reduction right
because I might then kind of pivot from
squirt to here to Cabana and now I've
done some data expansion right I've got
some additional data I've casted a wider
net and I now have some more potential
victims to go on maybe some additional
attacker IP space that I might need to
investigate notice all of these are
hyperlinked so if I then take a look at
this IP address I can just click on it
that's going to spawn another cabinet
tab going again to our indicator
dashboard focusing on that particular IP
address all right so let me also show
you the fact that this UID is hyperlinks
so that's the bro unique identifier
that's the connection ID so if I want to
see all of those bro logs kind of at the
same time for that particular connection
ID I just click on that and I see that
I've got HTTP Conn and files now final
finally in this hyperlink here for
underscore ID that's the very special ID
field that I talked about before and
that's our very special hyperlink into
cap me so when you see underscore ID
think full packet capture so let's just
see if this will work for us we pivot
over to cap me again not having to
authenticate and this may actually take
a few seconds due to internet it's
probably trying to do a DNS lookup
normally if my internet connection was
up this should happen pretty fast hey
there it goes so there's our full packet
capture all of that 30 seconds
was was really it just trying to resolve
this IP address here otherwise it would
be instantaneous so again you're able to
very quickly and easily pivot not only
from one interface to another not only
from squirt to kibana to cap meet but
pivot from multiple data types and
multiple data sources just like Chris
was talking about so let me quickly kind
of talk about some of our menus over
here I'm not going to go through each
and every one of these but I'm gonna
pick a few highlights you'll recognize a
lot of these if you've used else in the
past you'll you'll remember on Elsa we
have that sort of list of canned queries
on the left-hand side a lot of these
came from there kind of taking those
standard bro logs like the connection
log that the NS log the HTTP log and so
for each of those kind of log types we
build a dashboard on that dashboard we
include visualizations for the most
interesting fields for that particular
data type so let me just show you a few
examples here bro notices right so this
is somewhat analogous to an alert so
this is included under alert data so
this is where you see things like the
team comer email where hash registry
matches that's always good fun there you
can see on this dashboard we've exposed
the most interesting fields from that
bro notice log and of course the
underscore ID field allows you to pivot
even from bro notices or other logs
which may not necessarily have that kind
of tuple of information that I talked
about before of source IP import
destination IP import kami has the
intelligence to go and find that full
packet capture for you elastol eart I
mentioned this before this is the method
that you can use to kind of define
arbitrary criteria to say hey I want you
to go and search for this thing this
thing and this thing and if you ever
find it I want it to email it to me or
page me or whatever the case may be and
we do have a dashboard for that so you
can kind of build your own
visualizations there of course we do
have a dashboard for network based IDs
alerts so you see all of your lovely
stored alerts here you can slice and
dice those to your heart's content
all kinds of nice hyperlinked fields for
additional
let's see I definitely want to show you
DNS because one of the things I talked
about was marks Python scripts for freak
server and domain stats right and this
is gonna be some some next-level hunting
capabilities because if I scroll down
here you see kind of the typical DNS
stuff but then when we get into highest
registered domain frequency analysis let
me zoom into this because this is
important notice most of these names
look pretty interesting when you say
right so when all of these logs are
coming in logstash is saying oh that's a
hostname that's a DNS name I need to go
and look at I need to run that through
freak server and I need to run that
through domain stats and I need to get
these frequency scores and that's going
to help me find these sort of random
looking host names and I can tell you
that about 90% of these names listed
here are domain generation algorithms
right that's pure concentrated evil okay
and this gives us a very easy way of
finding that stuff all right so let's
see if we can zoom back out we have the
same thing for parent domain so we have
highest registered domain and parent
domain so mark created the Python
scripts Justin Henderson created the
docker images which house those Python
scripts then we also have this here so
that domain stats PI it enables us to
look for baby domains right so notice
admin a offline was created August the
25th of 2017 alright so when a bad guy
goes and registers brand-new domain
names whether it's domain generation
algorithm or whatever the case may be we
can find that very quickly and easily
here all right so let's zoom back out
scroll back up
let's see what else do I want to show
you we look at my cheat sheet here we
talked about pivoting the Kami a last
alert hunting DNS HTTP SSL so SSL
Certificates they do that same kind of
scoring of host names using frequency
analysis and entropy and things like
that
SMB so if you're a if you're a hardcore
bro user you know that the current
version of bro does have experimental
SMB traffic analysis so you can kind of
monitor your Windows File Sharing
traffic and we have the log stash
parsers in place to parse all of that
experimental bro SMB logs there's four
different logs that encompasses we parse
all those who create the visualizations
and the dashboards all that's there for
your hunting pleasure all right so
that's SMB go out and endpoint
visibility one more thing and then we're
done so let's see host hunting I
mentioned before sis man sis Mon I love
sis Mon let's see if I go to last seven
days hey I've got data so I built a
little Windows 10 VM I installed system
on I started collecting those logs and
we consume all those we adjust those
into log stash we give you some
visualizations so here you can see I've
got some nice host visibility here I can
see exe es executing on my endpoints
right so we all kind of realize as
security practitioners that more and
more of our network traffic is being
encrypted so we then need to make sure
that we're filling in the gaps in our
analysis by giving ourselves that
endpoint telemetry system on is a great
way to do that and we fully support that
here all right so very good in points
limit tree they're very excited about
the
oh one more thing so let me show you
just you can kind of see a little bit of
the plumbing behind the scenes this is
when I was talking about before relating
to kind of the plumbing of cross cluster
search and how we send that traffic over
the SSH tunnel right so you've got your
master server here it communicates with
itself and then it communicates with
sensor one over 170 to 1801 450 thousand
and then sensor to over port 50 thousand
won all that's ssh it's all encrypted
it's all good to go all right
did that demo actually work it's amazing
[Applause]
yes thank you kind sir thank you all
right let me go back into full-screen
mode not from beginning why did you do
that
computers are hard the demo was the hard
part the slides are even harder we're
almost there
there's another problem yeah there's
another problem
this sure is Hey all in all this is our
best hunting platform ever we're very
excited we've worked very hard but wait
there's another problem feedback yeah we
need it okay so we have gotten a good
amount of feedback based on technology
preview one technology preview two
technology preview three no pool no
problem hey just fill up the trash can
with some water
there's your swimming pool right there
and you know what you guys you've got
trash cans you've got your own networks
right you can you can fill that out with
some water you can you can you can play
with the elastic stack alpha because
it's available today we are now at alpha
release if you take a look at our blog
blog on security onion net at 3 o'clock
p.m. Eastern Time the alpha release went
live so you can play with this today all
the latest and greatest stuff that I
just demoed all the visualizations all
the dashboards all the log stash parsers
all the cross cluster search all the
distributed deployment you can do all of
this today and Joel one more thing
it's all available in an ISO image so
1404 dot 5.30 available today this is
our very first ISO image containing the
elastic stack again I need to emphasize
this is the alpha release do not I
repeat do not deploy this in production
okay but if you can deploy it in semi
quasi production kind of off to the side
of your existing production sensor and
you can feed it some copies of your
production traffic and you can give us
some feedback on that that would be
amazing
so download the ISO image play with it
give us your feedback you can go to
blogged on security on your net you can
send your feedback to our mailing list
we monitor that every single day we're
very much interested in feedback
especially on this alpha release help us
get to beta we want to get there and we
want to get there fast but we need your
help to do so your next question is
going to be about timeline and so I'm
going to preempt your question by
answering it right now okay so we want
to get this released by the end of the
year if possible maybe early 2018 if we
have an issue okay but again we need
your help to do so if if you guys don't
play with it and you don't give us your
feedback then we're not going to get
there right but if you can help us out
provide feedback that's going to help us
get there much much faster now this is
very important to note once we reach
that full final release of the elastic
stack there's going to be a six-month
timer and Elsa's going to go end-of-life
in six months okay because we can't
support both forever so get ready right
if you're running Elsa in production
today you're going to need to migrate to
the elastic stack before we hit that
six-month end-of-life all right a couple
of announcements we have a couple of
it's tomorrow who's going to be sides of
us too should be everybody yes
absolutely so we're very excited about
besides the gust I hope to see you there
secure Dania solutions we'll have a
vendor table set up there and we will
bring back onion arcade folks seem to
like it last year so we'll be back again
this year and it might be version 2.0
not going to tell you what that means
you're gonna have to stop by and find
out what it's all about we have a four
day basic class coming up in San Antonio
that's in November registration is open
now we may have a four day advanced
class maybe the very first public
advanced class ever which might be in
late 2017 or early 2018 so stay tuned
for further announcements about that if
you're interested in training at your
own facility we do go on-site and do
training classes with an 8 student
minimum so reach out to us if you're
interested in that you can find more
information at security onion
solutions.com and with that ladies and
gentlemen I thank you very much we made
it through the demo we didn't go down in
a blaze of glory
questions or comments okay
brant the ISO image already includes the
docker images yes so you can just
download the ISO image you can just run
setup as you always have you'll see a
new option inside of setup which will
ask you if you want to run stable setup
or experimental setup your run
experimental setup and it will give you
all of the elastic goodness
using the docker images that are already
built into that ISO image one more
question
yes sir mr. Kevin so currently out of
the box you're only going to have Kabana
on the master server so just like we've
always done with Elsa you just have the
Elsa web interface on the master server
itself so if you were to look at my
sensor 1 and sensor to Caban is not
running at all now it is possible in
theory because I know where you're going
I know your use case it is possible to
run kibana
on that sensor and have it looking at
its own local elasticsearch so that is
possible get with me for more
information that's not that's not a use
case that everybody does but in theory
it's possible all right so I think we
are out of time
I want to say thank you thank you thank
you yet again to all of our sponsors all
of our speakers and to each and every
one of you thank you for being here hope
to see you tomorrow and hope to see you
again next year thank you