hi i'm john spriggs and i'm giving a
talk today called automating os
hardening with little help from my
friends cis benchmarks and ansible
so as is fairly customary in talks like
this i should introduce myself i'm john
spriggs
sometimes called john the nice guy i'm
an automation and orchestration
specialist uh focusing mostly on cloud
security i'm also a distinguished
engineer of the company who employs me
well actually that was
last week
as of this week or next monday rather
i'll be a technical account manager for
a very very large company don't know
what that all entails here but anyway i
also podcast blog do twitch and youtube
streams and well stuff like what we're
about to go through
just a little bit less polished and i
like to talk my wife said i should just
leave it there but well i should follow
that up by saying i like to talk at
conferences so this is exactly the sort
of stuff that i like to talk about
and what am i going to be talking about
well this is a talk for the blue teamers
out there i'm talking about hardening
your operating systems and server
applications with a framework called the
cis benchmark i'm also talking about
automation tool called ansible
now this may already be in use in many
of your organizations or if not
answerable then something similar the
main alternatives that i know about are
puppet chef and salt but i really know
ansible so that's what i'm going to be
talking about
so let's get on with this show here is a
mildly tweaked version of the cis
benchmark website this lists all of the
benchmarks they offer covering operating
systems like amazon linux debian ubuntu
red hat enterprise linux and windows
they also cover browsers virtualization
platforms office applications and even
server services like apache httpd the
bind dns service free radius ios
sharepoint mysql i did remove the list
of mobile operating systems whilst i was
shuffling the list around and by mistake
i forgot to add it back in but it is
supposed to be there too now this page
is the one that you get to from
whichever benchmark you click on from
the main site so if you go and search
for anything in the cion um
benchmark site you get to this page
eventually
they email you a url which takes you to
another list which gives you the actual
download they don't really care which
benchmark you're actually clicking on
just that your email address is valid
uh because it's an email address i'm not
really sure whether you get put on a
spam list at that point because the
company that i
used to work for had actually signed up
for a corporate corporate membership at
this site so i get to go in a different
way but i don't recall getting any extra
spam when i signed up for it with my
personal address so
your mileage may vary i don't know
um
sorry just got lost there for a second
it's also worth mentioning the terms and
conditions here as well you're not
allowed to use this as a commercial
offering so you can use it to having
your own servers but you best not offer
a cis hardening service if you want to
go with the free account i think even
the paid corporate service prevents that
too so just check what you're planning
to do with those benchmarks before you
use them okay that's all the legal
disclaimers out of the way let's take a
look at the ubuntu benchmark
well actually it's just the table of
contents for right now you see
each of those numbered points there
uh
1.1.1.1.1.1 and so on and so forth
these are checks to perform now on my
screen i can see file system
configuration which can covers
preventing certain certain kernel
modules being loaded setting volume
amount configuration values next is
software updates file system integrity
checking and so on just on this one page
of the table of contents there's over 40
checks so let's look at the next page
oh look
more checks setting up access control
banners disabling gui logins removing
server services network protocols you
see this is blanket guidance turn off
what you're not using on the box justify
what you are it's just like a check test
hmm
strange that anyway next page more
content more networking stuff enable a
firewall configure it turn on order d
use it
then you get more auditly more logging
authentication sudo ssh
pam
users permissions etc
goodness this is just the table of
contents
well here we are last page all in all
over 250 checks in here spanning 11
pages just of content and nearly 500
pages of actual content so should we
have a look at one of the actual checks
so this is um a simple check i've
checked skipped past the check whether a
kernel is loaded module my kernel module
loaded checks and gone straight for the
installer package for faster to
integrate
file system integrity checking
basically you've got six sections here
what sort of profile machine this will
check relevant to which cya cis
controls does it support
um
why would you want to run this check how
do you run this check
and then how to remediate a failure of
that check this one also lists a few
other bits and pieces like the details
about the problems you might run into
when you're using this
so this is looking for a particular
software package in this case eight and
it's telling you how to install it and
then how to perform basic configuration
on it even without automation side of
things these are actually really useful
documents so
what's next
well let's look at ansible now i thought
you might have had a bit too much text
on the previous few pages so i drew a
pretty diagram well
say pretty ansible is an open source
project from red hat you can run the
command line tool on any unix like shell
including linux and osx doesn't natively
run on windows but if you're running
windows subsystem for linux wsl it'll
run quite nicely albeit slowly on there
if your environment doesn't use wsl or
let you run it in a bastion host you can
install the ansible automation platform
which is a charged product from red hat
or their open source upstream project
awx awx is basically an unbranded
version of the ansible automation
platform and in theory runs on any
system that runs docker personally i've
only tried awx on ubuntu and ansible
automation platform on braille
awx and the anti-ansible automation
platform have engines that run the same
playbooks that the command line tool and
civil runs so from this point i'll refer
to everything as though we're just the
command line version
which is good otherwise you'd have even
more pointless screenshots in the
forthcoming pages
so answer will use an inventory file or
an inventory script to determine which
hosts it needs to talk to it also reads
a yaml file which details what plays
it's going to execute and a play is a
combination of a host selection and a
collection of tasks which will be
performed sequentially across all those
hosts each task is executed against one
of the following a server connected over
ssh or winrm
a network device over https or ssh
and a cloud or sas api over https so
what might that look like
so here's a simple representation of
that previous slide
so on our unix like shell
we execute the command and simple
playbook telling it which playbook to
read
and which inventory file to read
then
here's our playbook the playbook has a
sim a single in this case play which is
named
confirm comment
that lists which hostile target
and the tasks it wants to be performed
now in this case the first task is going
to be a connection check using the
module ping that's not the icmp or udp
ping but more like the ilc ping pong
challenge response
um
it's named confirm we can connect and
registers the response in the comms
check variable
next we output our response using the
debug module which we pass in our
argument of the variable columnscheck
that we previously defined we also say
we only want this command to run if the
previous command didn't fail
so that's our playbook done in our entry
file we first list the localhost now if
we run ansible without any inventory you
get the localhost added automatically
but as soon as you add an inventory file
you need to manually specify the
localhost and here we can see that the
localhost variable has a variable
assigned against it from the outset the
ansible connection equals local
so by default ansible talks ssh anytime
we're not using ssh we need to tell
ansible that we'll see another example
of that in a bit
so next we jump down to the group linux
all linux servers
now again we've included the local host
in this group as it's actually running
wsl so therefore it's kind of a linux
environment
i've also added a web load balancer and
because that doesn't resolve to a
specific host in either the dns server
nor in our ssh config file
i've specified the real hostname it will
connect to so this means you can give a
long complex host name a short alias or
it can give a meaningless host name or
ip address descriptive names for your
logging purposes
lastly in this block i've added a dns
resolvable range of three back end
servers now naturally
those won't actually resolve
well you'll see that in a bit
um i've also added some windows servers
even though they're not referenced in
the playbook because well
maybe there's another playbook which
targets windows servers or perhaps we
didn't get to those tasks yet when we
were writing the playbook either way
we have two ip addressed note hosts 81
and 82
and like with the load balancer they
don't have dns names instead they have
an ip address
we also have seven dns resolvable rds
servers excellent we're not going to
connect to those but you'll see what
happens anyway these windows servers all
have some common connection variables
like they use with rm for example
they have a common service council
against them and if i were being
completely and entirely insecure i'd
dump a plain text password
for this service account into the
inventory but i'm not completely foolish
no instead i've stored that password in
an encrypted file in the group vars
directory for this group of servers now
ansible has its own name for this
encryption system called volt it uses
standard encryption primitives offhand i
don't know what they were but i think
it's aes256 something like that so it's
not completely unreasonable and actually
this is one of the few serious benefits
of ansible tower and awx which is the
awx or ansible tower can segregate the
action of storing access credentials
away from users who are actually
executing the ansible playbooks so
they're still in one central location
and you can harden protect that host
accordingly but they're not completely
accessible to everyone anyway let's move
on so the last thing we have in this
inventory is a final group called all
servers which has two child groups
associated to it all linux and all
windows servers so in theory we could
target both platforms with a standard
set of configuration steps we don't do
that here
but you can see how you might extend
this out to other things as well so what
does this actually look like when it
runs
skipped too far
so let's run this video
and it's stored off elsewhere so uh
sorry about that it's not gonna look
very pretty for a second
let's run this
so that's playbook minus i inventory
playbook
you see it's confirming the comms
running the play confirming comes and it
does the first thing it does it runs
this gathering facts task now you see
there it's failed to connect to some
hosts because it couldn't resolve the
host names
after that it ran the test it then
output the debug results we asked it to
and then you get this recap at the end
where you see here
the fact that localhost ran okay it was
able to run three tasks um
the three back end servers were
unreachable unreachable because it
couldn't resolve the dns names and then
the load balancer it connected too fine
so that's good
so let's uh let's close that screen and
come back to
our select
so how does how else can we use ansible
so that previous slide and in fact all
the rest of these slides as well
actually don't do
really any templating but this is quite
a large part of why i like ants we see
almost anywhere you see a defined
variable in an ansible playbook or a
config file it can be templated and by
that i mean ansible will on demand
render that templated string to build a
new value
like in the yaml file here at the top we
provide a default value when something's
missing so some var might be defined
somewhere else and if it's not there we
use a default value you can run if else
if
else end if script and you can even do
ternary you know if value is true then
return true and so if value is x then
return y and if it's not x then returns
it
you can also create template files as
well so like in the bottom block there
you can see a for loop there um stepping
over items uh to build up a
more complicated um
more complicated configuration file or
documentation file
you can also see that there's um you can
use these strings in tasks
um
so let's put ansible and the cis
benchmark together
so here we have our setup
importing a role which currently has two
files in it
the defaults file which stores some
overrideable values and the task which
will be executed as part of that role
now i'm not going to go too far into
what this role does right now but
basically it does the remediation steps
we documented in the benchmark
but only if that overrideable value
down here execute cis harden os one one
one one is true
now when we put that role
into your playbook
it becomes a reusable block of code
anywhere that you want to use it
this screen shows two roles as part of a
test playbook embedded into the
environment using a github module packed
now you can see where you might put
those files to testings you can also
store this role elsewhere in your
environment and ask your developers to
edit their requirements there's loads of
documentation about this on the ansible
website
now if your team is already using
ansible then perhaps they'll contribute
fixes tweaks improvements to your
playbook you never know
now if you're interested how a role gets
put together this slide shows you what
files go where feel free to screen grab
this or take a picture or even as this
is going up as a video you may want to
play it all back and you know catch a
specific part of it
even better if you want to get involved
in the project that i'm writing
to write these 240 checks for ubuntu and
later some of the other cis benchmark
checks
then click on the qr code that's there
if not visit back come back to
to look at the the url that's in the
top of all of these slides click through
to that link at the bottom there to the
github repo
on the other side there you'll see that
i've already written some of those tests
in fact i've written the first eight of
them so
that's good
anyway thank you very much for listening
to my presentation i wish you lots of
luck getting yourself started on using
ansible or the cis benchmarks or even
better
maybe use both
and if you want to talk to me about any
of this lot then please feel free to
give me a shout thanks very much