so we have got a million issues we've
got little technical things
and a million things sort of going wrong
and we're asking you all
to be with us okay
[Music]
it's a tiny team and we're doing the
best that we can but you are all so
welcome so nice to see you
and we're going to do a few things just
notices
obviously we're not asking you to wear
masks
but can we all sanitize social existence
as best you can
you sold half the capacity that this can
hold
in the hope that there's enough room for
everyone
um
[Music]
how to conduct
uh everywhere and can we please make
sure that we all abide by it and read it
there are no excuses and we will beat
you into anything
against it
so you all have a weird
45 vinyl which is your b-side rifle
badge
please we have checked them
there was a couple that were borderline
offensive by what you mean there's like
i was gonna say it now there was like
rolf harris was in there for example so
if that's the case please feel free
to swap and shop and change i'm the john
lennon glasses obviously because you
might have noticed there's a bit of a
beatles theme in this particular part of
liverpool
and
i want to say we run this thing on a
bootstrap right we run it really tight
you don't want to make extra money and
we just want it to go into the event so
on that score you have
half of until they don't know this
morning
constantly it's constant
and
yeah coffee's until they've run out this
morning there's coffees again this
afternoon until they run out because our
code is another thing there's less
reviews on the tickets you sold so we
should be absolutely golden for coffee
constantly
um there are there are lunches including
veggie vegan eye options
and a paper bag lunch so you'll get that
and if you want to say after
you finish around about five o'clock all
be well tech being well
downstairs there is burgers
although you'll have to pay for your own
booze and they will not be selling
drinks alcohol until five o'clock okay
so five o'clock you know start
millionaires if you want to be up with
your vegas which are
free but i say three they're not free
because
our sponsors got us here
and and so
i need to see it i need to see it and i
think it's fun
[Applause]
this
hi we've
brian just put his hands up welcome
network this ride
also
[Applause]
is
[Music]
got a street charity scene today we have
got bullies out which is going to be a
film running
and we've got the lean in group which
are joining us
they sent a film
but that's to encourage women in india
and
uk as well but indian girls into stem
so support that and see it and treat
them maybe
and that one's out but we've also got a
joining us a bit later
a refugee women connect refugee women
can act on a charity in liverpool i'm
going to let them explain what it is
but at the moment if you've got that in
your title
it's very difficult to raise funds um so
they'll literally raise down there and
then i come to explain to you this
afternoon
but also all proceeds from the stickers
and everything else today will go to fg
women connect because they just need
money and hashtags and banners are great
but they need cash so that's what we're
doing
on that note the scout's passports
which elected from last year are like
three quid but if you want to pay a
fiver a genuine scouts will sign it for
you and just to say it
is a genuine
[Music]
[Applause]
um
you're awesome
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah and we'll show it we'll do it at
the end liz is going to do the auction
you just volunteered yourself
videos
um
so please
[Music]
tomorrow