good in the day bad at night these
garden gnomes have a surprise in store
today I'm going to take 2 common lawn
ornaments and combine them to create a
new more evil gnome okay let's get
started
I have here a box of garden gnomes that
they caught in China and cryogenically
preserved put them in a box you can get
them at Harbor Freight for 3 for about 6
bucks
and I also have here want to roll off
the table at the moment I have two solar
lights that I bought from Home Depot and
they are about 250 apiece and they'll
make a great power source for our nose
we have three gnomes first guy has a
watering can got this guy he's a little
perv he seems to like doing strange
things with vegetables this guy
he's holding a hoe but maybe we can
pretend this an axe because that's
slightly creepier all right the first
thing that we're gonna do is we're going
to take a cordless drill we're going to
drill holes into his eyes what I'm going
to use to drill the eyes is a special
type of bit that's designed for masonry
and for glass and what it has is a
carbide piece here instead of a fluted
spiral that you would find in most
drills see that end I've found that this
works great for masonry and not at all
really for glass so for glass what you
really want to use is a diamond bit I'm
going to start by drilling a hole
through each of the gnomes eyes the key
here is you want to go slowly with not a
lot of pressure so that you don't crack
it make sure that your drill bit doesn't
walk
with not very much pressure
okay so there's one hole and we'll just
do the other now our gnome has holes
where his eyes are the next thing we're
going to do is take a section of wire
and strip the ends off and to do that
I'm going to use a wire stripper tool
what this is is it's sort of like
scissors that has a notch in each blade
and if you carefully close these you can
strip the insulation off without
actually cutting through the conductor
inside just put the wire here and just
strip a small section off of each just
like that now we'll take an LED and cut
the lead short an important thing to
know about an LED is that if you see
here on this video just cut the
reflection and if I can catch it again
here there there's a flat spot next to
one of the LEDs what this is doing is
indicating the polarity of the LED you
can also see that the wires on the LED
are one one is longer than the other
this also indicates the polarity we're
going to pay attention to that when we
attach the wires in our case we're going
to connect the flat lead to the white
striped wire now I'm going to take my
soldering iron and apply a little bit of
solder to the leads of the wire the
white wire will go on the flat side so
I'm just going to add a little bit of
solder to my soldering tip
they're going to touch the wire to the
led very carefully and just bring the
soldering iron down to touch it the way
you want to do this is touch your
soldering iron to the lead itself and
then bring the solder in to touch it
this pre pre heats the conductor that
allows the solder to wick in much better
now I'm going to take the gnome that I'm
going to put this in I'm going to
measure a length of wire that should go
to the eye and out of the bottom of the
gnome just a little bit and cut it off
there so now we have one LED complete
I'm going to do the other LED just the
same way now this is all ready to go now
I'm going to take the gnome I'm going to
thread the wire down through the eye
hole out of the feet and with the LED in
position I'm going to take some hot glue
keep it locked into place just apply a
little bit around the eye and we'll do
it with the other eye so now we have our
wires coming out of the feet of the
gnome and I'm going to go ahead and
strip the ends of those as well and
attach them together so that the LEDs
are wired in parallel I'll go ahead and
strip them I'm stripping a longer length
here because I want to twist the twist
three wires together and just make it a
lot easier and I'm going to do this with
the additional piece of wire that goes
through the solar light as well before I
go doing this I'm going to cut some
sections of shrink tube that I can slip
over the wires to keep them from
touching after I have soldered all this
together so once again I touch I touch
my soldering iron to the wires and bring
the solder down and let it wick in there
we go we have it soldered now I'm just
going to take and fold these over like
this slip the heat shrink tubing over
top of all that now there heat shrink
tubing is in place I'm going to shrink
it with a lighter and what you don't
want to do is hold your lighter there in
place for a long time and really cook
the heat shrink tubing you just want to
move it around let it shrink when you
see that it's shrunk in a certain
section it's time to move on
there we go now the top side won't have
been shrunk yet so I'll just hit that as
well great and we'll do the other one
there we go now we're going to move on
to our solar light the first thing that
we need to do is drill a hole in the
clear part so that we can get the wire
out of out of the solar light going to
go ahead and slip the wire through this
hole now now I'm going to take the
remainder of my solar light and take it
apart there you have it there's the
battery is in here and we have one small
circuit board it doesn't really have all
that much on it the solar cells are here
I have four solar cells each solar cell
produces about 0.5 volts so altogether
this is producing about 2 volts right
here in the center is a cadmium sulfide
cell and what this is is a
light-sensitive resistor in case we're
going to remove the circuit board you
want to be careful that you don't wiggle
the wires too much otherwise they will
break off from the circuit board now I
have the LED exposed now I could leave
the LED in here but will get longer
runtime if I take it out what I'm going
to do is just heat both leads up at the
same time and get them red-hot and then
I should be able to just wiggle it out
of there with my soldering iron now I'm
going to quickly strip
the end of the wire that I just slipped
through the solar lights enclosure I'm
going to tin it
I'm going to apply a little solder to
the end of it one more thing you need to
drill a little hole through here so that
can sneak the wire through there as well
just connecting to the board
so now I'll just reattach the screws
again making sure to not wiggle the
wires too much because otherwise they
might break and we'll reattach this to
the top of the solar light but as you
can see here we've now have a garden
gnome one solar light and when it loses
its light eyes light up red one
interesting suggestion that came from
our writer Mike Nathan was that you
could make the gnomes so that they are
only evil when somebody gets close to
him by having a passive infrared sensor
so whenever they detect motion the eyes
come on and when it stops they're off so
from a distance it doesn't seem evil but
get close and you make them angry so
there you go this is Jack Buffington for
hackaday comm with a simple project that
you can do in an evening it takes a good
gnome and turns it pure evil