okay we are somewhere on the road in New
Mexico and during the Southwest tour
we've been hitting different
hackerspaces at each one I've been
gathering parts for stuff I have a 3d
printed jacket a logo piece from a
little handheld fan that's like the
battery holder piece some batteries a
whole handful of DC motors contact
switches some guitar strings I'm gonna
make a tattoo gun like a jailhouse
tattoo gun
we'll see if I can make this work as far
as tools I have my little Leatherman
multi-tool scissors stuff electrical
tape a little bit of wire and a lighter
and pen we'll see if this works
[Music]
this is where I'm at so far use the fan
kit battery holder a switch DC motor all
just taped together and I made this
little what cog that's hopefully going
to be a cam shortly I don't know if
that's gonna work I have some guitar
string here that'll go from that down
the barrel of a this pen to make the
needle that actually stabbed you for the
tattoo gun
[Music]
okay so it's done here it is you can see
I had to replace the cam with a
different system the old one wasn't
working but fire it up it goes the
needle goes in and out I don't know if
you can make that out in the video but
the needle is going in and out of that
chamber it actually does work on a
second it actually does work breaks the
skin we sanitize this with some hand
sanitizer and I did my arm here if you
can see that it's kind of bleeding a
little bit we'll do a little bit more
here
[Music]
you see it start to bleed there again we
used hand sanitizer
you wouldn't actually want to use this
for tattoos they're gonna be really
cruddy quality you want to go to a
professional tattoo artist if you want
to tattoo but just to show that it could
be done that's a hack on the road
you