three guests on stage and and the idea
of this session is that you get to ask
them anything within reason
um
and um but i think it'd be nice to start
maybe with a couple of minutes of
introduction from each of our uh
panelists each of our celebrities and
uh i'm gonna start with yuan and maybe
you could just take a couple of minutes
to introduce yourself if you don't mind
yeah you yeah yeah
and then then we'll do kathy and then
we'll do then we'll do you i think that
will help seek questions from the
audience so maybe
i didn't prepare anything so uh yeah so
i um diamond i um
do symmetric crypto
i did a phd at the time at cosic
at 95 and then i went to work for
industry
and i continued to collaborate
with vincent who i met at uh kylie
leuven
and we did a series of papers that led
eventually to reindeer which became a
yes
and that
gave me the opportunity to do crypto
research free crypto research at the
company i was working on and my boss
even
that
kind of was um i should say
um
shielding me from the upper management
and to do what i like and that's
when i met sheil vanash and mikhail
peters
and we did
research that would lead with a lot of
detours to finally catch up which became
chatri
and then
at some point
i got on the radar of hotboat university
and i started there one day per week
and later two days per week you know
three days per week and then five days
per week and i'm now there since i think
2018 full-time or 17
and i have now a team and i tried to
keep them busy with the same symmetric
crypto we're trying to innovate
that's it great thank you johan so if
you want to win in this competition you
know who to go to
okay kathy could you give us a quick
introduction thank you hi cathy yun
um let's see where to begin well i um
currently am at google i've done sort of
a variety of things at google i've done
like protocol design for cryptography
i've done security reviews focusing on
cryptography and ads
and i'm currently working on fhe and
prior to that i worked on zero knowledge
proofs in the blockchain space um
co-wrote the bulletproofs library with
henry and oleg
and prior to that i was at mit for
undergrad and my master's
i did my master's with vinod and shafi
doing function secret sharing so that's
a little
about me thank you very much welcome to
the stage
hi i'm yuval um i'm currently to the
university of adelaide in australia
i mainly work on trying to understand
what
computers do when we tell them what we
want them to do
and
how that affect the the security that
they claim to promise
and
before that
i've been i've done my phd at the
university of adelaide so it's homegrown
and they
before that i've been a bit in the
industry and
yeah then it's really far in the past i
don't remember much
thank you and welcome great so if you
have a question for our panelists either
collectively or individually just come
up to the mic and
join the queue there currently there are
zero people in the queue so until the
queue forms i'm going to start off with
a question for our three panelists
um i read on twitter today that tomorrow
is world quantum day
um
apparently so if you go to the twitter
account world quantum day you can read
all about it
doesn't matter
it depends on which side of that you
look
so you guys need to share three mics
between two um so i guess you just
indicate to each other so do should we
really care about quantum computers is
it really a thing
yeah
but
yeah i think it it helps um keeping a
lot of good mathematicians busy
so
maybe it exists maybe it doesn't but at
least there's a lot of mathematicians
that get a job because of it because
again they can do crypto research or
they can do mathematical research
calling it crypto so
i think it's good and if a quantum
computer exists we will have what it
takes
but if we have what it takes maybe it
doesn't there's no need to develop a
quantum computer anymore so yeah
okay thank you
other panelists i mean you can just say
pass if you want to pass that's also
okay
you get three passes and then and then
it seems hard to evaluate the
probability but the impact of that small
probability is high enough that i think
it makes sense to at least look at
hybrid
um options
well um
i guess from my perspective
it gives
cryptographers incentives to develop new
cryptographic schemes and the new
cryptographic schemes offer new
opportunities for people that want to
break them
and
but until i really get a
quantum computer under the oscilloscope
then
i don't know what they are used useful
for
okay thank you so now we can come to the
line and i see you already eleanor's
there so go ahead yes so i'm helena
uh my question is probably for yuval
i would like to know how you stumbled
across micro architectural side channels
how did that come about there were other
side channels before but this is totally
new and kind of out of the blue and how
how did that happen
so
i assume that we are talking about the
recent wave and um
the way it happened is uh in chess 2017
not like what was in the uh
in santa barbara i think 2016 2016-17
one of those
i spoke with a
mike hamburg
and
he suggested hey you know that there is
speculative execution
and that might
might do something
and then we uh
we started looking at that and uh
i guess that
admitting
failures at this stage i looked at that
as a way of breaking a
donna 64 way of breaking a
cryptographical implementations only
uh
next chess 2017
we met
paul kocher and we discussed that with
him and
he showed us that it can be used for
more than that so we had things working
and he showed us how to use that and
that specter
and after that it
just exploded so
it's a new field now so thank you
so maybe i can ask a quick follow-up
should we care about psychiatrists
um
probably about as much as we should care
about the
mpc fully homomorphic encryption we
should care about the quantum computers
okay
thanks um there's a question in the chat
actually specifically uh for kathy um
muhammad usama sardar is asking
what kind of tools are used in google
for verification of security of
protocols
is that something you can say something
about
um that's not something i directly work
on i know
jade is an audience somewhere works on
formal verification in general and um is
working on trust zone so that's
something that is looking at formal
verification i also know there's project
oak which does formal verification um so
yeah those are teams that exist but
that's sort of the extent of my
knowledge okay thanks
uh nigel oh yeah so i kind of noticed um
this is the first conference for two
years so i noticed there's a bunch of
people here i don't know so there's
loads more youngsters in the audience
okay and they probably don't want to get
up and ask this question but you've got
people here who you know we're in
academia people in a big corporation
someone who's went from a big
corporation and jumped into academia
what advice do you have to all these uh
young people in the audience who are
looking to step out on their career or
those who are looking for a change in
direction
you and you've not said anything for a
while why don't you take it i'm not
the guy giving career advice
i'm the worst person possible i think
i think you should do what you like
what's your passion i follow your
passion that's i think what you should
do
and that can make you happy
if you want some pseudo advice
i feel like it's really helpful to have
in whatever capacity you're able to but
have a little taste of both whether
that's you know doing internships at
companies but doing research just to
understand if you're doing research
who's going to end up using this
to inform
your direction of research
yeah
i guess
very similar
do do what you believe in do what you
think is is interesting what you find
interesting because if you do what
someone else finds interesting you'll
get bored
okay thank you um so from the chat um
kevin mccurley no less is asking for any
of you what do you think will ultimately
happen with cryptocurrencies
he's a controversialist well-known
controversialist
i can take the hat seat i think that
some really cool cryptography is going
to come out of it
unclear about the rest though but you
know i'm excited about the cryptography
part there's some really cool work
happening in this space there's a
smattering of applause there but it's
not wholehearted applause for those
maybe we should do maybe should we do a
quick poll of the audience since you
know everybody's here so hands up if you
think the effect of cryptocurrencies is
a net positive for the world
oh
to the world
not for us for the world
and hands if you think if it's a net
negative
okay that's like 80 20 maybe even 85 15
i would say
that's very interesting uh so other
other views on cryptocurrencies from the
panelists
yeah there's mostly this uh
ecological aspect of course of all this
mining and i don't see a solution for
that so
except for the uh
there are like
interesting problems there it's not
for cryptography for a
other stuff but
overall uh i don't see anything
positive that came from the
cryptocurrencies themselves outside the
things that how they operate and the
how we can build them answering these
questions so as an academic exercise
they would have been wonderful
um at least from my like
from what i've seen because i used to
work on zero knowledge proofs in the
blockchain space i think that um like
cryptocurrencies have allowed for and
like funded so much interesting research
and really pushed that space forward and
now we have way more efficient proofs
and now we can do things in like
for instance google where we're like hey
now we have really efficiency and
knowledge proofs where can we use that
for different applications like you know
federated learning or you know other you
know
other places where you'd want to do uh
verification so i think that's really um
helpful and it's maybe sort of like
arguing you know when we like
you know launch rockets we get like
velcro out of that it's like maybe maybe
velcro is like very tangential but at
least for um for me i am very interested
in the velcro part so i'm very excited
thank you
uh chris i think is it yeah go ahead
chris uh my question's for kathy um but
for starters did you say at the
beginning that you're getting into the
fhe space for the first time
yes okay um so that's perfect um
two questions the first is uh can you
tell us a little bit about some of the
applications of aph you've been thinking
about and what do you make of the field
so far overall
right so um some context is i just
changed teams within google to work on
fhe so i'm yeah super new to the space
um i think the math is super fun it's
not very apparent to me
what um applications there are that are
practical right now i think the like
moonshot applications are like if fh is
super practical everyone can like
encrypt all of their data and then have
someone else do computation for them or
even join encrypted computation sets
between like healthcare providers or
anything else that is handling really
sensitive data so that would be really
cool
but i think you know as iran um
mentioned in his uh talk
right now it's really really impractical
and so i think we have many years of
work before we get to a place where like
yeah just you know send your fhe
encrypted data to the cloud and then
like have them do compute for you um
that'll probably
not be something we see for a bit um but
i'm very excited to
work in that direction can i ask a quick
follow-up of course
give me enough money
um is there anything you learned over
the last couple of days that gave you
hope about the practicality of ffhe
i think there are a lot of like
super smart people working on every step
along the way and i think that's like
very exciting and does give me hope
where it's like you know everywhere all
the way down to like different the
hardware level and then all the way up
to like how do we do efficient compiling
from you know generic statements into
different backends and so just seeing
people come together and like
trade ideas and collaborate um
yeah gets me excited about maybe
it's not like a five-year thing maybe
it's like a three-year thing i don't
know um exactly what the timeline looks
like for this to be usable thank you
very much
thanks for the question i have one more
here from the um from the chat and this
may require some interpretation on your
part i'm doing my best so suppose you
have a blob of data
what provides greater security and
cryptography using any cipher to create
cipher text or cryptography using image
steganography to obfuscate the bob
and um sorry if i was giving you evil
works
i don't i only ask the questions i don't
state the questions i i didn't get the
last words there what they are so image
is something a steganography to
obfuscate the book so should we use
steganography or should we use real
cryptography
i feel like this is the wrong audience
to ask if you want a varied answer to
that
we should go through about steganography
next week yes
i think um image steganography may work
in the same way that security through
obscurity works
yeah
you know i i've never seen a
steganography scheme that um would hold
to a
little scrutiny so
i would go with cryptography okay
thanks you and you're also noting i have
nothing to add i agree completely yeah
okay
thank you very much okay simon you have
a question
hi so
we all know that rules law is dead now
uh what does that going to do with
crypto research
can we just continue looking at cool
mars and
go forward with that or do we need to
say we need
to focus more on efficiency and
to support all the new
applications as well
that are emerging into the market
can you say what you said in the
beginning what is it was law sorry it
was law uh the transistors are getting
smaller and smaller
so
i would say why not both there is enough
room for everyone
other panelists want to say anything
no
okay thanks for the question
it is an ema so you can ask anything
me again yep
so you won maybe this time yes um
given that you already have i guess two
winning algorithms in this competitions
what is your pitch right now to get the
third one as a winner too yeah
in the lightweight crypto section this
time
yeah but i think it will not happen this
why not
yeah just that's my feeling
yeah
what are you very much counting on
i'm not counting on it no no
no but i think we just tried to break
better algorithms for the future
yeah and the current
competition is just more like
the current thing but let's try to make
things for the future that's what we try
to do yeah if they pick our thing it's
fine but if they don't
it's too bad but i'm not counting on it
no
shall we bet
shall we bet maybe yeah no i'm not gonna
bet against my own proposal
no i'm not doing that
okay thanks
mateo go ahead
so speaking to the man who gave us shah
3 and as
beside
unpronounceable names what's the secret
ingredient of very strong cryptography
[Music]
that's a difficult question no but
yeah like
yes
the nice thing was that we were already
years
uh
working on it
before this competition started so
vincent and myself and we actually had
already done what they were asking
before they asked it so that was kind of
we had a head start
that was
and for satri i don't know
i don't know
but we also took a long we really
invested a lot of time
and it was like uh
open research so it was not we didn't
have to publish
we were just looking at the crypto so it
was not
we were not under pressure of producing
a psd or having students that have a phd
we could really do free research
and that really helped
and i messed up now a bit because now i
really have all these students that have
to get a phd so i have to publish so we
have to
write papers about stuff but i would
rather do
open research but yeah
so the answer is open research and time
i think so yes but also luck of course
so you must be lucky a bit
to be in the right place at the right
time yeah i work with great people so
because it's not me yeah it's the team
it's with vincent and it's with uh with
jill and mikael and guido
yeah thank you for your answer
thanks so we have a question uh in the
chat here specifically for you val
um what do you think will be the future
of intel sgx
is that what do i think or what do i
hope
so uh intel has uh
stopped producing uh the sjx for uh
the end user and um
there's a lot of speculation on in the
uh
on the internet on why they did that and
probably the
most appealing
answer i think is that
at the end of the day if you have
physical access to a machine that has
enough secrets you will break it
uh
our defenses against physical attacks
tend to put a price on how they attack
how
costly the attack is rather than
probably protect
and
and the original
security guarantees were not
it could not all be in practice
uh so
it seems they are shifting it towards a
towards servers only and in servers
we still have the
assumption that maybe the cloud provider
cannot access the data inside sgx or
so we don't have that guarantee but we
need this guarantee less
and sgx becomes sort of defense in depth
it's another defense mechanism that we
can use if we need slightly more
a lot more protection
so
i believe that it will continue or
something like it will continue because
it serves
an important purpose it does protect us
from
the um
cleaning crew in the
in the cloud providers but
it's not 100 protection as
some people try to sell it to market it
thank you kathy do you want to add
something what's up no just agreeing
yeah
good so i i have a question um
so
we saw these great talks today about how
techniques like prio are very quickly
going from research papers into
production
we also saw in the morning thought a
really wonderful talk about crypto
developers and how they see cryptography
and problems that they really care about
so is the gap between theory and
practice and cryptography narrowing or
is it increasing in size
i think for everybody but yeah kathy
sorry go ahead
maybe there's like a there's like quite
a broad spread even just like talking
within google there's like a large
spread from like now me working on fhe
being like really experimental to like
folks working on more practical things
like mariana talking about
exposure notifications and so i think um
on the side of
uh
folks who are working on things that
have a very clear end use
i do think that that gap is narrowing
but because
there are people working on that and
proving that hey cryptography is like an
interesting technology to invest in
therefore companies are maybe more
willing to take the risk to invest in
things that are longer tail like longer
term investments and so there um maybe
the gap is still very wide
thanks the other panelists some of you
intermediate crypto is narrowing so
because the requirements are much more
real worlds and we build no longer block
cycles but we build authenticated
encryption we look at site channel so i
think it's really improving and the
current landscape is much more much
better than 20 years ago for instance
yeah you got any thoughts i i you really
don't have the um
the the uh
historical view to
i'm not cryptography by uh
trade
okay thanks
uh there's a question in the line uh
i'll just add really quickly um maybe as
a teaser for the talks tomorrow i do
think that um one trend that we're
seeing like in industry is that there's
more of a push for privacy in like data
management so i think like privacy
sandbox is going to talk tomorrow about
that um in the ads ecosystem and meta as
well um and so there is a little bit
more industry push of like we want
interesting cryptography so that we can
keep your data private but still like
extract interesting information for ads
purposes and so that is a big driver of
like you know
applying cryptography and closing that
gap
i'm gonna turn the conversation in
something more practical so
whether your opinion on
passwords versus biometrics
the age-old question
guess you can always change your
password
[Laughter]
any comments from the panel
i find it practical that i can sign with
my finger on my
iphone so that's really practical yeah i
don't know how secure it is but i assume
it's secure enough no i signed a pdf
document the other day by um typing my
name in and then it turned it into
something it looked like writing so is
that a biometric i don't know
it's like okay
you know um
again i don't know much um i i tend to
trust passwords more because i
understand them more i stand where they
can fail more
but
i think that biometrics are
somewhat useful
as john said uh
it's easier than typing a password
easier than remembering a password
but
it's a difficult one what people will
decide i guess
i think maybe for this crowd passwords
are like safer because we understand
that we have to like set good passwords
but maybe for um
like the general population just rolling
out biometrics for like logging in might
result in better security as a whole
um i will add those that i really really
dislike the fingerprint biometrics
because i climb and then after i climb i
can no longer unlock my phone
very annoying so
[Applause]
that's my personal gripe thanks
uh deirdre
hi if
i publish a paper and it gets accepted
to a conference and then some person
goes and implements it and deploys it in
their crypto system and there's a bug is
the program committee that accepted that
paper responsible for those bugs
[Music]
i don't think this but there are people
on the internet who think this
after published
now yeah after publishing
f bugs part of life and uh we have
mistakes and we have whichever science
advances by finding the uh mistakes of
previous works
if you got a proof uh paper and
proofable security and the paper
contains a proof and the paper is
accepted at the conference you would
think that the reviewers have reviewed
the proof
that's not the case yeah and
i was once in the program committee and
i thought this proof is unverifiable it
was so complex and i said yeah i cannot
verify the proof and then another
reviewer said yeah but it looks sure it
looks okay it looks okay let's accept
the paper
but that's a plausible skill that's not
proven
but if it is a proof and and you had a
bang and you have a bug in the proof and
it's incorrect i think that the um
honorable thing to do is to withdraw the
paper not wait for anyone else to
to do it for us yeah
okay did you get an answer i hope so
kinda
okay um there's a there's a question
we're coming to the end now but we have
a question in the chat um
from giorgio nicolas who says you're all
very experienced which means you've seen
more real world horror stories
than most when it comes to the security
and privacy of our data have you ever
dealt with paranoia concerning this and
if so how did you deal with it
i'm not sure about paranoia but tell us
some good war stories what's the worst
thing you've seen in in production or in
a research paper or tell us tell us your
worst horror stories
i've seen some pretty bad things but i
can't talk about them
we have also fixed them so you know
don't worry too much
good
thanks uh do you want to take a crack at
that one i
it's hard to think of a concrete example
at the moment but
you see
that that
it seems that people don't learn i guess
people just keep doing the same mistakes
that we have known about for too long
and
in a sense it's a bit disappointing uh
you know i can't complain it gives a lot
of us
good careers but
it's it is disappointing
things like master keys in a word
document and a banking master key or a
system in the word document that's
somewhere on the on the network and
things like that yeah yeah
so maybe maybe a follow-up question oh
kathy go ahead
oh i think um
one thing that i can mention is like we
have this really cool tradition at
google when you leave the security team
where you can opt into getting your
password stolen
and um and then the security team just
like really gets into it and so i will
say that even with remote work
um they were successful in stealing my
password when i left the team um and and
this it's one of those things of there
are so many interesting ways that you
can break systems and
most of them at least if you're looking
at like successful uh leaving tradition
hacks are not the cryptography a lot of
it's just like the system the key
storage you know very simple uh wrappers
things like that comparison
yeah fishing is sometimes the last
resort but it also gets things done
okay we have uh question the line maybe
this will be the last the last one okay
so
i've heard several times the word
privacy or privacy depending how you
want to pronounce this uh how do you
define privacy
it's philosophical
very loaded question
it depends who you ask and what their
motivations are
you ryan do you want to take a bite at
that one how do you define privacy yes
uh yeah i have it on a slide because we
are teaching security the first year
students and i don't i cannot remember
it now
but
yeah they asked our students to uh to
provide an answer to that at the exam so
i would fail at my own examination you
just take all of their answers and then
you average the results yeah that's what
we do yeah that's then that's your
definition of privacy yeah okay maybe um
i'll ask one more question since i think
we have 30 seconds left so there's a
truism in cryptography that you should
never roll your own cryptography right
this is something you know you shouldn't
design your own blog cipher
um and now we have to think about the
protocol level you shouldn't roll your
own protocol so who should
[Music]
um actually deirdre's got a really great
podcast
uh cryptography security whatever where
she spends a whole podcast episode
answering this question and i think the
takeaway is like
someone has to do this in the end and
maybe the best thing that we can do is
say
you should give it a shot but you should
get it peer reviewed bring a friend
basically make sure you get a lot of
eyes of people who have done this before
successfully
that can take a look and that way we're
not filtering people by confidence but
rather by actual competence
is that an okay summary
okay great
i certainly think it's true that the the
dunning-krieger effect you know is is
alive and well in cryptography um so you
and did you want to say something no no
no okay i was just accepting the mic
okay then i think that's a great place
to leave it because there should be a
reception very soon just remains to
thank all of our panelists for being so
game and thank you so much