thank you frederick so let's have a look
at the designs that we used in the
private analytics system in exposure
notifications
as we already mentioned it was important
for us to work to use a work that is
well recognized
and meets our privacy and robustness
requirements for the system
for this reason we chose to use the
system prio which is a private robust
and scalable computation of aggregate
statistics and it was introduced by
henry corrigan gibbs and dan bonnet in
nsdi 2017.
this is a multi-party computation system
which distributes the trust among two
parties that are jointly computing the
aggregation
this system protects individual
contributions and guarantees that only
aggregated data is revealed as an output
a useful property for this system was
that it was compatible with various
differential privacy mechanisms which
helped us achieve our goal to provide
differential privacy for the outputs
this system protects against malicious
users that are trying to skew the output
of the computation and render it useless
in particular it guarantees that the
most a malicious user can do is cheat
about their own input within some
allowable range
and if you have been a regular attendee
of real-world crypto you have seen this
system used in another context
in collecting firefox telemetry
for
another application
so the prio system architecture relies
on two aggregation servers that jointly
compute the final outputs
and the privacy guarantees of the system
rely on the assumption of non-collusion
which says that these two servers are
run by two independent parties which
will not put together the data that they
see during the execution of the
computation
we will discuss later in the talk uh who
are the two parties that run the
aggregation servers for exposure
notifications private analytics
so how does a user contribute input in
this aggregate measurement system
in our system the input of a user is a
binary vector
which is split in several fixed length
sub vectors that correspond to the
different metrics that we collect
each sub vector
is a representation of the of a
partition of the range for the value for
this particular metric and the client
contributes in the bucket that
corresponds to their
own value
so in this example we see the metric of
the severity of the exposure
notification and here the client is
contributing input which says that they
have received exposure notification with
severity level three
once the client has prepared their input
to this binary vector what they do is
they compute two cryptographic shares of
this input and the properties of these
cryptographic shares are that if you
look at only one of them it is
indistinguishable from random numbers
and only when you put together these two
shares you can reconstruct the input
in addition to the two cryptographic
shares of its input value the client
also computes a cryptographic a
distributed cryptographic proof which
shows that they provided a valid input
where valid input here is defined as
binary input and the way this proof
works is that it shows that each entry
in this vector satisfies a degree two
polynomial which has roots zero and one
so the client computes the shares of its
input and the shares of this distributed
proof and sends them to the two
aggregation servers
in the aggregation phase the two servers
can jointly verify the range proof and
for all contributions that pass this
verification they can aggregate their
respective shares and thus
obtain
shares of the output which can be
provided to the designated output
receiver
as we also mentioned
our goal was to provide differential
privacy for the final output and the way
we chose to achieve this in our system
is by leveraging a technique that
amplifies the differential privacy
guarantees using the aggregation that's
already happening on the shares
so what happens in this system is that
each client adds a small amount of noise
to their input and in particular when we
have this binary vector input so what
this means is that the client flips with
a small probability each entry of the
vector and then
the aggregation step amplifies this
noise and provides the final
differential privacy properties for the
output
so let's look again at the goals for the
private analytics system and how we
achieve them with this design
so first we minimize the collection of
the data by collecting only metrics that
[Music]
answer specific
health authority questions
in terms of privacy this architecture
guarantees that we release only
aggregate and differentially private
outputs
in terms of
integrity of the data that is provided
we use the range proof that i already
mentioned and also device attestation
techniques which i will describe a
little later in the presentation
of course to scale this system to
millions of users and constantly
streaming data it was very important to
choose an efficient solution and in this
respect this design is a single shot
solution from the perspective of the
clients they contribute only once
in the system and don't need to be
involved any more in the computation all
the heavy lifting of the computation is
performed by these two servers
and even in that aspect this computation
requires only a single communication
round between the servers
last but not least we had this common
solution between google and apple which
was our goal
so now that we have an idea about the
cryptographic
designs behind this protocol let's look
at the specific instantiation of these
designs that we used in our
implementation and deployment
so taking these designs into a system
that
works on constantly streaming data and
serves millions of devices
daily
required coordination of many moving
parts
first we needed to decide who will be
the the parties the independent parties
that will run the two servers that will
satisfy the trust model for our system
we also had to decide how we will enable
health authorities and users to be able
to choose whether they want to
participate in the private analytics
system
we needed to design an architecture that
collects
stores and processes this amount of data
we had to take decisions on whether we
want to do further authentication of the
data that is coming from devices
what parties we needed to require to be
online all of the time and which parts
of the computation could be performed
asynchronously offline
in terms of the aggregation servers
there were requirements for code
development and also choice of
infrastructure on which the protocol
would be executed
we had to make different choices of
concrete parameters for the
instantiations of the different schemes
and consider different tradeoffs related
to the differential privacy tradeoffs
finally when we had
all of the components and an end-to-end
system we had to decide how we will be
able to debug and verify that the system
is working correctly
so let me start by telling you uh who
are the two parties that run this system
in our us deployment the two aggregation
servers are run by the internet security
research group which after this morning
you should be well acquainted with
this is a california public benefit
corporation for digital infrastructure
projects and as we heard isrg operates
let's encrypt
the second aggregation server is run by
the national cancer institute at the
national institutes of health which is
an agency of the us department of health
and human services
these were two parties that are
independent and were already operating
in the public sphere for public benefit
the servers the two aggregation servers
are built on kubernetes and are running
on two distinct cloud providers
in order to facilitate the access of
health authorities to this aggregate and
differentially private data
we also provided a web portal that
gives nice graphical representation of
the final outputs that health
authorities can easily consume
and this web portal is
maintained and run by the mitre
corporation which is a non-for-profit
organization
in our system we added one additional
party which we refer to as an ingestion
server
the need for this party came from the
desire to be able to do additional
authentication on the data coming from
clients and in particular we wanted to
be able to aggregate only data coming
from real devices
in order to achieve this goal we wanted
to use device attestation techniques
which both google and apple offer for
their respective operating systems
so in our architecture google and apple
run their own
ingestion servers these are the only
parties that are required to be online
all the time
this ingestion servers receive encrypted
data under the keys of the two
aggregation
servers
they perform the device attestation
checks and filter data that is coming
from real devices
they additionally remove any metadata
such as ip addresses and time stamps
and then they batch and forward these
authenticated shares to the two
aggregation servers
in our system the ingestion servers also
generate the randomness that is used in
the verification of the distributed
range proofs if you're familiar with the
prio system uh the ingestion server is
generating the random point
that is used for the polynomial identity
test
so thus we
had this design which is of an
asynchronous system that consists of the
three following
stages
the first we have the data collection
where the injection servers receive
encrypted data
run
device attestation strip metadata and
then they periodically write the
authentication batched
batches of contributions to a shared
storage with the
aggregation servers
in the second phase the data aggregation
the two servers read periodically from
this shared storage
they process the data
which includes
decryption verification of the proofs
and then aggregation
and then they forward their aggregate
parts to miter
every eight hours
in the final stage of the computation
which is the data consumption
miter sums up what it has received from
the two aggregation servers and presents
a 24-hour view of the final aggregated
and differentially private data to the
health authorities
now if we want to put all of the parties
involved in the system in the same
figure will have
the ios and the android devices that are
sending data to the two ingestion
servers run by
apple and google respectively and then
those servers are forwarding encrypted
shares to the isrg and the nih
aggregation servers and finally the
outputs are reconstructed by miter and
presented
to the each state health
authority so in our system we have two
levels of consent
first a health authority that wants to
take advantage of the aggregate private
analytics uh needs to opt in into that
and the way they do this is by signing a
contract with mitre who is running uh
the web portal on their behalf
the second level of consent that we do
is for the user each user has the option
to select whether they want to
contribute their inputs in this private
analytics system
so
the
exposure notifications private analytics
system has been deployed since december
2020 and it has been running since then
it is currently operating on four in 14
u.s states and four
mexican states it is collecting nine
distinct metrics and the aggregation
servers are processing millions of
devices contributions every day
the washington state health authority
used the data
produced by the exposure notifications
private analytics to conduct a study
that estimated
the number of lives that were saved and
the number of infections that were
prevented by the exposure notification
system
this was a very gratifying to see the
output of our
system used for this type of study
if you want to learn more about the
specific designs that we used in enpa
you can have a look at our white paper
and now i'm going to pass on to tim who
will tell us more about the challenges
that we faced in the development and
deployment of the system
thank you mariana
okay let's dive right in so the first
problem that we tackled was establishing
uh trusted channels between all the
protocol participants uh there's two
distinct challenges here uh the first is
bootstrapping trust between the servers
and then there's the trickier challenge
of distribution of the aggregator's
encryption keys to the millions of
clients the mobile devices in particular
we wanted to enable revocation of
encryption keys
so the server server case was solved
relatively straightforwardly by
bootstrapping trust from the web pki
each server fetches the security
parameters for all of its peers over
https this is things like mailbox
addresses or public keys
so the web pki gives us well-defined
mechanisms for the issuance revocation
and even transparency of certificates
which bind a public key to some server's
identity so it's very tempting to use it
uh to also solve the problem of
distributing encryption keys
uh we learned that
doing this however is inadvisable
the reason is that if you issue a
certificate whose extended key usage
field says server auth but then you use
it for something that isn't tls such as
the encryption scheme that was used in
the npa
the result is
only borderline acceptable under ca
browser forums baseline requirements
which is the set of standards that
govern the issuance of certificates in
the web pki
um further
this kind of technically okay but now
really intended usage of the web pki
makes it harder for that community to
improve and clarify standards in the
future
to make the web safer for everyone
so in the end we opted to
issue certificates over the over the
encryption keys from an apple controlled
ca that is trusted by mobile devices for
the specific application
but not generally trusted by web
browsers and it's not subject to ca
browser form requirements
um so our recommendations here are to be
very careful when you work with the web
pki uh it and tls are obviously
remarkable achievements but their design
is uh
very much tailored to the to the web and
it's surprisingly easy to find yourself
outside of the use cases that are well
supported by those technologies
fortunately anybody can solicit advice
from the top experts in this field
simply by posting ideas or questions to
the mozilla dev security policy mailing
list which is always a good idea if
you're about to do something a little
bit unusual with the web pki
so going forward it's clear that mpc
systems are going
to want secure and transparent systems
for distribution of keys and other
security parameters and ideally ones
that feature some kind of a parameter
commitment scheme
we can learn we should learn a lot from
the experience of the web pki here but
it may be wise to instantiate distinct
pkis that are tailored to these uh mpc
applications
okay
the next big challenge was deploying
this across multiple clouds
early on in the project we decided that
in order to mitigate the risk of any one
organization being able to see both sets
of input shares and thus defeat privacy
we would run each of the two aggregators
on a distinct public cloud namely amazon
web services and the google cloud
platform so right off the bat that meant
that the aggregation server
implementation had to be portable across
the two clouds which takes non-trivial
extra effort that has to be accounted
for when planning engineering work
um also early on in the project we were
concerned that the batches of inputs
being transmitted from the ingestion
servers to the aggregators would be on
the order of hundreds of megabytes
perhaps too large to fit reasonably in
an http request body
so to make things easier for the
aggregators we decided that we would
instead use aws s3 and google cloud
storage buckets as mailboxes in an
asynchronous messaging scheme now the
trade-off there is that this meant we
had to figure out how to get workloads
running in one cloud to securely access
resources that are hosted in the other
now the good news is that it is possible
to do this and without actually sharing
any secrets between the two deployments
uh and i do think we should you know
acknowledge the this because it had to
have taken a ton of work on the part of
security teams at aws and gcp to make
this possible that being said the
resulting authentication flows can be
pretty complicated so we illustrate this
on the right hand side with a sequence
diagram that shows how a workload
running in amazon's elastic kubernetes
service might go about obtaining a
credential that would let it say
download an object from a google cloud
storage bucket
um we don't have time to get into all
the details of this and it would be cool
of me to expect you to actually read all
the text there but the upshot here is
that in order to get a credential that
ultimately lets you do something like
download an object from a bucket you
have to perform four different
credential exchanges each of which
involves an rpc to some remote identity
service um each one exchanging you know
one identity token for the next in a
chain
now all of those token exchanges those
credential exchanges exist for a good
reason because each represents
a meaningful transition across from one
security domain to another further the
performance overhead from getting all of
these is essentially negligible because
the token that you end up with can be
cached for some configurable period
something on the order of an hour
what's concerning here though is that to
get all this to work properly you're
going to have to go configure i am roles
and service accounts and oidc identity
providers and for each of those things
you have to carefully construct this
magic string that allows a running
application to exchange token n for
token n plus one in the chain
and each one of these is an opportunity
to get something wrong and leave a
security hole in your deployment that
would uh possibly defeat the purpose of
all this uh you know novel privacy
preserving cryptography that we've got
so our recommendations here are um to
try as hard as you can to use simple
synchronous messaging schemes say based
on http request response if as in fact
wound up being the case for us the
availability requirements that are
imposed by message sizes and request
rates make that kind of a design
feasible because if you can do that then
you're going to be in a position to
abstract away all the cloud primitives
used by any given service implementation
which will significantly reduce your
exposed api surface and make your
deployments quite a bit easier
going forward um mpc deployments are
going to continue to be interested in uh
multi-season diversity in cloud
platforms and compute platforms in order
to better uphold the privacy guarantees
based on non-collusion and that's not to
mention all of the other reasons that so
many organizations have an interest in
multi-cloud deployments nowadays so for
that reason uh simpler tools for the
configuration and auditing of
cross-cloud identity federation and
permissions are going to prove quite
valuable
the last challenge that we're going to
discuss today is the testing of such
systems
now end-to-end integration testing and
distributed systems is always very
challenging but it's even harder in an
mpc setting where any test that you run
has to be done across multiple
organizations
that don't share a deploy system or even
a calendar server and then it's even
acutely more difficult than a privacy
preserving system like this because if
you were to have uh invalid or corrupt
intermediate products from the process
they're deliberately indistinguishable
from correct values
so in
mpa setting up an end-to-end integration
test required setting up two devices to
simulate an exposure from one to the
other an ingestion server and two
aggregators so any such test spans at a
minimum three different organizations
that have to coordinate deployments and
verification
um we also found that we had to produce
uh uh special uh builds of the clients
that enabled us to disable certain
features like differential privacy uh in
order to make the outputs predictable in
test or experimental settings
so when working on a system like this
consider that your usual integration
test practices may not be sufficient uh
one thing that may come up is that you
may need to test
the staging instance of your server
against a peer server or against clients
that cannot get on your vpn you're going
to want to start working with your
security and networking teams on this
sooner rather than later
besides that think ahead on your test
plans as we did you're going to want to
create a custom clients that disable
certain privacy features and also
consider driving test inputs from a seed
that you record somewhere so that you
can repeat experiments and predict what
the expected value of an aggregation or
the output of a process will be
um finally consider that your debugging
challenges don't end once you've
deployed the system because when
incidents occur and in distributed
systems incidents always occur
you're going to want to be able to
quickly isolate diagnose and address
problems that arise
so this requires
a robust and principled approach to
continuous verification of correctness
of the system as well as observability
so that's uh metrics and alerting on on
your system to see how they're working
you're also going to want to establish
procedures for responding to incidents
and crucially
good communication channels with all
your partners because dealing with these
problems is usually going to require a
close uh coordination with people who
are outside of your immediate
organization that is you know people who
are not on your own slack
so
to wrap up um
we've presented the exposure
notifications private analytics system
whose purpose is to evaluate the
effectiveness of exposure notification
using privacy-preserving measurement of
epidemiological metrics
we believe that this work demonstrates
the viability of mpc at scales
sufficient to address real world
problems
this project involved about 30 people
across five different institutions
it took about six months from the
initial idea to the first production
deployment which was in the american
state of maryland in december 2020.
since then we've scaled the system to
serve to serve a population of tens of
millions of users across the united
states and internationally
and in the united states alone we've
aggregated over 22 billion individual
metrics
so we've got all this great cryptography
and now we have some actual experience
of building and operating systems but
use it
what remains is challenges of education
we have to figure out how to make the
privacy protecting properties of these
systems cogent to both end users that's
someone whose phone is asking them
whether they want to participate in a
system like enpa as well as potential
adopters uh think here of a regional
public health authority that is
considering whether to offer enpa to the
population that they serve
um
so we believe that this challenge will
be aided although not you know not
completely solved but aided by efforts
to standardize privacy-preserving npc
techniques which will also help with
interoperability of implementations and
transparency
um so there's a number of efforts to
this end going on in a number of
industry bodies uh so there's a
community group a two in w3c there's at
least one competition on going at nist i
believe and if you'd like to learn more
about one such protocol that's currently
being designed through the internet
engineering task force then you can stay
right where you are for the very next
session which we'll get into detail on
the privacy preserving measurements
protocol
that's it thanks very much
thank you very much we're ever so
slightly over time but if there is a
quick question or two i think we can
make time for it so please come to the
mic if you have a question
step right up
please make your question short if you
can yes i was wondering if you guys uh
took stable attacks into account
i think this is uh hand out with the
device attestation that we're doing at
that level we are doing as much as
we can
thanks for the talk uh you mentioned
that there were some issues using the
webpick air for mpc and that you would
like to see something different can you
elaborate a bit on that
well i don't have a design in hand for
you but um you know the idea is that if
you
so you know in this system for instance
this deployment we knew exactly who was
participating right it's apple google
isrg and the nci and miter so it's not
that hard to do like out of band um set
up a basic parameters right but you know
looking forward to the general
deployment of systems like this
uh i think i think an important goal is
going to be interoperability right so
consider like a general purpose privacy
preserving measurements um i don't know
what's called an ecosystem you know if
you're some service and you want to
gather metrics while respecting people's
privacy it's nice to be able to say go
to like a marketplace of a ton of
different aggregator operators you pick
two and you start aggregating metrics
so if you have a space where there's you
know who knows how many different
operators out there um there anything we
can do to make it as easy as possible
for like my implementation of you know
free and other algorithms to
interoperate smoothly with yours um
well yeah i just feel that like some
some pki that addresses this but isn't
as tightly bound to the to the web uh
will be valuable
thank you
okay last question from the room go
ahead uh what epsilon and delta values
did you get for the differential privacy
part
for differential privacy the what
epsilon and delta values did you get
there
uh we were aiming for epsilon one
okay yeah at the final output level
okay thank you
and we have time for one question from
the chat so uh alexander asks is there
any data you can share about the
likelihood of users to voluntarily
participate in such a system so what
kind of user adoption rates do you see
in as much as you can say
maybe apple and google can answer
separately
yeah
we we don't have the numbers here so
can't really uh we can get back to you
on that no problem
22 billion items is significant number
of items so there's obviously some
participation going on i think this was
something that we consider the privacy
uh metric that apple and google do not
know we are not collecting this
information
okay thank you very much let's thank all
the speakers again thank you
and we'll move right on to the next talk
uh which is very much part two
and uh i think the talk is going to be
given by chris patton
from cloudflare if i recall that's right
yep please go ahead chris as soon as
you're ready thanks all right so i'll
try to make this a little short because
i know we're a little short on time for
starters i'm going to
shorten exposure notifications private
analytics to enpa i'm going to just
uh save a bunch of time that way okay
um
so i'm gonna start this off with um what
i think is uh one underlying premise of
the previous talk which is that
operating a large complex service often
requires measuring certain aspects of
user behavior in order to understand how
to make that system better
but in many cases we don't actually use
individual measurements what we care
about is aggregated data
and of course collecting these
individual measurements is dangerous
because they're privacy sensitive often
times
so we want to do anything that we can to
avoid seeing them in the clear
now what the enpa system we just heard
about demonstrates at least one thing
that it demonstrates
is that a practical way to solve this
problem
to improve privacy is to distribute the
computation of the aggregate among
multiple servers using for example the
prio system
but of course empa was designed with a
specific use case in mind stepping aback
a little bit um what it's basically
useful for is aggregating bit vectors
um and that's pretty useful already you
can imagine a lot of different ways of
adapting that system but what about
other types of aggregates things like
simple statistics what's the mean
standard deviation of the distribution
of the input say
um
or you might be other interested in
other related questions so uh what are
the most commonly occurring bit strings
among my set of inputs for example
um and the good news is that we've seen
a lot of uh really great work in the
cryptographic literature
presenting a variety of mpc techniques
for these problems and a lot others like
them
but one thing you notice about this
literature is that the design goals for
these papers often vary quite
significantly
often starting off with different
security objectives and ending up with
very different protocol designs
and having different shapes and
different architectures
what we think is missing is our clearly
defined design criteria that would
provide a roadmap to deployment
so what i want to do today is introduce
you to the ietf's initial attempt to
provide one such roadmap
and this work really began in earnest
earlier this year as we formed a working
group
whose stated objective is to standardize
multi-party computation techniques for
the purpose of privacy preserving
measurement
what we mean here is we want to develop
technologies that allow one to uh
aggregate privacy sensitive data without
seeing individual measurements
and the types of aggregates we're after
are are wide-ranging
from simple statistics to we would very
much like to be able to support machine
learning machine learning applications
that
people need for different purposes
the main criterion here is that what
you're after the aggregation function
you want to compute needs to be specific
and in particular we're not looking to
standardize or we're not looking to just
uh anonymize data without also
aggregating it
and also um we're just as an aside we're
not looking to use some general purpose
mpc technique for this application
so um what i'll do today is give you an
overview how this work has played out so
far we're early on we have a long way to
go but we've made some great progress
and i'm going to start off with by
looking at some of the candidate
constructions that we've been kicking
around and talk about why we think
they're interesting why they make sense
for standardization
and then i'm going to give you a very
brief overview of the sort of of the
framework that we've built up around
these protocols
and the road map to deployment that we
envision
okay
so when we started off uh thinking about
how to do this work uh over a year ago
now our initial goal was to just uh
standardize prio
not just because we've had some
deployment experience with it with enpa
and other applications
but also there's just a ton of different
things you can do with it so what i want
to start off with is
i want to elaborate on the capabilities
of prio going uh beyond what we saw in
the previous talk
so um i want to to make this concrete i
want to have a sort of running example
to to work with
um so let's imagine you're a website
operator and you want to understand
something about the uh
the uh your users experience in
particular uh whether or not users are
experiencing higher than expected
latency when they say load a certain
page
of course there's lots of different ways
to refine this question which we're
going to do as we move along
all right
in so
this is hopefully will look familiar to
all of you who since you just learned a
little bit about prio so i'll go through
this very quickly
so we start off with a bunch of
measurements and in prio our primary
tool for protecting them is simply
additive secret sharing so uh where each
client begins by encoding its
measurement as a vector over some finite
field and then we're going to split that
vector into
multiple secret shares and
distribute these secret shares amongst
the aggregation servers
and what's the aggregation once an
aggregator has received enough input
shares from enough clients it's just
going to sum them up to get a share of
the aggregate result and it'll just send
this to some data collection endpoint
and on all that collector has to do is
sum up the aggregate shares to get the
final aggregate result
so um the thing i want to point out
about prio here is that the aggregation
function that's computed is simply the
sum of the encoded measurements and
it turns out that there's a lot of
useful aggregation functions that can be
expressed in just this way
so
remember that in the enpa system what we
saw is basically
uh
vectors of counter so each user has
either a one or a zero and we want to
just compute the sum
so this already uh gives us one way of
understanding uh our the
the uh the performance of our website
right so you might imagine you just have
each client report after they load a
page
whether or not loading that page took uh
a particularly long time say more than
half a second or something like that
but of course you might want to know
something about the distribution of the
load times
so
prio for example will allow you to
compute simple statistics like the mean
standard deviation and so on um or you
can estimate the distribution more or
less directly using a histogram uh
kind of in the way you would imagine
doing that
and and you could do lots of other
fancier stuff with prio so for example
suppose you wanted to understand the uh
the load time as a function
of the uh the distance from the client
to the server um that's something you
can do with prio you can frame that as a
linear regression problem so yeah
there's lots of different possibilities
here
it's simply a matter of figuring out how
to encode your measurements so that the
aggregation function can be expressed as
a sum of the encoded measurements
of course the uh
key problem that we have to solve and uh
is deciding whether a set of input
shares uploaded by a client sum up to
some valid uh input otherwise it's
always possible for the uh the client to
just send secret shared garbage and cr
and corrupt the entire computation
um so how do we solve this problem in
prio while still
uh
providing so many
uh providing support for so many
different uh aggregation functions
um well this is where the details really
get interesting
as was mentioned in the previous talk
there's this is going to require some
amount of interaction among the
aggregators in order to do this input
validation and for the sake of time i'm
going to skip the details i just want to
note quickly for those familiar with the
prio system
we ended up what the proof system that
we ended up wanting to specify and
standardize is based on a paper from
crypto 2019 which improves upon the
original prio system in many different
ways
so um that's prio in a nutshell
you could use it to solve a lot of
different data aggregation problems
but of course it's not going to be well
suited for every use case
and i want to give an example
and to illustrate it let's refine our
question about latency a little bit
suppose we now want to know from where
in the world are users experiencing high
latency and in particular from which
autonomous systems
um
now uh this question can be framed as an
instance of the uh heavy hitters problem
so here we have a multi-set of
arbitrary bit strings uploaded by
clients and we want to know how many of
these strings occurred at least t times
for some threshold t
um okay so one way of solving this
problem is the poplar protocol
which was presented at ieee snp last
year
um so the uh key idea the key uh
the key to this the popular protocol is
this new primitive called an incremental
distributed point function or idpf
so i want to kind of illustrate how the
idpf solves this heavy hitter problem
all right and um
and to do that let's uh let's pick a
distribution so let's say that this
is the distribution of high latency
pings that you get to uh your website so
here each red dot represents the
location of a client uh when they
reported that uh they loading the page
took a particularly long time um
okay
and let's uh for the sake of
illustration let's also imagine there
are just 16 autonomous systems worldwide
and that they arrange across the globe
in in roughly this way
so each cell of this table represents an
autonomous system uh and you can see
that we've given each a unique four bit
identifier so what a client reports is
basically one of these strings the the
identity of the as that they were in
when the bad thing happened that we want
to measure
okay
so idpfs don't solve the heavy headers
problem directly what they do is do is
solve a simpler problem
so
what it what it allows you to do is
count the number of strings that begin
with a given prefix so for example we
can count how many uh inputs begin with
a zero or a one which already gives us a
little bit of insight into our data but
doesn't uh but you know we're going to
want to drill down on it a little bit
further
and we can naturally extend this of
course to count the number of strings
that begin with each 2-bit prefix and
each 3-bit prefix and so on
now as we drill down on the data this
way what we start to realize is we can
eliminate certain say sets of as's as
potential sources of heavy hitters and
that's simply because the hit counts for
the corresponding prefixes are below our
target threshold
so um we can we can extend this idea one
one bit further
um and what we end up with at the end of
the day is the set of uh
uh strings that occurred at least as
many times as our target threshold this
is our heavy hitters
okay so
what i want you to notice about this
idpf evaluation process is that it has a
remarkably remarkably similar shape to
prio
clients begin by splitting their
measurements into input shares and
distributing these amongst the
aggregators the aggregators will query
these input shares on a set of candidate
prefixes
uh getting a set of out of output shares
um and then uh the aggregators will need
to interact with one another in order to
make sure that the output shares are
well formed
but once they've done that all all these
servers collectively have to do is sum
up these output shares to get the hit
count for each candidate prefix
now there's one wrinkle here to solve
the heavy hitters problem we're going to
have to allow the collector to interact
with the aggregators over multiple
rounds where in each round we compute
the next set of candidate prefixes
all right if that didn't make any sense
don't worry
this is the point
where we've arrived is a sort of high
level architecture for the distributed
computation of some aggregation function
where we have some aggregation parameter
i.e the set of candidate prefixes um a
set of measurements and um the uh what
it outputs is the aggregate that we're
after
and of course we built this around prio
in poplar but our hope is that lots of
interesting and useful papers fit into
this framework
now a good example is prio plus which
fits quite neatly uh and
you can sort of think of this as an
alternative to prio that that um uses
different npc techniques that uh leads
to different trade-offs that uh for
deployments um and this is you know the
sort of the thing that we would
absolutely want to make room for in a
standard it should be possible to trade
uh like client time complexity for
server communication costs etc
um
and uh of course there's uh lots of uh
interesting papers out there that share
similar ideas but don't quite fit in
here and a good example of this is the
masked lark paper from microsoft
research that came out last year where
the goal is to compute gradient descent
in a privacy preserving manner while
still being extremely lightweight and
easy to implement
um and their their system also uses
secret sharing but they don't try to
validate the secret shared data in any
way um like we would do in prio or
poplar
and not all of the the uh privacy
sensitive data ends up getting secret
shared so we would like to uh but but it
raises an interesting question of
whether gradient descent can be computed
uh in a way that's fully private and
verifiable
and also that fits into this overall
architecture
but regardless of the answer here the
the the thing i want you to take away is
that there are a lot of different secure
aggregation problems we can solve in
this setting um but not every problem is
going to have the same solution
what we expect to happen is that
protocols will continue to be tailored
to particular problems and that's okay
but we do need to make sure of a couple
things one that these schemes all meet
some baseline security requirements
and also that they have a similar enough
shape that it's possible to build
applications around them
so in that spirit the name that we've
given for this uh basic mpc shape is a
verifiable distributed aggregation
function or vdf so these are uh these
are will be specified in this internet
draft we're working on i've linked it
here the goal of this draft is basically
to lay out the design criteria for new
constructions um and also to kind of
define the api boundary that
applications can expect which would
allow them to build uh application
allows us to build applications that are
agnostic to whatever aggregation
function it is you want to compute
one such application is the ppm protocol
the uh
the namesake of the the ppm working
group um and the goal of this draft is
to spell out exactly how one would
evaluate a vdf over https and along the
way it has uh it addresses a number of
operational considerations and we will
also have additional security
considerations on top of those for vdas
including providing uh defenses for
civil attacks uh and also supporting
different differential privacy so that's
the lay of the land thank you all for
listening uh if you think this work is
interesting or important we would love
to have your participation uh for
starters please join the ppm mailing
list and get involved
i there are
the two drafts that i talked about there
are currently calls for adoption out for
both so one thing you can do to help
with this work is to read these drafts
and endorse them on the list if indeed
they're worthy of your endorsement
thank you very much and i'm happy to
take questions if i have time
[Applause]
thanks chris i see we have a question
already go ahead
hi uh thank you for the really great
talk um
i guess i have a question sort of about
failure so um these proofs are
basically all the clients upload their
uh secret shared data and the proof that
the data is falls within whatever range
that the data is acceptable for and i
assume right now uh in the design these
proofs are verified with every batch
that's uploaded i'm curious like have
you considered doing something like
uh verification and identification of
cheaters
uh
after
uh identifying that a failure has
actually occurred so like for example
you could send all the data to the
aggregator check to see if it's within
whatever like global range and then uh
verify on failure so just to be clear
the data the thing that we verify is
whether a single set of input shares is
valid basically it some if we aggregated
it would it corrupt the computation so
the the thing that's proved only
pertains to one input if that makes
sense
right but the question is have you
thought about uh aggregating everything
seeing if the if the batch overall is
correct and then identifying the the
cheating oh
yeah um
yeah i mean uh
yeah there's that's a whole that's a
whole bag of worms and i'd like to talk
to you about it in detail if you if you
don't mind later
okay thank you for that question
um let me ask one more slightly
provocative um we saw in the previous
talk that cryptography in the end was a
very small component of the overall
functioning system there were so many
other pieces required
and to build something that was actually
useful why do you think a standard in
this space is going to help
yeah i mean
so i think
i think that there are
um
one thing is that i think one of my
takeaways from the previous talk and
basically conversations with tim is that
it's useful to abstract away the cloud
primitives um and it's useful to build a
protocol that's sort of agnostic to
those
because you don't want to have to just
rely on gcp or just rely on aws or just
rely on cloudflare
and another thing is that
we
there's this problem of like
the the solution is often specific to
the problem and we need to make room for
that so i do think it's helpful
uh that there there be a standard this
is what the vdf spec is supposed to
fulfill there should be a standard that
says this is the shape of the solution
for those who want to you know go work
on on this problem that you know yeah
okay thank you very much
let's thank the speaker again very good
and we'll move on now to the third talk
in the session uh which is a remote talk
so i think if we can
get some help from the back of the room
hopefully we can get some av up and
running
so this talk is about oblivious message
retrieval and uh the speaker is aaron
tromer who should be online
do start thinking about your questions
for the ama session if we can't find
iran it might be short starting sooner
than planned
if someone from the av team could give
me a wave to indicate that they're
working on this that would be tremendous
okay thanks
here we go here's the slides
[Music]
hello am i visible in audible
uh hello erin um you're not visible yet
but you're certainly audible
i'm curious
i do believe my video is on ah we can
see
a little black box at the top of the
screen i don't know if that's
the little black box is most likely the
zoom controls um if you don't have
anything at the top of your slides it
should not be an issue
oh but it's no longer
okay here he is aaron take it away thank
you very much
thank you uh it's uh it's an honor to be
here both for me and for my antibodies
and i i'm delighted to be able to tell
you about the current work that i'm
doing with my student at columbia
university zarya neo
about oblivious message retrieval
so our work is motivated by the problem
of anonymous message delivery systems
like
a signal and what's up for messages or
monero and zcash for
payments
and more generally systems that try to
convey some kind of payload for
recipients to from centers to recipients
in a privacy-preserving way
now this is a large well-studied problem
and it has many facets
in particular numerous works on
sending privacy
how to hide the identity of the standing
party
that includes both the content and the
machinery by which the message is
appended to some kind of joint ledger
uh there also works on how to keep the
ledger itself private and avoiding the
broadcast of information
um and uh there are systems like apple
horn that combine these and show how to
route messages
uh
after a secure connection establishment
or dialing
but all of these culminate in a
situation where you have a large
bulletin containing all of those
encrypted messages was route to the
bulletin was hidden and now the
recipients need to collect those and the
question remains how can the recipients
collect that information without
leaking what they are retrieving
so the simplest solution is for the
recipient to just download the whole
bulletin
maybe scan the whole blockchain as is
customary in some legacy chains and uh
that is obviously too expensive in
bandwidth and also in computation
especially for limited clients and large
bulletins
so it seems inevitable that we would
have a model where there is some kind of
server let's call it a detector that
fetches messages from the bulletin
and somehow produces a digest of those
messages that are pertinent to the
recipient or the digest is much much
smaller than the full bulletin and
easier to uh to process
there are several recent works that
tackle this in concrete applications um
one widely deployed is the zcash
lite client protocol that
basically compresses the full bulletin
into just the pertinent part of its
speech transaction for
what amounts to a trial decryption
um however that is still linear in the
size of the bulletin and therefore does
not scale well and there are there is
analysis in the z cash community of how
expensive and impractical this is
there is a recent work that tackled this
problem heads on called fuzzy message
detection
and that css 21 paper
after defining the problem uh suggests a
solution based on decoys basically
inducing
a false positives in the trial
decryption intentionally
in order for many of the messages that
are
detected by the detector
using the trial decryption done on
behalf of the recipient making many of
those be messages that are not truly
pertinent
so the detector knows what are the
messages um that are pertinent to the
recipient plus a bunch of decoys and
that provides some level of privacy
but not very strong privacy because for
example anything that is not
detected by the detector is
automatically ruled out as a pertinent
message and that by itself already
allows for fairly devastating active
attacks
as well as statistical deductions
um furthermore this scheme is uh
implicitly assuming that the
the senders and the recipients are
honest in how they generate their keys
so
uh the security notion is weak
furthermore uh another
recent work uh private signaling
tackles a similar problem in a slightly
different model but the differences are
insignificant in our context
and we suggest two different schemes
one is based on
trusted hardware so the first private
signaling scheme has a trusted sgx
enclave run by server
that is entrusted with users effectively
trial decryption keys
and uh
the as the security model is as you
would expect from transmit hardware in
the uh break once
violate everyone's privacy model
furthermore it also assumes other
centers and recipients
and lastly the other private signaling
scheme from the same paper
replaces the sjx enclave by a
multi-party computation
which avoids the trust in hard work but
it does assume that the participants in
that multi-party detector even though
they are ongoing in ongoing
communication they never collude at
least one of them is not merely honest
but curious but actually never leaks
anything
and that again is a strong assumption uh
and furthermore uh there is uh the
assumption that unders
the recipient
of honest recipients and senders
so what we aim to do is to improve the
efficiency and the privacy properties
and achieve an oblivious message
retrieval scheme
that is fully private
achieves strong security notions and the
way we achieve it is using fully
homomorphic encryption which you might
think would be completely impractical
but it turns out that by using carefully
customized optimizations for this
specific application scenario uh we can
achieve a low cost in fact by some
measures lower than any of the prior
solutions
and concrete costs that are quite
practical even for bitcoin scale private
messaging
in the limited time of this talk i will
try to convey some intuitions about
how this works
what we've learned and
how its case
let's start with defining uh the system
model
just to be on the same page so we have
the senders we have the recipients we
have the bulletin and we have the
detection server
in our model the recipients will
create some secret keys
and
those would consist of a clue key to be
shared with all potential senders it's
effectively part of their public address
as well as a detection key that they
will be sharing with the server
the senders will be using those clue
keys in order to create uh clues for
every payload
uh those are accumulated in the bulletin
and
the server fetches the uh sorry the
server having received the detection key
from the recipient
can uh
fetch all of the bulletin payloads and
uh close and uh
digest them on behalf of the recipe and
into some accumulated digest that
eventually the recipient would be able
to decrypt
um the results of that whole process is
the plaintext payloads for example
signal messages or z cache transactions
which the recipient can then act on in
an application specific way
the properties we desire we desire are
the following
on the functionality side uh we want uh
the uh oblivious message retrieval
functionality where we get the actual
payloads
it's also useful to have the weaker
functionality of oblivious message
detection which was the one actually
achieved by some fireworks where you
only learn the indices of the pertinent
messages and maybe fetch them by some
other means that is useful for some
protocol compositions
and
in terms of
the goals
we want to
leak nothing to the detector anywhere
else in the system about which messages
are pertinent and which aren't and in
fact we don't even want to reveal who is
doing the retrieval
on their performance size we want the
digest size to be much smaller than the
bullet size and also much easier to
process ideally we want both size and
processing to be proportional to the
number of pertinent messages addressed
to the recipient rather than the much
larger total bulletin
so
our starting point um and our sort of
proof of theoretical feasibility uses
fully homomorphic encryption
let's start
with this uh strowman solution and uh
a lot of the actual engineering work uh
is making it practical
but at high level uh the idea is pretty
straightforward using the the
the full power of full homomorphic
encryption
we can uh they have the recipient
generate generate fhe keeper
and then
share that with the senders the centers
would encrypt a bunch of ones
to the cloaky of the recipients
and then the detector would uh for every
such uh clue simply try to decrypt all
of them homomorphically under the
recipient secretly encrypted
under the fha
and then compute the end function
if all the payloads were indeed uh
sorry for a payload that is indeed
associated with the clue that contains
just encryption of ones the result of
the end would be one the decrypt
the decryption of that by the recipient
would be one that is detected as
pertinent
for any other clue
under suitable assumptions that
decryption is likely to be zero because
at least one of these ciphertexts would
be decrypted randomly into a zero and
that would be detected as non-pertinent
beautiful
it actually all works out
except that it is
completely impractical
so
uh
oh my gosh excuse me for a second
okay strangely enough are you missing a
slide lovely hand-wave
um
okay so the um
the
the problem with the previous approach
is that the pertinency vector that we
created
was linear in the number of the whole
bulletin and we can compress that using
this technique inspired by private
stream search where we have a bunch of a
ciphertext serving as accumulators and
counters
and we add linear combinations
to these in a randomized fashion
concretely we take the pertinent vector
on the left and we multiply it by the
indices in order to get a vector that is
zero for impertinent messages and
contains the index for pertinent ones
and then we add each such entry into a
random counter and accumulator
so we increment the accumulator by the
value and the counter by one
consequentially as long as there are no
collisions the decryption by the
recipient can just decrypt they
accumulate the accumulators and bring
out the indices and that yields
detection
if there are any collisions that these
counters larger than one then that would
be detected as well and we can cope with
that by a variety of techniques
um finally in order to
achieve retrieval we need to also handle
the payloads and we do that by general
generalization of the previous technique
this time we take the payloads and
multiply them by the front lens vector
and then we accumulate that using a big
matrix
and
we get ciphertext which are linear
combinations of the pertinent payloads
and
if we use a suitable sparse linear
random code to generate a matrix then we
have the property that even for a very
small digest proportional to the number
of
pertinent messages or at least quite
linear in it
the
the resulting message can be it can be
decrypted
and there are a lot more details in the
paper that i'm skipping
so we achieve a scheme that uh
based on generic fhe gives us a
functionality and it is asymptotically
efficient and succinct but of course the
asymptotics have a high huge constants
using generic fh
and uh
even the state of the art of generic fha
it would still take
kilobytes just to represent the
ciphertext and
a milliseconds for every end gate so not
practical by itself
the key optimization to really make this
practical is to use a bespoke
combination of carefully tailored
encryption schemes
and specifically the pvw encryption
scheme based
on a similar assumptions the lwe to uh
the full-blown full homomorphic
encryptions but it's much more
lightweight in ciphertex size and in its
uh decryption uh
when done homomorphically
so it so happens that uh the inner
product that dominates the cost of pvw
decryption
um it's simply taking the the ciphertext
and computing its inner product with a
secret key
can be plugged into a different fully
homomorphic schemes say the bfv scheme
and be executed as a simple the
circuit of multiplicative depth one
and the rest of the decryption namely
range checks can also be done
efficiently
and downright this yields a dramatic
improvement in efficiency
taken together what we achieve is the
same system overview that we discussed
before but uh with
various encryptions under various
schemes floating around connected the
right way and making the best use of the
properties of each one
other techniques i will not have time to
go into is a lot of optimization of the
way we use the bfv scheme
and
combinatorial optimizations for this
scenario and the trade-offs uh tailoring
the
the scheduling of the operations to
reduce the memory footprint uh reducing
the key sizes all of this and more in
our apron paper
lastly i want to briefly discuss the
security aspects beside the obvious one
we've discussed i also alluded to some
assumptions that previous schemes made
about honest recipients and cinders and
this is where that comes in
in the ideal world uh we just have nice
senders sending messages and uh they are
all summarized by detectors on behalf of
multiple recipients
however imagine that one of those
servers is malicious and they inject a
malicious clue
into the system
or maybe they were fooled by a malicious
recipient to give them a malicious
cloakie that gen that generates
malicious clues when used by an honest
sender
either way a malicious clue may for all
we know have the property that once
injected into the bulletin it infects
every the
payload
sorry it detects it
it infects every detection process
such that all the digests are polluted
with that payload and are basically
flooded
with
arbitrarily many copies of that same
message causing a denial of service on
the system and concretely overflow of
the digests
uh it turns out that the pyro schemes
are concretely vulnerable to this this
was also observed by others and our
scheme uh explicitly mitigates that
another issue that prior schemes had is
an issue of killing ability because even
if looking at an individual message some
privacy guarantees are given looking at
the keys they may be linkable and what
we want is that the detection key is
coming from different parties or
clookies coming from different parties
or detection includes coming from
different parties are all
indistinguishable from the case where
they came from the same party
and that means you can create multiple
keys and give them around use z cash
diversify addresses have multiple
detectors serving you all without
leaking what you're doing in your access
patterns and this is an additional
property that we define non-trivially in
the chip
performance turns out to be surprisingly
practical for example for detection the
digest size is less than a byte per
message
the detector's computation
is about a tenth of a second per message
the recipient's computation this is all
for typical parameters uh is uh
about five milliseconds
um
the clue size is less than a kilobyte uh
the one sticking point is that the
detection key size uploaded to the
server for processing is about 100
megabytes which is awkward but we
discuss in the paper uh
the not terrible practicality of this
uh finally all of this is achieved with
the
with the full strongest notion of
privacy and no assumptions about the
environment
likewise for full retrieval uh
communication for typical parameters
inspired by zcash and bitcoin is about
nine bytes per message um
and um
the computation is also a deep sub
millisecond the message process and
finally the recipients computation is as
you may notice in fact faster than any
other scheme including those that rely
on trusted hardware or make stronger
assumptions
um
sorry i misspoke it no it did not work
cool uh in terms of scaling uh the
asymptotics are portrayed here and uh
um the bottom right parts of every graph
are basically our schemes so as the
bulletin size grows our schemes are more
competitive than any others
and uh let me conclude with some real
world considerations um the concrete
costs in terms of dollars running on the
cloud expense are less than two dollars
per million messages scanned
um the detection costs are a negligible
for current privacy preserving uh the
schemes
and can even be paid for in the
underlying cryptocurrencies
there are many integration
considerations when you look at the
specific blockchains and uh how you
would convey the additional information
these are discussed in the paper but i
will reveal that
under gas grant by the z cash foundation
there is now an ongoing prototype
implementation showing that all of this
is workable
and uh lastly uh while i uh project the
github url for the the code which is
rapidly being developed and improved
i'll mention ongoing work reducing the
detection cost
reducing key sizes and communication
[Music]
reducing a computational assumption that
is needed for
achieving denial of service resistance
without a performance overhead
um
improving the integrity protection
against malicious detectors privacy is
already there
and extending to additional
functionality like group messaging as
well as the aforementioned integration
with concrete systems
thank you again and i'm
delighted to take your questions
[Applause]
okay uh thank you very much aaron for
that that talk and thank you for
fighting through the technology um if
you want to ask questions of aaron and
your remote you should use the zulu
server not the chat feature in zoom i
saw somebody i think it was dimitri
posting there dimitri please copy your
question across to uh to zulip and
actually we're out of time for questions
i'm sorry iran you used the full 20
minutes
so please join us on zooloop and maybe
there'll be some questions for you there
and you'll be able to get some
interaction going but i think we want to
move move along and i'll invite to the
stage now our general chair who's
carrying a chair this is what a general
chair does
[Applause]
the work the work never stops for peter
peter you wanted to make an announcement
of some kind i think
you'll do that after the third share
okay so he's building up to an
announcement
maybe you can ask people on stage
already yeah sure so um please welcome
to the stage our participants in the ama
uh so we have yuan are you there
welcome uh and we have yuval yaram
and last but not least i think we have
uh kathy if she's there
great and this is
maybe the perfect moment for you to clap
and
[Music]
and then for me to make a very short
announcement so if somebody lost their
phone uh we have it at the reception
desk also if somebody who attended the
hacks workshop before this lost their
glasses we also have those