all right good afternoon everybody our
good morning to folks remote good
evening to folks in more easterly time
zones
uh
this this is the
1 30 p.m amsterdam time session about
secure messaging um i will be your
session chair i'm richard barnes
um now i believe the conference has had
a few remote presentations but i will be
the first
remote session chair of the of the
conference so i appreciate it you know
we might have a couple of bugs to work
as we go so i appreciate your tolerance
there
uh with all that said though um i think
let's go ahead and
get straight into things um our first
speaker today on secure messaging is uh
britta hale uh to talk to us about uh
securing messaging authentication
against active men and middle attacks
with that uh proto please
hey thank you
[Applause]
the secure messaging has gathered quite
a bit of attention the last several
years due to its ability to have for one
support asynchronicity
as well as some post-compromise
basically features such as forward
secrecy and the ability to heal from a
passive attacker
and this work we'll look at the active
attacker case
this is joint work with my co-author
benjamin darling
the signal is fairly representative of a
typical continuous key exchange protocol
used in the messaging space and what
we'll focus on here but the
observations we have applied to other
messaging protocols as well
what you see here is the core of a
signal ratchet essentially the
asynchronous diffie-hellman ratchet
between alice and bob
with ratchet keys shown in blue and they
are combined to make a premaster secret
which is then kdf for a root key
and every time we drive a new key we see
that i think your slides are not
transitioning you may want to re-share
your slides
oh thank you for letting me know i'll
give that a try
let me know if you can see the next
slide please
no
okay
it is showing that i cannot resume share
it's blocked permissions
there's something in the chat that says
so you need to do control i in the pdf
can you av team at the end hop open
there we go thank you
can you see the different slides
that looks good to me all good okay
go go ahead all right
so we're back to alice and bob and we've
got distribution service in the middle
uh supporting this asynchronous key
exchange
so so far so good uh these sessions are
often lasting for
months or even years so it's a
continuous long-lived session
and that raises some questions about
authentication because in a normal key
exchange protocol parties will
authenticate at the very start of the
protocol
so how do we do this in signal for
example
well in signal we have a variant that
uses the user as an out of band
mechanism
to support authentication and it works
on trust in the first use method
otherwise so you just trust the keys at
the beginning but at some point the
users meet up and compare either numeric
codes or scan qr codes
that are paid based on public
keys so this very important point they
are based on public keys uh they're then
used to compute fingerprints and are
concatenated
so the claim in the app is that this
will verify the security of the user's
encryption
but there are a few issues
first of all these fingerprints again
are based on public static information
so unlike with a normal mutual
authentication protocol where
the users are proving knowledge of some
secret key here they are proving
knowledge of public static values
this is further complicated by the fact
that we are showing them to the user
through a display and there's various
attacks in the literature that actually
target the display
to and from the user
these types of attacks do not generally
imply compromise of the secret keys on
the device so it's not a typical crypto
compromise instead they
either through malware or various
techniques are able to display something
to the user
or alternatively
manipulate the user input on the screen
another
consideration to this is the possibility
of
impersonation after compromise so if a
device was compromised in the
cryptographic sense
a man in the middle could basically
impersonate alice to bob or bob to alice
uh fairly trivially that's the active
attack that's normally out of scope and
in signal analyses
however if you're talking about alison
bob comparing qr codes out of band for
example this will not be detected
because once again those are based those
qr code computations are based on
long-term static values and have nothing
to do with happening with what's
happening here in a given epoch so
essentially alice and bob can compare
everything looks great in person
all the while being mad in the middle
so this is not exactly ideal
and the question is can we do better
now i should know that there is a
possible argument here where we say
actually compromise is our scope for
signal authentication or any similar
messaging authentication
so this simply doesn't apply
however the natural
observation encounter to that
is that if we are not considering
compromise why are we doing a ratcheted
key exchange at all
because if we're not considering that a
device could be compromised then we
could just assume that a long-term
static symmetric key is fine
so if we would really like to get
authentication on this that matches the
signal context this ratcheted key
exchange context somehow we need to tie
it to the epochs
and we also need to
basically
model that human user in some way
now that's not necessarily intrinsic
that you always have to use this user
outband but that's the current paradigm
so how can we capture that how can we
get some sort of security model that
correctly reflects the types of attacks
that we see on that sort of channel
so in this work we actually look at
that type of framework with the
immediate epoch three priority
authentication model
and we do this by splitting into two
pieces it is three-party but it's not
your typical three devices because again
what the user does and their interaction
is completely distinct from having
simply a third device
on the device the device channel we have
all sorts of typical queries that one
sees in a continuous keygrain agreement
protocol analyses
and models and then on the user to
device channel we have similar but
different types of queries essentially
that we have short-term
access and we also have long-term access
to either what is displayed to the user
or what the user is able to enter into
the device so possibly misinterpreting
user inputs and so forth
we then further split this up uh into
different cases and look at them
separately in crossfire when the
protocol is secure and when not so in
one case we say it is a typical
cryptographic attack where
the adversary has complete control on
what happens from device device in other
words a compromised device model but we
restrict it on the user's device side
and in the flip side for the compromised
user
we say the adversary has unrestricted
access on the user side
but we are going to restrict it on the
device's device
so that compromise device is really that
classic case of a man in the middle
possibly attacking and us wanting to
detect it that they have complete
control
and for the reasons already noted a
signal is insecure in both of these
settings for our model
so how can we fix this what can we do
about it and the beauty of this solution
is that it is so incredibly simple first
of all in order to get authentication
for
at the epoch to be able to
detect everything
that could be a man in the middle we
maintain a hash over all the public
ratchet values up until the point of
comparison of the qr codes
we also include role separation which
will come in in a minute when we
basically
compare whether or not you do numeric
comparison or simply a qr code scan with
where you can differentiate with the qr
code scan so that you don't have
reflection attacks from just reading a
screen
and from this hash from these hashes we
combine them with an authentication key
now this authentication key is a new
introduction to the protocol it's simply
one more key derivation
and that's derived per epoch
we then compute the fingerprints the new
fingerprints
over these authentication keys and the
hash ratchets
to
basically
have a new value that a user can compare
and by maintaining two of these we're
able to account for asynchronicity as
well
now
this does not mean that they need to be
driving fingerprints at every epoch
that's a very important point you don't
need to be doing that
instead the user when the user wants to
compare outbound which may be you know a
year from now
they will flip the screen in the normal
signal setting so that means they have
to stop messaging right and it will flip
over to that i want to authenticate to
generate say their qr code
and at that time you can actually
compute these fingerprints
so you don't have to compute them all
the time at and you only need the last
two authentication keys which are
separate from all other keys already
derived
so what does this look like for
signal well in the
prior signal setting
this would all be x red x's
and now we can certainly achieve better
because we're able to tie
information in
for the epoch values that's the
compromise device so that active
adversary that man in the middle is
really that compromise uh device setting
that you see in green here
so even if we simply make
all assumptions are okay on the user's
device channel we can now at least
detect that man in the middle and we can
get even better with some under even the
compromise user setting if we are
allowed non-matching in the scan and the
details of that of what the different
comparison methods are can be found in
the paper
so on that i will hand it off to the
next speaker who is actually continuing
with this work to
take a look at how to do this without
necessarily relying on the user in the
middle and we'll take a joint q a at the
end
thank you
thanks
[Applause]
so now we will switch over to alexandria
who is i believe in person
yes so thank you for the presentation
okay so thank you very much for the
presentation
i will be talking about continuous
authentication in secure messaging which
as we tested is kind of a follow-up of
the work they have done and which also
tackles the issue of active
man-in-the-middle attacks in secure
messaging
and because we have mostly worked on the
signal setting i will be presenting
continuous authentication in the signal
with signal
so
yes so let's have a quick recap on
signal security
so signal offers secrecy and
authenticity as stated in the previous
presentation as well as forward secrecy
in the presence of an adversary which
can fully compromise the network as well
as leak the
secrets of some users
so here for instance if the adversary
leaks the secrets of alice then
secrecy and authenticity are no longer
no longer ensured but hopefully there is
this post-compromised security property
which states that if the adversary
remains passive then after some message
is exchanged
alice and bob will retrieve some
security because they are generating
some random numbers that they can
combine in a different manner's secret
key that the adversary will not know
but
if the adversary remains active
then the
adversary can conserve its in the middle
position which can have some dramatic
consequences as sessions are really long
leaves in signal
and he will actually
have two different sessions one with
alice and the other with bob and there
is no way on the invent channel that
alice and bob can detect such an
adversary and that is why they need to
rely on some fingerprinting
mechanism using an out-of-man channel
like we saw in the previous
presentation
and
our work is to tackle this issue and
because
almost no one is actually using those
out-of-band checks we want to make
something in-band
by leveraging the identity keys that are
used in the session initiation and are
no longer used afterwards
those identity keys could be
authenticated using an out-of-band
channel but afterwards active
adversaries would be detected on the
invent channel thanks to our mechanism
and so this is what we have contributed
we have first created a model that
captures active
so post compromise autumn
security against active
man-in-the-middle adversaries if they
have not compromised long-term keys and
we have created a generic extension that
can be applied to any secure messaging
scheme like signal to get the security
and as a proof of concept we have also
implemented this on top of the java
signal library and
[Music]
but we will not cover that here
so
our method
the core of our method is authentication
steps those are detection procedures
that happen regularly during the
communication
and which will leverage the identity
keys of users
so in this example there is an adversary
between alice and bob which has managed
to inject a message
but at some point alice and bob will
have this detection procedure that will
try to detect if there has been an
active adversary in their communication
and to do that they create a transcript
which is basically a series of cipher
texts that they may hash to save space
and alice will sign this transcript
using a identity key and send the
signature to bob and when bob receives a
signature he will also compute on his
part the transcript his own version of
the transcript and verify if his version
of the transcript
has
is
and if the signature alice has provided
is a correct signature for his version
and if there is some injection like here
then he will detect that there has been
some tempering because the signature
will not verify
however if the signature is correct for
his transcript then he can be convinced
that
only the order of the identity of alice
would be able to
force to create such a signature and it
can be convinced that they have seen the
same cipher text
so for signal and other messaging scheme
the computation of such a transcript is
actually more complex because
signal operates on an unreliable channel
and so they first need to agree on the
transcript of messages to stein because
even without attacker some messages may
get lost but it is basically
only some additional messages where
alice will send
to bob every message he has received bob
will do the same and after that they can
agree on the
set of messages to authenticate and can
perform as in the last slide
however
we are not sure that the attacker has
not compromised long-time keys and in
this event the attacker could in the
detection procedure replace alice's
signature by a forge simulator if he has
compromised alice's long-term key and in
that case there is no way that bob can
detect in-band this active adversary
however
they can use afterwards an out-of-bend
channel in some kind of fingerprinting
mechanism to exchange their transcript
and in this instance they will see that
the transcripts are different because
there has been some injection
yet they passed the detection procedure
in band and that is a proof for them
that alice's long time key has been
compromised
and
therefore
we have this
we have used two cases where either the
long term key is not compromised and
thus our generic extension will ensure
that tempering can be detected in band
and so it is some kind of
post-conforming security against active
adversaries
or we have the key compromised but then
if
alice and bob use an out of vent channel
they can detect that such a key has been
compromised and they can change it only
when necessary where we have some kind
of we force the adversary to use this
key in order and to reveal its knowledge
in order to avoid invent detection
so this is a generic solution because we
didn't use any
property of our signal is implemented so
we are
pretty sure this can be
applied to any kind of
messaging protocol to get this
bus confirmed security property as a
proof of concept we implemented it on
top on the official java library for
signal and also this is currently a work
in progress we are also investigating
other alternative solutions which may be
simpler for the specific case of signal
so thank you for your attention and
we can go to a q a with grita also
thank you alexandra um i
i can't see the mic line yet um i think
the
local team is going to turn the camera
around so i could help there's my q um
but
that's what's going on as people are
queuing up um
one question from i said i'm kind of uh
comparing uh this uh signal-like uh
code comparison flow to other
kind of what i think it was more
traditional authentication regimes where
you have things like certificates um
which you can imagine carrying forward
to a messaging situation so what i'm
wondering is you know if you imagine a
messaging situation where you had
something like certificates for users
would a bunch of this stuff still be
necessary for asynchronicity or
continuous security
or would would the certificates and
credentials handle most the
authentication needs
well i can have a go at that since it
has to do with the user side
so
you don't need a lot of the stuff that
would go into the actual like the qr
code comparison for example so
that's the good news you still need some
sort of ratchet authentication so like
what alexander pointed out is that
you need something that you're pulling
out per epoch uh in addition to
you're you're essentially lying relying
on long-term secret keys in the
certificate so you're pulling something
out per epoch
uh but but if you're combining those in
the right way then you can bypass some
of the user side
overhead that you have to compete on
great thanks
and i'm told there's someone in the
in-person queue so uh whoever's uh there
in the in the room you feel free to ask
a question please
um okay uh i have two questions one is
about the first talk and the other is
about the second one so i'll go with the
first
um doesn't
like when a device is compromised
doesn't it isn't it possible for the
attacker to
like
influence the ratchet keys that would be
used to into generating the fingerprints
later on
and wouldn't that be like
counterproductive
and for the second uh
uh presentation
doesn't the
the add-on you you
you present the signal uh completely
remove the property of reliability
that's it
i need to answer the first question
absolutely the use the adversary can
inject its own ratchet secrets and it
can manual connections simply like as
presented
what will be different is that when it
can't control the user channels when the
users compare these codes out of band
they won't match
so the users can know that there is
basically a manual some attack at some
point in time
all right
and for the deniability question we
actually are using some designated
verifier signature so it's actually
conserved in liability because only the
designated verifier can check if the
signature is correct or not
okay thanks
all right thanks for that question and
thank you again to britain alexander for
the presentations
thank you i think we need to
move on to the next next talk
again um next up we have uh matt green
talking about uh
evaluating the risks of client-side
scanning
okay uh one second i'm just
getting my video working give me two
seconds ah sorry i just stopped sharing
do that
okay hi everybody
i hate doing this remotely um excellent
okay just let me know if that's working
okay
i'm gonna take silence as a affirmation
i see it on zoom
okay
let's go with that okay today uh first
of all i'm very sorry i can't be there i
was really looking forward to this
conference but uh and then in any case
um i am talking today after those two
very strong technical talks i'm giving a
slightly less technical talk about uh
the risks of client-side scanning and
this is a talk with my co-authors uh who
are here on the screen uh some some of
whom were planning on coming but could
also not make it um and i actually want
to um
pitch a report that some of my
co-authors wrote about this topic and
i'll talk about it at the end um good so
this is a very important uh topic i
think because obviously you know we're
all talking about the technical details
of secure messaging the question now we
should be asking ourselves is you know
should we be allowed to deploy secure
messaging and that's a major debate
obviously people have talked about this
already i hate to summarize a very very
complicated policy debate in a single
slide uh but if i could summarize that
very complicated policy debate it's that
an end-to-end encrypted messaging and
end-to-end encrypted systems have begun
to proliferate we have maybe two billion
people worldwide who are able to use
antenna encryption and that number
continues to increase mostly because
companies like facebook are pushing very
hard to increase the amount of
end-to-end encryption in their platforms
this has created a lot of blowback and
the blowback is mainly from law
enforcement agencies and governments
around the world who are very concerned
that these new platforms will cause
problems uh for law enforcement for the
ability to actually trace suspects and
to do other kinds of things that they
they believe are critical um over the
last i would say up until 2019 or so
this debate was a relatively simple one
uh the question was can we gain access
to encrypted messaging in exceptional
circumstances this capability was called
exceptional access and it involved
basically having some kind of
targeted decryption capability for
governments or for for law enforcement
with a subpoena uh and the only really
good way that we had to realize that was
using key escrow and there was a you
know there were a lot of concerns about
the security and the reliability of key
escrow systems and where that debate
wound up by about 2019 was mostly kind
of a stalemate
even
people on the policy side of the debate
on the law enforcement side of the
debate felt that there were some
concerns with the existing technology
for key escrow and that there were
deployment concerns and that for at
least data in motion for messaging there
were probably some serious risks that
couldn't quite be overcome with the
systems that we had available and just
as evidence for that if you don't
believe me uh there's some great reports
one by the national academy of sciences
here in the u.s another by the carnegie
institution that really summarizes this
with a broad
group of stakeholders kind of saying the
same things that i'm saying today and
that's that's where we got to by about
and when you're in a sticky situation
when you're stuck in a chess game maybe
the answer isn't to continue playing the
chess game maybe it's to flip the board
and so in about 2019 the strategy at
least coming out of high-level
government officials in the us the uk
and australia changed and this was
represented by a open letter that was
signed by then attorney general u.s
william barr
as well as the home secretary for the uh
uk and the uh corresponding person in
australia who unfortunately their name i
don't know um and this basically
resulted in a kind of a substantial
change in the request and i don't think
that technically people realize how
substantial this change was but rather
than asking for occasional exceptional
access to
encrypted messaging this letter
essentially said hey we have all of
these essentially mass surveillance
systems these systems that are
constantly scanning messages for the
presence of abusive content such as
child sexual abuse media and other types
of content these systems will stop
working the minute uh there are
encrypted end-to-end encrypted systems
handling those messages and this was a
just a technically maybe from a law
enforcement perspective this wasn't a
big shift
technically it was a massive shift in
essentially what this entire technical
debate was about and i just want to
quote one section from the open letter
that was published back in 2019 um it
had a very specific request and the
request was this it was to embed the
safety of the public in system designs
thereby enabling you to continue to act
against illegal content effectively with
no reduction to safety and facilitating
the prosecution of offenders and
safeguarding of victims
and so this actually you know not only
did it sort of change the technical
shape of the debate but it led to a new
sort of set of research and and
discussions
in the technical community where people
began to ask is it possible
to build systems that can scan for
abusive content while maintaining end
encryption and i think for this audience
probably much of this history is not
necessary but i want to just kind of go
over the very very basics just to bring
us to a point where we're at least all
on the same page um i want to show you
briefly hopefully you can see this what
csam csam is child sexual abuse media
what what the csam detection
infrastructure looks like today in
unencrypted messaging and data sharing
systems many of you already familiar
with this
generally speaking when i send a message
through a system like facebook messenger
which is not currently uh by default
encrypted what happens is my client
sends that image up to a server that
server then computes what's called a
perceptual hash of that image and that
perceptual hash is not really a
cryptographic hash function it's a
specialized hash function that is
designed to be robust to changes in the
actual image encoding so you get a hash
or a digest that roughly summarizes the
semantic content of the image and so
there is you know typically these are
exact hashes or they can be inexact
hashes that allow comparison with some
differences to get a similarity metric
and on the server there's also a
database which is a proprietary database
of known abusive material and the image
is then compared to this database and if
it matches some kind of internal flag is
raised
there is a second version of this
approach which is being pioneered by
google which does not use perceptual
hash functions and actually uses neural
network classifiers and i just want to
compare these two because they're both
relevant since they're both being used
in unencrypted systems the hash based
approach is excellent at finding known
content even if it's been slightly
modified but it's limited to finding
known csam content these newer
approaches like the one being pioneered
by google are trained on large uh corpue
of uh known content but they can then
recognize potentially novel content and
this makes them more powerful but also
with a higher risk of false positives
potentially so these are kind of the two
systems that are in use today outside of
um encrypted systems
they both have limitations that make
them unsuitable for the deployment of
end-to-end encryption one of them is
that the server has to see the obvious
one of course is the server has to see
the media end-to-end encrypted systems
block the server server can't access
this data and so we're locked out and
can't do much um it has there is at
least you know some advantage which is
that the databases themselves and the
matching algorithms are proprietary and
they can be kept behind on the server
which makes it more difficult for
criminals to evade these systems or find
ways to uh spoof these systems
they also create another possibility
which is there's this possibility for
abuse and surveillance by providers
however we tend to discount that because
the systems are not end to end encrypted
in the first place so adding a
surveillance system on top of a
non-end-to-end encrypted system tends to
not rub people the wrong way or at least
it doesn't make the situation
dramatically worse
okay good so these are the systems that
don't work with encryption how do we do
client-side scanning how do we do
scanning when we have encrypted
systems so there are a couple of answers
to that the obvious straw man answer is
we do the scanning on the client side
and that means performing the hashing
the verification the matching on the
client side where the data is not
encrypted and then when we find a match
the client can simply report the
existence of that match up to the
provider
and this works well enough if you trust
the client but it has a major limitation
which of course is actually devastating
in the setting of csam the problem is
that nobody wants to make that hash
database available to clients and they
also in some cases don't even want the
hashing algorithms to be available to
clients and so the result of this and
there are several reasons for this one
of which is that existing perceptual
algorithms hashing algorithms may be
slightly reversible which means that you
could expose
victim content to outsiders who could
potentially reverse this you might
obtain a very low resolution image from
some of these hash values but you could
still obtain something so there's a
confidentiality risk for victims
it also allows for the possibility that
people can detect whether they are going
to be caught and they can find ways to
obey by not sending certain images and
they could even potentially create new
csan material if we were talking about
one of the systems that used a neural
network so this is generally believed to
be unacceptable exposing the hash
database directly to the client
themselves
the obvious answer and you know this
audience in particular should know the
the obvious answer is let's use crypto
uh ultimately we can build some kind of
two-party computation between the client
and the provider in which the provider
submits the hash database maybe even the
algorithms the client submits their
image that's going to be sent and the
2pc does some kind of matching procedure
and that matching procedure could be
limited it could be you know across many
messages if i send 30 messages that
match only then will some kind of signal
and possibly the decrypted content be
delivered to the provider and this is an
area that was kind of entering active
research
up until i would say august of uh 2021
so last august
and i think again this audience should
be familiar with you know what happened
last august which is that research
became very real
in a hurry um and that happened with the
release of a proposed system that was to
be deployed in all apple uh iphones at
least in the u.s last august it was
supposed to be released with ios 15. um
this received a lot of press so i won't
belabor it but uh apple developed a
client-side or two-pc based scanning
system that used a private set
intersection and a new perceptual hash
function they developed to perform uh
client-side media scanning of photo
libraries on apple phones
and really i i i can't say enough good
things about the cryptographic elements
of this protocol i think it's you know
beautifully
executed but also unfortunately i think
fairly dangerous
and i hope that i still have a little
time i'm going to just briefly talk
about some of the obvious concerns
and talk about sort of why i think apple
didn't address these this is not really
an apple focused presentation and then
hopefully i can we'll still have a
little time for people who have
questions at the end
there are a number of risks in these
systems and kind of figuring out how to
address these risks was the biggest part
of the research question that i think
was being addressed in the the year
prior to last august and the biggest one
for me
is the possibility of mission creep
these systems ultimately perform
scanning of a live database that can be
updated by a provider that database
contains information
the information is provided by
organizations that are quasi
governmental like nicknack which is the
national center for missing and
exploited children
those the actual raw imagery for very
very good reasons
is kept confidential and so ultimately
what nikmec releases is a series of
perceptual hashes of that imagery and
they are then notified after some
internal mod monitoring by companies
when there is a customer who matches
that database um so there is this
possibility that you know with or
without the consent of providers like
apple or facebook these databases could
be expanded either surreptitiously or
overtly to include new kinds of content
and i think this debate became very
heated on the internet last summer but i
really just i want to point out one
thing that you know this is not some
theoretical concern in fact if you go
back to the 2019 bar
patel letter uh you actually see that it
doesn't just talk about adding the
capability to scan for csam material it
lists other type of material as equally
important and the two types of material
that are that are given as examples are
uh terrorist content which is something
that providers in the uk at least
already stand for pretty rigorously as
well as and this one's a little weird
foreign adversaries attempts to
undermine democratic institutions
i'm not sure what a hash database looks
like for election disinformation but if
one could be built there's certainly
motivation to do this so this is not
theory there's clearly a demand to do
this
um and i just want to sort of you know
highlight apple's response to this which
is well no we won't do this
i you know there's been a lot of debate
about how credible it is that a single
provider could basically block
governments requesting this i i guess
that's the major question is you know
now that we've removed the technical
restrictions can providers actually hold
back on adding to that database
okay the next obvious concern is
unauthorized surveillance so this is a
flavor of the previous which is that
malicious providers and government
organizations can obviously sneak uh
unauthorized content into the scanning
system and there is certainly motivation
this might be a hacked provider or it
might be a hacked organization adding
this content the challenge here is that
privacy preserving two pc protocols make
this extremely difficult to prevent and
just to kind of show you you know if you
look at how difficult this is let's take
apple as an example uh apple in their
their literature says the system is
designed to be auditable
and that this is in their frequently
asked questions but when you dig into
the published documents of the protocols
that were put out by apple and you look
at their actual systems you see that
there is no evidence in any of the
actual cryptographic protocols or proofs
that these auditability systems were
built in and just to give you one very
concrete example there is a point in the
apple psi protocol where you insert when
there is an empty space in the encrypted
database you insert a random element
that random element should be a random
element but of course the distribution
of meaningful database elements is
indistinguishable from random elements
and the protocol does not do a good job
at least as currently specified at
ensuring that this doesn't happen to
real systems so there are many
challenges it's possible this could be
built into an auditable system but as
published today that hasn't been done
and that's beyond the question of how do
you actually verify the content
that's being put into the system is is
valid
uh don't want to go over here so uh last
obvious question is how do you prevent
malicious false positives with many of
these models and hash functions it's
possible to generate essentially
collisions uh harmless images that you
can send to people as memes and you can
put into people's photo libraries that
will register as matching a known hash
database and so far the current solution
to this is mostly to try to keep the
hash functions and the models secret
unfortunately this doesn't work it took
about two weeks for apple's neural hash
function to be reverse engineered last
summer and it took about three more days
for people to develop viable reasonable
looking collisions between different
images this one on the top is from greg
maxwell and the others are actually
natural collisions uh the one on the top
right and the one on the top left are
natural collisions people found just
looking through databases
um the one i want to point out at the
bottom is a call out to my students who
have been doing the same kind of work
for photo dna and other perceptual
hashes and these turn out to be just as
vulnerable to this kind of collision
attack
okay nearing the end here um what i want
to say is two things uh the first is
that none of this is over apple has
delayed its plans to deploy these
systems and we'll find out apple is a
leader so what they do will tend to
influence the industry but there are
other people who are considering this as
well uh many people have decided that
because apple delayed their plans that
the debate is over even within apple and
so on it's probably not these systems
exist and they will be built and there's
going to be a continual debate about
whether deploying them makes sense even
if apple backs off its proposal the idea
is not going to go away
the last thing that i want to say and i
want to say it to this audience of you
know many
younger junior people whose careers are
just starting out which is that you know
this is a substantial and important
debate even if we use privacy preserving
technology really backwards privacy
preserving technology where the privacy
is not applied to the users
end-to-end encrypted content detection
is a surveillance system and it's one of
the most powerful ubiquitous
surveillance systems we've ever
considered deploying
and at least in democratic nations and i
think we should think very very
carefully before we build that
infrastructure if we must build that
infrastructure then we have to figure
out how as researchers we can make it
auditable and fundamentally resistant to
abuses
from the start rather than waiting until
after it's been deployed and trying to
bolt on these systems
okay the last thing i will say is that
there is an excellent paper about this
by some of my co-authors not myself but
some of my co-authors is called bugs in
our pockets it has a much more detailed
argument about the risks than anything i
could give you in this short
presentation so please go check it out
and read it and thank you very much
[Applause]
thank you matt um
uh we have a few minutes for questions
if people have uh if people like the
microphone
or put them into shadow result
um well people already organized that to
try try and maybe pull a silver lining
out of your black slides um
i wonder you know
setting aside
the law enforcement applications you
know are there things that have been
learned through the development of these
kind of psi and npc things that have
been developed that might be applicable
to more benign uh features of messaging
systems
yeah i think that the development of
these psi systems and even two pc neural
network evaluation has been incredibly
valuable and i think you know the the
ability to do this kind of work and do
it very efficiently is important
um so you know there are clearly
applications where this is not going to
be a violation of privacy where people
need to do this kind of scanning so
there's no problem with the technology
the the concern that i have is that you
know sometimes we develop technology
before we know how whether we're ready
to do it you know what we're ready to do
with it it's kind of the jurassic park
problem of cryptography is that you know
we we need to make sure that we know how
to control the dinosaurs before we set
them free on the island but i do think
the technology is wonderful and i'm very
enthusiastic about it
okay
here we have one question my friend
please go ahead
hi thank you very much for the talk
i remember reading at some point a
report by i believe the australian
federal police
about facebook pdq uh reasoning about
the fact that while for non-malicious
they call them modifications the
performance of detecting through
positives was very good
uh this degraded very quickly as soon as
you put a minimum effort like slightly
rotating the picture or something like
that so i'm wondering uh
do you have a clear understanding of
what's the adversarial model that law
enforcement is is thinking of because i
understand that season users sometimes
can be
very much looking into uh being
adversarial to evade control while
honest users might instead not be
worrying about that and
get tracked as a consequence of enabling
this kind of technology
yeah i think that these systems what
we've learned about these systems is
they are not particularly robust to
adversarial behavior of any kind even
mild attempts to evade the system are
very easy to get away with uh this is
particularly true with the open source
algorithms but you know there's no such
thing as a secret algorithm we learned
that because both neural hash and uh and
photo dna leaked out in this summer
within weeks of this apple announcement
so you know these public algorithms are
not robust they will never be robust
it's impossible to make them so so we
are targeting a really low hanging fruit
of users who are just not trying to
evade um you know that unfortunately is
relatively easy to do right now because
it turns out that most users were caught
sending csam content don't get
prosecuted 97 of them are outside of the
us at least here so our agencies can't
really do anything with most of the
reports that we get so there's not
really much incentive to invade if the
system to work well maybe the
adversarial model would be would be
stronger but we're not there
thank you
all right
thank you again matt
great talk
thank you
[Applause]
so next to turn our attention to some
analysis on telegram four attacks and
approve for telegram and i think we have
igor stefanos um on the uh zoom to
present
igor are you there
let's see
yes can you hear me that's great please
go ahead
let me show you my screen
[Music]
okay can you see the style
yes thank you
thank you uh so let me start son
uh so this talk is based on the telegram
paper that will appear in the security
and privacy conference in may of 2020
and so uh let's start by discussing the
relevance of
it is uh one of the most uh used instant
messaging applications
uh
uh in terms of monthly active users it
has uh roughly 550 million
users
so according to the study published
previous year in new cynics uh telegram
was a predominant messaging used in the
hong kong protests in
2019 2020
and generally telegram was perceived by
protesters to provide more security than
its uh competitors
and so uh
the important advantages of telegram
according to the protesters in hong kong
are
the support of
public and private group chats up to two
uh hundred thousand people
whereas in signal you have group chats
up to at most one thousand
whatsapp supports 256.
uh second advantage of telegram is that
it supports psychonymity meaning you can
use a pseudonym rather than reveal your
phone number to the linear group
uh this is not supported by signal and
whatsapp and there are a number of other
features that
are valuable to the protesters such as
anonymous polls disappearing messages
timed or scheduled messages ability to
delete messages by other people
and so uh
i guess the most valuable thing for us
that was discovered in this paper is
that uh
the common use cases for telegram was
that it was uh generally used in large
groups
in large public groups up to 50 000
members
and in small privates so here importance
is that it's mostly used for group chats
and uh
yeah there are two different use cases
for different sizes of charts
okay so uh the telegram offers two types
of chats
shots and secret shots
in cloud chats
you can
do group communication you can do
one-on-one communication
uh you get a client server encryption uh
and
cloud chats are enabled by default so by
default you do get client server
communication
uh in contrast in secret shots uh you
can only do one-on-one communication
uh it is sent to and encrypted but it is
not enabled by the
when you open the one and one chats
[Music]
so uh in order to uh
provide this encryption uh telegram has
invented its own empty proto protocol
it's uh it is telegram's equivalent of
the tls protocol so in cloud chats
telegram uses the empty predator
protocol script and authenticate
messages from the client to the server
and then from the server to other
clients
whereas in secret chats in addition to
that
uh
the messages are also end to end
encrypted this in particular means that
uh
secret chat message each entered
encrypted message is encrypted first
to the key
and then on top of that it's again
double encrypted
you to the key of the server
encryption going on here
uh so the empty protocol
the telegram was launched with version
one of the protocol in 2013
in 2016 uh
a cca
attack against empty proto version one
in 2017 telegram updated the protocol
to release version 2.
in 2017 and 18 uh
there were two works
that
reported some words with the protocol in
2020 a paper uh proved empty
secure
in the symbolic model
assuming i feel building blocks and
obstructing away all implementation and
primitive details
and so uh the focus is literature this
part has actually been on the secret
shots whereas as discussed uh
in relation to the protests in hong kong
we do want to mostly study the cloud
charts meaning we will study the client
server
and at this point i guess the reasonable
question would be why you just not used
to instead of md proto
and uh there is no
uh
well
well basically the telegram development
team insists that they do prefer empty
proto and that it's good enough for
their purpose
so there's no sort of deeper razor than
that
okay uh so let me
explain uh how empty proto
is designed
here i will start at a very high
abstraction level and i will gradually
add some more details however it's uh
it's so complicated that i will omit and
simplify some of the those that are not
relevant to this talk
okay so let's start by
sort of the overreaching idea is that
empty proto is designed as a variant of
the encrypted mac composition
here you have some payload that
gets hushed uh with the mac algorithm
that is keyed with some long term mackie
mk
and you get the tag
as the output which is called
in empty proto
and at the same time this payload is
also
encrypted with symmetric encryption
scheme with some key in iv we'll get to
this in a second
to produce a cyber text
okay so now uh
let's uh flash out more details so this
key in ib for somatic encryption scheme
is
using a key derivation algorithm that
takes uh
the tag
as input and uses some long term
the key derivation key
as well
so
okay so this this basically represents
the
encryption algorithm in the empty
protocol
you can now imagine basically that the
decryption algorithm would google
everything first it would take the cyber
text
and the message key it would derive the
symmetric key using the kdf from the
message key decrypt the ciphertext and
then it would have to do the
notification of the hash in order to
confirm that
the type of text was not tampered with
okay so now uh
i guess the most important detail here
is obviously that
uh in in genetic
script and mac constructions uh them
outwards reveals the quality of the site
of the blank text or playing paint modes
here this is not a problem because
payload is uh
uh
payload consists of a bunch of metadata
and it will guide that uh nautical
plaintext will be the same
uh so in particular the uh
the details of the payloads will be
important for our attacks so let us look
at each
so the payload starts with two
128-bit blocks of metadata uh followed
by an arbitrary number of blocks
containing the actual body of the
message
and then some random padding uh from
twelve to one thousand points
so in the first block you get server
salt and session id those are random
64-bit values uh the server result is
changed by the server roughly once per
hour
the session id value remains the same
until the long term keys are changed
block
you get the message sequence number
and message length the first
sequence number sends a distinct counter
to each message
the message length is basically the
length of the message
uh in bytes
um
yeah so
now uh let's continue with the
design of empty proto this metric
encryption scheme that is used here is
actually
an
infinite garbage extension mode
based on as256
the infinite garbage extension is not a
commonly used
operation and there is some prior work
showing that ige does not satisfy
certain security notions
however observe that when compared to
the cpc mode the ige mode in addition
make source each plaintext block the
next ciphertext block
this makes it rather straightforward
that if cbc provides cyber text
inductability
from uniformly random strings on a piece
and so does ige
and we will show well we show in our
work that this property is sufficient so
ig is fine for the purpose
uh now let's look at uh the construction
of the
message authentication code algorithm
and the kdf algorithm
most of them are actually based on
sha-256
the mac algorithm concatenates the
long-term message key with the payload
runs it through shuffle 256 and then
truncates out
the middle 128 uh bits of the output
that's the tag uh the kdm
splits the long term uh kdf keying helps
it's
two
evaluations of sha-256 function
one of them could get nice message key
with the
first half of
long-term key
the second concatenates the second half
of the kdf keys message key eight
outputs the concatenation of uh
cases that they derived
uh
finally it also turns out that different
but related mock and kdf keys are used
uh depending on whether a message never
be pro present from a client to a server
or in the opposite direction
here you can see a picture
that shows how to drive the kdf in my
keys
from a row g x y value that is uh
obtained as a result of dp harm and key
exchange
and you can see that
depending on which direction you send a
message from client or from server you
would use related keys
in order to
run kdf and mac
okay so
now
to finish the about the construction
uh in our work we managed to prove that
the variant of mt proto satisfies some
form authenticate of authenticated
information
but this comes with many caveats
our formal definition of empty
prototypes from the actual real world
construction
or simplifies it in several ways for
example
uh we have to assume that the output of
the dp helmet key exchange gx y is a
uniform bit string it's actually not
furthermore our proof relies on novel
assumptions about the block sniper
shackle 2 that is used in the davies
meyer construction of the shah 256
compression function
we need it to be perfect
different forms of related key
plated keys and key leakage
it seems that any proof here would help
to deal with such related keys questions
about chakaltu
to conclude the discussion about
probable security further analysis is
needed to reach any conclusions or
security of empty proto as the
uh actual real world
okay so now uh
now that we have uh disposed of the
proof let us simplify
uh
our picture for empty proto design again
so now we'll discuss attacks
psychopaths will only need this much
uh details in particular we will not
care how a mac and kdf algorithms are
constructed we only care about the
structure of the payload
and about uh
ig mode of operation
[Music]
so uh we found four weaknesses in empty
proto
and we reported them to telegram on
april 16 2021 uh telegram of knowledge
just soon after and they acknowledged
the behaviors
on june 8
2021. uh via disclosure on july 16 2021
uh telegram told us that they do no
security or bug fixed religions except
for immediate post-release cash fixes
they
wish to issue security advisories that i
was watching
and they did not commit to release
20 release dates for specific fixes
and so eventually they uh
brought the fixes as part of regular
updates in
version 781 for android 783 for ios and
284 desktop
now uh let's speak about our attacks
so we have four attacks um
we have an attack showing
empty proto is not idcpa secure this is
a purely theoretical attack with a
message reordering attack uh it is
trivial and easy exploits
obviously not very impactful we have
site
timing sectional attacks against client
and server uh the one against the client
does plaintext recovery against the
server that's men in the middle and key
exchange uh unfortunately they are not
rather fortunately they are not
feasible in
practice uh and yeah telegram awarded
the back bounty for situational attacks
and for the overall analysis with it
okay so i'm gonna scroll through these
first two attacks quickly because they
are trivial
uh for the id
attack uh
i'm not going to the details here but
basically what happens is that
uh if a payload is encrypted
and sent from a client to the server but
the client does not receive an
acknowledgement uh that
that the encrypted payload was received
then
uh the client would re-encrypt the
payloads again using all the same
metadata uh this message but a different
budding different random padding
so what it leads to is that uh
if there is a collision in pudding
across multiple encryptions of the
payloads with no acknowledge in between
then the birthday would give you a
collision message key collision key
would result in some blocks of the cyber
text being equal
so you would be able to tell whether
the ciphertext coming from the server to
the client do encrypt an acknowledgement
of the receipt
of your payloads or not
an idcp attacker
the second attack uh does message
reordering attack uh
so for the message reordering an
adversary sitting on a wire from a
client the server can simply reorder
it's encrypted messages
and uh
the server is uh it's a server actually
time stamps uh the cyber text it
receives
in the order that it receives them
rather than in the order they are sent
from the client
and so then eventually even the client
who were sending these messages
initially what's uh update is
transcripts to use the same order of
messages
okay so let's get to the interesting
attacks uh
uh first uh programming session will
attack against clients
here uh consider what happens when
you run the empty proto decryption
algorithm
so you run you take a separate text you
run it through ig
mode decryption
and as a result you get uh
the first two blocks of the payload
server sold session id
the message sequence number message
length and some message
so what happens in three of the what
happened before
it's fixed obviously in the three
official clients was that
the clients run some sanity checks and
decrypted payload prior to verifying the
hash
so in particular
here we see examples that uh
immediately after decrypting
uh the cyber text and according to
payloads the message length value is
compared to different values in
different clients
either both to allow you to supply the
attacker or to a value supply to or the
constant 2284 or some more complicated
check in either way if this
uh
sanity check of the message length
failed
uh
then in the worst case in the second
case in desktop client uh the
verification
of the hash was completely omitted this
obviously gives a
great opportunity to run
uh time exceptional
uh
igor we're running a little short on
time so if you could try and wrap up
please
yeah
okay so
uh what we do here is we use the
uh
we use the id from the
ssh paper in 2009 against cbc
uh
assume that we know uh message m1
and message mi minus 1
we want to learn the contemi
what we do is we
take the value at the input of the block
cipher
function for the message you want to
learn and move it to the second block
so we
set c2 equals ci
i minus 1 xor
m1
we uh and we observed that at the
outputs of the second decryption
we get uh
m i x or c i minus one the same on the
blue dots here and here
so in the result we get
uh two equals this blue thing x or c one
now uh the central analytics that i just
explained allow us to infer some
uh some bits of m two
basis sectional attacks we also know c
one and c i minus one so we can learn
the bits of i
again in the similar way uh to the paper
from 2009
so unfortunately this attack fails
because we don't actually want
uh and one that one contains several
salt and session id it's not clear
whether these two values were intended
to be secret in empty proto but in
effect they are secrets
uh so
so still
this attack highlights that the empty
proto design is brittle
so as we discussed before empty proto
basically adopts the variant of the
ecliptin composition uh protecting the
integrity of plaintext
rather than the cyber text necessitates
operating with the decryption key and
untrusted data this opens up the
possibility of timing side channels
so we found three such side channels in
the pressure clients but empty proto
also encourages
the use of third party clients so there
is a possibility that more developers
got it wrong
it points at some ambiguity on whether
working uh
on new open source implementations of
this protocol introduces more security
to the ecosystem or other risks adding
new attack vectors
so all of these sort of devices could be
entirely intercept
by protecting the integrity of the
cybertex
the plaintext
so uh
quickly uh
uh so since we
so
so studying the telegrams exchange for
society scope will probably work but uh
since we knew that the server sold 1090
values for the attack on the previous
slide we went ahead and broke the key
exchange in order to play these values
so key exchange used uh textbook rsa
encryption it uh encrypted data uh that
was significant a good connection of the
actual thing to put it with a hash of
this date and reach some pudding
and again this goes to release similar
times uh time exceptional attackers in
the previous slide
and so we managed to recover the data by
solving noisy linear equations via
lattice reduction
we could use this data to recover
several stalls in session id uh fields
we could
theoretically use it for demand in the
middle attack against the you get the
change exportedly that's not feasible
because
the time excitation null is really small
recovering session id requires to
disperse for computations and key
exchange for timeout before
the middle can be completed
the problem here is that uh
telegrams uh server code is not open
source and they do not want to open
source
uh so we could not verify any of this
any of this ourselves we had to rely on
uh what telegram told it would or not
would not work as an attack
okay so finally uh let me conclude by
saying that
um
large parts of telegram remain uh
unsteadied
like secret shots key exchange
multi-user security forward security and
so on and so there is a lot of resting
topics for future work
i will conclude with that thank you and
you can find information at the link
[Applause]
okay so um
i think we are way over time sorry so
this this time we will not be taking
questions
uh and i propose we move directly to the
next speaker okay with you richard
yes thank you
and finally our last speaker will be
repeatedly who i believe is in person
don't see him at the podium though oh
there we
are great
uh so everyone's going to talk to us
about making signal postpones and secure
savior please take it away
hi everybody
[Applause]
hi my name is
and i'll talk about how to make signal
post quantum secure and we'll do this by
using a post quantum version of another
chronos in albuquerque exchange protocol
based on designated verifier signatures
and camps this is joint work with
jacqueline with jacqueline brendell
felix gunter kiss and jansson and
douglas stabila
so we're looking at the setting of
instant messaging where alice wants to
talk to bob you've probably seen this
before
so but what do we do if bob is offline
at the point in time when alice wants to
initiate the conversation for this case
bob needs to pre-upload his key material
to a key server so alice can fetch it
whenever she wants to initiate the
conversation
and this property we call asynchronicity
another property that we want is mutual
authentication meaning that alice should
be sure that she's talking to bob and
vice versa
and the third property that we're
looking for is offline deniability or
especially signal is looking for this
property intuitively this means that if
you have a protocol sorry a transcript
of a protocol execution then you can
deny that you were involved in producing
this transcript but i get into more
formal details on this later on
and with this
message flow this is actually split into
two protocols so the first one is the
initial handshake protocol extender
triple diffie-hellman or x3dh for short
and afterwards come the double wretched
protocol which you use to keep getting
new keys to encrypt your messages
and let's get into the details of the
initial handshake protocol x3dh
so in the beginning bob sends over his
pre-key bundle the key material from the
previous slide to alice
and this freaky material consists of
bob's public key so bob has three keys a
long term key medium
medium term key and an ephemera key
while alice is only using her long term
key and ephemera key
and then they doing lots of
diffie-hellman
so this is how they're pairing their
difi haman shares alice is using her own
long-term key paired with bob's medium
term key
and then alice is pairing her ephemera
key with all of bob's keys
and then alice will send over both of
her divi helmand shares to bob so bob
can recompute the same tiffi hammond
secrets
and now they have a shared secret the
problem with this approach is it's
relying on defend and as we all know
this is not post phantom secure and that
is the starting point of this work how
do we replace this because quantum
computers are a threat so we don't know
when they are coming but if they come
and we have a huge problem
right as we've seen the initial
handshake is vulnerable to to quantum
attackers
and then the other part the double
ratchet protocol this can be replaced
from key encapsulations mechanisms i was
shown by alvin at r in 2019 so the focus
of this talk will be how to replace the
initial handshake protocol
another candidate for this are key
encapsulation mechanisms because they
are a primitive that is being
standardized by nist currently so post
quantum secure versions so this is what
we are trying to use and let's see if
this works out first let's recap what
key encapsulation mechanisms are
so bob has a key pair consisting of a
public and a private key and he sends
over his public key to alice
alice can then encapsulate against bob's
public key resulting in a cipher text
and a key then ellis sends over the
cipher text to bob and bob can
decapulate the cipher text with the use
of his secret key now both of them have
the key which they can use to come well
which is their shared secret
this is what uh key encapsulation
mechanisms are right
so how can we build a post control
version of signal using just
encapsulation mechanisms a direct
construction could look as follows
bob has three chem key pairs a long-term
medium term and a family again and then
alice is encapsulating against each of
bob's keys
then alice can send over all of these
three cyphercam ciphertexts to bob who
can then decapsulate them the problem
with this approach is that there is no
ls to bob authentication from bob's
perspective anybody could have produced
these encapsulations
so what can we do to get some alice to
group authentication
maybe we can add a signature
the problem with the plain signature
though is that it breaks deniability
because only alice can create a
signature that verifies under her public
key
and as we've heard earlier deniability
is an important feature to signal
so this approach doesn't work
however let's keep this in mind
the idea of using key encapsulations to
build a post quantum version of the
initial handshake protocol has been
around for a bit though so there was um
this split cam paper by brendlat allen
2020 who proposed to use a new primitive
they called splitcamps
and it turned out though that this is
not instantiable
with
sufficient security parameters
but the design idea from the previous
slide is stuck around so using key
encapsulation mechanisms and not
signatures but some form of deniable
authentication
and we propose to use designated
verifier signatures for deniable
authentication
independently hashimoto came up with the
same idea and they've been using ring
signatures for deniable authentication
so next let's review how what designated
verifier signatures are
alice wants to deniably authenticate a
message m to bob
so how does she do this she's using the
signing algorithm which takes her own
secret key and bob's public key as in
alice is designating this signature to
bob
and this produces an ls to bob signature
and the
next algorithm which is the difference
to plane signatures is the simulate
algorithm which allows bob to simulate a
signature so this uses alice's public
key and bob's secret key and this also
produces an alice to bob signature and
the cool property of dvs schemes is the
source siding property which tells you
that it is indistinguishable if this is
a signature analyst to bob signature
that was produced by the sine algorithm
or by the simulate algorithm
spoiler this is where we're getting our
deniability from
right so what's the core idea of our
protocol and of the protocol from
hashimoto at al
[Music]
just the core idea so i'm skipping the
medium term keys for a bit
we have long term keys for both parties
which consists of a dvs key and for the
responder side we're also using a chem
key
so the responder is using a camke
actually for both long term and
ephemeral key
and then what does the initiator do
alice encapsulates against both of bob's
chem keys resulting in two
cam cipher texts
and next we still need this deniable
authentication which was a problem
earlier and we use the dvs signature for
this so
we have a designated verifier signature
designated from alice to bob and the
message we're signing are the two cam
cipher texts
this is the core idea of our protocol
and let me briefly mention that
hashimoto
follow the same approach however they're
using ring signatures here instead of
dbs but it turns out that dvs signatures
and ring signatures are equivalent for
rings of two users under some
constraints
right
now that we've looked at the protocol
what is this deniability property in
more detail that i've been talking about
so this is an excerpt from the signal
specification on the initial handshake
protocol and what they want is that
there is no cryptographic proof that
for it
okay the laser pointer doesn't seem to
be working so there's no cryptographic
proof that if you have a third party
who has access to who has compromised
the private keys of all parties and this
third party furthermore has access to a
conversation transcript then it has to
be the case that this transcript was
produced by some party with legitimate
private keys
okay this is a block of text how do we
parse this into a nice cryptographic
definition so first case
we have alice who has used the run
algorithm to produce the message using
her own secret key resulting in a
transcript and a session key
second case bob has faked a transcript
so the fake algorithm is something that
we've also included in our syntax
here bob uses his own secret key to also
come up with a transcript and a session
key
and next we have this third party the
judge and the judge cannot tell
if the transcript and session key was
produced by the run algorithm or by the
fake algorithm and that should be the
case even if the judge has access to all
of the secret keys
and
this is the new deniability definition
that we propose
so there's the prior definition
deniability definition by the remainder
at all but compared to their definition
our definition is weaker in the sense
that it gives the fake algorithm access
to the secret key of the responder
so they're
fake they basically have public
simulatability on the other hand our
definition is stronger in the sense that
our
judge gets all of the secret keys
and we believe this to be a very
important point to achieve deniability
against nation state adversaries or
other nation state judges
because they may somehow find out your
secret key by compromising your devices
by issuing a super ena for you to give
up your secret keys or whatever else
and lastly
our definition has the advantage that
you can build a proof with respect to
our definition without needing any
strong knowledge type assumptions
right
and this is not all there is to our
construction the full construction is
what we call signal in a post quantum
regime or spqr for short
and it includes the full scope of what
needs to be covered by signal what needs
to be covered by an initial handshake
protocol to be usable in the real world
and that is we also include medium-term
keys to protect against the case that
all of the ephemera keys are used up
this is also
the case for the currently used x3dh
protocol also we achieve security
against
randomness exposure by using a twisted
prf
and of course we show a security of our
protocol with respect to a security
model similar to the one from the
original signal analysis by cone gordnet
all from 2017 and of course we show a
deniability of our new protocol
with regard to the newly proposed
definition that i just talked about
earlier
okay
and there's as you can see on the right
hand side there's lots of details which
you can all find in the paper
right
then there's more concurrent work
because this is such a pressure crashing
issue
more people have looked at it lobster
and galbraith have proposed to lift the
x3dh protocol to the setting of super
singular isogenes and they've kept the
same message flow as for the original
x3h protocol but now we're over super
singular isogenes and that's where we
get the post quantum security
so all in all there's three um different
proposals for how we can get an initial
handshake protocol that is post quantum
secure sorry to be more precise s4 so
the baseline that we can measure against
would be the original or the x38
protocol which is currently in use but
it's not post quantum secure
and this was shown to be deniable with
respect to public simulator ability so
the definition from the remainder at al
and it filters the the full scope so
they have medium term keys and security
against randomness exposure
then there's two protocols suggested by
hashimoto's all
both of them are post quantum secure and
they are using cams and ring signatures
and their second protocol that they
suggest is using music on top and they
need the musics to get this deniability
with respect to public simulatability
however their protocols do not fulfill
the full scope they do not include
medium term keys or maximum exposure
security and next there's our protocol
spqr
which is based on cams and dvs and as
post quantum secure and shown to be
deniable with respect to strong judges
also our protocol prefers the full scope
and lastly there's the super singular
isogeny x3gh protocol from dobson
galbraith which is also also post
quantum secure and deniable with respect
to public simulatability
and for first the full scope let me also
point out that the
that the protocols by hashimoto as well
as ours are generic constructions so you
can plug in a cam and dvs or ring
signature based on whichever hardness
assumption you want while x3dh and super
singular isogeny at x3dh are fixed to
one problem which we assume to be hard
so to conclude
how do we get signal to be post quantum
we have several suggestions for how to
replace the initial handshake protocol
we can use the protocol from
hashimoto.al our spqr or the suggestion
from dobson galbraith
and for the double wretched protocol we
can use the for example the construction
from the encapsulation mechanisms by
avanadahl
so one question no actually two
questions for the audience for the
broader community so to say
which deniability notion do we want um
that the initial hashtag protocol
achieves
do we need deniability with respect to
strong judges do we want public
simulatability do we want a stronger
version of both of them what type do we
want and also how do we instantiate
these protocols
so which hardness problems do we want to
rely on or do we want to rely on always
on our misogynist
this these are my questions for you sir
to say thank you very much for your
attention and i'm happy to take
questions
[Applause]
thank you for that um i believe we have
someone in the audience for a question
please go ahead
thank you very much
did you have a look at the
signal group chats as well
no
all right easy enough question
thank you again for the presentation
[Applause]
and with that we are at the end of our
session and we are at the coffee break
for those of you there in person so